In this clip, we're going to take a look at the classic load balancer.
So, the classic load balancer has been around at Amazon for a long time,
and its primary job is protection,
and you could also say its primary job is to work with auto
scaling groups to actually give you scalability.
The first concept to have about these load balancers is they're a big,
managed server farm, and when you select a load balancer from the portal,
your load balancer deployed in a public subnet with an elastic IP address,
and that protects your web servers.
That's the first line of defense.
Optionally,
your application servers could use this load
balancer hosted in a private subnet.
So maybe you have application servers that don't need
any more balancing past layer 4, so it might work for you as well.
Now,
the instances can be configured to accept traffic only from your load balancer.
So we ultimately have some protection there as well.
Well how do I do that?
I install it in a virtual private cloud.
I can use security groups.
I can define access in that way.
Now I can also use CloudWatch metrics and monitor my load balancer,
and those metrics can also be used to throw alerts.
Hey, network traffic has increased, add more servers.
Hey, network traffic has decreased, get rid of some of those servers.
And these metrics include things like back-end connection errors,
healthy host count, back-end error codes,
so they're very, very useful.
Logs for the load balancer will capture the requests.
Where are my logs stored?
Oh yeah, S3, and they're published every 5 minutes.
CloudTrail can also track all the calls made to your load balancer.
Your API call history could be really useful to perform security analysis,
tracking of resource changes, compliance auditing.
So up to 20 load balancers can be created per region
for the different client needs.
So,
you could assign multiple load balancers with different
settings for the different types of devices that are
accessing your web applications.
So for example,
you might have desktop users and mobile users using
a specific protocol and port, and so the load balancer is using a listener,
and this is a process that checks for connection requests.
Once that connection is made,
it's sent to a port at the back end to send it to the instances.
Now let's take a look at the classic routing of the load balancer.
So the node of the internet-facing load balancer
has a public elastic IP address.
And when you make your load balancer internet facing,
there's a DNS name that's created, linked to the public IP address,
and Route 53 then knows about that elastic load balancer.
So the client will use this.
They'll say well I'm going to use Route 53 to
resolve the domain name that I know, and this,
of course, could be built into the application.
So if somebody's going to buy coffee from Wired Brain, they get their app.
Embedded in the app is here's where you go, this is the public IP address.
So the client's found the load balancer.
The listener is listening.
The client request goes to a healthy registered instance.
How does the load balancer know it's healthy?
Oh that's right, it's monitoring it, those health checks,
but it's sending it on its private IP address.
Again,
the web server isn't exposed to the public side with the public IP address.
Now the typical technology in the background for
the listening is DNS round-robin.
There are other options you can use.
This is kind of the classic, standard way that it's done for web servers.
Round-robin means, say you've got client number 1,
client number 1 gets sent to server number 1,
client number 2, server number 2, client number 3,
server number 3.
Of course the pool of servers, maybe there's only two,
maybe it balances one, then the other, one,
and then the other.
In fact,
this load balancer is able to determine that the instances that it's talking to,
it will actually be able to determine the size of the instance and
how many requests an actual instance could handle.
Now does it make sense to have an unbalanced number of
sizes in your load balancing pool?
Not really, but the load balancer is smart enough to be able to handle that.
So you're communicating from the front end to the back end.
How long should that messaging, should that channel be open?
Well, the default idle timeout is 60 seconds,
and you can change this,
but the timeout applies to the front-end and the back-end connection.
Some caveats,
the classic load balancer routes requests to your
instances on the private subnet, really want to hammer home that point,
so if you look at your own design and say,
hey, why do we have public IP addresses for these web servers?
We don't have to do that.
The instances don't need a public IP address to receive public requests.
They want them from the load balancer who knows the instance,
it's in that pool, it's in the VPC, the security groups are set up, we're all good.