In this clip we're going to take a look at interfaces and addressing, i.
e.
network interfaces on our instances.
So when I look at an instance, I can have a number of network interfaces,
this is how I'm going to communicate across either the public or
private network and when my system starts up,
I'll get a public and a private IP address,
so what kind of public and private IP address.
Well if I'm running in a VPC, then I can have a network interface.
It kind of makes sense doesn't it?
I'm on a network, I've got IP addresses,
I've got subnetting, so in the VPC I define the networking that I want.
Now the attributes of this NIC include a primary private IP version 4 address,
the default network interface is always an eth0 and that
can't be detached from the instance,
so there's a little bit of Amazon control for you,
but one or more secondary private IP addresses can be added.
These include a public IP version 4 address and one
or more IP version 6 addresses, and a MAC address.
So we've got some flexibility for additional NICs and how I
want my system to interface and communicate.
Now the network interfaces are going to inherit the
addressing from the subnet that you create or not,
meaning that if you don't pay attention to the VPC,
you'll have the default VPC with default IP addressing that's
where your addresses will be chosen from.
It almost goes without saying that public means public access from the
internet and private means you're on the private network.
So let's expand upon the private and public addresses.
So doing a comparison with the public IP address versus the private IP address,
first of all on the public side,
it's assigned from a pool of public IP addresses that Amazon
maintains and your system boots and depending on what you've
defined when you built your instance, the addresses are assigned during launch.
When your system turns off,
your system doesn't need that address so the address is now disassociated,
it's released back into the public pool.
You turn your system back on, you get another public IP address.
So if you think of a pool of web servers that's say auto-scaling,
2, 3, 4, 6, 8 servers, addresses get assigned,
systems aren't needed, addresses are taken back,
systems are turned off.
What about the private side?
The private address is the primary on the private network
based on the subnet that you're in, assigned to that default network interface,
we talked about the eth0.
On the public side, these addresses are not associated with your account,
what's that mean?
Well we'll talk about that in an upcoming slide.
On the private side, they're associated using an elastic network interface,
now the term that's interesting is the term elastic.
There's a little bit of scalability with that address that we'll explore.
On the public side, yeah it's accessible from the internet, we would think that.
On the private side, hey it's not routable through the internet,
it's on the private network, private means private.
On the public side,
use an elastic IP address if you want a persistent public IP address.
Ah-hah, so I can have an address if I want it always to be the same.
Why would I care?
Oh yeah, load balancer right?
So there'll be times when you might require an IP address to be
persistent and there will be times when you won't need that.
On the private side,
well communication with the other instances on the private network.
So address schemes, public and private.
Now let's go into the elastic concept, the elastic network interface.
So we've got two systems, an orange NIC hanging out with the system on the left,
if I want additional interfaces, well I create them.
I go into my account and say I'd like to create a new interface.
If I then detach that network interface,
assuming I'm allowed to, the first private one I can't,
others I can, so I detach it and I reattach it on a second system.
So the idea is that when a network interface moves from one instance,
say the instance on our left, to the other instance on the right,
the traffic will be redirected.
It doesn't know any better, it's going to that IP address,
to the new interface location.
So it's something that we can do for failover or control.
Along with the elastic network interface, we have elastic IP addresses.
So these are where the account comes in.
So the static IP version 4 address is linked to your account,
much like when we looked at IAM and setting up policy,
linked to our account.
So we allocate the address, once we request it,
to my account,
then it's up to me to decide where I'm going to associate that address.
Well the only place I can associate it is with a network interface.
Public IP version 4 addresses are elastic IP addresses,
reachable from the internet.
Now hiding the failure of an instance, yeah,
I can remap the address to another instance,
kind of cool.
Again, part of the toolbox for failover or DR.
When I have an elastic IP address that's not in use,
it remains in my account, I'll get charged for it,
until I delete it.
Once I delete it, I'm not being charged.
So elastic IP addresses, elastic network adapters,
giving us the ability for failover.
So a public IP address auto-assigned by AWS,
could that be considered more secure?
In some cases yes because if somebody is trying to hack me,
they won't be able to go back to that address.
By the same token,
why do I have a public IP address without protection in the first place?
So it might be kind of a redundant argument.
If it's just for a pool of web servers, let those addresses be assigned by AWS.
You don't need an elastic IP address in that case because you have a pool
of web servers and you have failover within that pool.
Alright let's move on to placement groups.
Now placement groups are instances that are logically grouped together within an
availability zone and I need a placement group or I want a placement group
because I want performance on the same 10 Gb network.
Why do I want this?
Well applications that need low network latency and
high throughput across the network.
So this might be obvious,
but you should choose an instance type that supports enhanced networking,
otherwise you won't get enhanced networking.
You could also choose single root I/O virtualization.
Now this gives you pretty enhanced networking,
pretty high performance on the instances that support this,
you're taking the load off the CPU.
And so it could be quite a handy feature,
of course the other aspect is the operating system of
the application has to support that, of course.
Again, a couple of additional scenarios as to ways I could group my instances together.