In this demo we'll take a look at security tools,
the tools that deal with the passwords,
and for that we're going to start with IAM.
So from the console under Security, Identity, & Compliance, let's pick IAM.
Now if you watched the last demo we ended up here and we can see
we've got the one administrative user and one group.
We can see the logon link, we're all go.
So IAM,
what we can do from the console is we can take a look at the credential report.
Now the credential report is created,
it's stored for up to 4 hours and I can download the report and
take a look at it by clicking this button,
having had a lot of log ons for this particular account,
it's going to save it as a csv,
let's see if there's anything in there that's of value.
And we can see that there is some information.
We can see that we did a log on, the last demo we logged on,
did the user create a password?
We can see all sorts of information.
So pretty handy report if you had a lot of users to look at the
status as to what's going on with the credentials.
Were you able to access?
Were you not able to access?
Did they change their password?
What was the date?
What was the time?
What else can we do here?
Well we have the credential report.
If I select a user, I've only got one user,
but in a way it makes it nice and simple to look at this interface,
and under Admin we can go to Access Advisor.
Access Advisor will give me some advise as to what can this user do,
and now that the user has logged on,
you may remember in the last demo there was nothing here,
now because my credentials have been applied through the
group I guess I can do a few things because I have
administrative rights and networking rights.
Now what did I access?
It doesn't look like I've done anything, that would be true.
So from the IAM console we can get a credential report and
we can deal with the access advisor.
We can also look at CloudTrail, so let's go over to CloudTrail.
CloudTrail is going to leave a trail of access and it says
well you've just setup this account, it hasn't started yet.
I probably should turn this on, so let's click Get Started.
I can have one trail for free and so what shall our trail name?
The wiredTrail.
All regions?
Sure.
Create a bucket?
What about wiredtracker?
So there won't be a lot going on because I've just turned on this trail,
something that we certainly should do for our account.
So let's go over and look at the other account.
This account has been running for a number of years,
so we can see that there's a whole bunch of information on API activity.
You can see there's lots of stuff going on.
Again, if you have followed all the demos,
you can see that I switched roles, I exited roles,
I did certain things with this account and so everything is being tracked.
So CloudTrail can be very handy.
So let's go into CloudWatch.
Well with CloudWatch we can set up some rules.
So clicking rules we can create a rule and say,
well I would like to find out when somebody logs in.
It is any user or is it a particular user?
Is there somebody I want to identify by the resource name?
For now I can leave it as any user and then I can select the target.
So selecting add target, well there's a few targets.
I could send it to a lambda function, that's automation,
so I write that automation saying if this happens carryout a task.
I can also get notified and then from the dropdown list I can pick a topic.
Maybe I'm tracking my sales team, so I could say sales configure my details,
give it a name, we'll call it consolecheck,
and create the rule.
Success.
We now have a console check.
Many different possibilities of tracking what's happening with
authentication and security of my IAM users.
But wait a minute, what's the console check going to do in its current state?
Let's go into consolecheck, let's check the SNS topic and see what's been set up.
That's my notification.
I have to create a subscription in order to actually get that information,
so I could then say although what do I want,
oh yes you could send me an email.
I could set up the other aspect of where that information is going to be
sent and you can see that there's a variety of options,
even text.
So let's set it up.
I'm subscribed.
Alright we're all set up now. So that's a look at security tools for AWS.