Hello and welcome back to a course on database's today we're going to install Microsoft as school server
for a windows.
So let's get started with this.
Now the first thing we're going to need is a browser.
So there we go.
Chrome is my browser and I'm going to look for apps skills or if you let it load here you'll see a couple
of links.
The one you need is actually this one.
So where in your cell you've got a scale server Eskdale server 2016 or at the time when you're watching
it might be a bit over a later version.
But you can go ahead and install that one.
So basically the latest version should be fine if you have the option to install 2016.
Then you can also do that too far along with the tutorials exactly exactly the same things.
But there's no big difference usually between the new versions as always good to know the new version
as well.
So once you're on this page it might change with time as well.
But just look for the downloads section.
And then when you go to the download section what you are ultimately after is the Express Edition of
Escal server so you have the free trial evaluation which is one hundred and eighty day free trial of
the full scale server.
You've got the developer edition we've got the Express Edition.
So for this course all we need is Express Edition.
It's free and you won't have all those unnecessary elements of the server that you actually don't need
in this class so go ahead and find the Express Edition of Asgill server.
Right now the latest one is Eskdale server 20:16 Service Pack 1.
So click download 1 download now and it's over there.
Actually dollars pretty quickly.
Go ahead and launch that.
There it is.
Yes.
And let's see.
So sex insulation type basic insulation is what we actually need is sufficient for us.
Read through the terms.
If you accept the terms click accept and select an installation path.
It will tell you how much space you need and it's actually going to download the files right now.
So that was just the installation starter and I are going to prepare the installation and go ahead and
install it so you can see the files have been downloaded.
So I'm just actually going to pause this recording and resume it when we're closer to the end of the
download so we don't have to wait.
All right so we're near the end of the download.
And Don successfulness installing.
So an important thing I wanted to mention is that for as Phil sort of 2016 you actually need Windows
8 minimum.
So if you have Windows 7 or below then you won't be able to install it.
So make sure you have Windows 8 or Windows 10 on your computer before you proceed with this installation.
And yeah that's a prerequisite and you can check those in the descriptions of SQL Server or it will
just not let you proceed with installation after a certain point if you don't have the right windows.
So that's something just to keep in mind.
All right.
So let's again pause the video until this installation process is actually complete.
All right so the installation is progressing.
And here we've got a solution as completed successfully.
So here's got some pausa ways which you can specify.
I prefer to leave them as default and that way I'll know that it's all set up correctly if you want
to change anything and then feel free to explore this further but I'm just going to Kleek leave it as
it is close and show an exit.
Yes.
And at this point you need to restart your computer for that installation to complete successfully so
I'm going to go ahead a resawing computer and then we'll continue with this video.
All right welcome back.
The computer has been restarted.
And now what we've really installed is Microsoft as kill server and in order to interact with Microsoft
Haskel So we're going to need to install a.
All right.
Welcome back.
So the computer has been restarted and therefore the installation of Microsoft SQL Server is complete.
But that is not the end for us.
For but that is not the end of our installation process because in order to interact with the database
that we have just installed we need a studio a way a program that will allow us to manipulate databases
and program and do exactly what we need to do in these tutorials and this situation is similar to what
we have with postgresql also we have postgresql which is a database engine itself.
And then you've got PGE admin which is the visual interface which allows you to interact with postgresql.
Same thing here we've installed Microsoft a SQL Server.
Now we want to install Microsoft Eskew all server management studio which will allow us to interact
with Microsoft SQL Server.
So let's go ahead and solve that.
We're going to go to the browser and we're going to search for M-S as KJo server.
There it is Massman studio.
And here just scroll down and find a link that looks like this is the end of March of that column and
here you'll find Esky also reminds miss shooter as the sims.
Also there is an option during the installation process of asking a server at the very end we could
have selected historicism as you can feel free to do that.
If you still have that window up or you can just download it from here install it.
It's exactly the same thing.
You'll get the same result so here we're going to install the current release of SDL sermons MS studio
so go ahead and just click the installation download.
It's about this one is about 900 megabytes is going to take a few minutes to download and we'll resume
the video when it's when the Delonas finished.
All right so a download is complete.
Let's go ahead and run this.
All right.
Microsoft as kill server management studio install Yes.
And let's give it a second actually is going to take more than a second.
So once again let's resume the video once there's some progress.
All right so any solution has been completed and now we're done so we can just close here.
Well so now we can go and launch Microsoft ask you all server management studio.
So let's have a look at what this looks like.
This is the task bar and here just type in something like Microsoft or even better as well.
There you go so as Kjellstrom as with studio
so you can actually what you can do is pin to taskbar what I normally do.
And that way it's always here.
So just click on it.
All right so now let's launch a scale Server Management Studio and a second.
There it is.
So everything is set up.
Just click connect here and voila everything is working.
So the set up is complete.
And in the next story we will learn how to start working inside Microsoft Asgill server code wait to
see you next.
Until then happy analyzing.