Hello and welcome back.
Today we have a very important topic to cover and I'm very excited about it and it's important we do
a bit of practice and skill to learn and understand if you still haven't.
Today's topic Well it's the end clause and or cloth as well.
The next logical step to improve your search results after specifying which data are you looking at
and where it's located and what specific condition it has to satisfy you need to put more and more specific
conditions.
Narrowing your results to only the most relevant.
This is where OR and AND clauses come to play.
Let's return to our example from previous lecture where we have to find a product from New York and
they issued has now let's say you want to also find older products from California and there are issues
now instead of running two separate similar inquiries you can run one query using simple or clause.
So to begin with.
Again let's open up the database make sure we have the table up and running it has 18 columns.
Now let's select to create the query to open a new window.
First we'll select the company name and the product name and the issues having inside that company name
just to get a bit of the Versteeg results.
Then we specify that we selected from consumer complaints and finally we say where state name equals
New York.
So as you remember this is the clause we had previously and as you can see I've made a bit of mistake
here because the company just goes like that and as you can see it returns Soss all the data we expect
to return to us.
So now as already mentioned if we want to display all the company's products and the issue does Farthing's
have from say New York and state of California we can run two similar rockeries and here we'll just
have to replace this with CA for California and that will return TAWS all of the company's products
and issues from state California.
Now instead of doing that what we can do is we can live this as it is and then just at the end of it.
Or and just copy the state name equals and then just put it in any state want.
In our case it's New York.
Now if you run it we should see that we have more results because now is displaying pretty much twice
as many results just to prove that it works.
Let's make sure that we display the state names as well.
And now when we run it we will see that all the state names will be either New York or California.
We should not get any other states here.
And as you can see there we go.
It all works right and correct.
OK.
Awesome.
Now let's take a look at the example of using and statement before we do toddlers quickly go and create
new query and so for example we need to display all the product and the companies that produce these
products were consumers who submitted the complaint were service members and they received the timely
response.
So at the first look this looks a bit tricky because we don't exactly understand where the service member
value come from and if we dig around in the table we will find out that the tags column consists of
such values as older Americans or service number.
So that's exactly what we need.
So now if we go ahead and think of all the key elements we need in order to complete this Querrey is
obviously tags to identify where they are the consumer who submitted the complaint to a service member
or not.
That is the timely response to identify whether it was a time to respond or not.
And of course product name and company.
So let's begin to write the query by putting and select statement.
Then we put in product name company that was specified that we take it from consumer complaints and
then we go to where.
And here we put in tags and you already know we just put in service member right here and then we just
specify that it has to be a time to respond.
And then we just put it like this.
So now let's run it and see what we get.
As you can see we've got three thousand two hundred seventy rows worth of data.
So that is why a lot not going to show you how the square works let's go here and put tags and time
response into the select statement.
So it displays everything for us and we can take a better look at it.
So you can see the time loose Boylan's has to be yes and it will be on all of these rows that tags has
to say service member and all of them well and then company and product name will be different depending
on the company.
And product name of course.
So the difference between and and or is that and it has to be.
So tags have to be service member time response also has to be yes.
Whereas if we vote or in the same statement and run it now we will get way more results because now
is basically two queries running at the same time and there is less exclusion of data happening.
We're including more data so including all the service member has admitted complaints even the ones
that did not receive a timely response.
And we also include all the complaints submitted by anyone where the time the response was yes.
So as you can see we get back and rose which is quite a lot because it's only about a thousand of the
complete set of rows here.
So as you can see in this case the tags can say even older American or nothing and the time response
can say no as well as long as there is a service member in the tag's condition.
So I hope you understand and and or sent this a bit better.
I mean it's nothing hard to get around but it is very useful because it's very simple conditions that
are used on many levels and you will encounter a lot for all the scores.
And actually when are you going to be programming in real life.
But before we're going up just a quick reminder that it does not matter which order you put these tags
in.
The only thing is it's personal preference.
Or maybe if you have a very big database to work with it's better to put in the smaller value first
so the programme runs quicker and then the bigger values are less number of them.
So the computer can analyze them in less amount of time.
Other than that it really has nothing to do.
Also I again like to put tags and time your response into this select condition all the time just because
it makes a bit more sense to show that and data form to the customers or clients or the people you're
working with because otherwise you just get these two columns and you have to write down to conditions
and a bit of background on what of what information this table provides you with which can be messy
at times.
But yeah I feel like of card and and or statements quite well.
They're very simple to understand but are very powerful tools if used correctly.
I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.