Hello and welcome back.
And today we'll be working with data type conversion so data type conversion are pretty rare to encounter
in a school because most of the time you would rather just drop the table and create a new one.
Or again important data with already the correct data.
The one that you need to.
But sometimes it is beneficial or it is more efficient to convert the data and work over it.
Inside the same table.
So the main reason for converting data in a column is to be able to work with different types of functions
for example including string functions or different sorting tools that cannot work with data for example
or with integers or reflowed numbers.
And another reason is to save space.
So some data types are stored more efficiently than others and it might be better to store word type
as integer if it only includes the column only consist of whole numbers rather than words.
And the last thing is just to change completely the column and the reasoning behind it.
And we'll take a look at this.
During today's lecture.
So let's go ahead and dive straight into it.
Today we'll be working with console games table.
So let's open our querido and quickly run it.
So what we want to do is want to say select all from the console games.
This will quickly just refresh our memory of what we have in this table.
We should have 12 columns all filled with data.
And that is indeed correct.
So as we can see right now it's all here.
Let's just quickly say I don't like this.
Ordered by game rank just to make it to be Nener and the first thing you see is specially coming from
previous lectures where we worked with console dates.
Is that game year in this table is stored as integer.
So it's basically a whole number and they consist of four numbers.
So 2006 1 9 8 5.
It's basically four separate numbers all the data type in that year.
And what we want to do is let's say that we want to change this data types I want to say that game year
will now be workhorse so we can work with it more efficiently if we need to.
So what we have to do is we need to say select cast and then year as Archer and in our case because
we only need four numbers for elements we can specify here in order to make our database work week.
So it does not allocate that much memory that much space to this column.
It only allocates the appropriate amount.
So I'll go and run this as it said just change the year to be Game year.
So that database works.
And now as you can see you have game year of type character.
Brian hold in mind that this will only be done for the duration of this query so follow the not of one
game year will return back to integer.
And if you want to change the column data type forever for prolonged periods of time that will be discussed
further down in the course.
We're actually going to be creating our own tables because you have to go through alter functions and
so on.
Here we're just showing in the quake function cost uses of cost function.
Now instead of writing this which can be a bit hectic what we can do sort of a shortcut is that we can
write a game here the column that we want to change.
Then we can put two of the samples.
And after that we can't say which data type one.
So in our case that scan weren't sure and we wanted to be only of four numbers.
So as you can see I just make a small mistake here and manage to work perfectly.
They can say again everything works perfect.
Everything works fine.
Now for a last example what we want to do is let's change Ghaemi year to be of an actual date type instead
of just war chart.
So another to us what do we need to do is we need to go ahead and say select and then when you have
these to date so you can't change two words or you can change to a lot of data types.
But in our case we want to change to date.
They don't want to put in cost and then when we go year as worker and then we want to put that restriction
that can only have four symbols inside of it and then one and just put here and just put this.
So they can see we have a column to date and a time date and it has Oldaker years.
But because we did not have months and days inside the table there's no way to get this information
from for as well.
It just puts first of January by default.
So if you want to fill these up with correct dates you can just later on to work with the SCV file see
file other database where you're going to be getting these files from and just set that to date.
Equals to wherever the data is located.
So converting data types is again pretty rarely used to in sequel and that's why this tutorial is so
short because most of the time you'll just convert integer to word char or vice versa.
So that's just the cost function.
So I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.