Hello and welcome back.
And today we'll have a very important Tauriel.
We will be working with nuns so nulls are classified as cells that have no data in them and they're
automatically filled with no value.
So I ask you all has a way to deal with them and you can operate with these cells with different functions
and statements.
So in this lecture today we will discuss how to find nulls in tables and how to deal with knowledge
from a data management point of view.
So first thing first let's go ahead and run our inquiry.
We're going to be working with console games table so all these years go ahead.
Select all from console games.
And now when we run this we will get our 12 columns all filled with data but some rows some tipples
will be missing some information in them and that's exactly what we'll be dealing with today.
Let's quickly go ahead and as you can see it will be quite hard to scan for all of these rows to find
empty.
Data.
So let's put a WHERE condition in order to narrow our results.
Now we want to say that the game name has to be
and if we're either Now as you can say or 10 results to us and these rows have all other data except
gamelike maybe the data get corrupted.
Maybe people who put them in put to them incorrectly or maybe they just forgot to do it altogether.
Things like this happen and it's very important to manage your database efficiently correctly so that
when you find those defined them as soon as possible and to correct them as soon as possible.
So you're probably wondering why we're not using equal sign because now is not equal to anything.
So now is not even equal to another now.
So we have to say that it is all rather equal.
So it's like now but not now.
And so the first thing the first method of dealing with now is when you find them in your database is
to completely delete distros and you might say well that's what's the point of that.
Well the point of that is if you have an extremely big database and it's not valuable what's inside
the Tarot.
So basically you have this database to manage averages maximum minimums so more you work more with aggregate
functions and predicting data and you have so much data that deleting a couple of rows will not affect
it.
That's a good way to deal with it to avoid mistakes and actual miscalculations inside the algorithms.
But of course this is like your last go to method.
The second one is to try and figure out what game it is.
So as you can see here we have the platform we have the game year and we have the younger.
And we also have the publisher
wait to check if you can find these games or not in our table.
We have all the games released.
So it's a very easy way to check how many games were released this year and how many games were released
by this publisher on this platform.
So we quickly go around this and say that and platform
sorry Game year and platform has to be equal G-B and genre.
Has to be equal roleplaying
we will find out that there is only
Sergius made a mistake here.
So if we're on this now we'll find that there is only two games that were released this year in this
genre or one just by far if we include publisher we can finish the search even down and get only one
is all back.
So all we need to do now is go to our initial research into the topic where we got the initial data
from and just pinpointed from there or we can ask our colleagues to do that.
And it's not a big deal.
So if you have sufficient data to find your missing data it's all good just You'll have to waste a bit
of time but it's all worth it in then.
So in all this take a look at another example.
So what we want to do is warn us like it all again from console games and then we want to say where
and this time we will say Japanese sales is no.
So let's see for me this will return.
As you can see it only returns 1.
So that's good.
But this one does not have Japanese sales and global sales and sales percentage because it just can't
calculate it as well as it cannot calculate global sales.
So how do we deal with this.
We can go online and try to find this information.
But let's say this information was lost or deleted or archived and it's not accessible anymore.
So and under way you can work with missing data especially when you're working with numeric values.
You can take an average.
So we know that a lot of games were released in 2005 but even less games were released for platform
D.S. and less games were released for publisher of Nintendo and even less games were released with specific
genres.
So we can go ahead search for that and then take the average of Japanese sales for those games and put
it in.
But the problem here is that the amount of games that were released for all of these parameters might
be so small that it will give us wrong average.
So in this scenario we have two choices when it comes to working with either rose from this table is
either we go by Game year 2005 and we get hundreds of different rolls of data and we get a very generic
result that actually might not be true at all for this particular row or we can narrow the data down
to a very small number of rows and that will not work either because just the data will be insufficient.
So what we can do here in this particular database in this particular example is because we have and
they sales use sales and other sales and all of them seem to be responding with chatter.
So 5 million for NH sales 2 million for the sales and 9 million for you sales.
It makes sense that Japanee sales will be somewhere on their level.
So what we want to do here is we want to take the average of these free and put it in Japanese sales.
I know it sounds crazy but in this particular example it actually will work because the numbers for
these free columns and numeric columns are so similar to each other.
So in order to get us what we want to do is again we want to work with update because we want this change
to be consistent.
We want this to remain in the table after we are done with it.
So we want to update console games and then I want to say we setting Japanese sales to be and then were
going rounding it up.
We're rounding the number up in case because adding this all up and dividing by tree might give us a
better long number.
So we want to just drugged up so it looks nice and neat.
And then when I say that we are adding sales with EU sales we have sales.
And then we divide by free.
And now if we do this we can actually mess up our whole database because it will basically replace Japanese
cells in all of the games with an average of these free columns.
And that is absolutely incorrect.
So what we want to do is we want to say where and then we put game name and then we put equals and then
we write the name of this game.
So it makes no mistake
so we just putting in the name of this game to make sure that we update only this row and outer.
So now if we run this it should actually work.
So always go ahead and run it as you can see it updated one.
And that's exactly what we were looking for.
So now let's go.
Let's actually leave the WHERE condition and we just want to say that we select all from console games.
And always run it.
Sorry about that console games.
And now we should have Japanese sales.
And as you can see it drawn it up to even integer hole number and that's good.
So now if you take a look at this row it makes sense because for 75 9:26 and to 0 5 it makes some of
the Japanese cells will be somewhere between four and six.
And that's how we work with Nelse.
Again there's three ways of working with them to delete the row delete the data.
Get rid of it.
Second way is to identify exactly what you're missing.
Narrowed down the search results so you can do extensive research and find that correct data and put
it in or you can take an average you can combine data in the table or in that specific row or in that
specific column and put it in.
And this concludes our whole section of working with data.
We work with the data types.
Words are integers floats.
We work with nulls.
We updated databases we work with sorting tools order by and we've done a lot in the section and I hope
you're very excited about what we did.
And Propp and proud of the fact that we actually managed to do it.
And third section in the chords become a bit more complicated step by step but they teach you more and
more useful skills that you will be able to apply in your real world work or life to sort real world
problems.
And that's the best thing about it.
I'm very excited to see in the next section and I hope I see you there.