Hello and welcome back to the course on databases in the previous tutorial we learned how to create
a very first live join and today we're going to talk about some tips and tricks for joins yes.
Already we're going to talk about that because it will help us streamline and expedite our learning
going forward.
It will really add value to what we're going to be learning throughout the rest of this section so it
is I think is a good idea to uncover some tips and tricks now.
OK.
So that's a new part to this code so maybe at the top of this previous part we're going to say that
we spoke about a left join now we're going to change this up a bit and we're going to talk about tips
and tricks.
And actually we're going to talk about.
All right Joy.
So first tip first tip is that as you can see here we've got quite a lot of the time we have to repeat
pets and owners pets and owners and so on.
And as you Joines become more involved to become more complex and that means and what you might have
more tables you might be specifying more columns you might have some conditions and so on.
So in fact let's just go ahead and do that.
Let's let's just rerun this query right.
And so we've got the pets and George and so let's say we want to let's say we want to find out which
of our pets and owners have the first letter of the same first.
There's a saying somewhere left pets were left name or pets taught name one equals left of owners.
Name one meaning one letter.
That's all we want if we run that you will see that here we've got eight rows total we've got Biskit
and Bessie Lily and Louisa cook and Carolyn Daisy and Dorothy Tiger and Tom Cook and Charles danger
and Dan Bruce.
Bruce actually one pet had the same name as the owner.
Very interesting.
So what we can see is that now we've even made it even more complex.
We've got a WHERE clause and again we have to specify pets and owners so we have to specify the data
or the table name every single time we refer to call them.
And as you can imagine that can get quite convoluted as your join grows and trust me your choices will
grow as you perform them more and more in your career.
And so there's a quick trick here that you can use to make things easier.
Are you still going to have to specify which data.
Which table this column is coming from there's no way around that but you can make a life easier by
reducing the amount of letters you need to type every time.
So what are we going to do here is we're going to say as a and here is as be so jarring this joint part
where you're saying from which table lift table as left table left join right table you're actually
specifying what you want to call them you creating aliases these are aliases for the tables.
So you're creating an alias.
An alias.
And now everywhere instead of Petz you can say a.
Let's fix that and everywhere instead of owners you can say B B B and B.
And as you see that reduces the amount of code you have to type and makes things easier.
So if I run this you'll see we get the same result eight Aitraaz selected.
It's just a little bit easier to type.
And whenever you're not really sure what B means and what it means you just look back at this part of
the code and you'll see very quickly.
So there we go.
That's that's part one that's tip number one tip number two.
So let's go ahead and copy that.
So here I'm actually just going to comment that when I say alias's for tables and here we're going to
say alias's all this is the tip.
Number two I'm doing it every four columns so you can also create the same way aliases for called and
this can be handy when I look at your data.
So if you look here you'll see that you've got name and name and unless if we didn't know the dataset
we wouldn't be able to tell which one came from which table which one is the only name which one has
the pet name and that's why here we can say selects a duck name and then we'll say as.
And we will specify that he is the pet name and he'll say as owner name.
So if you run this now because we can see that table A's pets will be owners and that's why they're
in that order if you're on that you'll see that the names of the table columns have changed.
Now pet name and owner's name and that can be handy when you are running these select statements.
So there's another quick tip for you that you can take away.
In fact skills quite advanced and to save even more time you can just avoid typing in this as here so
you can just get rid of that and you can just say a and b and it'll still work.
So far on that you see that everything works totally fine.
And same thing here you can get rid of that get rid of that and run that and you'll see that everything
works fine.
So in you well you don't have to type in the as you can just say a dog name pet name breed name or name
and will understand what you mean.
But personally I don't take it that far I prefer not to.
I prefer to keep that as just so that you know other people read my code don't have to think about it
and understand what's going on.
So I recommend leaving as two totally kind of mood if you like.
And finally to finish off the day we're going to talk about the right join.
So right join here.
And why are we not spending a whole separate tutorial on the ride.
Well because a right join is identical to the left join in just that the tables are switched around.
Then let's have a look at that right now.
So to take this.
We're here.
This query from here and place it here.
Let's get rid of the WHERE clause see if I run this.
This is a left join and there's a result.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to switch this to a right join but I'm also going to switch to
tables or on the ground take pets and put it here.
We're going to take owners and put it here.
Now one thing that you do need to remember is that that is insufficient.
You also need to switch to alias's if you are using aliases because pets used to be a and now everywhere
here you see a dog name is pet name.
And now it's going to be incorrect so we have to change this to a and this to be a quicker way to do
this would have been if when you switch around the tables if you just take pets as a put it here owners
as B and put it here.
And that's the correct way of doing it.
So now you've got pets keeps its own alias and then you don't have to worry about the rest because you're
probably not going to be doing that much in your career switching a 11.0 right join.
But if you do happen to need to do that just remember about aliases.
So now I'm going to write join and I've moved the tables around but if I run this I'll get exactly the
same result as I have here.
Say again 100 rows exactly the same result because indeed the left left join and the right join are
identical is just the tables are basic which aren't.
And that's why we're not spending so much time on the right join because you can always replace a writes
join with a left join if you just switch around the tables.
That's why you'll find that joins are way more common.
It's just because the way we're used to reading code and reading text from left to right and that's
why we're kind of used to having the primary table on the left.
Having said that situations when the right joint might come up in are or include situations where there's
like the join is so complex there so many different tables that you're joining at as many different
Joines going on that is just more code efficient and more ergonomic to put her right joining me.
Imagine like you've got a lot of text here and then you've got a lot of text here already and you need
to join those two tables and you just put a right join in between them instead of like trying to switch
it around and wasting time on that.
So that's one of the stations which you might encounter I join but those are quite rare.
And now because we had this little quick example you really know how to deal with.
I'd join as well.
So there we go.
That concludes our tutorial for today.
I hope you enjoyed these quick tips and tricks so we had three.
One was alias has four tables to save you time.
The next one was alias's for Calment columns to make the select statement more user friendly.
And finally we've got the right join which is in fact the same thing as a Left-Right homepage this Tauriel
and I look forward to see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.