Hello and welcome back to the course on databases now that we've talked about lots of different types
of joins today we're going to take a step further and we're going to talk about joining in multiple
fields.
So the two tables we're going to be working with this time are the procedures history table and the
procedures Details table so let's go ahead and look inside these two and see what we're going to be
joining soapstar from procedure's history and detail.
So if we look in the history table you'll see that we've got information on which pets had which procedures.
But this table doesn't provide the full picture right so we cannot tell the pets name the information
about the pets and we can't tell the information about the owner of the pet.
We only have the pet I.D. and that's fair enough because this is a good way of structuring databases.
We've got the pet information in its own table with the owner's information in its own table.
We can join to the pets table through the foreign key here pet I.D. and we can also then join onto the
owners table through the owner ID field in there.
So that's totally fine.
But then on the other hand on the right here we also don't have the full picture of the procedure.
We have the procedure type in the sub code but we don't actually know the name of the procedure and
then other information about the procedure.
And why is that.
Well because that information is also stored in a different table in the procedures details table.
So if you run this you'll see that here you've got the procedure type procedure sub code and you've
got the description.
So back in the history table for instance we had vaccinations right.
So we had vaccinations number five but we don't know what kind of mix of nations these are because pets
can have lots of different types of vaccinations.
They can have rabies vaccinations they can have Lyme disease vaccination and all.
Lots of other types of vaccinations.
Whereas if we now look in the procedures Details table and we look at vaccinations you'll see vaccination
number five is indeed rabies.
And here you even have you don't have just the description.
You also have the price.
So our task for today is going to be to join the two tables so that we have the history of the of not
just vaccinations but of all the procedures and then on the right we have information additional information
about that procedure.
So the description and the price we want to add that information into this resulting table.
Now my challenge for you is to actually pause this video an attempt to perform this on your own.
And why is that.
Well because we've already discussed joins in quite a lot of detail and hopefully by now you're quite
comfortable with the concept of Joines at the end at the same time.
We've already talked about joining on multiple fields in the theoretical tutorials for this section.
So if you combine the knowledge from those two you have quite a good chance of making an attempt at
performing this Join this is going to be quite a sophisticated joint but you have a good chance of performing
it on your own and then comparing to the video.
So give that a try and if you don't succeed then don't worry because you can always just continue playing
the video and compare what you got to what I will be demonstrating in this video.
All right.
So if you'd like to attempt the challenge and post a video now.
Otherwise I'm going to proceed and demonstrate how I would solve this challenge.
So three to one here we go.
We're going to just keep this part of the procedures history and then we're going to say left and join.
So why is it a left join this artifact.
Well it's a live joint because we definitely want to keep all the information we have in this table
in the procedures history table we want to keep everything and we just want to add to it.
We want to add additional information to it on the right.
And so I love joe and it's very similar to a view look up in Excel if you used to them so whenever you
just want to add information to an existing table that's the Left Join the only kind of difference between
live joy and no major difference between a live joint and a real hookup is that if the table you are
looking into.
So we're going to be joining to the procedure Details table if for some reason one of these rules and
say this row gets matched to two of them.
Then what'll happen here is this roll will be duplicated and we've spoken about that several times that
duplication of rows occurs to match the number of matching rows in the second table.
So that's something you don't see in Excel you just get get a result but that would happen.
So basically whenever you're just adding information you should think of it as a left join.
So there we go we select from procedures history all have different procedures details and what field
we're going to be joining on.
So this is the tricky part.
This is the interesting part because this is basically what we are going to be discussing in this tutorial.
But let's give it a shot.
Let's say out of these fields we decide the procedure sub code looks like a unique identifier of the
procedure and therefore we're going to join on the procedure.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I would say as a as B I would say a dot procedure sub code woe to my knee.
Go equals the same thing.
And now before you're on this join what I wanted to bring to attention is that how many rows are we
going.
Or do we expect to have in the files.
And this is a good way of thinking about choice.
It's kind of like preparing for them and always being on top of your game.
So basically right now we have two thousand two hundred and eighty four rows you can see here on the
right at the bottom.
And that is in our just in this top table in the procedures history time.
Now that's basically what we're trying to do is we want to add information to this table we just want
to add additional the table so additional columns is table so the number of rows shouldn't change.
So let's go ahead and run this and join in let's see how many rows rows will get.
Once we're on the join you'll see that we have 8000 179 rows.
Right so the number of rows increased drastically.
And why does that.
Why does that happen.
Why did the number of rows increase so much.
Well the reason for that is that in our left table when we were joining.
Right.
Sometimes the value of the rows matched up several times.
So for instance this row pet ID 5 4 3 5 9 procedure date the 5th of February 2016 vaccinations procedure
sub code as you can see it's repeated many many times here so of all the way up to here so though these
rows got duplicated and this is something we talked about that rosea a duplicate when they match up
to several in the second table.
And here you can see it matched up to vaccinations.
Number five orthopedic number five general surgery is number five vaccinations number.
Oh actually sorry it did.
It only got repeated three times so there you go.
So this robot repeated three times and you got matched up to three rows here.
So vaccinations them are five orthopedic number five general surgery number five.
Right.
And then a similar thing happened here.
This robot matched to three different ones.
And why is that.
Well that is because we were matching on the procedure because you can see that the procedure code here
and here is the same here and here is the same here and here is the same.
And that is because in the second table on the right there were three rows of procedure sub code five
and so it did everything correct.
It's so that there's three matching rows so it made copies of this row two so that each of the matching
rows would have a would be connected to two linked to some row in the first table and that's exactly
how it was supposed to do it don't.
The issue here is that procedure some code is not a unique identifier of the type of procedure or of
the true of the procedure itself.
So basically there are procedures some code is a sub code for the procedure type.
So within vaccinations there are several.
So let's go have a look at the procedure Details table that will give us a better picture.
So if we go select
store from procedure details you'll see here that for instance vaccinations has six different sub codes
that hospitalization has one orthopedic has seven sub codes so sub codes they actually repeat again
and again as the big actually has nine general surgery has even more.
So there's lots of different there's some they repeat across different procedure types.
So therefore our unique identifier is not just procedure sub code on its own.
It's actually the combination of vaccination of a procedure type and procedure or subclass that.
So in this if we use these two together as them joining condition then you'll see that this out of these
three only the first row will be a correct join this wouldn't have happened this wouldn't have happened.
Same thing here.
And so on.
So this is a great example of when there's an aha there's a hierarchy so procedure type is you know
the first level higher than a sub code is the next level hierarchy in that the procedure identifier
and you need to use both of them when you join.
So that's exactly what we're going to do.
We're going to say on procedure sub code and a Daut procedure type you close the door at procedure type
Sinaloan for on this you'll see that resulting table has 2284 rows as we expected.
And everywhere there's only been one match so this this row got matched to this row.
And then this Droguet match to this row and so on.
So this is exactly what you wanted the result that we were looking for.
I don't think that I would change about this.
Join is now I would just actually put them all the way around and say Take this and put it above.
Why.
Well it's just an is the anaesthetic thing.
You don't have to do that.
But I like hierarchy's to be ordered correctly so procedure type is you know the first level so it comes
above then procedure Sopko but that's just just the way you like way to structure code you don't really
have to do that you can leave it the way it was.
And now when you run this of course same result and you can see that once again we can get all the information
here what the procedure so you can get the description you can get the price for every single procedure
that was performed.
So there we go that's how we join two tables on multiple fields the same rules apply for lift joins
in or joins right joins outer joins.
It's always the same you just simply just keep specifying the number additional conditions for joins
through these and statements.
So I hope we enjoyed this Tauriel and I'll see you next time.
Until then I'll be analyzing.