Hello and welcome back to the course on databases now that we've got our table uploaded here it is transactions
we can go here and start normalizing it and see what will come up in the process.
So let's get started with the first step which is going to click anywhere here and search query tool
and we're going to write a very very simple query and just say selects are from transactions just so
we can see what we have inside this table.
Now let's quickly just the columns we're doing this so that we can see the full name of the column and
also we can see some of the sample data in full just so that we understand better what's going on.
So here is we've got shipping state item item let's give it some more space.
All right so what is our very first step in the process of normalization.
Well the very first step that we need to perform is we need to check if this table is in first normal
form.
Right.
In order to do that let's go ahead and just first of all get acquainted with these columns and see what's
going on.
So here we've got the transaction ID.
It's a unique identifier for every single row.
And the way these columns normally work in databases is the database is already set up for this to be
the primary key.
And as you know as you just add new columns this is a bit different because we uploaded this file from
osseous from Assissi right.
We uploaded this there from US-Israel river.
But when it's in an actual online transaction processing database or some other kind of database what
happens is as new records come into this table this idea is just increased by one every single time.
And so this is like an incremental idea and that guarantees that it is going to be unique and you can
see that this is exactly the case which was happening here.
So you can see this is the newest transaction and then they're falling off in descending order.
So these are later transactions that happened earlier on.
And as you can see the idea was also smaller so the idea was increasing as the transactions were coming
in then.
So that's how timestamped and it's in seconds.
So it's up to the second.
And then you've got the customer ID that I identify a number of the customers got the customer first
name surname the shipping state.
So basically this is the state of the customer where they live.
So that's where the item is to be shipped the item that they purchased.
So this is their item code then the description of the items are pillowcase mints pajama's sheets coat
blanket and so on.
And the retail price of that item and the loyalty discount that was applied to that purchase as we can
assume because it has the word loyalty that means it's related to the customer.
Right.
So customers who have been shopping for longer will have a higher loyalty discount or there's some sort
of correlation and maybe some customers that purchased have purchased more in their history.
So there we go those are our homes and the first thing we need to do is check now if the tables in personal
form and so if we remember all mnemonic which talks about the key.
So basically every attribute every non prime attribute should tell a should say a fact about the key
the whole key and only add nothing but the key.
And so basically the first part is that there is a key and what that tells us if we remember from the
theory part is that there cannot be any duplicate rows.
That's number one and number two which is a bit unrelated to the mnemonic is that we cannot have any
We cannot have cells with more than one value in them right.
So let's go ahead and go through the stable like we just look through it and just try to understand
if it's possible that they are unusual.
It's possible that any of those conditions is not met.
So here you can see that this is indeed every single time unique.
So by definition they cannot be any duplicate rows in this table.
And also you can see that by the looks of it every single cell has a atomic value.
Those values are called Atomic.
So it's a very controversial term Tolmach you can read a bit more about it online.
Some people prefer choosing some people prefer not to use it is hard to say if it's it's a good term
to use.
But basically what it implies is that every single cell has indeed a single value.
Sort of like comma separated or somehow otherwise separated values that should be in different rows.
So as you can see it looks like both conditions are met here.
I'm just going to show you another way to 100 percent verify that there is no duplicate rows.
So what are you going to do is we're going to say select count
star from transactions you run that he'll tell you how many zeros.
Three hundred three thousand fifty five.
So just put a comment and say three thousand four fifty five.
And now do the same thing.
But this time instead of just saying Slick's can start from transactions.
We're going to replace transactions with a subquery and I'll explain this in a second so just follow
along and type in this code.
So here we replace transactions with two brackets for null and opening and closing bracket.
And inside we're going to say select store or select distinct star from Trend actions.
And so if you run just these two lines by themselves what this will do this distinct word it it modifies
this query to only select the unique rows from this table.
So by running this query that you're guaranteed that there are no duplicates in this table anymore.
And now what we're doing is on top of that.
So on this table that we've got as a result now we're applying this select count from the subquery.
The only thing is here we have to say as a team or something that's so tempy distinct doesn't matter
what name you give it you can just say a something.
So let's say ABC.
So if you run this now it will count the number of rows in this table which only has two distinct rows
and therefore it will count two distinct rows in the whole table.
There we go 300 three thousand four hundred and fifty five.
So we have confirmed that the number of rows in the table is equal to the number of distinct rows.
So if there were any duplicates this number would be less.
But since the number is the same as it was for the normal count that means that there are no duplicate
rows.
And so basically what that does for us is it confirms that this table is in first normal form.
So we've seen that there are no values 2 values in one cell and we can see that.
And also it's you can investigate that further just by knowing where the table came from and how it's
been structured.
Also we've confirmed that there are no duplicate rows.
So as a result of this table is in first normal form.
Next we're going to investigate the second and third normal forms.
And those are going to be some very exciting tutorials called wait to see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.