Hello and welcome back to the course on databases and the first tutorial we investigated our current
database designed to check if rules conforming to the third normal form.
We have two tables we've got the Customers table in the Transactions table.
We learned that the Customers table which is this one does conform to the third normal form at the same
time.
We learned that the transactions table which is this one unfortunately doesn't conform to the third
normal form.
At this stage.
So what are we going to do today is we going to change the design of our database to make sure that
this table also conforms to the third normal form or meets the criteria of the third normal form.
And what that will do is it will make sure that the whole database while the whole schema is in third
normal form.
So there we go we've got an exciting challenge ahead.
But the good news is that we already know what we need to do.
We already know what's part of this table is actually is actually preventing it from passing their normal
form criteria.
We know that we've got the item code here and then we've got the item description and the retail price
of the item we established last time that these two columns or each one of these columns.
So here we've got the candidate key and then we've got another candidate again.
So we established that description is not directly dependent on this candidate and is not directly depend
on this candidate.
It is actually transitively dependent on each of those candidate keys through the item code like that.
So the item code is what dictates the description even though indeed each one of these is one of these
rows has a has an item description and a retail price.
But in reality there's a transitive dependency description depends on the candidate keys through the
item and retail price depends on the candidate keys through the item as well.
So item dictates these two values.
So what we need to do is basically separate out these columns into a separate table where item will
be the primary key.
So basically we'll have item description and the price item description price and so on.
And then in this table we will keep the item column on the out of these three columns and that will
item will be the foreign key here for us to connect or to join to that new table that we're going to
create where the item information is going to be stored.
So that's what we've got ahead of us for today.
And without further ado let's get started.
So what are we going to do.
Well we're going to separate the transitive dependencies so let's write that in the comment Tran of
div pen and CS need to be separated into their own table.
All right so we're going to use the temporary table again and that's why it's a good thing that we removed
it so we can use the same name and we can say create table by the way before I proceed the process here
is going to be very similar to what we did to modify the second normal form.
Now that we know what needs to be done it's going to be very very similar to what we did or we're here
for the second normal form.
So if you'd like to practice then I invite you to pose this video and try to create this code on your
own and see if you can indeed separate out these three columns into their own table and get rid of the
duplicates and so on and then check that that table also conforms to a third normal form and then play
the video and see how I'm going to go about accomplishing this task and compare your results to the
results we get in the tutorial and that'll be a good opportunity for your practice.
But otherwise I'm just going to continue with this now and feel free to stick around and see how I'm
going to come up with the solution to this challenge.
All right so here we are going to create the timber table and we're going to say create table as select.
And we just want to select these columns into our TMB table item or item Qamar description Khama retail
price and where it's like the from from transactions semicon.
So if I run this part.
OK.
Tran is actions plural.
My bad.
So there we go.
If we run this part you'll see that beef's.
To those comma columns.
Now if we just run this whole query we're going to put them into a table which is going to copy this
as the comment.
So right now we have three thousand four hundred and fifty five rows in the item table.
But as you can imagine that's way too many because in our items table we have duplicate because in our
transactions table we had several an item could have been purchased many times by many different customers
at different times different time stamps.
Therefore that table had duplicate items and therefore this table has to be good.
So let's just check.
It's always a good idea to check your table to impy that you've just created.
Let's have a look.
That it is indeed created the way we wanted it.
Yup.
So if you just scroll through these you will inevitably find duplicate So there is a duplicate code
and it's actually got even the same code.
Sometimes you'll find that the description is the same but the items are different.
Right.
So that's that's normal that means you know there's two different types of scarves or two different
types of T-shirts.
That's fine.
But in this case we see that the description is the same right.
Those are the items the same.
The description is the same and the prices is completely duplicated.
So we need to get rid of those and we just want a list like a price list.
Basically we need a price list here and instead of a extract from the transactions list.
So we're going to continue with that.
And here we're going to say two and why why are we doing this.
Because we want to make the new table one enough so we want to put in first normal form.
And that's why we want to remove duplicate rows.
OK.
So create a table tray table and you want to call it what to call this one we'll call it items as.
And same thing as we did previously.
Right so same thing as we did here.
Select Distinct from Tempe.
Right so we're selecting the distinct values from the same table select distinct
distinct store from tempy.
So if you just run this you'll get the distinct items so you can see 126 rows right.
So far on this we got a hundred and twenty six rows so there's only 126 items on sale at the store.
And now we're just going to check read say select star for all items I mean call on are on this you'll
see that now.
126 rows.
So if you go through here you'll see that it doesn't have the book you've got the T-shirt she's a blanket
sweater you will find cases when you've got the same description as we discussed like baby quilt baby
quilt.
But they have different item codes.
And here the price is different.
It's a very expensive baby quilt.
$100 for a baby quilt.
I probably I don't know.
I don't know much about baby clothes but that sounds expensive $100.
OK.
So we've got the table with the items.
And now the last thing that we want to do or one of the final things that we want to do is we want to
go back to that table.
So basically before we go back to the table to the transactions they will remove these rolls.
There's a switch which in which order we did it previously.
So we've we've done this now we just want to let's go ahead and make sure that this table that we have.
Right so let's make sure that this table that we have that the items table is in the third normal form.
So I'm going to refresh this.
And so we have four tables we're going to drop the tempy table so we don't need to worry about that
very check that the customers table is indeed in third normal form so that's good.
No transitive dependencies there.
We're still working on the transaction stable but so far we've come up with the item stable so let's
go ahead and while we are here check that it is in third normal form.
Just to check that check it off and make sure that so we don't have to come back to it later.
All right.
So in the items table what is our what are all kind of the keys.
So we've only got one kind of ticket item here because indeed the item codes are unique in this table.
And so you won't find to repeating item costs you on that same time you could find two repeating descriptions
you could find repeating retail prices.
Therefore this is our candidate.
And no other combination here so description plus retail price.
Actually if you take description price retail price that that could be a close call right that could
be if you've got to think about that.
So if you've got an item right the item might change but what if.
So if you know the description and the retail price could they be could they have.
Could they be.
If you take those too.
Could they be a candidate.
Q Right so the question is if you take the description in the retail price does that mean that based
on those two you can you can identify or you you can uniquely tell what the item code will be.
Oh that's a very interesting question because basically to paraphrase it can we have two items two different
items two different item codes that have the same description and the same retail price.
So it depends it depends on the way your store operates.
If you have let's say if every time you have a new item code right then either the description has to
change or the retail price has to or his description has to be different or retail prices to boot.
But when you think about it you could let's say you could have a handbag for $114 77 cents under this
code and you could have another handbag under the under this under a different code.
Under this say this code you can have a handbag for $114 and 77 cents again.
Right.
But they would be different handbags right.
So one could be from Gucci and one could be from Louis Vuitton.
And so the description is the same the price is the same but the item codes are different.
So makes sense just through that example.
We can tell that description at retail price the combination of these two fields is not a candidate.
So a bit of thinking went into that.
I hope I hope that was a good good explanation.
So basically the item is definitely a candidate key.
These two together do not form a candidate key because two different items could still have the same
hand by hand because have the same description and retail price.
Right.
So there we go.
We know that this is our candidate key.
These are.
So this is our prime attribute these are non-prime attributes.
So this tables is indeed in first normal form because there is no duplicates and there are no cells
that contain more than one value so all values are atomic.
So this is this sounds like one value even though this slash in between is just a description that's
how description is been written up then is this table in second normal form so basically when to check
that each one of the non-prime attributes depends on the candidate key or the can.
Or each one of the candidate keys in full or depends on the whole of each of the candidate keys.
Right so here we only have one candidate key.
So you cannot and it's consist of only one column.
So you cannot split it up and so therefore by default each one of these columns indeed depends on this
candidate key in full in full or wholly or fully depends on this candidate.
So this table is in second order form and to check a third or form we need to check that there is no
transitive dependencies.
So the description then an item or does depend on item through price.
No it depends the require an item and the same thing for price does prize depend on description on item
through description or doesn't depend on item directly so depends on item directly but the way to think
about it is basically if I say all right so this price is fixed 9:29 What if I change the description
right.
Will this price have to change.
Well not necessarily.
You could have sheet's a 29 it was.
You have a blanket at 29 90 a sweater 29 90 so the price doesn't depend on the description there's no
connection between them.
They both just depend on it.
So this table is in three N.F. the N.F. confirm it.
Great.
And finally we just need to finish off with our transactions table.
So what we need to do is now remove the extracted rows from the Transactions table but keep the foreign
key item right so we want to keep this.
If we look at the transactions table there it is once you remove remove these Toro's basically and just
keep this one so we know what items purchased so we don't lose all of the information about it.
So simple alter statement alter table transactions drop column.
So we're going to have description and cheer up call them retail price semi-colon.
If you're on this.
There we go so we've dropped those columns and now if we select start from transactions
you can see that now this table is much more simplified.
So you've got it's just the transaction ID the time timestamp when it occurred.
The customer ID right.
So this is it.
This is also a combination of these two columns are cabinet key and you've got the item and then in
addition to that one thing that we need to do is drop table t MP Kallen and rid of the tempy table.
So if we refresh that.
So now we have three tables.
We know that the transaction table indeed conforms to the third normal form because we've removed the
columns that prevented that from happening.
So we don't even need to check.
We can say three N.F. confirmed and we also know that the rest of the tables We've already checked that
they conform to the third normal form.
So basically we have a database design where all of the tables conform to the third normal form so therefore
this whole database is now in the third normal form.
And as you can see right away we've saved so much space so much processing time and so much potential
for error.
We've removed that by removing those columns which through the process of normalization.
So we've now normalized our database and we've got these new to your table so if you ever are curious
about a certain transaction you want to find out more about this transaction and you want to know the
customer ID then you just basically take this table and you perform a join like join this table to the
customers table and you will be able to match it up to this customer I.D. And if you want information
about the items you join this table to the items table and you'll get information.
So as you can see as we discussed now it's easier to write into the stable.
But reading is become harder so previously if you just wanted to read information about a row in the
original transaction table you just select just read that redoes roll right from that table because
all of the information is right there and that is good for oil a.p.
Online analytics processing.
But if you wanted to OLTP then writing is more important because you want to save time and increase
efficiency during writing.
So therefore now in this table it's very easy to write the rows because you only need to write four
columns instead of much greater amount of columns that we had previously.
So hopefully you enjoyed these tutorials on normalization.
It is quite a lengthy process but nevertheless it is rewarding and it is fun.
It's fun to perform these investigations and around this around this code.
So on that note we've achieved our results with normalized the database and I look forward to seeing
you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.