Congratulations on completing the course.
Here's a summary of what we learned.
First we learned how to download install and customize Visual Studio code Visual Studio code is a free
version of tile cross-platform idea that we can use in web development to write HVM and CSSA code.
Next we learned about HVM fundamentals.
We covered several concepts in the H himself fundamental section of the course.
We looked at what HVM is and several tags that HDMI gives us to add content to our Web page.
After that we learned about displaying data in H-G M-L we learned how to create lists tables layouts
divs and spans and forms and HVM.
Then we learned about colors in each team.
We learned about the different ways that we can specify color in each team male and the elements that
we can color using each team.
Next we learned about embedding media and graphics in each team so we covered a range of topics in this
section including embedding images video audio and other web pages into our web page.
We also learned about the HVM canvas and how we can create SVGA or scalable vector graphics using HVM.
Then we did a deep dive into HVM tags.
We learned about formatting tags metadata tags and tags new to HVM L5.
After that we looked at each Demelza global attributes including those specific to each team L5.
Then we learned about events in each team all the groups of events we looked at our keyboard events
mouse events drag events and clipboard event.
We then learned about layouts and web pages and Mail.
The majority of this section pertain to bootstrap but also contains some information on dynamic text
and images as well as menus and header bars.
After that we got some hands on practice using H.M.S. to create a web site.
We created several sections of content on our Web page and got practical experience using the tips and
techniques we learned up to this point in the course.
Then we learned about sh t m l the extensible HyperText Markup Language.
Topics covered include what SH team L is sh t M-L syntax and how to convert HMO code into Exige here
Malko.
Next we learn some techniques for debugging each hemol code we learned about what debugging is common
T.M. errors and how to fix them and how to use an h l validator in the second half of the course.
We learned about C Ss Cascading Style Sheets.
First we learned about the basics of C Ss including how to create a CSSA style sheet.
CSSA syntax.
The cascading order of styles and the box model.
Then we learned about modifying text using CSSA.
Topics covered include a basic text effect fonts and text properties.
After that we learned about colors and CSX.
We learned about what elements we can color how we can specify color using CSSA saturation opacity and
filters.
We then looked at some groups of CSSA properties groups of properties included background properties
border properties box properties outline properties positioning properties and clipping and masking
properties.
After that we learned about CSSA tables.
Topics covered included table style and display table alignment and cool effects that we can do with
tables.
Next we learned how we can style lists and CSSA we learn about list properties as well as how we can
color less than we learned about CSSA animations including transition properties animation properties
2D animation and 3D animation.
After that we learned about the properties that we can animate using CSSA.
These included background border column Flack's font margin height with text and padding We then learned
how we can style buttons in CSSA we learned how to add States to when the user hovers over and clicks
the button.
Then we learn some advanced styling techniques for our buttons.
Finally we learned how to add animations to our buttons.
Then we looked at pseudo classes and CSSA we learned about pseudo classes that can be used with the
input and paragraph elements as well as other HVM elements.
After that we learned about CSSA selectors.
We looked at selectors that can be used at the paragraph input and link elements.
Next we learned about rules and CSSA we looked at what that rule is and several rules that CSSA gives
us access to.
After that we learned advanced CSSA topics including gradients shadows and effects advanced positioning
and Blon modes.
Then we used the CSSA skills we learned to sterilize the web page recreated in the H-2A male hands on
section.
This gave us practical experience using the styling techniques we learned in the second half of the
course.
After that we learned some common techniques for debugging success.
We learned how to approach debugging CSSA issues and looked at some of the common CSSA errors and how
to fix them.
Finally we learned about some useful CISSP civics.
We looked at how we can utilize siestas entities and CSSA units to our advantage when styling web pages.
Congratulations on completing the course.
You now have a solid foundation in web development using HVM L and CSX.