In this section we will set up the idea that we will use for the rest of this course.
It goes without saying that this is one of the central sections of the course you will need an itto
write your code that you will run in the web browser first.
We will look at how we can download and install Visual Studio code onto our computer.
This lecture will take you through the process of navigating to the download page online all the way
to installing and running the software on your computer.
Next we will learn how to customize the ideas to meet our needs.
This will include modifying the color scheme the hot to use text size the auto save feature and the
cursor style.
We will learn the process of modifying user settings and preferences for Visual Studio code in order
to tap into its ability to customize our editor to fit our needs and preferences.
Finally we will learn how to run our code in the web browser running code in the web browser is how
we will see the result of the code we typed in the ID.
This lecture will teach you the ins and outs of making sure you can efficiently test the code that you
write in the web browser of your choice.
By learning these simple techniques in this lecture it will allow us to progress faster later on as
we write and test code in the majority of the lectures and this course in the next lecture we will go
through the steps of downloading and installing Visual Studio code.
The interactive development environment we will use in the rest of this course.