In this section we will learn about how we can stylize HDMI lists using CSSA.
First we will learn about several list properties that we can use to modify the style of ordered and
unordered lists.
We learned how to customize the type image and position of list markers or bullet points that appear
next to each item in a list.
After that we will learn how to add color to the different parts of our list.
We will look at how we can add a background color to the whole list and also specify a background color
for just the list element by the end of this section.
You will have an understanding of how to use CSSA style customize and color HDMI lists and the next
lecture we will learn about specifying lists types using C Ss.