In this section we will learn about color and HMO.
When creating a web page color choice is crucial for making the web page appealing to users.
It is important that each team of developers understand the various ways that color can be used in each
team l h team l gives us several ways to specify the color of our elements and we will look at each
of these in this section.
We will learn about specifying color by name or G-B value or a value hex value H.F. cell value and HSLDA
value by the end of this section.
You will have a solid understanding of how to use color in each DML including how to specify the alpha
value of a color to add transparency to element and you will understand terms such as hue saturation
and lightness and how to work with these color values in each team.
In the next lecture.
We will learn about color and HMO.