In this section we will learn about layouts and web pages and HMO.
First we will learn about how we can responsively size elements on a web page.
This is important because we want to make sure the elements on our Web page scale appropriately based
on the size of the browser.
Next we will learn about how we can create a menu or head or bar 400 web page Hetter bars and menus
are a common form of navigation for an HMO web page.
After that we will learn about bootstrap.
Bootstrap is a popular web development framework that can make responsively sizing our HVM elements
and laying out a web page a lot easier.
We will look at how we can use bootstrap to position elements on our Web page layout menus and UI elements
modify images work with text and add detail to the layout of our Web page.
By the end of this section you will have a strong understanding of how you can write each DML code that
scales responsively to the web browser and how you can use the bootstrap framework to lay out your HVM
content.
This will result in you being able to create scalable solutions and speeding up your development time
by using the latest development strategies and frameworks and the next lecture we will learn about making
the images and text on our Web page responsive using HVM old code.