In this section we will learn about each team event.
Events can be added to HTL element to call a function when the user performs a certain action.
We will learn about four main types of HVM l events in this section keyboard events mouse events drag
events and clipboard events.
First we will learn about keyboard events if we want to fire an event when the user presses a certain
key.
We can use keyboard events like Auntie down Auntie press and Auntie up to program the functionality
we need.
Next we will look at mouse events and HVM all mouse events allow us to call certain functions when the
user performs certain actions like clicking double clicking and scrolling over elements.
After that we will learn about drag events HVM l drag events allow us to fire code when the user drags
or drops an element we will use these events to create a simple drag and drop program in each team.
Finally we will learn about clipboard events and M-L clipboard events are useful for when you want to
fire code when the user copies pastes or cuts in element by the end of this section.
You will know how to use h t m l events to your advantage to call functions when the user performs certain
actions.
You will be able to write code that responds to presses mouse events dragging and dropping elements
and clipboard events in the next lecture.
We will look at keyboard events in HD M-L.