In this section we will learn about more HVM l tags that we haven't yet covered in the course.
The purpose of this section is to expose you to several more HVM tags and you can have in your web development
skillset.
First we will look at the tags that has to do with formatting.
After that we will learn about metadata tags.
Finally we will learn about the tags that are new to HVM L5.
We have already learned some of these new tags so we will just recap the ones we know and then look
at examples of new tags that we haven't yet learned about.
By the end of this section you will know several more H.T. M-L tags and you came into this section knowing
you will also know more about metadata tags and understand their uses.
Finally you will know which tags are new as of each team L5 in the next lecture.
We will learn about formatting tags.