In this section we will learn about sh t m l sh t m l stammerer extensible HyperText Markup Language
and is used to ensure accurate syntax and quality of web pages first.
We will learn about what sh t UML is.
We will look at the reasons.
Sh t M-L is used by developers and the role it plays in web development.
You will understand how X HVM all relates to HVM mail.
After that we will learn about the syntax of sh TNL you will understand the things that you need to
do in order to write.
Sh t m l document.
Finally we will look at an example of actually converting a block of h t l code to x each M..
This will give us hands on experience that will allow us to understand the syntax differences between
these two languages by the end of this section.
You will know what sh t m l is its advantages and disadvantages and have experience writing BASIC sh
t m l code in the next lecture.
We will learn about what SH T.M. is.