In this section we will learn about global attributes an HMO a global attribute can be applied to any
HVM element.
First we will learn about the global attributes that aren't specific to HVM L5 and apply to other versions
of HVM now they are access key class.
Dear ID Lang style Tairbh index and title.
After that we will learn about the global attributes specific to each team L5.
They are content editable context menu data draggle hidden in check and translate.
By the end of this section you will understand how to use HVM else global attributes including those
added an HMO five in the next lecture.
We learn about some of the global attributes and HMO.