In this section of the course we will learn about how we can modify text using C Ss First we will look
at text StarLink concept we will learn how to transform text decorate text and modify letter spacing.
Next we will learn about basic text effect using the text Shatto property.
We will look at how to create a basic text shadow blur text shadows color texture Mattos add multiple
text shadows and layer shadows to build 3D text.
Then we will take a look at fonts and see.
SS We learned about the concept of a font family and the differences between a specific font family
and a generic font family we will learn how to scale text and make it bold or italic.
Finally we will learn about other text properties that CSSA gives us access to.
We will look at wrapping an overflowing text in various forms of spacing and controlling whitespace
by the end of this section.
You will have a solid understanding of how to modify text using a variety of properties and see SS in
the next lecture.
We will learn about text styling concepts.