In this section we will learn how to style buttons using C.
SS First we will learn about how to write code that changes our button depending on what stage it isn't.
We will learn how to create different effects for when the button is idle when the mouse is hovering
over the button and when the user clicks the button.
After that we will look at some more styling that we can add to buttons.
We will learn how to specify a roundish for a button add a shadow to our button add a custom image for
background and swap custom button images when the user clicks the button.
Finally we were learned about how to animate buttons on a web page.
We will create a pulse animation for when our button is idle and a button pressed the fact to make it
look like the button is being pushed in 3D when the user clicks it.
We will create a pulse animation for when our button is idle and a button pressed the effect to make
it look like the button is being pushed in 3D when the user clicks on it.
By the end of this section you will understand how to use CSSA to stylize and animate buttons.
You will be able to customize the display and functionality of buttons on your web page and the next
lecture.
We will learn how we can work with Button States and CSSA.