In this section we will learn some advanced CSSA techniques to stylize our Web page first.
We will learn about gradient CSSA supports both linear and radial gradient.
We will learn about both of these types and explore different options we have for customizing the look
of our gradients.
Next we will look at shadows and effects.
We will learn about different options we have for mastering etting chateaus to our HVM element.
We will also learn how to add other cool effects to our HMO elements.
After that we will learn about the different types of positioning and see.
We will learn about relative positioning absolute positioning and using the z index to order elements
in 3D.
Finally we will learn about blends MoJ and CSSA blend modes allow us to control how overlapping elements
blend visually on our Web page.
In the next lecture we will learn about how we can create gradients using CSF.