In this section we will put the HVM l skills that we have learned to use as we build a website.
For example we will create a website for a new pizza parlor.
Here is what the website will look like when it is finished.
As you can see it will have four sections home about us menu and contact.
First we will create the header bar for our web page.
We will add images to the top and links to each section.
After that we will create the home page for our website.
This page will have an image carousel that cycles through a series of images.
Then we will create the about us section which will include adding text and image content to a web page.
After that we will look at creating a basic menu.
We will do this using cards and Bootstrap which allow us to easily group an image or the title description
and button.
When one of the buttons on the web page is clicked it will display the name of the item and the price
is an alert at the top of the browser.
Finally we will create the contact section for our web page.
We will create an HMO form that can be used to compose an email since we would need server side code
to actually send the email.
We will just display the email information as an alert to the user using basic client code.
By the end of this section you will have practical experience combining the skills you learned so far
in this course to create a functioning Web site in the next lecture.
We will start to build our Web page that we will add to in this section of the course.