In this section we will learn about some specific features of CSSA that are somewhat advanced but also
very useful to know the purpose of this section is to build on your CSSA knowledge and add some more
specific knowledge to your web development skillset.
First we will learn about entities and CSX entities are special combinations of letters numbers and
symbols that we can use to display characters on our Web page.
After that we will learn about the different units that CSSA gives us to specify the size of elements
on our Web page.
By the end of this section you will have a broader knowledge of some specific and useful CSSA features
you will understand how to use SS entities to display special characters on your web pages.
You will understand the different Unix CSSA gives us to size elements on a web page in the next lecture.
We will learn about CSSA entities.