In this section we will learn how to stylize each Chmela tables using CSSA.
First we will learn about how to change the style and display of our table.
This includes adding a border to our table in the cells in our table adding a width and height to the
table and specifying where the table caption should be displayed in relation to the table.
Then we will look at how we can align text within our table.
We will learn about aligning text horizontally and vertically and also how to specify which alignment
algorithm is used to determine the table layout.
Finally we were learned about how we can use CSSA selectors and properties to add cool effects to our
table to make our tables stand out and be more appealing to users of our Web page.
By the end of this section you will have a solid understanding of how to stylize tables using C Ss in
the next lecture.
We will learn how we can modify table style and display using C Ss.