In this section we will learn the fundamentals of each team.
First we will look at what HVM is and the history of each GMO then we will look at the format of an
AGM document.
Next we will learn about tags.
The building blocks of each team.
After that we will break down the structure of each team l code to learn about concepts like elements
and attributes and take a closer look at the syntax of HVM our code.
We will then learn about page and title headings and their importance in an HMO document not only to
the user viewing your web page but to the search engine filtering search results.
We will then look at paragraphs and text and different options we have for controlling how text is displayed
in the browser.
A look at the style attribute will benefit us in learning how we can add styles to our elements to control
how they are rendered to the browser.
We will learn how to format text in HVM in terms of aligning text on our Web page and different effects
we can add to our text like highlighting and cross-out.
Next we will look at hyperlinks and how we can allow the user to click on elements like text and images
on our Web page to load.
You are rolling a closer look at images and HVM will let us explore some more image display options
and how we can make parts of an image clickable.
Finally we will learn how we can add comments in our age Chimo code and then we will look at a recap
of what we learned in this section.
By the end of this section you will have a solid understanding of the fundamental concepts and basic
programming constructs of HVM L and you will be able to create basic web content to display on a web
page in the next lecture.
We will learn about what each animal is and some of the history behind it.