In this lecture we will learn how we can animate the words spacing and letter spacing properties using
CCS.
Let's look at an example of how we can animate the words spacing property to stretch the text on a webpage.
First we will create a text that will be animated on our Web page.
Next we need our opening and closing style tags to our paragraphed tag we will add an animation of text
and a duration of three seconds and make our animation loop using the infinite keyword.
Then we will create our animation we will name our animation tech Stanham and specify that it will animate
the words spacing property from a value of five pixels to a value of 100 pixels.
When we run this code on the web page we should see the spacing between the words and our text increase
as the animation plays.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We will also look at an example of how we can animate the letter spacing property.
We don't need to create a new animation we just have to make a few modifications to our existing one.
For starters let's change the word spacing property to letter space and also let's change the value
at the end of our animation from 100 pixels to 20 pixels.
When we run this code in our browser we should see our letter spacing animation play in the next lecture.
We will recap what we have learned in this section of the course.