In this section we learned about various ways that HVM allows us to display data on our web pages.
HDMI lets us display data in the form of lists tables layout divs and forms various types of lists exist
that explain data in unique ways unordered lists serve bullet pointed lists ordered lists or labeled
with numbers and letters to organize how their elements are displayed.
Description lists associate a term element with the description element similar to how a dictionary
or flash card Associates a term to its definition.
The lists can also be nested regardless of their type.
So we could have any type of list nested within any other type of list.
Tables are made up of rows and columns and HVM l provides just a variety of ways to customize rows and
columns in our table using styles we can also customize the display of our table including adding style
to the table header body and footer.
We also have the option to specify styles for each individual cell in our table layouts and each team
will provide us with several elements with specific purposes lay out elements include sections articles
and asides and are useful to support multi-column displays and web pages divs and spans are used to
group elements in a customized developer defined manner divs or block elements that we can wrap related
content in to style the related content in a uniform manner.
Spans are inline elements that we can use to group other in line elements.
They provide similar customisation to divs except that they work on inline elements not block elements
forms and age Chimay will allow us to obtain user input.
There are several options we can give the user to get their input including text input fields checkboxes
color picker's and multi-line text areas.
Having forms that are clear to users and provide them an easy to use interface to obtain their input
is a crucial element of web design.
In the next section we will learn about color and HMO.