In this lecture we will learn how we can hyperlinks to our Web page.
One important feature in each team is the ability to add hyperlinks to our web pages hyperlinks or links
that the user can click on that take them to another web page.
HVM provides the anchor tag to allow us to create a hyperlink the A-Trak property allows us to specify
the URL to take the user to when they click on the hyperlink.
For example we can type the following.
Let's go to the web browser and drag over our HQ mail file to run the code.
Notice that the content of this element is the actual text to be displayed as the hyperlink that the
user can click on.
We can also use other types of content like images as links to see an example of this.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Let's change our current code to the following.
To run this code we will jump back to the web browser and Draeger HDMI file into the browser.
Now if we click on the image notice that it will take us to the link we specify using the ATRA attribute.
Notice that when we move our mouse over something clickable on our G-mail web page the cursor turns
into a handy icon.
The default behavior of a text hyperlink an aged humoral is as follows.
If the user hasn't clicked on the link it is displayed in blue.
If the user has previously clicked on a link it is displayed in purple we can use a style attribute
to change these default behaviors.
For example we can change an uncooked hyperlinked color from blue to another color by using a style
tag and specifying the linked state of the anchor tag.
Let's go back to the editor and look at an example of this.
We will add an opening and closing style tag and between the two we will add the anchor selector which
is the letter A followed by a colon and the word length.
We will then add an opening curly brace.
The word color or colon the word pink and a closing curly brace.
If we put back the hyperlink code we had before go to the web browser and when our code.
You will notice that the link is now displayed as pink instead of blue.
We can also add a tooltip that will display when the user hovers over the hyperlink by using the title
attribute to see an example of this.
Let's go back to the editor.
We will add the title attribute to our anchor element and give it a value in quotes to use attribute
take effect.
We will go back to the web browser and run the code.
Now when we hover over our link you will notice that the additional information that we added using
the title tag is displayed as a tool tip in the next lecture.
We will take a closer look at images and HVM L and techniques we can use to add images to our webpage.