In this lecture we will learn about the basics.
Each female provides us with two create buttons to create a button you can use the button tag we will
start with an opening button tag the text that will appear on our button and then a closing button tag.
Once we have typed that we will go to the web browser and drag the HDMI file over to run our code.
We can also specify the type of button using the type attribute.
In this case we want specify the type to be button the text between the opening and closing tag is the
text that appears on the button.
Let's jump back to the web browser
noticed that we can click on the button in the browser.
However nothing happens when we click the button.
This is because we haven't specified the on click behavior for a button we can specify what happens
on click of our button by using the on click attribute to see an example of this.
We will go back to Visual Studio code and add the on click attribute to our opening button tab.
We will specify that an alert button was clicked should be displayed in the browser when the button
is clicked in this case we were making an alert that the button was clicked using the alert function.
We will go to the browser and drag the HMO file over to run our code.
Now if you click the button you will notice that the alert we specified is shown.
Let's go back to the editor and learn about the autofocus attribute the autofocus attribute puts the
button in focus.
Once the web page loads being in focus means having a blue outline around it as though it is currently
selected by hitting the enter key while our button is in focus.
You will notice that a button click is performed.
We will add the autofocus attribute to the opening button tag.
Then we will go back to our browser and run the code.
If you hit enter you should see the specified on click behavior.
Let's go back to the editor the disabled attribute allows us to disable a button and the disabled button
on our Web page will be greyed out and not clickable we will remove the autofocus attribute that we
added for the last example and instead add the disabled attribute then we will go back to the browser
and run our code
as you can see the button is greyed out and not clickable.
Now we will go back to the editor.
Let's take a closer look at age mail buttons and the on click attribute.
Aside from showing an alert we can perform other actions when our button is clicked.
We can change the color of our button when it is clicked to do so we will specify the on click attribute
to change the background color style of our button.
Let's go to the web browser and run the code.
Now when we click the button you will notice that it changes color.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Note that the on click attribute is a global attribute meaning that it applies to all HDMI elements
not just buttons text on our web page can be clickable to illustrate this.
First we will add an opening paragraph tag and specify the unclick attribute to set the color to red.
Then we will add some example text content.
Finally our element will be closed with the closing paragraph tag.
Let's go to the web browser and run this code.
Then we will click on the text and we should see the text turn red.
Now we will go back to the editor.
An image can also be made clickable using the on click attribute.
For example we will start out with an opening image tag and then assign it a source of star dot PFG
then we will give it the on click attribute and pass it the click function.
This is a custom function that we are going to write the value of the unclick attribute is the name
of a javascript function to make an working example in this case.
We will add a few lines of javascript code to our file.
Let's first add an opening and closing script tag.
Then we will add the following function code which will simply display an alert on the web page when
our image is clicked.
Don't worry if you don't fully understand this part we will go over the script tag and writing BASIC
code to interact with our HVM l code later on.
Let's go back to the browser
when we run this code in the web browser and click on the image.
You will notice that this alert is displayed in the next lecture.
We will learn about comments and each team will.