In this lecture we will look at the properties that CSSA gives us to modify the background of our each
team out element.
To illustrate these examples let's add a paragraph element with some example text to a web page the
background color property allows us to color and elements background.
We will get an opening and closing style tag to our code then we will use the background color property
and give our elements a background color of orange.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code
as you can see the background of our text is orange.
Let's jump back to the editor.
The background image property allows us to get an image as an element background let's remove our paragraph
element and add a development to our Web page.
We will also use the development selector instead of the paragraph element selector.
Let's give our div a height of 230 pixels and a weight of 250 pixels.
Let's use the background image property and give our development a background of our star PMG image.
To see the result of this change we will go to the web browser and run our code.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
The background repeat property controls how the background repeats if this property is set to a value
of repeat.
Which is also the default.
The image will repeat in both the x and y directions.
If we increase the height and width of our div to 500 and write our code in the browser you will notice
that our store image repeats we didn't have to explicitly use the background repeat property here since
the background repeats by default.
Let's jump back to the editor if the background repeat property is set to a value of repeat x the background
will only be repeated in the x direction.
Let's see the background repeat property to the style code for our give and give it a value of repeat
x then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our star graphic only repeats horizontally
and not vertically.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
If the background repeat property is set to evaluate repeat y the background will only be repeated in
the y direction.
Let's give the background repeat property evaluate repeat y then we will go to the web browser and run
our code as you can see the star graphic is repeated vertically in the y direction on our Web page.
Let's go back to the editor if the background repeat property is set to values.
No repeat the background image will not repeat.
Let's give our background image property a value of no repeat and then go to the web browser and run
our code as you can see the image does not repeat.
Let's jump back to the editor the background attachment property specifies that the image scrolls on
the web page scrolls of value scroll is the default and means that the background image will scroll
with the webpage.
Let's see the background attachment property to our code and give it a value of scroll to see the effect
of this code.
We need to add a paragraph element to our Web page and copy and paste it so that there is enough content
on our page to have to scroll.
We will give our first paragraph element an ID of P1 and use that ideas are selector.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our background image scrolls with the web
page.
Let's jump back to the editor of value fix to make a background image not scroll when the web page scrolls
we will give the background attachment property value of text and then run our code.
As you can see our image remains fixed in this position as the web page scrolls.
Let's go back to the editor to see the effect of these next few examples.
We will remove the paragraph elements that we just added.
We really use that development and give it a height and width of fifteen hundred pixels the background
position property allows us to position our background relative to our element.
We can assign it a value of left to position or background at the left of our element.
Let's give our driver background position property with a value of left.
This will make the image be positioned on the left side of the development then we will go to the web
browser and run our code as you can see our background is now positioned at the left of our element.
Let's jump back to the editor we can assign the background position property values center to position
the background at the center of our element.
Let's assign a background position property value of center and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see the background image is now centered in the middle of our development.
Let's go back to the editor.
We can assign the background position property value of right to position the background and the right
of our element.
Let's give our element the background position of right and run our code as you can see the background
image displayed at the right of the element.
Let's go back to the editor.
We can also specify a second value to say whether the image should be positioned at the top center or
bottom.
In other words giving a background position of right top means that the background will be positioned
on the top right of an element.
Let's use a background position of right top and then run our code as you can see the background is
aligned to the top right of our development.
Let's jump back to the editor possible combinations for these values are left top left center left bottom
center top center center center bottom right top right center and right bottom.
We can also specify an x and y position in pixels.
Let's give our background image an exposition of 20 pixels and a wide position of 50 pixels.
Then we will run our code as you can see our background image is now positioned at 20 pixels right and
50 pixels down in Argive.
Then we will go back to the editor an x y position can also be specified using percentages.
We will give our background image an x value of 70 percent and a Y value of 20 percent.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the position of our background image
was adjusted based on the code that we type in the next lecture.
We were learn about the border properties at CSSA gives us access to.