In this lecture we will learn about the background properties that CSSA allows us to animate.
We can animate and element's background background color background position and background size.
Let's look at an example of how we can animate the background color property we will create a development
that we will apply our styles and animation to then we will add or opening and closing style tags that
we will add our style code between lets add some style to our div.
We will add a width and height of 500 pixels to our div.
We will also give our div a background color of red to start out for animation property we will specify
our animation to be rainbow and in an animation that we will create the delay for animation will be
set to five seconds and we will also add the infinite keyword to make the animation run on a loop.
We will also add an animation delay of point seven five seconds.
Now we will write the code for our animation we will add that keyframes rule and add an animation name
of rainbow and we will create an animation that will cycle through the colors of the rainbow.
We will set the background colors red orange yellow green blue indigo violet and purple at keyframes
of 0 percent 15 percent 30 percent 45 percent 60 percent 75 percent 90 percent and 100 percent respectively.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our divs background color cycles
through the colors of the rainbow.
Let's jump back to the editor
Next let's look at an example of how we can animate the background position property.
First we will add a development to our Web page then we will add our opening and closing style tags
so that we can write our style code for this animation.
We will assign some styles to our div.
We will give our div a width of 500 pixels and a height of 500 pixels.
Then we will assign our give a background image of our star PLG image.
The initial background position of our div will be top left in our animation code we write in a second.
We will make our background position change from top left to bottom right.
To move our image from one position to another we really add an animation property and specify our animation
name as move B.G. give it a duration of three seconds and specify a loop behavior of infinite.
Next we will use the CSSA at keyframes rule and write the code for animation.
We will specify that at keyframe 100 percent.
The last keyframe the background position of our div will be bottom right.
It is also important to note that the animation name needs to be moved Biji the same name as we specified
as the animation for div in the above style code.
When we run our code in the browser you will see that the images background position animation from
top left to bottom right.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We will alter the code from the previous example so that we can see how to animate the background size
property in order to do this.
We just need to make a few changes to our current code.
First we will change the background position property to be background size.
For this example we will give our div a background size of 30 pixels by 30 pixels.
Then we will go to our animation code and change our code to animate the background Size property to
60 pixels by 60 pixels.
When we run our code you will see that the background size animation 30 pixels by 30 pixels to 60 pixels
by 60 pixels.
Those are examples of how we can animate and elements background properties and see SS.
Don't forget that we can also add to meet the shorthand and background property which lets us specify
the color position and size of our background.
All in one in the next lecture we will learn how we can animate the height and width properties.