In this lecture, we will learn about CSX entities, CSX.
And these are combinations that allow us to display characters in HDMI.
There are many, many CSX entities.
But we will cover some cool ones in this lecture.
The format for a CSX entity is as follows open, quote, escape character for characters that are letters
or numbers.
And finally, a closing quote for the first set of examples we are going to look at.
Let's create a paragraph element with some example text inside of it to start things off.
Next, we will add an opening and closing style tag to our page so that we can write some style code
inside of our style tags.
We will add a style to the paragraph element and use the before pseudo class to specify that we want
to insert content before our text.
We will also use the CSX entity code to six to F to display a yin and yang symbol before our text.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see, there is now a yin and yang symbol to the left of our paragraph element.
Let's jump back to the editor.
There are tons of CSX entities that we can use to insert cool characters into our Web page content if
we want to, instead of playing cards speed symbol before our text.
We can change the code to two six six zero and run the code to see the change.
As you can see, there is a speed symbol to the left of the text.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example to insert a club playing card symbol
before the text.
We use the code two six six three.
Let's change the code to two six six three and then go to the Web browser and run our code.
We will see a club to the left hand side of our text.
Let's jump back to the editor.
A code of two six six five allows us to add the heart playing cards symbol.
We will change the code to two six six five and then wrote our code in the Web browser.
You will notice that a heart symbol is now displayed to the left of our text.
Let's go back to the editor.
Changing the code to a two six six six will let us say the plane code diamond character to our text.
We will change the code to two six six six and then go to the Web browser and run our code.
As you can see, there is now a diamond on the right hand side of the text.
We will now go back to the editor.
Want to add all four characters in a row before our text.
Simply add all of the codes to the content.
We will add the code to six six zero two six six three two six six five and two six six six, all to
a string of content.
Of course, don't forget the escape character before each.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code to see the result.
You will notice that all four playing cards, symbols are now displayed on the left hand side of the
text.
Let's jump back to the editor.
To add a music note to our content, we can use the character code two six six be.
Let's change the code to two six six B and then go to the Web browser.
When we run our code, you will notice that a music notice now displayed to the left of our paragraph
element.
Let's go back to the editor.
If you want to add a warning similar before the text content, you can use the CFS entity Code two six
eight zero.
We will change the code to two six eight zero and then run our code in the Web browser.
Now there is a warning sign to the left of our text.
Let's go back to the editor.
Another cool thing we can do with these CSX entities is to use them as bullet points for lists that
we create.
To illustrate this concept, let's say at an unordered list to our code and give it three list elements.
Item one, item two, an item three.
Then we will change the style to a plug to the ally tag instead of the P tag.
We will also give our ally element a list style type of none.
We need to do this in a new block of code since the current block is using the before pseudo class.
Let's use the entity code two seven one four to add a checkmark character before each item in the list
to see the result of these changes.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
You will notice that a checkmark is next to each item in the list.
Now let's jump back to the editor.
If we want to add a checkmark with a different look and feel to it, we can use another checkmark entity
that has a code of two seven oh five.
Let's change the code to two seven oh five and then run our code in the Web browser to see our change
take effect.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example, some CSX entities are arrows.
These also make for good list item markers.
Let's change the entity code to two one D2 and run our code to see the result.
There is now an arrow next to each item in the list.
Then we will jump back to the editor.
Another style of Arrow has entity code two one nine two.
Let's change the code to two one nine two and then run our code in the Web browser to see the result.
Then we will jump back to the other.
Another useful entity for drawing attention to list items is a hand with a finger pointing at the list
item.
This entity has a code of two six Wante one.
We run the code.
You will see what this looks like in the Web browser.
Since there is a lot of detail in this entity, you may have to zoom in to see it clearly.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can also use CSX entities as content.
At the end of our element, let's go back to using a paragraph element with example text inside of it.
Then we will change our style to use that after Shuto class on the paragraph element to add an ellipsis
character, we can use the entity code two oh two six.
Let's go to the Web browser and run our code.
Now, there is an ellipsis character on the right hand side of our text.
Let's jump back to the editor.
If we want to add a double exclamation point after our text, we could use the entity code two or three.
We will change the code to two or three C and then run our code in the browser to see the result.
As you can see, there is now a double exclamation mark to the right of our text.
There are many more CSX entities that you can use.
This video just showed an example of how to use some of them in the next lecture.
We will learn about CSX unit.