In this lecture we will look at common CSSA areas and how to fix them.
One common CSSA error is missing a semi-colon between declarations.
It is important that we had a semi-colon between each declaration in order to ensure that our CSSA code
works properly.
To fix this error we can find where the semi-colon is missing and added another common CSSA error is
having an invalid declaration in the code.
It is important that the properties and values we use in our declaration are valid CSSA properties and
values.
If you have a property name or value is invalid or not recognized by CSX it will have no effect on the
element to fix an invalid declaration.
Find which part of the declaration is invalid and change it to make the declaration valid.
Another error you may encounter in CSX is an invalid selector since selectors control what element certain
styles are applied to.
It is very important that we make sure the selectors we are using in our code are valid.
If a selector is invalid none of the elements it is supposed to apply this style tool have the styles
applied to them.
Essentially the whole block of styles for this selector will not be applied to the HDMI element.
To fix an invalid selector error find the Selected of an invalid and change it to a valid selector.
The areas that we learned about in this video are just some of the errors that you will run into when
writing CSSA code.
However this gives you a good starting point of things to look out for when you are programming in the
next lecture we will learn about using a CSSA validator to debug or CSSA code.