In this lecture we will download and install Visual Studio code which we will use to write HVM and CSSA
code during this course.
You can use any idea that allows you to write HTL and CSSA code but I am choosing Visual Studio code
because it is free and cross-platform.
You can use this editor regardless of whether you are running Mac Windows or Linux.
ID is an acronym for interactive development environment when writing code an idea provides many useful
features that make the task a little easier.
Many IDs have features like syntax highlighting and intellisense.
Another great feature of Visual Studio code is that it provides programmers vast customisation options
as we will learn about in the next lecture to get started.
Let's go to the following You are a
HTP.
Ask colon slash slash code dot Visual Studio dot com forward slash download.
We will click on the download icon for whatever operating system we were running and follow the prompts
to download and install the software.
I will speed up the video of this process.
OK now that we have downloaded and installed Visual Studio code we can open it up if you left the prompt
open the editor after installing your software.
It should open up automatically.
Let's go to a file new file and take a look around the editor
the left hand side will show us the folders and files in the project you're an
to the right of that is the file you're currently editing at the top is the action bar where we can
access several menu options the File menu bar option gives us access to common features like creating
opening and saving files.
You will also notice further down the menu that we can access the preferences from this menu hovering
over preferences will reveal the preferences sub menu where we can do things like change the color theme
set up keyboard shortcuts and modify the user settings.
All of these things we will learn about in the next lecture the end sub menu gives us access to features
like copy paste cut and the ability to toggle line and block comments in our code a line comment comments
out one line of code a block comment uses a single line comment to comment out multiple lines of code
one Hartke to make note of here is that we can highlight a line of code and then use the Control forward
slash keyboard shortcut to comment out that line.
We can also highlight several lines at once and use the same key combination to comment out all of those
lines at once.
The selection of menu gives us options to modify our selections the positions of the lines in our code
and the position of our cursor in the editor depending on your coding style.
Some of the hot keys you see next to these options might be of use to you to view sub menu gives us
access to modify the display of the windows in our editor.
One particularly useful menu option here is the command palette menu where we can browse through the
default hotkeys that the editor gives us access to.
We can also search for a command to see the corresponding key combination that we will use as a hot
key to trigger that command.
We can also control where the sidebar is displayed.
We can toggle the sidebar to the left or the right.
Speaking of the side bar this bar that is on the left hand side of the editor is referred to as the
sidebar.
The first option gives us the ability to toggle the file explorer on the left hand side of the editor
which shows us the files and folders that we currently have open in the editor.
The magnifying glass icon on the sidebar gives us access to common functionality such as searching and
replacing text in our files.
The third icon on the sidebar allows us to link Visual Studio code to source control programs like get
Haub or bitbucket.
The fourth sidebar option will toggle the debug window where a developer can step through and debug
our code.
The fifth icon on the sidebar lets us configure extensions on the editor the gear icon at the bottom
of the sidebar gives us access to common settings and alerts us if there are updates available for our
editor.
It is a good idea to update your editor to the latest version when new versions are released.
Since companies frequently release new versions to add features to editors and patch bugs that they
find and fix in their editor software going back to the top nav bar and cooking on the go option gives
us the ability to go to a certain line file definition or symbol the debugging menu option gives us
access to the debugging features of our editor.
When working with HVM Allen CSSA as we will be working within this course these options will be of less
help to us when debugging our best options for debugging or to use validators and the tools built into
whatever web browser we are using.
The tasks menu gives us options for working with tasks in the editor.
And a programming editor a task is something that allows us to automate common processes that can save
us time when coding automating tasks is something that you will want to master over time as a developer
as it can save you a lot of time and energy and allow you to free up time to spend more focus on writing
and testing your code.
The final option we have access to on this top Hetter bar is the help option.
Here we have useful options such as accessing the documentation release notes a reference to keyboard
shortcuts some introductory videos a tips and tricks section and more in the next lecture.
We will learn how we can customize the editor to fit our preferences.