In this lecture we will learn about how we can use CSSA to change the style of our button in different
states.
Common states have a button in digital applications or the idle state the hover state and the pressed
state in CSX we can specify what happens when the user hovers over a button with the mouse cursor using
the hover selector.
First let's say add a button to our webpage.
We will add an opening and closing button tag and give it some text content that will be the text displayed
on our button.
Next we will add an opening and closing style tag to our code.
We will use the hover selector to give our button a yellow background when the user hovers over the
button with their mouse.
When using selectors and SS We first specify the element name followed by a colon followed by the name
of the selector.
Let's go to the web browser and write our code
when we hover over the button with our cursor.
You will notice that its color changes to yellow.
Let's jump back to the editor and build on this example.
We can use the transition duration property to specify how long the transition between the idle and
hover stage should be.
Let's say the transition duration property to our button styles and give it a value of 1 second then
we will go to the web browser and run our code.
This time when we move our cursor over the button you will notice that the transition to the yellow
background color takes a duration of one second as opposed to being an immediate transition.
Let's jump back to the editor the active state can be used to modify the style of the button when the
user actually clicks on it.
Let's use the active selector and specify that our button background become orange when the button is
clicked.
We will also specify a transition duration of zero seconds as we want the transition to take effect
immediately when the user clicks on the button.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code when we hover over our button.
It turns yellow.
Based on the code that we wrote before when we click on the button you will notice that it turns the
color orange in the next lecture.
We were lynched at Advanced button styling techniques we can do in C Ss.