In this lecture we will learn about lists and HMO lists are an important way of displaying data.
There are three types of lists and HMO ordered lists unordered lists and description lists
this tag is also paired with a closing tag in HVM mail list items are created using the ally tag.
Let's look at a basic example of using an ordered list.
Say we want to create a grocery list and we wanted to buy apples oranges and pineapples to start our
list.
We would type an opening or well tag.
Next we would create a list item element for apples like this we would follow suit for the next two
items on our list.
Oranges and pineapples.
Finally we would end the list by using a closing ordered list tag.
Let's jump to the web browser and run this code
as you can see when rendered to the browser to the elements in our list are numbered by default.
Let's go back to the editor.
There are several other options besides this default.
We can have ordered lists with letters both uppercase and lowercase and we can have lists with Roman
numerals both uppercase and lowercase.
There is a type attribute associated with the ordered list tag that specifies which type of ordered
list we want to use.
If there is no type specified or the type is 1 then the list will be numbered with numbers 1 2 3 etc.
If we want to label our list with uppercase letters we would assign the type to a value of capital A.
Let's add the type attribute to our ordered list tag and set the value to capital A.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
Now we can see our ordered list labeled with capital letters.
Now we will go back to the editor if we change the capital a to a lowercase say.
And then when our code you can see that the list is now numbered with lower case letters.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can also label the items in our list with uppercase and lowercase Roman numerals.
If we change the type to a value of capital I and then run our code we will see our list labeled with
upper case roman numerals.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
If we change the capitalized to a lowercase XY and run the code we will see our list labeled with lowercase
Roman numerals.
Now we will go back to the editor.
Another type of list and HDMI was an unordered list.
Each list element has a bullet point next to it.
Instead of a number or letter to create an unordered list you can use the UL tag.
Let's switch our list from an ordered list to an unordered list for an ordered list the type attribute
can have one of four values desk circle square and none the desk type displays the traditional fill
in bullet point that we are used to.
This is the default option if no type is specified the circle type is a hollow circle that isn't filled
in.
Let's set the type of unordered list to be circle.
Then we will go to the browser and run our code.
The square type sets the bullet point to a square shape.
Let's go back to the editor and change the type of unordered list to square.
Then we can go back to the browser and run the code to see the result of what we just did.
If we don't want any bullet marker next to the items in our list we can specify the type none.
Let's go back to the editor and change the type value to none for a list.
Then we will run the code in a web browser and see that there are no bullet markers next to the items
in our list.
Let's jump back to the editor.
The third type of list that each team supports is a description list.
The best way to think of a description list is that it matches a term with a description or description
list is created using the DL tag.
Then we can use the DTD tag to add a term to our list underneath a term we can have one or more definitions.
These definitions can be specified using the DD tag.
Let's run our code in the browser to see the result of the HVM L we have written so far we can add as
many definitions as we want.
Underneath that term going back to the editor.
Let's add a second DD element to our term when we run the code in the editor.
We will see the second description added underneath our term.
Let's go back to the editor.
It is also possible for us to nest lists.
This gives us all kinds of combinations.
In summary each team will provide several options to create and customize lists including ordered lists
unordered lists description lists and the ability to nest lists within other lists regardless of their
type.
And the next lecture we will learn about tables in HMO.