In this lecture we will lay out the basic foundation for our website and include the code needed to
import bootstrap into our project.
First we will led the team L5 doctype at the top of our program the signal to the browser that we are
writing HVM L5 code.
After that we will put the opening and closing HVM tags into our code.
We will add the language of our web page to the opening HVM l tag to specify that our web page will
be in English.
We will give the langue property a value of n.
Next comes the heading section for our webpage.
We will add an opening and closing head tag to our code inside of the opening and closing head tags.
We want to specify the character in code and we are going to use in this case we will specify the carousel
UTF 8.
We do this using the meta tag and specifying the carousel property value as UTF 8.
The title tag is mandatory for any webpage.
Remember that the title you give your web page is displayed in the tab at the top of the browser but
not visually on your web page.
For this example we will call our title pizza Web site.
The next four lines of code will come after the title but still within the head tags of our web page
they are used for importing bootstrapped for into our project.
The first line will be a link to the bootstrap for CSSA style sheet.
The second line imports Che Querrey into our program.
The third line imports the popper J s library into our project.
The fourth line imports the bootstrap for javascript library into our project
under the closing head tag.
We will put an opening and closing body tag the closing body tag will come before the closing HVM Elkhead.
Now that we have set up the basic outline for a web page we are ready to jump into developing it in
the next lecture and the next lecture.
We will add a header bar to our webpage.