In this lecture we will stylize the hetter bar of our website.
First we relate a background color and border to our nav bar.
We will wrap our NAV element in a div that we will add these styles to.
We will then add a white background color to our div then we will add a solid border of three pixels
with a color of all our G-B 190 0 0.
Now that our links are on a white background we can make our links black.
We will use the link selector and specify that the unclick links on our page will be displayed black.
Next we will use the visited select and specify that any visited links on our web page should be displayed
to our G-B color 16 27 27.
We will then use the hover selected a change the color of a link when we hover over it.
We will specify the color to be R.G. be 170 0 0 0.
Finally let's change the color of a link when it is active or currently being clicked on by the user.
To do this we will use the active selector and give our linker color value of R G B 2 or 7 to 2 when
we run our code in the web browser.
You will see that the color of our links change when we hover over and click on the links
in the next lecture.
We will Starlight's the home page of our website.