In this lecture we will look at the many properties that CSSA gives us access to in order to style text
transforming text means to change its capitalization in some way.
CSSA gives us the text transform property which can have one of several values non capitalize uppercase
lowercase initial and inherit to see these examples of how we can modify text using CSSA.
Let's first add a paragraph element with some example text to a webpage of value of non-means that the
text capitalization will not be modified in any way.
Let's say it an opening and closing style tagged to a web page and give our paragraph the text transform
property with a value of None then we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see no special styling was applied to our text since we assigned the text to transform property
of value of None.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of capitalized will make the first letter of each word capital.
We will give our text the text transfer value of capitalized and then run our code in the web browser
as you can see the first letter in each word is capitalized.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of uppercase will make all of the letters in a text element uppercase.
We will change the text transform property to a value of uppercase and then go to the web browser and
run our code as you can see all of the letters in our text are now uppercase.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of lowercase to make all of the letters in a text element lowercase.
Let's change the text transfer value to lowercase and then run our code in the browser.
All of the letters in our text are now lowercase.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
A value of initial will change transform text back to its original state before it was modified by any
transformations.
We will assign the text transform property of value of initial and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see our text is now back to how we typed it as the content for a paragraph element.
Next let's jump back to the editor.
A value of inherit will make the text inherit the text transferred value of its parent element.
For example if the parent element has a text transform value of uppercase the child element will inherit
that value as well.
Let's say at a parent development around our current paragraph element and give it a text transform
value of uppercase We will also add a style to our code specifying the text transform of the text on
a web page to be set to lowercase.
Then we will give our child text element the value of inherit which will make it inherit the parent
elements uppercase text transform.
If we did not use the text to transform value of inherit then our text would be lowercase due to the
style that we just defined.
However due to the text transform value of inherit it will inherit the text transfer value of its parent
div.
We will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the child element has inherited the text
transfer value of its parent causing all of the letters in the text to become uppercase.
Let's jump back to the editor for the next examples.
We will put our code back to the way we had it before with one paragraph element on our Web page at
an opening and closing tag where we will add our style code.
The text decoration property allows you to underline over line and cross out text giving or text declaration
property a value of underline underlines the text.
Let's say I add the text declaration property to our style code and assign it a value of underlying.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our text is now underlined.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of Oberlin will draw a line above our text.
We will give the text decoration property of value of overlying and then run our code in the web browser
text now has an over line above it.
Let's go back to the editor of value of line through will draw a cross out through the text.
We will change the text decoration to line through and then run our code in the web browser as you can
see there is never a line through our text.
Then we will go back to the editor to get additional customization over text decoration.
We can use the more detailed properties of text decoration line text decoration color and text decoration
style using the text decoration line property.
We can combine multiple keyword values.
For example we can both underline an overlying R-Tex.
Let's use the text decoration line property and assign it a value of over line and also a value of underline.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the text is now over lines and underlined.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can also use the text decoration color property to assign a color to a text decoration.
All of the color types we learned about previously apply here.
We can specify a color name hex color or G.B. color etc..
For this example we will use the text decoration color property to make or underline an overlying the
color blue.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the text decorations are overlong and underline
are now the color blue then we will go back to the editor the text decoration style property is used
to specify the style of the line we can specify a value of solid double dashed dotted or wavy a value
of solid will draw a single line.
Let's see the text decoration style property and give it a value of solid.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of double will draw a double line.
Let's change the text decoration style property to a value of double and then run our code in the web
browser as you can see both the overlying and underline are now double lines.
Let's jump back to the editor of value of dotted will draw a dotted line.
Let's change the text decoration style to a value of dotted and then run our code as you can see the
overlay on an underline are now dotted then we will go back to the editor of value of Dasht will draw
a dashed line.
We will change the text decoration style to a value of Dasht and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see the overlying and underline are now dashed.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
A value of wavy will draw a wavy line.
We will change our text decoration style to a value of wavy and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see the on and underline are now wavy.
Let's go back to the editor.
The real fun comes in combining these three properties to get an interesting resulting line.
You are probably familiar with the red wavy underline that some text editors use to highlight misspelled
words to replicate this effect.
Let's give our paragraph element the text decoration line property with a value of underline a text
decoration color property of red and a text decoration style property of wavy.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see our text is now underlined with the red wavy line that we just created.
Let's go back to the editor.
We can you CSSA is text indent property to indent the first line in a paragraph of text.
Let's give our paragraph elements a multi-line text content then we will give our element a text indent
value of thirty pixels.
Let's run our code in the web browser as you can see the first line of our text is indented.
Then we will go back to the editor.
We can also use the letter spacing property to control how much space is between each of the letters
in a text element.
Let's use the letter spacing property to add a space of five pixels between each letter of R-Tex.
Then we will go to the web browser and run the code to see the result.
Let's jump back to the editor a positive value for the letter spacing property will increase the spacing
between characters as we saw in the last example when we gave our text a letter spacing value of 5 pixels
a negative value for the letter spacing property will decrease the spacing between characters.
Let's change the letter spacing property value to negative 5 pixels and then run our code in the web
browser as you can see.
This has greatly decreased the space between the letters and R-Tex.
In the next lecture we will learn about basic text effects we can create using CSF.