In this lecture we learn about some basic text effects that we can apply to text elements using see
SS CSSA provides us the text chattel property which allows us to add shadow behind our text for this
example we will add a paragraph element with some example text then we will add an opening and closing
style tag when using the text Chatto property.
There are two values that are required.
The first is the horizontal position of the shadow.
The second is the vertical position of the shadow.
Let's give our Chatto a horizontal position and vertical position of two pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
If we use a positive value for the horizontal position our shadow will be placed to the right of the
text.
As you can see there is now a text Chatto behind our text.
Let's go back to the editor.
If we use a negative value for the horizontal position our shadow will be positioned to the left of
our text.
Let's change the horizontal position of our text chattered in negative to and then run our code in the
web browser.
Note that the shadow is now behind our text to the left.
Let's jump back to the editor.
If we use a value of 0 for the horizontal position the shadow will align horizontally exactly with our
text.
Let's change the horizontal position of our text chatter to 0 pixels and then run our code as you can
see the shadow is now exactly vertically aligned with our text.
Then we will go back to the editor if we use a negative value for the vertical position the shadow will
move up relative to the tax.
Let's give our text a vertical position of negative 2 and then go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see our text Chatto is now vertically positioned above and behind our text.
Let's jump back to the editor if we use a positive value for the vertical position the shadow will be
positioned below the text.
We will give our text Chatto a vertical position of 4 pixels and then run our code to see the effect
as you can see our shadow now appears below the text.
Then we will go back to the editor if we use a value of zero for the vertical position the shadow will
vertically align exactly with our text.
We will change the vertical position of our text Chatto property to 0 pixels.
When we run our code in the web browser you will notice that the shadow is perfectly aligned behind
our text and not offset in any way.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We will change the horizontal and vertical positions of our text chateaus to two pixels each so that
we can see the effect of the following examples.
There are some optional values that we can assign to this property that can add some cool effects to
our text.
We can assign a color value to change the color of our shadow.
Let's give our text Chatto a color of green.
Then we will jump to the web browser and run the code
as you can see the text Chatto is green as a result of the code we typed.
Let's go back to the editor another optional value that we can specify as the blur radius which will
blur the shadow behind our text by default.
If not specified this value is equal to zero meaning that there is no blurred or artex the blur radius
is the third value that we can assign to our text Chatto property and it comes before the caller is
specified.
We will give our text Chatto a blur radius of three pixels and then run our code in the web browser
as you can see the shadow behind our text is now blurred.
Let's jump back to the editor if we want to apply multiple dropped shadows to the text.
We could do so by separating each group of values using.
For this example we will add three text chateaus to.
The first text shadow will have a horizontal position or three pixels of vertical position of two pixels
a blur radius of one pixel and a color of red.
Then we will add a comma to separate the first text châteaux we just added from the second text Chatto
that we are about to add.
Our second text Chatto will have a horizontal position of four pixels of vertical position of three
pixels a blur radius of two pixels and a color of orange.
Then we will add a comma.
Finally we will add a third text Chatto with a horizontal position of six pixels of vertical position
of four pixels a blur radius of three pixels and the color of yellow.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see.
We now have a text Chatto that blends from red to orange to yellow behind text.
Let's go back to the editor.
We can offset multiple shadows by one pixel to layer the shadows and create a 3D text effect.
We are going to add six text channels to create this 3-D effect.
First we will add awkward text Chatto with the horizontal position of one pixel of vertical position
of one pixel and the color of Aqua.
Then we will add a comma.
Our second text shadow will have a horizontal position of two pixels of vertical position of two pixels
and the color of blue followed by a comma for the third text Chatto we will add a horizontal position
of three pixels of vertical position of three pixels and the color of Aqua followed by a comma or fourth
shadow will have a horizontal position of four pixels of vertical position of four pixels and the color
of blue.
Don't forget to add a comma after the color before defining the next Chatto the fifth shadow will have
a horizontal and vertical position of five pixels and the color of Aqua.
Then we will add a comma before we add the sixth text Chatto are six then final text Chatto will have
a horizontal position of 6 pixels of vertical position of six pixels and the color of blue.
Don't forget the semi-colon at the end.
Then we will go to the web browser and write our code.
We could see our 3D text Chatto effect now on our Web page.
The key to creating an effect like this is staggering the horizontal and vertical position by one pixel
each time and layering several chateaus on top of one another in the next lecture we will learn about
fonts and see SS.