In this lecture we learn about the properties that CSSA gives us to modifying elements border the border
style property allows us to specify a style for a border assigning the property value of solid gives
our elements a solid border.
First let's say a paragraph element to our Web page and give it some example text content.
Then we relate an opening and closing style tag to our code.
We will use the paragraph element selector and give a paragraph element to border style of solid.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see our element has a solid border around it.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning the border style property a value of dotted gives our elements
a dotted border.
We will change the border style the dotted and then run our code.
As you can see our element now has a dotted border around it.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can give this property a value of double to give our elements a double border.
Let's change our border style to double.
Then we will run our code in the web browser.
You will notice that our text now has a double border around it.
Let's go back to the editor giving this property a value of Dasht will give our elements a dashed border.
Let's give our elements a border style of Dasht and then run our code as you can see our element now
has a dasht border.
Let's go back to the editor in addition to giving all four sides of the elemental border.
You can specify which sides of the border to assign a style to using the border top style border right
style border bottom style and border left style properties.
The border top style property allows us to assign a style to the top of our border.
We will use the border top style property and give it a value of Dasht.
Then we will run our code in the browser as you can see our element now has a dash top border.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
The border right style property allows us to assign a style to the right side of our border.
We will use the border right style property and give it a value of solid.
Then we will run our code as you can see the right border of our element is now solid.
Let's jump back to the other the border bottom style property allows us to assign a style to the bottom
of our border.
Let's give our element of border bottom style of double and then run our code in the browser as you
can see our element now has a double bottom border.
Then we will go back to the editor the border lovechild property allows us to assign a style to the
left of our border.
We will give our element of border left style of dotted and run our code.
You will notice that the left border of our element is dotted.
Then we will go back to the editor.
There are several 3D styles that CSSA gives us to apply to our borders.
They are groove Ridge inset and outset a the border style property value of groove gives our element
of grooved border.
Let's give our paragraph element to border style of groove in order to see the effects of these border
styles.
We need to assign a color to a border using the border color property.
We were led the border color property to our style code and assign it a value of Orange.
We will also use the border with property and give our border a with of 10 pixels.
Then we will run our code in the browser as you can see our text now as a group border around it.
Let's go back to the editor assigning the border style property value of Ridge gives our aliment a ridge
border.
We will change the border style to ridge and then run our code as you can see our element now has a
ridged border around it.
Let's jump back to the editor a signing or Borders style property value of inset gives our element and
inset border.
Let's change the border style to inset and then run our code as you can see the border around our element
is inset.
Then we will go back to the editor of value of outset that will give our element a border style of the
outset.
We will change the border style the outset and then run our code as you can see the border around our
elementis outset.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
The border with property allows you to specify a wished for a border rule change the border style the
solid in order to see the result of the next examples aside from a pixel value we can assign a border
with a thin medium or thick preset with assigning the border with property value.
Then we'll give our elements a thin border.
Let's give our elements a thin border and then run our code as you can see our element now has a thin
border.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
Assigning a border with property values medium will give our element a median border will give our element
a border with a medium and then run our code as you can see there is a medium with border around our
element.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
Assigning the border with property values thick will give our elements a thick border.
Let's give our elements a border with a thick and then write our code our element now has a thick border
around it.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can also assign a with to an individual side of our border using the border top with border right
with border bottom width and border left with properties the border top with property allows us to add
a whit to the top of an element's border.
Let's give our element of border top with him then and then run our code as you can see the top border
on our elementis.
Then let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
The border right with property allows us to add a with to the right of an element border.
Let's change that property we are using the border right with and then run our code in the browser as
you can see the width of the right border is now.
Then let's go back to the editor.
The border bottom with property allows us to add a way to the bottom of and element's border.
We will use the border bottom with property and assign it a value within and then run our code as you
can see the bottom border of our element has a whistle.
And let's jump back to the editor the border left with property allows us to add with to the left of
an elements border.
We will change the property we are using the border left with and then run our code in the web browser
as you can see the width of our left border is then.
Then we will go back to the editor CSSA gives us the border style property which is a shorthand property
that allows us to assign a with style and color to a border all at once.
We will use the border property and specify a border to be thick solid and red then we will go to the
web browser and run our code as you can see our element has a solid thick red border around it.
Let's jump back to the editor the border radious property allows us to make the corners of our border
rounded to the radius that we specify We will use the border radius property and give it a value of
three pixels.
Then we will run our code in the browser as you can see our border now has round corners.
Let's go back to the editor.
Also we can specify a radius for each corner separately if we choose.
In that case each value separated by a space and the order is top left top right bottom right and bottom
left.
We will give our border radius the following values to pixels for pixels 8 pixels and 16 pixels as you
can see from the top left going clockwise the corners of our element get progressively rounder.
Let's go back to the editor the border image source property allows us to specify a custom image for
a border.
We will use the border image source property and give it a source of our example border PAGG image.
We will also give our element a border with of 10 pixels and a border style of solid.
Then we will run our code in the browser
as you can see our border now has a custom image as its source.
Let's go back to the editor the border image slice property enables us to specify how the source image
is sliced and displayed.
We will use the border image slice property and give it a value of 30 then we will run our code in the
browser.
You will notice how our image was sliced according to the value that we gave the border image sliced
property.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
Border image with allows us to give our border image with.
Let's give our border image a with of 20 pixels.
We will use the border image with property and give it a value of 20 pixels.
Then we will run our code in the browser as you can see our border image has a wealth of 20 pixels.
Let's go back to the editor the border image outset property allows us to specify an amount for the
border image to extend outside of the bounds of an element border.
We will give our border image and outset of 10 pixels and run our code in the browser as you can see
our border images now outset by 10 pixels.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
The border image repeat property lets us specify how the image will fill the space the border image
repeat property can have a value of Strach repeat round or space assigning the bore image repeat property
of value of Strach will make the image stretch to fill the area.
We will use the border image repeat property and give it a value of stretch and then we will run our
code in the web browser as you can see our border image is now stretched.
Let's go back to the editor giving the border image Ropeik property a value of repeat will make the
image tile to fill the border area.
Let's change the value of the border image repeat property to repeat then we will go to the web browser
and run our code as you can see the border image is never repeated.
Let's go back to the editor of value of roundel rescale the border image so that it fills the border
area.
We will give our element of border image repeat value of around and then run our code as you can see
our border image now fills the border area.
Let's jump back to the editor Ossining the border image repeat property value of space will add space
to abort border image so that it fills the full space of the border.
Let's change the border image repeat property to space and then run our code to see the result.
The border image properties are shorthand property that allows us to specify the source slice with outset
and repeat values of a border.
In the next lecture we will learn about the box properties that CSSA gives us access to.