In this lecture we will create the hetter bar for a web page.
We will have a roll of images across the top of the page and a row of links underneath the images that
the user can click to jump to different sections on our Web page.
First let's create the role of images across the top of the page.
We will add our images inside of our div.
Let's put the image tag for our first image.
Let's say the source attribute to our image tag and assign it a value of icon that PAGG another mandatory
attribute of the image tag is the all too attribute.
Before we run our code in the browser to see our image displayed let's add some styles to it.
We will add the style attribute to our image tag and give our image a right margin of 10 percent left
margin of 5 percent a height of 300 pixels and a width of 300 pixels.
OK so now we can run our code in the browser and check the result of the code we have so far.
If all goes well we should see our image in the top left corner of our webpage.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
Let's make the background of our Web page black by adding the style attribute to the opening body tag
and giving it a background color of black.
Time to add our second image.
We will add another image tagged to our webpage.
This image will be the logo of our pizza parlor and will be displayed in the top middle of our webpage.
The source of this image will be the logo.
PFG file the all the attributes for this image will have a value of Logo.
Finally we will add the style attribute to this image.
We will give the image your right margin of 10 percent a width of 300 pixels and a height of 300 pixels.
Let's run the code in the browser and see our image
then we will jump back to the editor.
The third image that we will add to our Web page will be a just open sign.
We will add an image tag and give it a source attribute with a value of our just open to TNG image the
all the attribute for this image will have a value of just opened for the style.
We will give our image a height of 200 pixels in a width of five hundred pixels.
Let's run our code in the web browser and see our third image appear on our Web page.
Then we will jump back to the editor OK.
Now we have our three images across the top of our webpage.
The next step is to create the navigation menu that the user can use to navigate to the different parts
of our web page or web site.
We'll have a total of four links home about us menu and contact.
Let's create a map that we can use as a container for our menu.
Recall that a nav element is used to create a navigation menu of links on an HDMI web page.
We will add in for length tags one for each section on our website.
We will add an 8 track attribute to each of our linked tags.
The value will be hash tag forward slash and then the name of the section the name of the section will
be the idea that we give to the div that contains the material for that section of the page.
The hash tag forward slash will keep the page from jumping when it transitions from one section to another.
Each of our links will have a class value of menu items which we can use to easily reference them and
stylize them later on.
We will give our NAV element an idea of Hetter.
Finally we will add the style attribute to our header.
We will give our NAV options of font size of two VW.
A position of relative a top value of 25 percent a width of 100 percent and aleft value of 20 percent.
Finally let's say at a div is a container for each section of our Web page.
We will also add a style element to our code.
It will specify that each element in the menu items class will have a right margin of 10 percent.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code as you can see the four links now appear on our Web page
in the next lecture we will create a home page for our Web site.