In this lecture we will learn about coloring elements and HMO.
Now that we know the different ways we can specify color and HMO.
Let's take a look at how we can apply this knowledge to color elements in each GMO.
First let's create a paragraph element which will be the text that we use for these examples.
Next let's add an opening and closing style tag to our Web page inside of our style tags.
We will apply a style to a paragraph tag setting the color to blue
then we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see the text is displayed blue.
Let's go back to the editor.
This is just one example of how we can identify colors by name as we looked at in the last video.
If we change the color name from blue to red.
You will see that the text is then displayed the color red and the web browser.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code
noticed that the text color change to red.
Now let's go back to the editor next.
Let's look at how we would color our text using an R G B value.
Recall that our GBI stands for red green blue and that we can assign each of these parameters a value
from 0 to 255 to specify a color as our G-B we first type letters R.G. be followed by opening and closing
parentheses inside of the parentheses.
We put the RGV values separated by commas.
In this example we have given the green parameter a value of 255 and the red and blue parameters a value
of zero.
So our text will display the color green.
We will go to the web browser and run our code
noticed that the text is the color green based on the org B value that we specify.
Let's go back to the editor.
Let's add to this example by using Orji be a first Add the letter A to the R G B function name making
the name or G-B A.
Next we will specify an alpha value from zero point zero to 1 point zero.
Let's make our text 50 percent transparent by assigning this parameter a value of 0.5.
Finally we will go to the web browser and run our code to see these changes
as you can see the text is displayed at 50 percent opacity.
Let's go back to the editor.
Recall that we can also specify color using hex values to do so we first need to put a hash tag or a
pound symbol.
Next we are going to put an R R G G B B value.
Each color is specified as a number from 0 0 to f f to make our text magenta.
Let's give it blue and red parameters a value of f f and it's green parameter a value of zero zero.
Let's go to the web browser and run this code as you can see the text is displayed the color magenta
then we will jump back to the editor.
We can also add an alpha value from 0 0 to F-F the value halfway between the two is 8 0 which will give
our text and opacity of 50 percent.
We add this 80 to the end of our hex color value.
Let's go to the browser and run our code
as you can see the text is displayed at 50 percent opacity.
Then we will jump back to the editor.
Let's now look at an example of using HSLDA specify a color for artex.
Recall that HSF stands for hue saturation lightness the hue is the color value.
The saturation is the color intensity and the lightness is the amount of light or dark in the color.
In this example we will make our text a dark red color.
First we need to type a call to the H S L function with opening and closing parentheses.
Then we will add the h s n l parameters.
Let's make the hue of value of 0 to set the color to red.
Then we will make desaturation 100 percent to make the color as intense as possible.
Finally we will add a lightness value of 30 percent which will make the Red Dark remember the larger
the lightness percentage be assigned here the lighter the color is we will go to the web browser and
run this code
as you can see the text is displayed a saturated dark red color.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
We can also add an alpha of value to specify an HSA L.A. color.
In other words hue saturation lightness alpha this alpha value will be supplied as a value from zero
point zero to one point zero.
For this example we will give our text an alpha value of 0.4 or 40 percent opaque.
Once you make these changes we will run our code in the web browser.
As you can see our text is now only partially opaque due to the Alpha value we added.
Note that these Kulish specifications can apply to any color attribute not just text color.
We can supply an R G B R-Ga. h s l h SLA hex color or color name tach beach like background color border
color etc..
In the next lecture we will recap what we learned in this section.