In this lecture we will learn about how we can add colors to our lists using C Ss we can add the background
color to the whole list by specifying the UL or all elements depending on whether we are using an unwanted
list or an ordered less.
Next we will go to the web browser and run our code then we will go back to the editor and look at another
example.
We can also add a background color to only the list elements by specifying that the background color
be applied to the elements using the ally tag.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
Let's jump back to the editor if they were ordered and unordered lists on your web page you can specify
which styles apply to the list items of one versus the other.
You do so by first specifying if the list is ordered to ordered and then specifying that the style should
be applied to the list items of that type.
Next we will go to the web browser and run our code
in the next lecture.
We will look at a recap of what we learned in this section.