In this lecture we will learn about the different units that CSF gives us for expressing the size of
our elements.
There are two types of sizes that we can work with in CSSA absolute and relative an absolute length
is a fixed unit that will make an element display the exact size specified a relative length takes into
account factors like viewport size when scaling an element.
When programming web pages for the computer it is best to use a relative length so that users viewing
the web page on different sized screens can see the elements at the proper proportions.
Let's go over absolute length.
First we will look at the units from smallest to largest in that order the absolute length units that
CSSA gives us access to our pixels point millimeters peakers centimeters and inches.
First we had a paragraph element with some example text.
Next we will give our paragraph element a style attribute the style will specify a font size in pixels.
In this example we will give our element a font size of one pixel.
The abbreviation for pixels in CSSA is p x.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code to see the result.
As you can see the result is very very small text on our Web page.
Let's jump back to the editor if we change the font size to one point you will notice the increase in
size.
The abbreviation for points and CSSA is Peetie.
We will go to the web browser and what are called as you can see the text is slightly larger than the
last size.
This is because points are slightly larger and pixels.
Let's go back to the editor.
Next up is millimeters which are larger than points.
The abbreviation for millimeters and CSSA is Amam.
We will change our code to give our text the size of one millimeter.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
The text this time is larger and more readable.
Let's go back to the editor after that come peakers which are larger than millimeters.
The abbreviation for peakers and CSSA is PC.
Let's change the unit of our font size to peakers and then run our code in the web browser.
At this point you will notice a considerable difference in the size of the text.
Let's go back to the editor then come centimeters which are larger than peakers the abbreviation for
centimeters and CSSA is S.M. we will change the unit of our font size to CM and then run our code in
the web browser.
Now you will notice that our taxes even larger than before.
Let's go back to the editor.
Finally we have inches which are larger than centimeters.
The abbreviation for inches and CSSA is an inch is the largest absolute length that CSSA provides us.
We will change the unit in our code to inches and then run our code in the web browser.
Let's jump back to the editor
and that's it for our absolute length CSSA unit.
Now it's time to go over the relative length c SS units that we can use to specify an element size in
terms of relative sizes we can specify units and E M E X S.H. R.E.M. VW VH the men the max and percent
and E-M is relative to the font size of an element say that we have a div with some text inside of it.
Then we have a span inside of our day with some more text inside of it.
We will give our div a font size of 10 pixels using the style attribute and then give our span a font
size of AM
when we run our code you will notice that the text in our span is twice as large as the text in Argive.
This is because we gave it a font size of Chewey which means two times the current font size.
Since the current font size is 10 pixels the spam's text is displayed at a size of twenty pixels.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
One rarely used unit in CSSA is the x unit.
This unit is based on the size of the lower case X in whatever font we use.
If we change the M in E-M from our last example to an X and run our code you will notice the change
in size.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Another relative font unit S.H. bases its size on the number 0 in a font.
C-h stands for character.
If we change our code to have a font size of two S.H. you will see the alteration in font size of font
size of two S.H. means that the size will be twice the size of the number zero character in the font
we are using.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code
then we will jump back to the editor.
The relative unit R.E.M. says the font size based on the font size of the web page R.E.M. stands for
a root E-M it bases the size around the size of the root element.
If the body element on a web page has a size of 10 pixels and we give our text inspanned text the font
size of R.E.M. the size of our div and span text will be 400 pixels.
We will go to the web browser and run our code
then we will jump back to the editor of VW Stenstrom viewport with unit 1 VW is equivalent to 1 percent
of the viewport.
So if we change our divin span to have a font size of VW or font size will be based on 4 percent of
the viewport width.
Let's run our code in the web browser or see the result
then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
Of the H stands for a viewport height Unit 1 VHS equivalent to 1 percent of the viewport height.
So if we change our div and span to have a font size of 4 VH or font size will be based on 4 percent
of the viewport height we will jump to the web browser and run our code to see the result.
Then we will go back to the editor the for a viewport minimum and this relative unit is based on either
the height or width of the viewport.
Whichever one is smaller if we change our font size unit to the men and run our code you will notice
the change in font size
then we will go back to the editor the max stands for viewport maximum and this relative unit is also
based on the height and width of the viewport.
Whichever one is larger if we change your font size unit to the max and run our code you will notice
the change in font size.
Let's go back to the editor.
The final relative unit that CSSA gives us access to is percent the percent value is relative to the
size of the percent element.
Let's give our development the font size of 100 pixels since our span element is a child of the div
we could specify a percentage that we want it to be relative to the divs size specifying a size of 50
percent will make our span font size 50 pixels.
Half of the font size of its parent element we will go to the web browser and run our code as we can
see the text in our span is now half the size of the text in the parent element in this lecture we covered
the units that CSF gives us to specify sizes for elements in the next lecture.
We will recap what we learned in this section of the course.