In this lecture we will learn about some CSSA rules.
What they do and how to use them.
We have already seen that keyframes rule in action when we created animations in previous sections using
SS that character that rule is used to define the character set used for that particular style sheet.
Usually you will be using the UTF 8 character set.
There are a few peculiarities that you should be aware of when using this rule.
It has to be the first element at the very top of your style sheet and can't have any characters before
it.
It also must have double quotes around its value.
Only one space between the rule and the value and have a semi-colon right after the last double quote.
This rule also has to be directly on a CSSA style sheet and not embedded inside of the style tags and
in HVM file.
Here's an example of a valid care said declaration or rather at rule that we can use in CSSA is import.
This rule is used to import styles from another style sheet for use in this style sheet just like we
can link CSSA files to HGL files.
So yes as files can also be linked to other CSSA files using the import app rule one peculiarity to
be careful of the ordering of these rules.
If your stylesheet uses both the carer set an important rule the carousel rule comes first and then
the import rule comes next.
If your stylesheet just uses an import rule but no Chrisette rule the import rule needs to come before
any other styles that you specify.
Another usual CSSA rule is the font face out rule which allows us to import fonts to use in our stylesheet.
This rule saves us from depending on only font files that users have on their computers.
This rule gives us the ability to import fonts from online and also from our local machine.
The font family lets us specify a name for our font.
The source property lets us specify that you are l where the font is located.
Note that these are just some of the rules that CSSA gives us.
However many of the other rules have very specific use cases in the next lecture.
We will look at a recap of what we learned in this section.