In this lecture we will learn how to use HVM to embed video into our webpage.
HDMI allows us to embed video into our web pages TED video to your web page use the video tag.
We will start by getting an opening and closing video tag to our code.
We will specify a web for video using the with attribute of the video tag.
Next we will specify the height of our video using the height attribute.
We will also add a source element inside the video tags as this will reference the video file of the
video to be shown.
HVM supports three types of video.
MP for webcam and old Gigi we need to specify the type as well.
We can do this by adding the type attribute to our source element and giving it a value of video forward
slash whatever type of video we are using.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the video is embedded into our web page.
Let's jump back to the editor and build on this example.
The videotape has several attributes that we can set if we want the user to be able to pause and play
the video as well as make it full screen cetera.
We can add the controls attribute to the opening video tag then we will go to the web browser and run
our code as you can see there are now controls on our video.
Let's jump back to the editor
if you want the video to automatically play once the web page is loaded.
You can add the auto play attribute to the opening video tag.
Let's say the auto play attribute to the opening video tag and then run our code in the browser.
Make sure to run this code in Firefox as Google Chrome has disabled the auto play attribute as you can
see the video starts playing as soon as the web page loads.
Since we used to auto play attribute.
Let's jump back to the editor
if we want the video to start over each time it is finished and automatically loop we can add the loop
attribute to our openings video tag.
Let's say the loop attribute to the opening video tag and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see once the video finishes playing it automatically replays since we had the loop attribute
to the opening video tag.
Let's jump back to the editor
if we want to play the video without any audio.
We can use the muted attribute.
We had the muted attribute to the opening video tag just like we did for the other attributes we added.
If we want to show an image before the user clicks play on the video we can use the poster attribute
the poster attribute takes a value of the source of our image.
Let's use the poster attribute and give it a value V-Star star PMG image.
We will also remove the auto play attribute so that our video doesn't start playing as soon as the web
page loads when we run our code.
You will notice that the star images displayed
Let's jump back to the editor we can use the preload attribute to specify how the video should be preloaded.
There are three possible values that we can assign to the pre-load attribute.
If we set the preload attribute to Ortal the browser will load the entire video on the web page loads.
If we set the preload attribute to metadata the browser will only pre-load the videos metadata when
the web page loads.
We can also set the preload attribute to none so that the browser doesn't pre-load the video and the
web page loads the web page will wait to load the video until the user actually clicks the play button.
If our video does not load for whatever reason we can display fallback text to the user.
We do this by adding text inside of our opening and closing video tags or such from any video files
to our Web page.
It is also possible for us to embed YouTube videos into our Web page embedding YouTube videos into our
web page as opposed to video files has the advantage that you don't have to convert your videos into
different file format every YouTube video has a YouTube video ID we can use this idea to reference a
YouTube video to embedded into our webpage.
In order to display a YouTube video on our Web page we can use the I-frame element.
Let's add an opening and closing I-frame tag to our code.
We will give our I-frame a width of 1000 a height of 500.
We will also add the source attribute to the opening I-frame tag and specify that you are Alef the video
we want to embed in our web page.
The source attribute will have YouTube's you R-AL forward slash embed forward slash the youtoo by D.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the YouTube video is embedded into
our webpage
adding attributes like auto play and loop to our YouTube videos is a bit different than adding them
to our video files that we embed with the video tag in order to understand how to add these attributes
to the YouTube videos embed you are all we need to quickly review query string parameters a query string
parameter is a piece of information appended to the end of a URL.
It consists of a variable and equal sign and a value.
The first query string parameter will have a question mark in front of it.
Any additional query string parameters will be separated by an ampersand.
There are four such attributes that YouTube supports.
Auto play controls loop and playlists.
Let's look at the auto play attribute first.
We had a question mark followed by auto play equals 1 to tell the video to play as soon as the web page
loads a value of zero for this attribute would explicitly specify that the video not auto play when
the web page loads we will have to run this example in Firefox to see the result.
As you can see the video starts playing as soon as the web page loads.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
We can also add controls to let the user be able to have controls like play pause in large etc. giving
the controls attribute a value of 1 specify that the user should be shown video controls.
Note that this is the default option.
If a value of 0 is assigned to the controls attribute this specifies that the user should not have controls.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code as you can see there are controls on our video.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can use the loop attribute combined with the playlist attribute to play videos one after another.
The playlist attribute allows us to specify other videos to play after this video ends.
We separate these video ideas by commune's lets use the playlist attribute and specify other videos
to play after this video.
Then we will run our code in the browser to see the result.
In the next lecture we will learn how to embed audio into a web page using H T-Mo.