In this lecture we learn about what HTL tags are in a variety of tags that we have access to an HMO
h female Tadg are the most fundamental concept of HVM L and they are used in all aspects of the language.
Tags are the building blocks that each female uses to define the content to be shown on the web page
a text starts with an opening angular bracket followed by the tag name and finally a closing on Guler
bracket.
Each team has a finite number of tags that can be used which are predefined by the language.
The more of these tags you know in use the more you will be able to do with HVM L..
In most cases tags come in pairs where the first tag is called the Start Tag or opening tag and the
second tag is called the end tag or closing tag ending tags include a forward slash before the tag name.
In between the opening tag and closing tag is the content of the tag.
Let's take a look at some of the most basic and important tags that Mail gives us access to allowing
us to define web content.
The paragraph tag is used to display text and the tag uses the letter P inside of angular brackets to
use the paragraph tag.
We put an opening P-TECH the text content we want to be displayed on our Web page and then a closing
tag.
If we go to a web browser and click and drag in each tremelo file that we just typed.
You should see the text that you added using the paragraph tag displayed on the web page.
Let's go back to the editor and learn about the image tag the image tag is used to display an image
and the tag uses the letters.
I MGE inside of angular brackets.
For example if we have to start PLG image in the same directory as our h him out file we are typing
in these examples.
We can specify the name of the source file.
In this case to be start PLG note that the image tags specifies the source inside and the tag itself
and does not use a closing tag.
We will go back to a web browser and dragging our each team out file to see the image displayed on our
Web page.
Let's jump over to the editor and learn about the input tag the input tag allows the user to input text
to our Web page.
It consists of the word input inside of angular brackets and has no end tag inside of the tag we specify
the type of input which in most cases will be text.
We can go back to our browser and run this code to see our text input field appear on the web page
we can click into the input field and type text using the keyboard that we will see displayed inside
of the input field as we type it.
Let's go back to the editor and look at HVM else.
Title tag the title tag defines the title for the document which is displayed in the toolbar of the
browser.
The title won't be shown on the page itself.
Just up on the tab at the top of the browser the title tag also has a closing tag.
We will go to the browser and drag the HTL file over.
Now we should see the title at the top of the browser or on the tab.
Let's go back to the editor and look at the next example.
The body text specifies the main content of the HVM l document.
It includes a closing tag to define where the body of the document ends.
The video tag is used to embed video clips or streams into the web page.
It includes an ending tag the source tag allows us to specify a movie file source and type to be used
as the content of the video tags the source tag does not use a closing tag.
We will start our source tag and give it a source attribute with a value of movie clip that MP for the
way that we can use the video and movie tags together is to first have the video tags and then put in
the source tag in between the opening and closing video tags as the content in our own course resource
files.
We have an MP for a file called movie clip that MP for
then we will give our source taga type attribute with a value of video.
Forward slash MP for to run this example.
Make sure that you have the movie clip that MP for file in the same directory as your HVM code.
Let's jump to the web browser and drag each team file to see the result.
We will go back to Visual Studio code and learn about the DIV tag the DIV tag is one of the most diverse
and important tags in HMO.
It allows us to define our own sections of each team all documents making it very useful and flexible.
The div tag includes a closing tag later in the course you will see or div tags can become especially
useful to us when we start styling our elements using CSX HQ Mail gives us access to 6 heading tags
numbered 1 3 6 that allow us to create heading text for our web pages each heading take has an opening
and closing tag.
Each of these heading tags has a default size defined by each DML with the H-1 tag being the biggest
and the each six tag being the smallest.
We will go back to our web browser and drag over the HMS file to run the code.
You can see the six different sizes that these headings are by default.
These are just some of the tags that HQ Mail gives us access to during this course.
You will be exposed to a massive amount of tags that the language provides to display various content
and how we can combine these tags to create interesting dynamic and responsive web content.
In the next lecture we will learn about the format of an HMO document.