In this lecture we will learn about the syntax of Exige to your mail.
It really isn't all that different from H.T. M-L except it is stricter.
The first step in writing and SH team all document is to add the doc type as the first line of the page
inside of the opening HTL tagging the HDMI layout and the x M L and S attribute the XM L and S attribute
specifies an ex-MIL namespace for the document ensure that all elements are properly closed and nested
also change all attribute and element names to lowercase.
Use the id attribute instead of the name attribute.
Finally make sure all attribute values have quotes around them.
This means that boolean attributes like enabled or disabled are written with their value enclosed in
quotes.
In the next lecture we will learn how to convert each DML code to Exige DML code.