In this lecture we will learn about positioning elements using C Ss to position elements in C Ss.
We can use the Position property.
There are five main types of positioning and C Ss static relative fixed absolute and stickie by default
elements are positioned statically.
The top right bottom and left properties do not affect statically positioned element statically positioned
elements do not have any special type of positioning to see these examples.
Let's add a paragraph element to a web page and give it some example text.
Then we will add our style code.
We will start with an opening and closing style tag and use the elements selector to apply the style
to a paragraph element.
Let's give our element the Position property with a value of static.
To illustrate the effect of having a position of static we will give our elements the top property with
a value of five hundred pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you will notice the top value of 500 pixels has
no effect on our element.
Since we specified it's position is static.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can also position elements using relative positioning.
We can use the top bottom left and right properties to offset the element from its normal position.
Let's change the position property on our element to have a value of relative and then go to the web
browser and run our code as you can see the top value of 500 pixels now has an effect on our paragraph
element offsetting it 500 pixels on top from its original position.
Let's jump back to the editor giving an element a position effect that makes it stay in the same place
on the page.
We used the top bottom left and right properties to assign a position to the element.
Let's give our element a fixed position and also give it a top value of 100 pixels and a left value
of 100 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see our text now is a fixed position of 100 pixels less and 100 pixels down on the webpage.
Let's jump back to the editor if we give the position property value of absolute the element will be
positioned relative to its first ancestor element that is not static.
To start off this example let's say a div to our code that will function as the parent for a paragraph
element.
Then we will move our paragraph element between the opening and closing div tags making it a child's
var div.
Let's give our div a position of relative and the top value of 100 pixels.
Then we will give our paragraph element a position of absolute and the top value of 100 pixels.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see the example text or paragraph element was positioned 100 pixels below each parent div
based on the value of 100 pixels we specified.
And the fact that we gave it a position value of absolute Let's jump back to the editor a position of
stickie will make our elements position be controlled by the user scrolling on the page the element
will be relatively positioned until the user starts to scroll past it.
Then the element will stick to the top of the page even as the user scrolls down.
Essentially stickie positioning is a combination between relative positioning and fixed positioning.
Let's say a development to our webpage then we will add several paragraph elements to our webpage so
that there is enough content to force the browser to give us a scroll bar to scroll through our content.
We can do this by copying and pasting the paragraph element several times.
Then let's say the style code for this example we will give our development a position of stickie and
a top value of 0 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
When you scroll down on the web page you will notice that the div content sticks to the top of the page
and displays over the other text on the webpage.
Let's jump back to the editor to specify which elements render on top of other elements we can use the
z index property for this example we will add two divs to our webpage.
We will give our first different idea of blue div and our second give an idea of green div.
Then we will add code to style or two divs.
Let's start with an opening and closing style tag between which we will write our style code.
Let's write the style code for our blue div.
We will give our blue DiVall with 150 pixels and a height of 150 pixels.
Then we will give our blue div a blue background.
We will also give it a position of absolute and Aleft value of 0 pixels.
Next That's right the style code for our green div we will give our DiVall width and height of 150 pixels.
Then we will assign a background color of green.
We will also give it a position of absolute last value of 20 pixels this 20 pixel less value is to offset
our Green did from our blue div since our green there was a find in our code after a blue div.
It will be displayed on top of the blue div to confirm this.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our green div is on top of our blue div.
Then we will go back to the editor if we want to control which element displays on top.
We could use the z index property.
Let's give our blue divisi index of 1.
And our green div is the index of 0.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see our blue div is now on top of our green div.
This is because we gave it a higher z index in the next lecture.
We will learn about grids and positioning and CSSA for Responsive Web design.