In this lecture we will learn about the column properties that CSSA allows us to animi the column properties
we can animate using CSSA or column count column gap column rule column rule color column rule with
column with and columns for this example we are going to animate the column count property.
We will create an animation that breaks a large block of text up into several columns across our webpage.
Next let's say at a block of text in a div that we can animi the key point here is that we will add
enough text so that the web browser is able to split it into columns.
After that we will add an opening and closing style tag.
We will stylize our development giving it a column count of 1 and an animation of column and with a
duration of two seconds and make it loop using the infinite keyword.
After that let's write the code for our animation we will cool our animation column and we will specify
that the column count go from 1 to 5.
When we run the animation you will notice that the text divides itself into columns.
If it divides itself into less than five columns that means that there is enough text in the div to
be subdivided and you need to add more text for the animation to have the desired effect.
In the next lecture we will learn about the margin properties that CSSA allows us to animate.