In this lecture we will learn some cool ways that we can stylize our table if you want to highlight
a row in the table when you use your mouse over the row.
You can use the hover selector.
We will use the hover selector on our table rows and specify the background color to be yellow if the
mouse cursor is hovering over a row in our table to see this effect.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code
when we hover over the rows in our table.
You will notice that they turn yellow.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can also make our table striped by alternating the background color of the table rows using the end
trialed selector.
We can use that even and odd keywords with the nth child selector to specify that a style be applied
to each table row with an even or odd number.
Let's take a look at how we could change the background color to blue of each odd row in the table.
First we specify t r to tell CSSA that we want this style to apply to our table row element.
Then we specify the selector and pass in a value to the parentheses.
In this case we will specify the odd keyword.
Finally we will specify that we want to add a background color of blue to any table row that meets these
qualifications to complete our zebra striped defect.
We will add a color of aqua to all that even table rows.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
You will notice that the odd rows in our table have a background color of blue and they even rows in
our table have a background color of Aqua.
Let's go back to the editor.
We can also specify a role of a particular number using the nth child selector instead of passing in
the even or odd keywords.
You can pass in a number of the role that you want to apply the style to if we want to stylize the first
row.
For instance we could pass in the number one.
We will put the number one inside of the parentheses and specify that the background color of the first
table roll be set to red.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see the background color of the first row in our table is red in the next lecture.
We will look at a recap of what we learned in this section.