In this lecture we will start like the About Us page.
First we are going stylize our list.
Let's go to our about us live inside of which is our unordered list.
We will give our unordered list a class of about lists then we will add the class attribute to our list
element and assign them a value of about list element.
Now let's go to the style section of our code.
We will add the following styles to our About list class element.
We will assign our about lists class a list style type of square which will change the circular bullet
points to square.
We will also assign our class a background color of dark red.
Then we will add styles to our About list element class will give the elements of our class a background
color of crimson and a margin of 8 pixels.
Next let's run our code in the browser and click the About Us link on our Web page to see the result
of the code we just typed.
Then we will jump back to the editor.
The other thing we are going to do to stylize or about us page is to make the text on the bottom flash
the colors of the rainbow.
To do this we will go up again to our about div and find the text element we will give our element an
idea of description text.
Next let's write the code for animation we will call our animation description then our keyframes will
go in 15 percent increments.
Going from 0 percent to 90 percent.
So our keyframes will be 0 percent 15 percent 30 percent 45 percent 60 percent 75 percent and 90 percent.
The colors of the rainbow are red orange yellow green blue indigo and violet.
Each of which will correspond to one of these keyframes.
Finally we just need to link the animation to our text element.
We can use the idea of description text that we gave it as the selector specifying the animation attribute
with an animation name of description and a duration of four seconds and the infinite keyword will link
our animation to the text when we run our code in the browser and could be about us link on our Web
page we should see the text on the bottom of our Web page animi cycling through the colors of the rainbow.
And the next lecture.
We will stylize the menu page for our website.