In this section we learned about the global attributes that can be applied to NEHTA male element.
First we looked at the global attributes added in prior versions of HVM all the access key attribute
lets us assign a key on the keyboard to activate or focus an element the class attribute allows us to
specify a class that are each element belongs to we use the DIR attribute to specify a direction for
the contents of our element.
The Lang attribute lets us specify what language the content of the element is in the style attribute
allows us to stylize our element the tab index attribute allows us to specify the tab order for an element
the title attribute lets us provide additional information about an element displayed when the user
mouse is over an element.
After that we learned about global attributes that were added as of HVM L5 the content editable attribute
allows us to specify our element is editable or not that context menu attribute allows us to create
a context menu that will appear when we right click on an element we can embed custom data into our
HMO elements using the data attribute the draggle attribute allows us to specify whether or not an element
distractible to hide an element we can use the hidden attribute the spellcheck attribute allows us to
have the contents of our elements spellcheck The translate attribute specifies whether or not an element
is allowed to be translated into another language in the next section.
We will learn about events in each T.M..