In this lecture we will learn about saturation and how we can use the SS code to specify levels of saturation
for our images.
Saturation refers to the intensity or amount of pigment in a color highly saturated colors are brighter
than less saturated colors.
The CSA has saturate function allows us to modify the saturation of an image by supplying this function
a high value.
We can make the colors in the image more intent increasing its saturation by calling misfunction with
a low value we can make the image colors less intense or less saturated.
To assign a saturation to our image we use the CSSA filter property and assign a value of the saturate
function.
Let's add an image element to our Web page and give it a source of our icon PMG image.
Then we will get an opening and closing style tag to our code.
We will assign our image the filter property and use the saturate function to make the saturation of
our image 100 percent.
Note that 100 percent is the default value and that this is how the image normally looks without any
modification.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code to see the result.
Then we will jump back to the editor
if we specify a saturation less than 100 percent our image will become less saturated.
Let's change the saturation of our image to 50 percent then we will go to the web browser and run our
code.
As you can see our image is less saturated than before.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
Let's change the saturation of our image to 200 percent.
Doing so will greatly increase the saturation of our image.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code
as you can see the image is much more saturated.
Note that the tan color of our characters face and hands is now a very intense yellow.
Then we will go back to the editor.
We can supply the saturation as an integer value of float or decimal value or a percent.
If we want to supply an integer value for the saturation one is the default value of 100 percent saturation.
Let's change our code to pass in the integer value 1 to the saturate function and then run our code
in the web browser to see the result.
As you can see our image is at 100 percent saturation.
Let's go back to the editor
passing in a value less than one.
For example a value of zero will decrease the saturation of our image.
Let's give our image a saturation of 0 and then run our code in the browser to see the result.
As you can see our image now has no saturation.
Let's jump back to the editor
if we passed desaturate function an integer value greater than 1.
It will increase the saturation of our image.
Let's change our code to make the saturation of our image 3 and then go to the web browser and run our
code.
As you can see the saturation of our image has been dramatically increased.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can pass a decimal value to the saturate function as well.
Let's change the value in our code to point zero and then run our code in the web browser.
As you can see our image is back to full saturation passing in a value of 1 point zero is the same as
passing in a value of 100 percent or an integer value of 1.
Let's go back to the editor.
If we pass desaturate function a decimal value less than 1.0 it will decrease the saturation of our
image.
Let's change the saturation of our image to 0.3.
Then we will go to the web browser and run the code to see the result of this change.
Observe that the image is a lot less saturated than before.
Let's jump back to the editor passing a float value greater than one point zero will increase the saturation
of our image.
Let's give our image of saturation value of 1.6 and then run our code into the web browser as you can
see the image is now over 100 percent saturation.
Using the filter property and saturate function allows us to have control over the saturation of the
images on our Web page in the next lecture.
We were learn about opacity and how we can control in images opacity using CSSA code.