In this section we learned about CSSA at rules CSSA gives us several at rules that each do something
different for style sheet.
We learned that an app rule specifies how a style sheet should behave.
The basic syntax of an app rule is the at symbol followed by a keyword that is the rule.
There are two main types of rules.
Regular rules and nested rules.
Regular rules have a syntax of an at symbol keyword and semi-colon.
Nested rules have a syntax of a symbol keyword and then an additional block of statements.
After that we got hands on experience using some of the rules that CSSA provides us.
We learned that the carousel at rule is used to define the character set for a particular stylesheet.
The import rule is used to import a style sheet into another stylesheet.
Then we looked at the font face at rule which allows us to import fonts from either online or a local
computer to use and our style sheets in the next section we will learn about some advanced styling techniques
we can use and in SS.