In this section we learned about debugging CSSA code in order to ensure that the elements on our page
are stylized properly.
We need to make sure that we write valid error free CSSA code.
First we learned about common CSSA errors and how to fix them.
The common CSSA errors that we looked at are missing semi-colon invalid declaration and invalid selector
a missing semi-colon between declarations in our CSSA can be problematic an invalid declaration will
cause the property to have no effect on the specified element.
If there is an invalid selector in our code the entire block of styles which is supposed to apply to
one or more elements will be invalid and will not be used to stylize any elements on our webpage.
We looked at examples of each of these errors and how we can fix them.
After that we learned how to check our CSSA code for errors by using a CSSA validator.
The Worldwide Web Consortium has a CSSA validator that we can use to check our code for syntax errors
just like the HVM validator the CSSA validator is an important tool that you should use frequently when
developing web pages in the next section.
We will look at some advanced and useful CSSA features.