In this lecture we will learn about what each team validator is and how we can use it to help us find
and fix errors in our HMO code validator is a program that we can run our files through to see if there
are any syntax errors.
This helps us to save time and energy when debugging.
Since H.E. e-mail code for an entire web site can be hundreds or even thousands of lines long depending
on the complexity of the Web site W3 see or World Wide Web Consortium is the main organization that
sets and maintains the standards for web development.
The W3 C has an online validator that we can run our code through to check it for syntax errors.
Let's open a web browser and go to HSDPA us colon slash slash validator dot W3 dot org.
You will notice that there are three options that we have for inputting or HVM all code.
If we have an online Web site that we want to check for hours we can enter that you R-AL into the address
input field.
If we click on the second tab validate file by upload you will notice that we can upload a file from
our computer that the validator will check for syntax errors.
We actually do have a file that we can run through the HTL validated to check for errors.
A slight variation to the hands on each G-mail web page we wrote a few seconds back I intentionally
added a few errors that we could debug for this example.
Let's hit the Choose file button find and select the file from our computer and then hit open then we
will hit the check button.
If we don't have any errors in our code Chimo validator will tell us that no errors were found.
If there are any warnings or errors for the file we input the validator will point out the error as
well as the line number.
As you can see there were some errors found in our HCM file.
Let's go through and solve these errors one by one.
The first error is that the head element is missing a required instance of the child element.
Title.
What this means is that we need to add a title element inside of our head element in each case team
l file there must be a title element inside of the head element.
To fix this hour let's add a title to a webpage.
The next error says that our ending link tag violates nesting rules.
The validator is telling us that this issue is occurring on line 52 of our code.
This may not be the exact line number but it is a good place to start.
Let's scroll down to line 52 in our code.
We are running into an issue with the closing length tag on that line.
Closer inspection reveals that on the line above it there is an opening span tag but no closing spand
tag.
We will add the closing span tag to fix this error.
Looking back at our validator the next error tells us that around inline 81 there is an ending age for
tag but there were open elements.
There is a secondary that is similar as well.
Let's go to Visual Studio and scroll to line 81 to see if we can make sense of this hour online 81.
We have an opening each to tag but a closing H for tag.
Then on the next line we have an opening H for tag and the closing H-2 tag.
Swapping these tags into their respective places should fix the last two hours and or validator.
Now we will save our file in Visual Studio and then upload the file to the HVM validator.
We should see that all of the errors were fixed and the code is now error free.
The third option we have for validating are each team old code is validating it by direct input.
As you can see when we click the third tab there is a text area where we can directly input him out
code to check it.
We can copy and paste code that we have written and run it through the validator.
Here are a few tips on copying and pasting code.
Be careful copying and pasting from software like Microsoft Word and other similar programs because
they may use curly quotes instead of straight quotes which some IDS may not recognize.
If you want to copy a line of code you can double click the line to easily select the whole line.
You can hold shift and hit the up and down arrows after highlighting a line to highlight the line immediately
above or below the line you highlighted prior to highlight all of the code in a file.
You can hit Control A.
These keyboard shortcuts make it easier to copy and paste your code into the validator.
Essentially the W3 see online H.T. mail validator is an excellent resource that we can use to automate
the checking of our code for hours as a web developer.
You should definitely understand how to work with this tool and use it frequently to double check your
code in the next lecture we will recap what we learned in this section.