In this lecture we will create an about us page for our website.
The code we are about to write will go into our About Us div to start.
Let's give our About Us div a style attribute with a font size of two VW of visibility of hidden top
value of 400 pixels and a position of absolute to signal to users that they are on the About Us section
of our Web page.
Let's add an H1 element to our Web page and give our page a heading of about us.
We will also give our H-1 heading aliment style attribute with a value of left 80 percent a position
of relative and the color of white underneath our heading.
We want to create a row of content including text in an image.
Let's say it a div element with a class value of.
We will then add another development that will store our text content.
Let's give our diverse style attribute with the top value of 50 pixels aleft value of 40 percent a position
of relative and the color of white.
Next we will add an image that will float to the right of our text.
Our image will have a source of about image on all value of about and a style attribute the styles to
apply to this element will be a float value of right a top value of fifty pixels left value of one hundred
pixels.
A position of relative a height of 300 pixels and a width of 300 pixels.
We will put the text why should you come here in a paragraph tag and then create an ordered list using
the UL tag.
We will add items to our list using the ally tag.
Finally let's add a paragraph tag with some more text content.
We will give the text the style attribute with a top value of 80 pixels a left value of one hundred
pixels a position of relative or color of white and a clear value of both the clear value of both will
force our text onto a new line underneath our image.
We will add the text we are a pizzeria that serves great food at an excellent price.
Between the opening and closing Peter eggs in order to be able to see are about us page we are going
to need to specify some behavior for our About Us nav menu item on click below the closing style tag
toward the bottom of our code.
Let's add an opening and closing script tag between which we can add some Javascript code.
We will write a short function that we will use to display a section of our webpage.
When one of our NAV menu items is clicked the function will be called show page section and it will
take as a parameter.
The idea of one of the sections of our web page will create a variable called list of ideas that will
be a list of the IDs for our menu options.
One benefit of this solution is that we can easily add more options to our menu if we want and then
we would just have to add its ID to this list to scale up our code.
Our list of IDS will be for strings home about us menu and contact.
After that let's write a for loop that will go through each ID and compare it to the ID passed into
this function as a parameter.
If the idea that we are currently on in the list matches the id pass then we will set it to visible.
Else we will set its visibility to head.
There is one last step we need to do before we can see our code in action in the web browser.
We need to go back up to her about us menu option and give it an on click value of show page section
with an ID value of about us past into it.
Now we can run our code in the browser and click the About Us option.
If we typed everything incorrectly we should see about Section display on the web page.
For good measure let's say an on click attribute to the other three menu items that point to the IDs
that they showed
in the next lecture.
We will create the menu page for all web site.