In this lecture we will learn about pseudo classes that apply to an element based on what child it is
and its parent the first child pseudo class selects every element of the specified type that is the
first child of its parent to see an example of this.
Let's add some example code we will have three parent does that each has two child paragraph elements
inside of them.
Then we will write the style code for this example we will add an opening and closing style tag and
we will use the first child pseudo class to turn the first child paragraph element screen.
When we run the code in the browser you will notice that each of the first children of each of the parent
divs is now green.
Let's jump back to the editor.
The last child pseudo class allows us to select the last child of a specified type if we change our
code for this example to use the last child pseudo class and run our code in the web browser.
You will notice that the second child and each of the parent lives turns green.
This is because they are each the last child and their respective parent div..
Let's go back to the editor the end child pseudo class allows us to select the nth child based on the
number that we specify.
We will change our code to use this pseudo class and we'll pass in an end value of 1 for this example.
When we do this and run the code in the web browser you will notice that each first child paragraph
element is turned green.
Let's go back to the editor.
The end The last child pseudo class selects the specified elements starting with the last element.
So if we change the code from the last example we looked at to use the last child selector and keep
it in an end value of 1 each of the second children will be selected.
This is because these elements are the last children or elements of their respective divs.
And the last child pseudo class starts counting from the last child.
When we run this code in the web browser you will see that each of the second children of the divs are
changed to the color green.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
The only child pseudo class will select every element of the specified type.
That is the only child of its parent.
If we change our example code to use the only child pseudo class and run our code in the browser you
will note that none of the paragraph elements are green.
This is because each div has two children so none of these elements are the only child of their parents
live in the next lecture.
We will learn about the pseudo classes that CSSA gives us that apply to anchor elements on a web page.