In this lecture we will learn how to embed web pages into other web pages using HVM L to embed web pages
into other web pages.
We use the I-frame tag first roulade an opening and closing I-frame tag.
Next we need to specify that you are Ellas the source using the source attribute of the I-frame tag
we can use the width and height attributes to define a width and height for our I-frame just like audio
and video tags frames can also have Fulbeck text that is displayed if something goes wrong while loading
the I-frame.
Be sure to put the full back text in a paragraph element between the opening and closing I-frame tigs
the frame border attribute specifies whether or not the I-frame border should be displayed.
If we assign the frame border attribute a value of 0 it will remove the frame border that is added to
the I-frame by default.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the web page we specified was embedded into
a web page without the frame border.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
If we assign the frame border attribute value of one the frame border will be displayed.
Let's change the value of the frame border attribute to one and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see there is now a frame border around the embedded web page in the next lecture we will
learn about the HVM Moul canvas.