In this lecture we will learn about the font properties that CSSA allows us to animate.
We can animate the font font size font size it just font stretch and font weight properties first lets
add some text to weaken animi.
We also need to add an opening and closing style tag to our page so that we can embed the CSSA needed
for the style and animation to be applied to our text.
Next we will specify styles that will be applied to the text in our paragraph tag the font size will
be three VW.
We will also specify the animation with the name of scale text a duration of 10 seconds and use the
infinite keyword to make the animation loop.
Next we will write the code for our animation we will give our animation a name of scale tax rules specify
that the text will go from a font size of 1 VW to a font size of 5 VW.
When we run our code we will see our text scale from 1 VW to 5 VW
in the next lecture we will learn about the border properties that CSSA allows us to animi.