In this lecture we will learn about the format of an HMO document each time and document follows a specific
structure that communicates to the browser how to render the content to the web page in its most basic
form.
Here's what an HMO document looks like.
This is a skeleton or rough outline which you will then fill in with all of the content you need for
your web page although the content will be different each time you create an aged female document.
The overall structure will be the same for each of the examples we do in these lectures.
We will have this skeleton already in our code so that we can easily write and test code that we can
run in the web browser.
I suggest that you type the skeleton code once save it and we use it as you follow along with the examples
in each lecture.
I will save this code as example.
Each female and I will use this example file for the rest of the videos.
The only exceptions are the HVM owl and CSSA hands on sections where we will be creating new files at
the top of the document is the doc type tag.
This tag was added to each Chimo in the latest version of each team l each team 5 and this tag allows
the browser to differentiate between the late stage female version and legacy or past each female versions.
Next comes the HVM melted this tag comes right after the duct tape tag on an HMO document and wraps
all of the HMO content on that document.
The head tag wraps the meta data of the web page metadata is describing data about our Web page.
You have to include a title in the head tag which will display at the top of your web browser in the
tab.
The body tag surrounds the content like text images etc. that will be visible on the web page.
When we are typing out tags and testing to see what they will display onto our Web page we will add
or code here let's expand this skeleton HMO document to show some more features that we have access
to.
A header is at the top of the document body meaning that it comes immediately after the opening body
tag.
It defines the content that will be displayed at the top of the page above all of the other visible
content.
Similarly we can add a footer to a web page which comes right before the closing body tag.
It defines the content which will be displayed at the very bottom of our Web page underneath all of
our other content.
In the next lecture we will learn about the structure of each team of code and learn the terminology
that we will use when describing each team out code throughout the rest of the course.