In this section we set up Visual Studio code.
The idea that we will use in the rest of this course.
First we went step by step through the process of downloading installing and running the program and
learned about it you I lay out after that we looked at how we can customize the ideas to fit our needs.
We ran through the different color schemes that we can set for syntax highlighting.
We also learned how to create keyboard shortcut and set other preferences like autosave and text size.
We took a close look at how we can customize the editor to the fullest and learned how to enable and
disable options like indenting in our HQ male.
We also ran through the different menu options that the editor gives us and what several useful options
do to make our life easier when coding.
Finally we learned how to run our code and the web browser.
Additionally we took a look at how to set up the folder hierarchy to be able to use images on our local
machine and our Each team will remember if you already have some web development experience and prefer
to use another ID.
You can you are free to use any ID you like as long as it supports HVM and CSSA code as those are the
two languages we will be using in this course.
Now that we have Visual Studio code set up on our computer we are ready to jump right into the fundamentals
of each team in the next section.