In this lecture we will recap what we learned in this section of the course in this section.
We took a deeper look at tags in each team.
First we learned about formatting tags and HMO.
The H.R. tag allows us to add a horizontal rule to our Web page the BBR tag is used to define an abbreviation
or acronym.
The address tag is where the web site owner or article author includes their contact information.
The BDO tag is used to override the current text direction.
BDO stands for bi directional override the Del tag shows text that has been deleted.
It displays the deleted text with a line through it.
The INS tag shows text that has been inserted the DSN tag allows us to define the meaning of a word
on a webpage.
The Kaybee detail EG is used to display keyboard input.
The essay MP tag is used to display sample output from a computer program.
The tag is used to indicate to a user that the text is no longer correct or accurate.
The queue tag is used to define a short quotation.
Next we learned about the tags that H Mail gives us add metadata to our Web page.
There are three such tags Mehta head and base the meta tag lets us add custom metadata information about
our webpage.
The head tag allows us to define several things that apply to a web page including the title style base
link meta script and no script.
The base tag lets us specify a base your L for all the links and relative image paths on a web page.
Finally we learned about tags new HCM L5 in previous sections we learned about some of these tags such
as audio source video canvas as Viji article aside details Frigg caption figure footer header Mark menu
item nav summary and section.
We learned about other new tags that we hadn't yet covered in HVM L5 the track tag is another new addition
as of HVM L5 and can be used to add subtitles or captions to audio or video files.
The embed tag is used as a container for plugins or interactive content.
Then we can add to our Web page.
The be-I tag is used to isolate a part of the text that could be formatted in a different direction
than the surrounding text.
The dialog tag allows us to create pop up boxes and modals on our Web page.
The main tag is used to define the main content on a webpage.
The meter tag allows us to display a gauge or meter on a web page.
The progress tag allows us to display a progress bar on a webpage.
The time tag allows us to define a human readable date or time.
The WDR tag specifies where it be OK to add a line break in the next section.
We will learn about global attributes and HVM L.