In this lecture we will stylize the menu page of our website.
First let's add some space between the description and button for each menu item.
We will do so by adding to break elements between those elements.
Next let's add a border around each of the menu items we will use the card classes our selector and
add a to pixel solid white border around each card.
We're going to add a button pulse to the new menu item or BBQ slice to make it stand out.
Let's create our animation and name it button pulse.
We will add keyframes at 0 percent 30 percent 40 percent 50 percent 60 percent 70 percent and 80 percent.
All of these will ever transform with a scale of one with the exception of the keyframe at 50 percent
which will have a scale of 1.1.
Then we will reference our button using its ID BBQ price and attach our animation to it.
We will specify the animation name of button pulse duration of one second and we will make it loop by
using the infinite keyword.
When we run our code in the web browser and click on the menu link you will see the result of the code
we just typed in the next lecture.
We will stylize the contact page for our Web site.