In this lecture we will look at a recap of what we learned in this section in this section.
We learned how to debug our HVM code.
Debugging is important because the quicker we can fix errors in our code the quicker we will be able
to produce effective quality code.
First we learned what debugging is in short debugging is finding and fixing errors in your code.
We learned that there are two main types of errors in each DML syntax errors and logic errors a syntax
error means that you typed something wrong.
As a result the code may not work properly or may not work at all.
A logic error means that the code runs fine and no error is thrown but that the code doesn't work the
way that you intended.
Then we looked at several common HVM errors and how to fix them.
We learned about errors like using an unsupported tag missing quotes or attribute values missing a closing
tag for an element and improper nesting of elements.
Finally we learned how to use the W3 c h t m l validator to automate detecting errors in our code.
The validator allows us to input your Olave a live web site a file from our computer or directly type
in HVM our code.
It will tell us any warnings or errors that it runs into as well as the line number that is causing
the issue.
Using a validator like the W3 c h t m l validator is a great way to save time checking HVM l code for
errors.
Debugging is an important skill for any web developer to have in the next lecture.
We will learn about the basics of C Ss.