In this lecture we will look at some other useful text properties that CSSA provides us the word speccing
property specifies the space between each word in our text.
First let's add a paragraph element to a web page with some example text then we will add an opening
and closing style tag to our webpage.
We will add the word speccing property and give it a value of 20 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see there is now a 20 pixel space between the word example and the word text.
Let's go back to the editor
the line height property and see SS allows us to specify the height of the lines in our text element.
When you change the line height you will notice that the space between your lines changes.
We are going to add a brake element to our text to force it to be two lines and then add some more example
text after the break element.
Then we will add the line height property and give it a value of 20 pixels.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code as you can see.
There is a 20 pixel space between the first and second lines of text on our webpage.
Let's go back to the Editor Note that we can also assign a small value to decrease the spacing between
lines.
For example let's give our text a line height of three pixels and then run our code to see the result.
The line height between our lines was reduced.
Let's go back to the editor the whitespace property allows us to customize how whitespace works with
our text if we assign the whitespace property of value of prae the whitespace will appear exactly as
it was typed in the HVM element.
Let's change our paragraph element back to having some example text content.
We will use the Enter key to put our second word a few lines below our first word then we will give
our text the whitespace property with a value of PRI.
When we run our code in the web browser you will notice that it is displayed exactly as we specified
the key to note here is that we don't have to add break characters to put words in our text on new lines
when working with a whitespace value of prie.
Let's go back to the editor if we set the whitespace property to a value of no wrap multiple spaces
will be condensed to a single space the text will continue on the same line unless the code has a break
tag in it to see this effect.
Let's keep our text exactly how we have it and give it a whitespace value of no wrap then we will go
to the web browser and run our code as you can see the text is continued on the same line despite the
fact that we had text on multiple lines in the element due to the no rap style.
Let's go back to the editor the word Arap property allows us to tell the browser to split a long word
onto two lines to make our spacing of our text more uniform.
Let's change the content of our paragraph element to have a very long word inside of it.
Then we will give our elemental width of 120 pixels using the with property.
First note that if our text has a very long word inside of it and we specify a wished for it to fit
inside of the breaks in our text look odd.
Tell us straight this.
Let's run the code in the web browser as is and see that the text breaks look odd.
Then we will go back to the editor.
Now see the result of us having a word wrap property with a value of Greek word.
Let's run our code to see this change take effect.
Our long word now is partially on one line and partially on another line in the next lecture.
We will recap what we learned in this section.