In this lecture we will learn about the CSSA box model the box model is not an actual piece of code
but rather a model that helps us to think about each DML elements and CSSA styles when we are programming.
You can think of each female element text images etc. as having a box around them that defines their
bounds.
There are four main parts to the box model.
The content is the main center area where the actual element appears.
The content would be the text image video etc. that the developer embeds into the web page.
Padding is an area between the content and its border padding directly affects the spacing of the element
itself.
The border is the outer bound of the element.
It is outside of the content and padding margins are outside of the border of the element.
One concept that may be unclear is the difference between margins and padding margins are external to
the element they are outside of the elements border.
On the other hand padding is inside of the elements border.
If we add padding to the element it will directly push against the content.
If we add a margin to the element it will push against the border of the element but not directly against
the elements content in the next lecture.
We will learn about padding and margins and see SS.