In this lecture we will create the menu page for our website.
The menu will display the different items that a customer can purchase from our pizzeria.
Most of our code for this lecture will go inside of our menu div that we created a few lectures back.
We will add the style attribute to our menu div and give it a visibility of Hedden top value of 400
pixels aleft value of 15 percent a position of absolute a width of 70 percent and a height of 20 percent.
We will add an H1 heading element to display the title menu at the top of this section of our Web page.
The styles we will add to this element are text align value of center a with of 100 percent and the
color of white.
We're going to add these items as cards to our Web page in one row.
So first let's add another div and give it a class value overall.
Let's create one of the core items for a web page.
We're going to add a total of five of these items but once we create the first one we will be able to
copy and paste this one and use that as a template for the others.
Since the majority of the code will be the same to start we will add a div with class values of card
and text center inside of the div we will add an image element.
We will give the image a class of Kord image top.
Source attribute with a value of sliced 1 p and G and then all value of card image.
Then we will add another div and give it a class value of card body between the opening and closing
div tags that we just added.
We will add a title for our card.
We will use an H-2 heading tag and give it an idea of cheese and a class of card title.
Between the opening and closing H-2 tags.
We will put the name of our item which is cheese in this case.
We will then add some text to describe the item we will use the H for heading tag and assign it a class
value of card text between the opening and closing H for tags.
We will put a description for item which in this case will be regular sliced with sauce and cheese.
Finally we really an anchor element with an ID of cheese price an ATF attribute of Hash tag and the
class of button and Button primary between the opening and closing anchor tags.
We will put the price of $3.
We want to add functionality so that when we click the button the item we clicked in its price will
be displayed in an alert to the user.
Let's go down to below where we wrote our last function in between the script tags and write another
function for this purpose.
The name of our function will be item on click and we will pass the idea of an item and the idea of
the amount we will use three variables in this function.
Our first variable we named item and we will use the document get element by ID function to find the
HVM element that has the idea of the item argument passed into the function.
We will use the inner h t M-L to access the contents between the opening and closing tag of this element.
The second variable will be named amount and we will use the document get element by ID function to
get the H DML element with the idea of the amount passed into the function and get the inner h t m l
of it.
Our third variable will be named.
Alert message and we will concatenate the other two variables along with some other text before passing
this variable into javascript alert function.
Next we need to add the on click attribute to our anchor element back up in the menu section of our
code and call this function passing in a string value of cheese for the first argument and a value of
cheese price for the second argument.
Before we run the code let's go between our opening and closing style tags and add a few styles to effect
the elements of our code.
We will give the card class A with of 20 percent a height of 500 pixels and a background color of transparent
or Orji be 0 0 0 0 0 0.
Let's give the card image top class A with 200 pixels a height of 200 pixels a margin of zero and auto
or card title and card text classes will be given a color of white
or Button class will be given a width of 80 percent OK.
Now if we run this code in the browser and click the menu option in our nav menu it should display one
menu item.
If we click the button we should see the alert displayed at the top of our web page with the appropriate
values.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Let's copy the chunk of code we wrote for our card and pasted four times.
We will modify these four blocks of code to display or other for menu items we need to modify just a
few values in our image tag we will change the source to slice to P and G in the H to element we will
change the ID to peperoni and the content to peperoni and our H for element we will change our content
to pizza with pepperoni topping for anchor tag will change the idea.
Peperoni price and the on click arguments the pepperoni and pepperoni price the content of our link
Allaman will be $4 for our third card.
We will make similar changes in our image element we will change the source to slice 3 PMG in the H2
element.
We will change the idea a mushroom and the content to mushroom in our 8:04 element.
We will change our content to pizza with mushrooms for anchor element.
We will change the ID to mushroom price and the on click arguments to mushroom and mushroom price.
The content of our link element will be three dollars and fifty cents for a fourth card we will make
these changes as well.
In our image tag we will change the source to slice for energy in the H2 element.
We will change the idea of vegi and the content to vegi in our h 4 element.
We will change our content to pizza with veggie toppings for anchor element.
We will change the idea of veggie price and the unclick arguments to veggie and veggie price.
The content of our link element will be three dollars and 50 cent profit.
We will make these changes as well in our image tag.
We will change the source to slice 5 PLG and the H2 element will change the idea of BBQ and the content
to barbecue in our H for.
We will change our content to pizza with chicken and barbecue sauce for our anchor element.
We will change the idea of BBQ price and the on click arguments to BBQ and BBQ price.
The content of our link aliment will be $4 and 50 Cent now.
We run our code and click the menu link.
We should see all five menu items we can click the button associated with any of these items to display
the item name and its price in the next letter.
We will create the contact page for our website.