In this lecture we will learn about the H I'll canvass the H I'll l canvasses a container that enables
us to draw graphics through javascript code and provide several mechanisms for creating interactive
content such as animation and games to create a canvas.
We use the canvas tag.
Let's start by adding an opening and closing canvas tag to our code.
We will also add a width and height to our canvas to each team.
Canvas has a context which is the actual surface that images are drawn onto.
Let's take a look at how we can draw an image onto the canvas.
First we need to add an opening and closing script tagged to our code.
Next we need to give our canvas an ID.
This is how we will get a reference to the context of the canvas inside of the script tags.
We can use the document get element by ID function to get a reference to the canvas.
We supply this function the value of the ID that we gave to our canvas canvases have 2D and 3D drawing
contexts.
Since we are going to render a true the image on the canvas we're going to use the 2d context we will
use the H chainmail canvases get context method and pass it a value of 2D.
We need to create a new image that we can assign a source to.
First we will make a new variable and then assign it a new image as you know from working with each
team l image elements.
They have a source attribute where we can assign them the image file that will be displayed.
For this example we will assign our image or source of our star PMG image.
This next piece of code waits until the image loads before we do anything with it.
Finally we will use the drawer image function to draw an image onto our canvas.
Note that we are specifically calling this function on our context variable as that is the actual drawing
surface of the canvas to draw image function takes three arguments.
The first argument is the image to be drawn to the canvas.
The second is the x position at which to draw the image on the canvas.
The third argument is the y position at which to draw the image on the canvas.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the image was drawn onto our canvas.
We will now learn about the co-ordinate system on each team will canvas each female canvas is essentially
a 2D grid.
The 00 origin point on the canvas is the upper left hand corner.
As you go from the left hand corner of the canvas to the right the x values increase as you go from
the left hand corner down to the bottom of the canvas.
The y values increase.
Aside from images there are many other things that we can draw to the canvas we can render text shapes
and gradients to the canvas.
Let's look at an example of each of these.
First we will look at an example of how we can render text to the canvas.
Next we can use the fill text function to render the text to the drawing surface of our canvas.
The full text function is similar to the drawer image function and takes three arguments.
The first is the string value of the text to be rendered to the canvas.
The second and third arguments are the x and y values of the position on the canvas at which to render
the text.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see the text that we defined was rendered to the canvas.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can further customize the display of our text by adding a font and a size to it.
Note that we supply a font value in pixels followed by a font name inside of the same string.
Make sure that this modification is done before the text is rendered to the canvas.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our text was assigned the specified
font and font size.
Let's go back to the editor next let's look at how we can draw shapes to the drawing surface of a canvas
in each TNL we can use the fill function to draw a rectangle onto in each team canvas the fill recked
function takes four parameters.
The first is the x position of the rectangle.
The second is the y position of the rectangle.
The third is the width of the rectangle and the fourth is the height of the rectangle.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the rectangle was drawn onto the
canvas.
Let's jump back to the editor next.
Let's learn how to render gradients to the canvas first.
We will need to create a variable that will store our greedy.
We call to create linear gradient method on the context of our canvas and passing for arguments the
starting exposition the starting y position the ending x position and the ending y position.
We will then add color stops that will define the colors for our gradient and their positions.
For this example we will create a blue gradient that fades to black.
First we will add a color stop for blue at the start of our gradient to tell the greedy and to start
on the left.
Use a value of zero.
Next we will add a color stop for black at the end of our gradient to tell Ingredion to have a black
color stop at the end of our gradient.
We use a value of 1.
Next we need to add the gradient as the style of the context.
Remember the Phil recked function that we used earlier to draw a rectangle to the canvas.
We can use that same function to draw a gradient.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see the gradient we created was drawn to the
canvas in the next lecture.
We will learn about scalable vector graphics.