In this lecture we will learn about creating a dropdown menu and nav bar using bootstrap.
Let's look at how we can create a dropdown menu using bootstrap.
First we will have the customary bootstrap container to a web page by adding a div and assigning it
a class value of container to create a dropdown menu.
First we add a development to our Web page and use the bootstrap dropdown class as its class value.
Then we add a button that will be used to open the dropdown menu.
We will give it classes of Button button primary and dropdown toggle.
We will also assign the type attribute with a value of button and the data toggle attribute with a value
of dropdown or label for the menu will be options.
We will then add a span with a class value of.
This related downward pointing arrow next to the title of our menu.
Then we will build the actual dropdown menu.
We will do this using bootstraps dropdown menu class which we will apply to our dropdown item list.
Our list will be an unordered list.
Each of the links will have a placeholder value of the pound symbol we will label the options of the
dropdown menu option 1 through Option 4.
There is one more thing we need to do in order to see the effect of this example.
We need to change our bootstrap imports to Version 3 3.7.
Let's change the bootstrap CSSA and Javascript imports from Version 4 dot 1.0 to Version 3 dot 3.7.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code.
Now if we click the dropdown button you will notice that the dropdown menu opens and shows the options
that we specified in the code.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
Next we will create a nav bar for our web page.
We will start by adding a nav element to our Web page and assigning it class values of nav bar and nav
bar default.
After that we will add a div with a class value of container fluid.
Then we will create an unworded list with class values of NAV and nav bar nav.
We will add three less items each of which will have a class value of NAV item.
Each of these list item elements will have a child anchor element the anchor elements will have a class
value of NAV link and a placeholder Atra value of the pound symbol.
The links will be labeled link one link to and link 3 respectively.
Then let's go to the web browser and run our code to see the result of the code that we typed as you
can see our NAV bar with our links is displayed on the web page.
In the next lecture we will learn how we can work with images and bootstrap.