In this lecture we will learn about the margin properties that CSSA allows us to animi CSSA allows us
to animate the margin margin bottom margin left margin right and margin top properties.
For this example we will animate the margin top property to make the text move down on our webpage.
First we will create the text that we will use in this animation.
Next we will add our opening and closing style tags to our text.
We will add an animation called text and Im a duration of two seconds and make it loop by using the
infinite key word.
Next we will write the code for the animation we will call our animation text and im and we will make
it animate from a margin top value of zero pixels to a margin top value of 100 pixels.
When we run the code we should see the text move down on all web page
and the next lecture we will learn about the padding properties that CSSA allows us to animi.