In this lecture we reload about some properties that we can use to position elements on our Web page.
The Position property allows us to specify how an element will be positioned on a webpage by assigning
this property value of absolute we can position our element anywhere on the web page by assigning an
absolute position.
Let's give our element a position of absolute.
We can then use the left right top and bottom properties or any combination of them to position the
element on our webpage.
We will give our element the left value of 50 pixels and the top value of 50 pixels.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our image has moved down and right 50 pixels.
Let's jump back to the editor will also be aware that giving the top property of value moves it down
on the web page the specified amount of pixels from the top ascending the bottom property of value moves
are element up a specified amount of pixels from the bottom of our web page to see this difference.
Let's change the top property to bottom and run our code.
You will notice that our element was pushed up on the web page.
Let's jump back to the editor
the float property allows us to specify if an image should be displayed to the left or right of text
to see the effect of the next few examples.
We need to add more content to our paragraph element to make it longer.
Let's add some more content to our paragraph element assigning the float property value of last will
position the element to the left of the text.
Let's first they add an image element to our Web page.
We will give it a source of our star PLG image then we will use the float property and give it a value
of less.
We will also give our image a width and height of 50 pixels.
Let's run our code in the browser
as you can see our images displayed on the left of our text.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning the float property value of right will position the element
on the right of our text.
Let's change the float value to right and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see the images displayed on the right of the text.
Then we will go back to the editor the clear property lets us specify the sides to not allow an image
on for example assigning a clear value of less to our text means that we cannot add images to the left
of our text.
Let's give a paragraph element to clear value of the left in our image element of float value of left.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see.
Even though we specified that our image should float to the left of our text the clear value of left
that we gave to our paragraph element made the image in text be placed on separate lines the clear value
of less tells the browser not to allow an image to go on the left side of our text.
Let's jump back to the editor we can also give the clear property value of right to prevent an image
from being positioned to the right of our techs.
Let's give our paragraph element a clear value of right and our image or float value of right.
Then we will run our code in the browser to see the result.
As you can see the image is on the right side of the web page but not the right side of the text.
The text was forced onto a separate line than the image since we give the text a clear value of right.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can also assign the clear property value of both to not allow images on either side of the text.
Let's change the clear property to have a value of both and then run our code as you can see the image
is not allowed on the left or right side of the text and is therefore kept on a separate line in the
text.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning a value of None to the clear property allows images to be positioned
on both sides of the text.
Let's give our text the clear value of None and then run our code since our image still has a float
value right.
It will float to the right of our text.
We will run our code in the web browser to see the result.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
The z index property allows us to specify which elements will appear on top of and below other elements.
In other words the order that elements at the same position are stacked on top of one another.
The higher the value of the z index the closer to the top the element will be positioned elements with
a higher z index will be rendered on top of elements with the lower z index.
Let's have two paragraph elements on our Web page.
One with red text and one with blue text.
First we will add the two paragraph elements to our webpage page then we will give our first element
an idea of green text and our second element to an idea of red text.
Next we will add some style of code to our elements.
We will make the element with an idea of green text the color green and the element with an idea of
red text the color red.
Let's give both elements an absolute position or green text we will give a left and top value of 0 pixels
to for our red text.
Let's give it a top value of 4 pixels in our left value of 4 pixels to offset it from green text.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code.
As you can see all red text is rendered on top of all green text since that came after all green text
in the code.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Let's look at how we can use the z index property to control the rendering order of these elements.
Let's give our green text as the index of two.
And our red text is the index of one since we are giving our green text a higher z index than our red
text.
It will be displayed on top.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our green text is rendered on top of our
red text in the next lecture.
We will learn about clipping and masking and see.
SS.