HVM code follows a specific structure.
We have already looked at tags and the content that is placed between opening and closing tags tags
that don't have a closing tag recalled empty tags as a whole.
The tags in their content are referred to as an element to an HMO inside of the opening tag.
We can put attributes which provide additional information about an element.
Usually these attributes have the following structure attribute name equals attribute value boolean
attributes or a special type of attribute that have only one value.
If you're familiar with the traditional concept of a boolean and other programming languages your prior
knowledge may be misleading in this case a boolean attribute an HMO is put inside of a tag and doesn't
have an equal sign or value given to it.
Selected and disabled are two examples of boolean attributes an HMO the selected attribute allows us
to show a pre-selected option when the web page loads the disabled attribute allows an input element
to be greyed out and unable to be quick when specifying values to attributes these values are surrounded
by quote.
You can use either single quotes or double quotes.
It is all a matter of preference.
However be sure not to perish single quote with a double quote or vice versa.
Elements in HVM l can also be nested if we want to italic size a word inside of some text.
We could use the IDE tag we would put the text instead of opening and closing paragraph tags and then
surround the word we want to emphasize that opening and closing our italicised tag.
Commonly you will hear elements in Chimay be referred to as other block elements or inline elements
block elements automatically have a newline inserted above and below them inline elements are usually
used instead of block elements and affect the content inside of the block element in the italicize example.
We looked at above the content with the paragraph tags is considered a block element and the italicized
tag is considered to be an inline element.
The italicized head does not define a new block of content but modifies the content inside of the meeting.
There are some key points to be aware of when dealing with block elements an inline element block elements
can only appear within the body tag of the HVM page.
Recall that the main content over a web page is contained between the opening and closing body tags.
This is where we put all of the block elements for our web page examples of block level elements are
div..
The div tag allows us to specify a page division footer the footer tag allows us to define content for
the bottom of our Web page.
H-1 through H 6 heading tags these heading tags allow us to display text that stands out as a heading
header.
The header tag allows us to define content that will be shown above all of the other content ally.
The ally tag allows us to define a list item for our list all while the old tag allows us to create
an ordered or numbered list.
P The p tag allows us to insert text into a web page and is known as the paragraph tag UL the UL tag
allows us to create an unordered list and the list goes on.
These are just some examples of the block elements we have access to when using HVM L in the next lecture.
We will learn about each symbol titles and headings and how we can use them when developing web pages.