In this lecture we will recap what we learned in this section of the course.
First we learned about using the background properties that CSSA allows us to animate using CSSA we
can animate elements background background color background position and background size.
We looked at it an example of how we could animate the background color property to cycle through the
colors of the rainbow.
Next we looked at how we could animate and elements border using C Ss we saw an example of how we can
animate and elements border radius property to turn a square into a circle.
After that we learned about the column properties that CSSA allows us to animate the column properties
that we can animate using CSSA or column count column gap column rule column rule color column rule
with column width and columns.
We looked at it an example of how we can animate the column count property to divide text into columns
on the web page.
Then we learned about the font properties that CSSA allows us to animi we can animate the font font
size font size adjust font stretch and font weight properties.
The example in this lecture was how we could animate the font size property to scale text on our Web
page.
Next we looked at the margin properties that CSSA allows us to animi CSSA allows us to animate the margin
margin bottom margin left margin right and margin top properties.
We looked at an example of how we could animate the margin top property to move an element down on a
webpage.
After that we learned how to animate elements heightened with using CCS.
We looked at an example of how we could animate a diverse height and width to scale it up and down on
a webpage.
Then we learned about the text properties that CSSA allows us to animate these properties are text decoration
text indent and text Chatto.
We looked at it an example of how we could animate the text decoration property to animate a line going
over and under our text.
After that we learned about the padding properties that can be animated using C Ss the padding properties
we can animate using CSSA or padding padding bottom padding left padding right and padding top.
We looked at an example of how we could animate the padding left property to move text from left to
right on our Web page.
Finally we learned about how we can animate the words spacing and letter spacing properties using C
Ss.
We looked at examples for how to animate both of these properties to animate the space between words
and letters in the text on a web page in the next section.
We will learn about how we can stylize buttons and see SS.