In this lecture we will write the CSSA code to start the contact page of our website.
Let's make the input fields on our form more even on our webpage.
We will go to our style code and specify that our elements with an idea form input field should have
a width of 100 percent and a clear value of both.
Let's say I add rounded edges to the three input fields in our form we'll specify a border radius of
five pixels to round off the corners of our input fields.
When we run our code in the browser and click on the Contact link we will see our input fields now have
round corners.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Next we're going to add a dark outline around our input fields when the user has that input field selected
to do this we will use the focus selector we will specify a solid border of 4 pixels with an -- B
color thirty four thirty four thirty four.
Running this code in the browser and cooking inside of one of our three input fields on the form will
show our dark border with the input field comes into focus.
Let's say add a light overlay to the input fields when the user hovers over them.
To do this we are going to use the hover selector on our email subject and body element we will specify
a color of light gray for the background color when the user hovers over these elements.
After that let's run our code and hover over these input fields as you can see when we hover over the
input fields on the form.
The background color changes to light gray as a result of the code we just wrote.
Let's jump back to the editor our form button is looking pretty plain on our page.
Let's add some code to stylize our button.
We can reference our button using its ID submit button to center our button horizontally on the web
page will give it a with of 20 percent and the margin left and margin right of 40 percent then we will
give our button rounded corners we will use the border radius property and give it a value of 5 pixels.
When we run our code and go to the contact section of our Web page we will see that the button is now
centered horizontally on the web page and has rounded corners.
After that let's say at hover and active States to our button to change the color of it when the user
hovers over it and clicks on it to change hover state we will reference Exidy of Submit button and use
the hover selector.
We will give our button a background color of dark gray when the user hovers over it.
Next we will add code to stylize our button when the user clicks on it to do so we will use the active
selector and change the background color of our button of gray when we run our code and hover over the
button.
You will see the color change.
Then when we click the button you will notice that the color again changes based on the code that we
wrote in the next lecture.
We will do a final cleanup of our files for our Web site and retractor our code.