In this section we learned about events and HMO events and H-G MLA or used to call a function when the
user performs a certain action.
First we looked at keyboard event the keyboard events.
HTL gives us access to her auntie down on key press and Auntie up the auntie down event is fired when
the user presses a key down on the keyboard the on key press event is fired between the on down and
on key up event the on up event is fired when the user releases a key Tomales keyboard events on key
down on key press and on key up are useful when we want to run code when the user presses a key on the
keyboard.
After that we learned about mouse events the mouse events each Chmela gives us access to her on click
on double click on mouse down on mouse move on mouse out on mouse over on mouse up and on wheel the
On Click event fires when the user clicks on an element the on double click event fires when the user
double clicks on an element the on mouse down event fires and the mouse button is pressed down on an
element the on mouse move is a mouse event that fires the mouse cursor moves and is over an element
on mass out event fires when the user moves the cursor off of the element the on mouse over event fires
when the user moves the cursor over an element the on mouse up event fires when the user releases the
mouse button over an element the on wheel event fires and the mouse wheel rolls up or down over an element.
HVM Ellas mouse events are useful I don't want to write code that will fire based on mouse actions.
Then we learned about drag events.
Each team has drag events or on Drag start on drag on drag and on drag enter on drag over on drag leave
and on drop the Ondrea starter event is fired when the user starts to drag the element the on drag event
is fired when the elementis dragged the on drag and the event is run at the end of the drag the.
Enter event is run when an element is drag to a drop target on drag.
Over is a drag event that is fired when an element is created over a drop target the on drag leave event
is run when an element leaves a drop target the On Drop event is run.
When an element is dropped HVM those drag events are useful when we want to code functionality around
dragging and dropping elements on the web page.
Finally we learned about clipboard events the HMO clipboard events are on copy on paste and on cut the
on copy event is fired when the user copies an element the on paste event fires when the user pastes
content into an element the on cut event is fired when the user cuts the contents of an element.
The h t m l clipboard events are useful when you want to fire an event when the user copies pastes or
cuts the contents of an element in the next section.
We will learn about layouts and web pages and HVM Mel.