In this lecture we will learn about clipping and masking and see SS clipping and masking or both techniques
to control which part of an image is hidden and which part of an image is shown the difference between
the two is that clipping is done via a vector path and masking is done via a mask image with clipping
anything that is inside of the vector image is visible and anything outside of the vector image is invisible.
SS gives us a clip path property to define a clip path for image.
We can give this property the value of a basic shape that will be the clip path for image a basic shape
is a circle inset ellipsis or polygon assigning a value of circle will make any part of our image inside
of the circle visible and any part of our image outside of the circle invisible.
Let's start off for example by adding an image element to our Web page and then giving it a source of
our checkerboard jpeg image.
Then we will get an opening and closing style tag to our code.
We will give our image a clip path and use the circle function to clip our image in the shape of a circle.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see our image is now displayed in the shape of a circle.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can use the inset function to give our image an insert Clearpath an insect is a rectangle and we
can supply a value to tell the function how much of our current image to clip off.
For example calling the inset function with a value of 10 pixels will chop 10 pixels off all four sides
of our image.
Let's change the clip pair the inset and past the inset function of value of 10 pixels.
When we run our code in the web browser you will notice that 10 pixels were clipped off of each side
of our image.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
We can use the ellipse function to give our image an ellipse shaped path.
Let's use the ellipse function and pass it a value of 50 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our image was clipped in the shape
of an ellipse.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can use the polygon function to create a polygon clip path for image the polygon function takes three
or more arguments which are x y coordinates separated by a space the number of arguments that you supply
in this way defines the number of vertices for your polygon where each x y point you specified defines
a vertex.
We will use the polygon function and passings 0 0.
Then 100 percent to 100 percent and then 0 80 percent then we will go to the web browser and run our
code
as you can see our image was clipped in the shape of a triangle based on the three points that we passed
into the polygon function.
Let's jump back to the editor
masking is similar to clipping but an image is used as opposed to a vector path anywhere that the mask
is fully white will be opaque and anywhere where the mask is fully black will be transparent anywhere
where the mask is a grayscale color between black and white.
It will be semi-transparent.
We can create a custom gradient as our mask.
First let's use our blue JPEG image for this example we will use the Web Kit mask image property and
create a Web Kit gradient.
After we take the code for our custom gradient we will go to the web browser and run our code
as you can see our images masked with the gradient that we find which alters its transparency in the
next lecture.
We will learn about some of the other properties that CSSA gives us access to.