In this lecture we're going to move our CSSA and javascript code to separate files so that we have three
files that are linked together.
One for each Yamal one for our CSSA and one for our javascript.
It is generally considered a best practice in web development to separate our code into separate files
like this.
When we modify our code to clean it up and make it conform to best practices This is known as refactoring.
The first thing we are going to do is move our CSSA style code into its own file.
First we will create a new file in Visual Studio code by going to file new file.
Next we will save our file and name it.
Pizza Dotsie SS Just type pizza as the file name and then use the dropdown menu provided to select the
file type of SS.
Then we will go to our HVM owl and cut and paste the code between our style tags into a new file.
Then we can get rid of the style tags and our each team I'll code the final step to link the CSSA code
to our HGL code is to add a link element at the top of our HVM l code underneath the bootstrap imports.
Now we are going to separate our javascript code into a separate file and then link it to our HMO.
First you will create a new file name it pizza and choose the file type of javascript.
Now we will go to our Chmela code and cut and paste the lines between the script tags which hold all
of our Javascript functions.
Then we can get rid of the opening and closing script tags in our HVM file since we don't need them
anymore.
The last step we need in order to link our javascript to our h t m l is to add a script element that
points to our javascript file at the top of our HVM in the head section.
Now let's run our code in the web browser to make sure nothing broke when we moved our code to separate
files.
As you can see we now have three separate files for each TMLC access and javascript code in the next
lecture.
We will recap what we did in this section of the course.