In this lecture we will learn about the concepts of padding and margins.
We touched on these ideas when we looked at the CSSA box model padding a space inside of the content
borders margins or spaces outside of the borders of an element.
Let's take a look at padding first CSSA allows us to add padding to the top right bottom and left of
an element.
There are five properties that we can use to specify the padding on each of the sides of an element
padding top padding right padding bottom padding left and padding to add padding to the top of an element
we can use the padding top property.
First let's add a paragraph element with some example text to our Web page then we will add an opening
and closing style tag and give a paragraph element to padding top value of 20 pixels.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code
notice that our text has a top padding of 20 pixels.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can instead use the padding left property to add padding to the left of our text.
We will switch the property to padding left and then go to the web browser.
When we run the code you will notice that the 20 pixels of padding was added to the left of our element.
Let's jump back to the editor and of course the same applies for both the padding of bottom and padding
right properties.
Note that we can also specify the padding as a percentage instead of a pixel value.
If we change our padding left value to 10 percent and then run our code you will see the change take
effect.
Let's go back to the editor we can specify a value of inherit to make the padding be inherited from
the parent element.
Let's wrap our paragraph element in a parent DIV tag.
We will change the padding left property of paragraph element to inherit and assign our div padding
left property with a value of 20 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our text now has 20 pixels of padding
on the left since it inherits this value from the parent development.
Let's go back to the editor when we have one or more elements nested inside of each other the inner
element is the child element and the outer element is the parent element.
We can also use the padding property to apply several possible combinations of padding.
If we give the padding one value it will apply that value to the top right bottom and left by default.
Let's remove the div and give our paragraph element the padding of 25 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see our text now is a top right bottom
and left padding of 25 pixels.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Alternatively we could specify for value separated by spaces to the padding property which the browser
will automatically recognize as the top right bottom and left padding respectively.
We will use the padding property and specify a top padding of 25 pixels or right padding of 20 pixels
of bottom padding of 15 pixels and the left padding of 10 pixels.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code to see the result.
In this example the top padding has a value of 25 pixels the right padding has a value of 20 pixels.
The bottom padding has a value of 15 pixels and the less padding has a value of 10 pixels.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Let's take a look at margins now.
There are five properties that we can use to specify the margins on each of the sides of an element.
These properties are margin top margin right margin bottom margin left and margin the margin properties
can have values of four types.
Auto length percent and inherit with a value of auto.
The browser will automatically calculate the margin the value can also be a specified size such as a
pixel value the value can be a percentage from 0 to 100 percent or the value can be set to inherit so
that the margin is inherited from its parent element to add a margin to the top of an element.
We can use the margin top property.
Let's assign our paragraph element the margin top of 20 pixels.
Then we will go to the web browser and see the effect.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can use the margin write property to add a margin on the right of our element.
Let's change the property to margin right and then run our code in the browser.
Our element now has a right margin of 20 pixels.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
The margin bottom property lets us had a margin to the bottom of an element.
We will change our property for example to margin bottom and then run our code in the browser.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example we can use the margin less property to add
a left margin to our element.
Let's change the property to margin last and then run our code as you can see there is a left margin
of 20 pixels on our element.
Let's jump back to the editor using the shorthand margin property we can add a margin of a specified
size to the left top right and bottom of our element all at once.
Let's use the margin property and give it a value of 20 pixels.
Then we will run our code in the browser.
Now R-TX has a 20 pixel margin on each side in the next lecture.
We will recap what we learned in this section.