In this lecture we will learn about webpage titles and headings and the various tags humoral gives us
regarding adding a title and headings to our Web page.
We can supply a title for a web page by using the title tag this tag goes between the opening and closing
had tag of an HTML document.
However this title will not be shown on our Web page.
It will only be used in the browser and search engine will be displayed in the browser toolbar Favorites
tab and search engine results.
For example to add a title to a web page we would add an opening and closing title tag to our code in
the head section and then type whatever the title is in between the opening and closing title tags.
Let's jump to the web browser when we run this code in a browser.
You will notice that the title we provided is displayed in the tab at the top of the web browser.
Note that the title element is a required element for a webpage meaning that in order for our code to
run we must give it a title element to display a heading on our Web page.
Each G-mail gives us the 6 heading tags.
Each one each to each.
3 4 5 and each 6.
These tags are meant to rank the content in order of importance.
For example the H-1 tag is the largest heading out of the six and would come at the top of the page
as an example.
Let's add an H1 heading element to our Web page by adding an opening and closing each one tag to our
code.
We will then give it text content based on the text that we want displayed as the heading.
When we run our code you will see our h one element heading be displayed on the webpage.
The size and style you see applied to the text here are the built in defaults for each one heading element
h to tag is the second largest heading and we would use it when we wanted a smaller heading than H one
but larger than the other heading tags.
Let's keep our Each one element in our code but add another element h to that we can use to compare
the size of the H-1 tag versus the H-2 tag.
To do this we will add an opening and closing H-2 tag to our code and give it some text content.
When we run our code in the browser you will see the latest element we added to our Web page or H-2
heading element
as you can see the H 2 element is smaller and stands out less than the one heading.
One reason that the content you put inside of the heading tags is important is that this is the text
search engine pull and use from your webpage.
This means that you should pay careful attention to make sure that you put in the proper key words that
are descriptive of the content of your web page so that it has a good chance of standing out in the
search engine.
If users search similar keywords when browsing the web.
Although each heading has a default size you can specify a custom font size using this style tag.
We will take a closer look at using the style tag in a later letter in the section in the next lecture.
We will learn how we can add paragraph elements and text content to a web page using HMO.