In this lecture we will learn about pseudo elements in CSSA we use pseudo elements to style specific
parts of an element.
There are five pseudo elements in C Ss before after first letter first line and selection double for
pseudo element allows us to insert something before the content of an element to illustrate an example
of this.
Let's create a paragraph element with some text content then we will use the before pseudo element on
our paragraph tag and specify content that should be put before the current content of example text.
For this example let's add a hyphen or dash character before the text.
When we run our code you will see that the hyphen is displayed before the text.
Let's go back to the editor the after studio element lets us insert something after the content of an
element.
Let's go back to our example and change the before pseudo element to after then when we run our code
in the web browser you will notice the hyphen inserted after the text.
Then we will jump back to the editor.
The first letter pseudo element selects the first letter of our text to apply a style to let's modify
our example code so that it uses the first letter pseudo element and changes the color of the first
letter of our text to read.
When we run our code.
Now we should see that in our example text be the color red and the rest of the letters be the default
color black.
Let's go back to the editor using the first line pseudo element.
We can add a style to the first line of a block of text.
Let's change the first letter pseudo element in our example code to first line.
Then when we run our code you will notice that the whole line of text is now the color red.
Then we will go back to the editor the selection pseudo element modifies the style of the part of an
element selected by the user.
Let's change our pseudo element in our example code to selection.
Then when we run our code and select the portion of the text you will notice that the text that we select
is change to the color red in the next lecture.
We will recap what we learned in this section of the core.