In this lecture we will look at a recap of what we learned in this section of the course in this section
we learned about how we can use CSSA to animate HVM elements.
First we learned about transitions.
Transitions are a way that CSSA gives us to gradually transition a property from one value to another.
The transition property allows us to specify a property and duration and it will transition between
the value specified for that property over the specified duration.
We also learned that we could transition multiple properties at once the transition delay property allows
us to specify a delay for our transition.
The transition property allows us to specify the property we want to transition the transition timing
function property allows us to specify that each type or speed curve for our transition of value ease
means that the transition will start slow speed up and then end slow a value of linear will give our
transition a consistent speed a value of ease in will mean that the transition will have a slow start
a value of ease out means that the transition will have a slow and after that we learned about animations
and see SS We learned to write code for our animations starting with our keyframes rule and specifying
a to and from keyframe for animation the animation Name property allows us to link the animation by
adding the name that we gave with the code we wrote for the animation.
The animation duration property allows us to specify a duration for animation the animation delay property
allows us to add a delay to our animation the animation iteration count allows us to specify the number
of times that we want the animation to play.
We can also specify this property value of infinite to make the animation repeat endlessly on our Web
page to control the direction that our animation plays and we can use the animation direction property
of value of normal will specify that the animation placed forward to play the animation backwards.
We can give the animation direction property of value of reverse if the animation direction property
has a value of alternate.
The animation will play forwards and then backwards a value of alternate reverse will make the animation
play backwards and then forwards the animation timing function property allows us to specify that each
type or speed curve of the animation similar to the transition timing functions.
We looked at earlier we could give this property of value with ease linear ease in or ease out and animations
fill mode is how the animation effects an element before and after the animation is played a value of
forward's means that the animation will keep the styles set by the last keyframe of the animation of
value of backwords means that the animation will keep the style set by the first frame of the animation.
During the delay period before the animation is played an animation film mode of both means that for
the delay period before the animation the style specified on the first frame will be applied to the
object and also the styles of the last frame of the animation will be applied to the object after the
animation is finished playing we can use the animation place state property to specify whether the animation
is paused or running the shorthands animation property can be used to specify several animation properties.
These properties are animation name animation duration animation timing function animation delay animation
iteration count animation direction animation film mode and animation place.
After that we learned about 2D animation the transform property allows us to move rotate scale and skew
elements by animating this property on our HVM elements.
We can make our elements move on to our Web page the rotate function lets us rotate our element.
It takes a value of degrees to rotate an element the translate function lets us move our element.
It takes a length value like pixels which is the amount to move the element the scale function lets
a scalar element.
We specify the amount to scale the element as a decimal value from 0 to 1 0 being 0 percent and 1 being
100 percent.
The skew function lets us skew our element the skew function takes a value of degrees at which to skew
the element.
Then we learned about 3D animation.
The main difference between 2D and 3D animation is that 3-D animation includes the Z-axis we can use
the rotate function to rotate our div around the x or y axis creating a 3D rotation effect.
We can also control the back face visibility of our HDMI element by using the back face visibility property
assigning this property of value visible.
Will make the back of the element visible when it isn't facing the front of our webpage in the next
section.
We will learn about animation properties and see SS.