In this section we learned about color and how we can use the properties and functions that CSSA provides
us to modify the color of HVM elements.
We first learned about what types of elements can be colored as we know text can be colored using the
color property the CSSA background color property can be used to give a background color to any HVM
element.
Next we looked at assigning a border collie using the border color property.
We learned how we can specify colors for individual parts of the border by using the border top color
border right color border bottom color and border left color properties to add color to our columns.
We can use the column rule color property to add color to a carrot in an input field.
We can use the carrot color property.
Next we look deeper at how we can specify colors using C.
We learned about some alias's for color names that specified the same color like magenta and fuchsia
or aqua and cyan.
We also learned about two important color keywords and CSSA transparent and current color transparent
allows us to specify a fully transparent color current color is a keyword used to reference the color
specified in that element's color attribute.
We also looked at some of the basic ideas of color theory as they apply to web development.
We learned that there are three types of colors primary secondary and tertiary Primary Colors are the
main base colors of a color system.
Secondary colors are created by mixing two primary colors tertiary colors are created by mixing two
secondary colors.
We also looked at how we can condense six and eight digit hex colors into three and four digit hex colors.
We learned about another color system the hue whiteness blackness color system and how we can use the
HWB function to specify colors using this color system.
After that we learned about saturation saturation refers to the amount of pigment in a color or intensity
of the color the saturate function allows us to modify the saturation of an image if we supply this
function of low value it will lower the saturation of an image if we apply this function of high value
it will increase the saturation of an image.
Then we learned about opacity the level of transparency an image has CSSA gives us the opacity property
to modify the opacity of an image.
Finally we learned about how we can apply filters to image elements by using the filter properties see
SS The Blur filter allows us to blur our image a specified amount the brightness filter allows us to
modify the brightness of our image a specified amount the contrast filter allows us to modify the contrast
of our image to drop shadow filter allows us to add a drop shadow to our image the grayscale filter
allows us to modify the scale of our image the hue rotate filter allows us to rotate the hue of our
image the invert filter lenses to invert the color samples in our image the set the filter allows us
to convert the image to a set the tone the opacity filter allows us to modify the opacity of our image
to saturate filter allows us to modify the saturation of the image we can assign multiple values to
the filter property to combine filter effects on our image.
We can also specify a filter value of None to display the image without any filter applied in the next
section.
We will learn about CSSA properties.