In this lecture we will look at other cool properties that each female gives us access to.
First let's look at the CSA as cursor property which allows us to change the appearance of the mouse
cursor when we mouse over an element assigning the cursor property of value of pointer turns the cursor
into a hand.
First let's create a paragraph element and give it some text.
Then we will add an opening and closing style tag to our code.
We will use the cursor property and give it a value of pointer.
This will change the mouse cursor into a hand when the user mouse is over the paragraph element.
Let's go to the web browser and write our code
when we mouse over the text on our Web page.
You will notice that the cursor turns into a hand.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning the cursor property of value of cross-hair turns the cursor
into a cross-hair when the user mouse is over an element.
Let's give our cursor property a value of crosshair and then go to the web browser and run our code
when we mouseover our text.
You will notice that the cursor turns into a crosshair.
Let's go back to the editor of value of zoomin will turn the cursor into his zoomin icon a magnifying
glass with a plus sign.
Let's give the Kershner property a value of zoom in and then run our code in the browser as you can
see when we mouseover our element.
The cursor turns into the zoomin icon.
Let's jump back to the editor.
A value of zoom out will turn the cursor into a zoom out icon a magnifying glass with a minus sign.
Let's change our code to use the zoom out value for the cursor property and run our code as you can
see when we mouseover text the cursor turns into the zoom out icon.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning the cursor property of value of GRABBE will turn the cursor
into the way it looks and you mouseover text on most web pages a vertical bar in the middle of the icon
and a short horizontal bar at the top and bottom.
Let's change the cursor value to grab.
Then we will run our code in the web browser.
As you can see our cursor turns into the grab icon when you mouse over the text on our Web page.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example.
A value of help will display a question mark next to our cursor.
Let's change the cursor value to help and run our code as you can see when we mouseover the text the
question mark appears next to the cursor.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning the cursor property value of wait we'll turn the cursor into
a wait icon usually in the form of a spinning wheel.
Let's change the cursor value to a wait and then run our code in the browser as you can see when we
mouse over the text cursor turns into a spinning progress wheel we'll then we will go back to the editor
and look at another example.
A value of not allowed we'll turn our cursor into a cross-out symbol we will change the cursor value
to not allowed and then run our code.
When we mouseover the text or cursor changes into a cross-out symbol.
Let's jump back to the editor and look at another example.
A value of auto will allow the browser to decide what type of cursor to display based on what element
you are hovering over.
We will change our cursor value to auto and then run our code as you can see when we mouse over our
text.
It turns into the grab icon then we will jump back to the editor.
We can also assign our cursor an image by passing in the file name as a value.
If you use a custom image you also need to specify a fallback cursor to be displayed in case the image
doesn't load.
Let's give the cursor property value of our cursor P and G image which is a red dot.
We will also specify the Fulbeck cursor to be auto.
We will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see when we mouseover our text the cursor
turns into our custom image.
There may be a time when you want to control what portion of text the user can select to copy and paste.
You can use the user select property to control whether or not the user can select and elements text
assigning this property of value of text allows the user to select the text.
Let's use the user select property and give it a value of text.
Then we will go to the web browser and run our code as you can see we can select and copy the text.
Let's jump back to the editor assigning this property of value of None prevents the user from selecting
the text.
Let's change the user select value to none and then run our code in the browser.
As you can see we cannot select and copy the text in the next lecture we will look at a recap of what
we learned in this section of the course.