In this section we've got hands on practice using the CSSA concepts that we learned in the second half
of the course first.
We stylize the header bar and added some color to it.
We used the link selector to modify the color of the links when they are uncloaked on our Web page.
We also used the visited select to change the color of the visited links on our Web page.
The hover selector was used to change the color of our links when the user hovers over them.
We also used to be active selector to change the color of our links when the user clicks on them.
Then we like the home page.
We use the keyframes rule to create animations we animated the pizza guy and used the transform property
to modifier elements or rotation.
Next we animated the just open sign to make the border become rounded and unrounded.
After that we stylize the About page.
We modified the list style and also added an animation to our text description at the bottom of the
About section which animated the color of the text to cycle through the colors of the rainbow.
Then we added style to the menu page.
We added a border to our menu items and a button pulse animation to the featured menu item.
Next we used CSSA stylize the contact page we added rounded corners to our input fields added a dark
border to whichever field the user is currently typing into added color to the input field when the
user hovers over it and centered and Starlog no button at the bottom of the form.
Finally we separated out our H T M L C Ss and javascript code for a web page into three separate files.
This helps us to keep our code clean organized and easier to manage in the next section.
We will learn about debugging CSSA code.