In this section we got hands on experience using the HVM skills we learned up to this point in the course.
The end result is this example Web site that we built we made a navigation menu that allows the user
to jump to the different parts of our website on the home page we created an image carousel that cycled
through the images using bootstraps code library on the About Us page we added image and text content
including using the paragraph tag image tag and the UL and ally tags to display a list of information.
Then we created a menu for a Web site we used bootstrap cart elements to easily associate an Image title
text and button for each item on our menu.
We also added on click functionality to these buttons using the H team L on click attribute.
Finally we created an H female form where the user could type in their email subject line and message
body.
Since making this form actually send an e-mail would require server side code using a language like
Ajax or ph P which is outside of the scope of this course.
We just made a simple javascript alert display with the information that the user typed in on submission
of the form.
Make sure that you save the code you wrote in this section you will need it later in the course when
we get hands on practice applying CSSA styles to our Web page to add cool features like aesthetics and
animation to it and the next section we will learn about X HMO.