In this lecture we will summarize and recap what we learned in this section.
First we learned how to create an external CSSA style sheet and link it to an HMO file using HVM Elle's
linked tag CSSA files have a file extension of Dotsie SS and HVM all files have a file extension of
either dot each email or dot each.
We learned about three different attributes of each Trimble's the linked tag the Rella attribute specifies
the relationship between the h t m l file and the firelit is being linked to the type attribute specifies
the media type of the file you are linking to the HVM file.
The third attribute of the link tag is the HSF attribute which specifies the file that we want to link.
After that we compared and contrasted when to use an external CSSA style sheet or embed style code directly
into HVM using the style tag.
When we link an external CSSA file to an HCM file it is called external styling.
When we use the style tag to add style information to the team document it is known as internal styling.
If we use the style attribute directly inside of an aliments opening tag to Starlee element we are using
inline styling.
When you are defining styles that will be used across the entire web site.
It is best to use external styling defining your styles in an external CSSA file when you are defining
styles that will affect one web page.
You should embed the style into the page using the style tag.
If you are defining a style that you don't intend to reuse you can use a style attribute directly inside
of an elements opening tag.
Then we looked at some terms common when referring to CSSA syntax.
We learned that a selector is how we tell CSSA code what HDMI element to apply the style to.
There are three types of selectors element selectors ID selectors and class selectors element selectors
or when we directly reference in Elements tagged in the style we specify as applied to all elements
of that same type.
Id selectors are when we use the pound symbol followed by a unique idea signed only to a single H.T.
M-L element.
The style we specify is only applied to the single element that has that Id class selectors or when
we use a period followed by a class name.
The style that we specify is applied to all elements that belong to that class.
Declarations are when we assign a value to a property.
A property is on the left hand side followed by a colon and then a value for that property ended with
a semi-colon.
We learned that comments have the syntax of forward slash asterisk comment text and then asterisk forward
slash.
This applies to both single line and multi-line comment.
After that we learned about CSSA is cascading order which specifies which type of styling takes precedence
if there is a conflict inline styles have the highest precedence followed by internal styles and then
external styles.
And finally browser defaults then we look at the CSA box model a conceptual model used by developers
to understand how each team l elements are laid out and stylize.
Essentially we can think of each h team element as being contained in a box and that box having four
distinct areas content padding border and margins.
The content is the actual element.
For example the image or text padding is inside of the outer bounds of the element and directly affects
the display of the content.
A border defines the outer bounds of an element.
Margins affect the element as a whole but don't directly push against the content of the element.
Finally we looked at padding and margins and CSSA padding a space inside of the contents borders CSSA
gives us 5 properties had padding to an element padding padding top padding right padding bottom and
padding left margins or spaces outside of the borders of an element.
CSSA gives just 5 properties to add margins to an element margin margin top margin right margin bottom
and margin left in the next section.
We will learn about modifying text using C Ss.