In this lecture we will learn about divs and spans nht.
Now when developing using H T.M. you will inevitably find yourself in a situation where you want to
group elements together for logical or styling purposes but these elements may not fall under specific
element categories like Articles section or side that we looked at in the last lecture when we need
a generic container that we can use to logically group HVM elements.
We use the DIV tag the DIV tag is essentially a container used to group other HDMI elements.
This is very convenient for when we want to group elements with different tags.
For example if we wanted to group A H to heading a paragraph and an image together we could just Arap
these elements in their own DIV tag.
For this example we will start with an opening DIV tag.
Then we will add an H to heading element to a web page.
After that we will add a paragraph element with some example text then we will have an image element
that references or Star start PLG image.
Finally we will add a closing DIV tag each of the three elements we just added to our Web page.
The H-2 element paragraph element an image element or all children or elements of the div.
Since there are within its opening and closing tag let's run this code in the browser.
Then we will go back to the editor
we can add an ID to our development to give it its own unique identifier that separates it from all
of our other HVM elements on our Web page.
Let's keep the example code we have and add an ID for our div and this demonstration our ID will be
Group 1 all HMO elements support the ID attribute meaning that we can give any HDMI element its own
unique identifier.
We can also give each element that is grouped inside of our development their own unique identifiers.
Let's give our H-2 element an idea of heading or paragraph element an idea of text and our image element
and idea of image recall that block elements automatically have a newline inserted above and below them
inline elements are usually used inside of block elements and affect the content inside of the block
element the DIV tag is used to group block elements.
If we want to group inline elements we can use a span tag for example if we have a H-2 heading element
and we want to group a few words inside of it we can use the spam tag.
This will make the words we regroup their own span element which can have its own separate style and
other properties added to it.
Let's look at an example of this.
We will start out with an opening h to tag and then some example text midway through our text we will
add an opening span tag and give it an idea of spanne one then we will add some more text content which
will be the content of the span element.
Finally we will add a closing span tag and a closing H-2 tag adding an ID to our span element is useful
because now we can apply a style to this spand element specifically let's build on the code we just
wrote to demonstrate this.
We will start with an opening style tag then a pound symbol that specifies the idea of spanne one that
we gave to our Spanta element and give it a font style of italic then we will add a closing style tag.
Finally we will go to our browser and run this code.
As you can see the text content that we added to our span is displayed in italics in the next lecture.
We will learn about forms and HMO.