In this lecture we will learn about some of the other useful bootstrap elements and classes that we
can use when we lay out our webpage to add color to an element background we can assign it.
One of the following bootstrap classes B.G. primary B.G. success B.G. info B.G. warning B.G. danger
B.G. secondary B.G. dark and D-G light.
Let's look at an example of using one of these classes to color and element's background.
First we will add a div to our Web page and give it a height and A with.
Next let's assign our div one of these classes.
I will choose to give it a value of B.G. primary which will give our give a blue background color to
see the result of the code we just typed.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code as you can see there is now a 100 pixel by 100 pixel
blue square on our Web page.
Let's jump back to the editor.
Another important feature that bootstrap gives us access to is the ability to easily create and stylized
buttons.
First let's create a simple button that we can assign a bootstrap class to.
We will add a button element to our Web page if we add the BT end class to our button.
You will notice that the corners become rounded.
Let's jump to the web browser and run our code as you can see the corners of our button are now rounded.
Let's jump back to the Editor.
However our button is still just a simple gray button if we want to add some color to it.
We can use some of the other button classes that bootstrap gives us access to.
For example we can assign a button a class of BICI and primary.
In addition to the original BTX class that we assigned it to give our button a blue color similar to
the background we gave our div and the last example.
Let's go to the web browser and run our code as you can see.
We now have a blue button on our Web page.
Then we will go back to the editor and look at another example.
Another important bootstrap class is the Jumbotron class which is a large grey box of content to our
Web page.
This is useful for when we want to call attention to something on our Web page and make it stand out
to the user.
Let's look at an example of how we can use this class.
First we will create a div element we will assign our div a class of Jumbotron then we can add a heading
to our Jumbotron using the H 1 through H 6 heading tags.
I will use the H-1 heading tag for this example.
We can also add text to a Jumbotron using the tag.
Let's say a two paragraph elements some example text for this demonstration.
Once we type all of that code we can go to the web browser and write our code.
As you can see there is a large gray block on our screen with the heading and text inside of it.
This is our Jumbotron.
Let's jump back to the editor in Bootstrap.
A card is a box element that we can easily add content to.
It is useful for associating content with other content.
For example if we want to add a title image description and button that is all related to each other
and displayed inside of the same container.
The court is essentially a box container with a border.
Let's look at a basic example of this.
First we relate a development which will be the container for the contents of our card.
We will assign this div a class value of card and a style with a width of 300 pixels inside of this
div.
We will create a second div and assign it a class value of card body.
We can use the card title class to add a title to our card for this example we will use the H 3 element
and give it a class value of card title.
The card text class is used for text content on the card.
We will add text to our card using the paragraph tag and assign it a class value of card text.
Then we will add a button to the bottom of our card.
We will use the button tag and give our button a class value of PTEN and BT and primary.
When we run the code in the browser We will see that our card is displayed and groups all of the content
we added to the card body in the next lecture.
We will recap what we learned in this section of the course.