In this lecture we will learn about working with text in HCM and how we can add paragraph elements and
text to our webpage text of course is a very important part of any webpage.
The paragraph tag allows us to add text to our Web page.
We will start with an opening Peter egg followed by the text we want to display and then a closing tag.
Let's go back to our browser find the file
and drag it into the browser to run our code.
We should see the text that we just added appear.
Let's go back to the editor and look at another example we can use the B tag to display text in bold
going back to the browser and dragging in our file will now show us that our text has been bolded.
Let's jump back to the editor and see how we can display our italicised text.
We can use the tag to display the text in italics.
Let's run this code in our browser to see the italicized text.
We will go back to the idea or write some more code.
To insert a newline into our text we will use the B.R. Teg B.R. stands for break and create a single
line break.
Note that this tag is an empty tag meaning that it doesn't have a closing Ted.
Once we add this tag in the middle of our text we will run our code in the browser to see the effect
of what we just typed.
Let's jump back to Visual Studio code
the pretend or pre-formatted text tag can be very useful for forcing text to be displayed exactly as
it is typed if you want to preserve spaces and line breaks in text.
You can wrap the text in an opening and closing price tag know the difference of the tag and the pre
tag the tag will display any text that you type on a single line unless you specify line breaks using
the B.R. tag.
Even if you manually use the Enter key to put text on multiple lines the p tag will reformat it to one
line.
In contrast the pre tag will store the information exactly as you type it.
So there is no need to use B.R. tags within the pretense.
We will change the tag around our text to be an opening and closing price tag and also add some new
lines manually to our text by using the enter key on our keyboard.
Once we have done that we will jump over to the web browser and drag in our H.M.S. file to see the code
take effect.
Let's go back to the Ed. H2 hymnal gives us access to the block quote tag to define a quotation the
site attribute of the block quote tag will refer to the you are L-A of the web page where you got the
quote.
The site attribute allows us to provide to you or else where we got the quote from.
For this example we will start with an opening blockquote tag and then use the site attribute to point
to w w w dot Google dot com
as content for this element.
We will have some example text.
Finally we can end our blockquote element with a closing blockquote tag when we run this code in the
browser.
We will see the resulting blockquote element that appears on our Web page.
Let's jump back to the editor.
We can use the Q tag to add an inline quotation.
A short quotation that doesn't need its own block of content but can be inline with other text.
We also use the site attribute to link to our source when using the Q tag.
Let's reuse the code from the last example but change the opening and closing tags to queue tag when
we run the code in the browser by dragging over our HMO file you will see the result.
Time to go back to the editor and look at another example.
We can add superscripts and subscripts and HMO.
Remember those xponent for math class to properly display an exponent value.
We can use the superscript tag in this example.
We want to render the text to to the second power equals four.
To achieve this effect we surround the text that we want to be used as the exponent in an opening and
closing superscript tag.
We will start with an opening p tag followed by the number 2 then we will put an opening superscript
tag followed by another two and then a closing superscript tag.
Finally we will add an equal sign.
The number four and a closing paragraph tag.
When we go back to our browser and drag in our HVM file to run the code we should see our equation displayed
in the browser.
Let's go back to the ID.
We can also use the subscript tag to add subscripts to our webpage if we want to display the chemical
compound h to all.
For instance we would surround the two in an opening and closing subscript tag.
For this example we will start off with an opening paragraph tag then a capital H followed by an opening
subscript tag.
Then we will add a to a closing subscript tag a 0 and a closing paragraph tag.
We will go back to our browser and run this code to see the result of what we just typed
in the next lecture.
We will learn about the style attribute and style tag which allow us to start Lizer each DML element.