In this lecture we will recap what we learned in this section in this section we learned about several
properties that CSSA gives us to stylize our elements.
First we learned about properties we can use to modify and element's background the background color
property allows us to assign a color to an elements background the background image property allows
us to assign an image as an element background CSSA gives us the background repeat property to control
how the background repeats the background attachment property specifies if the image scrolls on the
web page scrolls the background position property allows us to position our background relative to our
element.
Next we learned about border properties the border style property allows us to specify a style for our
border.
In addition to giving all four sides of the elements a border you can specify which sides of the border
to assign a style to using the border top style border right style border bottom style and border style
properties assigning the border with property a value of Vic will give our element a thick border.
We can also assign a wish to an individual side of our border using the border top with border right
with border bottom width and border left with properties we can add a custom images a border by using
the border image property.
The border image source property allows us to specify a custom image for a border the border image slice
property enables us to specify how the source image is sliced and displayed border image with allows
us to give our border image with the border image outset property allows us to specify an amount for
the border image to extend outside the bounds of an elements border the border image repeat property
lets us specify how the image will fill the space.
After that we look at box properties that CSX provides us to allow us to modify the elements box.
The combination of its content padding border and margins the box sizing property allows us to specify
whether or not padding and borders should effect and elements width and height we can use the min with
Max with min height and max height properties to specify the minimum or maximum height and width for
elements.
The men with property specifies a minimum with for an element the max with property.
Let's specify the maximum with for an element the min height property specifies the minimum height for
an element the max height property lets us specify the maximum height for an element.
The box Shatto property lets us he had a box shadow tour element.
Then we learned about properties that allow us to stylize are elements outlines an outline is completely
outside of an element and doesn't contribute to an elements overall with or height the outline style
property specifies the style of our outline outline with property specifies a thickness for the outline
we can use the outline offset property to add space between the edges of the element and the outline
CSSA also gives us the outline property which is one property that we can use to specify the outline
style outline color and outline with.
After that we learned about properties that allow us to position elements on the webpage the position
property allows us to specify how an element will be positioned on a webpage.
We can also use the top right bottom and left properties to position our elements the float property
allows us to specify if an image should be displayed to the left or right of text the clear property
lets us specify the sides to not allow an image on the z index property allows us to specify which elements
will appear on top of and below other elements.
Then we learned about the properties CSL gives us for clipping and masking CSSA gives us the clip path
property to define a clip path for image CSSA gives us the mask property to add a mask to our image.
Finally we learned about other useful properties that CSSA gives us access to the CSSA cursor property
allows us to change the appearance of the mouse cursor when we mouse over an element.
You can use the user select property to control whether or not the user can select and elements text
in the next section.
We will learn about how we can style tables and see SS.