In this section we're going to look at more of Python's built in sequence types.
We'll start with lists, coming up in the next video.
Before that though, let's learn a little bit more about what a sequence type is.
So we'll start with the documentation.  I'll paste in the link,
and again, it's in the resources section of this video.
So we're gonna be looking at three basic sequence types in this
section.  That's lists, tuples and range objects.
We've already seen some of the most common sequence operations,
when we looked at strings, in an earlier section.
Although this version of the documentation doesn't include
str as one of the basic sequence types, they are in fact sequences.
So what do I mean when I say sequence?
So I suggest you bookmark this page in your browser, because you'll find it useful to refer to.
We're going to start by looking at the first of these sequence types, lists, in the next video.