in this section we're going to look at
databases and the sqlite database
that's included with the python
standard modules now if we are going to use a
database in our programs it's very
important to understand specifically
what a databases is s think of a
database is just an organized collection
of data that can be used to store
information on a computer or access from
a web server over the Internet
also though if you've used an android or
iOS phone or tablet and run an app on one of
those devices chances are really high
that a sqlite database has been used in
some capacity Android itself uses many
databases to store things like your
contact info text messages and your
browser history search history is also
stored in the database which is how the
Google search on your android phone if
you've got one knows watching search for
previously can then offer suggestions
anything that stores and retrieves
information can really be called a
database these days though the term
database is normally used to refer to
more structured data
now vendor such as Microsoft Oracle and
IBM produce database management systems
based on a relational database over here
data is stored in rows and columns with
a row corresponding to a single record
and the columns representing the fields
that make up a record such as the name
address and date of birth in the case of
a person's record or stock number
description qty in a stock keeping
application
now theirs a huge number of database
systems out there probably the most
well-known of the traditional databases
being sql server oracle and db2 the
Oracle own the Java language after
buying sum micro systems but they were
originally created as a database company
now these traditional databases
typically use structured query language
shortened to sql or SQL depending how
you want to pronounce it and use these
for performing or use a sql for
performing operations such as query and
updating data but is now also a growing
interest in no sql databases used for
storing and processing big data
getting back to android the android
operating system includes a public
domain database engine called sqlite
and Python includes support for
sqlite databases in the standard
library now unlike traditional database
management systems such a sql server
or oracle sqlite is completely
self-contained it doesn't actually need
a separate server to run on now sqlite
was designed to be embedded into systems
originally actually missile guidance
systems so it uses the sql language
which makes it very easy to use if you
already know a bit about databases and
it really means that you can move on to
use another sql database or other
databases once you've learned the basics
of sql with sqlite
and getting back to the history of
sql it was developed originally from
Edgar F Codds work on relational
databases in the nineteen seventies and
became an ansi standard in 1986 now
sqlite implements most of the
features of sql 92 and although their has
been for revisions of the standard since
sql 92 includes everything needed
for most database tasks and just as an
aside text messages on iphone are also
stored in a sqlite database so really
sqlite is used quite
heavily out there
now if you freaking out about now at
the prospect of having to learn yet
another language
don't worry sql is the language but
it's nowhere near as complicated as Java
or Python in fact you can actually do a
lot of database work with only the four
commands select insert update and delete
if you are going to do a lot of database
work then you will need to learn sql
more fully than what we need here and
you'll also need to learn about things
like normalization but the basics that
i'm going to cover will allow you to create programs
that can do basic storage update and
retrieval of information in a database
so sqlite itself has been around
since around the year 2000 it's a very
fast and very stable standalone database
in fact it's the most widely deployed
database engine in the world actually
close to being the most widely deployed
piece of software any kind which is
pretty impressive if you think about it
so if you want to go and check out some
examples of its use in justifications for
the claim that it's the most widely
deployed database engine in the world
check out....
....
you can also find more information out
about sqlite that same website
just visit...
or if you happen to have
been on the other pages click on the
sqlite logo to get back there good
information on that site you want to
find out more about sqlite
alright so let's start off in the next
video by having a look at some basic
database terminology for things like
tables records and fields recordsets and
why they're important and after we've
done that we'll then move onto actually
using sqlite to create databases
and store information but in the next
video as i mentioned we'll go ahead and
start looking at that terminology see
you in the next video