Now that we can perform calculations and
display the results, it's time to move on
to see how we can get Python to make
decisions and perform tasks repeatedly.
Like many programming languages, Python
works in blocks of code. One of the
design principles of Python, though, was
that it should be uncluttered and
easy to read. Because of this, Python doesn't use
delimiters around blocks of code.
If you've used other programming languages,
you may be used to seeing braces,
that's left and right curly braces, or BEGIN and
END around code. Python doesn't use
anything like that, but instead uses
indentation to indicate when a new block starts.
I've opened the exchange_chart program in IntelliJ
so that I've got some code to talk about.
Now you won't need this file in your project.
We're not going to be running it
in this section. This is one of the few
times in the course when you won't be
typing along. So relax, sit back and
watch the video, as l show you blocks
of code in this program.
Alright, so let's look at the blocks of code in this
program, firstly, starting on line 66,
we've got a for loop. That starts a new
code block and we can see that line 67
through to lines 82, which is just off
screen, well it's actually on-screen but
I'll move up a little bit more, like so.
So you can see those lines 67 to 82,
they're all part of that code block,
which is the for loop defined on line 66.
Now I don't want you to try and
understand the code here, because most of
it probably won't make sense at this
point in the course. You should be able
to work out that line 67, though, is using
replacement fields, and I'll just move that
over a little bit more so we can see it,
and that's using a replacement field to
put the year and month at the end of
that URL. But most of this code in
general will be confusing, and that's
fine. What we're interested in now at the
moment are the various levels of
indentation. So concentrate on the shape
of the code and we'll learn what it all
means in due course. Alright, so we've got
a block of code from line 67, through to
and including lines 82. We can make it
easier to see the blocks by turning on
indentation guides. Now most modern IDEs
will have a similar feature.
In IntelliJ, you go into Settings.
Now that's Preferences if you're using a Mac.
In my case, I'm on a Windows machine,
and it'll be the same for Linux, File, I'm
going to select Settings.
You want to then navigate to Editor, then down to
General and then here into Appearance.
You want to make sure that the Show
indent guides is actually checked, so I'm
going to check that now. Click OK,
and you can see now that IntelliJ draws guides
to show the indentation levels. You can
see that slight, really gray, light gray
line now in the indentation. So line 67
and line 69 are indented one level.
So below that, line 70 is indented another
level, line 72 is also at that second level
and so are all the lines 74 to
79, and you can see there's a third level
of indentation on lines 80 through 82. So
each level of indentation is a new block of code.
So let's see them again. The main
code has no indentation and starts
up against the left margin. Lines 67 to 82
are all part of another block of code,
and are indented one level. The
convention is to indent four spaces at a time.
Within that second block we have
other blocks for lines
70 and 72 and also lines 74 to 82, then
finally there's a fourth block, lines 80 to 82.
So that's how we create blocks of
code in Python.
Now I haven't explained why you want to
do that. At the moment we're looking at
what a code block is. So as you can see, a
block of code can contain other blocks.
We start a new code block by indenting
the code. Now have you noticed anything
else about the lines that start a new
code block?
Well lines 66, 69, 71, 73 and 79 all start a new code block.
If you examine those lines carefully,
hopefully you can spot something
that they all have in common.
Did you spot it? Well all those lines end
in a colon. Whenever a line ends with a colon,
Python will expect a new code block to follow it.
That means that the next line must
be indented. When you've finished
all the code for a block,
you remove the indentation
for the next line. The blocks of code on
lines 67 to 82 finished with line 82,
because the indentation for the next
line is removed, and you can see that
line 84, right towards the bottom of
the screen, isn't indented. Line 72 is a
code block containing only one line.
Line 73 is indented back one level.
There's another code block a bit further down
and I'll scroll that so you can see it,
and the the block of code on lines
87 to 88. You can see those there.
Only those two lines are indented, which means only
those two lines are part of the for loop.
Once again, don't worry about the code,
just concentrate on how indentation is
used to create a new code block. We're
learning why in the rest of this section.
Alright so that's the end of the
demonstration and what code blocks are.
Next we'll see how to create them. So I've
created a new project for this section
and I've called the project ProgramFlow,
which probably isn't very imaginative.
You may want to call your project
something else, like flow control or
program flow or something of that nature,
or something that makes sense. I'm going
to close this file now because we are
done with it for now. Close it down.
So what I'm going to do is click on my
project to open it. I'm going to right
click it, select New, Python file and
let's go with the name, blocks.
Alright and I'll just close down the project pane to
make a bit of space. Now I'm going to start with
some code that we've seen before. It
still won't make sense but it will let us
see how to create a code block. So I'm
going to type on the first line, for i in range
parentheses 1 comma 13 right
parentheses and a colon. Now when I type
that colon, IntelliJ IDEA is showing an
error. If I hover the mouse over it,
you can see a description that says indent
expected. So if I then press ENTER here,
you see that the error has now moved to the
next line, and that can be very confusing.
You've hardly typed anything and you've
already got an error. Don't worry,
you will sometimes get things like this
until you finish typing the code.
IntelliJ's trying to make sense of
code that isn't finished yet, and it gets
a bit confused, and most IDEs will do
the same thing if they provide syntax checking
while your type, like IntelliJ is doing.
Helpfully though, IntelliJ has
automatically indented that new line,
when I pressed enter. So I'm going to start
typing print. You can see there that was
already indented for us. I'm gonna finish
this line, print left parenthesis,
double quotes, No, we'll put number, or No for short,
period, then left and right curly braces,
squared is, and left and right curly
braces again,
and cubed is.
Then we want our left and right curly braces again, but within those we're going to put : 4.
We have talked about this in a previous section,
finishing off the double quote and put
dot format parentheses i comma i ** 2 comma i ** 3
and two right parentheses to finish the line. Note that
that's now cleared the error, and notice
also that the cursor is automatically
positioned when I press ENTER now,
at the same level of indentation.
Now if we wanted more code inside the loop,
we just keep typing. There's only one line I
want in this block, so we're going to use
the backspace key now to delete the
indentation, and you can see just one
backspace went right back to the start.
Now if you want to indent again,
press the tab key.
Notice that the IDE adds four spaces
and removes four spaces, when I use
backspace again. So it knows, in other words,
that we're in a code block and
automatically adds the correct number of
spaces for us. Now you can also select
a line of code and use shift tab to
remove a level of indentation. To see
what I mean I'm going up to line 2.
I'm gonna hold down shift and press tab.
I can indent it again with tab,
shift tab to remove the indentation and tab again to edit.
Alright, so moving on to the
next line now, line 3, I'm going to
type print parentheses double quotes,
and put an asterix in the double quotes, then * 80, right parenthesis.
Now if I run this program,
we can see we get the squares and cubes
printed, followed by a line of asterixes.
So the block of code inside that for
loop executes 12 times. but we only get a
single line of asterixes at the end, and that's
because line 3 isn't part of the block.
However, we can make it part of the
block by tabbing it across. So come over
here on line 3 and tab it over, so it's
now indented at the same line or same
level as line 2. If we run the program again,
notice that we get a very different result this time.
The output's very different, as you can see there.
Both lines are now part of the same
block and therefore both lines get
executed 12 times. Alright, so that's
how we create a code block using the tab
key to indent the code. We're also
starting to see why we might want to do that.
We get very different results when
we include line 3 in the block,
compared to having it outside of the block.
The code still won't make a lot of sense.
What are for and range? Well that's some of the
things we'll be looking at in the rest
of this section, but now that we
understand what code blocks are,
we can start to use them in our code.
We'll make a start on that when we look at
telling Python how to make decisions, in the next video.