So in this video we're going to download
and install Python for the Windows platform.
Now if you're running on a Mac
or a Linux machine, skip this video and
refer to the appropriate video for your
operating system, which is in this section of the course.
If you're on a
Windows platform we're gonna start by
going to python.org,  which is the official Python website.
Now I'm not going to select
to download there at the moment, cos if we
come over here and select it'll start
downloading, but if we come down to windows instead,
note that we've got a version there, for both X64, which is
x86 64, which is a 64-bit version of
Windows, and a 32-bit. So you will need
to download the appropriate version for
your operating system. If you're not sure
whether you're running a 32 or a 64-bit
version of Windows, we can come down here,
and just type in under here, 32. That'll pop
up this little thing here and see if you
have a 32-bit or a 64-bit version of Windows.
Check on that, and if that didn't work,
you can just go into About in system
settings, and that would also get you there.
And note down here under system
type we've got, in my case, 64-bit operating
system, so that tells me that I'm running
a 64-bit version of Windows, and thus I
need to download the 64-bit version of
Python.
Now if yours doesn't say 64-bit but
instead says 32-bit, then obviously you'll
need to download the 32-bit version.
Alright so I'm gonna close that down,
and go back to the Python browser, and in my case,
what I'm going to do is select
the executable installer for a 64 x86 64 which means 64-bit.
If you're on a 32-bit machine, you would select that version down here, just the x86.
Alright so I'm gonna click on executable. I'm gonna select run. Now that that's popped up I'm going to
close down the browser, and you can see
confirmation there that I've selected the
64-bit version of Windows. Importantly
before we start, make sure you check this
box down here, Add Python 3.7 to path, and
that's so that you can access Python
from the command line, which will become more important in future videos.
For now though, now that we've
done that, we can come up here and click
on Install now, click on that. We're going
to click on and select yes to that, and
we'll let it go through and finish the
installation of Python now.
Alright so at this point now, we don't
need to do anything else. We click on
Close, and we've now installed Python for
the Windows platform.
So at this point you can now skip
forward to the install IntelliJ IDEA
installation video,
and bypass the Mac and Linux versions
of the Python installation, cos we've now
installed Python for the Windows platform.
I'll see you in that
installation video, IntelliJ IDEA, next.