All right just before we move on now with his course, I've actually got a set of free video resources
that I suggest you check out.
Now, these videos are freely available on YouTube, and there's a link to this playlist of videos in the
next video - in the next lecture, I should say, here on Udemy.
Now the purpose of these videos, which I've put together and then continuing to record, is to give you
a resource to answer the most common questions that relate to programming.
Now these quote these videos on YouTube aren't going to teach you how to program.
And that's because that's what this course is all about.
But they answer a lot of very common questions. Things like how long does it take to become a programmer?
Do you need to have good math skills to become a programmer?
Am I too old to start a career in programming? How to transition from another career to programming?
and lots of other questions. And I answer questions like that on the YouTube channel. And I'm putting
them on the YouTube channel because it's a resource that I can give out freely to all my students.
There's no catch there's no obligation it's totally free.
So check that out, and you can click on the link in the next lecture here on Udemy to access that playlist.
And when you get there I suggest you click on this little icon here, it's the subscribe button and then
also click on the little bell notification, and what that does is send an email, or YouTube rather
will send you an email, every time I release a new video.
Now I'm currently releasing a new video six days a week, and the other important thing here, the other important
thing to mention here, is that if you've got a question relating to a career or something of that
nature, you can leave it as a comment on any of those videos.
And I'll actually follow that up with a video in the future.
So it's a resource there for you, to really help complement the skills you learn in this course and
answer a lot of your career related questions.
That of course we all have when we're starting out in a career in programming.
All right so that's enough about that, I just wanted to throw that out there. A link, as I said, in the next video.
But for now let's continue on with the videos in this course.