Alright, so let's look at improving the
code that we've been working on, in the
last few videos. Looking at our menu
first, on lines 21 through 27. So our menu
options can, effectively, be stored as a
list, and what we can do is then iterate
over the list, using a for loop to print
out the options. So to do that, what we
need to define a list and we'll
do that right at the top of the program,
on line one. Alright, so I'm gonna start by
typing available_parts is
equal to left square bracket double
quotes computer double quote comma.
Next line, monitor in double quotes comma,
next line, double quotes keyboard double
quote, next line mouse in double quotes
comma. Next line, mouse mat in
double quotes comma and then finally our hdmi cable in double quotes. And I'm gonna press
ENTER to leave the square bracket, on
a line by itself, on line 7. Now that
we've done that, we can come down and
have a look at our code on lines 28 through 34,
and we can replace that with a for loop.
So I'm gonna start by deleting that code
now. Then I'm going to tab over to the
same indentation level and I'm going to
type for_part in available_parts colon, print and in
parentheses, part.
Alright, so let's run the program.
It's still working, as you can see, so we're
part of the way there. We've got the
parts printed out but we haven't got the
number. The customer's no way of knowing
which numbers to type in. Now we
could get the index of each part and add
one to it. So what I mean is, we'll close down this program.
So again, what I'm saying we
could do here is, change the print, print
parentheses double quotes left and right
curly braces 0, then right clearly brace
colon, and the same for 1 - left and
right curly braces with a 1 in the
middle there, double quote dot format. And
then in parentheses, available underscore
parts dot index,
and in parentheses, after the index part
and outside of the right parentheses,
plus 1 comma space part, and then two
right parentheses to finish the line. So
we could do that. What I've done there is,
I've used string formatting and
replacement fields there, to display the
index number and the part, and I'm adding
one to the index, and that's because
indexes start at zero. We want the first
number to be number one on the screen,
rather than number zero. So let's run the
program to see that it works, and you can
see that the menu's appearing now, with
numbers. Now you may get a dialog saying
that buy.computer's not allowed to run in
parallel, if you didn't exit when you
last ran. You saw that I closed down the
program. And again, you've seen it a few
times - just click stop and rerun to run
the latest version, if you get that
dialog. But getting back to our code - that
looks good, and if we add new items to a
list, they should automatically appear in
the menu. Let's try that. I'll exit out of
the program. So let's add another item
here. We'll add a dvd drive - dvd drive and
I need to add a comma on the
previous line, and now if I run the program,
I've only changed it in one place. Notice
that the dvd drive is appearing as
option 7. Now looking at the code,
we still need to change this code - the code
on lines 15 through 26 - and we're going
to do that soon. Before we do that, though,
I want to show you a better way
of writing lines 29 and 30. What we've done
there isn't very efficient, and that's
because Python has to look up each item
in the list, in order to get its index
position. And that's not very efficient,
especially if you start dealing with
huge lists. Index can be useful, but if
you see it being used in a for loop
like we're doing, then there's a much
more efficient way, and we'll see what
that is in the next video.