Alright so in the last video, we talked about the two challenges but I didn't really explain in detail what
they were.
So the first file challenge1.py,
remember you can get that from the resources section of the last video.
The challenge for that first one is to rewrite the following code to use a list comprehension, instead
of a for loop, and you can see the for loop on lines 10 and 11.
Now you need to add your solution below the loop, so that the resulting list is printed out below the
output, so it makes it easier to check that it's producing exactly the same list and avoids entering the input
text twice.
So basically, we're going to do that.
So let's go ahead and look at that first.
And you can see that we've helpfully got a comment here
to say type your solution here, and that's exactly where we're going to start typing it.
And by the way, I mentioned down here that it could be useful to store the original words in a list
as well.
The for loop would look like this;
down here you can see the example of that,
and notice the extra parentheses so that we get tuples in the list. You can see the extra parentheses there
on line 23. But we'll get to that shortly.
We're going to do this first bit first.
So for the first part, our comprehension will iterate over the list that's produced by splitting up the
input text.
Now we want the length of each word,
so the comprehension's going to use the len function for that. So lets type in the code and we can see how
we go about that.
So I'm going to start on line 16, answer is equal to, left and right square brackets because it's a comprehension,
a list comprehension, len parentheses x for x in text dot split parentheses.
Then on the next line we can print parentheses answers, or answer I should say.
So basically, we want the length of each word and the comprehension's using the len x function, as you
can see on line 16, the same as the for loop did. Nothing unique there.
So lets run the program to make sure it works.
And obviously, we'll see the for loop version running as well.
Now for the text, we're going to go with What have the Romans
ever done for us.
So you can see that we've got the same output for both the for loop and also for the comprehension.
So that's a good start.
Now for this second part of the challenge, I mentioned that it could be useful to store the original words
in the list as well.
Now the for loop would look like the example you can see there with the extra parentheses, so that
we get tuples in the list.
And obviously, you're going to type your corresponding comprehension down here on, starting on line 29.
So basically, we want a tuple containing the original word and it's length.
Let's go ahead and type in an answer to that.
And we'll start this one on line 30: answer is equal to left and right square brackets, parentheses x comma space len
left and right parentheses, x then we've got two closing parentheses as you can say there, then 4 x in text dot split
parentheses. Then we'll print the answer on the next line,
print parentheses answer. So basically, is we're producing a tuple containing the word and its length.
And what I'll do is, I'm just going to copy the exact same output that we typed in up here. Run the code,
and once again, you can see our comprehension produces the same list as the original for loop did. Converting
a for loop to a comprehension is quite straightforward, and they're a very useful addition to your programming
tool kit.
Now before I move onto the solution to the second challenge, there's a couple of things to say about
this one.
Now the first is, we probably don't want duplicates. In other words, if the same word appears more than once
in the input,
there's no point in counting it twice.
So to get around that,
what we could do is use a set comprehension instead.
Now we've already seen how to do that, to convert a list comprehension to a set comprehension.
We just replace the square brackets with curly braces.
So let's go ahead and do that,
and let's run that. Now I'm going to provide a different input string here,
so we've got some duplicated words.
So the input text contains repeated words in the input.
OK, save that, and you can see in this example down here now, we get a set returned,
and because sets don't contain duplicates, we get each word only once.
Now note that the words aren't necessarily appearing in order.
In fact, they're definitely not in order as you can see here. We've got the word 'contains' here, c is after the letter r
alphabetically, and that's because by definition there's no ordering in a set.
Now you'll probably be doing this to produce some sort of metrics, such as an average word length for example,
and therefore the ordering wouldn't be important.
Now when you're considering using a comprehension,
remember that set comprehensions can also be quite useful.
They work the same as list comprehensions and can be very useful for avoiding duplicates.
OK so the next thing isn't really a problem with comprehensions.
It's got to do with the way that split works.
So we split our text up to get words,
and it works fine as long as each word's separated from the next with white space - white spaces, space tabs
and the new line characters, although we can't enter line breaks in the input. Now to see what I mean,
let's run the program again and use some punctuation.
So this time we're going to enter What have they
comma the Romans comma ever done for us, ever done for us
with a question mark on the end, enter. Now the program still works, but they now show, for example, the word 'they' over
here, as being of length five, five characters, and that's because of the comma after the word 'they'.
We've also got 'Romans' showing a seven as well, and 'us' even having three over here, and that's because of
the question mark.
Now I'm mentioning this because we can use a nested comprehension to fix it.
Remember the problem, and we'll come back to it when we look at nesting comprehensions later.
Right,
so that's the first challenge. I'm going to close down that challenge1.py now.
So the second challenge, we had to create a list comprehension to convert a tuple from inches to centimetres.
And just as a note here, in case it's not obvious, a list comprehension produces a list, but it doesn't
have to be given a list to iterate over.
Now you can use a list comprehension with any iterable type.
So we're going to write a comprehension here - that was your challenge - to convert dimensions from
inches to centimetres.
Now our dimensions will be replaced by tuple for the length, width and height, and as a reminder it's 2.5
4 centimeters to 1 inch.
And then down here, once you've got the correct values, change the code to produce a tuple rather
than a list.
Alright, so we've got our code there printing out the measurement, and again in case it's not obvious, a list
comprehension produces a list, but it doesn't have to be given the list to iterate over - that's the important
part.
And that's really why I actually created this challenge in the first place, really just
to demonstrate that a comprehension can use any iterable type or sequence.
You don't have to provide a list to a list comprehension. So the list, or set, in list comprehension refers
to the type of object produced by the comprehension. Alright, so we've got the value here, so on line 13, let's now
enter our comprehension. I'm going to delete that code there in between the square brackets,
and we're going to go with inch
multiplied by two point five four for inch in inch underscore measurement.
I'll leave the code to print the cm underscore measurement.
So the comprehension iterates over each item in the tuple, and multiplies it by the number of centimeters
in an inch, two point five four.
So let's actually run this to confirm that it works.
And you can see we've correctly got the values there,
seven point six two, twenty point three two and fifty point eight. Alright, now our
next part here, we need to convert the code to produce a tuple rather than a list.
All we have to do is parse the comprehension to the tuple function to get that to work.
So let's add the code there to do that. Now line 18, we'll do a cm underscore measurement is equal to tuple,
then we want parentheses, then we need to add the list comprehension to the tuple call. So in left to right
square brackets,
it's going to be -
now I could just paste that code in, but I'll just quickly type it in - inch times two point five four, for
inch in inch underscore measurement. And then on the last line we'll print out
cm_measurement again.
So basically, this call here on line 18 is converting a tuple of values in one unit, inches here, to an
equivalent tuple using another set of units, centimetres.
And I think that's pretty impressive for one line of code,
but lets actually just run it to make sure we do get the right results.
We've now got the identical results in a tuple.
Alright, so I'm going to stop the video here. In the next one, we're going to look at adding conditions to our comprehensions.
So I'll see you in the next video.