In the previous videos, we stored some strings in variables, without really explaining what was going on.
So let's have another look at strings.py. I'll open that up.
We created that of course, if you recall, in an earlier video.
If you want to download these slides.
In fact the entire slides for the course, go to the very last video this one here in the course.
Right down the bottom there, and watch that video? It's only a short one, and it gives the details of how to go about downloading,
these slides. And it also has got access to, or gives you access to a document with lots of other information career advice,
and so on and so forth. So watch that bonus video to download the slides.
So in this code, strings.py, we've got a
string with the value Hello.
That's on line 6 as you can see.
We've attached the name greeting to it.
Whenever we use the name greeting in our code,
Python knows that we're referring to the string, Hello.
On line 7, we use the input function to get some text from the user.
Whatever they type in will be stored in memory, and we attach the name, name, to it.
And you can see there on lines 8 and also on lines 11,
we use those variables to print out the strings.
The Python documentation uses the word bound instead of attached.
It would say that the variable greeting is bound to the string Hello
So what we can do is create another variable called age and bind, or attach it, to the value 24,
and then print it out. So let's have a go at doing that.
I'm gonna come down on line 14 and type age equals 24
And the next line, print parentheses age.
Alright, I don't want to have to keep typing my name in every time we run this program,
so I'm going to go ahead and change line 7 here.
I'm just going to change the input just to a double quote, or set of double quotes and the word Tim.
Alright. So if we run this now, I need to right-click because we're now using strings instead of escapechar,py.
There's no surprises when we run the program. We get the two greetings printed, followed now by the value 24.
In the introduction to Python video, I said that Python is a dynamically typed language,
and also a strongly typed language.
This is a good time to see what that means. So I'll start by explaining what we mean by type.
There are a number of data types built into Python. We've already seen the string and integer types.
Greeting is a string type, and age is an int.
But you don't have to take my word for that. We can ask Python what type it thinks they are.
I'm going to go ahead and type some code for that.
So we'll come down here on line 17, I'm going to type print parentheses type parentheses greeting,
And the two closing parentheses, right parenthesis.
Then line 18, print, same thing there but this time with age, so type parentheses and age,
and the two closing right parenthesis.
So if you run this code now,
and you can see that Python reports that greeting is an object of type string, str, while age is an object of type int.
And it's using the term class there, but we'll talk more about class a little bit later.
But these abbreviations, str and int, are Python abbreviations for string and integer, respectively.
Python's got other types built-in as well.
The float type, for example, that lets you work with numbers that have a decimal part.
We can also create our own types, and we'll be doing that later
So type, which is also called data type, describes the kind of information that we're storing.
It's so usual to talk about a variable being of a certain type,
but it can be more useful to think of values having a type, rather than variables.
When we use the value 24 in our code, Python stores that value somewhere.
The type of the value is int, it's an integer value.
We bound the name age to it, which makes age have the type int.
In Python, you can rebind a name to a different value.
So, for example, we can come down here, and on line 20, I can type age equals, and double quotes, 2 years.
So that stores now, the string value 2 years in memory, and binds the label age to it.
That wouldn't be possible in many other languages.
Once a variable has a type, you can only assign values of that type to it.
Java and C are examples of languages that behave in that fashion.
And that's why I said it can be more useful to think of the value as having the type, than the variable in Python.
Here, age is now bound to a string value. It's no longer an int, it's a string, so let's confirm that.
I'm going to print it out, and then print its type out.
So I'll start on line 21, typing print parentheses age,
on line 22, print parentheses type parentheses age.
And we'll run the code.
Alright, and as you can see, we've now got 2 years and class string showing for our variable age.
So line 20
looks like we're assigning the string value two years to a variable called age,
and that would be true in other languages such as C and Java.
In Python though, it's more helpful to say that we've rebound the label age to the string value 2 years.
So I'll finish by saying that programmers have been talking about assigning values to variables
for, now, over 60 years.
It's become the way we speak and you'll find Python programmers talking in that way.
And you'll probably notice me do it too, in these videos.
It's not wrong, but some things will make more sense if think about a variable as a name or label,
that's bound to a value.
Alright, so I'll stop the video here, and in  the next one, we'll see why python is a strongly typed language.
See you in the next video.