so going back looking at our code again if we opened up song.py and I just closed down
the run window incidentally I just want
to point out that the line on 132 the
print that format doesn't work with Python 2 so in another words Python 2 doesn't
allow printing in that way but you can
import the print function from the
future module if you wanted to work again
just for Python 2 so if your running Python
3 you don't need to do this but I'm just going to quickly show how to that fi you happen to be running Python 2
just come up here onto the first
line and add an import
....
intelligence saying are you using
something from an older version of Python so click on no
for now
so from __future__
import....so if you added that to your Python code and added 2 blank
lines for Python 2 you find that
this should work and that print statement that
I pointed out should work on Python 2 but I'm gonna delete that now because
of course we're dealing with Python 3
so we ran it and then we had a quick look
at albums.txt and check.file.txt
in the previous video and they seem to be the same so what we can do as I alluded to
we can compare 2 files in IntelliJ
so the way to compare two files you just
select them so albums.txt and holding
command and clicking check file and holding control if you're on Windows or
Mac and once you've selected both here on the left hand
side you can come up here to the view
menu and click on compare files or could have done a command D or a control d on Windows or Linux so
click on compare files and its open up a window and has put contents are identical you can see
that's actually compared with
or compared both files and incidentally
just going back to the code and if
you select one file click one like that
you can then go to view and click on compare with
the second file you can actually grab
that file literally from another
project if you wanted to compare it that
way so that's really useful if your comparing files that are
in different projects such as your own
code compared to the code downloaded
from the resources for this course for
example so you don't have to have the 2 files
comparing within the same file but just having
a look at that the compared results their
again looking at this it's probably a
good indication that the program is
reading the data correctly but it
doesn't prove at the moment and the
program doesn't have any errors and as
it turns out there's actually quite a
serious flaw in the program but the test
data doesn't reveal it and it's very
important to test program with a range
of different inputs and be very
suspicious of data that is to neat such as the
example take albums.txt file so we just close this
comparison down and go back to the albums.txt
examining that files it's nicely ordered with the album for each artist following on
from each other and all the songs for an
album group together but real world data
often and probably usually isn't like that and
so we should at least probably scramble the
file up a bit to be able to test this
properly now it doesn't take much
scrambling to reveal the errors so we are gonna edit albums.txt
and what i'm gonna do is cut out all the songs for zz top albums so come down here to
zz top right down the bottom so what I'm gonna do is I'm going to cut out all the songs zz top album antenna
this line 657 down through 668 so cut those command x on a Mac and
make sure I delete the extra line as well be
control X on Windows or PC and what I'm gonna do
is I'm going to actually put them in a
different spot in the file so go back up back
up to the top and put them somewhere
completely different say aerosmith will do so
let's put it
somewhere around here so maybe between
permanent vacation and jim so just
here lets just put it in their so we are putting it in a different order now just to see what happens if we try and run this
and again I made sure that there's no
blank lines either the lines I've
added here or back where I cut it out which
was on lines 650 making sure
that there is no other lines there and
there is a blank line on the line at
the end of line 685 which I have left I haven't touched that so we've now split
two artists albums up a little bit
remembering that last time when we ran this
it resulted in twenty-eight artists
so lets run this again and we got a different
result as you can see here we've now got their are 30 artist and again
remembering those 28 last time when we ran
this in the previous video and
we just go and do that
comparison again
so albums.txt and check file selecting them both
again and click on view and compare
files and just open that compare files results but it still
says in the top left hand corner
contents are identical but its now reporting
their is 30 artists so obviously somethings
is badly wrong here because we only had
twenty eight artists in the previously
video we've now got 30 but yet the output is still the
same so the point that we're making here
is really does illustrate how important
it is when you testing to test with
varied data sets ok so that is the problem so onto
what or how to go about fixing it
problem is that each artists boundary in the
data causes a new artist object to be
created without considering whether
there's already an object for that artists
so as a result we end up with two
objects for Aerosmith and to for zz top
as it turns out the code to fix this
is quite easy
you really just have to check to see it is
already an artist in the list before
creating a new artist object and to do the
same each time a new albums found
but rather than fixing this version though
we're going to go ahead and use a
slightly different approach
now the way that this program
currently works does have some
disadvantages including the need to
check if there's an outstanding artist
or album record at the end of the
this is the code down here on line 116 onwards
so we have to do that final check for the
last line so the method uses
easy-to-understand and sometimes it is
necessary to do things this way as an
example with restoring the data in a data
base and we might want to ensure that
an artist had at least one album before adding them to
the database now with some data such as
financial records it may also be a
requirement to wrap the database
insertions into a transaction so that
either all the data of an artists including
albums is written or not if it is so that
way there's no chance of incomplete data
being stored in the database
similarly you may need to make sure that
all the song for an album are added when
the album is added or abandoned the attempts
to store the data  altogether so taking this approach
of not adding the object to their lists
until the related data has been read
from a file is one way to sort of
achieve this that doesn't really apply to
this particular example though because
all the data will fit in memory but with
a data file that was to big for available
memory would really be necessary to
store the records as soon as everything
related to an object had been read so
although the algorithm that we've used may
not be the best for this particular case it
can be useful in other cases and that's
why that we've actually included it here
and algorithm is a series of steps
for solving problems so I've described the
algorithm for this approach briefly
before writing the load_data function but I'm gonna bring up a flow chart to
show this little bit more formerly and I'll just bring it up on the screen their now you can see I've got flow chart here
so this is really describing what's
what's really happening now with the
flow of the program code and it can be
useful if you haven't seen these before
to investigate and find out more about
flow charting when your trying to
put together how something works it can be useful to put this together but you can see what
is happening here is that we're starting
the process it's reading some data it is
then splitting the data into the various
fields
and you've seen that before and we start with a comparison
here is the artist the same as the field
field being what we have read in if it is the same then it flows over to here we do another check is the album the same as the
field
if it is we are going to add song to album checking to see if there's any
more data if their is it goes back and
sort of reloops through and in the case of
their wasn't anymore data will save the
artists and then we stop bullets so that is in that
scenario their and that is with the
artists was the same as the field but if
the artist isn't the same as the field then we
save the artists and we created that artist object and we move to here and we go through this decision
again to see to check whether the
album's the same as the field it is
it comes over to hear then adds the song to the album object and sort of flows
though their that we have talked about before that
sort of process to be reading more
lines of data or we reach the end to
save the artist and stop but in the case of the
album not being the same as the field
we save the album and the artist
object we created the album object
then come up back up to here and then we
add the song to the album  object and go
through to this point again so basically
artists objects isn't saved until the new
artists is found in the data set or
when their no more data to read now as I mention
this could be a reasonable approach to
take in some circumstances but I'm gonna
change things so that new objects are
save as soon as they created so we are not using a database here so by save what I mean is
their stored in their respective lists so the
flowchart of that is going to be a bit
different so let me bring them up on the
screen so close that one down here is the 2nd
flow chart so the main difference with this one
and I'm not gonna go through it all then
now but you can sort of go through that at your leisure
but outlining the major difference and
that's that the objects are save as soon
as they created and that means that an
artist we put into the list before any
albums are added to it likewise an album
object is going to be added to the artists list of albums before any songs have been
added to it now if we were
using a database to store these details what
that means is that if something goes
wrong we could end up with albums in a
database for with some songs missing but for
this example though you know when where
we're reading everything into memory the
code using the new
algorithm ends up being a lot simpler
so I'm gonna add some extra steps to check
if an artist or album already exists and
if they do then the existing objects can
be retrieved from the list instead of
creating a new one so to do that
lets introduce a slightly more complicated version so lets
bring up the flow chart for that so I'll
close this one down and lets open up the
third flow chart and you can see the new
sequence here to check to see whether
the artists already been stored if it has
only been stored its gonna retrieved the
artists and flow on and
likewise when we tested for the album is
the album already stored if yes we are gonna retrieve the
album's first and then move on to that
if it hasn't of course we are going to
create the album object and of course over here if the artist hadn't
been stored then we create it
which we need for the first time one
thing that probably stands out looking
at this flowchart is that the new steps
that have been added into the flow for
both artist and album practically
identical and this sounds good candidate
for function so I'm gonna start by and going
back to the code and looking at adding a
find object function before load data but we will start working on that in the next
video