in the previous video we did our
first part of the challenge and that's
where we set up this cave underscore initialize dot py
which ultimately save
our locations and vocabulary
dictionaries to convert them to shelves
what we wanna do now is we want to change
the code that runs the game the actual
game itself and make the changes so that
instead of using a dictionary it uses
the shelves created we created in this so what I'm going
to do is go back to
challenge you see that cave_game.py that is the file name we want to use for the
game part of it so we are going to
create that new python and its going to be
cave_game.py and what I'm gonna
start with is just a copy this code in line 45
from the challenge.py through to the
end and paste that to
cave_game.py so that's the basic
game so obviously we got some erros showing
at the moment because we haven't got the
locations and the vocabulary set up so we
need to actually do that we need to come
up here initially on line 1 we need to
import shelve of course because we are going to use the shelve module.....
and the other thing we need
to do while we remember is down here we ill close
them so....always have to do that
remember, if we are not using with to close things manually which is we have done there
the other change we need to make is on line 6
you notice it currently we got loc equals
one and that's an integer I want to
change that so its initialize to a
string because of course if you recall
in cave_initilaize.py we
set it up so we will use strings because
of course shelves need to use strings
as keys s so because locations is gonna
be key ultimately that will need to be
a string so I'm gonna put single quotes around that
so that is now a string and the other thing we need to do then
is on line 12 we're testing to see
whether 0 has been received
because it's a string we need to do a test
against a string string comparison and
that's going to be two single quotes to do that comparison now
that should be it so what we'll do is
we'll give this a run just to make sure
that does work and I'm going to run this
the first time so that, and just check
the I called that he correct name......vocabulary that should be correct we will just
run it again you can see the problem here was in a line 8
so lets checked that out
and we acutally see that so lets close this down so it is having a
problem there with line 8 at which is
available exits and the
problem is if we run it again to check, it is
having a problem with the keys
themselves so let's go back to cave_initialize
just to make sure that I
haven't messed up something and that seems
that I've made that error again the one I made about
three or four times or more in this
course is of course when I ran the
initialize hadn't been set up the first
time and I can see that it hasn't been set
up so consequently the error we are getting
here when we run these cave_game I'm running
now is basically saying well those files
don't exists and the reason they don't
exist is of course I didn't run it so
what happened was the challenge code
was actually run or actually more likely the
example.py was run and I wasn't
really paying attention to the screen
which I should have so what we need to
do now is go back to cave_initialize.py
that's correct as it is right click
that run cave_initialize that's going to
create a our shelves witch I should have
done and then go back to cave_game than
any other code changes we should be able to run that as well and now we are not getting an error what a surprised Tim if you acutally rung the right file it might work
and we will do a bit a testing to make sure that
it's working
so go north and we're getting an error
there and ok int object has no attribute
I think what I've done is I've forgotten to
change something in the cave_initialize
so I'll close this down and go
back and have a look and actually what I
haven't done which I should have done
you notice we are using a key for the locations it
was an integer and I change this correctly to a string but the location
is also used in the exits as you can see
in the named exits and I haven't changed
the value to a string now the values has to be
string because we gonna be comparing the
string value here to the location we entered there so we could convert
that to an integer but  probably the
best practices because we are gonna be
continually converting it to get the
data right the first time so in that
situation I recommend you do is you
changed the data type your going to be using
which in this case is gonna be
string so I'm gonna change all of these
to strings...and that should fix the problem once we are done with it
you can see that IntelliJ tries to be helpful
I've put a single quote around before a number that's fine but if I put it after it adds two because it thinks you
wanna put some numbers something in the
middle of it so it all a matter of cursor
position to get this right
....and we should find that it will work after we do this, couple more to do, and that should be that so what we've done is we've
converted
hopefully all of them hopefully I didn't miss some strings and actually there is a couple I miss
there Tim what are you doing? so now I think we are done, no there is still another one, goodness I'm having a bad day
Ok I cannot see any more now so what we're
going to do is rerun this we should recreate
the shelve and then when we go back to cave and its going to work
so again just to be clear the reason it
wasn't working
was we converted the locations two
strings here and then in here we had a
location and direction to go to but we
also had the location stores integer so
what was happening was there was a
string integer comparison taking place
in here so it successfully printed
it out but when we try to do a comparison but we ultimately
crash because it was that string and
int comparison that is occurring in game so
lets go back to first to cave_initialize right click that and run that to
recreate the shelve that's been done so if we go back to cave_game
right click and run that a see if its going to
work for us so type north south east west will
try typing north that's good and try typing quit
and that is it so
albeit with a bit of bother we got to actually the
end and I managed to get this working so
that's good so that was our solution the solution
myself and JP came up with so hope you
enjoy that and what was quite
interesting I felt was that really there is
very few changes required to the actual
game so we swipe out the dictionary
that was in the game
quite easily by replacing the lines 3 and 4, 34 and 35 and we had to little tests
we need to change we need to
change the test on line 12
and also change the variable type from
an integer to a string on line 6 and of
course the bulk of the changes
were in the data in this format where we
actually wrote the correct
dictionaries to shelves so this is
what we always recommend you do is get
you data correct so don't write the
program to sort of manipulate problems
in the data so in other words what
I could have done there was I mention
when I was converting these which
should have been two strings by putting
the single quotes around them we could
come back to the code here and
started doing a comparison and checking
converting integers back to strings and
so forth and doing comparison like that
but that would all be sort of coding to
cover up the fact that time we made a
mistake with our data by getting the
data correct it means we don't have
to do any extra coding in the game and that
applies to a lot of coding in general
getting the data correct is a great first step
to being able to with a minimal amount of
code go through and manipulate use that data as we did so as it
turns out there's very few lines of code
that were needed to get the
game working with shelves so that's it
that's the shelve challenge I hope you've
enjoyed that so that's actually also the
end of this section so in the next
section we gonna be starting to talk
about modules and functions so we look
forward to taking you through that and
we'll see you in the next section