Alright so let's go over the challenge
that I introduced at the end of the
previous video. If you recall, the
challenge was to rewrite the program so
that it tests for a correct guess first.
So to do that we need to start by
changing line six. At the moment it's
checking the guess is not equal
to answer, so we need to change the not equal to become equal to. So we're now checking,
specifically, if guess is equal to
answer, then we're going to change that
if it is. Then I come down here and take
a copy of this code, and I'm going to
paste it under, we indent it on line 7.
So if guess is equal to answer, we're
printing out the message "You've got it
first time", and the code here is going to
remain the same, if guess is less than answer. I'm just going through the process of checking.
In fact, I should really have
just cut that out altogether because I
copied it, but that line is no longer
needed anymore. So I'm going to delete
that, and we're doing that for the
scenario where they haven't got the
answer right. So what we need to do is
remove this else altogether, and we need
to come down here, after line 7, and
go back to the first indentation level
and put an else colon there. And again,
what's happening here if guess is
not equal to answer, then the else
clause gets executed and the code
starting from line 9 will then go
through and get executed. And obviously,
in the case of the guess equaling the
answer, which is the comparison on line
6, if that's the case, only line 7
is going to be executed. So this is
a third way to write the program and it
still does exactly the same thing.
It's just phrased differently, just like you
can do with human languages.
So here we're checking for a correct guess first.
Now it doesn't really matter which way
round you do it. There's no necessarily
correct way of doing it.
We're looking for the result here or for the solution, so if you manage to get the solution, congratulations.
So let's just confirm we've
got this right. We'll just do a quick test.
And firstly, I'll test to see whether
the number is correct, works,
"You got it right first time" which is good. Lets do a
test where it's 1, "Please guess higher".
We'll do 9. You can see that code has
been executed,
and we'll do a test where we're starting off with a
high value, 9, "Please get lower", 1,
"You have not guessed correctly". We'll just do one
more scenario, start with 1 again,
we'll do 5. So clearly the code is still
working. Alright, so do make sure you
test the programme as I've done, even
though I haven't done a complete test,
and in the next video we're going to
start looking at more complex conditions.
See you in the next video.