Let's now look at improving the
for loop that we introduced in the last
video. So looking at that code on lines
29 and 30, we've got a for loop that
assigns each of the values in our list,
to a variable called part. On line 30, the
available_parts list has to
be searched, to get the index position of
each part. If the list was sorted, we
could use a binary search, but our list
isn't in order. Python has to check each
item, to see if it equals the value of part.
The first part will be found
straight away - the second part will take
a bit longer. Python will check if
monitor equals computer, then go on to
check the second item in the list. That
matches, so that can return 1 as the
index value. If there are hundreds or
thousands of items, finding the index
positions will take a while. Now this is
a very common thing to have to do when
programming, and fortunately, Python
provides a much more efficient way of
doing it - and that's the enumerate
function. So enumerate returns each item
with its index position. Let's see that
working . So I'm gonna make some changes to
this code. So we've got for part in
available_parts - we're
going to change that line: for number
comma then part in enumerate,
with available parts in parentheses. So we've
got two variables in our for loop now,
and then on the next line, we're gonna put
format, we're going to replace everything
up until this comma, with number. So we've
now got number. We still need to add the
plus 1 - put that back
because, of course, indexing starts at 0
comma part. So we'll replace the index
method call entirely, with number.
So let's actually run the program to make
sure that it works, and you can see we've
still got the same output. So we've got
our menu with the correct numbers. And it
will still work - we can add items. Option
7 won't work, and that's because we need
to tidy up the first part of the code - the
code up there in our in, and also in our
elif blocks. So I'm going to exit the
program now. So overall, the menu is
working,
which is good. Alright, so when I
discussed for loops in Section 4, I
said that a for loop starts with the
word for, and then the names of one or
more variables. If the object that's
iterated over contains more than one
value, you can use more than one variable
in the for loop and that's what we're
doing on line 29. enumerate returns pairs
of values - we get the index position and
the item, as a pair of values. The first
value is the index position and the
second value is the item. So looking
again, at our for loop on line 29, each
time around the loop, number will be the
index position and part will be the item
from the list. Good news is, we can use
enumerate with any iterable type. All
sequences are iterable, so let's see
another example here. I'm going to create
a new Python file called enumerate.example.
I'm going to type for index comma
character in enumerate, and in
parentheses double quotes, and within the
double quotes I need to type abcdefgh.
Then on line two I'm going to type print
index character. That should have been a
colon on the end of the line, of course. Now note that
there's nothing special about the
variable names I'm using here. You can
see that I've used indexing character here.
Index will get the index position and
character gets each character from the
string, in turn. Let's run the program to
make sure that it works, and you can see
the index numbers match the characters
in the string. So make a note about the
enumerate function. It's built into
Python and provides a very efficient way
to get indexes, as well as the values in
a loop. Alright, so in the next video,
we'll go back to our computer parts menu,
and tidy up the conditions that append
the parts to the list. See you in the
next video.