Alright, so let's now look at
improving the code in our buy_computer program.
So you can see I've got buy_computer.py
on-screen, and we want to see how we can
use a list to tidy up those conditions -
these are the conditions on lines 15
through 26, inclusive. Now at the moment,
our program isn't working because we
haven't included 7 in the string, on
line 13. Rather than hard coding the
values 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, what we can do is get
Python to generate it from the number of
items in the list. Ideally, we'd use a
list comprehension for that. Now we'll be
covering comprehensions and generators
later in the course, but I'm going to put
the code in now. I'm doing that because I
want to show you good practices, when
programming in Python. So our code is
going to use a for loop, but I want you
to be aware that there are more
efficient ways of doing some things. So
let's see this comprehension.
So directly below line 8, I'm going
to type valid_choices
equals left square bracket str
parentheses, with i in those parentheses.
Then for i in range left parenthesis 1
comma len, and in parentheses, available
underscore parts. Then we've got our
right parenthesis plus 1, then our
closing right parenthesis and then our
closing right square bracket. Then we're
going to print valid choices. So I'm
printing out the valid choices list on
line 10, just so you can see what's being
produced. So let's run the program,
and we can see that valid_choices is now a list containing the strings 1 to 7 -
you can see that right at the top of
the output pane. Alright, so looking at
that code on line 9, it looks horrible.
When you have worked through the
lectures on comprehensions, though, it will
make perfect sense.
Until then, be aware that there are more
efficient ways of doing things, but that
you can't learn everything at once.
Alright, so what I'm going to do is
comment out that line and replace it
with some code that'll make sense.
So I'm going to type valid_choices is equal to an empty
list and left and right square brackets.
Then on the next line I'm going to type for i
in range parentheses 1 comma len
parentheses, available_parts
in that parentheses, closing right
parenthesis plus 1, then our closing
right parenthesis and a colon. On the
next line, valid_choices.append,
and in parentheses, str, parentheses i and the two closing right parentheses.
And we'll leave the print
valid choices as it is on line 13. Now be
careful with the parentheses on line 11.
We add 1 to the length of available
underscore parts, because the final
value in range isn't included. The 1
isn't inside the len function's arguments -
we're adding 1 to the length and
that's obviously outside of the
parentheses there. You can see we're
missing white space around operator
there, so I need to put a space there,
just to keep IntelliJ happy. Alright, so
we run the program again now, stop and
re-run there, and you can see we've still
got the same output, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 as a list.
So we're using this str function, on
line 12, because the customer is entering
strings, and remember that input will return
a string. If their input is going to
match an item in this list, then this
list should also contain strings. Ok now
that we have a list that automatically
contains the options allowed, we can use
that list on line 18. Let's go ahead and
do that, so instead of putting if current
choice is in 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, we'll just
need to replace that, to be valid
underscore choices. Alright, so far so
good. The last step now, is to replace all
those if elif statements with simpler
code. We have a list of the available
parts, and we know which part the user
chose, so it's quite easy to get the
part name from the list. We can index
into available_parts to get
the required item.
There are two slight complications:
First, the choice is one greater than the items
index. That's easy to fix - we just
subtract one from it.
The second complication is that current
underscore choice is a string, and indexes
have to be ints. We saw how to handle
that when we used the int function
earlier. So let's have a look at changing
this code. So directly below the print,
I'm going to delete the other if
code shortly. We're going to put index
equals int parentheses current choice -
again we're using minus one there -
chosen_parts is equal to
available_parts, and in
square brackets, index. Then the third line,
computer_parts.append, and in
parentheses, chosen_part. Let's delete the
rest of this if and elif block, or
statements, just to tidy things up.
I think you'd agree, that looks a lot tidier.
We've effectively replaced twelve lines
of code with three lines. We've also
allowed the program to be updated, just
by adding or removing items from the
available_parts list, up there
on lines 1 through 7. So let's
check that the program works before
changing the list. Go ahead and do that.
So I'm gonna start by adding a computer,
option 1, a dvd drive, option 7.
I'm gonna try to add option 8 - that should display the menu again and it did do that,
so that's working fine, and if you type
anything else that's not a valid option,
the menu will also be displayed again.
Let's test that. I'll enter my name here, Tim,
same deal - we get the menu back again.
And that's a very strange thing for a
customer to choose, but we've got no
control over what people may type into
our programs. You can see we've got the
menu displayed again, so that's good -
our code behaves sensibly and doesn't
crash, it doesn't crash in that scenario.
Alright, so let's finish by entering
zero, and we get our final list which
contains a computer and a dvd drive. So
far so good.
Let's go back up and what we'll do, is
we'll delete the mouse mat from our list.
Go ahead and do that. Run the program
again, and you can see it still works but
now it's minus the mouse mat, because
we've deleted it from our available
underscore parts list. Alright, you can
see that things are still working.
The menu now only contains six items and we
can add them to the list of parts we
want to buy. Let's try a few; computer
then hdmi cable, option 7 - we now go
back to the menu, whereas previously, of
course, we had option 7 as being the
dvd drive - zero to exit and the two items
I chose were computer and hdmi cable.
Everything's working as it should do. So
we've used a few lists in this program.
On lines 1 to 7, we've got a list of
parts that are available to buy. On lines
9 to 11, we create an empty list
and then add the valid choices to it.
Line 14 defines another empty
list, computer_parts, which
will contain the parts that the customer wants to buy, and we're appending their items -
ones that they've chosen to
buy - on line 21, so that ultimately
contains the list of items that they
want to purchase. So using lists for the
menu items makes the code much shorter.
More importantly, though, it's much easier
to maintain. We can add and remove items from the available_parts list
and we don't have to change any
other code, as a result of doing that,
as you saw. So test the program thoroughly.
You might want to add things like a
webcam, microphone and loudspeakers to
the list. Also, make sure it copes with
invalid choices. When testing a program
like this, don't just focus on the
correct input - make sure you try to think
of other things that a user might type.
Alright, so in the next video, moving
ahead, we're gonna get the program to
cope if the customer changes their mind.
See you in the next video.