Now we had a problem in the last video, when we tried to use else in our comprehension.
So let's start by reviewing the problem.
Now what I've done is I've opened a new file here, condcomp1.py, or created it, and I've copied the code from
our original condcomp.py that we used in the last video, and I've deleted all the code after the for loop
and after we printed out the meals.
So basically, starting from scratch there again.
So if I run this file now,
you can see that the for loop creates a list containing just the two meals that don't contain spam from
the original list, and if a meal isn't included,
we're getting the string 'a meal was skipped' instead.
So the first part, getting a list of the meals that doesn't contain spam, is easy as a comprehension.
So let's start that first, so on line
twenty one we'll put meals equals, left and right square brackets, meal for meal in menu,
if double quotes spam not in meal.
We've got our right square bracket there, and we can print out meals.
Let's just confirm that that works.
And you can see that that works.
So I'm getting the same two, basically the same two meals as the for loop,
but of course we're not getting the 'meal was skipped' messages in that list. So that bit was easy,
but at this point we're now stuck, because we've already seen in the previous video that we can't add an else
clause to the filter.
So how can we actually proceed here.
Well the expression that we're using to build the list can be as complicated as we need. Now at the
moment,
we're just adding the individual items for menu -
the expression part in the meal, in the variable meal, at the start of the comprehension.
Now if we instead, replace the simple expressions with something a bit more complicated, we can then get our
comprehension to produce exactly the same list as the for loop.
So a conditional expression is pretty much what it sounds like.
So it's a condition that we can assign to something or use anywhere else that an expression's needed.
So let's see one in action.
So we're going to add some code down here on line 24, x equals 12,
and on the next line, expression equals double quotes, twelve with a capital T, although it doesn't really
matter,
space if x equals 12, two equals there. Now we've actually got an error on that line at the moment.
So what we've typed is the first part of the expression with an error there.
And if you think about it, hopefully it's obvious why we've got that error -
this is on this line.
Now expression will be equal to the string 12 in double quotes if x equals 12,
but what value will it have otherwise.
So when using a conditional expression there must be an else
part.
So let's revise that, and add on the end of it else
double quotes unknown, then on the next line we can do print expression. If we run this now, there shouldn't
be any surprises.
And you can see that we're getting the output 12, because you can clearly see that x is defined as 12,
and the if clause there is basically true,
so therefore we're getting the result 12. And just to really confirm that, lets change it to something else, to 15, run it
again, and we've got unknown.
So that's working like we think it should.
So now that we know what conditional expressions are,
let's see how one can help us with what we're trying to achieve here.
So what we're trying to do, is we want an expression that evaluates to the meal if the meal doesn't
contain spam, otherwise it evaluates to the string
a meal was skipped.
So how do we do that? Well we go back and, lets, we go back and close the run window, and we're going to modify line
21, so it should be now meal equals, and we've got double quotes meal.
And what I'm going to do is, just to make it easy, I'm going to type it, so you can see me type the whole thing in
again. So, meal equals and we've got our double quotes meal, if double quotes spam not in meal, else a meal was skipped,
for meal in menu, and we'll leave the print meals there.
So lets actually run this, confirm that it works, and you can see that we're basically getting the identical
list to what was outputted for us on the previous lines, with a meal skipped,
eggs, sausages, bacon etc. So we're basically getting everything. We're getting the if and the else condition being
evaluated.
And just in case this isn't clear, what we've done is remove the filter and we've put the condition into
a conditional expression in the comprehension.
So in this slide you can see that this is just like our first list comprehension,
but now the expression part's a bit more complex. Now
the expression can be as complex as you need,
although you can also use a function to avoid excessively complex code. Alright so back to IntelliJ again.
So conditional expressions can be more complicated than this.
Now whenever there's an else, it can be followed by another if, whenever there's an if part that must
be followed by an else.
So what I'm going to do is comment out all the code other than the definition. I'm just going to just close the run
window down.
So basically, comment out all this code from line 13, right down to and including line 26.
I'm going to start again on line 28, and let's try this; for meal in menu,
colon, then on the indented line, on the next line,
print parentheses meal comma space double quotes, contains chicken, double quote,
if double quote chicken double quote in meal, else contains bacon, if double quotes bacon in meal,
else contains egg.
Then we've got our right parentheses. So lets actually try running that to get an indication of what each meal
contains.
So note here that the order is important when creating the conditional expression.
So the first two meals don't have a message that they contain egg,
and the reason for that is in the expression which we can't quite see
now - that's better.
We're actually checking for bacon before checking for egg. Now
only if there's no chicken and no bacon
do we get that 'contains egg' message.
Now that example was to show how to include several conditions in an expression.
Now you really wouldn't perform the test that way and it's also wrong.
Now we can see that, by changing chicken to sausage. So I'll go through to our expression
and change that to sausage.
OK and we'll run that,
and you can see that it's actually showing our chicken and chips meal down the bottom, as containing egg.
Now containing egg is the default and it's going to be printed if none of the other conditions match.
Now as I said, you probably wouldn't perform this particular test in that way.
Now exactly how you would write the code
depends on what you're trying to do, and the requirements here are a bit vague.
It was just really an example of a more complex conditional expression.
So you'd probably want to test for membership in a list or a set instead.
So first we can create a set of all the items that our meals can contain, and I'll actually print a blank line
to separate this output from the preceeding results, so lets go ahead and do that. Close down the run window
for now.
So I'll just do a print first, an empty line.
So we'll start with items equals set parentheses, then for meal in menu on the next line, colon, for
item in meal colon, items dot add parentheses item.
Then we're going to go back and print items print, just to make another space there, so print parentheses.
So I'll run the program.
And I'll just put a space there to keep Python happy,
run.
So we've now got a set of all items that could appear in the meals.
So now that we've got that, what we can do instead is loop through the meals and print the first matching
item that each meal contains. So lets do that.
So on line 44, meal in menu colon, for item in menu,
Sorry, for item in items I should say.
If item in meal colon print parentheses left and right curly braces in double quotes, contains, and
another left and right curly
braces double quote dot format, meal
comma space item, two right parentheses and then we'll do a break. Alright so now we can loop through
the meals and print the first matching item that each meal contains. So lets try running that, and you
can see we've got a much better result this time. So conditional expressions can be very useful but don't
try to use one just because you can.
They really should only be used to solve specific problems.
So as another example,
let's get the computer to play fizzbuzz.
Now that's a very simple game.
If a number is divisible by three you say fizz instead of the number, if it's divisible by five you say
buzz, and if it's divisible by both 3 and 5 you say fizzbuzz -
so if it's divisible by 15, in other words. Otherwise you say the number.
So let's have a look how to code that expression, and we'll put that into a loop to get a range of results,
or so we get a range of results.
So I'm going to start typing here, for x in range, parentheses, we go from 1 to 31 colon. So
fizzbuzz equals fizz buzz in double quotes, space if x modulus, so the percent sign, 15 is
equal to zero, two equals,
else double quotes fizz if x modulus again percent three equals zero, else double quotes buzz if x
modulus five - that's the percent sign again - equals zero, else,
str x. Then on the next line we're going to print fizzbuzz. So remember that x modulus 15 will be
0 if X is divisible by 15 and the same for x modulus 3 and x modulus 5.
Now the order's important here. We have to check 15 fist,
otherwise one of the other conditions will be true.
Now let's run the program
and confirm that it actually works.
So you can see we get the number or buzz word printed out for values from 1 to 30 inclusive,
and that looks pretty good to me.
Alright, so I'm going to finish the video here. In the next one,
we've got some challenges to practice what we've done so far, and you can probably guess what the first one's
going to be.
So I'll see you in the next video.