So let's look at simplifying chained
comparisons. The code on line 3,
if you check carefully, is underlined
with s squiggly line, which intellij and
PyCharm do when they have a suggestion
about your code. So if we hover our mouse
over that, you can see there it's saying
simplified chained comparison.
When dealing with numerical values in a
condition, you can often replace
and with a simpler comparison. So what I'm
going to do is comment that line out and
we're going to make this a bit simpler.
So instead what we're going to type,
is if 16 less that equal to age less
than equal to 65 :
So I think that's much easier to  understand now because it's obvious that age is in the range
of 16 to 65. The condition is the same as
the previous one but it's phrased in a
more understandable way. We should still
test it, though, so I'm going to run the
program and repeat the inputs that we've
used previously. Alright, so when we ran it
previously we tested a value between 16
and 65. I'll enter 34. That's working okay.
We're getting the message printed out. So next
if we run it again, we tested a value
less than 16 and a value greater than 65.
So I'm going to enter 12 for the first test
and nothing's printed out, which is
correct. Run it again. This time I'm going
to enter 78. No output again, so that's
correct, and the final two tests
were to make sure the code works when we enter 16 and 65. So I'm going to do that, one at a time.
16 works, 65, that also works. So
alright, that's working fine.
We could also turn the condition around or use or
instead. As I've said a few times,
there's often several ways to get the same
result when you're programming. But let's
make a change to the program now so that it prints a message when the condition's
false, in other words, if age is outside of the range 16 to 65. So I'm going to come up end up put
an else in there, so else : and on the next
line indented, print parentheses
and in double quotes I'm going to type Enjoy your free time, like so.
Let's also, on line 9, put a
row of dashes so that we can tell which
block of code has produced which bit
of output. So I'm going to type print
parentheses double quotes and put a dash
in the double quotes, and outside of the
double quotes * 80. Let's have a go at
doing this now, using or instead of and.
So staying on line 11 I'm going to
type if age less than 16 or age
greater than 65 : Then we're going to type print
Enjoy your free time, else
print, on the next line, parentheses and double quotes,
Have a good day at work.
So now if age is less than 16, we're printing the message, Enjoy your free time.
The code will do the same thing if the other part of the condition is true, if age is greater than 65.
Now we're using or on line 11, which
means we'll get that message if
either of those conditions is true, as opposed
to and, where they both needed to be true.
If neither of them is true, we'll get the
message in the else block.
So let's run the program. I'm going to enter 16, and you can see we have a good day at work printed twice.
Both bits of code are
doing the same thing. If you recall, when
we used and, and that's the code on line
4, both the conditions had to be true.
With or, as you can see on line 11, Enjoy
your free time will be printed if either
condition is true. Generally, one way or
the other will be more natural in some
situations and which to use will depend
on the context. There is one important
difference, though, that's useful to be
aware of.
When comparing conditions using and,
Python will stop checking as soon as it
finds a condition that is False. When
comparing conditions using or, it'll stop
as soon as it finds one that's True. So
looking at line 11, if age is less than 16,
then Python doesn't have to check to see
if it's also greater than 65.
This can be very important and we'll be coming back to that later.
For now, it's just something to be aware of. Right, so I'm going to stop the video here and in the next one,
we're going to take a look at
boolean values. See you in the next video.