so in this video we are going to do a
challenge I'm gonna challenge you to
complete a particular challenge for this
section of the course which is of course
dealing with time zone and what I'm gonna
do is paste it in and talk about it
and then get you to actually do the
challenge so first things first is create a
new file here I got the same project
open as last time right click on that
new Python file I'm gonna call it timechallenge
that is the timezone challenge going to paste the code in
so let's go
through and discuss what the challenge
is and essentially I'm asking you to create a
program that allows a user of your
program to choose one of up to nine
different time zones from a menu you
can choose any zone you want from the
all_timezones list that's going to be
where you save the time zones for
this program and the program will then
display the time in that time zone as
well as local time and UTC time entering
0 choice from the menu will quit
the program so you want to display the dates and
times in a format suitable for the user
of your program to understand and you should also
include the timezone name when
displaying the chosen name so that's it
that's the challenge so I suggest you do
now is go away and see if you can solve that and
when you're ready to come back you can come
back and check our solution and take
it from their so pause the video now and
I'll see you when you get back
hopefully you managed to get this working or
have a good stab at it any way so lets go through now
our implementation and see if its something
similar to what you came up with so
first we need to do our 2 imports from modules which we have been doing....
.....
.....so next we need all the time
zones lists where we can choose where we can
choose from up to nine times and so what
we're going to do is create that so....
.....
.....and I'm gonna start with one
that's gonna be the choice for the menu you don't
have to strictly use these
that I come up with as long as you got
separate ones......also get the spelling on these correct because
if their wrong and they don't match the time zone
you get a problem....
.....
...so that's
our available list of nine options so what
we want to do now is accept input from
that and then start displaying it so
first things first lets print a message that
people see on the screen so... which we mentioned was
part of the instructions there.....
.....
......
....the format began to include
the place which was obviously from the
list and also available_zones....
...so we are getting the number as well as the actual location so
that's our loop to display them on the
screen and what we're doing now is
work on the loop that accepts input from
the user and continues to loop until I press 0
so put...so its going to continue
looping until I enter 0 to exit...
.....
....
...so that's going to break out of the while loop and end the program but if
we're not exited then what we need to do is we need
to look up and see whether the choice
entered is in the keys so the way to do that is...
.....so
in other words if the number 1 to 9 has that
been entered if it isn't there we are gonna put....
.....
......
.......
.....
....and we're going to format that to a proper
time we talked about that on line 10 display dates and times in a format
suitable for the uses of your program to
understand so we've done this before we are gonna do
something similar
we are....
.....
....
.....so that's the first one
we also want to print out local time so that's part of the
challenge as well to do that so lets go
ahead and do that and it's going to be.....the local time is of course the local
time in which ever time zone your
currently running this in for me its gonna
Australian central
Daylight Time format and it's going to
be..... we are going to use basically the same format very similar format
and we are going to use...to get the current time but then
format the actual time so...
.....
....
.....and the difference there is
we're going to use instead of now we're
going to use UTC now to get the current
UTC time and everything should be the
same and add one last final print to space it out a bit in the end and that should
be it that should be all we need to do and I'll just delete the spaces and leave one space as per the standard
Python way of doing things and now we've
done that we should find that we're good
to go
what would do first is try
running it right click and run time
challenge you can see we've currently got
the menu showing please choose a time zones or 0
to quit so type 0 to quit to make sure that works ok that work well
as we expected to do all right so let's to
time zone that we know works lets do 3 for Australian
Adelaide and we got an error on line 38 now
we just have a look at that error
unknown time zone and the reason
that's unknown is up typed Australian
instead of Adeliade how embarrassing my own timezone
so that should be
Australia Adelaide remember earlier in
the challenge in this video I mentioned
the need to not make any typos and of course
is another one on line 4 in my haste to
try and dp this video and type of the
same time I seem to be failing at task
need to make sure that you fixed the typos to have any chance of this working
lets try it again number 3
Australia / Adelaide this time and we actually
got something which is good and we have
a look at our time wednesday at 1:40
which is converted to 1:49 their because you can see
it was on 55 seconds
UTC time is second of the third sixty
you can see the format we used and noticed
before when I look at the code we did the %z for the first line and
then we can see that by doing that we
added the time zone information the
extra information that's appearing on
this first line the others lines have also
got the current day and then the date month and year and time but we also added
timezone and that's what the other entry was so that's working ok so lets try a couple
of others to make sure we don't got any problems here 1 the time in
Africa Tunis is Wednesday 4:19 a.m.
CET so if we actually do a search for current
time we put current time 4:19 am and its
GMT +1 time in Tunisia which should be
correct obviously and you can see where
+1 there is as well so its definitely
working and just try another
one lets just try 6 Japan current time
in japan is 12:20 and +9 which is JST current time Japan
...you can see currently the time is 12:20 JST time and if you go back and have a
look again 12:20 so that is all working and what the heck of it lets try another Hawaii current time -10 HST
so you can see obviously the time zones are
working nicely
lets check that current time Hawaii
5:20 p.m. 2nd of February HST 17:20 which is 5:20 p.m. so that's it that's
actually the solution that's the
challenge done and dusted so I hope you
got a lot out of that so we are now done
with time time zones dates etc
in the next lecture what we're going to
do is we're going to take a little bit of a side ways
trip what we gonna do is start
looking or have a brief look at tk enter
this is the tk  widget tool from Python which
allows GUI programs to be created
so it's not going to be like a huge sort
of section on this but it's going to give you
an idea on how to start looking at
GUI interfaces so will start looking
at doing that in the next video