Let's talk about boolean expressions,
True or False. So a boolean value is a
value that can either be True or False.
There are only two values that a boolean can have.
Python defines two constants,
True and False. Note that they're written
with a capital letter. All names in
Python are case-sensitive, so True as a
capital T and False has a capital F. A
boolean expression is an expression that
evaluates to either True or False. We've
seen a few boolean expressions, so far in
the course - things like age greater than
equal to 16, for example.
Boolean expressions aren't restricted to just
testing numbers. We could also test a
string value. Name is equal to Tim, so
that's a boolean expression that will
evaluate to True if the value of name
equals the string Tim.
It will evaluate to False if name has any other value.
Boolean expressions can be very complex. For example, you might have a condition such as: if day is equal to
Saturday, in double quotes, and
temperature greater than 27 and not raining.
So you can see in that example,
we're checking to see whether day is
equal to Saturday and whether
temperature is greater than 27, and we're
also using and not here. Now in this
example, raining is a boolean variable.
It has the value True or False. Not is used
to reverse the value.
So we can use not to reverse a boolean value: not True is
False and not False is True.
Alright, so back to the code now, so let's actually
create a new Python file.
I'm going to call this one truefalse.
Alright, we're gonna
start typing some code: day is equal to,
in double quotes, Monday with a capital M.
Line 2, temperature is equal to 30.
Next line, raining is equal to True, remembering
we need to use a capital T
when using a boolean variable, as
we've done there. Then we'll have a
look at that condition, so if day is equal to,
so it's two equal signs, Saturday
in double quotes with a capital S, and
temperature is greater than 27
and not raining colon, print parentheses double
quotes Go swimming.
And the next line else :
then on the line 8, indented,
print parenthesis double quotes and within the
double quotes, learn Python.
Now didn't mention it when I created this file,
truefalse.py, but be careful with
the names you choose for your Python
file names. You're starting to learn
quite a few Python names and keywords
now, so it's getting easier to avoid
using them as the name of your file. Now
if you'd called the file true.py with a capital T,
then that wouldn't
be a good idea. You might not get an
error straight away but it could cause
problems eventually. So just keep it in
mind and try not to use Python names and keywords. And I do suggest experimenting
with different boolean expressions to
get used to how they work, as a good idea.
We're obviously doing that here with the code that we saw on the slides.
It's essential to attach the
names to values before you use them in
your boolean expressions.
If you don't attach date or value, for example,
then you'd get an error on line
5. The same for temperature and raining.
Alright, so let's run the program, and we
should see Learn Python,
and you can see we're seeing that down the bottom there. To make sure this is working because we
know that temperature is 30 and raining
set to True, let's change the day to Saturday,
remembering I need to type it exactly how I've typed Saturday on line 5,
in this case, with a capital S. Run that,
and in fact, we're still learning Python. Why?
Well that's because it's raining. We set
raining to True on line 3.
All three parts of the condition, on line 5, must
evaluate to True in order for the entire
condition to be true. The last part of
the condition on line 5 is: and not raining.
So raining is true, as we can see on line 3. That means that not raining is false.
So what we can do here is change
the and, here in line 5, to an or,
and once we do that and run the program again, this time we get the output, Go swimming.
When you're experimenting, remember which
strings have to match exactly.
On line 1, we've got Saturday with a capital S, which matches Saturday in the condition on line 5.
If you'd spelled one of them
with a lowercase s, so I had another typo,
they wouldn't compare equal and your
program wouldn't work as expected.
Before I finish the video, take a closer look
at line 5 in our code.
Can you tell by reading that line, what the true intention, or what I wanted that line to do?
It's ambiguous to read, so we know how
Python will interpret it because the
precedents of the operators is
well-documented, and you can find the
table in the documentation in a link in
the resources section of this video.
But I can also bring it up on screen, which
I'll do now.
So there's the table. Now we discussed operator precedence for the arithmetic operators in the previous section,
but boolean, or conditional
operators also have precedence and you
can see the or and not there, talking
about boolean. So we can see here that and
has a higher precedence than or. Now
that's why we go swimming even though it's raining,
looking back at the code again.
Raining is True, as you can see on line 3.
So is that a bug, or is that what
I intended? The point of this is that
that line of code doesn't really give
you any indication of what I intended.
Even if they aren't necessary, we should
use parentheses to make it clear.
So let's change the day to Friday to see what happens.
Capital F there. We run the program. We
can see Learn Python, outputted at the bottom of the screen.
The condition day
is equal to Saturday, evaluates to False.
The condition temperature greater than
27 evaluates to True,
but False and True is False, as we established in previous videos. Not raining is also False,
which means the code in the else
block is executed. So what would happen
here if we changed raining to False.
Let's do that.
Run the code.
This time we go swimming. As I said, you don't have any
indication if that's what was intended
Maybe I want to go swimming on hot
Saturdays or on any other day
that's not raining. So let's add some
parentheses here, to make it clear
how this code is being interpreted. So I'm
going to put a parenthesis in front,
a left parenthesis in front of day, and the
other right parenthesis after
temperature greater than 27, over here.
Now this is how the code's interpreted at the moment,
because and has a higher
precedence than or. So even if that's
what I meant,
then I should still use the parentheses.
They're not needed by Python but they
make the code much easier to read.
Looking at this code now, it's now clear
that we'll go swimming on any day
when it's not raining, as well as on hot
Saturdays, whether it's raining or not.
As a general rule, always use parentheses when you mix and and or in the same condition.
Doing it makes it clear what you intended. More importantly,
it makes it less likely that you'll
introduce a bug.
When you use parentheses, you don't have to worry about remembering
whether and has a higher or lower  precedence than or.
Alright, so try different values for those three variables,
and then have a go at creating your own
boolean expressions. In the next video,
we're gonna have a quick look at some truthy values.
See you in the next video.