Alright, so in this video we're going to
talk about sorting lists. So lists have
another method that doesn't appear in
the table that we were looking at
previously. The reason that it doesn't
appear there, is because not all mutable
sequence types have it. The method is
called sort and it unsurprisingly, sorts
the list. Now that sounds simple enough,
so why am I devoting an entire video to it.
Well the reason is, that there's another
way to sort things in Python, and the
difference often confuses new Python
programmers. So let's start with sorting
a list. We're going to open our number
underscore list.py program. I'm
going to delete all but the first two
lines. Now there's not much point sorting
either of those lists because they're
already both sorted. What I'm going to do
is combine them by using the extend
method, and that's another one of the
operations in the mutable sequence types
table that we were looking at previously.
Okay I'll move down to line four and
type even.extend, and in
parentheses, odd. Then I'll add print
parentheses even, and if you run the
program now, we've got a list containing
the values from one to nine, but note
that they're not in order, though. So the
extend method takes all the items from
the iterable that we pass it, and adds
them to the list. So in this case, on line
four, we pass the list odd to the extend
method. That adds each item from odd to
even. To sort the list, we call it sort
method. On line seven, I'm going to type
even.sort
parentheses, and let's print parentheses
even again to see what the list looks
like after the sort. Run the program, and
you can see now the list is sorted. The
sort method has two key arguments that
we can use. One of those won't make sense
until we've covered functions, so I'll
come back to it later. I will discuss
keyword arguments in more detail, in the
section on functions. The reverse
argument is used to sort in reverse order.
So what we can do, in parentheses
on line seven, we can type reverse equals
true with a capital T. This time when I run
the program, we'll see that the list is
sorted in reverse order. You can see
it's nine, eight, seven, six, five, four, three,
two, one. Now note here that the list has
been changed. We didn't get a new list
created - the contents of even have been
rearranged. Now that can be important
when dealing with very large lists. The
items in the list are sorted without
creating a copy of the list. In the next
video, we'll see another way to sort
things that does create a copy. Now if
your list is several gigabytes in size, for
example, and you have to create a copy to
sort it, you could run out of memory.
The sort method doesn't create a copy of the
list - it rearranges the items in the list.
You'll also see this technique described
as sorting the list in place. Remember
that lists are mutable and their
contents can be changed. That explains
the behavior we get, after making a
couple of changes to our code. What I'm
going to do is bind another variable to
the list and print it out. So after the
first print there on line 5, down to line
6, I'm going to type another underscore
even equals even, and print parentheses
another underscore even. Then we'll leave
the code on lines 9 and 10 to sort and
print out the values.
So I can see that when we run the program we get the same list printed out twice. That's our first
two lines of output. Now there shouldn't
be any surprises if I print another even
at the end of the program, which I'll do
now, and the code for that on line 11,
print parentheses another underscore even.
So make sure you understand what that
will print before running the program.
Now if you're not sure, then review the
earlier videos in this section. The ones
titled Mutable objects and How many
lists are there. Run the program, which
I'll do now, to see if you were right.
When we print another underscore even,
that's also sorted in reverse order.
That's because there's only one list and
we mutated the list by sorting it on
line 9. If that's not clear, again review
those earlier videos in this section of
the course.
In the next video we'll have a quick
look at the documentation about Pythons
built-in functions, and see another way
to sort things. See you in the next video.