so once again with now got a working
program but it is now time to remove
those circular references that we've
talked about previously now there is no
need for the song class to store an
artist object anymore we now have a way
to find an artist in the list if we know the
artist's name and that's using the find_
object function which you've seen as using the
code and in addition theirs no need for the
album class to store the artist object
once again the name is all that we need
to be able to
reference that again using the find_object function so it makes
things a lot easier and the class diagram
is now much simplified and I just want to bring
that up on screen you can see there that we can
simply this a lot with it is
simplified by removing that
relationship so once we do that we'll
end up with something like this
the top diagram as you can see there so
that's what we're trying to achieve so
how do we go about doing that and removing the
circular references
well thats the challenge this is the challenge that I'm gonna set you to actually fix in this
video so let me just paste in the text for the challenge so you know what is exactly needs to be done ok so here is what we
want to do we want to modify the program so
that the class structure matches the
simplified diagram now artist objects can
hold references to album objects and album
objects can hold references to song
objects but the key here is there must
be no circular references so that is really
what you're trying to achieve here is to
remove that or set up so their aren't circular references so its now time to do that
so pause the video and go away and see if you can complete that challenge when you
ready to come back and check our
solution start the video again and I'll
go through and show you how to do that
ok so hopefully you managed to solve it so let's go
through and see if we can get this working
so I'm just going to undo these
changes and removed this from the doc
strings because we don't need it their so what need to do well the first change is in the song class and what we gonna do is first change
the doc string to reflect the fact that
the song subject is now going to store the
name of the artists rather
than a reference to the artist object so
come up to the class song which is on
the screen at the moment
we got artist which is an artist we are going to change
it because it is going to be a string now and it's
going to be the name of the songs
creator....
and we don't need to make any other
changes its pretty straightforward
that's really all we need to do with the
song class but of course when we create
new song objects were gonna be passing
the artists name as a string to the init
method instead of passing the artist
object and we are doing this to remove
circular references so the next step is
to go ahead and do that to remove the
circular reference between album and
artist
so go to class album and bring it on the screen
here so artists the artists responsible
for the album if not specified
this is now going to be a string here
that's the name of the artist name of the
artist as supposed to the object responsible for the
album and if not specified
that's all exactly the same as it what it was before
down here on line 39 we got self.artist equals various artist if the parameter
pass or the argument pass was none we are going to
change that
so you no longer going to be trying to create an artist object we are going to be setting that to string
the string of various artists that's
all the change we need here now the
add song method doesn't need to be changed
the reason for that is that it uses
self.artist and then now we are storing
artist as a string that will automatically
be used when creating the songs so finally
we need to change the artists class so
that when it creates a new album it's using
its name rather than passing self
so in that way the artist class will only be
storing the artist name as a string rather
than storing a reference to the artist
object as it is currently doing so
scrolling down to look at the artist class
the change will make the album we
got equals new album name year and self
we no longer want to pass self we want to pass
the attribute self.name so that is
literally the only things that we should
need to change at this point the program
should know run and will tests that shortly
so the artists class stores references
to albums in its list now and the album
class towards references to songs but
they aren't circular references any longer
so neither the song class nor the album
class store artist objects anymore they
just hold the name of the artist as a
string and of course they get looked up with
the find_object function when we
need to find out more information about
that so lets run this and confirm that
it does run...so we will run this and we still get the same
results as we got before so everything is
working nicely with the changes that
we're actually made so that's actually it
that is a basic introduction to
object-oriented programming in Python and
we've seen what classes are now and how to create our own basic classes and
we also look at the concepts of encapsulation and delegation now by taking a program and
changing it to use object oriented
techniques hopefully we've given you an
appreciation of how this alternative
approach can really provide huge benefit
and reliability and also allow you to become
more productive at the same time now we
have really only scratched the surface
of object oriented programming is really
a lot more to cover yet and in Python their is also different implementation options to
consider so I'm going to be covering all that in
the remaining videos in the section so
I'll see you in the next one