in the previous video saw how to use the
connection and cursor objects to execute
sql queries against out database and
also hopefully they've got an idea on
how important it is to commit your
changes to the database when you're
inserting or updating data but in this
video we're going to look at
placeholders and parameter substitution
alright so what are they and what's the
problem more importantly that they're
actually designed to solve let's
actually have a look at our original
update query in the contacts 2
. query going to change the code back
to what it was before we actually have
changed it we had this where clause so
...and if you
recall the actual update was update
.com but i'm actually
going to changes
and I've done that so that we can
actually see that things are being
changed when we eventually re run this
query now the problem with this is that
where we left it in the previous video
is that we hard coded the new email
address and also the condition in the
sql statement the where clause
normally you'd want to provide these
details from variables a program that
can only set the email address to another
update update. com for rows where
the phone number was 1234 would be a bit
limited to say the least
so let's create a couple of variables to
store the new email address and the
phone number so i'm going to add those to line 5
we're going to start with new
email so...
....
....now we could
use the string formatting that were
already familiar and changed
line 8 to something like this
so we could do that and that would
actually work fine in fact lets actually
run that just to confirm that does work
and you can see that only the record
brian with the ID 1234 got his
email address
updated to another update update .com so
clearly that update actually worked and
the string formatting that put in place
has actually done the job but what would
happen if we allowed the phone number to
be type-in by user so let's actually
change the program slightly to see that
i'm going to leave the new email
addresses as it was and put...
....
...so I actually run that now please
enter the phone number so if I actually enter the
phone number 1234 you can see we've got
one row updated here so clearly the
updates work we don't see any different
because the new email address is already
been updated but you can see that our
codes working now
at the moment we're only executing a
single update query and python is
actually quite clever and won't allow
multiple statements to be used when we
call the execute method but sometimes
you want to do that so I'm going to
actually alter line 11 here actually what I'll
do first is after the update
lets actually print that out....
....
.....here on line 11 we're actually gonna
leave that line as it is but thus next line
is where it's got update cursor .
execute going to change that to execute
script.....lets also change the
email address so we can really confirm
this is working...
....
so let's actually run that again please
enter the phone number
and we can see the update has
proceeded and by the way you get minus
one rows updated here the execute
script method doesn't actually set the
row count properly so therefore you can
ignore that particular value showing
their but overall we can see that
everything is working fine in that
the email address was updated now why
do i use the execute script method for
well that method is designed for running
more than one sql statement in a
single call now the individual
statements must be separated by
semicolons and python will execute them
one after the other and I know right now
we've only got a single statement here
but if I'd use multiple statements it
would just be confusing make it harder
to see what's going on in this next bit
alright so i want to show you know
something by running it again this time
we're going to type in the numbers 1 2 3
4 semicolon drop tables or dropped table...
....and we
actually get an error at this point
specifically the error we are looking at
is down here on the bottom
no such table contacts so it's obviously
something pretty serious has happened
here and you can actually print have a
look at the SQL statement that we
printed out the code we added to line 9
you can see what happened here
the two sql statements here so
you see our valid update but then
followed by a drop table contacts and
obviously we know what that does that
actually physically drops the table from
the database
oops and that's an understatement i'm
going to switch back to our check DB
and just run that just to confirm and we
haven't got a table so the table
has been dropped
what just happened here is known as a
sql injection attack this is where an
attacker injects sql statements into
the sql that a program executes now a
relatively short time ago
it really was a simple as I've just
demonstrated an attacker with a good
knowledge of sql was able to craft
their input so that additional
sql statements would be executed
you might be thinking at this point but
hang on to tim you have to know the name
of the table let's just see how hard it
is to find out as long as we know the
type of database you're attacking and
even if the site doesn't have something
like powered by Microsoft sql server
displayed at the bottom of the page a few
carefully crafted queries will soon
determine which database is being used
well so we'll assume at this point we've
worked out that were attacking a sql
lite database going to start by running our
original contacts .py program again
because that's going to recreate the
table
let's do that....will just go
back into checked db just to confirm
that the tables back again you can see
and that's working and now that i've
confirmed that's working lets actually
make a change here instead of select
star from contacts going to do select star
....you can see it's
actually come up quite helpful IntelliJ
told at the table looking to work on
so when I actually run that we get
the full details of all the tables in
the database so injecting that select
query when you know the results will be
displayed such as in a retail stock
search page for example can provide a
lot of information about the database
structure now sql injection attacks
were actually very common and successful
for a while they're actually still a
serious problem but because database
administrators and programmers that's us
by the way and now aware of them
it's much harder to attack databases
that it used to be but only remain as
hard as long as we stay aware of the
problem and we write our code
accordingly
now this is all being a little bit
contrived for one thing i had to change
our code to use the execute script
method came back to contacts 2. py
method code on line 12 have to
change it to use execute script rather
than execute which you wouldn't normally
use when executing a query based on user
input but i did that to demonstrate the
problem and to give a rough idea of what
a sql injection attack is these
days it's not a simple to perform an
injection attack but it's still
definitely possible
you just need a deeper understanding of
sql
and your target database so let's actually
see what happens if I change back
the execute script back to execute again
here on line 12 if we run this again
bearing in mind that last time with the
execute script able to successfully
dropped the table so enter input
...we
actually get a warning this time you can
only execute one statement at a time so
the python execute method is wise to
this trick and won't actually allow
multiple statements to be executed but
with that said we have crushed the program
and that's not good
alright so this is all leading up to
using placeholders and parameter
substitutions so lets actually see how
both of those things can actually help
alright so first going to
duplicate this line and i'm going to
comment out the one the top line and
going to change the line to update
contacts contacts...
...
...so we end up with a string
like that and then we're going to come
down here to the update cursor .
execute method instead of just having
update SQL we're going to add two
parameter here so...
...
let's see whether that works
first you must enter some valid input
1234 just to make sure that it does work
because we've got one row updating in
there and i'll just put up a little bit
higher so we can see that each time we
run and the email has clearly been
updated so that's working but let's try
running again and see if we can add an
SQL injection attack again so 1234
....this time
the program hasn't crashed we got these zeros
updated and the Brian record hasn't
changed at all but the point is we
haven't actually got an error here so
it's obviously something else going on
when we use the parameter substitution
rather than manipulating the updates
sql string so using placeholders which
other question marks in a string on line
9 and parameter substitution allows the
python sql light library to
sanitize the input so that means it
will check for things like additional
sql statements that an attacker has
tried to execute now there is a lot more
to it than that and sanitizing the
input is quite complex
luckily we don't have to worry too much
about that and if you are writing a
database library like the sqlite
three module then obviously it's
something you have to fully understand
but in our case for our purposes it's
enough to know that using placeholders
rather than building up sql strings
ourselves is much safer so all the hard
works been done by the programmers who
created a sqlite three module and
all we have to do is remember never to
build up a single string using any
values that may have come from outside
our program now it's perfectly
acceptable to use string formatting to
provide table and column names from
constant stored in our code for example
but never do that if the values may have
come from user input or from parameters
passed to your functions from external
code
alright I'm going to finish the video
here in the next one we're going to go
on and start looking at how we actually
use placeholders because we've talked
about the problem they are designed to solve
but let's actually move on to looking at
them in more detail
see you in the next video