Alright so moving now onto Challenge 2.
And I've gone through the details of what this challenge was, in, not the previous video, the one before that.
And we've also got an outline here but I won't go through it again.
What I will do though, we'll start talking about the expression we want to use.
So basically, we want to provide the items for the list, so the expression we want to use is the value
from the locations dictionary,
that's locations exit in square brackets.
Now we do that for each of the keys in the exits dictionary.
We're going to filter out, or filtering out, any values that don't contain the forests
key, 5 in this case.
So let's start running some code to understand what we're doing here.
So I'm going to start by adding some code on line 35,
actually we'll start on line 36, loc location equals 5. I'm just going to move up to make it a bit clearer in case you've
got subtitles on. So forest is equal to left square bracket locations exit in square brackets, for exit
in exits, and then we're going to add an if here, so
if loc, l o c,  in exits left square brackets exit right square bracket dot values parentheses, and then we've got
our right square bracket. Then we're
going to print the forest.
So again, the expression we're using here, to provide the items for the list, is the value from the locations
dictionary,
and that's locations exit.
Now we do that for each of the keys in the exits dictionary, filtering out any values that don't contain
the forest key, which you can see here we've assigned on line 36,
location 5, and I assigned that, as you can see, to the variable loc just to make it easier to test different locations.
So if we run this program now, you can see we get the expected results: the road, as well as the hill.
Alright, now to get the list for the road,
it's a simple case of just changing the loc to one, the location to one.
And I'll move this down a little bit.
Lets change the location to one, and run it again, and you can see this time we're getting the building, the
valley and the forest as output.
Alright, so the next part of the challenge was to produce a list of tuples.
So let's copy the comprehension we've already got, and then change the expression to include the value
of exit.
So I'm going to copy these two lines,
and we're modifying the expression part.
So we're going to come down here, so where this is locations, you want to change that and put parentheses
around that.
That's going to be exit comma space locations square bracket exit then right parentheses, then for exit
in exits if loc in exits, square brackets exit, dot values, the parentheses and the right square bracket,
and then print it out. So then when we run that, when we run that, we should get the locations key as well as
the description,
remembering that exit is iterating over the keys in locations.
So let's try running that,
and you can see that we've also got the locations key,
now returning for us as well.
Now before we move onto the final part, you may have spotted something in this code, and it's to do with our
control variable, exit in this case.
We're getting an error if I highlight it, or warning rather; shadows or exit shadows builtin name exit.
Now it's not really a problem here, because exit only exists in the context of the comprehension in Python
3 at least,
but I suggest renaming it anyway.
So let's go ahead and do that, we're going to right-click that and do a refactor, rename.
Let's just call it xit instead of exit, refactor. What I wanted to point out though, is that the second
comprehension hasn't been changed. Though they've both used the same name, exit, it refers to different
variables
in each case.
So the scope of exit is confined to the comprehension.
So I mentioned that in an earlier video, and this hopefully now demonstrates that quite nicely.
OK so moving on, now rather than changing the value of loc on line 36 to process each of the locations,
what we can do instead, is put together a for loop around a second comprehension.
So let's go ahead and do that, put for loc in sorted parentheses locations closing parentheses and a
colon.
What I'm going to do is indent
that code, but we'll also add another bit of code here.
Print parentheses and double quotes locations leading to,
left and right curly brace, closing double quote dot format,
parentheses loc, right parentheses
comma, end equals single quote, backslash t for our tab character, and right parentheses.
So that should make things look a bit better.
Then we'll leave the next line in there, printing out forest.
So let's try running that and see how it goes.
So basically, as you've see there, I've added some text to the output so that each line shows the location that
we're checking, and also sorted the keys before iterating over them just to make the output more readable.
Now they're just frills. As long as your loop created a list for each location, then that's fine.
And there's actually no need to sort the keys in Python 3.6.
I'm talking about the code here, in the, the code on line 40, the for loc in sorted parentheses locations.
So there's no need to do that, but the documentation does state this behavior shouldn't be relied on.
So I've run the program as you can see to get the key in description, for every location that leads to
each of the others.
Now location 3, inside the building and location 4, the valley, well they can only be reached by the road,
so you should only get the road for those two locations, and you can see that on our screen there, 3
and 4 are showing just that.
Now we should probably rename the list because forest was only a really good name when we were getting
the links to location 5, the forest.
And even then, using a specific location name, rather than a name that describes a list wasn't a good
choice.
So something like exits underscore to underscore destination perhaps, would be a more suitable name here.
Now the challenge was included to show you that you can mix for loops and comprehensions.
Now it is possible to produce the same set of lists with a nested comprehension,
and we're going to be looking at those in the next video actually.
Right so this is just a quick discussion about Challenge 3,
just to remind you of what we were doing there.
So for this challenge, the idea was to convert all comprehensions in the previous challenge to for
loops.
So we start off by creating a list comprehension from a for loop.
This challenge is to go the other way: convert each of the comprehensions in the previous challenge into
a for loop that produces the same result.
Alright so let's have a look at the solution for that. Alright so if we have a look now, I'll just close down the run
window now, to make a bit of space here.
So we'll start putting some code in here, as of line 40.
So we'll put forest equals an empty list left and right square brackets, for exit for xit in exits colon.
Then we're going to put if loc in exits left square bracket xit right square bracket dot values parentheses colon,
then forest dot append parentheses locations left square bracket,
xit right square bracket, and then a closing parentheses, right parentheses, and then we're going
to print forest.
OK so lets try running that. Well actually we'll add another print there to separate the output as well.
Let's try running that now, and you can see these first two lines of output.
So we're obviously getting the same list printed twice. They should be identical and you can see in this case
they are identical, because the for loop's now doing the same thing as the comprehension.
Now here it may be important to call the control variable xit rather than exit, because it'll be
the inner global namespace,
so it'll prevent you from using the builtin exit function if you shadow the name exit here.
Now of course, if your program isn't going to use the builtin exit function then this probably doesn't
matter.
But as a general rule, shadowing builtin names isn't a good idea though.
So I suggest you do take note of the warnings that you get from your IDE, and try to avoid this sort of
thing whenever possible.
And I added an extra print statement as you saw down here on line 46, to print a blank line between the
two solutions, just to make the output easier to read.
Now the second comprehension, by the way, is very similar.
In fact, we can copy that loop and paste it into the for loc loop replacing the comprehension.
Alight so we've got our printout there so let's go ahead and copy this
code. So we're going to start with,
copy that forest line to initialize it in the loop, let's move this up a little bit so we can see, and we'll obviously
replace the other version. Or what I'll do
before I start, I'll just undo that,
and we'll take a copy of that, paste it, and I'll just comment out the old version so you've got that code if you need to.
And so with this new version we're going to again, change forest.
We're going to just create an empty list initially, and then we're just going to copy that other code.
So I'm going to copy this for loop with the if and the append. Lets copy all of that.
Copy that down to below forest,
and we make sure that we've got the printing out now in the right order.
So we've got print and print forest, and then we need to change the appended value to be a tuple, which we haven't
got at the moment in the append line.
So this is the code on line 56.
Alright so we now need to change
the append line, so I'll just delete it and rewrite it which is probably easier. So that's two parentheses now because we're
dealing with a tuple, xit comma space locations,
left square bracket xit right square bracket closing right parentheses times two.
And that should be that.
Alright so that should be the code there, so lets try running that,
and you can see for the first one we've got all of the above,
all of the locations showing.
And they all potentially lead to zero,
number one,
we've got three, four and five, number two, we've got one, four and five,
number three we've got one,
and number four we've got one. We talked about that before.
And location 5 is only one and two, just the road and the hill.
Alright so that's the two challenges now completed in this section.
Now if you're still struggling to understand comprehensions, then try converting them back into a for
loop. By doing that it really can help you understand what they're doing.
And in the next video we going to look at nested comprehensions, which work just like the concept of nested
for loops.
Now nested comprehensions can be very useful, but they can also be quite hard to read.
Now once we've seen what they are, we'll use one for this last solution.
You'll then have three different ways to do the same thing, and you hopefully will get a good feel for when
you might want to use each approach.
So as always, see you in the next video.