ok so in the previous video we talked
about the problem that place holders
were designed to solve but it's time you
have a good look at how we use them
now as you saw when i modified the code
to use placeholders rather than string
formatting they actually worked in a
very similar way we can see that
by comparing the code on line 9 to the
comment out code on line 8 instead of
python replacement fields
that's the opening and closing curly
braces we just use a question mark to
indicate the places where values will be
placed then inour execute method we
provide a tuple containing the values
that will be used and you saw that on
line 13 now the tuple should have one
value for each ? in the string so when we
actually called the execute method on
line 13 we actually passed the tuple
containing the new email address and the
phone number now we have to use
parentheses around the tuple here
otherwise python would interpreted as a
method call with three arguments now
update string on line 9 is very similar
to the commented out version on line
8 but again we'll just use ? ?
character instead of the left-to-right
curly braces now one other thing to note
is that we have an enclosed the first ?
in single quotes now the library's
parameters substitution takes care of
correctly quoting strings where
necessary which makes our life a lot
easier and that's really just about
everything we need to know about
placeholders and parameter substitution
use a question mark when you want an
actual value to be inserted and provide
the values as a tuple when you call the
execute method on a cursor or a connection
and obviously there's quite a lot going
on under the hood so to speak to
sanitize the values and to make sure
that it won't cause problems but from our
point of view using placeholders is
really very simple and all the python
database library support placeholders
and parameter substitution so you can
take the same approach when using a
different database mysql for example
but the placeholder characters may be
different
the sqlite library use question marks
but other database libraries they use things
like a percent s
or colon one etc the documentation for
the library will tell you what characters
you need to use as a placeholder
everything else will work in the same
way as it does withour sql databases
alright I'm going to finish this video
with a short challenge now the challenge
itself is quite simple but if you find
yourself struggling then what I
suggest you go back and watch the two
videos on tuples in section 7
alright so here's the challenge so your
challenge is to modify the check DB
program so that it asks the user to
enter a name then uses a where clause in
the sql statement to retrieve just
the row for that one person now it seems
simple but if you find yourself
struggling with the Python syntax as i
mentioned go back and watch the tuple
videos in section 7 before you start
also remember to change the table name
in check db back to contacts because if
you recall i change that to sqlite
_master in the previous video so
that's a challenge so how you go
pause the video and I'll see you when
you get back ok so how did you get on
with that hopefully managed to solve it
now here's my solution to the challenge
alright so let's start by adding a name
for the user on-line 5 so come back
up here put name...
...
...we're going to
change the sqlite master that was
changing the previous video that will be
our contacts again...
...
....so I've modified
the query to add a where clause and use
the placeholder for the name we want to
find now because we're using a
placeholder we need to provide to the
parameter to substitute
that's the bit that may have caused you
some problems in fact that's actually
the reason I set this challenge
providing variable number of numbers of
arguments to functions using a tuple is
very common and it's probably something
you find easy you'll find easy where
there's more than one value where people
struggle is passing just a single value
to a tuple like we've done here
obviously I have separated the name
variable in parentheses but there's also
a comma after that before the ending
right parenthesis so when you're telling
python that you want a tuple containing
a single value you have to put a comma
like I've done after the value and because
the tuple was being passed as an argument
to the function call
we also need to enclose that in
parentheses so we actually run this now
just to confirm that it works enter a name
to search for type my name Tim press
enter and we get my detail showing now
the equals check in a where clause is
case sensitive so you may have use like
instead so firstly just to confirm that
it is case-sensitive will use a
lowercase tim like so we get nothing this
time because the record save with the
capital T if we change this line here
and I'll commented out duplicate it and
commented out to change instead of
putting the where clause well we still need
we're clause but instead of putting the
equals we put like and if we run that
you should be able to do a search
for lower case tim and it still matches
that even though it started with
uppercase and just running it again with
the upper case either case it's actually
working nicely now you may have just
tried passing the value name like this
when you try and do that and run it
actually got a really weird error
incorrect number of binding supplied the
current statement uses one and there are
three supplied which is a little bit
bizarre looking at the code it's
actually hard to see how three values
are being supplied to anything on line
eight
but might actually become clear if we
run the program again and try searching
for brian this times so lets do that now
it's saying the current statement uses one
and there are five supplied but not
specifying that name is a tuple
we're actually confusing the sqlite
library the number is showing in the
error message is a number of characters
in our name string 3 for tim and five for
Brian now that's not really important
i'm just pointing out sometimes that
error messages really aren't as helpful as
they could be this to make very good
subject for a google search thought to
find out more
so if you get stuck placed the entire line
of the error message into your search
engine
alright so that's the first attempt and
having decided we should be passing a
tuple we put name in parentheses so if
we go back and put the parentheses back
in around name variable noting that i
haven't got a semi a comma at
the end though when we run this we still
get the same error three in this case
because i choose time and we also got a
warning here remove redundant
parentheses so remember when it's not
the closing parenthesis that define a
tuple it's a fact that more than one
value is specified so we do need
parentheses here even though at the
moment intellij saying we need to
remove our redundant parentheses but we're
passing the tuple to a method and
commas are actually used to
separate individual arguments in a
method call but the parentheses
themselves don't turn this with the
parentheses around name into a tuple
to do that we do need to add the comma
at the end of name before the closing
right parenthesis and notice the warning
disappears at the same time just to
confirm will run this again brian now
successfully works so if you struggled
with that and couldn't get it to work
don't worry you know how to provide a
tuple that contains a single value when
calling methods and functions and that's
something that you'll probably be using
fairly often and it is something that
people do struggle with substituting
a single statement in sql statement
is common so I have included this
challenge to make sure you knew how do it before
we move on
alright so that's the end of this video
in the next video we're going to leave
databases briefly and have a look at
handling exceptions in python see you in
the next video