Alright so before we finish with conditions,
I want to look now at in and not in.
There are two uses of in and we're
going to be seeing it used with a for
loop later. Here though, we're concentrating
on using in as a condition. So we need a
new Python file for this one and I'm still
on the same project. I'm going to call
So in is used in sequences and we'll make much more use of
it when we come to look at lists in a
later section in the course. One sequence
that we have used, though, is a string - a
sequence of characters. So let's type in
some code: parrot is equal to Norwegian
Blue. Line 3, letter equals input
parenthesis double quotes enter a
character colon and a space there.
Line 5, if letter in parrot colon print
parenthesis double quotes, left and right
curly braces in the double quotes, is in,
left and right curly braces double quote
dot format parentheses letter comma
parrot and two right parentheses.
Then on the next line else colon. On the line
after that print parenthesis and in
double quotes, I don't need that letter.
So we'll run that program. I'm gonna start by
entering the letter a when asked for
a character here - a is in Norwegian Blue. So
that assigns the name letter to a string
value a and line 5 checks if the
letter appeared in the parrot string.
a does appear in Norwegian blue so their
condition evaluates to true, and we get
the message a is in Norwegian Blue printed
out, as you can see. So we're going to run
the program again. This time I'm going to
try a letter that doesn't appear in the
string, so I'm going to enter a z. I
don't need that letter, is output.
When you enter the input remember that
string comparisons are case-sensitive.
If you enter a capital A it won't be found
in the string, and you can also check for
longer sequences. So if we run the
program again now, I'm going to enter
blue with a capital B and press Enter.
Blue is in Norwegian blue.
If you try that with blue all in lowercase it won't
be found, and I'll just confirm that,
showing indeed that in is case-sensitive.
Alright, so as well as checking if
something is in a sequence we can test
if it isn't, and we do that using not in.
So we're going to create a new Python
file here and we'll call it notin.
Start by typing activity is equal to, then in
double quote input parenthesis and in
double quotes, What would you like to do
today? A space there before the double
quote and then the right parenthesis.
Then on line 3, if and in double quotes
cinema in lowercase not in activity :
print But I want to go to the cinema
and then the double quote and the right
parenthesis. If you run this program now,
and I'm going to type I want to learn Python.
We get the output, But I want to go to
the cinema. Because the string cinema
isn't in I want to learn Python, the
boolean expression evaluates to true.
Remember that we're using not in here. So I've mentioned a few times now, that string
comparisons are case sensitive and this
can cause confusion for our users if we
don't handle it correctly. To see what I
mean I'm going to run the program again,
and I'm going to enter the text I want
to go to the cinema, but I'm going to use a
capital C for cinema, and we still get
the message But I want to go to the cinema.
Now that's a bit confusing, or
could be, for users of your programs.
Fortunately though, that's an easy thing
to deal with.
Python strings have a load of useful
functions and one of them converts a
string to lowercase. In fact there are
two functions that do a similar thing.
I'll show you how to find them all in a
moment but firstly, though, let's modify our program slightly.
And what I'm going to do
is, where it's got not in activity after
activity, I'm going to put .casefold.
So the casefold function converts a
string to lowercase, but it handles
different character sets better than
just converting to lower case would.
Unless you're familiar with languages like
German, they have different lowercase
representations of some letters, you
probably wouldn't be aware of the problem.
But don't worry, just remember to
use casefold rather than lower case
when you want to compare strings.
Alrighty, so if I run the code again now,
and this time we're going to type the
same thing in, I want to go to the cinema,
with a  capital C again. We don't get that
confusing message anymore because the
match has now clearly worked using casefold.
Alright so I'm going to finish this
video by having a look at all the
functions that the Python string class provides.
Let's open a browser and I'll paste
in the link, and this link is in the
resources section of this video. Alright,
so you can scroll down to the string method
section, or what we can do here to save a
bit of time, we can just do a search.
I'm gonna search for string methods. There's
string methods. I can just click on this,
well it's just down here anyway. So I'll close
down my search. You can see them on screen.
So this is an alphabetical list of all the
methods that the string class provides.
You can see there that casefold
is the second one there, and you
can read a description there of what it
actually does. Now I wouldn't suggest
trying to memorize all these methods but
it is worth spending some time reading
about them. When you need to do something
such as checking if a string contains
only digits, for example, you'll remember
that there's a method to do that.
You won't remember what it's called unless
you've used it a few times, but you'll
know where to go to find it. We'll be
using quite a few of these methods
through the course so you'll get a lot
of practice at using them.
Alright, so we've covered quite a bit about
if statements and conditions. Before we move
on to start looking at loops, the next
video is going to be a challenge to let
you practice some of what you've learnt
so far. See you in the next video.