So it's very common to nest one for loop inside another in programming, and we can do the same thing
with comprehensions, and that's called nested comprehensions.
Now the basics are quite straightforward, and as an example, let's see how we can produce a range of
burgers from a few basic ingredients.
So I've created this new file, nested1.py, for this example.
So we're going to have three basic burgers with four different toppings,
and what we'll do is produce a list of the various burgers for sale.
So I'm going to type burgers equals left and right square brackets, and in double quotes beef comma double quotes chicken
comma, and then double quotes, finally spicy bean.
Then we've got our right square bracket. And on the next line, we've got toppings equals left and right square brackets, and
cheese in double quotes comma, egg in double quotes
comma, beans in double quote, double quotes
comma,
and spam in double quotes.
Then we've got our closing square bracket. And the code on line 4, meals equals left and right square
brackets, parentheses burger comma, topping and closing right parentheses, for burger in burgers for topping in toppings.
And then we'll print, on line 5, meals, and
lets now run that to confirm that it works.
And you can see that we've got each burger type with one of the available toppings, so as an example, beef with cheese
beef with egg, beef with beans, beef with spam and then so on.
It does the same for chicken for each ingredient, and spicy bean as well.
Now the equivalent for loop: lets write that out just so we can see the difference there.
So add on line 7 empty print, to separate
things a bit.
And we're going to put on line 9, for burger in burgers
colon, for topping in toppings colon, and we'll do a print, two parentheses burger comma space topping, and two right parentheses,
and I made a typo there,
burgers
for burger.
OK, so let's run that to confirm that it actually works,
and you can see that we get the same results.
Now I've printed out the burgers in the for loop instead of adding them to another list
but you can see by looking at this list here, we've actually got the same combination of burgers and
toppings
printing out. Now incidentally, we could have modified the comprehension to do the same thing.
It produces a list which we can just iterate over, so we could come back up here to line 4, and do
something like for, for meals, and this time we'll put an in there instead of an equals sign. Then on the end we'll put a colon.
Then on line 5, print parentheses meals.
And what I'll do is change this, so I'll delete that print meals there,
so we've just got line 7 showing like that.
So if we run that,
you can see we've essentially now got exactly the same. So basically as you saw I just added for at the start,
changed the equal to an in, and added a colon to the end.
So after that change, we printed the combinations instead of storing them in a list, and again confirmation
that the program's now printing out exactly the same
output, well is actually showing or outputting exactly the same output twice.
Now if you're going to iterate over a list, and don't intend to use it again, then seriously consider
using a generator expression instead.
Now I'm going to come back to this point shortly,
but for now though, we've created a nested list comprehension that does the same job as the nested for
loops.
Now that's quite a simple example to start with.
We're using existing lists, burgers and toppings, which makes it quite easy to see what's going on. Now we've
used a comprehension to combine two existing lists, to produce another list containing all combinations.
Now, I wouldn't recommend doing that in this case.
The reason, is that we've produced what's called a product of the two lists, and Python actually has a function
to do that in the standard library.
Now I don't want it to digress
at the moment. We're focusing on nested comprehensions at the moment,
so you'll see that in the video after next. But with nested list comprehensions you can write the
comprehensions in a different way, to get different results. And to see what I mean we're going to copy the comprehension
and paste it in after the for loop, then we'll comment out the for loop,
just to keep the output a bit tidier. So I'm going to come up here and copy these two lines, line 4 and 5, then
we're going to comment out lines 9, 10 and 11 for now,
and then what we're going to do is paste in line 13.
And what we're going to do is add some left and right square brackets, so we're going to add the first left one here,
to the left, so for meals in and two left square brackets,
and the other one, I'm going to come down here after burgers, and put the right square bracket there.
Alright so lets try running that.
So by making a slight change to the code on line 13, we've added a bit of structure.
Now if we have a look at the list there we've got a flat list containing tuples, which is our first one
up here,
the beef and cheese, beef and egg and so on, but this next one down here, the second output which was from
the character on line 13 and 14,
that's a nested list containing a list of tuples.
So in both cases the lists contain tuples but the first list holds all the tuples,
whereas the second list that's being output here, is made up of four lists each containing the tuples, and
you can see that as it goes through.
Now I should probably, to make things a bit simpler here, let's just change the names for that, so it's clear,
so in our program, nested meals, nested meals but the concept again is the same, we've just changed the variable name there.
Run it again and we still get the same output as you can.
But that second output, that's not the only way that it differs from the first one. You may have
noticed that the ordering has now changed.
Instead of getting the beef burgers followed by chicken, then all spicy bean, we're now getting all the cheese
toppings, followed by the egg and so on. So from left to right we've got beef cheese, chicken cheese and spicy bean cheese,
and then same for egg, beans and spam, as opposed to the first list which was each burger type, and it's
individual type, available list of toppings.
Now we haven't changed the structure of the final
list. We've just changed the way that the comprehension's executed.
Now that may seem strange because everything's in the same order.
We've still got 'for burger in burgers' in our code here,
followed by 'for toppings in toppings'.
And that's obviously the same for both comprehensions on line 4 and line 13.
So what's actually going on here and why have we got a difference now?
Well the difference is, on line 4, this contains the expression here, burger toppings in parentheses
which is just a tuple, and the rest of the code forms the iteration part.
And we've actually got a double iteration iterating over two different lists.
So this is a comprehension with multiple iteration parts.
So it iterates over
the burgers list,
then over the toppings list for each burger.
So let's just clarify that.
So we've got a comprehension with two iteration parts.
After getting the first burger, beef, the second iteration part returns each of the toppings in turn,
and once all the toppings have been used, the first iterator, the first iterator part, moves onto the
next burger, chicken. Now the second iterator then runs through all the toppings again,
then we move on to the next burger and so on.
So technically this probably isn't a nested comprehension, rather it's a comprehension with two iterator
parts.
So it produces a flat list as we saw, rather than lists nested inside another list.
Now it's worth noting that the Python docs don't use the term nested comprehension, but you'll see people
referring to both of our comprehension forms as nested comprehensions. Alright so with that said how is
the second one different? Well here we have got a comprehension whose expression is another list comprehension.
Now the outer comprehension
iterates over each item in toppings, then evaluates the expression for each one.
Now the expression is itself a comprehension that iterates over each of the burgers. When written like
this using another comprehension as the expression, the outer iteration values are used first, and that's why
we get the ordering changed.
So don't worry if you struggle to understand or remember this. When you want to create a comprehension
to produce a specific result, you can get there with a bit of trial and error.
But understanding this just cuts out the trial and error, and you can create the correct comprehension
first time.
Now remember that there are different ways to phrase your code, and that you can alter the way a comprehension
works, just as we've done in this example. Now if we wanted our second comprehension to produce
the same ordering as the first one, and the same as the for loop, we just have to swap the two iteration
parts.
So lets just see how that would work.
So I'll just add a print here to separate the output, then on line 18, for nested underscore meals, in two square brackets parentheses,
burger comma topping, right parentheses, for topping in toppings, then one right square bracket.
And then we end with for burger in burgers right square bracket colon.
Then on the next line print nested meals.
So lets run that,
and you can see we've now got the output, beef cheese, beef egg, beef beans, beef spam as opposed to the other example,
where we're getting beef
cheese, chicken cheese, spicy bean cheese and so on all the way through.
So it's basically producing all the beef burger variants,
then the chicken burgers, then finally the spicy bean burgers, just like the original loop did.
Now we have got a different structure though,
a two dimensional array if you like. The main list contains three further lists, one for each of the burger types.
Alright so time for a challenge. Alright, so what I'm going to do is create a new file here, and this will be in the resources section
of the video.
Let's go ahead and create our new one, we'll call it nested challenge,
nested underscore challenge. Then I'm going to paste in the code there, close down the run window, and I'll just read this out to make it clear.
So in an earlier video we used a for loop to print out the times tables for values from 1 to 10.
Now that was a nested loop and that appears below.
Now the challenge here is to use a nested comprehension to produce the same values. Now you can iterate
over the list to produce the same output as the for loop,
or just print out the list,
up to you. And we'll just run this just to confirm the output we're looking for.
So there's the output there. Right so I'll stop the video here.
I'll close down the run window, and we'll go through the solution in the next video.