so in this section we looked at blocks in
python and seen how the level of
indentation is crucial in determining
which block a line of code belongs to
we then use if and else to test
conditions and only execute blocks of
code if those conditions were either
true or false
we then went to create more complex
conditions and saw how to use Elif to
check several conditions in turn so next
we moved on to execute blocks of code
repeatedly using for statements to
iterate through a range of values we
covered continue and break to interrupt the
normal flow of a for loop and else to
define a block that always execute if
the loop finishes without a break
this is a different use of the else
keyword to how it's used in an if
statement which is a little unfortunate
and can also be confusing but that's the
keyword that has been chosen so we have
to actually live with that unfortunately
and then finally we digress to look at
augmented assignment and why you should
use it in preference to a normal
assignment where possible or whenever
possible
I'm going to finish this section now
with the short challenge to give you a
chance to practice what you've learned
in the course so far and you have a
chance to make use of the string
formatting that we covered in previous
videos as well as reading an input that
a user types at the keyboard so i'm
going to do now is create a new python file
i'm just going to paste in the
actual challenge then you can get
started I'm going to right-click over
here and i've created a new project and
select python file and we'll call this
one
challenge and we're going to paste in
the challenge
ok so the challenge is to create a
program that takes an IP address
entered at the keyboard and prints out the
number of segments that contains and the
length of each segment
now an IP address consists of four numbers
separated from each other with a full
stop
but your program should just count
however many have been entered in
examples of the input you may get are
you can see their 127 . 0 . 0 . 1
another one with a dot 192 . 168 .
0 . 1 another 1 10 . 0 . 123456 . 255
then 172 . 16 and finally 255 another
words you program should work even with
invalid IP addresses what we hear
interested in here is the number of
segments and how long each one is now
once you've got a working program here are
some more suggestions for invalid input
to test and i'm not going to read
those out but you can see them down there or
you can see them on the screen there
from line 17 to 21 not forgetting line
22 which is basically pressing enter
without typing anything making sure your
handling that scenario as well so this
challenge is intended to practice for
loops and if-else statements so although
you could use other techniques such as
splitting the string up
that's not the approach we're looking
for here alright so that's the challenge
see how you go with that
pause the video I'll see you when you
get back ok so let's get started and
just a note here that is probably as
many different solutions to this as
there are people trying to solve it so the
test is not that your solutions should
look like on what I'm about to present
but rather that it produces the correct
output
even if provided with invalid input
alright so let's get started I'm going
to start with IP address.....
....
...
so we start by getting the IP address from the
user and then we are initializing two
variables now each time we find a full
stop or period in the input string
we're going to increment a counter of
how many segments there are now unless
the input is blank
they'll always be at least one segment
we're going to initialize the variable
segment to a one
you can see me doing that on line 30 now
we're also going to count how many
characters are in each segment so the
variable-length will be used for that
now do be careful with the name of this
variable it may be tempting to use a
shorthand name for example Len LEN
but if you do that your len variable
would actually replace the built-in Len
function and you'll get some weird
problems now we do
fortunately get a warning from
intelliJ if we try to do that so i
rename this over here to len
temporarily you can see we've got an
underline showing their i can highlight
that this is shadows built-in name len
and I can come over here click on more
shadows built-in named len and over here
we get the
same warning over here that
shadowing the built in name
so what that basically means is we're
providing another function for the word
len here overriding the original one
and that's certainly not what we want to
happen here so make sure you do watch
out for warnings like that because you
can lose the ability to use built in
functions if you reuse the same name in
your code we certainly don't want to do
that and in fact looking at that
probably a better name would be
something like segment.....
we can use len their if you wanted to i'm going
to use...that makes a
lot more sense so we're going to use that
name instead alright so the next step
now is to loop through all the
characters in the input string IP
address and check to see if you've got a
full stop or some other character
let's add the code for that it's going
make a bit of a space here
ok so we're going to start with four
character in IP address
....
.....if we get to a full stop which as a
student pointed out is called a period
almost everywhere else outside australia
in the UK and that signals the end of
the segment and the start of a new one
so again I often referred to a period
as a full stop
they're both the same thing but in any
event if we get to this full stop /
period then that signals the end of the
segment as I mention and then we start a new
one at that point now on line 35
we're printing out the details of the
previous segment and then we increment
our segment counter now because we're
about to start reading the characters in
a new segment at that point we're also
taking the opportunity to set the segment_
length variable to 0 now if the
character isn't a period or a full stop if
you speak English proper like what I do
then we just increment the count of
the length so how do we do that we're
going to add an else their so.....
....
looking that code it looks like it might
just work but it doesn't quiet but when
you're learning it's a good idea to run
your code as you build it up that way
you get to see the problems with your
logic before you've written to much and
can make adjustments so I actually run
this program now gonna start by right
clicking it click on run challenge i'm
going to move this down to the bottom so
you can see it a bit easier it's asking
for an IP address if I actually type this
....and
press enter
you can see we've got segment one
contains one character segments 2
contain
one segment 3 contains one but it's
missed the last one so i'm looking at
the code we see that only prints out the
details for a segment when it finds the
full stop
sorry period that terminates it so the
final segment isn't terminated by period
so as a consequence it doesn't get
printed
now there's a clever and slightly
sneaky way to handle that but i'll start
by doing it the obvious way what we need
to do is add an extra bit of code
after loop to check to see if the last
name was a period and print out the
final segment details if it wasn't going
to come down here to do that on line 41
jut a note here....
....
and then the actual code will be if....
.....
....
....now if we run this again
....we can
see that it's now handling that fourth
fourth number correctly
alright so now it's a good opportunity to
start testing the various inputs
that I listed in the challenge so I got them
all listed up here let's just go through
those one by one we tested the first one
we'll start with the first one...
....you can see we got the right
inputs for their 3111 which is correct
run it again this time we'll try typing...
we actually got
five segments the first one 0 33 11
okay next so far so good....
....and that should be 216 and
three in terms of the number of
characters in each segment that's
correct
ok let's try another one let's try....
....
three and two that's correct
we will try one with just a number 255
segment one contains three characters so
far so good
ok next one was....
....0
32 32 in terms of number of characters
for each segment which is correct
alright so.....
....we got 3411 there and we'll try
big one......
....33 and 9 and got two more to do
here to test....
...232 and the very last one now
....
....212 122
so everything seems to be working
fine theirs only one last test to do now
which is to enter nothing i'm going to
start again and press ENTER
and we get an error that isn't good this
error happens because there's no
characters and IP address and that means
that the for loop that we starting
on line 33 doesn't have any values to
iterate over and consequently the
variable character is never assigned a
value and in fact IntelliJ is aware
that this might happen and it's actually
getting this warning down here if you
hover over that name character may not
be defined now any Java or C++ programmer
is watching this would have been
horrified that I type that final if
statement in the first place in those
languages character would never be
accessible outside of the for loop but
in Python that's perfectly acceptable to
do but only if the for loop is guaranteed to
execute at least once
as long as the loop is entered the
variable character will have a value and
that value will be available outside of
the loop
but the problem here is that the loop
didn't execute at all
that's because there were no characters
in IP address to loop over there is a
relatively easy fix here that's just to
initialize character to be an empty
string at the same time as we initialize
the other variables
let's go up and do that so.....
...and incidentally
I use double quotes there
because 2 single quotes can appear as
one double quote on the video but you
could actually use 2 single quotes like
that again video may not shown to clearly
i'm using two double quotes both
are the same result
the important thing now is that the
variable character has a value whether
the for loop runs or not so this time
when i run the program and press ENTER
segment one contains zero characters we
get the correct result I won't spend any
more time in this video running through all
the other tests again try them out
and they will all actually work fine
so that's the solution if your solution
works with the same amount of input
getting the same results congratulations
but remember again that there are many
ways to solve a problem so your code may
be very different to mine the important
thing here is that isn't that you've got
the same code but that it produces the
same results
alright I'm going to finish the video
here now in the next video I want to
talk about that sneaky method that i
mentioned earlier this video involves
thinking about things slightly
differently and a clue is in the that
comment that i added before the final
if statement this part down here unless the
final character in string was a
period so let's look at that in the next
video