In this video I'm going to show you how
to perform case-insensitive
sorting. There's only one extra argument
we need to add to the sort method, or the
sorted function. It involves using a
keyword argument and I won't be
explaining how they work until later, but
it's a useful thing to know about now.
So I don't want you to worry about
understanding how this works - just
use it if you need to sort some text,
without worrying about capitalisation.
So let's start by seeing the problem. So I'm
going to continue with sorting.py
from the previous video, and I
better start by fixing the error that I
caused in the last video. And by the way,
if we hover over the variable that I
renamed, it actually helpfully tells you
that Shadows built in named sorted. So if
you see something like that, that's
probably an indication that you've
renamed something that you didn't want
to do. Alright, so what I can't do here,
is use refactor this time, and that's
because we'd also change sorted on lines
3 and 14, and the second sorted on line 7.
So what I'm going to do is just change
lines 7 &amp; 8 manually. So I'll change them
back to sorted_numbers, as it
was in the previous video before I made
the change.
And if you run this, no errors anymore,
and at the end of the output
we've got a capital T appearing before
the other letters. Now we can use a
keyword argument, as I mentioned, to
specify how the items should be compared.
If we don't want capitalization to
matter, we can use the case fold method
of the string class, and we've used that earlier.
So I'll add the keyword argument
on line 14, and down here on line 14
I'm going to put a comma, because I'm running
out of screen real estate here.
On the next line, I'm going to type key=str.casefold
without parentheses.
So I'm going to delete those parentheses.
So I mentioned not including the
parentheses. It's very important that we
don't include those parentheses after
the function name. That would call the
function, which isn't what we want here.
What we're doing is telling the sorted
function the name of another function it
should use, when comparing the values. As
I said, don't worry too much about that
just yet. Whenever you want to perform a
case insensitive sort, just add
key=str.casefold as an argument to sort or sorted, as I've done here on
line 14 - well I've actually added it
to line 15. So if we run the program now,
noting that T no longer appears at the
start of the list, and if we scroll over,
you can now see the capital letter T appears
where we want it to appear, in amongst
the other letters. So you'll learn all
about keyword arguments later, but this
one is useful when sorting things and
that's why I wanted to mention it now.
Alright, so I'm going to finish the
video with another example. This time
what we're going to do, we're going to use
the .sort method to sort a list of names.
Let's start on line 18 by creating a
list. So I'm going to type names is equal to
left square bracket and right square
bracket, which of course, denotes setting
up a list. We're going to type Graham in
double quotes, with a capital G comma, then
on the next line, John, with a capital J,
in double quotes with a comma,
terry in double quotes this time, all in
lowercase, comma, outside of the double
quotes, eric in double quotes, all
in lowercase, comma. On the next line, Terry
with a capital T in double quotes with a
comma, and on the last line, michael in
lowercase in double quotes. Then I'm
going to press ENTER on the last line.
We'll go back one character there, just
so the left and right square
brackets line up. Alright, so on line 25
I'm going to type names.sort
parentheses, then I'll print out names. Now I
mentioned when I was typing,
some of these names are all in lowercase,
which is something that you might find
in data that you're processing. So if we
run this, we can see that eric, michael
and one of the Terry's are at the end of
the list. So to put them back where you'd
probably look for them, we can use case
fold again. So we can go back to the code there,
names.sort, and in parentheses
I can type key=str.casefold,
remembering not to use, or not to add the
parentheses, like so. Run the program again.
This time we get the names in an
order that humans would look for them.
Alright, so we've seen quite a few things
that we can do with lists but we're not
done yet. In the next video, we'll look at
other ways to create them.
See you in the next video.