alright so there's one more thing that
we need to talk about with these
properties and that's an alternate way
of coding them now in fact this
alternative method I'm going to show you
is more common and you all probably more
likely to see it when you read other
people's python code now it
uses something called decorators and
does exactly the same thing as we've
just seen it's just the syntax that
differs now the decorator results in the
property line being done for you which
is why people tend to prefer it to the
method that we've seen in the previous
video you do need to be aware of both
approaches though and the way we've just
looked at it is easy to understand which
is why we started with that
so let's see how to use this alternative
syntax by adding a property for our score
attribute so we're going to go back to
our player .py class and we're going to
start off by hiding a score variable by
renaming to _score on line 7
right-click the refactor rename will call it
_score you can see it also
change the line I changed the line
25 as well which was also using score
the score data attribute now next thing we
need to do is add the methods to get and
set the score but we decorate those methods
by putting a special comment before them
going to add them after other methods
before our
STR method down here so let's start
by putting....
....
...
....you can see what happened when we did
that so that's it for the getter we add
the @ property decorator before the
method on the previous line and the
decorator takes care of the score equals
property line that we otherwise
have to write now we haven't covered
decorators yet so just treat this as an
alternative syntax which it really which
is really all that it is now the method
can perform any other tasks it needs to
so could multiply the score by the
number of lives left for example now the
setter is also the same sort method
that was used for the other setters the
decorator this time is in the name of
the property followed by dot setter so
we're going to come down here make a bit
of space here which will clean up a
little bit afterwards we're going to
type....
....
...
let's clean this up a little bit now
so again the setter method is the same
sort of method that we've used for the
other setters the difference here is
that the decorator i use this time when
the line prior to it is the name of the
property followed by dot setter you can
see the line 37 now be careful though
on line 39 if you type self dot score
equals score instead of self dot _
equals score you can get the same
recursive problem we had in the previous
video that applies to all the setters
not just because we're creating this one
differently so back in the main
program main.py come down here and
let's go ahead and do...
...we should find that
works run
see that's working fine and we've
got to score incremented or setter
I should say to 500 so that is properties and
getters and setters in python now
there's really nothing to be gained from
making our score into a properly i just
did it to show you this alternative
syntax but getting back to the play.py
while I'm talking but as the
class stares at the moment we could just
have lifted accessing the score data
attribute directly now the setters for
lives and levels do perform useful
functions so changing them to be
properties was a useful thing to do now
the document
for properties can be found at
this link that i'm going to paste into
a browser
you can see that it could be worth
checking that out as well
alright so I'm going to finish this
video here now in the next video we're
going to start looking at inheritance
which is an important and sometimes
overused feature of object-oriented
programming see you in the next video