Let's talk about creating lists now, in
Python. So it may seem strange to have
the video on creating lists, so far into
the section, but some of this wouldn't
have made sense earlier. Now we've
already seen a couple of ways of
creating a list. Firstly, let's open up
our number_lists.py
program that we wrote, and let's review
those methods. So I'm going to delete all but
the first two lines and then add an
empty list at the top, so let's go ahead
and do that. Okay, then back on line 1
what we're going to do, is type empty
underscore list equals left and right
square brackets - so it's an empty list, in
other words, that we've created. Alright,
so we can create a list by using a
list literal. Line one creates an empty
list - there's nothing between the square
brackets. We've also got two other lists,
as you can see on lines 2 &amp; 3. Each list
is a comma separated list of values
enclosed in square brackets. You can also
create a list by concatenating existing
lists. Let's have a go at doing that.
So on line 5 I'm going to type numbers is
equal to even plus odd. And let's just print
out the result, so print and then
numbers in parentheses on the next line.
So the new list here - numbers - contains
all the items from the two lists that
we've concatenated. So let's just run
this to confirm. So notice after I ran it
there, that the two items are in the same
order as they were in the original list.
The odd numbers appear after the even
ones because we added odd to even.
A third way to create a list is to use a
function that returns one. We've seen a
function that does that - the sorted
function. Let's put some code in for that.
So line eight I'm going to type sorted
underscore numbers is equal to sorted,
and in parentheses, numbers. Let's
print out the result of sorted underscore
numbers, or the value of sorted
underscore numbers. Let's run this.
We've now got another list there - sorted underscore numbers - that contains all the
items for numbers but now in order. And
we've seen that before. I mention it
again because it may not have been
obvious that a new list is created.
The original numbers list is still in the
same order as it was, and we can check that
out by printing it out: print numbers, run
it again. If you want to sort a list in
place without creating a new list, then
you'd call the .sort method. If you
want a sorted list without changing the
original, as we've done here, you can use
the sorted function. sorted() will take
any iterable object. We can give it a
string, and a new list will be created
from the characters in the string.
So let's try that: line twelve, digits
equals sorted parentheses double quotes,
432985617.
Then close off the string and
parentheses, and print digits on the next
line with print, parentheses and digits
in the middle of that. Now before I run
the program, have a think about what it's
going to produce. What will the digits
list contain? Pause the video and start
it again when you've worked out your answer.
Okay, so run the program now to see if
you're right and I'll do that. We get a
list of strings. So each string is a
single character - a digit. When you create
a list from another object, the contents
of the list will normally be the same
type as the items in that object. On line
eight we create a list from a list of ints.
The list that was produced - sorted_numbers - is a list of ints.
On line 12, we create a sequence of
characters, and the digits list that's
produced is a list of strings. So in
Python a character is just a string of
length 1. Let's just run that again to
confirm. So we've got integers first,
and we've got a list of strings, or
characters, on the last line of output.
What if you didn't want to sort the
items? You might have noticed the list
function when we looked at the built-in
functions earlier, in a previous video.
Now technically, list isn't a function -
it's a class initializer. But don't worry
about that - you can just call it, just as
if it is a function. And you will be
learning about classes in the
Object-Oriented Programming section,
and then you'll see exactly what list is
doing. Until then we're going to pretend
it's a function, and we can use that
instead of sorted on line 12. So if I go
back and change sorted here, to list,
and I run, this time we still get a list,
but the items are in the same order as
they appeared in the string. You can use
the list function to create a list from
any iterable, and we can use another list,
for example. So let's have a go at
doing that. So line 15 I'm going to type
more_numbers is equal to
list and in parentheses, numbers.
Let's then print that out, so print on the next
line, parentheses more_numbers.
Run the program, and you can see
we get the same list of numbers
that line 10 produced, now in the output on
the last line of output. So why might you
want to do that. Well it's one way to
copy a list. We've now got two lists with
the same items; numbers and more_numbers.
They're not the same
list, though. We can check that in a
couple of ways. I've already shown you
how to print out the IDs, so you could do
that. We can also use is to see if
they're the same, so let's have a go at
doing that.
So line 17 I'm going to type print, and
in parentheses, numbers is more
underscore numbers, then the closing
parenthesis. We'll run this, and you can see
that the output is False, meaning they're
not the same list. They are equal though,
because they contain the same items in
the same order. Let's verify that.
print, this is on line 18, parenthesis numbers is
equal to, so two equal signs, more
underscore numbers, closing parenthesis.
Run the program again now. This time you
can see line 18 has produced the value
True, meaning the lists are equal because
they both contain the same items. However,
the previous line of output from line 17
showed us that they're not the same list.
There's another way to copy lists and
that's to use a slice, and that's
something else we've seen before.
So what I'm going to do is comment out line 15.
We're going to add a new line 16, which
will copy the list using a slice. So on
line 16 I'm going to type more_numbers = numbers,
in square brackets, and then just with
a colon in those square brackets.
And that should be numbers, not number.
So if we run this now, this does the same thing.
We've now got two lists again with the
same items. So another way to create
a list, as you saw there, was to slice an
existing list. There's actually at least
12 different ways to copy a list in
Python. I don't suggest you use most of
them, because they're not very readable,
and some are also not very efficient.
The most readable way is to use the copy
method that was added to lists in
pythons 3.3. So let's comment out line 16
I'm going to replace that, this time on
line 17, with more_numbers is
equal to numbers.copy, this time with
parentheses because we do want to call
the method.
If you run this you can see we still got
the same output. A lot of code you'll
come across will have been converted
from Python 2. That means you'll see the
slice I've now commented out, on line 16,
being commonly used to copy a
sequence. In Python 3, the slice still
performs quite well. The fastest way,
though, involves using star to unpack the
list, but we haven't covered that yet.
We'll look at that in the section on
functions. If you want to check out the
various ways of copying lists and their
relative performance, there's an
interesting Stack Overflow post here. I'm
just going to bring up a browser.
The list is in the resources section as
always. So this is interesting for a
number of reasons, not the least of which
is that it benchmarks the various approaches.
So check that out at your leisure. There's some good information in there
if you want to find out more. Alright, so back to the code.
So this video didn't contain much that was new but
hopefully, you found the revision helpful.
We've seen a few different ways to
create lists and a few ways to copy an
existing list. It may not have been
obvious that you can test lists for equality.
== will return True if the lists contain the same items, in
the same order. The is operator will
return True if two variables are
referring to the same list. So moving on
now, in the next video we'll go back to
that table on operations on mutable
sequence types, and we'll see how to
replace slices in a list. See you in the
next video.