I mentioned in the last video
there's just a couple more things we
need to look at with exceptions
I guess I said a couple of things but I
really meant 4 so there's two optional
clauses that we can add to a try
statement else and finally so we'll have
a look at what they are next
now it can be important to consider the
order that you catch exceptions using
accept and i'm going to explain about
that as well and the fourth thing is
raising our own exceptions which you
sometimes want to do in your functions
if there's really no sensible action they
can take your functions have to catch
the exception
otherwise your program will crash
as we've seen but if you can't take any
sensible action then sometimes the
best approach is to pass the exception
on to whatever called your function for
it to deal with going to start with the
finally Clause because our current
example program provides quite a cool
demonstration of the fact that a
finally Claus will always be executed so
a finally clause starts surprisingly
with the keyword finally followed by the
block of code that you want to execute
whether an exception was raised or not
let's go ahead and put the finaly clause
into effect and do that on line 13 so...
finally call on the next line as print
...
...now if you use
a finaly Claus it must come after all
your except causes right so let's just
run this and i'm just going to add some
valid input 10 and 5 notice the
finally clause pop up there 4 and there's
the finally executing again if we
run this again and this time I do my
contribute command trick and again
ctrl D on windows or linux notice that
the process still executed but the finally
clause was still executed as well so the
finally Claus really is executed
regardless of whether an exception was
handled or not that's particularly
impressive considering what the code
does when I terminate the input with
control D
so in the end of EOF or end of
file error exception block on line 11 we
we actually called sys.exit to
terminate the program but even though
the program's been told to terminate on
line 12 the finally block on line
fourteen is still executed first so if
you think about it that really makes
finally an ideal place for performing
any tidying up that may be required
before your code finishes now the sorts
of things that you want to do in a
finally block would be things like
closing a database cursor or connection
or closing any open files if your
program is open any those types of
things and that will actually use a
finally clause when we get back to our
database to make sure we close our
cursors
alright so moving on an else clause is
executed if the code in the
try block doesn't raise an exception
so in that sense it's equivalent to the
else clause in a four or a while loop if
you remember the else
in a while loop will execute if the loop
terminates normally so it executed
there's no break or return statement to
execute the loop prematurely so the same
is true of else when used with a try
statement if no exception is handled the
else clause will be executed
otherwise it won't be now the use of the
word else in these cases perhaps
unfortunate it may help to pretend that
a word like completion has been used
instead but unfortunately it wasn't so
we have to remember the two different
uses of else
an if statement and identifies a block
that will be executed if no earlier
condition is true and in for while and
try it's executed if the previous
code complete successfully so if you
use the else clause in your try
statements
it must also come after all the except
clauses but before any finally clause if
you've got one
alright so let's add an else clause to our
program to see how it works
we're going to print a message if the
division was successful going to come
down here after the code on line 23
we're going to add an else on line 24
...
....okay
so I run this again this time lets enter a
couple of values so...we
get 90 / 45 is 2.0 and division
performed successfully so if we run it
again
90 this time but 0 for the second
number you can't divide by 0
and this time we haven't got the message
division perform successfully on screen
so how this is different to finally well
the code in the else clause only execute
if the triblock completed without raising
an exception
so when we attempted to divide by zero
else code didn't execute if i change
else on line 24 now to finally and run
this again and repeat both tests so 90
and 45 we correctly get the answer 2.0
and division perform successfully run it
again this time 90 and 0 as a
second number and we get the message
showing this time division performed
successfully so finally is always executed
even if there's an exception or as you saw
earlier even if the program is
terminated in the try block so code in
the else clause only executed if the try
completes it won't be executed if
there's an exception or if the trial
code returns or quits the program now
you might be wondering this point why we
didn't just put the division perform
successfully message after the code on
line 20 in other words after we printed
out the result in this case we could
have done just that
that's because our print statement can't
raise an exception so there's little
point using else clause here else is
really intended so that we don't
accidentally catch an exception that
wasn't raised by the code we're trying
to protect with the try block so going
back to our bank account example if you
were protecting the updating of two
transactions using a triblock would only
want the code to roll back if there was
an error saving the values to the two
accounts if we add
a load more code inside the try block
and that code raises an exception then
the transactions will be rolled back
even if they completed successfully and
will see that in a video coming up soon
where it makes more sense to use an else
clause so this last example is a bit
contrived to demonstrate really how else
and finally work and the difference
between them
now there's one last thing that this
program is useful to demonstrate before
we abandoned it and move on to something
else
now exceptions like everything else in
python are objects in python three
they must be derived from the base
exception class or one of its subclasses
that wasn't the case in python two
although it was recommended and that's
also mentioned at the start of the
document we're looking at the browser
earlier you can see here in Python
all exceptions must be instance of a class
instances of a class that derives from
base exception so most exceptions will
be subclasses of exception rather than
base exception which is the
recommendation in the fourth paragraph
on that page programmers are encouraged to
derive new exceptions from the exception
class or one of its subclasses and not
from base exception so why is that
important well the first reason is that
you can catch exception in your except
Clause to catch any exception that's
derived from it so let's actually have a
look at how that works in our code
so go back to the IDE so on line
nine we've got this line except
value error now we can
check that value area is a subclass of
exception by holding down the control
key or on in my case on a Mac the
command key clicking on it to see the
code you can see their class value error
exception then click on that and have a
look
so you can see here that value error
inherits from exception and if we click
on exception
you can see that exception inherits from
base exception so what that means is we
can come back to our code gonna
close it down means that we can actually
change this on line 9 and replace that
with exception and if we run this we
should find that still copes
with invalid input 90 and 0
just bogus number valid number and then 0
so still coping and basically
catching those exceptions
now with that said I'm not recommending that
you do this or suggesting you do that
it's generally a good idea to be
specific in the exceptions you catch
rather than just catching everything one
reason for being specific is that you
can handle the different exceptions
differently now if you can just catch
all exceptions as we're doing here
the code will react in the same way
regardless of what exception was raised
that may often not be the appropriate
way to react and in fact we've got a
problem with our code now so it looks
like it worked fine until you understand
this next bit you probably won't see
anything wrong by looking at the code now
IntelliJ is aware that
something is not quite right
we actually got a warning on line 11
that's where we catch the end of file
error you can see the exception
superclass of exception class EOF error
has already been caught so let's
actually see the effect of that before
talking anymore about it i'm going to
run it again going to do the ctrl D
command D on the mac you can see what's
happening here we're going into a loop
our programs running wild again i'm
going to stop it and cancel out of that
the question at this point is what went
wrong
remember when I said that the order that
you handle the exceptions is important
what's happening here with our code is
that exception is a subclass of EOF
error now subclass of a base class is
also an instance of its base class so
this case EOF error is an
instance of exception and when we catch
exception on line 9 we're
actually catching all exceptions that
inherit from it including the eof error
exception that has been defined on line
11 so what that means is that the code
that runs when eof error is raised is the
actual code on line 10 so therefore the
program doesn't get to exit it just
prints a message and loops or allows the
loop to go around again and again and
again because the input streams closed
and we keep getting these
eof errors raised by line 7 IntelliJ is
aware of this and that's why its giving
us a warning
so when you're handling multiple
exceptions like we are here it is very
important that you catch them in the
right order
so the more specific exceptions have to
appear first so you can fix this program
up by moving lines 11 and 12 up until
before we catch the exception on line 9
so I'm gonna just copy those cut
them out and pasted above the code that
was on line 9 and if you actually run
this and enter some bogus text that isn't a
number here we get invalid number and
now if I come back here again and do a
command on a Mac ctrl D on windows or
linux we actually get it to exit
correctly with exit code one so you can see
the code that we generated for the
exception eof error is now being
executed correctly when we do the
control d e so it's not often
that you specify exception as the
exception to handle your except Clause
but this applies whether you're catching
multiple exceptions and some of the ones
you want to catch derive from others and
by the way we are getting this other error here
about two broad exception clause this
warning is that perhaps we should be
more specific
alright so the last thing i want to
mention is related to this now remember
from the documentation that not all
exceptions have to be derived from
exception the requirement is that they
derived from base exception or one of
its subclasses so if you really do want
to catch any exception then there's a
way to specify the sort of wild card
exception meaning everything to do that
just leave off the exception type so
the except Clause is just the keyword
accept and a colon so this example is
going to delete the exception on line 11
and just leave the colon there before I
do this just to be clear I'm going to
change the finally here on line 24 to an else
again
so that when I make the code
available in the resources it's showing
how it should be done rather
demonstrating how not to do it right the
other thing I'm going to do here is on
line 11 is just to make it clear here
with a comment
we should really be except...
...
alright let's test the program a few
times let's try a number or partial
numbers i will test for invalid input
using numbers and letters invalid number
will try just letters that works and try
76.....that works ok running
again and again we're getting the errors
caught successfully invalid numbers by
the Wildcard accept on line 11 so that's
good right second time lets do a divided
by 0 so 32 and 0 the finally clause always
execute and you can't divide by 0 and
we done a assist.exit 2 as you can see
there the code on line 23 was executed and
let's do the control d check again run
that and do a control command D on a mac
and control d on a windows
or linux and the finally clause
always execute and we're finishing the
code on line 10 is executed
correctly
so everything's working so
that's exceptions and how to handle them
in python so in the next video we can
have a quick look at how to raise our
own exceptions before we ultimately get
back to databases so see you as
always in the next video