In this video we're gonna go ahead and
download and install Python for a Mac.
Now if you're running Python on a
Windows machine or running Python on a
Linux machine, then you want to actually
refer to a separate video that I've got
in this part of the course for each of
those other platforms and the reason for
that is that the process is a little bit
different depending on which platform
you're actually running it on. So in this
case, we're going to install a Python
on a Mac, so first things to do first
thing to do is to go to python.org and
we're going to download the latest
version, so I'm going to hover over here
to downloads noting that because I'm on
a Mac, it's come up and showing me the
download automatically, so the version we
want to select is one here to the left,
Python six three point six point
two and that's the current version as of
the time that I'm recording this video,
you might find in the future it'll be a
later version, so you just grab the
latest one that appears and click on
that I'm gonna save that and what I want
to do though is just mention here that
this Python 2.7, we definitely don't want
that and the reason is that this course
deals with Python 3 but the other reason
is that Python 2 actually already exists
on a Mac. So while that's downloading,
well it's actually finished now, but I
just want to briefly go into terminal so
I'll press the command space and typed
terminal, I'm gonna type Python so we
haven't actually installed Python yet
we've only downloaded it. We'll go ahead
and type those commands and notice that
we actually get something working,
it's come up and said Python 2.7
so that's installed by default on a Mac.
So in case you're wondering how it got
there it's when you install or whether
your Mac is installed with the new
version and whatever operating version
of OS X that you're running Python
version 2 is installed, but in our case
we don't want to use version 2, we want
to use version 3, so consequently I'm
going to exit out of that prompt by
doing a control d and the command we
would normally type would be Python 3
that would be how we access version 3
and higher, but you can see that the
moments coming up coming up and saying
that python 3 command were not found. So what
we now need to do is swing over and
install python 3, so i'm going to log out
the topping exit close down terminal and
come over here to where it was downloaded
to open the package that we downloaded
python 3.6, we're going to go ahead now
and install that, so I'm gonna click on
continue we're going to continue again
and one more time you can read all these
things if you want but clicking
through fast to get the installation
completed, we're going to agree to the
software license click on install,
I'm going to type my password we'll give it
a moment to complete.
Okay so I can see the installations now
been completed so I can close
that down, I'm going to move the
installer that we downloaded to the
trash because we're finished with it.
Now the last thing we need to do in this
video now is just check that Python 3 is
available so I'm going to hold down
command and press space again and type
in terminal just going to select what's
there because that's remembered it from
last time press enter and if recall
last time we try this Python 3
didn't work, but now if I type Python 3
we can see that in fact it's now working.
So what's happened is python 3 has been
installed and the Mac has been updated
with that and we can now start accessing
that and we'll be using that server
version of Python throughout the course,
control d to exit in just a confirmation
if we just type Python without the 3 on
the end, we still get access to the old
part of it so in effect we've got two
versions, we haven't affected the version
that comes with the Mac by default what
we've done is installed an additional
version and we'll be using that
additional version as we go through this
course. Alright, so we'll finish the video
here, I'll see you in the next one.