In this video, we're going to download
and install IntelliJ IDEA, which is the
editor or IDE, Integrated Development
Environment,
we're going to be using to create
programs in this course. So what we need
to do is start out by going to jetbrains.com, and
Jetbrains is the creator of the
IntelliJ IDEA product. So I'll go to
their website. I'm going to come down to
the Tools menu, hover over that. Move on
down to IntelliJ IDEA.
I'm going to click over here to  Yes I agree, just to remove that little pop-up. I'm going to select Download.
Then when we do that there's
two options here; we've got the Ultimate
Edition, noting that it's also
available for Mac OS and Linux as well.
So we've got the Ultimate Edition and the
Community Edition. So we can use the
Community Edition in this course and
that's completely free and open source.
There's no cost, and there's never
going to be a cost to use it - it's
completely free. The Ultimate Edition,
out of interest, is available if you're
looking at some extra tools. That's more
for professional developers; things like
Java Enterprise Edition and Spring and
so on and so forth. But we're going to be
using the Community Edition so I'm going
to click on over here to download it.
Then I'm gonna select Run, noting that you
may have to save this to a folder
somewhere and double click it, once it's downloaded,
if your browser doesn't allow you to do what I've just done.
So we'll give that a moment to complete now.
I'll just fast-forward this a bit. Alright, you can see we're just about done now
Okay, when this pop-up comes up I'm going
to click on Yes that we're going to
allow this app to make changes. I'm going
to close down the browser at this point
because we've finished with that. We're
going to go through the installation setup.
I'm going to click on Next. I'm going to  click on Next again.
Alright so this little pop-up, you need to specify whether you're a 32-bit or a 64-bit user.
Now nine times out of ten you will select 64-bit, but if you know that your operating
system is 32-bit then that will be the
box you'll check.
You can optionally update the context menu to add an option to Open folders project.
I don't actually use that so I'm going to leave that
unchecked, and I'm going to create these
associations; the dot Java, the dot groovy
and doc Kt which is for Kotlin,
because that's useful if you want to
edit those particular files in this
IntelliJ IDEA product as well. So
generally, I would suggest you just click
those options anyway, even if you don't
think you're going to use them at the moment.
Click on Next, Install, and this is now
installing IntelliJ IDEA.
Once this is completed there's a few little minor installation configurations we need to set
before we end the video.
Alright, just about finished, as we can
see now.
Alright, the next thing I suggest you do is check the Run IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition, because there's a
few things we need to set up. Click on
Finish.
Eventually this little pop-up will come
up. We've got the option to select a Config
or installation folder, or Do not import
settings. Do not import settings if this
is the first time you've used IntelliJ
IDEA. Set that. The Configure
installation folder is there if you want
to import settings from a previous installation.
In our case, we're not
going to do that so I'm going to click
on OK, after selecting or making sure
that Do not import settings is selected.
We're gonna accept JetBrains Privacy
Policy by clicking the check box and
clicking on Continue.
You've got the options to send JetBrains
usage anonymous statistics. I'm gonna
click on Don't send but you're free
to select and choose to send
those statistics if you wish.
Next we're prompted as to whether we
want a dark background, which is
generally easier on the eyes when you're
programming, or a light background.
Now I'm going to choose light because that
tends to come out better in the videos,
but if you want to choose the darkula
theme, the darker one, then do that,
noting that you can always go back into
settings later and change this.
So I'm gonna click on next. I'm going to leave this
screen alone, noting that the screen will
be different, if you've chosen the
ultimate edition of IntelliJ.
We don't need to make any changes there, we can
just leave everything as it is. Click on Next.
Same deal there, I'm not going to
change anything. You can always come back
and install these things later, if that's
something that you want to do. We won't
be using any of those in the course, and
click on Start using IntelliJ IDEA.
Alright, so at this point we're now
done. We've now successfully installed
IntelliJ IDEA. So now that we've done
that we do have a few minor
configurations that we need to finish
off. Specifically, what we need to do is
configure it for the software
development kit, so that we can start
creating programs in this course, but
we're going to do that in a separate video.
I'll end the video now, and we'll
see you in the next video where we start
making a few other changes to configure
IntelliJ IDEA.
So I'll see you in that next video.