We've seen how we can store values
in variables, and print them out.
We've also looked at getting input from the keyboard,
in the previous section in this course.
We'll now start getting Python to
make decisions, based on the values of
variables and input. Just to quickly recap,
I'm going to just type in a quick
program. I'm going to delete the last
three lines from the last video.
I'm going to type name equals input parentheses and
double quotes, Please enter your name,
colon and a space there, and on line 2,
age equals input parentheses double
quotes again, How old are you comma space.
Then we want left and right curly braces,
replacement fields, zero in the middle,
question mark to the right of the right
curly brace and a space. Then a closing
double quote dot format name and two
right parenthesis. Then line three, we're
going to print out the value of age,
so print parentheses age. Alright, just as
a quick recap to what we've done
previously, I'm gonna run that code now,
and remember to click into the run
window as I did, before typing your name
if you're using an IDE like IntelliJ.
So come down here and click on that and
I'll just move this down a little bit.
I'm going to type in my name, enter, How
are you Tim, like to think I'm 21,
press enter, 21 is shown in the
window. So note that we can use
replacement fields in any string,
including the one we're using as a
prompt to the input function. The input
function returns as str or string datatype.
We have to convert it to an int
if we want age to represent a number,
rather than the string, and we do that
with the int function. So if we change
line 2 slightly. Instead of putting input parentheses
we'll put int, left parentheses.
Then right at the end, now we've done that,
we need to go to the end
of the line and add a right parenthesis
there, to keep Python happy.
So using int and input together like this is very
common when you want to get a number
from the user. It does have a serious
problem though. Your code will crash if
you type anything that can't be
converted to an integer. Now we'll be
looking at how to handle that later in the course.
Until then, make sure your only enter valid
numbers when our programs expect a number.
Alright, so if we just run this to confirm,
enter your name again, Tim,
25, we're getting the value of 25.
And let's just quickly show what would
happen if we do insist on typing
something that's not a number. I'll type in
the text twenty.
You can see we've got an error there,
and again, we'll talk about how
to fix that later in the course.
Right, at this point though, we've got a
number. We saw that that was working,
and we can make, at this point, some decisions
based on the person's age.
So let's start by checking if they're old enough to
vote. In many countries,
including Australia, the legal age for voting is 18.
So let's come up and on line 5,
type if space age is greater than, and the equal
sign, 18 colon press enter.
So we started with the keyword if and followed it with
a condition, and here the condition is
age greater than equal to 18. Now notice the
colon that I placed on the end of that line.
That means we're about to start a
new code block, and in fact, we did
start a new code block when I pressed
enter, and the IDE indented the next line
for us automatically, as we've seen
previously. The indentation is very important.
That's how Python knows that
we're starting a new block of code.
Alright, so if they're old enough to
vote we'll print out a suitable message.
So let's do that on line 6 and put
print parentheses double quotes,
You're old enough to vote. Okay. So if the
condition is true,
in other words,  the age entered is greater than or equal to 18,
then we're printing out the message, You
are old enough to vote,
and I'll just press backspace there to remove the
indentation. Let's run it.
We'll do it a few times just to make sure, with
different ages, that it is working as expected.
So if I start by typing my
name firstly, then the age is 18,
You are old enough to vote, so that's
working. Tim and I'll try 17. We get just
the value 17, we don't get a message
saying we're old enough to vote,
and lastly, do one 50, Tim 50, You are old enough to vote.
And again, remember to type a valid
number, or you'll get the error that I
showed earlier in the video, if you're
not using a number. Alright, so what
we've done there on line 5, that's how to
test a condition in Python, keyword
if followed by condition, in this case,
age greater than equal to 18,
and finishing the first, and finally ending
the line with a colon.
Now conditions can be a lot more complex
than that, as we'll see. We know that a
colon tells python to expect a new code
block, so line 6 is indented by 4 spaces.
If age is less than 18, nothing happens,
which is a bit unfriendly. We can cater
for that by adding an else clause to our
if keyword. Now we don't want any more
code inside the if block, which means we
remove the indentation on the else line.
So I've already done that. You saw me do
that earlier, but we'll start typing on
line 7, else : press Enter.
Notice how IntelliJ has helpfully
indented again. We'll type print
parentheses double quotes, Please come
back in, and we use a replacement field
with a zero in between the left and
right curly braces, space years, double quote comma,
and we'll put format parenthesis 18 minus age,
and the two right closing parentheses. So
if the person's age is greater than or
equal to 18, the first block of code is
executed, otherwise the second one is
executed, asking them to come back when
they're 18, or more specifically, in a
number of years, asking them to come back when they're 18.
So we run this a few times just to make sure that
it works. Let's do that, Tim, 18,
still get the same result, 18, You are old enough to vote.
Tim, 50, You are old enough to vote. That's
working, and we'll do one more, this time
if they're less than 18, Tim, we'll say 9, Please
come back in, and we made a typo there.
I'll put a comma there. Notice I put a
comma there instead of a period, which is
a subtle little bug. I'll do that.
We didn't see that until we entered in the value,
so Tim, How old are you? 9. There it is
again,
Please come back in nine years
and that's because I enter the age of
9, and the calculation on line 18 was
18 minus what we entered, in this case, 9.
So it says come back in 9 years, when of
course you'll be 18. Alright, so as we saw
in the last video, a block can contain
several lines of code to execute.
So let's go ahead and add something, a
second line under line 6, so on line 7
I'm going to type print parenthesis
double quotes, Please put an X
in the box,
and we'll close off the string and then
right parenthesis. Because line 6 and
7 are in the same block, in other
words, they're indented to the same level,
we should find that both messages will
be printed if the age is greater than
equal to 18. So let's just run that to
confirm that is the case. Please enter your name,
Tim, 19, You are old enough to vote.
Please put an X in the box. There's often
several ways to do the same thing when programming.
It may seem natural to deal with the voters first,
but we can do that the other
way around as well. So to see what
I mean I'm going to add some code.
I'll add that down here.
We'll start on line 11. We'll leave line 10
blank. We're going to put if age is less than 18:
and let's just copy the line, here,
we'll copy that line. Notice when you
moved the cursor down it automatically
moved over to the indentation level. We're
going to paste that as if the age is
less than 18, else:
I'm going to grab the two lines up here.
I'm going to paste those in as well.
Notice that IntelliJ helpfully indents
at the right line, or to the right
indentation level, and again we're doing
things the other way around. We're not
dealing with the voters first this time. We're
dealing with people who, in fact, aren't
old enough to vote, first, and the people
who are, second, just to show you there's
another way of doing the same thing. So
we run this. I'm going to enter the same
thing twice now for Tim, 15, Please come
back in 3 years, as you can see.
We've got exactly the same output two
times and that's because we've got two
conditions in there, two code blocks if
you will. So if I enter that again,
Tim, 21, and you can see we've got the
output again, duplicated,
because effectively, we've duplicated, we've got
two if code blocks with the appropriate
else clauses entered. So the code,
ultimately, that I've added does exactly
the same thing, but it's checking the
condition the other way around.
If the person is less than 18, we print the
message asking them to come back,
otherwise, we print the two lines
asking them to tick the box.
So it doesn't matter which way round you phrase the conditions?  Well in this example, no it doesn't,
but in the next video, we'll see why it can matter.
See you in the next video.