So this section, we're gonna look
at input and output in Python.
So, I/O, input output just means
getting data into a program and
getting it out again.
Now, we've already seen one way to enter
data into our programs from the keyboard.
But in this section we're gonna be looking
at another way that can also be useful.
And we've also covered printing
results to the screen.
But so far every time we've needed data
in our program, we've had to type it in.
So wouldn't it be useful to be able
to save that data to a file so
that we can use it over and over again?
So in this section we're gonna be looking
at a number of ways to write data to
a file using the computer's disk drive.
And we'll also include writing
the data in a similar way,
To how it's printed on the screen.
This is a process you'll
understand a little bit later.
Another process we're also going to look
at how python dictates object provide
the basis for
a very useful way to store data.
So, let's make a start.
The first we're gonna talk
about reading text files.
And the good thing about this is
that reading text files in Python
is incredibly easy and just really
consists of three simple steps.
So, first we have to open the file.
And we And we use that using the Python
built in function called Open.
Then the next step is to read in the file
which we can do either one line at
a time or we can actually try and
read in the entire file in one go.
Finally to close the file when we're
done with it is the final step.
Now this is very important,
especially when writing to a file
because if it's not done the file
can actually get corrupted.
Now the resources section of this video
contains a text file that you can see on
the screen there now.
That we can use to
practice reading a file.
So download that file, and place it in
a suitable directory in your local drive.
It contains Lewis Carroll's
poem Jabberwocky,
from through The Looking Glass.
So we're going to use that,
and read that into Python.
Now I've actually stored
this on my desktop.
But you can literally store anywhere.
So, let's go ahead now and write a program
that will read this file into Python.
So, we're gonna start by typing Java = and
We're gonna type open which is
the built in function to open a file.
We're gonna put home/dev/Desktop.
Now that's actually the path
that I've got on my computer
to this file and it's called sample.txt.
Like so, and then we can go ahead and
type for line in jober.
Print line, and lastly, jabber.close.
So again, the first line opens
the text file on line one.
On line three and four, we're actually
cycling through each line in the document.
Then we're printing it
out one line at a time.
So we're cycling right through
to the end of the file.
And line six closes at
the file when we're done.
Now the other thing I didn't
put here which we actually need
at the end of the open is we need
to provide the mode as well.
So if you think about it when
you're opening a text file or
a file on your computer you need to tell
it what type of input output you want.
So in this case we don't want to write
to this file, we want to read to it.
So to do that we just Put a comma and
we put the letter R in single quotes,
which again stands for read-only or read.
Now the thing here also is you can provide
a full path, as you can see on the screen
here, or you can top a relative
path as part of the [INAUDIBLE].
This is the first example;
this is a full path.
If you're on a Mac or on a Linux system
Just run this first just to check that it
works, then we'll talk about
the Windows side of things.
And I'm actually getting an error
that the file isn't found, so
I'll just confirm that
it is on my desktop.
I'm gonna open my terminal We
probably made a mistake in the path.
I'm gonna go to my desktop.
That's why I put in /Home.
It should be /Users/dev/Desktop.
So you can see there, that's the path
on my computer to the desktop.
So I'm too used to typing
/Home being on a Linux system.
So I'm gonna go back and change the code.
And paste that in.
And put another slash there
in the name of the file.
We'll try to run that again, and
we should be able to get it to work.
You can see that we've got all
the data coming from the text file and
the poem's coming out quite nicely,
so that's good.
Now the thing to point out here is again
this is a mech path which is very similar
to Linux path.
You'll notice the slashes
are going forward.
And that's the convention for
mac influence.
But if you're running on
a Windows computer, and
you had a username of Tim,
you'd probably do something like this.
You'd type java, equals open.
And it'd be something like C
colon backslash documents.
Is settings/tim/mydocumentssample.text,
if you have it in your documents folder,
sample.text, and The origin to
set it up for read only mode.
Now, that doesn't always work
with the slashes with space.
Sometimes it's bit of an issue.
And there's also certain
characters to cause a problem,
because if you put a /n for argument sake.
/n is interpreted as a command and
/t as well.
So, what it can be a good idea to do for
your slashes is to put double slashes here
and that just makes it clear to Python.
This is a path, and it doesn't try and
interpret the character after the slash as
something else, so
you might do something like that.
Even though that looks a little bit funny,
that does make sure that that makes--you
know, really makes sure that the path is
going to be treated as a path and
not as something else.
So I'll comment that out and
go back to my code because obviously I'm
on a Mac, so I'll need that to work.
Now if I type in something, well,
we saw the example earlier where
the path doesn't exist when we run it.
We get an error to say,
cannot find In the file.
So it's pretty clear that there's
a problem out in the file, and so
it will actually crash at that point.
And put that back in there.
So again just a note about slashes.
The forward slashes work equally
on a Mac and a Linux machine.
But, they're, but the same.
But with a Windows machine
it's back slashes.
But you can't use back
slashes in a Linux or
Mac path,
you need to use the forward slashes.
So You wanna get clear based
on your operating system as to
which way you're using your slashes.
Obviously if I haven't
got the path in there,
if I actually remove my path altogether,
I run that, I'm going to get an error.
And the error is you can say
it's looking for this folder,
user/dev/documents-programs/pauseandprogr-
ams/folderIO.
It's looking for that folder, And
it's actually looking for
sample.text in that folder.
So that's why it's best to have
relativepath to get that to work.
If you're not located
in that relative path,
it's not going to actually work for you.
What I can do, though, is set up a new.
Go back into our folder.
Now, take a copy of that and what I'm
going to do is go into the programs,
Python, File I/O, I'm going to
paste the sample of text in there.
So I've now got it in my path,
which you can see is
Users\Dev\Documents\Programs\Python
Programs\File IO.
So now if I run that, without specifying
a path, because we know the path
by looking up here We run that,
we find that it does find it.
So it's all a matter of choosing
the right folder to put the files in.
You can even just specify a path in full.
Or if you know you're in that particular
folder, you can just use the,
or select the actual name,
without specifying the path.
so at this point forward,
I'm not going to specify a path anymore so
all the files that we read and write are
going to be in that particular folder so
keep in mind that when you're working
along with this, to make sure you put
the symbol dot text in the actual folder
where this particular program resides.
Now, when you go online to
find Python examples, or
you read the official documentation,
you'll come across the term Pythonic to
describe the Python way of doing things,
compared to other programming languages.
And I've used that word a few
times as we've been through.
Now, this is an excellent
example of what Pythonic means.
In most of the languages, after opening
the file, You have to check for
the end of the file,
normally by using a while loop.
But Python, that's to interact
through the lines of the file
as though it were a list,
which is pretty fabulous.
And you can, of course,
perform another processing as
you iterate through the files.
For example, we could check each line, and
only print out the ones containing
the title character, for arguments' sake.
So, we could do something like this,
if Jabberwalk, in, line dot lower.
I'm converting it to lower case there so
we can do a case check
against the stream that we've entered,
which is already lower case.
Only then,
you can get a print line for this,
also print end equals what so, so
it doesn't go into the next line.
Run that.
I'm not too sure what's showing an error
there, but the code is definitely valid,
so it could be something to do with the
new version of the Python plug in perhaps,
but that's definitely
valid code there anyway.
So, you can see that it's working,
and it's only returning the lines
that have got the word Jabberwalk in,
and printing them to the screen.
Remember that string's just a sequence
of characters, so as a result,
we can test for
the sequence general being in the lines.
You can see that I've done a line four.
Now, we haven't specifically covered
a string's lower method to ensure that we
find Jabberwock whether it's in upper or
lowercase or a mix of both.
Now, I mentioned earlier that
we're using .lower, so that way,
we're testing whether the string
Jabberwock Text is upper or lower case.
We're still gonna find a match because
we've typed what we're searching for
in lowercase.
And we're using the .ToLower method,
which is from the string class.
and that's enabling us to do a comparison
in respective of the case that's being
typed in for the.
And what the n did, was it specified
that it should not automatic line
after each line was printed,
and you saw that when I ran it.
You didn't space it out like
the other examples we're showing.
And the reason we're doing that
is because the value of line,
as it's read from the file,
contains the new line character
that is in the file itself
to move on to the new line.
Which is why earlier on when I was
running this display, In the entire file,
we've got double spacing.
That's specifying n equals and basically
two single quotes keeps print from
printing another two-line character,
which in this example is perfect.
And finally of course on line seven,
jabberwock close closes
the file To tidy everything up.
Very important to do that.
In fact, failing to close a file after
reading from it can result in subsequent
attempts to read or
write to that file to fail.
And if you fail to close
a file after writing to it,
then the file itself can become corrupted
and not all data can be written to it.
Now, with this example, there's an even
more Pythonic way to open files that,
as well as being more concise,
also removes the risk of
failing to close the file afterwards,
which is always a good thing.
So, Python has a width statement that
was introduced initially in Python 2.5,
and if an object supports a use of width,
and a file does, then width
will tidy everything up automatically
once the object's no longer needed.
So looking at the previous example,
let's just comment that out and
let's top it using width.
So with the top open, sample dot text,
[INAUDIBLE].
Test java.
Full line in java.
If in line
print line end equals Single quotes again.
And again, we're ignoring that there
because it's not really an error.
It's just showing red for some reason.
Okay, so run it, and
you can see we got the same result.
But there's no need to specifically close
the folder this time because the width
takes care of that for us.
You'll notice also the way that these
open files are associated with a variable
by using S Jabber.
So that we can refer to
jabber in the loop, so
you have to use the earlier myth that
if you're writing parse and to code and
also in that case to remember to close
the file when you are done with it.
This has got an additional advantage.
Without using with,
if there was an error in reading the file,
The with stopping the file
may not be closed, which,
in a especially could mean that
it can't be deleted or moved.
So programs often have to areas and
ensure that things like files are closed
if an error in fact does occur.
Now we're going to be
looking at error soon.
But using width here means that it's
not something we need to worry about.
If there's an error reading from the file,
then the width statement will
the exception, and close the file before
the error terminates the program, and
that's pretty cool that's
handling all that for us.
So, from now on in the course,
we're going to be using width
whenever an object supports it.
So there are plenty of examples
to get used to using that, and
we do suggest that you do
use it as much as possible.
Now, before we move on to
look at different modes for
opening a file, we'll have a look
at another couple of ways we
could've written the first program to show
the use of read, read line and read lines.
SO, i'm gonna close this down and
we can also change this.
We got could've put line equals.
And so what i'll do is what I done before
commenting code you got the various
code you use in each lecture.
So, we'll start again with open.
Sample.text again.
Read only, S jabber, and
this one we'll talk line equals jabber
.readline while
line, print line.
And we talk line equals jabber.readline.
Like so.
And if you run that
you can see we've got
the whole poem this time.
And notice that it has no
double spacing anymore because
the end=' ' has removed that extra line.
Because, of course, there was an end
line in the actual text file itself.
And so, what we're saying is.
By putting n="" or an empty string, we're
saying don't print that line as well,
and that's why we're not
getting that double up anymore.
And in terms of using red line,
you can see that we read the first line of
the file on line 14, Into the variable
line, and if some data be read,
in other words, the file wasn't empty,
then we enter the wallet.
Now, if there was a problem,
and the file was empty,
it wouldn't process from line 15 onwards.
It wouldn't get into the wall,
in other words.
At that point the while loop is gonna
continue until there's no lines,
there's no additional lines to read.
And this code is probably closer to the
way that a file is normally processed in
other programming languages,
sort of line by line as you can see there.
And as another example I'll just take
a copy of that and then comment that out.
And then down here posted it again.
There's also another example,
we could use lines.
this case, lines equals dot read lines.
And we can literally then just
get rid of the y altogether.
Change the print just to print lines.
We don't need the end any more.
And we don't need the line either.
So that's going to read the entire
file and return the list,
which can then be processed
automatically as ever we would like.
As any other list for that matter.
So I could do that first, run it.
You can see that's been
converted to a list.
And then what we could also do then, is we
can put four lines using a standard list,
loop four line in lines.
Print line and
equals single quote, single quote.
And if we run that,
we get a similar thing there.
We've got going through the list
element by element effectively.
And pretty up your typo.
And the other thing I wanted to point out,
just run that again,
can you see the slash end there?
This second entry there.
The slash end there is the sort
of end of line character.
And that's on each element so
that's why we need to use the end
equals single quote, single quote.
Or entry string, in other words, to avoid
that being processed and doubling us up.
So that's In the file itself, which you
would expect when you're creating a file.
When you press Enter, that's what happens,
the file normally includes
that character in there.
That does bring up an interesting point.
It is very useful, when you're de-bugging,
to print things like this,
because you may not have been aware
of that, for argument's sake.
And just seeing that that's in
the data itself that's returned
from a read lines method can be really
useful for de-bugging purposes.
So printing variables as a rule like this
is very useful, and you really see what
the data is, because it may or may not
be what you had expected, and obviously,
you would never leave that type of
output in a finished program, but for
debugging purposes,
while you're developing it, testing it,
debugging it,
it's really useful to see what's going on.
So, read lines, let's close that down,
read lines reads
the entire file in one go.
Now this may not be a good idea for a very
large file, but can have interesting uses,
depending on the file itself.
So what we could have done,
and I'll just copy this again,
down here we can put four line in lines,
and then we'll change that to a range, and
we'll put minus one, so, and
now if we run that That might appear
to be a bit frivolous, but it really
demonstrates what readLines is doing.
By iterating through a reverse
slice you can see that
we do indeed have a list of lines.
So you contrast that with using
read in this next example and
the instructions to print the value of
the lines variable is being removed.
So contrast that with this code
I'm about to write here now.
[SOUND]
So we'll do the same thing again.
This time I'll leave that line as well.
We'll get rid of that.
Leave the print lines out there.
And we'll change this to read
instead of read lines, just read.
And run that.
And you can see now the difference.
And the instructions will print the value
of the lines variables being removed to
make it clear what's being reversed,
as you can see there.
So that's been completely
reversed using .read.
So read.
Are really more useful
dealing with binary files.
But this does demonstrate that the way
we've used it here to read the entire file
into a string in one go, which is,
of course, another way of,
of manipulating files.
Readlines also reads the entire file.
But gives a list of strings
rather than just a single string.
So just to summarize before
we finish this video,
readline reads a single line from
a file and returns a string.
Now this is the same behavior
as we did when forline in Java,
which is at the start, one of the first
things we did in this lecture.
The files read one line
at a time in other words.
The latch file this is
the recommended approach and for
obvious reasons because it doesn't read
the entire file into memory and depending
on your devices and the computer you may
not have a lot of memory to work with.
Now read lines.
Reads the entire file and
returns a list of strings.
So, the entire file is readed into memory
which can again cause problems if you
got very last files
occupying a lot of memory.
And read, as we last used it on the last
method there on the last
example Raising tar file and
if it's a text file returns a string
containing the contents of the file.
So read can also take
an optional parameter
specifying how much data to read,
and we'll see that in use later.
So that's it,
I'm going to finish the video here now.
In the next video we're going to start
talking about writing to a text file.
See you in that next video.