so its now time for a challenge what
we're going to do is challenge your
understanding of TKinter and get you to
solve a particular challenge that we've
come up with so what I'm going to do first is
open a new Python file and paste in the
challenge so just gonna call it challenge and let me go ahead and paste in what the
challenge is all about so here is the
challenge the challenge is to write a GUI program to create a simple calculator layout that
looks like the screen shot that I am about to
show you actually I'll show that first
there's the screen shot of what we try to
produce here
so when you're going
ahead creating this and you are gonna be using
Tkinter for it you will try to be Pythonic as possible so it's ok if you want to
end up writing repeated
button and grid statements but consider
using lists and also a for loop then there's
no need to store the buttons in
variables as an optional extra refer to
the documentation to work on how to use
minsize() the function to prevent a
window from being shrunk
so the widgets vanished from view and just a hint you
may also want to use the widgets
.winfo_height function as well as .winfo_width the function method for that
as well which case you should know that
they will not return the correct results unless
the window has been forced to draw
the widgets by calling its update method
first so keep that in mind and a final note if you are using
Windows you probably find that the width is already
constrained and can't be re-sized to small
the height will still need to be
constrained so that's it that's the
challenge to produce this interface as you can
see on the screen there so it's now time
to go away and try that out so pause the video now
and get that working and then come back
when you're ready to see what our solution was
..ok so hopefully you
were able to get it working so let's go
ahead and show you our version as always our is just one version one possible
solution you don't need to have produced
an identical challenge result the
main thing is you've got something
working ok so gonna start with try because I want to import TKinter
....and you saw this code before...
...ok so what we are gonna do first is create
some keys and ultimately this are going to
contain the various settings and so forth
that we need so...you will see how this all works shortly....and your probably figuring out these are the various entries for the calculator....
.....
.....ok so there's our
keys so that's the various keys that are
forming part of the interface the actual
keys that you would type on a calculator ok we are gonna specify the variable for our
padding....
...set that as we've done through out this
section on TKinter.....
...ok so lets setup our entries so.....
.....
......
.....ok so next is going to be a
loop so put.....
...so we are gonna go through our keys to defined on line 29 and add each row but also each column within
that as well so we are doing column now so....and we are going to add buttons for all of those so....
......
.....
..so we are going through the
various columns and rows and once you've
done that that should be all we need to do
and on line 57...so just going through that loop now although we could have
actually just use a similar line like you
see on line 53 to create all the buttons
individually the more Pythonic way is
to set up a representation of the
buttons in a nested lists of lists to
represent the rows of the keypad and
also the keys within each row so a simple loop as
you can see then gets each row from the
list that we defined on line 29 an
inner loop gets the caption and the
column span values for each key in the row as a tuple now the sticky properties is used to
make each button fill the width of its cell
because the row height is determined by
the size of the buttons using north and
south is unnecessary here now the TKInter
module contains a number of constants
so we used a couple of those in
previous videos but also includes the 8
compass points so you can see when your using TKinter.e
for east and tkInter.w now
although there's no difference between
the way would set sticky here and the
previous way of using a string its useful to see this method using the Tkinter
constants because you may come across it at an
existing code
often you'll find that Tkinter has been imported
using star so you might see e+w as
well and the way we've been setting it up
to this point involves less typing and
there's no need to include the row and
column numbers in the data so that they can
easily be calculated in the loops and
that's why we've dont it that way and for the
optional extra we can work at why the keypad is using winfo_width property you
can then add on to the Windows padding to do
that and similarly winfo_height is going to
give us the height of the keypad and
result to entry box which we can add to get
the total height needed these
values are use in the main window as
min size method to prevent the window from re-sizing too small at first lets just run what
we've got before we actually go ahead
so gonna run that right click on run the
challenge and there's our basic calculator as
you can see on the screen at the moment
and obviously it needs to be fixed a little
bit but re-sizing will be good but we will come back and do that but basically we got our entry box
for our numbers we got the various buttons on the
screen coming up so we are off to a good start so lets
close that off and come back down here and I mentioned
previously but until the main loop
is called nothing has actually been drawn so
the sizes are not available so in order to
get these values before main loop is called which we want so that we can
actually re-size it according to the
buttons we need to use the update method
so we actually before this main loop put
in some code.....to call
it so we've got access to those values and
now we got that we should be able to......
.....
which we defined on line 36 main window padding is 8 we are adding that
as well which we need because that's already in
use so we want pad over to the right area
and adding that to the total size and
we also put....
and we need to add the keypad info to that as well so....
....and if we run that
so we've now got our application working and if we
just minimize this we can see that the minimization is actually
working now so it's actually stopping us
from making it too small and all the
buttons remain on the screen and
obviously you saw the fact that we can still maximize it past its normal size which is
not great and if we stop this run it again
when it first starts of course its too big
so although we haven't talked about much the
other thing we can do it just to finish
off the challenges we can use a max size
we could set it up so that the max size is also not
too big and that can be useful in
situations like this when a calculator
where it doesn't necessarily make sense to
expand it anymore given the size of the
screen so let's just finish off the
challenge doing that so we can do
something similar we can just take a
copy of that line paste it and change min to max
and by doing that that's going to
make the minimum maximum size the same
so that means its going give us
the right size should work for any
version Windows Mac or Linux and it
should actually enable us to have a
minimum and maximum size and for that to
be correct but what we're going to do is
suggest you type in here
...then after this line here
...so what we are trying to do is make the maximum size 50
larger horizontally and also 50 vertically so by doing that
we can actually see the difference so lets just
run that and see what it does and notice how it
automatically start on the right size
and so consequently we can now bring it
back to the smallest size the minimum
size but the maximum size I can't
physically drag it anymore and
that's why I added the 50 their just to make sure that you
had something to be able to make a larger or smaller like so if you decided
that the value that we came up bearing in mined it is calculated to fit
anyway
was correct for the maximum size then we can get rid of that again.....do something like that...
run it again and now we got a screen that we can't change sizes and its already correct for the controls that
we actually placed on there so that's it
and I know that wasn't part of the challenge
but that is something else for you to
look at doing if you want to create
screens of a given size and want to
make sure that it doesn't extend too small or
too large
the two the min size making it to smaller
is something more important is
something that you using more than the
maximum size because often you do want
to expand to a larger size but again in a case
of this challenge I didn't really tell
yo to do that we really only talked about min size
so don't feel you should have done
that other section I just wanted to
make sure it was complete and also show you
the max size as well
one final note is IntelliJ is giving us
a warning mark to the right-hand margin and
if we have look if we didn't actually
use the import Tkinter method with the
try catch then you probably got an additional message
and we just highlighted it we can safely
ignore that because we know that that's
the case we are importing with a capital T
if you recall so that it works with Python 2 as well
so now that we've done this we've got a reasonably good
looking calculator but obviously none of the buttons
actually do anything
so in order to make the buttons work what we
really need to do at this point is link them to
functions so what we gonna do is leave our calculator for now and in the next video we are gonna have
a look at how to write our own functions in Python and ultimately that's
gonna enable you to if you wanted to convert this back to the calculator and actually add
some code to get it to work like a calculator so will see you in the next
video