Alright so in this video, we're going to
make a small change to our code and see
how it handles numbers that a user
enters at the keyboard. I'm also going to
take the opportunity to explain why we
have to initialize separators on line
2. I'm going to start with that in fact.
Let's just remind ourselves what this
program is doing by running it. I'm not
debugging it this time. We've got the output at
the bottom of the screen there, and
basically the separators are printed
out and the code produces a list of the
seven numeric values contained in the
number variable. So that works fine. The
question we're looking at is, why have we
bound separators to an empty string on
line 2? Well let's comment that line
out and see what happens when we run it.
The first thing you'll notice is that
we've got warnings wherever the value of
separators is used in the code. So line
6 over here, is trying to take the
current value of separators and
appending the char to it. The problem is
that Python has no idea what the current
value of separators is, and that's because we
haven't bound separators to any value -
it doesn't exist.  If we hover over that,
we can see name separators can be not
defined. We need to create the separators
variable by attaching it to a value,
and that's what we're doing, effectively, on
line 2. So if I run the program now
with that line still commented out, you
can see we actually get a crash there,
name separators is not defined. So
basically, we need to define our
separators variable, by binding it to a
value before we try to use its value.
So that's really why line 2 is necessary.
So I'd better uncomment that, I'll just
undo that change to fix that, so that our
program doesn't crash anymore.
Alright so let's see how we can handle this code
to get several values from the user.
On line 1, what I'm going to do is change
this to get input from the user, instead
of actually using a string literal that
we're currently doing. So I'm going to
change it to be number equals input
parenthesis double quotes
Please enter a series of numbers using
any separators you like colon and I better
put my spelling head on, separators.
Okay, so if we run the program now,
and for the first example let's go with
1 comma 2 3 semicolon 4 5 6 : 7 8 9 0 1 2
and what I'll also do is take
the opportunity, I'll just go back and
put a space after the first comma as well.
1 comma space 2 3 semicolon 4 5 6
: 7 8 9 0 1 2, also noting here that all
the values I've entered have a
different number of digits.
That's something that our slice
wouldn't have been able to handle. So
when I press ENTER here, we get a list
containing the 4 values 1, 23, 456, 789012
Remember that we're only interested in
the for loop at the moment. Again, don't
worry about understanding lines 10 and
11 at this time. I'm going to finish this
video by making our program a bit more
useful. Instead of just printing the
values, I'll get the program to add them
up and print out the total. Python's
actually got a sum function built-in and
you can find a list of the built-in
functions, the link I'm going to put
into a browser now. The link is also in
the resources section. You can see sum,
which is the one we're going to use, but
again, you can check that at your leisure.
Going back to the code, let's make a few
changes. Firstly, I'm going to comment out
line 8, then I'm gonna come down to line
11. We're going to change this to
calculate the sum. So to do that I'm
going to add sum after the left
parenthesis, with a left parenthesis,
and right at the end I'm going to add
another right parenthesis to make the
line valid. If we run the code now, we've
got a useful calculator for adding up a
series of numbers. So we could do exactly
the same as we did previously; 1 comma
space 2 3 semicolon 4 5 6 colon 7 8 9 0
1 2. We've got a value there 789492,
and run it again. You can use any
separator you want with the numbers,
so let's try another one;
1 comma 2 space 3 semicolon 4 colon
space five space 6 space 7 comma 8 : 9
space 10. Press enter,
and you can see, we get the value now of 55. the
important bit about this code is the
for loop on lines 4 through 6. That
iterates over the input and builds up a
string containing anything that isn't a
numeric character. Because we're
extracting the separators from the
user's input, we don't then have to care
about what separator characters they're
using. This code is already quite robust.
Have a go at entering all sorts of
input and you'll find it's very
difficult to crash the program. It is
possible to crash it by holding down the
control key, for example, but for normal
input, it should cope with anything
you can type. Moving forward in the next
video, we'll look at iterating over
another iterable type - the range. See you
in the next video.