as I mentioned towards the end of the
last video you can also create your own
exceptions their just objects after all
so we can provide more immediate
feedback to the developers using our duck
module so let's go back and have a look
at the add_duck method you
can see that their on line 50 now we
provided a hint that it should be
passing a duck or subclass of duck now
if we extended the duck class to create
a mallard class perhaps then a mallard is
also a duck but we can do better than
this we can check the type of the
argument that's past and show you how to
do that so we're going to type in here
in the add duck method...
...
...if we go
back to our file again and run it this
time we get all seven ducks taking off
and there's no exception
now that's because Percy isn't a dark so
this test on line 51 fails and Percy
doesn't get added to the list and
incidentally make sure you use the
lowercase D in the first duck this part
here on line 51 if you used a capital D
there then you checking the type of the
duck class which is a class so the
type function returns the type
of an object so here we are testing that the
duck that's been passed to our method
really is a duck never do this
now not only is this is not python
it's also wrong
now it's an obvious thing to do and if
you used to programming in java you
probably expected to work but to see why
it doesn't we're going to create a mallard
class that extends duck i'm just going
to put it just after the penguin
class....
...
....if we were really
creating a mallard then you add some of
the properties of a mallard but here we're
just demonstrating that the previous
code fails with sub classes so going back
to the migration .py file we need to
change your definition and will actually
change for percy here and we'll put
Percy equals duck . mallard this time
let's run this and you can see that we
still only get the seven ducks flying
so this type function that we're talking
about now on line 55 returns the exact
type of an object and we check to see if
that type is duck which isn't is mallard
in this case of the one that we set up
for percy here on line 11 now if
you want to do this there are
occasionally times when you need to then
use is instance instead of checking the
type so let me change this duck method
now so instead of type...
...
....first one is the lowercase
version for the variable the second one
is the actual class name and if we do
that now that we've done that if we
go back to our code run it again and what I
should have done is remove this last
part so all we really want to do at this
point is if is instance and then in
parentheses duck , duck now if i try
run that this time you can see
we've actually got all 8 ducks in the
air
the reason for that is this is
is instance function so again if you must
do this type of checking always uses this is
instance or there's also is instance
method if you're dealing with classes
rather than instances of classes and
don't check the type like we did earlier
now keep in mind though it's still not
pythonic though in Python remember we're
not interested in whether percy is a
duck or not
we're only interested in wether percy
can fly if it flies like a duck it's a
duck now checking like this again
is sometimes appropriate if your
function or method requires and int for
example it does make sense to check if
you've got an int or subclass of int and
yes in Python you can subclassing if
you want to it wouldn't be practical to
check all the behavior of an argument to
see if it quacks like an int but when
dealing with the most other objects the
pythonic way is to focus on the behavior
you want not on the type of the object so
what we really want to do is check to
see if the arguments gotta fly method if
it can fly then we can add it to the
flock so there's two steps to this first
what we want to do is check if there's
an attribute called fly the next we
check to see that this is a method and
not a data attribute so let's add the
code for that instead
so again we're doing this code on that
line 55 going to change that line again
so the first line of the add_
duck method we're going to put....
...
....so the get
attributed method checks an objects
dictionary to see if it contains the
attribute we specify fly in this case
now if the attribute wasn't present
would get an error so it works very
like a dictionaries get method by
specifying a default value we get none
returned instead of the error
next we're using this callable
function to check if the fly method is
callable now functions and methods are
callable data attributes aren't now that's
not strictly true because you can't have
a callable data attribute in python but
if we call the fly attribute
then our code will work so this test is
perfectly fine and just to confirm if we
go back and run it again we are getting
all 8 ducks flying
alright so let's change our percy now
back to being a penguin again and to
confirm this time you run it again we
now getting seven ducks taking off
so clearly the fact that we have
change percy back to penguin means that
the code that we've defined here is
correctly figuring out that the penguin
class hasn't got a fly method and
not trying to call it and and
consequently not trying to add it to our
list so now that we've done that this is
the pythonic way to do the test we're
not interested in the type of the duck
argument we are only interested in whether it
can fly or not
now for our purposes if it flies like a duck
then its a duck
now sometimes this will be an
appropriate solution as it is often you
want to notify the caller that
something's going wrong and the Penguins
been excluded from the flock now this is
really a programming error the user of
our module shouldn't be passing
flightless birds to a module that deals
with bird migration so this may be
another place where raising an exception
is actually appropriate let's go ahead
and do that so if we don't add the duck
to the flocks list let's raise an
exception at that point we're going to
do is put an else to the if callable
...
....
....so again what we're
doing here is if we don't add the duck to
the flocks list because we established
that because we established that it hasn't got an
attribute called fly and that it's not
callable then we're going to raise this
typeerror we saw earlier that there are
a lot whole load of exceptions available
so you should try and choose the most
appropriate exception to raise here
they're passing something that can't fly
so a type error is a good choice and is
also shows a valid use of the type
function so we're not going to check what type
something is but to provide
information on the type of object that
caused the problem in Python if you find
yourself using type to check what type
something is then step back and consider
if there's another way to achieve what
you're trying to do so now
I've done that we go back to migration
and run it again you can see we've got
an exception here cannot add duck are you
sure it's not a penguin and probably
got an extra space that I could fix up just to
be clear run again
okay so we are now getting an exception
raised before the migration is started
at the time the flightless penguin is
added to the list now the stack trace
here is useful and shows where the
exception was raised as well as the call
that originated the error now this error
would be picked up straightaway testing
and the programmer can modify the code
to remove the bug so it's really
easy to stick to the Python principle of
if it quacks like a duck while still
making functions and methods type safe
for one of a better expression now
there's another reason you may want to
raise exceptions and that's in order to
test your exception handlers now to see
this working we're going to fix the
code so that Percy does have a fly
method in fact i'm going to give him an
aviat method instead and it'll be
clear why shortly
let's go back and do that we're going to
add another method down here for the
penguin class...
....
now going to explain a bit more about
that but first i'm going to run the
program to make sure that works let's do
that you can see that that's work fine
we've got I won the lottery and bought
a lear jet and haven't got an exception
anymore and going back to our code
looking at the init method here on our
line 35 we created a new data
attribute called fly and we assign it to our
reference to the aviate method and I
mentioned not to include the opening and
closing parenthesis after aviate and
noting that IntelliJ actually tried to
add them for us which would have
prevented this from working properly so
by removing the parentheses we're adding
just a reference to the aviate method that
this code here on line 36 now everything
in python is an object even functions
and methods so you can assign a method
to a variable then call that variable
self.fly in this case just like you
called a method that points to now we
saw that when we created the deal_
_dealer and deal_player
functions and assign them to the command
attribute or our tk buttons all the way back in
the blackjack game in Section 11
alright so back to raising exceptions for
testing we've now got a working program
that contains exception handlers so how
do we test that the exception handlers
are working correctly
well with a program like this we could
do it by passing inappropriate arguments
to the add_duck method and
we've seen that working but sometimes
getting real exceptions isn't that easy
simulating something like
perhaps a disk full exception that
prevents writing data to a file is possible
but very fiddly to set up
you may also want to respond to
exceptions if the network link goes down
while you're downloading data and if you
have a test team then probably they will do
things like switching off the router
while downloading to make sure your
program kept gracefully like situations
like that but before it gets to the test
team you can test your exception
handling by raising your own exception in
the code that's protected by a try block
so going back to our migrate method of
the flock in here let's now raise an
exception inside the for loop i'm coming
down here to the try then the ducks duck
. fly and after here what we want to do is
you want to put raise attribute error
...
....
....if we test this now you can see that
i'm basically getting this exception
its raise after each duck flies and we
can see the one duck down message after
each duck
once all the ducks has been process the
exception is raised and then get the
stack trace that's a useful technique
for testing your exception handlers just
raise an exception that you're handling
in the code inside the try block and
again that's this code here on line 73 now
one final thing before I end this video
if you forget about that test exception
and release your code things aren't going to
go well so what you can do is get
IntelliJ to help make sure you remember
to remove the test code and the way to
do that would be to put a comment on the
line hash...
....adding a comment that contains
the word to do and it's not
case-sensitive causes IntelliJ to track
it as an item that needs to be done
note that the comment from the to do
here appears in a different color depending
on your choice of theme it'll be
probably blue or in my case it's sort of
a yellow so that's the to do but
also what we can do is we can bring up a
tab to see all the to dos in our
projects i'm close down the run window
this is to do down here that down the
bottom left click on that and that
actually shows us all that to do entries
and then clicking on them to be taken to
the relevant bit of code so even though
it's on the screen i can click on there
and it just shows on the screen pretty
cool
alright so that's the end of our
discussion on exceptions in python in
the next video we're going to get back
to databases but we are gonna start making
use of exception handling in our code
see you in the next video