as I mentioned in the end of the
previous video you can't really get that
calculator to do anything until you
understand how to write our own functions
in Python now we've been using
functions throughout the course so
far but now it's time to actually
look at how they work and importantly
how we can create this for ourselves now in
Python functions are created with the
word dev followed by the function name
and a pair of parentheses
because the function introduces block of
code that dev statement must be followed
by a colon and I'm gonna show you just
how this works with an example so lets define a
function called python_food so....
and then we type the code we want in the function so....
and we can call the function here....notice how intelliJ has found it for us and knows
that's a function so we put that code in their and we can
run that now obviously it doesn't do a lot it
just prints spam and eggs as you can see on the screen their but you can see that the keyboard
dev is followed by the function as I mentioned and parenthesis and then also
colon as well and then the actual
method code you want executes is indented so the
statements that make up the body of the
function are indented in the usual way so
as soon as the indent is back to the left
margin then that new code or any new code at
that point is no longer
part of the function definition now the
python_food function as can
see on line 5 is called just like any
other functions that we have used previously in the course and running the
program results in a
Pythonic meal appearing on the screen
as you can see now although it is not obvious here all
Python functions return a result
that's important so if you don't tell the
function what result to return then its gonna
return none and we can see this with a
simple change of the program what we're
going to do is just add a print
surround our function in a print we can
actually see what is returned from that
functions so run that you could see it still
done the output on line 2 its is printed
that out but also its return none and
that's because we haven't defined
the parameter now you wouldn't tell
Python to print the result of the function that
isn't intended to return anything
but that example really demonstrates what happens
when you call when you use a function
call as an argument to another function
so we've use print a lot now in the course
and you probably very used to it so I'm certain you should be using that and
taking on one or more arguments using
parenthesis and then of course that
prints them out but if one of the argument is
a function call then the function is
executed and its result is used as the
argument to print which is what is
happening here in this case you can see
the print is print has outputted the word
none so we've actually called the
python_food function and
this return none and the print after
executing that function has returned the
output that came back to it on the screen
to none now obviously that's a pretty boring
function so let's try make it a little bit more
interesting so if we go back and make some
changes to so I'm just gonna closed the run window and
see if we can actually center the text
.....
......its a
calculation to get an entry that is going
to print in the middle of the screen so
what we gonna do their now is instead of
printing as we did there we are going to delete
that we're going to print a space and
multiply that by the number of spaces
which we have calculated on line 4 so if
margin and we are also going to print text
like and we will just get rid of the print on line 8 and make it so its just calling the
function now that is a bit more useful but now it can only print the same thing o its called but lets just run it first and
see and you can see there now we actually got
it centering and obviously you need to be in a
window with 80 characters across to see it centered correctly but you can see
how it is their is some calculation and is
trying to figure out the center if I move this window a bit
to roughly simulate 80 characters that will be roughly the middle as you can see there
we can actually test that by changing
this and by adding a parameter and instead of
printing the hard coded it on line 3 we
can print the parameter that was passed
to this methods so what we'll do is we'll
create a new method so we are going to leave
the python food method their and create another one I'm going to type....
.....
......
we are now going to call the function that we've
created three times with a different
parameter which is going to be
automatically place in the text variable
and we're using that to figure out how
why to format it all and we should see if we
run this in that window that I saw that I previously that it will be
re-centered on that screen incidentally
just while I remember the Python style is
to have to blank lines before a function
definition and IntelliJ will actually give you
warning if you only leave one so if you
take this back you can see how that's
actually complaining and go back and have a look at the code expected 2 bank lines found one so it
know their should be 2 so if we press enter their we should get rid of that warning and then
we'll be good to go
ok so let's try running this and you
can see their the text is now correctly
centered now in terms of defining the
argument or parameter whichever way you want
to call it could be called anything we
happen to call  text which happened to
coincide with the variable name text on line 3 so we
used the same name but that can
literally be anything you wanted it to be as
long as it's a valid variable name
obviously the text makes sense here
because that's what we're doing is we
are formatting and printing it out some texts so I decided to stick with that now when centered
text is called it needs a single argument
between the parenthesis which you can see
down here on lines 14 through 16 this argument
used to provide the actual value that
the parameter text is set to when the
function runs so the first time
we call it as you saw if we just run again you can see
the first time was spam and eggs and I've centered
that then next we went through did another
call to its spam spam and eggs and then spam
spam spam and spam and it correctly
figured out the width for each one how
wide it needed to be to center it on
the screen and worked each time for us so each
time we are calling it the argument that is being
passed to the method to the function is
changing the different value and its
calculating that and printing it on the screen
and I've use the term parameter an argument
you've heard me both say those in this video
just to be clear parameters refers to the
variables defined in the function
definition that's that is here the definition on line 8 and also the one on line 1
although that hasn't got a parameter their and argument refers
to the actual values used when the
functions is called which is these down here
line 14 through 16 and may have found the two
teams used interchangeably with
parameters now often uses instead of argument technically
speaking it's incorrect but spoken and
for the matter written language is often
littered with grammatical errors and
this is just one more example so long as you are
aware of the correct usage if your asked in a job
interview for example then don't worry
too much about it and know that a lot of
code and a lot of videos that their will
use the two terms interchangeably but
again technically to be correct
parameter is the definition it's the
variables defined in the function
definition itself as you can see on line 8
so we refer to text their
as a parameter then the arguments are the
actual values used when the function is
called on line 14 through 16 so its good to know both of them
but you can certainly use both terms
interchangeably
now the functions that we've created so far are really
quite simple but they do demonstrate the
basics of defining a function in Python so center_text also introduced
the idea of function parameters and how
they used but there's a lot more to
functions the basic concept is that you
write a block of code once you call it
whenever you need to perform these
actions in your program that's the
reason that you're creating functions and
this obviously saves a lot of typing but
more importantly it makes the actual
code you create much easy to maintain so if
you find yourself writing the same lines of
code repeatedly in a program that's a
good indication that could you should
really consider putting that code in
a function now functions can often
return results we mentioned that
earlier in this video the face that all Python functions do
return results and Python will ensure they
return none if you don't specify another value
before we look at how to do that we
should really fix an error in center text
so anyone used to printing text in Python would
probably expect center_text to
behave
similar to print but if we try and use
it to center a number we actually get an error
so in other words if we come back here type....and we run it
we actually get an error so the first two
lines print fine as you can see their spam
and eggs and spam spam and eggs but when
the code processing got to line 16
where we used a number as a argument we get an error
on the screen as you can see object
of type int has no len now the good
thing here is that Python makes life easy
but not forcing us to worry about
variable types most of the time but there
are times when we need to be aware of
the type of the variable we are using now here
when we get the length in characters and
you can see that's the code on line 9
using len and texts which is the
variable in the parameter the argument
we're assuming that its character length is actually
meaningful but the thing to remember
here is the numbers don't have a character length though so  if that sounds odd consider
that the string spam consist of 4 characters but we cannot really say that the
number 12 consists of two characters
remember that in a computer 12 is stored
....so basically in computer
terms 12 would be stored as the
binary number 1100 this is what would
happen internally or in 16 bit notiation
it would be 0000 1100 you didn't really
need to know this I'm just trying to point out how they are stored
differently so that's how a number would
be stored but in hexadecimal it will be
stored as a C so looking at it in those
terms when we are not storing and using texts
such what would really be meant by the
length if we're trying to get the length
of the number doesn't really make sense as can see so we've used the print
function to display numeric variables
and what happens when we do that is that
Python automatically calls one of two
functions to produces a string
representation of that variable
the two functions are STR and REPR and
if string is defined for an
object then the print function will use
that otherwise it is going to use this sa REPR
so what we're going to do is we are going to look at these two functions in more detail when we create
our own objects later in the course but for
now we can actually make a little bit of
a change to make sure that this works
so lets just delete what I added their about binary numbers and
go back to our method now what I want to do is
make a change
here on line 9 so I want to type in.......and by doing that we should not need to
change anything else and we should find the
code now works you can see how its
now work and what's basically happened is
that by adding that code to line 9
we are explicitly calling STR the STR function to
convert the argument that was passed to
a string and we're doing that before we
attempt to get its length so consequently
in the first two cases its already strings
so nothing else has done it still a string
but in the third case where we passed the
parameters as an integer of the value 12 that
gets converted to a string first time on line 9 so consequently on line 10 the len
function is called is now a string that is
the argument that sent to the len function
and that's why it works so we got now a
really useful function that can be used
whenever we wanted to print text centered
on the screen
this is a assuming and 80 character screen of course but it doesn't really act
as a for replacement for the built in
print function if you remember from
section 10 print can be used to write data to a file which is something center_text
function clearly can't do
it at the moment because it's a useful way to
introduce optional and default parameters what we're
going to do now is modify the function
so that it could be used
really pretty much as a direct
replacement for the print function and
we also have a look at another approach
to the same problem now you already seen how
can look at the Python source from IntelliJ by using to control click if your in a
Linux machine or a Windows machine and on a
Mac you can do the same by holding down command
and clicking it
so what we are gonna do is we're gonna have a look at
the definition of print so I'm holding down
command and click print so as you can see that's the
definition for print so the first thing
to note is that you can actually view the
real source of the built-in functions
the modules builtins.py
stubs file and that what that means is that it
only contains descriptions of the
functions without any actual
implementation so it's used by
IntelliJ to provide the tool tips when you
were typing print for example showing
you what arguments but the actual
implementation of the
functions is actually written in C
although we can't see all the source code
for the print function as such we can
see its definition
in a doc string describing the parameters
so you know its really still useful
as you can see on the screen there now a .doc string just to be clear is a way of documenting your functions
and we are going to be looking at them a little
bit later but here everything between the
two sets of triple quotes as you can see
from the line 477 through 486 is the doc
string print so you can see the first
parameter looking at line 476 first
parameters is called args and the fact that it's a plural rather
than arg gives an indication of what the
asterix means so if our parameter is prefixed with a stab then
Asterix and it represents a variable
number of arguments and what that really means is
you can pass as many as you want
separated by commas now seeing tha down a couple times in the course
but we haven't really explained in detail so
here is an example what we mean so I'm going to
close it down for now so type in.....then this prints the
5 arguments so if we run that first second 3 4 spam so it prints the five
arguments on the same line automatically
separating them with a space so what
we could do is provide the
same functionality to our center
text function quite easily and will start
doing that in the next video