ok so as well as adding extra behavior
to our subclasses we can also change
the behavior of methods that exists in
the superclass so to see how to do that
we need to create a new vampire enemy
but i think that makes for a good
challenge
ok so the challenge for you is to create
that new vampire class that's a subclass
of enemy now vampires have three lives
and take 12 hit points of damage you can
create a new python file for the
vampire if you like but I've actually
suggest adding it to the existing enemy
.py file
you want to test your class by creating
one or two vampire instances and
displaying their details also inflict
some damage to make sure that the
take_damaged method is working ok
and also make sure that the trolls can
also take damage because we haven't
tested that so far
alright so that's a challenge see how
you go with it pause the video and I'll
see you when you get back
ok so let's go through my solution so
what I'm going to do is add the vampire
class to the enemy.py
so....
...
now we're going to be coming back
to add more features to our class that
vampire class but for now that's all we
need for the challenge
let's test this I'm going to go
back to the main .py file the
first thing we need to do is import the
vampire class into this file so I'm
going to add a comma at the end...
again the warning because it's
unused at the moment unused import
statement going to delete the monster
references out but let's actually add a
vampire....
...
....so that's
clearly working ok ok now because our
trolls and vampires all inherit from
enemy they have all the methods that the
enemy class defines so we can inflict
damage on both trolls and vampires by
calling the take_damaged method so
let's go add some damage to the
second troll...
...
...so let's just confirm this
will run it scrolling up we can see I
took 18 points of damage have five left
the message that was for ugh and ugh
has now no more live one-hit points5 and
scrolling down that took 5 points
damages got seven left and you can see
the confirmation of that live 3.7 but we
should really test the other path
through the take damage
let's give ugh a hefty thrak with the
sword glandarin and inflict 30
points of damage and go back and do that
will separate this will do...
...
...i'm going to
switch this to floating mode so that it
doesn't affect the subtitles at the
bottom of the screen then click on that
that's going to put the run window up a
little bit higher still be down a little
bit more as well but you can also
hide it when running it actually
going to close it for now and run again we
can see that ugh is now live 0 hit points5 so
I'm still got a problem with hit points
but you can see that ugh has lost a life
here and we haven't got the message that
appears when he's got zero or more hit
points left so clearly this is something
we need to fix close that down for now
and go back to enemy.py
really when a monsters got no lives
left there dead at the moment you saw
that we can keep fighting ugh
had written a attack method it fought back
that's not good but what is good is that
we don't have to make changes to all
our monsters
okay we only got 2 at the moment but you
could create 8 or 90 monsters in
the game
adding code to each class to track when the
monsters dead would be a lot of work
with that many enemies we also have to
test the code for each monster to make
sure we hadn't introduced to bug but
getting back to our enemy class because
all our monsters all subclasses the
enemy class we can just add the
necessary code to the enemy superclass
and will be then automatically available
in all subclasses so let's go ahead and
make a change to start tracking when
they reach their hit points where there
should be dead and to do that want to
start on here on line 8 by adding
another attribute is going to be...
....and what we
want to do is have a look at this code
in the take damage method and it's under
this else where the life's self.lives
is minus equal to 1 we need a
test their the test is going to be...
....
ok confirming that we've got a new
attribute called alive that's
initialized to true init method on line 8
we then change the take_
damage method so after losing a
life we check to see if the life's left
is still greater than 0 if the monster
still has lives left
we print a message saying they lost a
life you can see that here on line 18
and otherwise we set self.alive to
false line 21
that's because they're no longer alive
because they reached 0 lives left
let's confirm that this works
so we're going to come down here and add
some code let's add some code via a
while loop that tests while the vampire is
alive so...
...
...basically going to keep
taking one point of damage until all his
life is overt in which case at that
point the alive attribute will change
from true to false the whille will exit
and then the program should exit as well
let's just run this to see if it works
you can see there that we've got
vlad take some damage there we got down
to zero points left lost a life
notice also hear he's lost another life
and another life because hit points
didn't get reset that's something we'll
need to look at to reset the hit points
back to a value when he has lost a life
but he's still alive but you can see the
principle of continuing taking damage
until he has died works the loop exit
and once you got to 0 lives blood was
dead
and the program exited and also up here
ugh was dead as well at that point and
again you could argue that we should be
putting the hit points back to their
original values when the monster
losses a life
that's up to as the designer of the class
and if makes more sense for the
monsters to behave like that then of
course you're the Creator you can do
that
alright so i'm going to stop the video
here now we've seen how to give a
subclass additional behavior when we
added the grunt method to the troll
class in the next video we're going to
look at how to override methods of the
superclass to change the way that a
subclass behaves and what I'll do is I'll
just run it one more time I'm just gonna
take this out of floating mode putting
that back their on the screen
okay i'll see you in the next video