Deleting the items from the end of the list
needs a bit more thought.
If there are billions of items, we don't to
work through the entire list to find the first
value to be deleted.
Instead, we can process the list from the end.
So let's have a go at doing that.
On line 18 I'm going to type a comment; we're going to process the high values in the list.
We're going to type start is equal to zero.
On line 19, we're initializing start to zero.
Next, we need a for loop.
And we want to work backwards,
which means that we'll start at the index position 1 less
than the length of the list.
So I'm going to type for index in range
parenthesis len parenthesis data right parenthesis
minus 1 comma.
Now we can't use 0 as the stop value.
We discussed that in the videos on indexing.
Remember that the last value in a range or slice isn't included.
If we use 0, the first item in the list won't
be included.
And that's why we're using -1 as the stop value.
I'm going to go ahead and put -1 there.
And finally, to work backwards, we use a step of -1, so I'm going to do that.
right parenthesis and a colon.
When you're creating ranges like this, I suggest
you print out the values that your range produces.
When you're starting out with all this, it
can be very confusing.
Heck, when you've been doing it for years,
it can still be confusing.
So let's make sure we're getting the index
numbers we want.
So there are 16 items left in our list, so
we want to get the values from 15 to 0.
So what I'll do is I'll print out index to confirm
that our range is correct.
I said 16 there because the earlier code
has deleted the first two items.
Our list started off with 18 items,  but by the
time we get to this code that we're writing, it'll contain only 16 items.
Let me go ahead and print(index)
Then we'll run this
You can see that's working, we've got 0 to 15 being output.
Alright, so we're going to be iterating backwards through the list, from 15 to 0.
If we find a value that's within the valid
range - so a value that's less than or equal
to 200 - we can break out of the loop.
So let's look at doing that.
I'll delete the printout, and change the code to be
if data left square brackets, index within those brackets,
that's less than or equal to max underscore valid
then a colon, then on the next line, start is equal to index, and then we're going to break.
This gives us a start value that's equal to
the position of the last item that we want
to keep.
So with our data,
that should be 13.
The last value we want is 191, and that's at index position
13.
So we'll print out start to confirm
it's what we expect.
So print start, in parentheses, and a comment there for debugging.
We'll run this, to confirm that we get 13.
We got 13, so that's working fine.
Next, we want to delete the slice that includes the values at the end of the list.
Let's go ahead and write the code for that.
del data left square bracket, start colon within the square brackets.
Let's print data after that, as well.
So our slice on line 26 includes everything
from the start value to the end of the list.
So we're going to delete everything from position 13 to the end.
Now that, by the way, will include the value 191, which isn't what we want.
For our data, we want to start deleting at
position 14, not from 13.
So what we we need to do is add one to the start value.
And we can do that on line 26.
Come up here and type start plus one.
That'll work - our slice will now start at
position 14.
Now we can do the same thing by changing line
22 instead.
So I'm going to undo the change I've just made.
So let's put the change, or modify, line 22, to be start = index + 1
Now that does the same thing, but the code's a bit cleaner.
As far as the computer's concerned, there's no difference.
We'll still be removing all the items from
position 14. However, the code's safer for humans
to work with.
The purpose of our for loop is to identify
the first item to delete.
It sets start to the position to start deleting from, rather than from the position of the last
item we want to keep, so that just makes more sense.
This is the sort of thing that comes with
experience.
Both versions would work fine, but it's cleaner
to have the correct start position when the
loop terminates.
Having to alter start, after the loop, is
a bit clumsy and it is something that's easy
to forget.
But don't worry too much about that.
When you're starting, you'll be pleased to just get code that works.
You'll understand
why this version's slightly easier to work
with, when we've looked at writing our own functions.
What I probably should do,
is add a comment to explain why we're adding 1 to the value.
Let's go ahead and do that, we'll do it right under the if statement, on line 21.
So basically we have the index of the last item to keep
So we want to set start to the position of
the first item to delete, which is one after
index.
Let's just type that.
and that's one after index.
I'm putting the variable names in single quotes there, in the comments.
Alright, so now that I've done that, let's see if it works. I'm going to run the program
And you can see that the list no longer contains the first two
values, and the last two values have also been stripped out.
So that seems to be working fine
- at least it's working fine with this particular
set of data.
In the next video, we'll look at testing it
more thoroughly.
See you in the next video.