Alright, so moving on now with the
completion of the challenge introduced
in the last video, it's now time to time
the functions. So to start off doing that
we need to firstly import the timeit
module. Let's go ahead and do that -
it should be on line 1, above the text
definition. So it's going to be import
timeit. Now as I said in
the previous video, I'm going to do it
slightly differently. So the challenge
was to time the code, and if you've added
code, something
along the lines of this; so
something like print parentheses timeit
dot timeit parentheses comp
underscore caps parentheses double quote
comma. Then do something like setup
equals, double quotes again, from
map underscore intro import comp underscore
caps, then number equals 10,000,
or actually make it 100,000. So if you did
something like that, or put the functions
inside the strings, then that's fine. You don't
need to watch me do something that we've
already covered, and we've looked at the
various ways that you can provide the
correct environment to timeit. However,
there is another method we can use,
and you have to read the documentation very
carefully to work it out. So let's have a
look at the documentation and you'll see
what I mean. So we'll just bring it up in
a browser. The bit I'm interested in is down
here, under 28.2.2,
Python Interface. Now in the
description of timeit, it says that this
method will create a timer instance with
the given argument, setup code and timer
function, and run its timeit parenthesis
method. Now these three functions are
convenience functions, to save us from
having to type, or create rather,
instances of the timeit class. That's
the three there that you can see, one two
three. Now as you can see, the
documentation is quite sparse. If you
want to know more, we should look at
that timer class which you can see down here,
immediately below those functions.
And there you'll find a more detailed
description of what the convenience
functions are doing for us and
it's worth reading the timer class
documentation carefully. Now if we scroll
down and have a look, the last paragraph for
the class itself, just before the
description of the timeit method down
here, is interesting because it says
that the statement and setup parameters can
also take objects that are callable
without arguments. Objects that are
callable, basically, mean functions. There
are other callable objects in Python,
classes for example, and they're called
to create a class instance. Alright so
what that sentence means is that we can
pass a reference to a function
as the statement to be timed. The function
must not have any parameters,
which becomes obvious when you see the code,
because there's no way to include
arguments in a function reference. Now
that'll make more sense when you've seen
the code. So what I'm going to do is go back to
IntelliJ. Now we'll just run this to make
sure that it would have worked. You
can see we did get a timing result there, so
that's working. But for now what I'll do
is, I'll comment that out. We're going to
replace it by adding the code
to timeout for functions. So I'll start off
with print, then it's going to be
parentheses timeit dot timeit. Then we're
going to do comp underscore caps comma
space number equals 100,000 and then the
two closing parentheses. I'm going to
take a copy of that line, and we'll actually
call the other functions as well. So I've
got comp underscore caps. The second one
will be map underscore caps, the third
one is comp underscore words and the
last one will be map underscore words. So
you can see that's a lot simpler. There's
no setup argument needed for one thing,
when you pass a function reference to
timeit. In fact it looks suspiciously
easy. So the real question here is,
does it work? Let's run the program,
and then you can see the timings there for our
four functions, so clearly it's working.
Now before we go into detail and look at
those times, let's review what we did
here. So we wrapped each of our code
blocks up in a function definition. You
either have to do that,
or turn them into a string in order to
time them. Next we passed a reference to
each of the functions, to the timeit dot timeit
function. Note that again, we're not
using parentheses. We're passing a
reference to the function, not a function
call. Now if you try to call the function,
you'll get an error. So if we replace
the first reference there - the comp underscore
caps - and add parentheses, try and
run that, you'll get an error. And that's
because when the documentation refers
to a callable, it means the function itself
not the result of calling the function.
There are other ways to use timeit
and now you know how it works, try Googling
for other examples. We'll come back to
this later when we've looked at
decorators. For now, I'm going to remove
the bogus parentheses and run the
program again, so that we can review
those timings in the bottom left hand
corner of the screen. There's not a great
deal of difference, but after running the
program a few times, you can see that
after running the program a few times,
as I'm doing now, there's not really a great
deal of difference but the
comprehensions appear to be slightly
faster than using a map. Now it's
interesting because when I actually ran
this on my iMac Pro, which has got many
cores, the first time that function - the
map underscore, the map underscore
caps function - appeared to be faster. But
as you can see here on this Mac, and most
probably on most computers that you run
this, you should find that comprehensions
version is slightly faster. So in other
words, the comp_caps
function and the comp underscore
words function should generally
be faster for you, and you can see that's
the case, in the code that I'm executing
here because I'm on a different Mac
computer now. So I'll run that again. You
can see, we're consistently finding that the
comprehensions version is slightly
faster than the map version. The timing
for the comprehension is the first value
in each pair, and the value for
com underscore caps and map underscore
caps, the first pair of timings was
pretty inconclusive, when we tried to run
it on a 16 gigabyte Linux system.
Capitalizing the words is more
consistent, though, with the comprehension
working out slightly faster, but you can
see in my case here though, in both
scenarios I've run this a number of
times, even though the results are close,
on every single occasion we're finding the
comprehension
version is beating out the map version.
In other words, it's faster.  If you come
across map being used in code that you
have to work with, you now know what
it's doing. When running your own code,
there's little reason to use a map,
though, instead of a comprehension. So
I'm going to stop the video here, and in
the next one we'll start looking at the
filter function. So I'll see you in the
next video.