alright so we finished up in the
previous video talking about how the
intellij refactoring didn't quite
work when it came to some of these
replacement fields and it would be quite
a bit of work to do this manually to
make these changes point here was that
just wanted to draw your attention to a
possible pitfall with refactoring data
attributes but also in this video
we're going to show you a quick way of
dealing with them all the important
thing here is that you can get problems
if you use this form of replacement
fields and then try to refactor the
attributes later okay so we've used
regular expressions in IntelliJ once
before and their incredibly
powerful and we'll be looking at them
at using them in python code later
in the course for now just follow along
and will sort out these incorrect
attribute names
we're going to get intellij
to do a search and replace and we can do that
by pressing command on a Mac which I'm
going to do or control r on a pc and if
you need to it's the Edit menu find and
replace find replace what i'm going to do
an alt r this little window pops up
they want to make sure that this reg ex
is actually ticked regular
expressions box in the top field we want
to type left parenthesis we want to put
a...
...
...and you can see
as soon as I finish the first one it
actually came up and matched a
particular field there for us so we want
to replace that we just need to type...
so both the curly
brace and the full stop in that first
field are typed in have special meaning
in regular expressions and
that's why we having to use the
backslash to escape them the backslash d
matches any digit and again you can see
that the occurrences are now showing up
now that I've actually into that in this
class obviously i needed to be an enemy
.py before I started this and for the
replacement in the second field and we
just need to put the dollar sign one_
...
now here that dollar sign means or
specifies anything that was matched
inside the parentheses in the search box
so when all set and done what we're doing
is just adding an _ after the
full stop
then click on replace all and that takes
care of all the replacement fields if
you happen to have made a mistake there
you can do a control z on a pc
commands z on a mac or come up to
and then undo and then try again so
you can't really go wrong it will just
undo those last changes for you
so now that I've done that I can close
down this window
go back to main and should now run for
us you can see it's now running again
properly so it wasn't the end of the
world but it can be a bit scary when
you factor things with IntelliJ and
your code suddenly breaks as this is a
common reason for refactoring data
attributes in your classes and that's
this form of the replacement field is so
useful i thought i'd show you what can
but what can actually go wrong and
possibly save you some grief in the future
if that happens to you
of course if would use the _ to
start with we wouldn't have had a problem
at all
now we can still change the values and
our program still does because this is
python and nothing is truly private but
there's now an indication that we should
really be changing those attributes
directly
let's move over now to a challenge
so to help consolidate your
understanding of inheritance got a
challenge for you to try out so the
challenge is to try and create a vampire King
subclass of vampire now a vampire king
is going to be incredibly powerful and
any points of damage inflicted will be
divided by four vampire King objects
will also start off with 140 hit points
so extend the vampire class to create a
new vampire King class with those
additional properties then you want to
test the new class by creating a new
vampire King object and checking that it
does start with a hundred and
forty hit points and only takes a
quarter of any damage inflicted alright
so pause the video here and try that out
and i'll see you when you get back
ok so how did you come up with that one
let's go through now and come up with a
solution for this we're going to start
by creating the new class i'm
going to create that just below the
vampire class is going to be class...
....
...
...now this constructor will
...create a new object that is exactly the same as a
an ordinary vampire so we do need to set
the hit point value after calling
this init method on line 60 let's go
ahead and do that so it's gonna be self
....
...so that's our
constructor done we're going to test
that in a moment but notice the single
parameter we use when calling the
super init method on line 60 now our
vampire class is a subclass of enemy and
vampire king is a subclass of vampire so
the method that will be called when we use
super init here is actually the
vampire class init method and not the
enemy init method now the init method in
the vampire class will then call init
in the enemy class so the calls will pass
up the chain with each sub class
calling the init method of its
superclass ok so next we need to
override the take damage method
so that the damage is divided by
four so let's create the damage
methods so def....
...
...so we are now dividing
the damaged by 4 when we call that
super method and used integer
division here because we don't
want to be subtracting fractional values
from the hit points so if we try to
inflict nine points of damage our vampire
king will only take two points that's
because integer division
actually rounds down
alright so what about the ability to
dodge well its important to understand
exactly which class is the superclass
here now vampire King extends vampire so
the super method we are calling is the
vampire method and not the enemy method
so what happens is that the vampire King
take_damage method calls the
method in its superclass which is vampire
the vampire class take_damage
method then calls its superclass
method so it calls the enemy take_damage
method now intelliJ has a
really useful feature to help understand
all of this back in the vampire King
class i can hold down ctrl or command
depending on your operating system and
click on the word take damage in the
super . take damage method down here
and actually click on that now notice
that the cursor has taken me to the
take_damage method from the
vampire class if i do that again now
coming over here to the take damage
that's now in the vampire class click on
it's now moved up the cursor to the
take_damage method which is
now in the enemy class again ctrl or
command is the key you click along with
the actual method to get that to
work on your operating system so
basically you can follow the trail back
which is great for checking exactly what
those overwritten methods are doing
alright so that's it let's now see if it
works and go back to our main py file
and we're going to comment out the code
in the main program
do that completely and leave it down the bottom
instead code at the top here and what
we're going to do is create a new
vampire King class called Dracula
Dracula...
thing we need to do because the moment
you can see the vampire is there we haven't
imported this class new class we need to
import vampire King like so and come back
here and specify that's the vampire King
class and we're going to call him
Dracula....so lets write it out to print him first to
make sure that the initial values are
said and he has got 240 points right then
Dracula starters take damage...
that damage will be divided by 4
so we should only get three points of
damage....
and see that it works so you can
see that in this case you got started of
with 140 points of damage but he actually
dodge successfully and therefore didn't
lose any hit points because I'm
remembering this only a one chance in
three the dodgers and avoids all the
damage in this case he did Dodge
so i need to run this again this time he
has managed to take three points of
damage 12/4 is 3 so he's left we still
with three lives and 137 hitpoints
alright so that's the challenge
completed now your solution may well be
different to mine and is always that's
fine
the important thing is that it works not
that it looks exactly the same as have
done here it's often said that if you
ask 10 programmers to solve a problem
you'll get in 11 different solutions
so there's very very rarely only one way
to write code so the main thing is if
your code solution works then
congratulations
alright so hopefully that's now
consolidated your understanding of
subclassing and how classes can inherit
from the superclass and in turn how they
can also be the superclass of another
class that extends them further
inheritance can be a very useful feature
but maybe because it's so often taught
right at the start of course is an
object-oriented programming many
programmers feel they have to use
inheritance they go out of their way to
look for ways that they can sub
class something to produce
something else they need and that's
often not a helpful approach especially
in a language like Python in python if
there's a need to use inheritance then it really
should jump out at you you you wouldn't
really have to go looking for it now all
our enemies were enemies they really did
share common traits and we intended to
use the more all of them in a similar way as
things to bash in vent our frustration
so the inheritance relationship
we created in the last few videos were
probably a good way to create the troll
the vampire the vampire King classes now
python relies heavily on an
object-oriented feature called
polymorphism i'm going to have a look at
that in the next video and find out what
people mean when they say if it quacks
like a duck
so see you in the next video