One of the other functions that Guido van
Rossum wanted to remove from the
standard library, is filter. So in this
video, we're going to have a look at what
it does and how a comprehension can be
used to achieve the same result. Now what
we'll do is, we'll start with an example
from an earlier video, this
time filtering out meals that contain spam. So
I'm going to paste in this code that we
used in the earlier video now, and I'll
create a new python file. So I'm going
to call the file, selecting Python file
there, it's going to be filtertest. Now
I'm going to paste in the sample
code into there. Now as you can see, this uses
a for loop and a list of comprehension
to extract only those meals that don't
contain spam. Let's just run this and
make sure that it does work. So you can
see there that it has successfully only
extracted the meals that don't contain
spam. Now the filter function can be used
to do the same thing. I used the word
filter in that earlier video, and again
a minute ago, so it's no surprise that the
filter function does the same thing.
It's a bit more complicated though, because we
need to create a function that only
returns true if an item is what we want.
So let's go ahead and do that. I'm going
to start on line now 25 here; def not
underscore spam then parenthesis meal
underscore list column list right
parenthesis and then a colon. Then we
want to return and in double quotes spam
not in meal underscore list. Okay and
then on line 29 I'm going to type
spamless meals is equal to list
parenthesis filter parenthesis not
underscore spam comma menu, then the two
right closing parentheses and then
let's print out that output. So print
parentheses spamless underscore meals.
Okay. So you can see there, that our not
underscore spam function is very simple,
and they often are when using filter. It
returns true if there's no spam in the
meal and false if there is. Just like map,
filter takes two arguments; the function
that does the filtering and an interable
to iterate over. So I'm going to run the
program, and we'll just confirm that the
list produced by our filter function is
identical to the comprehension. And
you can see there that we've got the same
output. You may not have agreed that map
was particularly harder to read than the
corresponding comprehension, but there's
no doubt that the filter code is more
difficult. Calling the function not
underscore spam helps a lot, because you
can take a reasonable guess as to what
it does without reading its code but
even so, the comprehension on line 19
is easier to read. I've tried to make the
filter code easier to understand,
by calling the list spamless underscore
meals on line 29. Using informative
variable names like that is a great
technique for making code readable.
Anyone reading this code doesn't even
have to bother checking what the filter
function is doing. It's obviously
intended to return a list of meals that
don't contain spam. Or is it obvious? To a
native English speaker, the made-up word,
spamless, does imply that the meals won't
contain spam, but as programmers, we're
part of an international community. To a
non-native English speaker, spamless
probably means very little. A sensible
choice of variable names can only
accomplish so much. You can't rely
on that alone to make your code readable.
Alright so let's time the functions now.
So I'll start by adding the timeit
module as the first line, so import timeit.
Next we want to wrap the two pieces
of code in function definitions and
return the values instead of printing
them, so let's go ahead and do that.
And then come down here to line 20, and actually,
I'll make that line 21, and we're going
to type def spamless comp parenthesis
colon.
Then these two lines, I'm going to tab
over to indent them because they're
part of the function. Then the print, instead
of printing out the output, we're in fact,
going to just return it so return
meals. I'll add another line there, to
keep Python happy. Then we've got our not
spam definition there, which we can
leave in, but down here we want to change
this line here, so I'm gonna go down to
line, start on line 33, def spamless
underscore filter parentheses colon,
then we'll indent these two lines of code
again, but then we'll return spamless
underscore meals instead of printing it
out.
That leaves us on line 36. So as always,
I'm going to call the functions
before timing them, to make sure I'm timing
a code that works, and then we'll add the
code to do the timing. So we go
down to line 38 there, and we'll type if
underscore underscore name underscore
equals single quote underscore underscore
main underscore underscore - we've done
this countless times now - colon.
So we'll print out the values, as I said,
so the values from the function calls.
The spamless underscore comp, we'll
call that first and print out the
value, then print parenthesis and do the
same for our filter, spamless
underscore filter, and then we'll add the
code to do the timing. I needed the two
equal signs there, on line 38, to fix that
error. Alright then we want to do print
parentheses timeit dot timeit.
That's gonna be parentheses spamless
comp, but no parentheses, comma
and number equals 100,000. Then on the next line,
print timeit dot timeit. That's going to be
spamless underscore filter
comma number equals 100,000. Okay. Alright
and let's run it and see what we get.
Alright, so you may have found the numbers
surprising there, the result surprising.
You can see that there's a huge
difference between the two approaches.
With the filter function, as you can see,
they're taking roughly twice as long as
a comprehension. The main reason for that
is the additional overhead of the
function call, but let's just run it
a few more times.
And we can confirm there that
it's fairly consistently the comprehension
is pretty well, half the speed
of the filter, as you can see there.
But again as I mentioned, the main reason
for this is the added overhead of the
function call, and we can check that by
changing the comprehension to use the
same function as filter's using. That's
something you may need to do, by the way,
if the filter function is quite complex.
Let's go back up to our spamless underscore
comp method and we'll change that.
So at the moment, you can see it's got meal
for meal in menu if "spam" not in meal so
let's actually just duplicate that line
and comment the first one out, and we'll
change this instead to be meal for meal
in menu if, then we'll get rid of the
if condition there, and we'll change that
to not underscore spam then parentheses
meal. So in other words we're using
that function now instead. And again this
is something you may need to do if the
filter function is quite complex. So
we run this again now, and you can see
now, that the timings are now a lot
closer. The comprehension was a little bit
faster there and I'll just run it
again, and you can see, in fact in
that case, we got the reverse true - the
filter was actually slightly faster. This
time you can see that the comprehension
is faster, filter's faster, comprehension's
faster, so it's very very close as you
can see. Basically, calling the not
underscore spam function for each item
in the list has slowed it down, just as
it does when using filter. Okay, so
I think it's pretty clear that we
should favor comprehensions over the filter
function, so I'm going to stop the video
here now. In the next one, we're going
to take a look at the reduce function. So I'll
see you in the next video.