Alright, so let's talk more about testing this
program we've written. To test if our
code works when only removing items
from the start of the list, what I'm
going to do is copy lines one to two,
comment that out, then delete manually,
the two outlying values from the end.
So I'm gonna come down and delete these
two entries here. Run the program, and we
can see that that's also working.
The next test is when there are only outlying values at the end of the list. So once
again, I'm going to comment the list out,
paste in the list I copied originally,
and delete the entries at the start - the
first two, four and five. Run the program,
and you can see that that works as well.
Alright, so moving on. The next test is when
there are no outlying values at all.
Same drill, I'm going to comment out those lines,
paste in the original. Now I'm
going to remove the outlying values from
the end, as well as the start. Run the
program again. There wasn't anything for
the program to do and the list's
unchanged, so that test also passes.
Alright, for the next test, what I'm going
to do is paste in a list that doesn't
have any values in the range we want, and
obviously I need to comment out lines 7 and 8,  like so.
Run the program, and we end
up with an empty list, which is correct.
I'll digress briefly here. I said that an
empty list is correct, but that's only as
far as our code's concerned. If we're
performing a statistical analysis and
removed all, or most of the values from
your data, then something's obviously not
right. Outlying values are ones that
deviate from the norm by an unacceptable amount.
If most of your data is
classed as outlying, then you haven't
identified outlying values correctly. Any
statisticians watching this video,
will know that you should do something like
calculate the standard deviation.
We'd then use some multiple of that in our
conditions, down here, on lines 18,
as well as line 29.
We'd subtract the multiple from the mean
to get the minimum value, and add it to
the mean to get the maximum. So just to
be clear, this program isn't identifying
the values to remove. We're focusing on
removing things from a list. The exact
values to use in those two conditions,
should be calculated from the data set -
and I'm talking about the code on line 29, as
well as the code on line 18. Even then
though, you should only remove outlying
values after investigating the cause.
In our imaginary scenario, we have
identified two machines that were broken
and giving incorrect data. So scrolling
back up to here, if we're measuring
the maximum speed of a new racing car,
for example, then clearly there's
something wrong with our equipment. All
the values in that last set of data
are significantly higher than the current
land speed record. Alright, so moving on,
the final test now, is an empty list.
So let's comment that out, and what we
want to do is simply type data equals
left and square brackets, giving us an
empty list. What we're testing here is
that our code doesn't crash when we give
it an empty data set. So if we run the
program, and we get an empty list. So
that's correct and the program didn't
crash. If we pass an empty list into our
code, we're getting an empty list back
out. Alright, so in the next video, we'll
continue looking at some other things
that you can do with lists.
We'll remove items with a list that isn't ordered. See
you in the next video.