So now that we've seen Map and Filter,
it should hopefully be easier to understand
how Reduce works. I covered those two
functions first because Reduce takes the
same arguments and we now understand
what they are. What reduce does though,
is a bit harder to understand. It takes a
function and a sequence, then reduces the
sequence to a single value by repeatedly
calling the function. The documentation
is a really good example of
documentation that's only useful
after you already understand it. So we're going
to just check that out briefly now. So
the first thing to note there, in that
link, is that Guido didn't remove it
from Python, obviously, but he did get it
removed to the functools module.
You can see there, functools, and if we scroll
down we can see here the functools
dot reduce function. So he managed
to get it moved into the functools module.
So basically, Reduce is no longer
a built-in function in Python 3. You have
to import functools if you want to
use it. Alright, so let's have a look at an
example. We're going to start with the
example in the documentation because
it's quite simple. It uses a Lambda which
we haven't covered yet, so I'm going to
rewrite it using an ordinary
function. I'll go back to IntelliJ, create a new
file. This time, this new Python file,
we'll call this reduceintro.py. Now let's
add the code, so we'll start by
typing import timeit and import func
tools, and our first function on line 5,
def calc underscore values
parenthesis x comma space y colon int,
then the closing right parenthesis and a
colon. Then the value we want to return
is x plus y. Okay and then on line 9 I'm
going to type numbers equals left square
bracket 2, 3, 5, 8, 13 and then on line 11,
reduced underscore value equals and
we're going to call our Reduce function.
So it's going to be func
tools dot reduce parentheses it's going to be
calc underscore values comma space numbers
and let's print that value out, print reduce
underscore value. That should be calc
underscore values, being the name of the
function. Alright, run the program
now we see that we've got the sum
of all the numbers in the list, which is 31;
2 plus 3 is 5, 5 is 10, 8 is 18 plus 13
is 31, being the list on line 9. So we've
got the sum of that list which is 31.
Now I'll go through exactly what it's
doing at the moment. Before that though,
I want to refer back to
Guido's comments that we saw earlier.
So let's just go back and open it up again
in a browser. You can see there's a few
paragraphs down here. He's talking
about the fact that Reduce - this is actually
the one I've always hated most. Unless
the function's trivial, as ours is, even Guido
van Rossum struggles to understand
what's going on. As he says, we already
have a sum function to take care
of addition. So back in our code, we can write
what we've done there, quite simply, with
print parentheses sum parentheses
numbers. Click and run that, and obviously, we
get the same result. So getting back
to Guido's blog post, he talked about using
product to calculate the product of a
sequence - that didn't get added to Python.
There is a product function in the
itertools module, but that
does something different. It calculates
the Cartesian product which is useful
when dealing with sets, for example. Guido
proposed adding all and any to the
built-in functions. That's been done and
we'll look at those in a minute.
The upshot of this discussion
is that there's very rarely any need to use
Reduce in your code. However, many people
disagreed and there's a link to the
comments at the bottom of the post,
if you go down and have a look -
118 comments there - so you can go ahead
and check those and see why people have
disagreed with it, if you want. Now going
back to our code now, let's see how
Reduce works so that you understand
what's happening. You'll need to know
what it's doing if you come across it in
code that you have to maintain. Alright,
so looking at our list on line 9, we've
got five numbers.
What reduce is doing, is calling our
calc underscore values function with the
first two items in the list, 2 and
3, then returns the result 5.
It uses that value and the next item in the
list when it calls calc underscore
values again. So that returns 10, so
10 becomes the first argument in the next
call, to the next call, of calc underscore
values. So if you wanted to know what a
long hand, or say a long-handed
version of what's happening here,
we could type that out. It'll be something
along these lines; it'll be result equals
calc underscore values 2 comma 3
and let's just, actually, I'll do the next one, result
equals and it's calc values again. This
time it's result comma 5 and now
I'll copy the lines, I'll copy the next two
lines, and so it's result comma 5
result comma 8 this time, then result
comma 13, and then we can print result.
We can run that, and you can see we've
got the same value there. So each time
around, the function is called with the
result from the previous call and the
next item in the list, and you can see
that when I ran the program, we got 31
returned for a third time. Alright so
addition's easy but the sum function is a
much easier way to do the same thing.
Multiplication is also trivial, so if I
go ahead and change our calc underscore
values function to perform multiplication
instead, by changing the plus to a
multiplication, which is the star.
of course. If I run that again now,
this time we get the value 3120. The sum
is still 31, of course, and there's no
built-in function to calculate
the product of a list. If you wanted to
calculate the product without using
Reduce, then you'd have to use a loop.
So what I can do is comment out the call,
the call to sum there - comment that out. So
result equals 1 for x in numbers colon
result star equals x and then we can
print result.
We could run that, and then we get the
value of 3120 again. Basically, all
three methods are giving the same answer. We've
been discussing comprehensions in this
section and I mentioned that every
comprehension can be re-written as a
loop. The opposite though, isn't true.
You may be expecting me to write
a comprehension that does the same thing
as Reduce - we did that with Map and
Filter after all - but you can't
replace Reduce with a comprehension. Well that's
not strictly true - you can pretty much do
anything you want with enough code.
If you search for solutions online, you'll
find some. You'll also see their authors
describing the solutions as insane,
and not in a good way. You should now be
able to work out what reduce is doing
though, if you come across it in code
that you have to use or maintain,
and we'll leave it up to you to decide
whether to use it in your own code. So
let's finish this video here, and in the
next one,
we'll take a look at All and Any. See you
in the next video.