Alright so let's continue with our
ranges.py program, to look at a few
more things we can do with ranges. If
you want to use a range just to repeat a
block of code a certain number of times,
then there's no need to provide a start
value. If you don't provide a start value,
it defaults to zero. So I'm going to
change the code there and delete the
comma 16 so we've just got 10 in
parentheses, and if we run the program
now, you can see the program has actually
gone through 10 times, 0 down to 9. Now we get
the values from 0 to 9 because the start
value defaults to zero and obviously
it's not included on line 1. So what else
can we do? Well we can provide a step
value to our ranges. If we do that, we
have to specify a start as well.
Otherwise, if we try and add just a
step to our existing code, comma 2,
Python then interprets what I've typed
as starting at 10 and going up by 2. The
default step value is 1 and you can't
count from 10 to 2 in steps of 1 and
expect to get any values. So if we run
the program as is, we get no output at
all on the screen. So to get the values
from 0 to 10 in steps of 2, because we're
using steps, we have to specify a start
value and I'm going to enter the value 0
here. So 0 comma 10 comma 2 and now if we
run that, you can see it gives us the
values we wanted - 0 2 4 6 8. Note that
we didn't get 10 printed out. If you
recall, ranges go up to but not including
the stop value, just like slices and as
we discussed in the previous video. Now
if you want to count backwards, you can
use a negative step range. So what we
need to do then, because we're going
backwards we'll need to swap the
start and end. So we're going to start at
10, go down to 0 and the step is going to
be a minus number, minus 2. If I do that
now and run it, you can see we get the
values 10 8 6 4 2. So the start value has
to be greater than the stop value when
using a negative step, for obvious
reasons. For the same reason as we didn't
get 10 in the previous output when we were
stepping up, we don't get 0 when using a
negative step. Alright so that's an
introduction now to
range class. We haven't created very
exciting code here but we've seen how to
create ranges of values to iterate
over. Now something else you can do with
a range, is check if a value is in it.
Let's open the conditions.py program
from a previous video that we've worked
on. You can see it here, conditions.pi,
so I'm going to open that up. Alright, so there's
our code from that program. Now on line 4
we're checking to see if age is between
16 and 65 inclusive. We could use a range
instead. Now I'm not saying that you
should use a range here and the current
code is the most efficient way of
performing that test, but let's see how
to do the same thing using a range. So
I'm going to comment out that first line,
line 4. I'm gonna replace it with if age
in range, and in parenthesis 16 comma 66
right parenthesis and a colon. Because
the last value isn't included in a range,
I had to use 66 as the stop value rather
than 65. So let's run the program to
confirm that it still works: How old are
you? Let's test another, 16 first, Have a
good day at work.
Run it again, we'll try it with 65.
That works okay. Run it again, this time with 15,
Enjoy your free time, and one more time,
we'll try it with, say, the value 75.
So clearly that's working as it should.
So you saw that I tested it with the, with
a variety of values to make sure it's
okay. So make sure you do that whenever
you're testing your programs, to make
sure you're actually getting a proper and
comprehensive test and obviously I could
do a lot more testing, but we've done a
basic amount of testing to confirm that
the codes are working pretty well as it
should. Now as I mentioned previously,
the code that's now commented out on
line 4 is more efficient, but testing
if a value is in a range can be useful,
and for that reason I've demonstrated
how to do that. Alright, so I'm going to stop
the video here. In the next one, we'll
start looking at nested for loops.
See you in the next video.