in the previous video we had a quick look
at Python functions and we saw how we can
use them to perform actions or
return results and of course sometimes
do both of those things now our function
to print text centered on a 80 page
character screen was modified to just
return the text to be printed to
demonstrate how a function returns a
result with the return statement and
also that there is often more than one
way to do something and deciding what to
use or which way to use is part really
of the programs designed so functions are
incredibly useful to allow the same
block of code to be used over and over
again now they make programs easier to
design by breaking down the programming
challenge up into manageable tasks and
the use of functions can make programs
more reliable by providing code
blocks that can be thoroughly tested to
make sure they perform their function
reliably now these advantages also
come from using object-oriented
programming and classes and class
methods are just functions so it's
important that you understand functions
before we move on to object oriented
programming in the next section now I'm
gonna start with some maths here but it's
not going to be anything too complicated
so don't be too worried now parabola is a
very interesting shape
parabolic reflectors can be used to
focus light or sound and are also used to
focus the satellite signals used for
modern TV broadcast you can throw a ball in the
air it follows a parabolic path as it
rises and falls back to earth now what I'm going
to do is create a very simple equation
for a parabola so what we're going to do
is so what I've done is I've created a new
project and I've also created a new
python file so let's start with a
definition of a parabola functions so
we're gonna type.....
.....
.....and that's
it so you can see it's a very simplest
equation for parabola is y = x
squared so X times X that I've done
on line 2 and so I've created a simple
function to return the value of y for various values of x so if we run this
we get to see you all the values of y
printed out and if you scroll up and
down as you can see here right down the bottom
you can scroll right to the top
and this is sort of a shape in the
numbers but just do that again you
can see how the numbers sort of going down smaller
and go up again so its a bit of a shape
their
so its an interesting phenomenon with parabola
but it will be much nicer if we could plot them on a graph
because that would actually make a lot of sense
to do it that way so why don't we do that
why don't we continue on from there and do
that so i'm gonna make some modifications
to this file now so that we can do that
so we leave the existing functionality we
got in there but I'm gonna come back up here
and we're going to use tkinter
again so come up with a try to start with you see this a number of times now so.....
....
.....we are going start on
line 7 we leave our parabola method their
we are gonna take out this for loop now because actually we are gonna leave that because we are gonna modify it slowly so lets leave that their so on line 11 I'm gonna
to start a main window for tkinter so....
.....
....and you can make yours
much bigger if you like just change that
to the resolution of your monitor to a
larger value we didn't know how big to
make it because we wanted to use values
that worked on pretty well all computers and
that's why we left it at 640 by 480 but
feel free to increase
those dimensions to larger number to suit
your computer so let's also create a
canvas so.....
.....
....
....so the program just creates a canvas and adds
it to the grid window manager it fills the
Windows so if we just run this is to confirm
what its actually doing and it is not going to work
until I end the main loop call so.... so I just remove the indent
....try that again and it is running now and it's a
very basic window as you can see so the program
creates a canvas and adds it to the grid window manage as you can see it fills the window and that way
we don't have to worry about which
manager to use as its going to be the only
thing in the window so if you want to
the pack manager would also do this as well
but we chose grid because we want to
briefly add another canvas later now
interestingly enough if you checked
out the documentation links from the
tkinter section you may have actually come
across canvas now it lets you draw basic
shapes such as lines rectangles and
circles and you can also place text and
images on a canvas
now the canvas coordinate system has 00 at
the top left
whereas a normal graph
have the origin 00 in the middle so it
also be nice to have the X&Y axis
displayed on the graph now we can find the
midpoint of the screen by dividing the
width and height by 2 and a canvas can
have its origin shifted by using the
scroll region option now we want to
shift it right by half the width
bringing 0 from the left hand edge in to the
middle and also shifted it down by half the
height so this is something we will want
to do when we try to plot graphs on a
canvas or draw axis function would be useful
for that purpose so lets defined that method now
I'm going to close it down for now because we are finish with that come up here after parabola method and we define another
one leaving two spaces between the other
function so as defined......and what I'll do
is type this out and go through what we have done....
......
.....
...so the first thing
that draw axis function does
is called the canvas update method and it does that to make sure that we can actually
access the width and height now we did
mention this that when we used
winfo width and winfo height methods at the end of the calculator
challenge that you do need to do that
you need to call canvas
.update to make sure that those values
are available for you so we use them on the
main window that time but actually
every widget is a window and has those
methods available
now the function that we have designed just divides those values by two to get the
values for the X&Y origin now the scroll
region is just a box with one corner at
minus x origin minus y origin and the
other and X origin y origin for example if you had a
10 centimeters square piece of paper in
front of you with its top left hand in
the middle of your desk bringing it up five
centimeters and left five centimeters
replace the center of the paper in the
middle of your desk and that's exactly what
we're doing here but on the screen so the
function after does that then draws a
horizontal line for the x axis and a
vertical line for the Y axis so that's
essentially what draw axis is
actually doing so when we call the draw
axis functions we are going to reposition the
canvases origin and draw the X&Y axes on
the canvas so we need to do in order to
do that we need to add a call to it just
below what we've added the grid down here we do that on line 28 so....
...so now we do that we run this we
should see the canvas divided into four
quadrants by the X&Y axes
lets give that a run
if you're running on a Mac you might find you get a
result like this and it may happen on
a Linux or Windows as well if that happens
the reason for its probably self-evident
as I move this over notice on line 17
and 18 I used fill = white well in this
case on my Mac the background is white so of
course drawing some lines is going to be
drawn white on white which we cannot see
so if you are not seeing any results
change the color so fill = white lets
change that to black we should now have black lines on a
white background and thats should work for us so lets try that we can see now that
is actually worked as we can see there
and the purpose was to divide into four
quadrants the canvas and we've done that
it's been divided into four quadrants by
the x and y axis so to draw graphs we want to plot
single points which a canvas doesn't
provide a method for but a line of length one
will do so just a bit of important distinction
so you can't actually plot individual
points on a canvas but by making their
line length of 1 it will effectively do the
same thing so that's what we're gonna do
so that also sounds like something you are gonna do a lot that's drawing those
single points and then a create a
function called plot that will take
a canvas as its first parameter followed by the
X&Y coordinates of the point to be
plotted so lets go ahead and create that
going to come down here so we are gonna define a
function plot and again the parameters
firstly is the canvas and also the X&Y
coordinates where we want to plot and in
terms of what we need to do is gonna be....
....
...and lets got with a different color this time
we are going with red so we should be able to see red on a white
background again substitute the color if
appropriate
if your getting a different result on your computer so that's all the plot needs to do
and what would then do is change that so
instead of printing the output is going
to actually plot the points instead so type...
....ok so lets actually
run that this time
now lets get a close up there you
may be can't see that very well because of
the video but you can see that the
axis are printed and what you really
can't see a lot of detail about is
because the points are very far apart
but there is actually a vague parabola plotted
their you can sort of see that starting down here
and moving down but again it's not really
the best example but with that said
there's really two things wrong with the
graph firstly its upside down and second
the values of y go to 900 which is far
more than half of the 480 that we have
available in windows so in other words
were trying to draw off the screen both
problems as it turns out can be solved
pretty easily and what we gonna do is make
a change
firstly I'm going to close this down on line out with our
parabola method currently we've got y
= x * x if we change that to x * x / 100 that's gonna make sure that things
are fit in that area it prevents the
y values from running off the screen so
that's half the variable but we also then we want to go down to where we are calling plot here on line 36 and if we use the
negative value of y negative y that
should flip the graph over and that's
because the canvas coordinates system has
the y axis starting at the top with
increasing numbers moving down the
screen whereas traditional grappling plotting
has increasing y value moving up from
the axis so lets try running that again
...so you can see we got a little bit different output this time its a bit more clearer but the parabolic
function isn't really doing all it can
do thought at the moment the program needs to loop
through the values it returns in order
to print a parabola so wouldn't it be more
useful if the function plotted the points
no need to tell how big
the parabola should be and give it a canvas to
draw on so we'll look at doing that and
also fixing up some of these warnings
that you can see on the screen in the
next video