In this video, I want to talk about
removing items backwards.
Let's see two ways to do that.
We need to create a new python
file here. So I'm going to call this one
gobackwards.py.
Let's start by creating some data, so data equals,
and in square brackets, because it's a list; 104
comma 101 comma 4 comma 105 comma 308
comma 103 comma 5 comma, and I'm gonna
advance to the next line,
107 comma 100 comma 306 comma 106 comma
102 and the last one, 108. We've got
our right square bracket to close off
the list definition. On line three I'm going
to type min_valid equals 100,
line 5, line 4 rather, max_valid
is equal to 200. So we've got
similar data to our earlier example but
it's not sorted. The values to remove
appear randomly in the list, and it's 4 at
position 2, 308 at position 4, 5 appears
at position 6 and the last one is 306 at
position 9. So we'll start off with a
similar loop to the one we used in the
last program, and we'll print out the
index numbers to check that we're getting
what we'd expect. So on line 6, for space
index in range parenthesis len
parentheses data and right parenthesis,
minus 1 comma minus 1 comma minus 1,
right parenthesis and a colon. And on line
7, print parentheses index.
So if we run this program now, you can
see we get the values from 12 down to
zero, which is what we want. We can safely
remove the outlying values now, because
the values that we've still got to
process aren't affected, when the items
shuffle down to fill in the gaps.
And this'll be easier to understand if we
print out the list each time, so let's go
ahead add some code. So I'm going to add
an if on line 7,
if data left square bracket with index
in it, if that's less than min_valid
or data index then square brackets,
is greater than max_valid:
then we want print index to be indented.
As I mentioned, it'll be easier if we print
them out each time, and then we'll
actually delete it, so del data left square
brackets index. And what we might do,
rather than just printing the index,
let's also print out the data as well; comma data. Alright. Let's run the program.
You can see that the first line of
output has an index of 9. The value at
position 9 is 306, which will be removed.
When the loop goes around again, we'll be
processing position 8. The items in the
list before position 9 aren't affected
when we delete 306. So that deletion will
work fine and won't mess up our loop.
Next we get to index position 6. The item
there is 5 and that's correct - that's the
next item to be deleted. 308 appears at
position 4, so that's also correct.
Finally, we get the value 4 at position 2.
When that's deleted, we should have a
list with all those outlying values
removed. So I should have printed out a
final list, so that we can check that.
Let's add that to the code; print line 11
parenthesis data. Run the code, and you
can see that that works. The four rogue
values have gone from the list. This code
is a lot simpler than our previous
example. If we ignore the diagnostic
output on line 8,
our loop is only three lines of
code. Now this'll also work with a
sorted list. Test it with all the test
data from the previous example, to
confirm that it works. I won't do that in
the video, but remember to always
consider edge and corner cases when
testing your code.
Alright, so if this short loop does the
same job as all this, and I'll open up
outliers.py again. So if it does the
same as all this code, which you can see
obviously here, contains two loops, why did
I spend time writing that longer program.
Surely shorter code is better. If there
are fewer lines of code, there's less
chance of having a bug in the code. Now
there is a reason for this longer
program. I'm going to keep you in
suspense a bit longer. We'll see why I
wrote all that, in the video after the
next one. In the next video, however,
I want to show you another way to iterate
backwards. See you in the next video.