so I mentioned at the end of the
previous video the parabola function
itself on line 7 isn't really doing all
it could do though because the main
program needs still needs to loop through
on line 34 where the loop is starting on line 34
and go through all the values it
returns in order to print a parabola so
I think it'd be more useful if the
function plotted the points and all we
had to do was tell it how big the
parabola should be and then give it a
canvas to draw on now before we get
into that though I just want to talk about
some of the warnings that are on the
screen and remember these warnings here on the
right hand side let's just fix a couple
of these up so the first one is at least
two spaces so I made a mistake we need 2 spaces when we are putting a comment
in line at the end of a line so that
should fix that one up the second one
camel case variable import as lower case
that's because we're doing import with a
capital T for Tkinter and s the lowercase Tkinter
for Pythont 2 so that is ok we
don't need to fix that but these other ones
here are all the same shadow name x show named
Shadow named canvas the errors is the same basically it's a different name but
shadow name from out of scope is the error
now what it is is one of the variables
in our function shadows of variable
with the same name in the main program
so the first one actually reads if you go back here and have a look actually we will do a better
example come down here to the canvas so shadow name canvas from outer scope
inspection that detects shadowing names defining outer scope so when they talk about
the outer scope what they mean is the
main program where we created a variable
called canvas and you can see that we
did get on line 29 the errors actually
coming up talking about the canvas
variable that is defined on line 12 as a
parameter to the draw_axis function and that's because when I
gave the parameter to the draw_axis function and name it canvas it the function
then lost the ability to see the canvas
variable in the main program that's
because they're both the same name so all
references to canvas within the draw_axis
function
mean that the perimeter referred to the
parameter that was passed in and not the
canvas variable from the main part of
the program even thought they are called the same thing
that's actually the reason why its
confusing so it's really important to
understand this variable scope as this is what it is and as
functions are one of the few big things
in Python that actually introduce new scope
it's worth spending a bit of time here
just to understand that so you are aware
of how this actually works so to explain
the difference between the canvas that
is local to the draw_axis function and
the one thats global what we gotta do is
create another canvas and then side those both so that they can each occupies half
of the window now our original canvas
will need its width changed to 2320 and this
is one on line 29 and the reason for that is
because we gotta put two canvases where
there was one before the same space so
if you're using a larger width and height
you will just basically divide it by 2 in this
case we are going to make it 320 that's the first one
and we are adding it to grid which is correct but then we are gonna add the
second variable.....
.....
....the difference
will be on the next line we're going to
add it into the next column so of course it
appears to the right hand side so...
.....
...and we got a draw_axis function on line 35 which
is correct but on line
36 we're going to add the draw_axis for the other side so.......
....so just confirming that if we actually
run that to see that it does work
and you could see it basically got
two canvases now we've got to the first
canvas which were drawing on the half
basically left hand side of the screen
and our parabola drawing just on
that and we also got this canvas on the
right hand side as well
and we are drawing the axis to that so in
the past in the previous program of course
it was just one occupying the entire 640
by 480 for our window so that's working
and actually what I didn't do what I might do now is I am going to come back here just to make it a bit more obvious
and then I'm gonna put....
....and that will make it clearer because we
got a blue background as you can
probably guess that will do now its a little bit
more obvious now that we got this new
canvas which we actually added which is now got a blue
background ok so each time it's called
it's own variable called canvas is assigned the canvas object that is pass to
the parameter in the call so here
basically on line 35 passes up a
passes the canvas object
and the passes on to line 12 to the draw_axis
function the that calls that canvasses as well
and likewise for canvas 2 even though we
referred to it as canvas 2 its
referred to as canvas for the function
name and it's going to be using that name when
it's processing that for also for canvas 2
now we can see that a little bit better by
printing out some details of the canvas
objects so there's a function that shows
the representation of the object called
repr r-e-p-r so let's just put that
in and you can actually just sort of
print out some details about an object
in a format suitable for printing
so i can type.......and that will just printed
it out each time it's called it's going to
print out the basically the memory reserved
so if we just run that to confirm it is actually working you
notice now that we've actually got this
little print out on the screen now and you can see here the number at the end of each
part of this tkinter.Canvas object print out is meant to represent the memory
location where that particular object
was created in memory so obviously there
we got a different number in both cases in
which means that they're obviously
separate objects which is correct but
the other thing is just out of interest
if we stop this close it and run again you will note those
numbers will be different
basically different each time you run
the program different in that these will be
different to each other because they are
separate objects but also the individual
numbers allocated to each object is also
different because the computer every
time you run it is a assigning its using making a
decision where to put these in memory and
that changes each time you run it and no doubt these numbers are likely to be
a bit different when you run it on your computer as well
that's good so we can see that their
separate objects
but what is also cool is we can print
local variables
so Python has this ability called using the
locals function to print out all the
local variables for a method so what we can do is make a change to that so lets put this at the end of
line 18 so type....and that is the locals is the method that enables a printout of
all the variables that have been defined
for that particular function obviously
has to be the code has to be in a
function too be called its
going to just basically look at all the
variables in that function so if we run
that you can see their its showing us that we got the canvas object and note that the numbers here
so for the first time we call it canvas
represents the same variable
canvas this first one here as we pointed that out and then
also its got a y location
y_origin and x_origin and that is the variables
that we are creating on line 14 and 15 but note
that we are getting consistency here we got
the number their corresponding to that
number the first time it's called and the
second time that number corresponds to
that one so we can see that it actually
is working so it can be useful tool when
you're debugging to have the locals
function and also the representation code
the repr function as well so you think
at this point ok so everything's working fine
so why is IntelliJ actually coming up
with these warnings what is the problem
well firstly with a small program like
this where we can pretty much see
everything at once on the screen is not
really that big a deal I mean all the
codes there on the screen we can access
it and you probably not gonna get into
difficulty but chances are that you
gonna be ending up writing much larger
programs and you can find it can cause
unexpected problems if we make a mistake
somewhere pretty much I can guarantee that will happen on
some point on your programming journey that you make a
mistake so what I'm going to do is
simulate one possible mistakes in the
way to simulate that is to rename the
parameter canvas and to call a page so
I'm talking about the parameter here
on line 12 so we are gonna change that to page you
can see their and we need to make a few
other changes we need to call this
now page.update so.....
and as I'm going to be doing this you might be
thinking well Tim why aren't you using the
refactor facility
well it's slightly contrived example
here because obviously that would
automatically rename all occurrences
for us but it's possible that you might
be making a quick change using some
other editor as I'm doing it manually
to simulate a potential problem so lets just assume I did that and I remembered most
of these so I'll change that one as well
.....
......so if I actually run this having knowing
that I forgot to make the change on line
18 and you notice we've got a different
output here we've got no y axis
showing in the right hand canvas so you
might be looking at that thinking well
why that suddenly stopped working
you know if you made this quick change like I have and you neglected to make that change as I did
on line 18 and what I need to do is run it again so we can see now that with the output from
the locals function that the variables
is called page so on line 18 the yaxis is
being drawn on the canvas from the main
program so that one has its axis drawn
twice effectively so I basically we can see
what's happening their the canvas
variable that's been referred to their on line 18 is actually the canvass
variable that was defined in the main part of the
program and not from this function now again I did say this was a bit contrived
but if I originally called the parameter
graph instead of canvas for arguments sake so if we
comeback and do that lets
presume that it was called graph......
and we actually run this clearly we get a different error
altogether and the reason we've now got
an error is it Python notice that ok this
variable graph doesn't exist we are not
shadowing the canvas variable from the
main program anymore and consequently
we've got you know we know that there's
a problem we can actually fix it this is
probably not only crops up if you try
to use a name the same name in your
parameter as your using for your variable that is
defined in the main part of the program so
although python did mind that local main variables have the same name it can
be a source error and that's one reason why
IntelliJ is warning you about that for
these types of errors that you might run
into and it's probably a bad idea to
have the same names but with that said
there's also another reason why
shadowing is a bad idea in Python and
will have a look at that a little bit
later so this example has also hopefully
demonstrated the scope of the variables
so draw axis has its own local
variable called canvas
that is now called page and in the main program there
were two canvases called canvas and canvas 2
but inside the draw_axis function we can
and did actually refer to the
canvas from the main program but if we
now we try to refer to pages in main program
it won't work so it doesn't go 2 ways so firstly I'll fix this Graph put that back to page so
clearly in the draw_axis function
we're able to refer to these variables
defined in the main part of the program
of the Python program but we can't do
things in other ways in other words we can't
come back here for example and put print
...if you try to do that you can already see you got an error and if we try to run it name page is not defined and that is
because we're a variable is visible it can be
used is called scope and that's really
all there is to understanding the scope in Python now their is some other some other things we
can do to specify the scope of a variable
but we'll look at that later but for now
just remember that a function can use
the variables from the main program but
the main program cannot see variables
that are local to the function so I'm gonna
end the video here actually what I'll do before I end I'm gonna delete line 40 so
that we haven't got any code errors their
and will continue on with this in the
next video