In the last video, we created a simple class
that can store itself into a database
and also initialise itself from the database
if that database exists and the data is in the table.
So, we should now have a few records in our accounts table
and up until now we used the sqlite command line interface
to view our database.
Now it's important to know how to do that
and also how to use the SQL commands,
but now that we're back in IlelliJ,
there's actually an easy way to database view,
so we're gonna be talking about that in this video.
Now I've closed the run window from the last video
because we're gonna need the space
and if you haven't already done it,
split line five like I've done here over two lines,
because that will actually get rid of one of the warnings
over here in the right hand side,
but I've already done that so consequentially,
I haven't actually got that warning.
Now, each line of SQL though, if we have a look at it
and just come over here, has basically got the same
error message, "No data sources are configured
"to run this SQL."
And you can see there's a few there.
And also down here, there's one.
And as I said in the last video, that's not a warning
about our pathing code, it's IntelliJ advising us
that it could check our SQL statements for us
if we configured a data source.
So what we're gonna do is start by opening
the Database Tool window, we can go down or up I should say
to View, Tool Windows and select Database.
I could also have clicked on Database over here
on the right hand side.
Now from here what we can do is create a data source.
We can do that with Control End or Command End,
depending on your operating system,
alternatively we can just click on this little plus,
on the top left here.
But the other way of doing it is just to drag
the database file into the window.
Now this only works if the file has got
the correct extension, now IntelliJ uses the Windows system
where the file extension determines the type of the file.
And that's why it was important to give the database
a .sqlite extension, even on Linus or OSX.
Those two operating systems don't use file extensions
in the same way, but IntelliJ
does rely on them on all platforms.
So what we can do is over here is, we can drag on
this accounts.sqlite and drag it and drop it
into the Database pane and you can see when I did that
we've now got an entry showing.
And I'll just move this over a little bit.
So, now that I've done that, you can see that
some of the errors have disappeared,
but we've still got some other ones here,
one "Unable to resolve column 'balance'",
but the ones that have disappeared
are the ones relating to creation of the tables.
The reason that it's disappeared is that
IntelliJ now knows the names of the tables
and actually recognises the data source.
Now we still got warnings, as I mentioned,
that we can't resolve the column names
and that's because InelliJ doesn't have
the correct driver for sqlite databases.
So the first time you do this, you'll need
to instal the drivers for whichever database you're using.
And that's why accounts in the Database window
is underlined as you can see here.
And if I hover over it, you can see we've got a message
"Can't find the driver, open preferences to download".
So we're gonna right click on this database now
and select Properties.
And there is a link down here where it says
Download missing driver files, so click on that.
And hopefully you can see that it's downloaded
the relevant files for us automatically
and I can click on OK.
And you can see the errors have now disappeared,
the warnings rather have disappeared,
the underline on accounts has disappeared
and IntelliJ is now fully aware of the data source
and as well as the tables and columns within that.
All right, so I just wanna show you a quick slide here,
if you're using Windows, because this step
you might actually get a Windows Security Alert popup.
So this is the dialogue that I'm talking about
and again, this is only a Windows thing,
so you may actually get this popup on your computer.
So if you do get that, it's important
to allow access on private networks.
So righter strangely, the dialogue appears
with Public networks already ticked
and you probably don't want to allow that.
So Untick Pulic networks and make sure
you tick Private networks before clicking
the Allow access button, so I'm just gonna bring
that on the screen again while I'm talking
just so you can see that image, if you don't allow access
on Private networks, you'll get all sorts of problems
with updates and so forth, so again, what we need to do here
if Public networks is ticked and you do get this dialogue,
you probably don't want to allow that,
so you untick Public networks and make sure
you tick Private networks before clicking
on the Allow access button.
All right, so back to the slide.
So notice that this dialogue may appear again,
after a Java update, so it is a persistent setting,
but a new of Java will trigger it again.
And again, this is only a Windows thing.
Okay, so now that we've got the right drivers,
the warnings disappear and IntelliJ can verify
our table and column names as you can see.
So that's pretty cool, but it does actually get better.
And I'm just gonna expand this out a little bit again.
And if we now expand this, we can see that
it's showing us helpfully the list of tables
and we can expand those further and actually see
the columns within tables and note that
for the transactions table, time is showing as TEXT
rather than TIMESTAMP and you'll only see
the normal sqlite types when you the schema this way,
so it's not actually perfect, you do have to take care
if you modify any nonstandard columns from here,
but it's still a very useful feature
and makes life a lot easier.
Now you can also double click on the table names
or use the Table Editor button on the toolbar,
which is this button here, which is greyed out,
because I haven't selected a table.
Clicking on that actually gives us a list
of entries that are actually in the database.
Or specifically in that table.
And up here, you've actually got an entry
where you can actually add a new row
and because we've got accounts open,
this toolbar is relating to the accounts table,
we can actually add a new record if we want,
so I click on that and double click into the record,
or into the column rather, enter a new name
say Michael, I can tab or double click on the balance
and let's put in 500, press enter there.
So we add another record, we need another Terry,
so let's double click type Terry in here,
and and we put in an amount of zero.
Now we get an error or rather,
we should get an error but we don't yet.
Now note that the two new entries
are highlighted in green here, we've added the rows
but the change hasn't been commuted to the database,
that's why it's in green.
So two buttons have become available up here on the toolbar
and they're quite small though so might have to
sort of squinch your eyes to see them.
So I've got this one here, which is gonna be Submit
and we've got this one here which is Revert.
And notice that it wasn't active, the Revert button
until I selected a record, so if I've got Terry selected
clicking on Revert once removes and if I click on it again
that's removed Michael as well and it's now disabled
because of course everything's been commuted to the database
and there's nothing to update or revert.
All right, so we're gonna add those two entries again.
Michael, 500 and also Terry, zero.
This time I'm gonna submit the change
and notice we've got an error down the bottom.
Abort due to constraint violation
(UNIQUE constraint failed: accounts.name)
So why are we actually getting this error?
Well, it's because the name column is the primary key
and primary key fields have to be unique.
And right down the bottom of the screen you can see
that it's even showing you the SQL that
it was trying to use to add these records to the database,
So in this case it's failed, again, because of
the unique constraint as duplicating the name Terry.
So let's go ahead and make this new Terry unique,
so I'll put Terry and we'll put TerryG there this time.
And if I submit this time, you'll see
that it worked successfully and the entries are no longer
in green which tells us that they've been actually
added to the database.
At this point I can't then Revert the change
and just to show you something here, if I change
this TerryG to TerryH, whoops, TerryH,
we can then revert that change if we want to.
Now on some operating systems you may get
something weird happen here, sometimes you might find
that the Revert button doesn't get enabled
and what you may have to do is click on
this little circular arrow thing here
to actually refresh the table and then you'll find
that you'll be able to use the revert button.
But as you see it didn't occur on my Mac,
but it may occur on Windows or Linux sometimes,
I believe it's possibly a bug with IntelliJ.
Right so, at this point now, we've actually got an account
for each member of my department and that's really
the IntelliJ Database Viewer in a nutshell.
Now you can actually use this Database Viewer
to view a range of different databases
and obviously you can't drag things like
Microsoft SQL Server databases into the window
to configure it, so if that's the case
and you want to do that, you come up here
and you click on plus, the top left of the Database window
and you choose the Data Source that you want,
Data Source, you can see there's quite a few there,
and you select the appropriate database type
from the listing, configure your connexion.
So for example you if I choose SQL Server (Microsoft)
we have the usual configuration options for
connecting to a SQL server database.
Now if you've never used SQL server, don't worry about it,
I'm just showing you what's possible,
if you do need to connect to a SQL Server or Oracle
or DB2 or whatever, the database admins will
give you the details to enter into this form anyway.
All right, so I'm gonna Cancel this.
All right, so there's one more thing that I wanna cover
before we move on, now we're going to be looking at
committing and rolling back database transactions.
But we've also got a table called transactions
that stores data of financial transactions.
Now using the same word for both of these things
is going to get confusing very quickly.
So what we're going to do is rename
our transactions table to history.
Now renaming tables and columns is something
you may need to do, which is why
I've contrived to this excuse to show you how to do it.
So firstly, I want to close down
this Database Viewer window for accounts
to go back to our code and I'm gonna close down
the database for now.
So the first thing we need to do is to make a change
to the code so that we don't go creating
a new row for Terry, so we come down here,
on line 53, and we're gonna make
that Account equals TerryG, instead of Terry,
so we avoid any problems with violating
the unique constraint and the other thing I wanna do
is now retrieve those two entries,
actually we'll change that to TerryJ,
so we wanna retrieve the two entries that we've created
in the Database Viewer, so michael = Account("Michael")
and then also terryG, which again we added
in the Database Viewer, = Account("TerryG"), all right.
So if you run this.
You can see we've got, I'll just scroll this up a little bit
just to expand this a little bit higher
so we can see everything, we can see that all six objects
are being populated from the database.
So the first one for John and then we've got one
for Graham, Eric, Michael and TerryG.
And if I just run that again, we can now that I've done that
I've got six retrievals here, we've got John, TerryJ,
Graham, Eric, Michael and TerryG, so all six now
are being populated from the database.
And if you recall with the Michael record,
we didn't specify an account balance,
but you can see here that the balance is showing as five,
so that was retrieved from the accounts table.
All right, so to modify the transactions table,
how do we actually go about making that change?
Well, we open the Database window again,
I can also click over here to open that.
And if we come over here now to the transactions table,
I can right click and choose Modify Table,
and in the Modify Table dialogue, we can just
type the new name for the table,
replace the existing name transactions,
which I mentioned we're gonna do and change that to history.
And notice on the bottom that IntelliJ is helpfully
showing the SQL command that it's gonna execute
to perform the action, so that's honestly pretty cool.
You know, but have in mind though, this doesn't
mean that we can now forget all the SQL movement
so far in the course though.
So I'm gonna Execute the SQL statement,
IntelliJ checks at our code, will check to see our code
to see if anything in there will also need to change,
so I click on Execute, you can see that it's telling us here
that we need to make a change, because it's still referring
to the transactions table, so keep in mind that IntelliJ
doesn't yet take care of changing the code for us
until we actually go ahead and click on Do Refactor.
So click on Do Refactor and you can see over here
obviously history is now the name,
so I'm gonna close that off, database.
But the other thing that we need to change though
is here on line five, noting that it hasn't changed
the transactions table there, so we need to change that
to history and lastly I'm gonna show you is this is also
an option here, when we go to our table
in the Database Viewer, we right click that,
we can click on Rename, but doesn't do the same check
in the source code, so for that reason I think it's better
for you to use the Modify Table
and that's we used that in this video.
All right, and we'll just run this again
to make sure it still works.
And we still got the same results,
we're now using the new table.
All right, so let's now remove the confusion
around the word transaction, so I'm gonna
stop the video here and in the next video,
we're gonna continue on with our accounts programme
and rolling back transactions.
See you in the next video.