ok so in the last video we had a lot of
talk about polymorphism lots of slides
let's now see how this all relates to
python code now we're going to use this
code again in the next section so we're
going to create a new python file so
lets create one new python file and
will call this one ducks
ok and i know it's taking awhile a few
videos ago I mentioned that there was a
discussion on ducks so
we're going to start out now with a duck
class....going to
define a few functions....
...
....
....so it's a very
simple class I haven't even created init
method so our ducks do have three methods
walk swim and quack and by the way
because we haven't created a init
method we are getting a warning here the
method walk maybe static will ignore
that for now
alright so what we want to do now is
create a function to test our duck class
so i'm going to come down here and we're
going do...
...
so the test duck function takes a single
argument and calls it's walk swim and
quack methods so i'll create a new duck
and see how it behaves now we may need
to import our ducks into another module so
make sure that the main code doesn't run
if ducks is imported and if you recall we
did see how to do that in a previous
section so let's go ahead....
....
...
...so lets run this
you can see down here when I ran it that
donald walks like a duck swims like a
duck and also quacks like a duck
alright so now that we've done that
let's add another class a penguin class
i'm going to add it after the Donald
class finishes leaving two black lines
between it so will call this one
class...
...
....
ok so you can say what we've done there and
added some slang there for those you who not
sure what I've done it are you having a
laugh okay so we've created both the duck
class now and a penguin class now it's clear
that the penguin isn't a duck but it
happens to have exactly the same methods
as our duck class and consequently we
can do exactly the same things with it
and we can do something here like Percy....
....
....let's try running that
so you can see here that our test_
duck function still works now
percy may will be behaving a little bit
strangely by duck standards but as far
as the test_duck functions
concerned percy walks like a duck
swims like a duck and quacks like a duck
as far as the test_duck
function is concerned
Percy is a duck so in other words our
Penguin's passing the duck test what
I'm going to do is switch to the browser now
and open up a link a wikipedia link
paste in the link as always and
close this huge message that's
appearing on the screen there maybe
later
close ok as you can see it says so the
duck test is a humorous term for a
form of reasoning and boils down to
being able to tell what something is by
how it behaves and the phrase is
attributed to an American poet James
Whitcomb raleigh and his original phrase
was when I see a bird that walks like a
duck swims like a duck and quacks like a
duck
I'll call that bird a duck
so what's the point of all this well that
approach is fundamental to the way that
python deals with objects unlike
statically typed languages that require
the type of every object to be declared
when it's used pythons dynamic typing
means that it's only really interested
in what can be done with an object if an
object has the necessary attributes then
python quite happy for it to be used
now the phrase is commonly used in
dynamically type languages like python
and you'll often hear them referred to
as duck type in fact we saw it in one
of the warnings and IntelliJ gave
earlier in the course and that warning
said due to dynamic dispatch and duck typing
this is possible with a limited but
useful number of cases now we know that
penguins aren't ducks and Percy has an
inherited any of these duck like behavior
from a common subclass the important
thing is that percy has the methods
that our test_duck function relies
on and so as far as python is concerned
Percy is a duck so i'll stop the video
here now and in the next video we're
going to have a look at implementing
polymorphism using something called
composition see you in the next video