Nesting a for loop within another for
loop is a powerful way to process data
In fact, that's something that's done a
lot. It sounds like something special, but
it's just really one block of code
inside another block. So let's see an
example of that, using for loops to
generate times tables. Now these were used
to teach children multiplication and
normally went up to 12. So I'm going to
call my new Python file timestables.py.
Alright, so in terms of the code, I'm gonna start by typing
for i in range parenthesis 1 comma 13 closing
parenthesis and a colon. Then on the next
line for j in range parenthesis 1 comma
13 right parenthesis colon. Then we're going to
print on the line after that, print
parenthesis double quotes left and right
curly brace with a 0 in the middle, times,
and left and right curly brace with a 1 in
the middle is and left and right curly braces
with 2 in the middle. Then closing double
quotes dot format. Then we're gonna type
j comma i comma i times j and we've got two
closing right parentheses. What I'm going
to do on the next line then, is print, and
we'll just print a series of dashes
to separate the output. Ok.
So what have we done here?
Well firstly, we've got an outer loop
on line one that goes around 12 times.
Inside that on line two, we've got another
loop that also goes around 12 times and
it'll do that each time the outer loop loops.
When i has the value 1, j will loop
through the values from 1 to 12.
i will then become a 2 and j goes
through 1 to 12 again, and so on.
So I'm gonna run the program first and then we'll
step it through the debugger. So when we
run it first, you can see we've got the
output there. We're printing the value of
j first as, you can see, and you can see
that looping from 1 to 12. The second
value on each line after times is the value
of i, so in the first table, i is 1.
When we go around the outer loop again,
i is 2. If we scroll down we see the next set of
tables there, and that's giving us the
second table, and so on.
Now the debugger can make, can
help with making sense of this.
So what I'm going to do is set a breakpoint on
line three, the line that does the
printing, and then let's run the program
in the debugger. Firstly we can see the
values of i and j in the variables pane.
Not all IDEs do this, but IntelliJ also
shows the values in the code pane. You
can see it at the top of the screen at
the end of lines one and two. That's
helpful because you can focus on the
code and still see the values changing,
but it also means that I can switch to
the console tab so you can see the
output being printed and still see the
values of our variables. So I'm gonna go
ahead and do that. Alright, so firstly,
let's try this. I'm going to step over
the first line and we get back to
line two - this is the inner for loop. Step
over again, which I'll do.
You can see j now has the value of two. When I
step over that line again, we get back to
line two, ready for j to get its next
value. So I'm going to continue stepping
through the code until j is 12,
and there's j 12, as you can see there.
That's the end of the inner loop, so if I
step over again now, you see we get to go
one more time and then it's hit line four.
We're still inside the outer loop
but the inner loop has now completed.
If I step over once more now, we're ready to
go round the outer loop again, and I'm
going to step over twice more to see i
gets its next value 2 and j is
starting counting from 1 again. Alright
so there's nothing really else to say
about this. If you want to continue
stepping through the code until you're
comfortable with what's happening, then
pause the video now and come back to it
once you've stepped all the way through
it. What I'm going to do now is clear the
break point, and use the resume program
button over here to let the program
finish at normal speed, and you can see
the program is now finished. Alright, so
let's finish this program now with a
mini challenge.
Here's your mini-challenge. What happens
if we: 1. Indent the print another four
spaces? In other words we move it over to the right.
What would happen? and 2. What
would happen if we move the indent
completely for that line. So work
out what you'd expect to happen before
you try it. Pause the video if you're
doing that. When you're ready, come back
and we'll go through that challenge then.
Alright so welcome back. How did you
get on? Did you work out what the effects
of those changes would be before running
the code? Firstly, looking at line four,
it's currently part of the block that's
controlled by the outer for loop. So that
means that all twelve lines for j get
printed out before we get the row of
dashes in the output. So if we indent
line four, it'll become part of the inner
loop and should print out every time
around the loop. So let's go up here and do
that now. I'm just going to tab over, like
so. If I run the program now,
you can see we get a row of dashes after
every line showing the multiplications,
and obviously it's made the output significantly
longer as well. Alright, so we'll close
down the run window. The second part was
determining what would happen if we
remove the indentation completely.
Alright, so removing the indentation
completely will take line four out of
both loops. So that means it should only
print once, right at the end of the
program. So let me do that.
So I moved it way over to the left, so in
other words, removed all the indentation for
that line. If we run the program again now,
you can see what's happened there.
We've only got one row of dashes,
right at the end of all the output.
So there's another couple of things we
need to know about for loops but we'll
look at them in the next few videos.
We've seen the basics of how a for loop
works, to iterate over some sequence. The
sequence can be a string or a range,
but Python also has other sequences that we
can iterate over. I'll actually be
talking about lists in the next section
but I'll introduce them in the next
video. They'll give you more practice at
working with for loops, as well as a way
to cover two more things we need to know
about them. So, see you in the next video.