In the previous video,
we saw an easy way to check the data in our database tables.
So now what we're gonna do is change
our accounts class to update the balance columns
and instal the transaction details,
which from now on are called history
or are called the history.
So, if we actually run this again,
I know we did run it at the end of the last video,
but if we run it again and see the balance for John there
balance on account John has ten dollars.
Well that's not actually correct.
And if we go over to our database viewer and check that out,
we can see that on the database,
we've got John showing a balance of zero.
So there's a couple things we need to do here
in the deposit and withdrawal methods.
What we need to do is create an entry in the history table.
And I'll just close this down.
So I create an entry in the history table
each time a deposit or withdrawal is made.
And we need to update the account balance
in the accounts table as well.
Now, if one of these updates succeeds but the other fails,
then our database would be in an inconsistent state.
So this is one time when we need to make sure
that all updates are performed
or roll back all the updates.
So I want to start by adding the code
to update the two database tables.
And then we're gonna look at how to cause an error
so that we can roll back the transaction if necessary.
All right, so let's start with the deposit method.
And what we're going to do is remove this line here.
We'll comment it out.
Or actually we'll delete it,
because we're gonna replace it anyway.
And we're going to do: new underscore balance
is equal to self dot underscore balance
plus amount.
And next, we're gonna do:
deposit underscore time
is equal to P-Y-T-Z
dot U-T-C
dot localise
And it's gonna be datetime.datetime.utcnow
parentheses.
And we're getting an error there,
but we'll fix that shortly.
And next line, db.execute.
It's going to be UPDATE
accounts
SET balance
is equal to question mark
WHERE space, and then, in parentheses,
name is equal to question mark.
And then we want to provide new underscore balance.
That's the first parameter.
And the second one is self.name.
Then that's the update for the accounts,
but we also need to insert a new transaction
into the history table: db.execute.
That's going to be INSERT INTO history.
VALUES is going to be three,
so we need three question marks here.
And the three parameters are gonna be
deposit underscore time, self.name,
and then the amount.
And we want a db.commit.
Then self dot underscore balance
is now equal to new underscore balance.
And we can leave the print on line 34 as is.
All right, so what have we actually done here?
Well, we started by calculating the balance
into a variable called new_balance
rather than updating the self dot underscore balance
attribute directly.
And that's because we don't want to update that attribute
if the database transaction fails.
So next we get the time of the transaction.
This is on line 29 here.
And this is exactly the same as the code we used
when we created a list of financial transactions
in the last section.
Now, we've got errors here because we need to import
the datetime and P-Y-T-Z modules.
So let's just go ahead and do that now
to remove those errors.
Import datetime.
And also import P-Y-T-Z.
That fixes that error up as you can see.
And next on line 32 and 33 as you can see here,
we're doing the update to the accounts table.
And then we're doing the insert of the new transaction
into our history table.
And remembering to commit on the next line down here,
line 34.
And finally we're updating our underscore balance attribute
now that the transaction's been completed.
All right, so let's just have a look here.
We can run this again.
And if we have a look at our database,
we've now got John showing a balance
of 10 dollars 30 currently,
bearing in mind that we've updated the deposit method
to update the database,
but we haven't updated the withdrawal method yet.
So we need to actually fix that to get this balance correct.
And if we have a look at our history table,
you can see that it's now correctly showing.
There's a history,
there's now a record for each of the three transactions.
And obviously there's not one for withdrawing yet.
And one thing you can do,
you can actually drag these tables
and put them somewhere else.
And it's a little bit hard for me to do
because I'm actually in full screen.
So I won't do it now.
But with the accounts and history table,
we can actually drag those off the tab bar
so that you can view the two tables side by side.
And remember to refresh the contents of the tables
using the circular arrow button.
So you can click on that
and then just sort of review it at any time.
And that's because the view doesn't update automatically.
So what I'll do is I'll just leave these here
and just quickly go through them,
but bearing in mind as we re-run the transactions,
make sure you do actually do the refresh.
All right, so anyway.
Essentially you can see John's balance
is $10.30, or 1,030 in integer,
as an integer value.
And the three transactions are showing correctly
in the history table.
So that bit's working fine.
So the code for the withdrawal method's almost the same.
So we're gonna be writing the time to the database again
using exactly the same code as in the deposit method
to get the current time.
So before we actually go ahead and do that,
I'm gonna add a modified version
of the static current underscore time method
that we used in the last section
to calculate the correct time.
Let me go ahead and do that.
So I'm gonna add it in the account class.
It's going to be: def underscore
current underscore time.
And yes, we need that leading underscore.
And we're gonna return P-Y-T-Z
dot U-T-C dot localise
and datetime dot datetime
dot utcnow.
And I'll just get rid of one of those lines
to keep everything kind of hunky dory.
And we'll also change this.
We can add an annotation there,
'cause it says it can be static:
@staticmethod to keep that happy.
All right, so we'll change now the deposit method
to use that function that we've just created.
So deposit_time is now going to be equal to,
here we're gonna change that to be equal to
account dot underscore
current underscore time.
Okay, so now the withdrawal method.
Let's actually get that working.
So we're gonna do the same here
as we did with the previous method pretty much,
with the deposit method.
So I'm gonna delete that first line.
Delete that.
And, in terms of the code,
we're gonna start with new_balance is equal to
self dot underscore balance minus amount.
Then we're gonna do withdrawal_time
is equal to account dot underscore current_time
to get the current time for our history table.
Then we need our two updates.
We could have copied this,
but I'm just going to type it out again.
UPDATE accounts SET balance
is equal to question mark WHERE,
and name equals question mark in parentheses,
and then the two parameters, new_balance and self.name.
db.execute is going to be INSERT INTO
history
VALUES.
And we're going to insert the three values
like we did in the deposit method.
And this time it's gonna be
withdrawal underscore time, self.name.
And one slight difference here,
we're going to negate the amount,
so it's gonna be minus amount,
db.commit to save the transaction.
And then we're going to update our attribute:
self dot underscore balance
is equal to new underscore balance.
Okay, and fix that typo.
All right, now before I run this code again,
I need to set John's balance in the database back to zero.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So I'm going to just come into here,
make that zero.
And remembering to commit the change as well.
So I've committed that.
And for the history, what we're gonna do
is we're just gonna delete those three transactions.
We're gonna delete those.
And again, I'm gonna make sure those changes are committed.
So now we've got nothing in the history,
there's nothing in the history record if I refresh that.
There's nothing there.
And for accounts, just to make sure we do a refresh,
you can see that we've got a zero balance for John now.
Okay, so in terms of what we've added
to the withdraw method,
you can see that the two methods were almost identical.
And in fact, if we allow negative amounts
for the deposit method,
then really the only difference between them
would be the first condition in each method
and the value returned.
So it probably makes sense to break the common code
out into its own method.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And I'm gonna just come down here after the balance
the show underscore balance method and put it in there.
So def underscore save underscore update self,
and then it's gonna be amount.
Again, we've got an underscore
in front of the save underscore update,
the start of the method name.
And what we're going to do is,
I'm just going to copy and paste five lines
from the deposit method.
And one, two, three, four, five,
basically right up to and including,
well, it's actually six lines, isn't it?
So I'm gonna copy those and paste them directly in here
in the save underscore update,
making sure that we've also got our last balance as well,
self dot underscore balance,
our update in the attribute,
which we are.
So that's fine.
So now that we've actually done that,
the deposit and withdraw methods
can now use this new method
with withdraw passing in a negative amount.
So, we go back up here now to our deposit method.
And what I'm going to do is just comment that out.
Then we just need to make a call
to the new method.
So it's going to be: self dot underscore
save underscore update.
And it's going to be amount.
So we're passing the amount
that was passed ultimately to this method.
And for the withdraw method,
again for now we'll just comment this code out.
And I'm leaving this in, the source,
so that you've got a copy of the original version
just in case you want to play around with it a bit more.
But in this case, we're gonna do:
self dot underscore save underscore update.
But this time it's gonna be minus amount,
'cause we're negating that, 'cause it's a withdrawal.
But everything else should be correct
now that we've actually got that method written.
Now, what might I do just to make this a little bit easier,
is I want to take a copy of that,
paste that there,
and we'll put this above the deposit,
so put it on line 32.
Like so.
Just so we can see it,
because of course that's being called
by these other methods.
All right, and again, just one final point is,
I've marked it as private with the underscore.
This is the same underscore update method
to indicate that it shouldn't be used outside this class.
And so let's go ahead and run this
just to make sure that it works.
And we've actually got an error here.
We just come up here.
It's because I've used self
and I've indicated this is a static method,
but by making sure that it was a static method
of course we haven't got a self anymore.
And if I'd got rid of that,
that would then be valid again.
But in this case, oops,
we actually do want that to be set as a static method,
so consequently the self shouldn't be there.
So okay, we fixed that.
So if we run this again,
we've now got, the updates have gone through,
so you can see there.
But more importantly we want to check the values
of accounts and history,
so note that this again hasn't updated.
We need to refresh, reload.
And now, correctly,
you've got a balance of 1,000 for John now.
And if we do a refresh now on the history table,
we've now got four transactions.
We've got the three that we had previously,
but also the $30 transaction's there as well.
All right, so that seems to be all working fine,
which is great.
So let's move on to the next video.
And in that one, we're going to start looking
at how to retrieve the history data,
specifically the time column.
So see you in the next video.