Sometimes you may need to interrupt the
normal flow of a loop, to either jump out
of it completely, or stop the current
iteration and move on to the next one.
In the next two videos, we're going to look
at the continue and break statements
that we can use with loops. We need some
examples to show how these statements
can be useful, so I'm going to start by
introducing lists. We will be looking at
lists in more detail in the next section
of this course, so this is a very quick
introduction to what a list is. So list
in Python is an ordered sequence of
values enclosed in square brackets. For
example, we might have a shopping list.
So what I'm going to do is create a new
Python file here called shopping.py
and let's start by defining a list.
So I'm going to type shopping underscore
list is equal to and square braces, as I
mentioned, or brackets as the case, as you
may call them, and I'm going to enter
some items that we might buy when we go
out shopping. I'm going to put, and
because they're strings I'm going to put
them in double quotes, so milk is the
first one, separating each one, each item,
by comma pasta comma and obviously, as
you can see, double quotes around all of
them comma because they're strings,
spam comma bread comma and the last one
rice, and then that hasn't got a comma
because it's the last one and then we've
got our square brackets as well. So that
defines our list containing six items.
Now you saw that those items were strings
but we could use numbers instead. In fact,
you can store any type of object in a
list in Python, but we'll stick with
strings at the moment. So make sure you
do use square brackets when creating the
list, as I've done. So we've bound the
variable shopping_list to our
list and we can now use that in a for
loop to print out all the items. So let's
add some code for that: for item in
shopping_list colon.
Then line 4, print parentheses
double quotes buy space plus item
and if we run this now,
and we now get a reminder to
buy each item in the list.
So that's simple enough. It's a basic for
loop that iterates over the list and
prints out a message containing each
item. But what if we don't like spam?
Well we've seen one way to deal with
that. We could check for the current item
not being spam,d before printing the
reminder. So let's try some code there.
So we could add it above the print: if item is
not equal to, spam in double quotes colon and
then we need to indent the print. So
we're only printing if the item isn't
spam. And looking at the list down the
bottom, it currently does have spam. If we
run the program, you can see that spam
has now been excluded from the output.
So that's one way to exclude
spam from the output, but there's
another way in loops and that's to use
continue. So let's see how that works.
What I'm going to do is comment out this
loop, just for now, so you've still got
the code if you're downloading it, and
let's try another approach. Line 7, I'm
going to type for item in shopping under
score list : if item is equal to, so two
equal signs spam in double quotes :
continue, otherwise I'm going to go down
to line 11 there, print parentheses
rather, double quotes buy space in those
double quotes plus item. Then we've got
our right parenthesis. Now remember to be
very careful with your indenting here, as
always.
The call to print is indented to be at
the same level as if, so it's not part of
the block controlled by if. So when I run
this, looking at the output we had last
time down the bottom of the screen,
running it now, you can see we've got the
identical output. So spam is still not
included. Basically, all the items except
spam have been printed. Alright, so
let's have a closer look now at what's
happening here. So we're going to set a
breakpoint on line 8 here, that's the if
checking to see whether the item is spam,
and let's run the program now in the debugger.
Then we're going to kick straight over
to the console tab, if you're using
IntelliJ or PyCharm, then obviously I'm
using IntelliJ, as you can see, because we
can see the values of our variables
printed in the Edit window at the top.
Alright so we've entered the for loop and
you can see the item is currently milk.
That doesn't equal spam so therefore
line 9 won't be executed, so we step over,
and you can see we step straight over to
line 11. So if I step over again now,
you can see buy milk has been printed out to
the console and we're back now again at
line 7.
So step over again, and this time you can
see the item has changed to pasta. Now
that also doesn't equal spam, so I'm
going to step over twice more to get
back to line 7, and you can see buy pasta
has appeared in the output pane as well.
The next item will be eggs, so I'm going
to step over three more times; one, you
can see item's now eggs, and two more times,
and buy eggs has appeared in the console
window and we're back up to line seven
again. So next we're going to get to spam,
so I'm going to step over it and we
should get to line eight. You can see
item is spam. This time the condition will
be True and line 9 will execute.
Let's step over to check that.
Alright so we're now ready to execute the continue
statement on line 9. continue causes
all the remaining code in
the block to be skipped,
so execution will jump straight back to
the for statement. So let's step over and
confirm that, and you can see what
happened there. We jumped right back to
line 7. So that's what continue does.
When it appears in a loop it causes
everything else in the
loop to be ignored.
We've avoided doing any processing when
the item is spam, so if we step over again,
you can see item is now bread. I'll
continue stepping through now, to let the
program finish, and you can see the
program has now completed. Alright.
So that's what continue does. You probably
won't use it very often. It's there if
you need it and you now know what it
does, if you come across it in code that
you have to work with.
I'll finish this video by comparing our
two bits of code.
The code that's currently commented out
on lines 3 through 5, produces exactly the same
result as the continue code on lines 7
through 11. If you've decided that you
never have to use continue, then you're
correct. In fact, a lot of languages don't
have the equivalent of a continue
keyword. Where it can be useful, though, is
in making code easier to read. So check
out the responses to this stack overflow
question that I'm about to put on the
screen. Link, as always, is in the
resources section of the video, and
someone's asking the question there, as
you can see, some example, for some
example uses of continue, and there's
some good examples there you can read
through, of using continue. Basically, some
other opinions from people there, about
continue. Certainly a useful read.
Alright, so coming up next we're going to
start talking about the break statement.
See you in the next video.