Alright so let's talk about the break
statement in Python. So it's also
possible to break out of a for loop
completely, using the break statement.
If we replace continue with break, we won't get
a reminder to buy bread or rice because
the loop will terminate when it gets to
spam. So what I'm going to do is delete
this commented code out completely from
the previous video and then we're going
to change continue to break.
Firstly, lets run it,
and you can see what happened there.
Basically, we saw the output milk pasta
and eggs, but after we executed break we
didn't get a reminder to buy bread or
rice, and that's because the loop
terminated when it got to the break
statement on line five, when it got to
spam. So break can be very useful.
Imagine we're searching through a list
containing thousands of items. If we find
the item we're looking for,
there's no point looking through the
rest of the list. You generally stop
looking when you find what you've looked for.
So what I'm going to do now is copy the
first line, line one here,
and we're going to create a new file called searching.
Ok, I've pasted that line back in.
Alright, so let's use a for loop to search for an
item. We're going to start with a couple
of variables, so on line three I'm going to
type item_to_find
equals spam in double quotes, and on the
next line found_at is equal
to None, noting that it starts with a capital N.
So we're gonna search for spam and I've
bound the variable item defined in the
string value that we're looking for,
that's on line three. If we find it, we
want to know its position in the list.
We're going to store that in the
variable found at, or found_at.
Now initialize that to None on line four,
and None is a constant that's used to
show that something doesn't have a value,
so it's roughly equivalent to null
in C or Java. Now I'm going to come back
to that line because new programmers
might be wondering why we've attached a
variable to something that doesn't have
a value. It doesn't seem like a very
useful thing to do. Well it actually is
useful. I wouldn't
be doing it otherwise, but it'll be easier
to show why it's useful when we see our
code working. Alright so now what we
need to do is write our for loop.
I'm going to write this one slightly
differently. What we're going to do is
loop over the index positions of the
list instead of looping over the items.
So to do that, on line six I'm going to
type for index in range
left parenthesis len left parenthesis again,
shopping_list and then we've
got the two right parentheses and a
colon. On line seven, if shopping_list
then in square brackets,
index and then closing right square
bracket. That's equal to two equal signs
item_to_find :
found_at is equal to index. Okay so
there's our code. So I've used a new
function there - the len function.
Len is short for length and lets us know
how many items are in the sequence. Our
shopping list contains six items, so len
left parenthesis shopping_list
right indices on line six,
that's going to return the value six. So that
means index, therefore, will get the
values 0 1 2 3 4 and 5. Remember that the
last value in the range isn't included.
So indexing a list is exactly the same
as indexing a string, and we covered
that in the last section. The item at
index position 0 is milk, the item at
position 1 is pasta, eggs is at
position 2 and so on. If we find the item
we're looking for, which is the test on
line 7, we store its position in the
variable found_at on line
8. When the loop terminates the value of
found_at, we'll either still be
null as we defined it originally on line 4,
if we didn't find the item we want, or
it'll be in the index position of the
item in the list, which was set on line
8. Alright, so the last bit of code now
we need to add, is to print out what we found.
So let's do that. Just as a reminder here,
I'm gonna put a comment on line 6.
This is what effectively is happening
here, that line seven, that's the len
shopping list returns 6, and that's why
it's equivalent to what I've typed there
if we weren't using the len function.
Alright so on line eleven then, we're
going to type print parentheses double
quotes Item found at position and left
and right curly braces dot format,
and in parentheses found_at
and then we've got our closing right parenthesis.
If you run the program,
you can see it says Item found at
position 3, and that's correct.
Spam is the fourth item in the list, at
index position three, and obviously as
the count starts from zero. Now I don't
think I need to step through the for
loop from the beginning, but do that if
you want to see, going around from the
start. What I'm going to do is set a
breakpoint on line nine, where we assign
the index number to our found_at
variable. If you run the code in the debugger,
you can see index is set to the
value of three and we've found the item
we're looking for. found_at is
currently still None. When I step over
you can see that three has now been
assigned to found_at
and that's good. Our program is working and
has found spam in the list. What's not so
good is what happens next. We found what
we're looking for and there's no point
continuing to search, but when I step
over again which I'll do now, we can see
that the code's still searching. You'll
have to continually step over here, till
that finishes its work. Eventually you can
see the program is now completed. So this
is where break can be useful. What we're
going to do is add a break after line nine,
indented to the same level, as you
can see there. So if we repeat the test
I'm going to debug it again, found_at
currently is set to None. If I step over,
found_at is now 3. When we're
ready to execute the break statement, a
break causes Python to jump out of the
loop, so when I step over now, you can see
the execution has gone straight to line
twelve. That's more efficient because we
don't keep going around the loop after
findng the item we want. Step over one
more time, and that's terminated the
program, as you can see.
So that's the break statement. If you
need to jump out of a loop, that's how to
do it. We'll be using break in some other
examples, later in the course.
I'll stop the video here and in the next one,
we'll look at what happens when the item we
want isn't in the list.
See you in the next video