so we are gonna leave geometric functions where we
left in the previous videos but
we are gonna carry on working with Tkinter to produce a very simple card game now there's a couple of
things that we haven't fully explored
with functions yet and as I mentioned
earlier there's another reason why
IntelliJ warns about shadowing variables
in the outer scope this game is gonna
give us a way to look at that in more
detail now blackjack itself is quite a
simple card game the aim is for players to
get a high score or higher total than dealer without going above the score of 21 now if
the total value of the cards in a hand
comes to more than twenty one then the
payers said to have bust or have busted and that is game over now their is variations on the
way the game is played so our version
as I mentioned is gonna be simple version
and will have the following conditions
the dealer deals one card to
each player then to him or herself each player
but not the dealer then gets a second card
the player then decided wether to stick with a
total they have or hit which means to get
another card now a player can hit as many times
as they like but as soon as their total goes above
21 their bust and its basically their goal stops effectively the cards that a player
holds when they go finish this is call their hand once all the players have either
stuck or bust which of the two options
the dealer gets a second card and the dealer
then decides whether to stick or hit
this works the same as for the players and that
the dealer has over 21 they bust
then all players that haven't bust effectively win
their is another constraint to the dealer though the
dealer cannot stick on less than 17 so in
our version game we will also play the dealer must also stick if they have 17 or
more now once the dealer has finished any
player whose total is more than the
dealer wins in any player with a smaller
total losses so if the dealer and the player have
the same score then they draw so to keep it
simple we gonna player with a single
player but you can add more players yourself once that game is working now in case for anyone who isn't
familiar with Western playing cards
their is 13 cards in each of 4 suits and that makes a
total of 52 cards in the pack
effectively
the first 10 cards are 1 to 10 and
then there were three face cards called jack
queen and king each also having a value of 10 in this game in other games the queen
will rank higher than the jack and king higher than a queen so the suits are called hearts clubs diamonds and
spades now their is one final complication to make
things interesting
the ace which is the card with the value 1 can
also have the value 11 then the player can decide
which of the two values it should take so they get the best total in their hand now before
we start I'm gonna show the cards on the
screen rather than printing three
of spades queen of hearts so we are gonna draw it so to do that we need some
graphics for the cards and their is a very good
collection created by David Bellot and
I'm going bring up this file or bring
up the link and you can download it
so I'm gonna open a browser svg-cards.sourceforge.net so it's actually the
image are license under the GNU LGPL Lesser
General Public License so that basically
allows you to do what you want with it
as long as anyone you give or some of
your program to also has the same rights
but keep in mind if your actually uses in
a program that you need to give people
the same rights and that rights include
full access to the source code so if you
were releasing an app you have to give
that source code access that's what
you're giving up for this particular
type of licensing and so basically by
giving you the link to download these
images are complying with the LGPL
and if you create and distributed a program
using these images read the license
carefully and make sure that you
comply and you can see the licensing
on the screen so all 52 cards
plus 2 jokers an image of the reversal with
a single .svg file possible to
leave them in that format and to
extract the individual images as the
program runs their are libraries to help with
this but to make a life easier what
I've done is I've extracted all the images and
you can download them from the link in the
lecture at the end of the course to get
to all the images in .png and .ppm
format
now it's interesting thing to keep in
mind with Tkinter that support for png
.png files are added into Tkinter 8.6 so if your using an earlier version which
I am because I'm running on a Mac which
has got 8.5 then I need to use
the PPM files so to save you downloading the images that you don't need
if you're a slow or metered Internet
connection
the PNG images only are in the cards_png.zip and the PPM images are only
in the cards_ppm.zip so check
your version of Tkinter if your running 8.6
might as well use the PNG so here's the files
you can see there I've got three here on my in
my folder that I've actually download so
PNG if you got tkinter 8.6 otherwise use PPM if you're 8.5
or if your unsure which version your
running because that will work for both
alright so that's enough talking we
talk quite a bit lets get
into starting some coding so I've created
a new project called blackjack and a new
python file called blackjack.py as well but before
we enter any code we need to extract the
cards folder from the zip file
and place it in the same directory as
blackjack.py now you can put it
somewhere else if you prefer but the path
will be using to find the coded images
will then need to be changed to reflect
your actual location so I'm gonna
grabbed the PPM files
...I'm gonna unzip those you can see the cards folder and that's all the various cards that are showing so I'm going to take a copy of this
gonna go back and go to the right click here which you have seen me do before click on reveal in finder
to see the location that is going to show me
the location of where the blackjack
folder is that I have just created today and go into that
folder and then paste cards into that
folder so either you download the PNJs or
the PPM
and unzip the zip version into a cards folder within the
blackjack project directory that
we just created so I've done that now ok so we are
gonna start the program by importing TKinter
as normal and because this is a card
game and we need it
degree of randomness to make an
interesting we are gonna also import the random
module so type....
.....
...and lets also setup the screen and frames for
the dealer
player.....
.....
now the program needs to have space for the
dealers and the players cards and some way to
display the result and also buttons for
the player to choose to hit or stick so
we can change the captions for the
buttons later but while we're
developing the program we are going to use one
button to deal cards to the player and
another to deal to the dealer that game is
going to look something like this so
gonna load this
up on the screen ok so that's what our
screen is gonna look like so the main windows has
got three widgets a label at the top
to display the result and two frames one
below the other top most of the two
frames is going to contain the
cards and score for the dealer and player and the ones below will hold the buttons as you
can see on the screen their now the card
frame will itself contained two other
frames one for the dealer and one for
the player as well as labels to hold the
name as well as the score so lets start
typing a bit of code in to start building this
interface....
....
.....
......
.......
...so we still got some more typing
to do so what I might do is stop this
vide now and in the next video will
continue on we still need to add the embedded
frame to hold the card images and just
while I'm talking I'll bring this up on the screen again this is the interface we are trying to build
here so we still need to we have done a lot of
these but we still need to finish off and
add the embedded frame to store the card images for
the player we need to add the buttons
the frame for the buttons and also buttons itself the dealer button and also
the player button so will continue on with our blackjack game in the next video