In the previous video, we checked that
python was installed and then went ahead
and installed idle on this computer, so now
we're going to have a bit more of a look
at idle. Now when developing software in
any programming language, an integrated
development environment or IDE makes
life a lot easier for developers and
that's because it allows you to enter
compile and run your programs without
having to leave the editor and really
saves you having to go to a command line
for a lot of programming. Now Python
provides a very simple idea called idle
which we installed and talked about
briefly in the previous video. Now the
name idle incidentally is a homage to
Eric Idle one of the members of the
comedy group Monty Python. Now idle
interfaces directly with the Python
interpreter. Now for a number of reasons
that will become apparent as we progress
through the course, we actually suggest
using IntelliJ IDEA or pycharm instead
of idle and in fact in the next video,
we're going to be showing you how to go
about installing IntelliJ IDEA, but that
said if you'd prefer to stick with idle
for any reason or if you have to access
idle, it can sometimes be very useful.
So in this video we're going to show you
how to use the basics of idle. So I'm
going to assume that you've installed it
as shown in the last video, so you can
start idle by going over to the
applications menu and just type in
idle, you can see that brings it up there
I can just click on that now to start it
up, there's my Python shell coming up
which is actually idle running or we can
go to the command line
just type idle.
And just a note that we talked about this
but Linux systems will usually also have
Python 2.7 installed so and as you saw
in the last video that that was the case
with my Linux distribution so make sure
you if you are running from the command
line your type idle 3 to get the latest
version at version 3 which we need and
not just order which will be the older
versions and you can see here
confirmation Python three point five
point two and that was the version that
we will talked about in the last video.
So I'm definitely running the right
version. Alright so once idle is running,
anything it type will be passed to the
Python interpreter and the results
displayed on the screen. Now ordinarily,
in a program you need to use the print
statement to display a result and you'll
learn more about that in a later video,
but you don't really need to do that in
the idle, so I just come here and
just type 2 plus 4 and press enter,
you can see I immediately get the answer
of 6 there. So what happened there was that
let me type the command in the
expression 2 plus 4 was passed to Python
and Python came back with the result 6
all right so I'm going to type in some
code here now, now don't worry too much
about exactly what this code means,
you don't need to understand it at this
stage, this is just really showing you
how idle works and in later videos
you're going to be learning the syntax
of Python. This video is demonstrating
idle, not explaining the Python language
at this stage. Now in the course examples
you'll often have to enter code blocks
and that just blocks of code spanning
several lines. Now idle knows when you're
typing in such a block and what
immediately executes anything until
you've finished typing all the block
code in and you'll know it's expecting
more text because of Chevron's and 3
greater than signs as you can see on the
screen there weren't appear until you're
finished. And to see that working I'm
going to type the code now, for space i
space in space range left parentheses
the number 10 right parenthesis and a
colon, once I press enter note bow
chevron aren't appearing anymore and that's
because idle was aware that this is a
code block, so I could type in my code
and hasn't executed anything unlike the
previous example and wait until I've
actually finished typing in the code
block, there's a colon by the way when I
typed in is very important and also the
indentation is very important as well
and we'll be talking more about that a
little bit later, so I'm going to press
enter again now and look at the cursor
moves to the next line but it remains
indented at the same level as cp of
print on the previous line, this time I'm
going to press the backspace button and
notice that the cursor moves back to the
left-hand side and this tells idle
that you finished the code block and
consequently when I press enter again,
it's going to execute the code, so I'm
going to do that now and you can see the
code was executed and what this
particular bit of code does is for each
element in the range, it prints out the
values, so consequently we get the value
0 through 9 printed out in
the screen. Again don't worry too much
about understanding the code, you really
don't need to understand the code at
this stage, so you can see that I don't
have some basic capabilities to run
Python code and this is all very useful
for checking simple instructions but
editing what you've typed isn't very
intuitive, so let's just say we wanted to
change the number 10 to 11 in the code
that we typed in, to do that we actually
move our cursor up up to that line of
code and then I press enter
and notice that it's duplicated the code
that was originally top here up on
the screen and change the number 10 till
eleven, now I can just move the cursor up
and move it over and delete the zero and
replace it with a 1 and to complete this,
I need to go down with my arrow keys,
press enter after the code indent and
press backspace and there at the stage
we're ready to execute the program again,
I can press enter and you can see the
code is now executed this time we've got
an additional number that's been shown
on the screen because we've increased
the range by one, so that's one way of
executing code and it can be very useful
if you just want to check out a bit of
code quickly, however you'll often want
to save programs in a separate file,
run them from there, so from the file menu
I'm going to create a new file,
click on file then new file and I'm
going to type some code in here,
I'm going to type print left parenthesis
double quote hello world exclamation
mark, another double quote then right
parenthesis and then press enter.
Now, to execute this program we just
typed in, we can either come up here to
the run menu and select run module or we
can press f5, so I'm in the menu,
I'm just going to select an option but
either will work there because this is
the first time that we're running this
program and we selected a new file
as with most programs the most word
processors etc, it's asking us do we want
to save the file? Well, it's actually saying
we must that- the file must be saved
before we can execute it, so I'm going to
click on ok and what I'm going to do is
put this on my desktop
I'm gonna call this one HelloWorld, note that
the bottom it says file dot py, so I'm
just going to press I'll click on save
and you can see how HelloWorld dot
py's now saved, firstly allow a
desktop which was the folder I selected,
but secondly notice down the bottom here
we've got this restart we want to path
to the file that we just saved but also
the output, so not only did it save the
file it executed it, that's of course
because we selected the run option.
Now again, we'd recommend that you start
using IntelliJ IDEA instead that's
because idle is fairly basic
it doesn't really provide any hint code
checking or all the other features of a
full IDE like IntelliJ does, but if you
want to stick with idle though this
brief introduction will got you
started and the installing IntelliJ IDEA
will be covered in the next video, but I
want to give you a few reasons why you
should consider using that rather than
using idle, firstly code checking as you
type, so IntelliJ IDES checks your
code as you type it and the flags errors
with a marker in the right margin it
also suggests improvements in both the
styling your code and the content and
that's incredibly useful especially when
starting out with a new language,
auto-completion works across the various
Python libraries to provide rapid
selection of the methods and functions
and hints on the system, idle on the
other hand only copes with core
functionality, so auto indenting it also
allows editing of xml and text files so
the same tool can be used to examine
data for some excellent refactoring
tools integrated python debugger support
for django and google app engine projects,
it also supports many languages in
addition to python such as java, scaler
pearl and groovy and many frameworks so
they really only need to learn one IDE
for all development. And also keep in
mind google's Android studio which is
a tool for Android app development
that's basically IntelliJ IDEA under the
hood. So now I'm going to be using
IntelliJ IDEA in this course, you can
still use your favorite IDE instead
if you prefer so if you're already using
something like eclipse or pycharm or
one of the many other Python IDE then by
all means carry on using them. Alright so
I'm going to finish this video now with
a short program that we've created just
to demonstrate some of the
power of the Python language. So the
program's going to collect exchange rate
data from the internet and produce a
graph showing three currencies for the
last 12 months now the complete programs
less than 100 lines of code, I think
that's pretty impressive given that it's
doing that all in real time and clicking
that real data from the internet.
Now generally I really strongly recommend
that you type in the code when watching
the videos in this course and personally
I can't stress that enough typing in
code rather than just watching me type
it really does help you learn faster and
consolidate what you're doing and that
really is important and without going
into a lot of Education Theory,
you retain about 80% of the things you do
compared to about 30% of things you just
see, and if that doesn't persuade you I'm
going to add that myself and Jean Paul
learn by typing in code,
the reason was starting out we didn't
have the interne, so to learn stuff we
need to copy code from magazines and
books so the act of typing it in makes
you focus on every word that you're
typing and correcting the typing errors
afterwards really does help you learn
what's going on.
And I'd also recommend that you watch
each video again after you've typed the
code, so you can focus on the explanation
of what that code is doing. With that
said, this next bits an exception to that
and that's because the code I'm about to
say is quite complex but I would produce
this program to show you the power of
Python and there's a lot of things in
the code that just won't make sense at
the moment at this stage of the course.
Now this program uses functions
generators external modules and things
like lists and tuples then by the time
you finish this course, you'll understand
what all those things are and more
importantly, how to use them in your own
programs and in fact you'll understand a
lot more than that. But now though, relax
and run the program they're going to
feel for what you can do with Python.
Alright, so what we need to do is open
a browser we need to download this file,
so we can actually run it so I'm
just opening my Firefox and I'm going to
go to learn programming dot academy forward slash py
download or one word in lower case dot
html press enter that brings up a very
simple file there, we can right click
this, click on Save Link As and I'm going
to save that on my desktop. You can see
the file in there, exchange rate py, click on
save. You can see that it's already
downloaded, it is a very small file so
I'm going to click on over here to close
the browser down and you can see we're
going to exchange rate to py showing the
other screen. Alright so back in idle for
the Python 3.5.2 shell,
it's called on Linux we're going to open,
I'm going to go to the desktop I'm going to
open or select the exchange rate to py
and here's the actual code for that,
so to expand it out of the list you can see
there and you can see it probably looks
very complicated to you if you
haven't seen program code before,
haven't seen Python. As I've said
previously in this video, you will
understand all of this and what's going
and what it's actually doing as you work
through the course, for now though run
the program and again you can press f5
or you can come up here to the run menu
and click on run module so I'm going to
click on select an option now and that's
now running the program and that's now
downloading the current exchange rates
in real time and drawing up a chart.
So there you go, you can see now that after
a short delay well then that was what
the data was getting fetched from
internet, we're now seeing a chart on
screen showing exchange rate for
Australian dollars Great Britain pairs
of the Euro against the US dollar,
and the program's actually displaying the
data for the last twelve months and
you're getting different month showing
on this x-axis over here and obviously
I'm running this in August 2017, as I
record this video, so the last date in
will be August but depending when you're
running this you'll see that this will
be updated to what is the current date
on your computer.
And personally I think that's pretty
impressive for any 95 lines of code,
and again I'm not going to explain how it
works at the moment because it does use
a lot of Python features but everything
that it does will be explained in the
course, so it will certainly all make
sense as you work through the course,
there's some of the coding again so
basically going through this course
you'll be understanding pretty well
everything in here, what it means and you
can use concepts like this in your own
programs. Alright so that's it, that's a
brief tour of idle. In the next video,
we're going to go ahead and install and
configure the IDE that I've talked about
IntelliJ IDEA and also talked a little
bit about pycharm instead which looks
pretty much identical to IntelliJ IDEA,
but it only supports Python programming.
As I said that, if you're already using
an IDE that supports Python and you're
happy with that, you can actually
continue to use that for the entire
course. Now obviously, if you do that your
screens will look different to the
videos but the code that you type in was
still function and work exactly the same.
Alright, so I'll see you in the next video.