Alright, so moving on now with the
example that we started in the previous
video. So a generator works like an
iterator, and what we can do is, we can
actually use next to get the next value
instead of using it in a loop, and
obviously, we used it in a loop in the
previous video. So what we're going to do
to see that working, we'll come up here to
line 17, and actually before line 17,
we're going to put a print statement in
there, so let's go ahead and do that. So
we do print, parentheses next parentheses
big underscore range. So what we're
going to do now is delete this line 12
because we don't need that anymore,
and by doing that, effectively, line 15
becomes line 14, so I'm just going to
change the reference to that so it's
clear in our code. And of course that code
we deleted was only there to show that
my underscore range wasn't called by
the assignment on line 14. Alright, so
let's actually run the code, and we can
see that it stopped on line 14, as we
would expect it to do. So the next line
to execute should be our call to next,
which is currently on line 16, and
that gets the next value from our
generator. Now as we haven't used the
generator yet, the next value is
currently the first value, so in other
words we should get zero printed here.
So press enter and you can see we do get
zero returned, as well as the message
that my underscore range starts and
we're now paused on line 22. So at this
point before we continue, I've actually
got a mini challenge for you. I'm not
going to use a slide, so you can actually
see the code which is on the screen at
the moment. So at this point, what will be
the first value appended to big
underscore list on line 25? So what will
be the first value appended to big
underscore list on line 25, given that we've
already had a call to the my underscore
range function. So pause the video, have a
think about that and see if you can
figure it out and come back and we'll go
through the answer.
Alright, so let's see what happens when
I press enter to startexecuting the loop.
And you can see my underscore range is
returning one, and we're in line 24, the
inside loop. So the first value that's going
to be added to the list is 1, and that's
because we've already consumed the first
value from our generator, and we did
that when we asked for the next value on
line 16. Now if you recall the discussion
of iterators in section 7, a for loop is
just calling next for us. So each time I
press enter now, the for loop is
effectively calling next to get the next
value. Now because the first value's
already been returned before the loop
started - I just do this and finish it off -
we actually only go around four times, as
you can see there, and the list is
showing the output, only one, two, three
and four in this case, instead of the
zero which it showed last time, prior to
our changing the code to call the next
function on line 16. So if you worked out
that that's what would happen,
congratulations and well done. Now that
also explains why it can be a bad idea
to assign a generator to a variable, and
that's as we've currently got on line 13 - the
big underscore range equals
my underscore range, 5 in parentheses.
Alright, so at this point we've exhausted
all the values returned from our my
underscore range generator. So if we go ahead
and add some extra code to the program,
it won't actually do anything. So what
I'm going to do at this point, is comment
out all those input lines so we don't
have to press enter, moving forward,
so let's go and do that, and I'll indent
that one. Alright and there's also one on
line 22 - we'll comment that out as well.
Right now I've done that, what I'm going
to do is add some code. I'm going to add
some code after our prints, right down
the bottom of the program. So let's
going to do that, after our print
big underscore list. So on line 31
I'm going to do print double quotes
looping again ... or not.
Then we're going to do for i in big
underscore range
colon, then print parentheses double
quote i is, then left and right curly
braces dot format i. Alright, so if I run
that program now, you can see that
nothing happens in that final for loop,
looping again or not. This print isn't
executed - there's nothing showing on the
screen and the program has actually
exited. So storing my underscore range 5
in big range is fine, if you want to call
next each time you want a new value, but
it isn't a good idea if you intend using
it again in a for loop. So in that case,
you should just use the my underscore range 5
method function call direct again.
So we'd go ahead and change that then -
instead of for i in big underscore
range, we change that for i in my
underscore range, then five in
parentheses, which is the number we want
to pass to it. So we're calling the
function direct. Run that again and you
can see, in this case now, we're correctly
getting the output because we're not
using the variable - rather we're
actually using the function call. Alright,
so the output is now correct and
returning the right values. Now before I
finish this video, I should mention that
range does work if we store it. So I'm
going to undo that last change that we
added. Go back to big underscore
range. Then we're going to go ahead and
re-enable the code I commented out on line
12 - big underscore range equals range 5.
So go ahead and do that, then I'm going
to comment out the call to our function,
like so, and now that I've done that,
I want to actually delete this call,
this line 16, because we don't want to
call next on the range object, so I'm
going to delete that as well. And now
when we run it, you can see that in both
cases that's working fine, and the
range class behaves like an iterable. In
other words, it's reset each time it's
used, which wasn't the case when you used
a variable that actually called the
function that we actually wrote. So again,
the range class behaves like an iterable -
each time it's called,
it's actually reset. Now here my
underscore range isn't really very
useful, other than to show how to write a
generator, so in the next video we're
going to look at some more useful
generators. So I'll see you in that next video.