So just before we get
started with dictionaries.
I just wanted to give you a bit more of
an overview of what we're trying to do in
this section with sets and dictionaries.
So in previous sections we've seen how
lists can be used to store lists of
objects, and then we can actually
retrieve those objects by their index.
Which is of course the position.
In the list.
In lists it generally used
to store similar items.
Although you can store numbers and
strings in the same list if you can
think of a good reason for doing so.
Now lists are also ordered sequences so
as a result you can interact through
all the items on the list and
process them in order.
And of course,
we've done that in previous videos.
So in this section, we're going to
look at dictionaries and sets, and
they're both actually
unordered collections.
They both also guarantee that there will
be no duplicates in that collection.
Sets as similar to lists in that they're
actually intended for storing similar
items But you can't actually access
individual items using an index.
The set is unordered, so an index is
meaningless in the context of a set.
You find out more information
about that when we get to
the set videos in this section.
So dictionaries on the other
hand Are again unordered and
I can take key valued pairs.
Now the values again are not accessed
by an index but by means of a key.
So that's part and
parcel of discussing dictionaries.
It's gonna give us a good opportunity
to introduce two new string methods,
not only the split end joint.
So let's get into dictionaries.
So as I mentioned,
dictionaries aren't axis point index, but
they're accessed instead
by means of a key.
Probably the best way to give you more
information about this is to show
you an example.
I'm going to start typing and
we'll start with fruit equals orange.
A sweet orange citrus Fruit.
Apple.
Where I'm putting the colon,
good for making cider.
Lemon:a sour
yellow Citrus fruit.
We'll do a couple more.
Grape, a small sweet
fruit growing in bunches.
And the last one let's do lime.
[SOUND]
Sour,
green, citrus, fruit.
And so if I do a print fruit and
run that first.
So no real surprises there, it's just
duplicated what we've typing effectively.
But what we can do to access a particular
element, we can type print fruit,
remember we can't use an index number but
we can use the key.
So we can type lemon for argument's sake.
Noting that IntelliJ is automatically
telling us the elements as we're
typing it, so Apple grape or
stopping typing something [INAUDIBLE] so
it's pretty smart.
Looking at the dictionary
giving some options.
Type lemon there we run this.
We get a sour yellow citrus fruit.
So the key is lemon, and
the description of the information,
the value in other words,
is a sour yellow citrus fruit for lemon.
So as you can see we can access
individual items by their key by typing,
in this case, lemon, And
in terms of entering them, you can say
that we enter a list of keys and valleys.
And the key is separated by a colon.
Not a comma so it's the key.
You can see the orange, apple or lemon,
grape and lime in the keys colon.
And then there's the description or
the value.
Which is what is associated
with that particular key.
And again,
we can access individual keys and
individual values by the keys which
you saw me do on the screen there.
And probably now looking at this,
you can see that it's easy to see
why they are called dictionaries.
And you could use one to store a list
of words in their definitions for
argument sake.
And you can also use a dictionary to store
different types of information And then
this example I'm about to type in we're
gonna store information about a motorboat.
And what we're gonna do is we're
gonna create a new file for
this because we're gonna be coming
back to the fruit later in the video.
So I'm doing file>new.
Just making sure that's selected up here.
Project file>new Python, and
we'll call this one motorbike, and
for this one I'm going to paste in
a bit of code to save a bit of time.
So you can see what I've done there.
I've got the make as a key, the model
as a key, the color as a key, and
the engine size as a key, and
the value as you can see Honda.
250 dream, color is red and
engine size is 250 19.
Now, that is a number and not a string.
So, what we can do is then do a print,
bike, engine size, and
again, intemijay is helping us there quite
helpfully Pointing out the particular key.
And we go print bike color.
And if we're running this, remember that
because we've got two files open now,
we need to select over here
the relevant file we wanna run.
So [INAUDIBLE] but
that one will actually come up the first
time until we've run this at least once,
or what we can do is right-click in here,
Making sure that we clicked into the right
window, we can run motorbike and
you can see we get 250 and red.
So the engine size correctly comes
back as 250 and the color is red.
And now we'd be able to select both
options here, dictionary and motorbike,
'cuz we've run them at least once.
So as you can see here the values
themselves don't have to be the same type.
So what we can do is we can
store the engine sizes and
numbers that you saw in line one.
And the good thing about it is that you're
not limited to strings and numbers.
Values can be used with just
about any path or object.
Even another dictionary.
So this particular use of a dictionary
is like storing records about an object,
in this case, a motorbike.
And although we're storing
different types of data,
they're all related to a common object.
So the keys can be also
different types of object.
The only restriction is that
they must be immutable.
So we can't use a list for example as
a dictionary key but we can use as they
are of course which we found out in
previous videos, so let's go back to our
fruit, go back to our dictionaries.pie so
we can add to a dictionary.
So what we can do is we could type
something like fruit, pear equals.
An odd shaped apple.
Print fruit.
So if we do that run it make a drop
here by selecting the rock file this
[INAUDIBLE] it's called dictionary because
that is what I called it and run it.
We have a look now.
When we can see pair is in here now.
It's an odd shaped apple.
So that's a way to add
an entry to the dictionary.
And we need to do it that way because
unlike lists there's no method to insert
or append items in a dictionary.
As you can see what we did there we just
assigned a new value to the dictionary by
specifying the new key.
And giving it a value, and
the rest of it happens automatically.
Now, whether accessing a value or
adding a new entry, square brackets
are used after the dictionary name to
enclose the key, as you can see there.
So, in other words, if we're
printing it out, The case on line 8.
We're selecting the value
that we want to print out or
we're creating a new entry we need to put
the key in both cases in square brackets.
The other thing that we mentioned was
the keys in the dictionary are unique.
So if we assign a value to an existing
key you end up producing the value
Rather than adding another entry so
it's really important to understand that.
So,again if you assign a value
to an existing key we end up
replacing the value rather than creating
another entry or adding another entry.
So, going back to that [INAUDIBLE] that's
working we can talk fruit, pear, equals.
Great with tequila,
print fruit, if we run that.
You can see we've got pear,
an odd shaped apple, pear, great with
tequila at second time we ran it.
We actually over wrote the entry,
there's not two entries for pear in there,
there's only the one.
So there's one key but now there's now
an updated value, great with tequila.
I'll just fix that typo
now that I've seen it.
And probably being more realistic,
fruit lime is great with tequila.
I'm not too sure that pear is.
So again, the same example there.
Lime has been updated, as you can see on
the screen, to be great with tequila.
Now there's nothing to stop you for
reusing a key when you initially create
the dictionary and python won't
actually give you an error, but
the behavior will be the same as
assigning a new value to an existing key.
So the entry that appears last in
the list is the one that will appear
In your dictionary and what i mean
by that i come down here i can put
apple even though we got it found
on line two we can find it again
[INAUDIBLE] [INAUDIBLE] [INAUDIBLE]
You see when we run it,
you see apple has come around and crunchy
That was the last entry that was added
on line six which over-rode effectively
the one on line two or to be more
precise it just updated the value.
So the first time apple and the value
was created good for making cider but
when you go to this entry.
It just updated the value to be round and
crunchy.
And note again that Python doesn't
give you an error there at all.
But both and
Picham will actually give you a warning.
So if we come up here,
it actually does tell you.
It says dictionary contains
duplicate keys apple.
So even though you saw there's
no Python error as such, and
it doesn't crash the program or
anything like that,
you will actually get a warning from or
Picham about that, which is pretty neat.
And that's just another reason to
make sure you are checking these
markers on a regular basis cuz it
will help you in your programming
as we established in previous videos.
Now before we have to look at some more
ways we can make use of a dictionary
is a few more things
that we need to cover.
That's always useful to be able
to remove items from collections.
And to do that with a dictionary
use the del command.
So down here, for example, if we wanted
to delete lemon type del then we
enter the name of the key in brackets.
So for example,
lemon would remove that item.
So we can put a print under that
The last entry now when we run it,
shouldn't have a lemon there.
So we scroll this over,
you'll see we got lima, lemon, and
then lemon has disappeared
from the last line of output,
which was of the line of output that was
processed after We deleted it on line 14.
Now the del command is a lot
more powerful than that example
probably indicates on the screen.
So make sure you use it with care.
So if you forget to specify key to delete,
then it removes the entire dictionary and
we therefore get an error
when we try to print fruit.
So I went back here, commented that
out and just made that Del fruit.
We should get an error on the last line
because the entire dictionary no longer
exists because we've deleted it.
And you can see name
three is not defined and
it's because it not only totally
removed the contents of the dictionary,
it deleted the variable incompletely,
and that's why we're getting that error.
So, if you wanted to delete all
the entries in the dictionary but
still wanted to retain the dictionary
like effectively an empty dictionary so
you could start adding to later,
So, it doesn't count venera but
you use something different
you use fruit dot clear.
So, you type fruit dot clear like so.
So, if we run that, and
fully error at this time and
the contents have been deleted
effectively or cleared out.
So, it's now empty waiting for you to
process or manipulate it some other way.
So we now know how to create the
dictionary, we've added items to it, and
we've removed a single item, and
we've also cleared the entire dictionary.
And we've said one way to access the
individual item is by specifying the key,
but one problem with
accessing items by key occurs
when we try to retrieve
an item that doesn't exist.
So if you delete lines, so what I'm gonna
do is just delete these lines here, so
we have still got something to work with.
Those it so we still got some
items in our dictionary so
if we try to do a print to outside.
Knowing that hasn't made it
into a cage it doesn't exist.
>> [NOISE]
>> Plus you run that.
Key error tomato.
So it's basically saying the key doesn't
exist of key tomato doesn't exist
in the dictionary.
So this is something you may want to do.
You may want to do some testing to check
if a particular key is in the dictionary.
And unfortunately we can get around that.
There's a couple of ways we can do it.
What I'll do first is going to modify the
program slightly before reading the keys.
So let's go back up here.
I'm gonna remove the second entry
cuz we don't need that anymore.
And I'm gonna comment out this code.
And actually what I'll do is I'll
leave the last print in, print(fruit).
And let's create some code that allows
you to type in the name of the fruit,
and it will try and press us there.
So, we can type while, true, we're gonna
try and look it up in the dictionary.
We're gonna type dict_key,
dictionary key abbreviated.
Equals input please enter a fruit.
If the dictionary key is equal to quit,
we'll break.
So, that just allows us to get out
of the loop, but failing that,
it should mean that quit wasn't typed or
assigned description
To be equal to fruit.get(dict), and
that is using the dict function.
print(description).
And if you run that and
we enter in something like grape,
we get the answer to that.
If we enter another one like apple,
And not in the amount
that come up automatically quit
out of it makes it like so, So,
again is saw out of dictionary
retrieves the value for
specialized very similar to providing
the key to square brackets but
the great thing is it doesn't give
an era if the key doesn't exist.
So, instead it returns none as you
saw when I just pressed enter there.
And you can actually test for
that if you wanted to.
And you can actually confirm again
If I typed in something like
instead of just pressing enter
we still get come up with none.
Because it wasn't found for it to be
typed on the it actually works just fine.
So, actually taking it one step
further before we finish this video.
For the moment it's sharing
a respective that it's trying print
out the description, but
what we can do here.
We could do a test just
after here before we
set the description to see whether
it exists in the dictionary.
So we can type if dict underscore k
in fruit, so using the in keyboard.
Then and
only then are we gonna set description.
And print.
Otherwise we'll put else, print.
Don't have a dict_key, making sure you've
got your indentation levels correct here,
cuz obviously the code
won't work without that.
And of course I need to put
a colon there to fix it up.
So if I run that now and
I just type something like apple.
But if you type in something
like tomato Tomato.
We didn't have a tomato.
Cucumber, we don't have cucumber.
Enter.
We don't have so
I guess we could have tested for that.
We could have made sure that did top,
something it better but
we haven't done that so consequently
it's just printed out the empty string.
If we put something like apple,
which is valid.
Apple, lemon, you can see it's
printing those out quite nicely.
We can type quit to exit out like so.
So, I'm gonna end this video here now
cuz it's getting a little bit long,
as I mentioned.
In the next video I'll
continue exploring and
going into more detail
about Python Dictionaries.