ok so moving on with our blackjack program I've made a bit of a typo on line 24 it should read
embedded frame to hold the card images ok so moving on line 31 we are about
to do the player card frame now so we will just
type a comment about that so....
.....
.......
......
...so hopefully
you're following along with a lot of
this TKinter code now because we have
discussed a pretty well all of this in
previous videos so I just a bit more of
a complex interface we've created before
alright so next is the buttons so lets add a button frame so...
.....
......
....
.....
....so that's
the basic code done so the main windows
got three widgets the label at the top
to display the result and two frames one
below the other and I'll just bring up our
little
image again ok so here it is on the
screen again what I'm talking so the moment
as I said its got 3 widgets a label at
the top to display the result and it's
also got two frames one below the other
the top most of the two frames is gonna
contain the cards as you can see on the
screen there and as well as the scores for the
dealer and player and the one below that
will hold the buttons as you can see right down the
bottom the card frame itself contained
two other frames went one for the dealer
and one for the player as well as the
labels to hold the name as well as the score
so the card frame contains as I said another
two frames that will hold the cards and by
putting the card images into separate
frames starting a new game is easier
because we just have to destroy the
entire frame rather than trying to find
out each of the card in it and destroy them
separately so this will make more sense
when we come to do it so let's move onto
loading the card images so the file names of
the individual images are quite well
formed and made up of the card's value
when sweep followed by an underscore
so we can have a look at that we can
go into here and have a look now
so you can see that's the card number and underscore and then the sweep so
it means that we can pragmatically load these
in pretty easily so for the cards from
1 to 10
we can actually load that with a simple
loop to load them all in
now the face card images can be
retrieved using a second loop that runs
through a list of names these ones down here jack king queen etc
and by wrapping all that in
another loop that runs through the list
of sweep names all 52 card images can be
loaded and this is something that the
program will only have to do once but
I'm still going to create a function to
do it by placing this code in its
own function the main program is going to be far
less cluttered and more readable as a
result so let's go ahead and do that i'm
gonna come up here and start on line 9 and
make bit of a space and put our
function in their so we are going to call this load images so.....
.....
...because these will be ultimately be matching what's the what's
in the file name so....
.....
and remember earlier I mentioned about to
the TK version 8.6 is needed to use PNG
files we're gonna put a test in here so...
.....
...so now we need to create our first loop so.....
...remembering our range finishes one number
earlier so we starting it at 1 11 and we put....which is the subfolder remembering that
we add as sub folder to store the card files in or the came out of the
zip file like that and were going to use.....
.....
......
.....so that's going to be
the name that we need but now we need to retrieve it
so do....and the name is the name
that we've created on line 23 and then
we need to save it so....
....and then finished off we've
done that first bit of the loop we'll let hat loop finish and
then we do next the face cards......so from
their we are going to put.....and you remember face cards on line 12 jack king and queen so we need to
also get those so......and the same thing with
the replacement field.......
.....
...so we got the right type off image
depending on the version of tkinter and
then the same deal.....
......
.....
..so we've now got our load images function written and
that should now be able to retrieve all
those images we need for our game into
memory and just to note their that if you extracted
the images to a different folder than what I
did make sure you do change this first
part here cards / because that is going to be
looking at the current folder wherever that
is for the sub folder called cards and whatever the name of the
file is so make sure you do change that if you
put it in somewhere else so you need to
change both their on line 23 and also
on line 29 so the card list should after this contain a
list of tuples each tuples storing
the value and image each for one of the 52 cards
and the images have been loaded into
Tkinter photo image objects which are
fairly basic but do allow images to be
displayed easily that's what we need
to do here and what we're going to do is
right on the bottom add some code to
just to test that this actually works s
lets try doing so add some code so put....
......
...and will print cards to see what it actually happens and will just add our
main loop so....and we got an error here so what have I done their I didn't put a colon their so
put a colon and its pretty good and its complaining about 2 lines their so we'll add another line their to humour that so its
actually happy and this other error is probably relating to tkinter camel case that probably want an extra space in their as well probably a good idea to fix those while we can you can't fix this
first one up because that's got to do with
Python 2 so we'll leave that at that so
if we run this now we should be able to get something it won't be very
exciting but we can at least demonstrate
that things are actually working and if we tab over to our interface its obviously not working yet
because we haven't added the cards
so close it down but we should be able to confirm
that we got our various objects in here and
you can see this multiple objects that
are the loaded so assuming it has work we'll just have to print out
the cards or display them =to
confirm that they've been loaded but it
seems to have loaded into the list
which is good so a new deck of cars can
be created from the cards list now we imported them then we can shuffle them using
the shuffle function from the
random module that we imported remember
we did that in the previous video so the
program will also need to store the
cards dealt to each player so before we
start creating the functions to make all
of this work
I'm going to initialize a dealer hand player hand list we might do that and might
finish of this video and continue on to the next one so after here we can type.....
.....
....
...its gonna sort of shuffle them in a random order which is
obviously what we want we don't our cards coming
out in any sort of order the whole idea
is that we don't know what the next card is coming
it's entirely random we want to create the lists to store
dealers and players hand so...so just
before I finish this video just a couple
of other things to note on line 73 I
used the list function to create a
new list from the cards and if I've done
something different for example if I hadn't change that code and made this instead
commenting that out and make that....which is another way of doing it
deck would then be exactly the same list
as cards so that's not necessarily a
problem when just shuffling but as the
cards are dealt they may be removed from the
list which could cause problems so every
game will then have fewer and fewer cards
until their are none left to create new
decks from so we definitely don't want to do it
that way we want to create a new
and separate list which is the way we've done on
lines 73 so I'm going to finish the
video here now in the next video we're
gonna go ahead and write some code to
deal the card we are gonna deal cards to the
players each time the button is click so we need a
function called deal_card
and we'll work on that in the next video