Let's talk about while loops in this
video. Python provides two main ways to
loop around a block of code; for loops
and while loops. We've seen how a for loop
can be used to iterate through an
iterable. In our examples we use the
items in a sequence and the numbers in a
range. Sometimes we need to keep looping
as long as some condition is true and
stop when it becomes False. We do this
using a while loop. So the basic form is
while condition : execute block of code.
The condition can be anything that can
evaluate to True or False, and so long as
the condition is True, the code in the
loop will be executed. When the condition
becomes False, the loop terminates.
Alright, so I think a few examples will help here.
Let's create a new Python
file. We'll call this whileloop.py.
Alright so I'm going to start here by
using a while loop to do the same as the
for loop that we've seen in previous
videos. Firstly, I'm gonna type in the
original loop, so it's for i in range
parentheses 10 colon print parentheses
double quotes i is now, left and right
curly braces dot format
and i in parentheses. Then we've got two closing
right parentheses there. Remember that
the starting value of a range is
optional and will default to zero if not
specified. You should be able to work out
what this code will do before running it.
So when I do run it now, you can see the
output down the bottom - we've got the
values zero through nine. Alright so I'm
going to comment that code out,
and we're gonna start instead on line four
and we're going to use a while loop to do
the same thing. So I'm gonna type i
equals zero on line four. Next line while
i is less than 10 colon, then print
indented parentheses double quotes i is now.
We've got left and right curly braces,
format then i in parentheses, then our two
closing right parentheses. Then
we'll put i plus equals 1. Okay.
So there's our code. So line seven just adds
one to the current value of i,
and basically, that line is identical to
this line, i equals i plus 1. Now we're
going to talk about this later in this
section. The code on line seven is
preferable to the code on line eight, and
I want you to see things written in the
best way whenever possible. Alright so
I'm going to delete line eight.
What I'm also going to do now is set a breakpoint
on line five before running the code in
the debugger. Now i is bound to the value
zero on line four and the debugger is
going to be stopped on line five. Let's
do that. We'll run the debugger, and you
can see we stopped on line five there.
If we click over to the console tab,
we'll see the output as we step through
the code. So we run line five ready to
test if the value of i is less than 10.
We can see that it is, so if we step over,
it takes us to line 6. We're gonna step over
again to print the value of i. The value
of i is now printed in the console. So
we're now on line seven, as you can see.
So this is that strange way of increasing
the value of i that I just mentioned.
Watch the value of i that's shown on
line four as I step over again.
1 is being added to i. It now has the value of
1, 0 plus 1 is 1. So we're still less than
10, so if we step over again, it takes us
back to line 6. Step over once more to
print the value and we move to line 7.
Alright so we're now on line 7. That's
going to add 1 to i again which should
give us the value 2. We should also go
back to line 5 to loop again. Notice that
I'm not mindlessly clicking the step
over button. When you're using the
debugger like this to understand your
code, make sure you stop on each line and
work out what's going to happen. As I
said earlier, we're learning to become
programmers, not mindless button clickers.
Alright so let's see if we were right.
Step over, and i does have the
value 2 and we have gone back to line 5.
Next time we go around the loop we
should get the message i is now 2 printed
out, and i will be increased to 3 and
after that happens we'll get back to
line 5.
I'm going to use resume program over
here this time. If you prefer to step
over a few more times then go ahead and
do that. You don't need to watch me
clicking the button repeatedly. Pause the
video frequently if you do need to catch
up, and if I click on machine program now, we
have got i is now 2 printed and we can
see that I has been incremented to 3. Resume
program again, i is now 4. I'm going
to click on the resume program 5 more
times until i has the value 9 and we're
back on line 5. Now things are going to get
interesting, so I'm going to come over here and
use step over once more to print
the value of i. So I'm going to step over
here, i is now 9, and when I step over one
more time to execute line 7, we're back
on line 5 with i having the value of 10.
10 isn't less than 10. That means the
condition on line 5 will be False now
and we'll exit the loop. Because there's
no more code in the program that means
the program should terminate. So let's
see if we were right. I'm going to click
step over one more time to execute
line 5, and you can see that has in fact
happened. The program has now terminated.
And we were right - there's no more
output from our code and we get the
message: process finished with exit code
zero produced by the IDE. Notice that our
programs output appears in black and
messages from the IDE normally appear in
blue. It sometimes uses red for errors
and other important information.
Alright so that's a while loop. As we saw, a
while loop will continue to loop, as long
as the condition evaluates to True. When
the condition evaluates to False, the
loop terminates and execution continues
with the code after the loop. We don't
have any more code, so the program
terminated as well. Alright I'll stop
the video here and in the next one we'll
look at a few more things about while loops.
See you in the next video.