so moving we now need to start creating
some functions that will ultimately
drive the game so we are gonna start out by
just dealing cards to the players each
time the button is clicked so we need a
function called deal_card after
the load images functions so gonna come up
here their is our load images after that gonna
start putting the code in their so putting 2 spaces as we have to do between 2 functions and start with
.....so first thing we need to pop
the next card off the top of the deck that's
gonna be the one that the card the
player's gonna get so...
......
.....
...so the functions got a
single parameter which you can see on
line 35 and that's the frame that the
image should be displayed on now up until
now we placed all the widgets using the
grid manager when it comes to adding the
card images a pack manager is a much
simpler one to use as you add new ones to the left
they just stack up against the ones already
there so in this case for cards its obviously
perfect every time we add a cards its gonna be
stacked now generally speaking its
a very bad idea to mix grid and pack in the same window and the Python 3
compiler will give an error if you try but it is ok to use the pack manager in its own window now as every
widget is a window packing the images into this frame is
fine as long as we don't try to add
anything else to the frame using grid now we had a good look at list at
one of the earlier section but we didn't look
at the pop method that we are using on line
37 now pop is a way to retrieve an item
from a list that also removes it from the
list at the same time so think about
it just the opposite of append now
append adds an item at the end of the
list
pop takes an item from the specified
position in the list
defaulting to the end if the position to be
taken from is not specified by
specifying position 0 we can take cards
from the top of the deck both insert and
pop can also be used with an index to add
an item at the specified position or remove
one from the specified position but if we
started popping cars from the middle of
the deck the players will not be very happy
with the dealer now once the next card
has been retrieved from the deck the
function creates a Tkinter label in the
frame that's passed into the function
and sets its image to the photo image
stored in the next card tuple the
label is then pack against the left side of the
frames so that all cards should stack up
against each other from left to right as
they are being added so the newest one is to the left
now the function then returns the next card tuples so
that whatever it is calling it can also
check
the face value of the card so that's
the function to deal a card we also need to link
up the function to the buttons now we briefly saw in the videos introducing TKinter
but the only button we actually got
working was the cancel button now
a function is associated with a widget
using the command property so it might be
tempting to come down here to look at
the code on line 72 and maybe add
something along the lines of....
so in a earlier tkinter
video I mention to you that you have
to be very careful when setting up the
command property of widgets the value
that you assigned has to be the
function you want to be executed when
the button is clicked now you definintey don't
want to call the function instead of assigning
the command and that's actually what
I've done here....and
that's what I've actually done here by
attempting to pass the frame to the
function at the same time as assigning the
function of the button so the actual
correct code would be.....
....but of course that's now
introduced another problem because
there's now no way to specify the frame
parameter that the function actually
needs and in fact that's true there's
really no way to pass a parameter when a
assigning a function in this way so if
you include the parenthesis after
the function name then what you're doing
is you're assigning the result of calling
the function rather than assigning the
functions itself and obviously we want to assign
the function here so that it actually
executed or called when the button is
clicked now if you don't use parentheses and
you can't specify an argument to a
functions so it sounds like a catch 22
well thing is we've only got two buttons so the approach that we're going to take here is
to create one function for the dealer
and one for the player and assign them
to the corresponding button now this is not the
only approach and for something like the
calculator that's got loads of buttons
it wouldn't be a suitable solution it wouldn't
be practical and I'll be looking at other
ways to deal with this later in the
course but for now what we gonna do is
just create two functions so gonna add
this
after the code that we've just added to deal card
so the first one is gonna be....
...so you can see what we've done their is
we've just created another function
that's gonna call the function that we
need with the required parameter being the dealer or the player card frame depending on
which method we actually called either dealer or
deal_player so now that we actually
done that we can actually connect the
buttons so we come back down here and where we've
got on line 80 text = dealer and I'll add an extra space
their to keep it happy and that should now be
...removing the parenthesis because again
we're assigning the function so that
will be executed when the button is
actually clicked and down here on line 83
we are gonna do the same....again
minus the parenthesis
so now we've done that the program should now runs so lets try giving it a go
you can see its working dealer and player...and
we could keep doing that and notice it does seem to be
in random order so it was
correctly shuffled and if we just go a bit wider you can see they are still being added and one thing I
haven't done is change the minimum and
maximum size at the moment  it's actually
going a lot wider than what would normally
like it to be but will look at fixing that in
the next video for now the code is
actually working and it is actually
adding a new card every time you click
on it which is pretty awesome and if we
kept going actually I'm not going to do that now
but if we did get to 52 the program will end up
creating an error when there's no more
card stack because of course it can't
deal anymore card if their is no more left for the deck and that's
because attempting to pop an item from
an empty list isn't allowed now as the
maximum number of cards a player can be
dealt without going bust is 11 that's
4 aces 4 2's and 3 3's it wouldn't ordinarily in a
single game we don't need to worry about all the
cards being dealt and so we can
actually ignore that error for now so the
next thing we want to do is to calculate
the players scoring and display it in the
frame and we'll look at doing that in the next
video