Alright, so continuing on from the last
video, make sure you've still got the while
loop.py program open in your
editor. So we've got a while loop on
lines five through three seven, and you can see
that it's functionally identical to the
for loop that I commented out on the
lines one and two. If you've programmed
in C or Java, that while loop is how a
for loop really works in those languages.
They both compile to the same code.
That's not true in Python. Although we're
getting the same result, the two loops
are doing very different things behind
the scenes. I mention that because you
wouldn't use a while loop just to iterate
through a range of values, but it did
provide a good example to see what's
going on. Before we look at more
realistic examples of while loops,
there's a couple of things I want to say
about this one. We've seen that the
condition i < 10 controls
execution of the block of code in the
loop. As long as i is less than 10 the
code will be executed. Once i becomes
equal to or greater than 10, the
condition becomes False and the loop
terminates. So that leads to two other
important things to consider. First, the
condition must be initialized before the
loop starts. With the for loop, we just
used i without setting a value first.
Python knows to give it the first value
from the range and continue from there.
With the while loop though, we have to
give i a value first and we do that on
line 4. If we hadn't, we'd get an error
that i is not defined. The second thing
is that we need some way within the loop,
for the condition to become False. So
remove the indentation, as I'm doing here,
before i plus 1, then we'll run the
program again. We run the program.
Now because we're not increasing i
inside the loop, the condition never
becomes False and the loop will keep
running forever. And we need to go up to
the run menu in IntelliJ and choose stop to
stop this.
I could have clicked on the little red button
to the left, as well. Now if you're using idle,
control C will stop the program as well.
When we stopped incrementing i in the
loop, there's no way for the condition to
become False, so the loop just kept going,
as you saw. We could just as well,
in that scenario, have written
the loop as follows:
while True, as you can see there, and that
would get us the same undesirable
situation. In some of our other examples,
you will see loops that just use
True as the condition, but the body of
the loop will then contain a way to
break out of the loop. It's easier to see
why our for loop is preferable in this
case. The codes on lines 1 &amp; 2 are easier
to understand and there's less chance of
introducing an error. There are many
reasons for looping around a block of
code that don't involve just carry
through items in a sequence. For example,
in an adventure game, players have to
choose a direction in order to exit from
a location. If they don't choose one of
the available exits, they stay where they
are, and that's an ideal use of a while
loop. So lets create a new file here.
We're gonna call this one adventure.py.
Alright, we're gonna start by typing available
underscore exits is equal to square brackets
and in double quotes, north,
double quote comma. We're going to do
south, east and west all in double quotes,
separated by commas. We've got our right
square bracket on the right hand side.
Line three, chosen underscore exit equals
and two double quotes, meaning an empty
string. Now our while loop is going to be
while chosen exit not in available exits
colon, and indented on the next line,
chosen underscore exit is equal to input
parentheses double quotes
Please choose a direction
colon space then we've got our double
quote and right parenthesis. Then on line
seven print and double quotes in
parentheses, aren't you glad you
got out of there. So in this particular room
in the game, the available exits are in
the available underscore exits list;
north, south, east and west. In order to
enter the loop at all, we have to
initialize chosen underscore exit to a
value that isn't in the list. We could
have used anything except one of
those directions, but an empty string
makes sense here. Because an empty string
is not in the list, the condition
evaluates to True and the program enters
the loop. And it's a very simple loop -
it just requests input from the player,
and assignes what they type to the
chosen underscore exit variable. The
loop then tests the condition again. If
the direction they typed is not one of
the ones in the list, then the code block
and the loop is executed again. This
continues until they type one of the valid
directions and escape. So if you run the
program now, and we'll enter various
strings when prompted to see what
happens. I'm gonna start by entering up.
Now that's not in the list so we get the
input prompt again, down, also not in the
list. Then we go around the loop again.
Then when I enter east here, the condition
evaluates to True and we leave the loop
One of the important features of while
loops is that they can be used when you
can't determine, in advance, how many
times you will need to loop. A for loop
will repeat for each item in a
predetermined sequence, whereas with a
while loop you don't need to know how
many times the loop will execute.
One particular application of this is
reading data from a file or an internet
stream. It's difficult, not impossible but
difficult, to know in advance how much
data there is to read. A while loop can be
used to keep reading until there's no
more data left. And we'll see this soon
when we look at file I/O, input and
output, in Python.
In the next video, we'll look at break
and continue with while loops.
See you in the next video.