All right so it's time
to start breaking some things.
What we're gonna do first is start
by deleting the accounts.sqlite in the project pane.
On Windows, you'll get an error
if you've got any tables open in the database viewer,
but it's a good idea to close them on a MAC and Linux too.
Let's just close those two down.
Delete accounts.sqlite.
We're just gonna run the rollback.pi again
just to make sure that both tables contain
predictable data after all the changes
that we've been making.
All right, you can see that's been created again there
in the project pane.
The history table has a composite key
made up of the time and account columns.
The combination of these two columns must be unique.
An easy way to simulate an error here
is to try and save a transaction
with the same time and account
as one that already exists.
That's actually easily done and the way to do that
would be to modify our current time method
to return the same number each time.
Let's start by deleting these two commented out lines.
We'll comment out also this first line
then what we'll do is we'll just return one.
We're gonna run the programme again
without clearing out any values.
Now the current time's returning one in every case.
If we run it, we actually get an error.
When we try to get a new history row
with the same time and account
as a row that already exists,
we get a Sql3 integrity error
because the primary keys are composite made up of
time and account and as we've established,
primary keys must be unique.
We have a look there, and we'll have a look at our data
so we're going to open up to the tables again.
Accounts and then History.
We'll have a look and see what's happened here.
First thing under accounts,
that's probably not as bad as it could be.
John's balance is now 2010
and there's a corresponding entry
if we have a look in history
which should be of 1010 as you can see there.
The database still tallys so that's a good thing.
The reason for that is because by default,
nothing gets persisted to the database
until it's committed and the crash happened
before the commit line.
Before the commit line call which I think is on line 41.
This one here.
The crash happened before that.
The new balance for the first deposit of 10
wasn't actually written to the database.
Of course our programme did crash
and that's not a good thing.
Let's see if we can avoid a crash.
You're gonna wrap the database updates in a try block.
We're gonna start here just before the db.execute.
Try and we want to add those two lines.
Indent them.
Then we want to type except.
It's going to be squlite3.Error.
If we do get an error,
we want to do a db.rollback.
Otherwise, we're gonna put finally
db.commit.
Just space it out a little bit
so we can see it a little bit easier.
What we're doing here is we're protecting
our database updates with a try block.
If there's an error, we're using
the connexions rollback method.
This one here on line 44
to rollback any updates that were pending
or that are pending.
Here we're getting an exception
when we run this code, or we will be
when we try to update the history table.
What this ensures is that the changes to the accounts table
which had already taken place on the previous slide,
this update here on line 41,
we ensure that they don't take place either.
If there's no error,
the finally block executes the db.commit is executed
and both updates the accounts table and the history table
are updated.
I'm using the word updated to mean any change,
even though one of the changes or the updates
is an insert.
Let's actually see how this behaves.
I'm going to run it again.
This time we haven't got an error.
That's a good thing.
The try is has obviously caught the error.
If we have a look at the history table again, we refresh.
On accounts we do a refresh as well.
You can see nothing's been updated this time
which is what we wanted because we've got an error
with that transaction record in history
because of the way that we modified
our current time method to always return one.
That's how you go about rolling back transactions
when you need to make sure that a series of updates
all take place and that the database itself
isn't updated if one or more of the updates fails.
There's still a problem here though.
Also I can almost hear you asking
why do we have to roll back the transactions
if commit isn't being called.
I'll deal with the problem first.
Looking at the accounts table,
notice John's balance.
However when I come down here and have a look at his balance
it's showing $30.10.
We've got 2010 in the accounts table
and $30.10 showing in the run window.
Looking at our code,
you can see one of the problems that we've got here
is that the balance attribute,
it's the last line here on line 48,
that's updated whether the data
is saved successfully or not.
We can't actually put that line into the finally block
because finally executes whether
there's an exception or not.
This is a great time to use the else clause.
What we really should do there
is change this to put except
and after the rollback,
you do an else and that's where we put this code,
the updated balance.
Else has to go after all exception clauses
but it has to go before the finally clause.
Let's just try running that again.
Hopefully we've got it working correctly now.
We've now got the correct balance showing there, $20.10.
Of course that equates to the accounts balance here
of 2010 which of course is an integer.
Dividing by 100, we get the $20.10 here.
That's now showing itself correctly which is good.
In fact, looking at this code,
really the db.commit should also go in the else block.
We got away with putting it in the finally block
because the transaction will have already been rolled back
when there's an error and calling commit
when there's no transactions to commit
doesn't actually do anything.
I started off writing it with a finally block
because try and finally are often talked about together
and you'll hear programmers referring to try finally blocks.
Doing it that way is something
that people will often do at first,
especially if they're used to other languages
such as Java.
If I don't do that, another bad habit if you like
is to update the balance attribute inside the try block.
Something like this.
I'll just copy this temporarily.
Something putting it in there.
That would be some code you'd probably see.
That would work fine, but if there's an exception raised
by either of the database update statements,
the code to update the balance won't be reached.
It's not wrong as such,
but really you should limit the code inside a try block
to just the code you want to protect.
This is an excellent demonstration of why Python
provides an else clause.
If the code to update the balance crashes,
the database updates will be rolled back.
Even though they worked, they would leave the database
in a perfectly consistent state.
I know that the assignment to the balance attribute
didn't crash the programme,
but it could be a function to call or some other code
that might crash and consequently it really does
belong in the else clause.
I'm gonna undo that change.
We'll now get rid of the finally clause
and perform the commit in the else instead.
Like so.
In fact, to be consistent we should really
swap those lines around.
We should put the commit before
the attribute balance update.
That's because if commit fails,
we don't want to store the new location in the attribute.
That brings us to the question now,
why do we have to roll back the transactions
if commit isn't being called?
Let's just update accounts table,
or refresh it rather.
Make a note of John's balance here which is 2010.
I'm gonna delete the last row, TerryG
and update the database.
I'm gonna go back and run our programme again.
Come back and have a look at accounts.
We should be able to see that TerryG's record has been added
and you can see that it was there.
Let's see how that works if we comment out
the rollback method call.
I'm just going to comment that out.
We'll need something else in the except clause
so I'm just going to add a pass for now
just to keep the compiler happy.
If I run this again,
come back to accounts and do a refresh.
I'm going to delete the TerryG record again,
update it, back to rollback.pi.
Going to run it again.
Come back to accounts and refresh.
You can see what's happened here.
We've actually got an incorrect balance now.
The balance is now showing as 1980
which is 30 less than it should be.
Obviously we do need to roll back those transactions
to make sure that doesn't happen.
Why?
Why, why, why?
You've probably noticed that I don't ask questions like this
unless I already know the answer.
This time I'm going to break with tradition
and not tell you, not just yet anyway.
It's time right now for a challenge.
What happened and why is the balance showing
as 30 less than it should be?
A good approach to solving this challenge
is to read through the code
and take the place of the computer.
Quote unquote, execute each statement,
and work out what's happening at each point.
These days, there are debuggers that will do it for you.
Each line is executed, and you can examine the contents
of all the variables to check the state
of the programme at each step.
Debuggers can be very useful
for tracking down really obscure bugs,
but using them can be very time consuming.
They can come in very handy
for things like loops that go round
hundreds or thousands of times,
because doing that manually is just impractical.
Like most tools, you'll make far better use of them
if you understand the manual process
that's being automated.
Reading code and understanding what's happening at each step
is invaluable.
The more you do it, frankly the better and faster
you get at it.
Give it a go and remember that our insert statement
will always raise an exception
because the primary key already exists.
If you run the programme again,
remember to delete TerryG's record
in the accounts table before running the programme each time.
The problem doesn't occur if all the records
already exist in the database.
See if you can solve this challenge
and figure out why the account balance is 30 less
than what it should be.
Pause the video, I'll see you when you get back.
How did you get on?
Did you manage to figure that out?
Firstly, you should hopefully have noticed
that John's balance attribute never actually gets updated.
That's because the else clause
doesn't get a chance to execute.
In other words, every time the save update method is called,
the balance is always the same.
The next thing to note is that the command
to update the balance column of the accounts table
executes each time we make a deposit or withdrawal.
Basically Terry, Graham, Eric and Michael's account balances
are also retrieved into accounts class instances.
The balance attribute starts off at 2010 and doesn't change.
When this first deposit here on line 82 is attempted,
the new balance becomes 3020
and this is written to the accounts table.
The update isn't committed,
but the transaction is rolled back
so that update is still pending.
The code raises an exception
so we quit the save and the update method
and move on to the deposit of 10 cents on line 83.
The balance attribute at this point
is still 2010 so the new balance becomes 2010 plus 10
which is 2020 and that's written to the accounts table,
but not committed.
At this point, there's now two pending updates
in the accounts table.
When the code continues execution on line 84,
it attempts the second deposit of 10 cents,
it has the same result.
There's now three pending updates,
each one will replace the balance columns value
that would have been stored by the previous update.
Next the code continues onto line 85,
attempts to withdrawal 30 cents from the balance of 2010.
That also fails, but now there's a fourth pending update
of the balance column.
Then the next few lines are largely irrelevant.
We're attempting, each one retrieves the details
from the database so we've got
Terry, Graham, Eric, and Michael's code
that is retrieving the data
from the account class instances.
They have no effect on the state of the database
nor on John's account instance
so we can safely ignore them.
That brings us now to TerryG,
remembering that we deleted that entry
from the accounts table.
The code in the inept method
is consequently called for this particular entry.
It inserts a new row into the accounts table
and, this is the important bit,
commits all pending transactions
by calling the cursor.connection.commit method.
As well as storing TerryG's details,
our four pending updates at that point
are also committed.
Each value is saved in the accounts table
and is then overwritten by the next pending transaction.
Consequently we end up with a balance
from the 30 cent withdrawal being the final one stored.
That's why the balance is 30 less than it should be.
It may not have been obvious,
but unless you roll back a database transaction,
it's still in there waiting to be committed.
Unless you knew exactly where to look,
using a debugger to detect that problem
would have been far from easy.
That's because the database wasn't updated
until right at the end
so checking the contents of the accounts table
each time around wouldn't have revealed anything useful.
I definitely recommend developing the ability
to step through code manually.
You can make that easier by adding print statements
to print out the values of variables
at various points in the code,
and you'll find detecting and fixing bugs much easier
when you can read code and step through it like this.
It does take time to get the hang of it,
but the more you practise, the better you get at it.
Strange as it may sound, manually stepping through the code
is actually often far quicker than using a debugger.
Before I finish this video,
we better put that rollback back in.
I'm gonna come back up here
to our save method,
our save and else or update method
and we're just going to uncomment the rollback
and delete the pass we no longer need.
Of course the other thing we want to do
is make sure we remove the code here
so that our current time method
is actually returning a valid UTC time.
Let's go back and delete the TerryG record again.
Update it.
Run our programme again.
Refresh and we've got it doing the right thing.
Obviously it's a little bit weird there,
but it did actually correctly add 1000
to the 2980 existing balance.
If you really wanted to be sure about this,
we could just go back to ensure it's working
as it's been working previously.
Delete all the entries.
Same for the history.
Delete all those, commit the change.
Run the code again.
Come back to accounts, refresh.
It's looking like it was.
Do a refresh.
I didn't delete those.
Let's do the right thing this time.
Delete them this time
and just to be sure I'll delete the accounts
and our table entries.
We updated both of those.
This is what I was trying to do last time.
Run it.
History, refresh.
We're now going to have four entries which is correct.
If you refresh that, we've got our correct balances.
All right?
That's that.
I hope you got a lot out of that.
I'll see you in the next video.