so what we need to do now is implement the deal_ dealer function now this
turns out to be very similar to the deal_player function but because
the players turn has finished by the
time the dealer gets more cards what we
can do here in this function is we can
add a bit of extra code to check to see
who is actually won the game because of
course the only check we got at the moment
is on line 69 to check to see whether
the dealer wins so we need see whether the
player wins as well we need more details
in addition to that because the moment
we are only really basically checking to
see at the moment if the players busted if the
scores greater than 21 could be a situation of
course we're both a dealer and the player got
cards less than 21 we need to do
that check as well as well as checking
to see whether the dealer is busted so lets make a start so go up here and start
typing....
...and we need to add the score so dealer.....
....and then we
want to show that on the screens so.....
.....and we now need to do some
checking to see whether it's game over
so what we want to do first is get the players score
again so....
....so what is the score for the
player currently then would need to do
some testing here to see who's won or if anyone has won so.....
....
...which may already been set on line 76 but we gonna put it
here anyway just in case we need to
put...
....so either way the
dealer is lost in this situation then the
player won so put.....
.....
...so we already establish
the both the player and the dealer
haven't gone busted at this point
because we've done those checks on line 66
and 68 so we know that they're both
less than 21 so now we are
doing a test to see whether the dealer
score is greater than the player score
then we are going to put....
....can you think what that
last possibility is well the last
possibilities is a draw we've done everything else we've done all the tests to see whether both the player and the
dealer had gone bust or whether the
players score or the dealer score is
greater than 21 or the dealer scorer is less than players score so we have determined that
the player can win as well and anything
left to do is going to be a draw so......
....because obviously if both score is the same if it gets to this
point that should be our method so it's
really quite simple no matter what the
dealers score is if the player went bust
and the dealer wins so that's the
first condition tested if the players
not bust the player wins if their score
is higher than the dealer or the dealer
went bust and obviously we get down
that last else on line 72 any outcome means a draw
alright so we should have the basis for a
game here so lets run this and see what it does
so let's see whether it actually works
we are gonna put dealer well will actually do the player first the
players got an 11 an ace which is
scored 11 which
is correct for the first ace dealer its got a 10 and according this the player has won
and we continue on player dealer and its still not quite working at this
stage but we've got the basis on here its
actually doing some basic calculation
but obviously we need we still need to
do a bit of work here because when we first
started it and I'll just run it again player dealer we are getting a message immediately that
the dealer wins because the score was
greater than the players so its a lil bit
disconcerting that because that message shouldn't really
be appearing until the dealer has finished
playing or player has gone bust so it's correct it's actually processing this
function correctly but we need to
actually put an extra condition in to
have the game go as far as it can before it actually
showing who wins so I guess it'd be
more accurate to say that deal is
winning so far this point in time click on
player again and obviously we got a bit of work here to do still so let's go ahead and continue
looking at this so one advantage of
creating functions that perform specific
tasks is that they can be used whenever
you need the functionality that they
provide and we saw an example of
that with score_hand which we
used in a number of places which
is pretty handy that we only written that
code once and we are able to call it multiple
times so in the main program we really
don't want the dealer to play they turn as their initial cards are dealt we just
just want them to deal a card and stored
in their hands so what we gonna do is
make a change their go down to the bottom so after
here after the deal_hand we
are setting up those entries to be empty
where we are starting after that we want to put.....so
the player gets the first card automatically and.....
....
..so what we want to deal player again so we want to deal first basically the player is gonna get two cards which
is how blackjack works and the dealer
is going to have one and if we run that
again lets see what that looks like so its definitely getting better now we haven't got any initial scores showing up we got the
correctly showing the player score to be 13 we got a problem here though the
dealer score is showing 0 for some
reason so it could be a bug or something
that we've introduced here because the dealer score should be
calculated and it should actually initially
be 9 so its getting better but its still not
correct yet because the person playing the
game has to click the button for each of
the dealers cards and once we clicked it
then incorrectly does the score but it didn't do
that initially but we wouldn't
ordinarily want that to happen the
computer should really play the part of
the dealer and all the player should do is
click their own button for more cards or
click dealer button once they want to stick
so the deal_dealer function
that's called when the dealers
button is clicked will need to score
the dealer's hand which only has a
single card to begin with and then
automatically keep dealing more cards until
the dealer score is greater than or equal
to 17 or the dealer goes bust and once
that has happen the score are then check and
the results are displayed so let's go back
and make a change to the code for that on deal_dealer function so we
got the dealer score calculated correctly so
what we gonna do is I'm going to temporarily
cut that because we're gonna put that
back on some code in a minute so the dealer
score so its calculated at first then
what we want to do is put.....
....
...so in other
words basically what a dealer score is 0 or less
than 17 and remember we establish the
rules that if scores less than seventeen
the dealer would
automatically grab another card and that is what
we do with that code
and then the other thing we need to do is after we've
appended we then calculate the score again so come back
down here will copy this bit of code put that in
there and then we actually show the score
on the screens so basically what
happened is we got to deal_dealer
it should automatically keep dealing
cards for us until it gets to score of
17 or higher and obviously it could still bust and
then the rest of the code will be executed
on line 67 down and we can establish
whether there's been a win or a loss and
the reason on line 61 were actually
calculating the score there is we are
dealing with the the score for the card
that's initially dealt when we first
start because you saw that when I ran this the previous time the dealer score
showing a 0 so that's why we are calculating that score first and then were actually
adding the score each time another cards dealt
so looking down the code we've got the
code down here so we got deal_player which draws the player card deal_hand
.append which actually called the dealer_card function to
deal the first card of the dealer and then we deal the card for the player again
so what should happen now is that
we'll see two cards for the player and
two cards or more for the dealer
depending on what the score was so lets try running
then see what happens
so now when we click dealer you notice how it went through and automatically selected the extra cards so
what basically won the game at that point and we got
no play again button at the moments so we need to
stop and start again and run again you can
see the dealer has got 18 compared to 9
now its still not really working correctly
because what we really need to do is
change this run it again so basically its the
wrong button that I'm actually pressing so we got the score
their players got a score of 19 at the
moment so if we want another card we
click on player to get another card and obviously we didn't get a bust we got to 21 so the dealer now when we click
the dealer button once and it's going right
through and finish the dealer shot and
that's really the point I was making the
player wins because we've got to
seventeen you remember the score has to be less than 17 otherwise it would keep
dealing another card so we got to 17 at that
point we actually won so will try it
again ok we got a score of 16 we are gonna click on player
again to get another card and obviously
we've gone bust so we gone over 21 so the
dealer has correctly won their so
that's good that's also working run it
again
just run it a few more times to make sure
it's working correctly
we got a score of 14 lets click on trying another
card we get to 20 which is good so let's
now click on dealer and see what the
dealer does the dealer got to 25 and the dealer
busts so player wins
ok try it again and see what I hope we can
get a draw here just to confirm that's
working as well so player got a score of 14 player I've busted the dealer wins that's correct
ok score of 17 I'm gonna hold on that so click on dealer and
the dealer wins with a score of 21 so I'll
try one more time to see whether we can
happen to get a draw but you can see all the other are working
now so run that one more time
with a bit of luck will get the score being equal so
we got a score 15 I'm gonna stick to that
so I'm just going to click on a dealer and
the player wins because the dealer bust so
I won't do that but basically the code
should work for the draw we've seen all
the other scenarios what seems to be
working correctly which is great so the
programs now playing a
reasonable game of blackjack and all the
dealing is being taken care of by the
computer so it's a bit annoying having
to close the window and run the program
again though for a new game and I think
it's about time for challenges so will
talk about that and also talked about
will also go through one more time about some
global variables comments that you might find
interesting and then work on a challenge
and the challenges is gonna be for
you to come up with a new game button start
a new game so we don't have to stop and
start the game each time like you've
seen me do so we will look at doing that in the
next video