And if you looked at the Python source code
in the past, you may have come across functions
or methods with the parameters *args and **kwargs.
Now usually pronounce star-args and star-star-kwargs
or KW-args, depending on how you want to pronounce it.
Now they look horrible, but they're actually quite simple
once you know what they are.
And more to the point, they're also very powerful
and can give your functions and methods
a lot of flexibility.
Okay, so I don't want to mess up our jukebox programme,
so I'm gonna create a new Python file to demonstrate this.
We're gonna call that star_args.
All right, let's enter some code
and then have a look at what's going on.
I'm gonna type print, left parentheses,
a couple quotes, hello, then ending double-quotes,
comma, space, and then double quotes again world,
end double quotes and right parentheses.
And no, you haven't ended up back at video one by mistake.
So before I explain why we're printing hello world again,
this isn't going to work for anyone using Python 2
and you'll actually get an error.
You can fix that by doing the following.
This is if you're running Python 2.
So from underscore underscore future,
underscore underscore, import, print underscore function.
Now this is a Python 3 course, so I'm not going to go
into the great detail about Python 2,
but I'm gonna point out things like this from time to time.
So also useful if you have to work on Python 2 code,
if you see that import, then you'll know
it's making some Python 3 feature available in Python 2.
So the underscore underscore future underscore underscore
module was introduced in Python 2.1
and you can find more information on that
by Googling for Python, you guessed it,
underscore underscore future underscore underscore.
All right, but in this case, I'm gonna remove the import
and that's because we're focusing on Python 3.
So what are we doing with that load of code?
Well, we're calling the print function
and we're passing two strings to it.
But we could pass more.
And we've done that at various points in the course.
So I can change that quite easily to hello planet
then another comma, double quotes, earth.
And if I run that, that still works quite nicely.
Close that little warning down there.
If I close down the run window
and if I do the command click on a Mac
but it's control on a PC, if I click on that
and click on print and have a look.
We can see the definitions in its source.
Now this isn't the full source for the print function
and that's because most of the stuff
in builtins.py is actually written in C.
So all we can see here is a stub showing the parameters.
But that's enough to see that it doesn't list
an infinite number of parameters to print.
So instead, the first parameter, ignoring this self,
is this *args that was talked about
at the start of the video.
Now that's the magic that lets a function or method
take a variable number of arguments.
So our three string values are wrapped up in a tuple,
so args, or *args, is the unpacked values in that tuple.
Args itself is a tuple, and the print function
takes each item from the tuple and then prints it.
Now as a result, it doesn't care how many arguments
we provide, it just iterates over the tuple
and prints them all.
Now I'm not gonna point you at the relevant bit
of the documentation for this just yet,
because it all seems backwards.
It states that the star operator unpacks the tuple.
Now that's technically true, it does.
And we'll actually see it doing that in a minute.
But unfortunately, it offers that as the only explanation
of how this works.
So you end up thinking, hang on, I didn't pass a tuple,
so how can star be unpacking it?
A good way to work out how a lot of things
in Python behaves is to experiment.
So let's go back to our code.
I'm gonna close down the builtins.py.
And we're gonna create our own function
that takes a variable number of arguments
just to see how this works.
Now I'm gonna keep the function really simple
so that we can focus on the arguments.
So we're just gonna calculate the average
of a series of numbers.
Now by average, I'm referring to the arithmetic mean,
where you add up all the values and then divide by
how many there are.
So let's delete that first line.
I'm gonna start with def space average
parentheses, then the *args.
Closing parentheses and colon.
Mean equals zero.
For arg in args colon mean plus equals arg.
Then we're going to return mean divided by len args.
Now obviously a very simple function.
So let's see it calculate an average.
So we're going to add the code to call it,
so I print average and we're going to pass the numbers
one space two space three space four,
obviously end parentheses as well.
So if we run that, over here we get the value 2.5.
And incidentally, if you're using Python 2,
you'll get the answer two, and that's because using
the slash here in Python 2 performs integer division.
And in Python 2 to correct that, you would actually
come up and type in from underscore underscore future
underscore underscore import division.
That would actually fix it.
That basically makes the slash behave
in the same way as it does in Python 3.
But I'm not gonna do that here obviously,
because we're basically focusing on Python 3.
And again, if you're using Python 2.1 or above,
but not version 3, you'll need to leave
that line in that I've just deleted.
If you're maintaining Python 2 code,
insert that import, you'll now know what it does.
All right, so in getting back to our average function,
let's add some diagnostic prints so that
we can actually see what's going on.
I'm gonna start by the line immediately
after the definition.
I'm gonna type print parentheses type parentheses args,
closing parentheses.
I'm gonna do print, parentheses, double quote,
args is left and right curly brace
colon double quote dot format args in parentheses,
closing parentheses.
And print *args double quotes is colon
double quote comma then *args, then right parentheses.
So let's actually run that and see what answer we get.
So we can see that the top of args is a tuple.
And printing the args results in the typical output we get
when we print a tuple.
The print function encloses it in parentheses,
as you can see here, so we've got args
is one, two, three, four.
And printing *args gives the four separate values
one, two, three, and four.
So you can see that the star operator, the asterisk,
has unpacked the args tuple on line four
when we printed that out or using the star here.
But we didn't pass in a tuple,
we provided four separate values.
So *args in the functions parameters up here,
on line one, that represents the unpacked tuple,
which means that args without the star is the tuple.
So that is to say that the *args parameter
is telling Python to expect an unpacked tuple
and the values we provide will be packed
into the parameter called args.
And just to show that, if we actually remove
the asterisk here.
And run, we actually get an error.
Positional argument but four were given.
Sorry, takes one positional argument, but four were given.
So if we don't specify that the parameter is *args,
what we're doing is we're forcing anything
that caused the function to put the values in parentheses
to pass them all as a single tuple value.
So we could do that, we could change our line 10 here
and put another set of parentheses
around those four numbers.
If we run that, you can see we get it working again.
And notice that the printout from line four
has successfully unpacked our args tuple.
So it's true to say that star or the asterisk
unpacks a tuple, but that's not what it's doing
when it appears as a parameter.
In that case, it's used to represent the fact
that the arguments will be an unpacked tuple,
so they'll be packed into the args parameter.
So there are a couple of things to note about this.
The first is the name args.
Now you can use any name you want,
as long as obviously it's a valid path
and variable name, of course.
The convention now is to call it args,
which is an abbreviation for arguments.
Now unless you've got a very good reason,
and frankly I can't think of one,
then stick to the convention.
And that's because it makes it much easier
for other people to read your code.
The second is that a variadic parameter,
as the documentation calls this,
must appear after all other positional parameters.
So it basically scoops up the remaining positional arguments
to quote the documentation.
So in other words, you can't do something like this,
this wouldn't work.
So we couldn't change this to put first underscore value
comma and space and then our *args again
comma last underscore value.
The first argument in that case would go
to first underscore value, but then all
the remaining positional arguments
will end up in args, which leaves no way
to provide a value for the last underscore value
without using a named keyword parameter.
So if we try that
we get an error and then even if I fix the code on line 10
and run it again, we still get an error.
Missing one required keyword-only argument,
last underscore value.
I might just move this down,
so I can read these errors a little bit easier.
Okay.
So if anything does follow the args, the *args,
it has to be a set of keyword parameters.
And we're gonna look at those in the next video, actually.
Right, so I'm gonna finish this video
with a short challenge.
Let's have a look at that.
All right, so the challenge is to write a function
called build_tuple, that takes a variable number
of arguments, and returns a tuple containing
the values passed to it.
Now the image below shows some sample input
to the function and also the expected output.
So pause the video if you wanna see what that is.
Actually, I'll show it on the next slide anyway.
Now the function itself isn't particularly useful.
The aim here is to test your understanding
of what we've just done, not to produce something
that you're likely to use.
And as a hint, it will be a very short function.
All right, so that's your challenge.
See how you go, pause the video,
and I'll see you when you get back.
All right, so how did you get on?
Did you manage to get it to work?
Well, let's actually have a go at doing that.
I'm going to delete our code in this stars_args.py file.
And we'll start with def space build
underscore tuple *args colon.
Then I'm just gonna return args.
That's actually it.
That's because when you provide a variable list
of arguments to a function, they're packed into a tuple,
so this function is probably the shortest one
you're ever gonna write.
All we have to do is literally return args,
sorry without the colon.
So that's it.
If you managed to solve the challenge, well done.
And if you're not sure how this function works,
it's probably worth rewatching this video.
But to what I'm going to do is just put
some code in here, just so we can test it
as I mentioned in the video.
And what I'm gonna do is just copy that code in,
save a bit of time here.
Just to confirm that it does actually work, like so.
So again, now if we run this, you can see
that we've got the expected output down below.
So again, if you're not sure how this function works,
it's definitely worth reviewing this video again
and trying to write some other functions
that also take variable number of arguments
and just to test your theories out.
Now examples you might wanna try here is
firstly, a function that takes a variable number of words,
then returns the average word length,
a function that returns the smallest or largest
of the numbers passed to it, a function to print
all the words passed to it backwards in reverse order,
so the output will read correctly from right to left.
And a hint for that one is, we saw how to reverse a string
using a slice of left to right square brackets,
two colons, negative one, and that can also
have a use with tuples.
Another example, create a list, let's say you call it words.
Then print the list, but also print *words
to see that star can also be used to unpack a list
as well as a tuple.
The documentation for all of this is on the link
listed on the screen and it's also in the resources section.
It's worth reviewing that section down to,
but not including, 4.7.5 Lambda Expressions.
And you'll also find an image showing
my version of those functions in the resources section
for this video, just to help you out.
So I won't show those images here.
I'll leave that for you to check out
so that you've got a chance to attempt
those functions first.
So see how you go with that, and if you do get stuck,
or you wanna confirm your answers, check out the image
that again is available in the resources section
for this video.
So with that said, I'm going to end the video here now.
In the next video, we're gonna look at the KW-args
or kwargs, as people like to pronounce it.
which is also another term for keyword parameters.
So I'll see you in the next video.