We've seen how to join items in an
iterable, using the join method.
Strings have an opposite method - the
split method. We called our last Python
file joining_things, so let's
create a new one, and I'm going to call
this one splitting_ things.
The split method splits a string up into words.
Now that sounds simple, so let's see it
working. So I'm gonna start by typing
panagram is equal to, and in double
quotes, The quick brown fox jumps over
the lazy dog. On line three, I'm going to
type words is equal to panagram.split,
leaving the parentheses in so
we're calling the method. On line four I'm
just going to print out words, so print,
words in parentheses. When we run that,
we get a list containing all the words in
the string. We didn't provide any
arguments to split, so it defaults to
splitting on whitespace. Whitespace
includes things like tabs and newlines,
as well as a few other characters,
including the space. So to demonstrate
that, what I'll do is use triple quotes
and space the string over several lines.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We've got three quotes at the start here, and
two down the end, and we're gonna space
it over multiple lines, as I said. So I'm
going to press ENTER after brown and
move the space. In between the word jumps
and over, I'm going to put a tab, \t,
I'm gonna press ENTER after the word
over, so you can see we've spaced that, now,
over three lines. So if I run that, and
you can see we get exactly the same
output, a list containing all nine words
of the string. Split returns a list.
You call it on a string and it returns all
the items in the string, that are
separated by one or more whitespace
characters. That's the default behaviour,
but it also has a couple of named
arguments.
I won't call up the documentation in a
browser. You've got the page bookmarked
and you can refer to that after this
video, if you wish. Sometimes, you'll just
want a quick reminder of the parameters
that a function or method defines.
The JetBrains IDEs - IntelliJ
and Pycharm - have a useful feature to let
you do that. Holding down the control key,
and hover over the method. You can see
I'm doing that for split, there. Now on a
Mac you'll use the command key, and also
most modern IDs will also have a similar
feature. So as you can see, that's a
useful way to get a quick reminder about
the arguments you can use, as well as the
names of named arguments. The first
parameter you can see there is called self.
Now this might sound strange, but
I'm going to ask you to pretend that
isn't there for the moment. One
difference between a function and a
method, is a presence of this self
parameter. You'll learn all about that in
the Object-Oriented Programming section
of this course. When you're using the
methods, Python provides a value for self
for you, so don't worry about it at the moment.
So moving on next, we can see the
sep named argument. That's used to decide
what separates the words in the string.
As I've said previously, the default is
whitespace, but you may have a comma
separated list, for example, that you want
to split. In that case, you can provide a
comma as the separator. If you recall,
we saw an example of that way back in
section 4, when we extracted all the
values from a string. So let's go through
that again. We had a string containing
digits separated by commas. So I'm going
to type on line 8, numbers is equal to 9 comma
223,372,O36,854,775 and
807. We can tell split to split the
string up at the commas, to get a list of
just sequences of digits. So I could type
print, in parentheses I can type numbers
dot split parentheses and this time,
within the parentheses, I'm going to put
a comma in double quotes. So run the
program - you can see, we've got a list
there, containing each of the numbers
from our number string. Now note that
they're all strings. When you split a
string, you get a list of strings. That's
why I had to use that strange code, back
in section 4. I wanted to add up all the
values, so they had to be converted to
integers first. You'll understand what
that code was doing, later in the course.
It's basically, a more concise way
of writing the code that you will create
for the challenge, at the end of this video.
Now there was another strange bit
of code in that example. I'm going to
paste that back in here, so we can talk
about it. Now don't bother typing that
code in because I'm not going to run it.
I just want to show you how we used
split in that earlier example. It won't
run in any case, at the moment. We've got
an error because separators isn't
defined. You should have the complete
code in the strings2.py file from the last section,
if you want to refer back to it. But
looking at the code on line 11, we used
the join and split commands. The line
still won't make complete sense because
of that strange code that we're passing
to join. What I'll do, though, is replace
the code with the sequence that it
produces. Okay, so the strange code on
line 11, produced the generated list on
lines 12 to 18, so it, basically, replaced
all the separators with spaces and
produce the list of all the characters.
And you'll learn how that worked later.
We can now start, now, to make sense of
how join and split were being used
together. Let's focus on the join part first,
and what I'll do is, I'll just
comment out line 11 now. Alright, so
let's focus on the join part of line 19,
first. First we're gonna start by deleting
the dot split on the end of that line,
like so, and we'll add it back shortly.
First though, let's see what join produces,
so let's run on the program. We've called
join on an empty string on line 19. That
means the items in the list won't be
separated from each other by anything.
Remember that the string you use
when calling join, is used to separate the
items that you're joining. So we end up
with a string containing all the items
from generated list,
essentially, from our generated list there,
on line 12. All the items were single
characters, and that's what we've got in
our output - a string containing the
single characters from the list. Each
sequence of digits was followed by a
space, and we get those spaces
in our output. And again, I'll just run it
again so we can see it. Alright, so the next
thing we want to do is split that string
up again. We know that split will split
on whitespace, and we can see the spaces
in the string, on the last line of our
output. So let's add some code, so down here,
on line 22, I'm going to type values_list is equal to values.split(),
so I'm calling the split function. Then
we'll print out the value, or values_list,
or the contents, I should
say, our values_list on the next line.
So we haven't provided a
separator when we call .split, so it
splits up the string at the spaces, and
if we run this,
we can see that the last line of the
output is a list, containing each of the
numbers that appeared in the string. And
we can see the string, on the line above that,
in the output. Alright, so that's
the join and split methods; join will let
you create a string from a sequence, such
as a list split. Split, on the other hand, will
split the string up again and create a
list. We'll be using these methods again,
in some of the later examples. Split can
be very useful when reading data from a
file, for example. Experiment with your
own lists and strings, and make sure you
understand how to use these two methods
before continuing. For now, though,
let's finish this video with a mini-challenge. So
looking at that last line of output,
we've got a list of strings. Back in
section 4, I used a comprehension
to convert that to a list of numbers. We
haven't covered comprehensions yet, but
we have covered everything you need, to
produce a list of ints. So your challenge is
to use a for loop, to replace all the
strings in that list with integer values.
So what I'm going to do is close down
the run window. So I'm going to paste in
the comments now - the challenge in a
series of comments, as you can see there.
So that's the challenge. See how you go
with it, and I'll go over my solutions to
that challenge in the next video.