so just when you thought we were able to actually move on from
blackjack but actually we got a little bit
more to talk about and we are gonna use
blackjack as this example now this is
specifically talking about underscores
in variable names now we've had a look
at a few of the modules in the Python Standard
library in previous lectures
and we jumped into the source to check
out how to use a few things and when we did
that you may have noticed that many
object names start or end with
underscores or even start and end
underscores and you might be wondering
what that's all about and obviously you can
see on line 3 we are using underscore underscore name underscore underscore now
we've discussed ending a name with a
single underscore when we looked at the
spin box widget in the Tkinter video
and you can set the range of values
that appears in the spin box using the to and from
underscore arguments but because from
is a Python keyword we used from
underscore rather than from now a convention
is to use a single underscore after a name
if it would otherwise conflict with the
name that's built into Python so
reserved a keyword in other words it's
probably better to use a different name
of course but if the name that Python
already uses makes sense for your
particular use then probably adding
an underscore to the end of the name is the
way to go
you can do that quite easily so in the
case of specifying a range of values
from a spin box widget to and from a
probably the best names to use so the
creators of the Tkinter module uses
convention adding an underscore in this
case to the from keyword so that's the
easy one out of the way now for other uses of
underscores around
names now unlike many other languages
Python has actually got no concept of
private or protected variables that
means that it's possible to do things
with a module that you probably
shouldn't do so let's have a look at a few
ways we can miss with our blackjack
module so we've got the project open from
the previous video we made the changes
in the previous video to it so we are able to
import it as a module and the project
should now have 2 Python files as
you can see on the screen now blackjack.py and import_test.py so
it's useful to be able to call the play
function as you can see me doing on line
4 and also using the cards list to
create decks for other games is also
extremely useful but beyond that though
their is not much else in the
Blackjack module that really makes any
sense to use once it's actually been
imported now there is a score_hand
function but that's really very specific
to blackjack and couldn't be used to
decide which of 2 poker hands are better for
argument sake because it's a completely
different algorithm
now in Java for example only the play function
and cards list would be made available to
other programs everything else would
have been marked private so that it was
hidden and then it wouldn't actually
show but as I said Python doesn't
have any or doesn't have private objects
and that means that we can do silly
things after importing the blackjack module so we are going to start by calling the deal_cards
function just to show you that it can be
done and not suggesting it's actually
a wise thing to do so come down here if we wanted to we
could do something like....
....and so let's run that just to
confirm that it does actually work so right click this and click run to make sure
we're running import_test and not
blackjack so do that we run it and tab over and
have a look and obviously we've got two
cards now the dealer has actually got 2
cards although at this stage due to the way
we designed it only the second one
is actually included in the dealer score and as a result that does look really
strange and that is because we've got a
total score of 13 for the dealer
but only the second one is calculated
again this is an ideal basically
giving access to areas of the game that
we wouldn't ordinarily want someone
who's imported this blackjack module to be able to
access our code that way because it's
sort of breaking the game as such this is
compounded by the fact there's really
nothing to indicate that we shouldn't be
calling this function so from that
perspective of someone who's imported
the blackjack module and is wanting to use
it their's no clear indication that you know
maybe I shouldn't be actually calling
this method here and obviously by
calling and then by trial and error
and running through and testing it and seeing that
it doesn't work they will eventually figure
it out but there's no easy way to know ahead of time if
that's the case by convention starting a name with an underscore indicates
that it should be treated as protected which means it's not intended to be
used outside the modules existence so
it's really a standard in Python now theirs a
little bit more to that when using
classes and we'll talk about that in the
next section when we start object oriented
programming but if we go back into the
blackjack module
we can actually refactor the deal_card
function so that it's called _deal_
card so we go back their go to our deal card and if I refactor that right
click it refactor rename and put an underscore in
front of it and refactor it...that should
have changed everywhere even here
back in the import_test.py but notice
what happened now IntelliJ has actually come
up and help us now its access to a
protected member_deal_
card of a module so we are now
correctly getting a warning that this is
a protected member in so much as far as Python is actually concerned so their is still
nothing preventing the access just wanna
make that clear we can still run it and
if we do run it the game still actually work so unlike Java or another programming language
where once we set it to like private or
protected we can actually restrict the
uses here we can't do that so it's still
gonna work but you do get a warning
that it's quite prominent its not just a little warning on the right hand side its actually
underscoring
you know the little underscore on the actual method name we are trying to access which will hopefully
get you to look at and think what have I done wrong here
so if you find yourself using an object
whos name starts with an underscore now
bear in mind that you probably shouldn't
be doing that the developer of the module
has defined it that way for you probably not
to access it that way of course if the
object is in your own code then you
probably know what you doing then its ok
but just be very careful if it existed
in a module that you didn't actually write
yourself and as you can see IntelliJ is
aware of this convention and provides us
with this very useful warning so that at
least we are aware of what
we're actually doing so just close it
down because there is actually another
implication of using underscored at the
start of a name so if your using
alternate way of importing blackjack
anything whose name starts with an
underscore is not actually imported
now we've recommended before that you
don't do an import* from a module
because all of the names from the
imported modules then have become part of your
modules namespace and it's then very
easy to lose track of what names belong
to what because the way we imported blackjack
we need to use blackjack. to access any
of the Blackjack objects which makes it
very obvious that we're actually dealing
with code that's part of blackjack
and you can see on lines 5 and 6 we are actually inputting the . their to
access that blackjack specific functionality so we can now
look at the difference in more detail so
what we are gonna do is comment out all this
code for now just leave the import in we are gonna
have a look at what's in global so I want
to list all the names separately rather
than in one long line that we get if
we just used print globals which have
used previously so gonna create a
loop here so...
...so if we run this but we get
an error straightaway so x is meant to
iterate through all the keys in the
dictionary but as soon as we've used X the
dictionary changes and Python gives
us an error so this code does not actually work
because obviously we knew very well that
we defined that has actually altered the
dictionary itself so we can't actually access the
the globals that why so one quick way
around this is to take a copy of the
globals dictionary then iterate through that
so that means we won't see our variable X
in that list but as a quick way to make a
copy is to use the sorted function then
the actual code has the added advantage
of producing a sorted list so let's go
ahead and do that so.....
....
.....so that way
there's nothing being added to the
dictionary when we go to iterate
through G and we should find that
it actually works without an error so
if we run this this time it actually has
worked so the list itself is pretty
small and a part from a few things underscore before and after their names
the only object that's present in here
is blackjack which of course we
imported on line 1 but let's just change
the import and see what happens if we
added a start so...
.....
...we do it that way and we run it....you can see we got a completely
different result but all our functions
as you can see and the variables are
showing up basically everything from the
blackjacks module namespace now appears
in our modules namespace so if we
created an object called cards for
example then the blackjack modules card
would no longer be available so I said
that everything from the blackjacks
module namespace is imported but to be
precise that's not strictly true for
example there's no assign there if you have a
look at the screen of our _deal_card function and if we
try and use it now we actually get an error so if we try and do that....and we got an error their unresolved
reference so the Python import
mechanism does actually take note of
this convention and it won't import any
objects that start with an underscore
when you import star now when we
import blackjack the objects from the
blackjack module aren't imported separately so
everything even names beginning with
underscores are available by the prefixing them with blackjack. so we
put the import back as to what it was like
before
....that's not gonna work
because it's an unresolved reference but we
go back and put blackjack in front of it
to tell Python that it's the
Blackjack module we are dealing with it and
for the frame....the error goes away and we are good to go we still get a warning here
from IntelliJ telling us that its accessing a protected member but it does work again now lets get rid
of this code......our app is running again all being with two cards again with
only one being scored so using a double
underscores at the start of a name invokes
Python's name mangling rules so this
convention really exists to prevent name
clashes when subclassing objects and
again we'll look at this in more detail
in the next section when we start dealing with
object oriented programming but in a
blackjack module two underscore would
really serve no useful purpose but of
course anything that starts with two underscores
automatically also starts with one so
import* wouldn't actually import
them now the final underscore naming
convention to discuss here is names that
start and end with two underscores now
basically things that
you shouldn't be changing now we've seen just
deleted it __name__ and use it to restrict the code
that was executed when our module was imported so it should be obvious from
the example that changing the value of
the __name__ isn't a
good idea so of course I will just go ahed and do just that
now to show you what happens the
same is generally true of anything
that's name with double underscores that
at the start and end they can be useful to use but they should never be change so we are gonna go ahead
now to our code and make sure that it's set correctly and I'll actually get rid of this code their....so now we've got our import we got our blackjack deal_card and blackjack.py
so we are ready to go with that so we tested
that will just test one more time to make
sure that it does work obviously our app is working nicely so that is good and of course we're
getting two cards because we're using
line 3 calling that method when we
shouldn't be doing that so next what we
gonna do is we are going to break things by
changing the value of name the __name__ in blackjack.py so we are going to their and close this run window down
just below the play method what I'm
going to do is change this variables so...
....
so obviously this is something you
shouldn't be doing good just making the
point that these two underscores at the start and end of the variable names is something
is Python way of saying you should never
change this but we are just doing this to see what
happens
if we run our import_test and have a look so you can see that the
game starts up fine but notice that the
dealers has got only one card so the code
the import_test hasn't yet
executed and that this is the original
effect that we saw when we first imported
blackjack because __name__
has been set to main or the __name__
I'm talking about this code
code we added to line 125 because we change that
the test that restricts code execution
on import is no longer valid and the
code runs when we import the module
so then if we actually get back to our
code and close this we then get an error because
by closing the window we've destroyed all
the TKinter objects so that nothing
works and the game cannot be played by calling
the play function so Python doesn't prevent you
as such from modify these variables but
if you do so then the results are
undefined and you can run into all sorts
of problems like I just introduced
to you the only thing you can be reasonably sure of is that their is something that is going to break so before
moving on i'm just gonna remove this offending line again because that shouldn't be
in their deleted that like so close this run
window so we just about done here and what I'm going to
leave you with now is one more use of
the underscore that will quickly go
through so a variable that's just name_ with nothing else indicates
a throwaway value so underscore by
itself is a valid variable name and
rather than
thinking of a name for something that's
not gonna be used the convention is to
call it either that underscore or underscore
underscore
so examples of things that you might have
to access but are not going to use include
tuples we want to use some of the
values of a tuple but not all of them
let's just write a simple code I'm just
going to comment out blackjack for now and put it below that
and will put.....
....
...
.....so as we saw in the tuples
video at the start of this course you can
assign all the values of a tuple to a
variables using a single assignment that
I have actually done here on line 8
but this code isn't really
interested in my age just my name and
country and so I've put an underscore
where the age would actually be now we could actually add another line to print the age if we wanted to
so....and that would
still quite happily work run it to make sure it
does work
Tim Australia and 24 so it is working
but the point here is that it's just a
way for you to name something as a
throwaway value that you know that you
are not gonna be using for the rest of your programs
obviously in the case of the age which
was just a second part their that is set to 24
currently if we actually gonna use the value then
you probably give it a better name than the
underscore so the single underscore
or 2 underscores as variable names are
used when you would not be doing
anything else with the value but you
have to specify the variable ok so
that's it I'm gonna finish here now and I'll see
you in the next video