ok so we're gonna talk now about a
namespace and more about scope because
there are some unusual aspects of scope and name space in Python and that can be
a little bit confusing especially if you've cross from another programming
language so largely things behave as you would expect them to do so what
I'm gonna do here is review some of the
basics and then discuss the behavior
that may be strange compared to other
languages so Python allows functions
to be nested in other functions which
also has an impact on scope in a
possibly unexpected way now one reason
for nesting a function within another one is
to perform initialization before a
recursive function call so  we are gonna start
up explaining a useful programming
technique called recursion so a recursive
function is a function that calls itself
and they can be very useful in dealing
with structures that contain themselves
such as directories in a computer file
system now for computing mathematical
functions that are defined recursively
so the mathematical factorial function
is a product of all the numbers from one
up to and including in so a function to
calculate the factorial for any number can
be written as a very simple loop we're gonna do that now so lets make a start and I've created a new
project here a new Python file so do that as well to follow along so let's
create our factorial function so...
......
....
.....again this is
the factorial algorithm that we are putting it together
here so we are gonna put....
...so that's the function so now can test this so
far I in range....
....
the n factorial btw is generally
written as n!
you can see I've done that in the
comments on line 2 and by convention 0 so 0!
is 1 so the functions
going to return 1 if n is 0 otherwise it actually
multiplies all the numbers from 1 to n so
the range starts at 2 because their's
little point multiplying anything by one and it stops at n + 1 to include the value n so remember
that the last value on our range includes
is one less than the stock value and note
here that we're assuming positive\values for any of our function so the loop
at the end of the program calls the fact
function for all the numbers from 0 to 130
which you probably gathered by the range
that I've got on line 10 and
this is probably the most efficient way
to calculate a factorial but it's also good
examples demonstrate recursion but we're
going to do first is to run it to see if it does work
and look at making some changes so we are going to
run it and you can see that we've
actually got the results
and their is our results their 0 returns 1 1 returns 1 2 6 24 and
so on and the numbers get progressively
larger as you can see it is quite a huge numbers
ok so as I mentioned this is probably
the most efficient way to calculate
a factorial but it's also a good example
to demonstrate recursion so let's have a
look at the recursive equivalent so from
the definition of a factorial and by
looking at the output from the program
which I showed on the screen we can see that for
example 6 factorials is 6 x 5
factorial or will just run it again
rather than me talking about the numbers you
not seeing on the screens so lets go back and have a look you can see on the screen now so 6 factorial is 6
x 5 factorial and factorial is 5 x 4 factorial etc so in
fact for any value of n n factorial can
be calculated as n take 1
effectively so what we are gonna do is write
another function a recursive
equivalent of this so let's do that so I'm gonna star that on line 9
not on line 10 because we need to two spaces
between functions two lines between
them so this one will call this one factorial....
....
.....
....so we just run it to
make sure it does work so it looks to me that
it's producing the same results as
before but obviously its now using recursive
function so I'm just going to close this
so I'm just gonna bring up an image on the
screen so lets bring up this image
on the screen so you can see a little
bit and I'll put it here so that you can see the code so
the program produces the same result as
before but it is now using this
recursive function with the name factorial that we created on line 10 now the factorial
function first checks if n is less than
or equal to 1 and if it is it returns
one but for any other value of n it calls
itself with a value n -1 then
multiply the result by n it can come a bit
confusing to get your head around recursion but
its helpful to think of the successive
function calls stacking up and you can
see this image will hopefully help you
understand that with anyone called
not returning until the function that n
is called returns that sort of makes sense so
when we start an n = 4 factorial
4 can't return until factorial 3
is finish so then
multiplies the result of factorial 3
by 4 and returns then of course
factorial 3 can't return until the call to factorial 2 is finished and so
on so in actual fact the mechanism is a
really no different from a function
calling any other function when a
function does call another function it
has to wait for that function to finish
and the same things actually happening
here so people sometimes find it confusing
because the function is calling itself but
as long as their some condition that causes the
function at the end of the chain to
return everything ultimately works fine
so another recurisve pattern in mathematics is the
Fibonacci series
this crops up remarkably often in
nature actually the petals on flowers
and the way they are plant and way the
plants grow are often follows a Fibonacci
pattern if you want to know more there's
some really interesting links from the
Wikipedia entry and I'm going to bring
that up on the screen
you wanna know more about to Fibonacci and the link will be in the resources section that maths get a bit heavy but section 15
in nature is quite interesting down here in nature now is linked up here
arrangements of leaves on a stem is quite
interesting to look at as well because it
shows many occurrences of Fibonacci numbers in plant growth so each
successive Fibonacci numbers is obtained by
adding the two previous numbers if f0
0 being 0 and f1 being 1 and the numbers are really easy to calculate recursively so let's have a
go at creating a Fibonacci method back in our code
Fibonacci function so going to start it on line 19 so.....
.....that's really what we're
trying to achieve so we're going to start
this again we are using a some so we are using
recursion here we are gonna put...
....
..and lets change the code here on line 26
so we will change the range to....
and the reason I've done that is
I've reduce the range to 36 because the
function takes a while to run once
n gets above thirty and in fact
this is a very inefficient way
to calculate Fibonacci numbers because it has to
call itself twice for each number and
when it comes to Fib n - 1
it has to calculate the value for fib n-2 which it then recalculates in order to add them
together so I just run this to make sure it
does work and see how the
thirties above is quite slow to process so its chugging a way we got
quite a fast computer their we go so 0 to 35 is basically done so recursive
functions can certainly be useful but it
theirs a simple interactive approach then that
will almost always be better so having
seen how long that recursive function took to
calculate the first 35 Fibonacci numbers let's
look at a iterative approached that runs
a lot faster so gonna create another
method here and will call this one Fibonacci so...
.....
...
....
...so that is our
Fibonacci method that is not using
recursion so let's actually have a run
of that just to see if it's any quicker
so we will actually run the Fibonacci method
this time instead of the fib method we created so
lets run that so you could see that
running it was significantly faster
compared to the fib function that we created
so again if you just go back and check the fib
function again using recursion and run
that it it takes a significant amount of
time once it gets to around 30 to process those numbers its still processing now as I'm
talking and that's finally finish so the last one was last time was 9227465
compare that to Fibonacci using the other method the other way of doing it without
recursion will run that you can see that's much much faster
actually I think we may have a bit of an
issue here with this method because I
think the other one ended on number 35 was
9227465 which I believe is correct and
this one is one out so probably I've
made mistakes but what we can do just to confirm
that lets actually print both out so......
....
...just to checked
they're actually the same results so lets
just try running that to see whether they are the same as
you can see that they're actually
different they're so obviously something
that's going on there you can see from number
seven onwards
they are pretty much all out as you can see clearly only 0 and 1 are the same but the rest are actually out so what I think I've
done is I've got the wrong range in the
Fibonacci method so in other words calculating one too many
numbers I think that should probably be n not n + 1....so we are actually going through the
range one too many times so run that again that's better we are now getting the same
results for both and as I quickly open
a browser will just confirm that these
are actually the correct results you can see we get the
right results so what I was doing was just
going to one too many numbers and the
calculation was sort of moving on to the
next number if that made sense so that fix that bug up so lets have a quick look at the browser.....
....the first 300
numbers that is what we want so if we just look
at say 35 is 9227465 and 34 5702887
bit of a spot check their 9227465 5702887 so we've actually got the right
results so that is the bugs fixed but again if we
just go through and when we ran it
initially when we did run initially
you saw that the recursive routine was
significantly slower than the regular
routine that sort of went through and
calculated by actually going through
to a range so recursions not
always the go to so it does really depend
on what you're trying to achieve and
just in some cases you might wanna make
sure you try an alternative way to see
which is the best way of achieving the result but there are useful
applications for recursive functions and
we're gonna look at one in the next
video and this is one that is dealing
with directory listings of a computer
file systems so let's work on that in the
next video