In the last video, we completed the
challenge to fix the guessing game so it
used the while loop, but I also finished
by saying that we should need ten
guesses or less, to guess any number from
1 to 1,000, which we've currently had our
program set to. So I want to talk about
that a bit more. The thing is, trying to
guess a number between 1 and 1000 is
difficult -
the guess will be wrong 999 times out of
a thousand. What if we could narrow that
range down, so we're only guessing a
number from 500 numbers? That improves
our chances - now we'd only be wrong 499
times. If we reduce that further to 250
numbers, we'd only be wrong 249 times. So
that's how a binary search works.
When you have an ordered set of data to
search through, you can split the data in
half each time. Guessing a number is very
much like searching for a value in an
ordered set of data. Of course, we know
that the value you're guessing does
exist. That simplifies things slightly,
but the basic steps are the same.
So our first guess is 500, which is half of
1,000. So if we have to guess lower,
we halve 500 and guess 250. For the third
guess, we halve 250 and guess 125.
Halving 125 gives a floating point value, 62.5.
Now we're only guessing whole numbers,
and we've seen that Pythons integer
division rounds down. The middle column
shows the integer values we'd use,
instead of the floating point values
that we get when dividing by 2. By
continuing to half the range of values
that we have to guess, we can guess any
number from 1 to 1000 in a maximum of 10 guesses.
Now the table only shows 9
guesses. It's showing what happens when
we have to guess lower each time, to show
how the range of values halves with each guess.
If the answer was 2, we'd have to
have another higher guess, after we
guessed 1. That would give us 10 guesses,
which is the most we'd need in order to
guess a number from 1 to 1000. Now we may
need fewer guesses, but we shouldn't need
more than 10. Of course, sometimes we'll have
to get higher, not lower, but the
principle's the same and you saw that
in the previous video,
when I started doing binary searches to
find the correct answer. When guessing
higher, we use the upper half of the range,
instead of the lower half.
Our first case would still be 500.
For the second guess, we'd split the
range from 500 to 1000, giving 750.
If we had to guess higher again, the third
guess allows the range from 750 to 1000
to give 875. With each guess, the range of
numbers we have to guess is halved.
In reality,
we'll use a combination of higher and
lower guesses. For example, let's say the
answer was 998. After our 9th guess, 999,
we'd have to guess lower. The range of
numbers to guess is between 997, our 8th
guess, and 999. So we'd guess 998, and
get it right with the 10th guess.
Alright so let's work through a real example.
To keep the slides manageable,
we're going to be guessing a number
between 1 and 10. We should be able to do
that within four guesses. So let's say
that the answer is 7. We start off by
guessing the mid-point between the low
and high values. The formula we use is:
low plus, and in parentheses, high minus low
integer divide by 2.
So putting our
low and high values in the formula, we
get 1 plus parentheses 10 - 1 integer
divide by 2, which is 1 plus 4 giving 5.
Remember that integer division rounds
down, and 9 integer division 2 is 4, so 5 is
our first guess. We're told to guess higher.
That means the answer must lie somewhere
between 6 and 10. We know it's greater
than 5, so the lowest it can be is 6.
That's our new low value for the range.
The mid-point now becomes 6 plus 10 minus
6 in parentheses integer divide by 2
which is 8, so therefore our next guest
will be 8.
We're told to guess lower. That means the
answer must lie somewhere between 6 and 7.
We know the answer's less than
8, so the largest it can be is 7.
That's a new high value for the
range. The mid-point now becomes 6 plus
parenthesis
7 minus 6 integer divide by 2,
which is 6 - integer division does round
down. So our third guess would be 6.
7 is greater than 6, so we're
told to guess higher. Our low value now
becomes 7, the same as the high value.
At this point, a human will guess 7
right away. The computer has to do the
calculation first. The mid-point now
becomes 7 plus, and in parentheses,
7 minus 7 integer divide by 2
which is seven. So our fourth guess will
be 7, and we get the correct answer.
So each incorrect guess halves the range
of numbers that we have to guess.
That's why this technique is known as a binary
search, or binary chop.
The binary search algorithm is the most
efficient way of finding an item in an
ordered list. It forms the basis for the
data structures that database
programs, such as SQLite and Oracle,
use for storing the database keys.
And that allows for very fast searching of
the data. Alright so in the next video,
we'll write the code to guess a number
using a binary chop.
See you in the next video.