So in the last few videos,
we've looked at the *args and **kwargs parameters
and how we can pass on arguments that we don't need
to handle or in fact don't even know about.
So now it's time to create our own listbox class
that includes its own scrollbar.
Now if we had to start this from scratch,
frankly, it would be a mammoth undertaking.
We'd have to learn another language to start with,
TCL, which is prounounced tickle,
which is what the Python TKinter library uses
to produce all its GUI elements.
But fortunately, we already have a working listbox class
and we can inherit most of the behaviour from that.
So back in jukebox.py, I'm gonna open that up again.
We're going to start some work on that.
We're gonna create a scrollable listbox class
and I'm gonna call that, unoriginally, scrollbox.
So I'm gonna go start this at the top of the file
and it's gonna be after the connect, the SQL connect.
And we'll start this on line 10.
So we're gonna start with class scrollbox
and it's tkinter.listbox.
And again, you have to have those two spaces there
between line seven and the start of the class.
And now we wanna define the init method.
So we're gonna do a def underscore underscore
init underscore underscore, and then we're going
to do parentheses, self comes up automatically,
comma, space, window, comma, space, and **kwargs.
And I'm gonna put a note in here for Python 2 users.
So, and I'm gonna comment that out.
And that would be tkinter dot listbox dot
underscore underscore init underscore underscore self
comma space window comma space **kwargs.
So the syntax is gonna be slightly different again
if you're in Python 2.
But in our case, now we're going to,
after that definition, to a super parentheses dot
underscore underscore init, and then we're going to
pass as arguments window comma space, then **kwargs.
And press enter, then a separate line there.
And we're going to do self.scrollbar is equal to
tkinter.scrollbar parentheses window comma space orient
equals tkinter.VERTICAL comma space
command equals self.yview.
And it's just a parentheses, there's no method call there.
So we're just using the right parentheses
to close off the line,
So what I've done there, you can see
it's pretty straightforward.
We started off by overwriting the init method
to add a scrollbar field after calling
the super.init method.
So super and then there's the creation
of the scrollbar field.
And again, the comment of that code
is for Python 2 users, that's the way to init a listbox,
as that would be done with Python 2's old-style classes.
All right, so now that we've done that,
we've defined our base class, we need to change
our listbox types to scrollbox.
So I come down here and we're gonna start
with the artist listbox.
At the moment, we've got tkinter.listbox.
Let's change artistList instead to be equal to
scrollbox and we'll pass the argument as mainWindow.
Then we need to come down and do the same for albums.
And albums we've done here, albumsList here.
Instead of tkinter.listbox, we're going to
make that scrollbox.
Scrollbox and the arguments there is still mainWindow
and listvariable equals albumLV, nothing's changed there.
And then we also need to come down
and do the same for songList.
So that's the songList here, tkinter.listbox.
We're changing that to be our scrollbox.
And the arguments are still mainWindow and listvariable
will equal songLV.
So if we run this
you can see that we've now got our scrollbox objects
created instead of basic listboxes.
And you can see, in fact, the scrollbar's there now.
We can actually use it to scroll up and down.
But essentially, the scrollbox doesn't add anything yet.
But it is a good idea to test your subclasses frequently
when developing them to make sure
that the programme runs without any errors.
And if it does error out, you'll know exactly
where you were before, and it won't take you
hopefully that long to figure out what's changed
since the last time it was working.
But in any event, now that we can replace
the TKlist box class with our scrollbox subclass,
we can start to add that extra functionality.
So we close that down.
And with our calls, we're passing on any keyword arguments
to the listbox init method.
So if we create one of our own scrollbox objects
with a different background, for example,
that would actually work fine.
And just to show you what I mean by that,
we can go back up to artist, the artist listbox
here on line 38 and we could add
an additional argument there, so background equals
blue and if we run this, we get a lovely blue background
from our artists scrollbox.
Or listbox, to be more technically correct.
So in other words, we don't have to worry
about dealing with any options that the users
of our scrollbox decide they want.
We're just passing the lot on in the kwargs argument.
Now black text though on the background's starting
to look awful, so I'm going to actually undo that change
and again, what I mean by that is
it's not really a good look there with that blue,
so I'm going to again just get rid of that blue background
by just undoing it.
I'm gonna go back to how it was now on line 38,
but keep in mind if you do want
to give your scrollboxes different colours and fonts
that's fully supported via the kwargs argument now.
But in our case, we've just created our own subclass
of listbox that we can add extra functionality to,
so let's do as the name suggests
and actually add a scrollbar.
So the time to do that is when our scrollbox
is added to the layout manager.
Now we're only going to support the grid manager
and so consequently to do this
we're going to override the grid method.
So let's go back up to our class definition.
And we're gonna add the code here.
And we'll start the code here on line 18
and we'll define that or override that grid method.
So that's gonna be def grid, self is the first parameter,
then it's comma space row, comma space column,
comma space sticky is equal to nsw in single quotes,
comma space rowspan is equal to one,
comma space columnspan is equal to one,
comma space, you guess it, kwargs.
And Python 2 users, the equivalent would be
tkinter.listbox.grid and I'll just type
this in real quickly.
Again, if you're a Python 2 user.
But in our case, we're now gonna do a super method
called dot grid.
And it's gonna be row equals row, comma space column
equals column, comma space sticky equals sticky,
comma space rowspan equals rowspan, comma space columnspan
equals columnspan, comma space, and yes,
KWargs on the end, **kwargs.
So that's the super call.
Then we also wanna do a self.scrollbar.grid
row equals row, comma space column equals column,
comma space sticky equals in single quotes nse,
comma space, and rowspan equals rowspan.
And then we wanna do a self left to right square brackets
and in single quotes yscrollcommand
and that's equal to self.scrollbar.set.
All right, so the first line in the method
is calling the super, the super class's grid method
and we're passing on any options that
we don't wanna use in kwargs.
And once again in the line above that
I've included the method you'd use for Python 2,
its old-style classes.
Now note that all the options we have included
in our definition of this method won't be present in kwargs.
As we saw in the last video, any additional options
that the calling code uses will just be passed on
to the super classes grid method.
So the remaining code is two lines starting on line 21.
This is just the code we used further down the programme
to display the scrollbar.
Now we use the scrollbar classes grid method
just like we did in the main code.
So we know the row and column because they were
passed into a grid method, so we can put the scrollbar
at the same cell on the grid.
So consequently now, our scrollbar should display
its own scrollbar and we can remove
the scrollbar code from the main programme.
So if we come down to the main code
and I'll just put that up on the screen.
So after the code on line 46, we can actually
delete these four lines.
The blink line and then these other three lines here,
the tkinter.scrollbar, the grid and the yscroll command,
because we're implementing those in our class.
I'm deleting that and likewise for album,
if we go down, we're going to delete
those four lines as well.
One, two, three, four, for the same reason,
we've got it in our own class.
All right, so that now looks a lot neater
and we haven't got the code that
we copy and pasted to create the scrollbars.
Let's just test the programme to make sure that it does work.
And I'm gonna have a look at the output.
And it actually looks like we have got a problem here.
You can see, we've got a scrollbar to the left here.
We've got one for albums, but we haven't got one for songs.
And I click on now what I've done there.
You can see the scrollbar that appears
to be for artists actually works for albums.
So I think I've got my sticky statement wrong.
And we go back and have a look.
So I've got sticky equals nsw,
so we're actually trying to stick the scrollbar
to the west, to the left in other words,
and it should be east, because we want it
to appear to the rightmost part of our listbox.
So I would suspect that's probably the error.
So let's just fix that, or run that rather,
and see that it works.
All right, that looks better to me.
We've got our scrollbar here that's disabled
because we haven't got any entries.
And for songs, we can see there's now a scrollbar.
And we've got the scrollbar that actually works
for albums now, that's much better.
All right, so you can see that they're all working now
and that's good.
Now we could improve it slightly by putting
a check in to the grid method.
At the moment, the scrollbar can only appear
on the right of the listbox.
That's assuming you've got the right sticky commands
pointing, going to the right.
So we could test the value of a sticky that's passed in
and then if it specifies east instead of west,
make the scrollbar sticky to the west.
So I'm not gonna do that now, but give it a go
if that's something you wanna do.
All right, so I'm gonna close that down.
And at this point, we've successfully subclassed
the tkinter listbox to create our own scrollbox,
as well as provide it some additional functionality.
So this is great use of inheritance.
What I'm going to do, though, is finish by splitting
the old-style call to the grid method.
So I'm gonna come back here and look at it on,
here in the code.
And what I might do is just separate this
on to two lines, even though we haven't
actually got an error, we have actually
quite a long line there.
So even though it's only a comment,
what I'm going to do is after the rowspan,
we'll just put this on a separate line.
All right, so at this point now we're ready
to continue and take this scrollbox class further.
And what we'll do in the next video
is we'll start work on creating a subclass of scrollbox
that populates itself from the database.
So see you in the next video.