So, in the previous two videos
we've talked about lists and
figured out how they work in Python.
So, what I'm gonna do now is just
run you through another example
of a more complicated version and
then move onto a challenge.
Now, what we're gonna do is we're gonna
use a concept we've used earlier,
which is a meal in a cafe.
So, what I'm going to do
is type in some code.
I'm going to actually delete what
we've got on the screen here
because we don't need it anymore.
And I'm going to start typing menu
equals two empty square brackets,
which is an empty list.
Then we do menu.append.
Notice the square brackets.
Egg, spam, bacon.
Bacon like so.
So that's our first entry and I'm just
gonna copy the first part of this so
I can copy it and
paste it rather than type it each time.
The next menu option is going to be egg,
sausage, bacon.
Next one is going to be egg, and spam.
Next one, egg, bacon, spam.
Next one, egg, bacon,
sausage, spam.
Next one is going to be spam,
bacon, sausage, and more spam.
Oops.
Then we're going to have two more here.
Spam, egg, spam.
Spam, bacon, spam.
And the last one we're gonna have is spam,
egg, sausage, spam.
So first things first,
you might be wondering why is there so
much spam in these meals?
Well, the menu's actually taken
from a Monty Python sketch.
And if you want to search the Internet for
Monty Python spam sketch,
then you can find out more about that.
You actually watch it on YouTube as well
when you feel you need to take a break.
So incidentally that sketch is the reason
we now refer to junk email as a spam.
But anyway so what we've done here is
we've actually created the empty list
as you saw on line one.
And we then went through and
appended each of the meals to it.
And of course each of the meals as you'll
now see in square brackets is actually
listed its own right containing
the details of that meal.
So we can actually print something out.
We can type print Menu.
Actually run that.
We can actually see the entries.
So it's a little bit hard to see because
it's actually menus within menus,
but you can sort of see that there's
the first on there on the screen,
separated by a comma, and they've
each got their own square brackets to
indicate they're actually each
a list in their own right.
Now that we've actually got a list and
we've got a lot of entries.
We can actually start writing a for
loop and
actually testing to see
how the in operator works.
So we could do something like for
meal in menu.
Then we could put if not spam
in meal, print meal.
So if we actually run this and
I'll just comment out this first line
here, just to remove the confusion.
And what that should do, and what that
actually does is only shows the entry
which is on line three
that doesn't contain spam.
And again each of the items on
the menu are themselves lists.
So the for loop here initially, for
meal in menu, is going through and
grabbing a list with each iteration.
So the first time it goes through the for
loop, the meal variable is set to the
list, which is the first list in the list.
So to speak.
And from there we can put
if not spam in meal, and
that's actually searching through that
individual list, the list that of
course is sort of a sub-list of
a major list, if that makes sense.
Then we're actually determining that that
wasn't in there, and we're only printing
out the contents if the word spam wasn't
found as one of the list entries.
So again, you can see that
Python is extremely powerful,
the way it's been designed and how it
actually handles this, is like this.
Okay, so it's time for a challenge.
What I am going to do is go to the first
line and paste in the challenge.
And that should be without spam.
So let's actually talk now about what
the challenge is actually about.
So what you need to do is
add to the program below.
So that if it finds a meal
without spam in it,
that it then prints out each of
the ingredients of the meal.
At this stage you can see that we printed
out everything, but you need to actually
go through each individual item,
rather than just printing the entire list.
So you'll need to set up the menu as
we did in lines five to 13 there.
So type that in to start with, and
then you'll need to modify the for
loop in some way.
This code down here.
So then, basically prints out
each ingredient separately,
rather than just printing out just
the list as it's currently doing.
Okay?
So, pause the video.
Go away and actually see if you can
come up with a solution to that.
When you're finished,
come back and check my solution.
Okay so how did you get under?
Did you figure it out?
So we're actually on the right track here.
We've actually got a lot of
the code in build already.
So we've got the first loop the outside
loop with is going through each meal
that's in the menu list
then grabbing that meal.
So that needs to stay there.
We also need to put the if not in there,
so
that we only get the meals
that haven't got spam in them.
And we can print out this initial list.
We can leave that in there like
we're seeing on the screen.
But what we then need to do is
iterate through the list of
entries in this particular meal and
print those out.
So to do that, we stay at this indentation
level cuz we're only processing a meal
if it doesn't contain spam.
And we type in for ingredient in meal,
colon print ingredient,
so that is literally it.
So we are taking it to the next level
we're actually now going through the list
from the meal.
So first, the outer entry, the initial for
loop, that was the master list,
the list of all the menus, whereas the
inner list for ingredient in meals is just
as you can see it's actually
the ingredients within a specific list.
So, if we actually run that now.
We finally get the output egg,
sausage, bacon, and
we're getting that because there's only
one entry in here that hasn't got spam..
And then also, we're then cycling
through that list that we retrieved, and
actually printing out
the individual items.
So, that's it.
That's the challenge,
I hope you did well with that.
And, I hope you've got
a lot out of this section.
And, I'll see you in the next video.