In this video, we want to download and
install Python for the Mac platform.
So to do that we're going to go to
python.org in a browser,
so python dot o r g.
Once we get there we're gonna click on downloads, and notice when I do
that I've got the option over here to
download for Mac OSX. I just need to
come over here and click on that. Choose
the latest version, which you can see on
the screen, as of the time I'm recording,
3.7.3, so I'm
gonna click on that. That's now downloading and you probably
saw it in the top right hand corner
there, that's already finished. So I'm
going to go to finder and check that out,
and I'm going to double click the pkg file to start installing it.
And what I'll do is I'll close down the browser now because we're finished with that,
for now at least.
Alright I'll just close down find as well.
Alright so I'm going to click on continue.
Click on continue, click on continue, click
on agree and click on install.
Enter my password,
and that'll go through and configure and install Python.
Alright so at this point we're actually
done. We can end the video here, so skip
ahead now to the installation of
IntelliJ IDEA, where we actually
start installing the IDE that we're going to be using to type our Python programs in this course.
See you in that next video.