so continuing on from the last video so
global keyword tells Python to
look for a variable in the global scope
which is the modules name space but the
non local keyword tells it to look
for that variable in the enclosing
scopes and you could see what we've done
differently to other videos is
we've got an embedded function here that we
didn't have at the blackjack program so
that's why on line 7 the global keyword wasn't appropriate so again the non local
keyword if that is telling Python to
look for the variable in the enclosing
scope so non local won't check the
global name space though so a
non local variable must exist in the enclosing
scope but not be global otherwise if it
was global of course you would use the keyword
global to do that another thing to know
about the non local variables is that they
must exist in the enclosing scope
they can't be created in other words by the non local keywords so if we change this to try and put a declaration
in their we get an error...end of statement expected
because it's looking for us just to define
the variable to say that it's a non-local
variable but it has to actually exist as
I mentioned in the outer scope or in the
enclosing scope to be more precise now
although we didn't do this we could have
created our global variables for
blackjack in the new_game method and they would have been
available in the main program but it's
not considered good style to that and
can lead to difficulty debugging the programs
but it's there and it is actually
allowed but the same is not true for non local variables and that's because Python
doesn't know which enclosing scope the should have existed and has really has no
way to know whether to create them so
they must already be present in an
enclosing scope or you get an error for that reason so at this point its a
good time to point out that the only
things that create scope in Python are
modules functions and classes now I've already
talked about variables in a module
being defined in a while for loop and
then and remaining available to the rest
of the program but that's because they
become part of the global name space now
that can seem odd if you come from Java
for example but the idea that functions
introduced a new scope will be familiar
know when you define a function Python creates a new name space for it and
any variables are part of the local scope and to that end we actually printed out the local
variables using the locals function in
the blackjack game a few videos ago so non
local tells python to look for
variables in an enclosing function and
if it doesn't find it there to check in a
functioning closing that and so on
it will not though check the global name space
as I mentioned so if you remember
that it doesn't include globals then non local is a good name for it variables that are not
local to the current scope ok so
hopefully that made a lot of sense
earlier implied that functions can be
nested inside functions and themselves
are themselves nested in another
function its quite rare to have
more than one level of nesting in any
code that did so would have to be quite
complicated so I use a variation of the
spam function in the tutorial to
demonstrate a deeper level of nesting
and bearing in mind its probably not
something you have to do very often but
the functions would be very similar and
just returned different amounts of spam
in this case but that will let us focus on
the scope issues rather than getting
bogged down in complicated code so we are
gonna create a new Python file called
spam.py and we are going to enter the
following code in it and just do a test
on this and have a look at these functions so...
....
.....so as you can see
here the function spam one contains
another function called spam 2 and
that's spam 2 function contains a third
function called spam 3 and if we run this
you can see  that spam 1 calls the spam 2 function and then adds its
result on to spam 1's text and
spam 2 in turn adds the result of the spam
3 function on its text and
subsequently we get a lot of spam
now to get a clearer idea of what's
happening here we can print out the locals
dictionary from inside each of the
functions I'm going to use a format
string so that we can add a label
before each dictionary to be sure where
it came from so let's go ahead and do
that i'm gonna start in spam 3....
....
so if we run this again now I've done the same thing in my haste here
so that should have been tabbed over
my bad their when I was adding the new lines so
try that again now we can see now and you can see that
it's showing which names are local to each function and we can see that for example
the function spam 3 just contains
the string variable z but spam 2
contains the string variable called y
you can see it here nearly off the screen but it also contains
a function as you can see there
called spam 3 you can see that reference their and also spam 1 has got a local variable X
and a function called spam 2 as you can
see here so within spam 1
itself we can't refer to the
variables y&z because variables in an
inner scope aren't available to the outer scope but however inside spam 2 we can
refer to x and inside spam 3 we can
refer to both X&Y
so an inner scope has access to the variables defined in an outer scope and we can use the
outer variables and spam 2 spam 3 lets do that by making small change to the code so
close it down lets have a look on what its gonna look like so if we change this now and I'll make that even....
....
and run this to make sure it works so you could see that is working ok
and because we're not assigning to X&Y in
the inner functions the names don't shadow
the variable in the outer scope and as a
result the values are then available for
use now I'm gonna demonstrate scope and
it's not necessary sensible thing
to do here but it will demonstrate what
we're trying to get across to you and
the reason is...
lines 16 and 17
cam be combined into a single expression
and when I change them lets have a look
and see what happens so this here I'm gonna make...
now the mini challenge here is before actually
running this program can you work at
what's going to happen and why its going
to happen because I only done a simple thing
as you can see I've merged lines 16 and 17 to make it
one line but I want you to see if you can
figure out what's going to happen and
why so pause the video now and have a think about it and when
your ready to continue come back and we'll go
through it
ok so hopefully you have a look at it
you might be actually curious if you didn't
figure it out so let's talk about what
actually happens now the change I made was
quite simple and it might appear at
face value to be a simple optimization
but in actual fact that simple
optimization breaks the code and without
starting the spam 2 function it wasn't obvious that the code was gonna break
so lets run it first to confirm that there
is a problem and you can see we get
these weird errors so three variable X is
referenced before assignment in closing
scope
we got errors here on line 2016 and 11
so what actually happened is that spam
2 the function attempts to use the
value of x but spent spam 2 is called during the
initial assignment to X so x doesn't
yet have a value as a result we get the
error free variable X
this down here on the bottom
free variable x referenced before
assignment in closing scope so theirs
actually 3 lessons to learn from the
simple change I'm gonna move the it their so we can look at the source code at the same time while we are talking about it so
the three things are wherever possible
try to write functions so that they only
use local variables and parameters only
access global and non-local variables
when it's absolutely necessary if you
can see an unexpected code such as our
use of 2 lines to assign x and even also to assign y on line 11 and 12 think carefully before
changing them because it could be that
the programmer who wrote them was having a
bad day but also their could be a very
valid reason why they used 2 lines
when one would appear to do so no matter
how trivial a change do you think you've
made test the program thoroughly to make
sure you haven't broken anything that's
often simple changes like that that will
actually break code and major changes
will probably get through testing anyway
but very simple modifications can get
overlooked and this will be a case of
the change that I've made on the 16 and 17 to
merge them into one line would be
something with that would often
get overlooked and actually there's a fourth
lesson here as well and that is that if your write unexpected
code such as our use of 2 lines we assigning X&Y make sure you include a
comment to explain why so the next
person who works on your code doesn't do
what you've just done so what we do is undo the change put it back to how it was
before and we come back and say....
.....and on lines 11 and 12 we would
say something like....
...you will actually be surprised how often that next person is
you so coming back to the code perhaps
have looked at the program you have written for a
number of days weeks months or even years so the person that you are writing
this comments for could ultimately be used and I just put in an extra space here should have bee watching the
warnings to keep the compiler happy so yeah the person could actually be you
that you're trying to help out here and you can quickly really forget why you did something
in a certain way so using comments like
this to explain anything you do that's
not obvious is very very highly
recommended now before I finish this
section out theirs two more things to look
at the first is very simple
their at the module level the local scope is
the same as the global scope so we can
see that by printing both out at the end of
the program so lets add these couples of lines of output
to just check that so...and if you run that
and if we scroll across you should find that the basically
the two outputs from locals to globals
is giving us the identical output here you can
see this looking pretty well
identical right through to the end
everything is basically identical that's
for those last two lines of output which
correspond to the output from line 22 to 23
so that confirms that in the module scope locals and globals are the same
second thing though is a bit odd and
you might be wondering about it if
you paid careful attention to the
program's output since I added the non
local variables so lets have a look at that again so spam 3 original
had a single variable called z but
now you can see up here it also has
y as local and spam 2 you see that has
now got an x its got the x as local as
well now this is very odd it seems to go
against everything I have just discussed
about non local variables but in fact
the explanation behavior of non local
variables is perfectly correct so
there's nothing to worry about what we are
seeing is a result of the way the locals
function works and some optimization of
the part of Python and that's because whether
you use a non-local variable in the way
we've done python adds it to the local
name space so that it doesn't have to
go hunting through all the enclosing
scopes every time you use it so it
still referring to the non local variable
its just a reference it in locals to make everything run faster and it might be worth your while
having a look at the documentation for the locals function as well I'm just gonna bring that up on the screen
theirs the link on the screen as you can see up there so we go to that
theirs locals so a free variable is a variable that's
used in a scope where it has not been
defined which is exactly the same thing
as a non-local variable when working
with the scope of variables it is helpful
to remember the analogy
LEGB and that stands for local enclosing
global built-ins and list the order to
which Python searches for names so again
its local enclosing global and built-ins so
closing refers to non-local or free
variables that I've discussed in this
lecture now globals we have also seen and we have
looked at how to use it and assigned to
global variables of course in our functions built in refers to the name that are built-in to Python
and that we've been using throughout the course
we've got into the builtins.py module
quite a few times now to have a look
at the various functions and built-ins are
the final place that Python will possible look to when trying to resolve a
name now if you remember and understand that LEGB in order and again that is local enclosing
global built-ins if remember that
for resolving names and take note of the
warnings that IntelliJ gives you should be
quite comfortable with the way Python
scoping works and then should also
be able to use non-local and global variables
when you need to
ok finally that brings this section to an end it's been a very very long one we've
looked at a few modules from the Python standard library and also the
documentation so that other modules should
be much easier to use when a program
needs the functionality they provide and
of course we also had a look at GUI
programming called TKinter we did a lot with that but we are not done with that yet and theirs few more
things we need to come before you can
use it to its full potential and then
covered functions showing you how they are or what they are I should say and how to write your own
and in the process we learn about scope in Python now classes are also
created a new namespace
and we are gonna be covering object oriented
programming in classes in the next section
so I'll see you their