Alright so why are we getting these
errors that showed up at the end of the
last video? Well we've got errors because
you must have valid code inside each of
the code blocks. A comment doesn't count.
Notice that there's a red tick in the
right margin next to lines 15 and 18, and
I can select them up here, and also there's this
red squiggle under each comment on
line 15 and 18. Now this can be confusing
when you're starting but it's the syntax
rules of Python.
You must have code inside a code block.
If there's no code, and that includes
just having a comment, then you'll get an
error like this. So notice that there
isn't an error on line 21 or line 24.
There is code inside those two blocks,
so we don't get that error. If getting an
error wasn't confusing enough though, the
error message makes it even worse. And if I
hover over one of them again, you can see the
error we're getting there is: indent
expected. But of course, looking at that
you can see those comments are already
indented - they're obviously indented.
So we can see that on the screen. You may
not see an error if you're using a
different IDE, but you will get it when
you try to run your code. So things like
this can have you tearing your hair out.
Fortunately, there are very few times
when something like this happens, and now
that I've pointed it out, you'll remember
it and avoid tearing your hair out.
What you'll often find programmers doing,
is adding a dummy bit of code inside the
indented block, to clear this error.
So there's a specific keyword in Python for that
and that's called pass. So I'm going to
come up here to line 16, tab over and
type pass. So come down to line 19,
tab over and type pass again. Now pass
doesn't do anything, but it makes the
code syntactically correct. So think of
it as a placeholder for the real code
that you'll add later, and you can see
that that's fixed the errors and we've
now got the basic structure of our code.
Alright so it's time to work out what
we really want to do in place of those
pass statements. If the computer had to
guess higher, well then we alter the
low value of the range and go around the
loop again. So let's do that. So I'm going
to replace that pass on line 16 with low
equals guess plus 1,  which is in
line with the comment that I've
added on line 15. Now similarly, if we have
to guess lower, then the new high value is
one less than the current guess. So
come out to line 19, replace the pass,
and it's going to be high equals guess
minus 1. Alright so the last step now
in our algorithm, is to break out of the
loop when the guess is correct. So we're
going to come down here. Then on line 22,
we're going to add the keyword break
so that we do just that. We break out
of the while loop if the computer has
successfully guessed it. If you've
programmed in other languages, you might
be wondering if we could use a case or
switch there. Don't bother searching for
how to do that in Python. Python doesn't
have a case or switch statement. If you
haven't programmed before, that won't mean
much to you, don't worry about it.
They don't exist in Python. Alright, so
that's our algorithm implemented with
Python code. So we're doing a bit more.
We're also counting the number of
guesses. So that means therefore we
should increase the count before the
loop goes around again. So we need to
come down and add that code, and we
both need to add it at the same
level as the if, and I'm gonna
put it down here on line 27. Actually, what
I'll do is I'll come down here and I'll
just, to be consistent with our code,
we're going to take that up one line,
and over here, on line 26 now, I'm going to
type guess, or guesses rather, equals
guesses plus 1. So be careful with the
indentation there. That line must be
indented one level, as I have it there, so
that it's inside the while loop but not
inside the else block. So for now, we're going
to ignore this suggestion from IntelliJ.
I'm going to talk about that in the next
video, but at this point we've now
finished, our program is finished. Check
your code carefully and then in the next
video, we'll test it out to make sure it
works. See you in the next video.