Alright, so to see some more things we
can do with tuples, we need to open up
the tuples_intro.py file. Now
we're going to keep the five tuples but
delete everything else after line eleven,
and I'm going to comment out these four
lines, as well. Alright, so each tuple
represents an album, with three items for
the title, artist and year. So instead of
actually printing out metallica 0
through to metallica 2,  as we did
earlier in the commented out code,
we can actually unpack the tuple. Let's
have a go at doing that. So on line 12, I'm
going to type title comma artist comma
year equals metallica, and let's print
the three items. So print title print
artist and print year. Alright, let's run
the program to make sure that we've
unpacked the tuple correctly.
We get Ride the Lightening as the title of the
album, Metallica for the artist and 1984
as the year that it was released.
It's much easier to see what the values
represent now, rather than those index
values on lines 8 through 10.
You're far less likely to make a mistake using
these names. Having to remember which
item number corresponds to the item you
want, makes it very easy to make a mistake.
Now, just as an example here, let
me put some code in. So we're going to type table
is equal to parentheses, and we'll start
with Coffee table in double quotes,
then we want a comma 200 comma 100 comma 75
comma 34.50, 34.50, and print
parenthesis on the next line, table square brackets 1,
within the square brackets, * table
square brackets 2. So if we run this,
then we get the result of 20,000,
the code's calculating the area of a coffee
table, but it's not easy to see that when
you look at the code. And it's also very
easy to get the index numbers wrong,
especially if you're dealing with a
tuple that contains lots of items.
What we can do is make the code more readable,
and a lot easier to work with,
by unpacking the tuple. So I'm going to
type, on line 20, name comma length comma
width comma height comma and price is
equal to table, and print parentheses
length * width. Run the program again.
We'll check that we've got the same value,
and it's now I think, a lot more
obvious, what we're actually printing out
on line 21. When we come to use those
values, we don't have to remember whether
the width is at position two or position
three. We unpack the tuple into
variables on line 20, and then we're
using those variable names in our code.
I can't stress enough how useful this is,
but it's also very easy to forget.
JP suggests that I include a reply he gave
to a student's question, when he forgot
to unpack a tuple. So both myself and JP
are certainly not ashamed to admit our
mistakes, if it will help you to learn.
Alright, so here's the question;
I'm going to paste in the link in a browser.
Alright, so here we are. So Aatif had
mentioned using a list comprehension,
so JP added one to the end of his first reply.
So in the code that appears after "If you
want to use a comprehension", which you
can see on screen now,
there was references - you can see there,
value zero in square brackets, value 1 in
square brackets and value 2 in square
brackets. Now in his second reply, and you
can see Aatif's reply there, then JP,
mentions here that he wasn't thinking
about unpacking value in the comprehension.
So you can see here, x, y &amp; z are unpacked
inside the comprehension. Below that you
can also see the equivalent for loop
down here. That also unpacks the values
into x, y and z - that's on line two.
Now, I've mentioned this for a few
reasons, not just to mock JP.
We'll look at that in the next video.