Alright, so let's go over the solution
to the unpacking challenge, we talked
about in the last video. Currently, each
of the items in our albums list is a tuple.
When we iterate over albums, we get
each tuple in turn, and we can unpack it
at the same time. So the change is to
line ten, so let's make a change to line ten.
So what I'm going to do is delete
the album part of the for album
statement, and instead, what I'm going to
do is type in there, for name comma artist
comma year, then leave the rest of
the line as it was, which was in albums.
If we run the program now, we get the
same output as we did previously.
So that's one solution. So you may have left
line ten alone, and instead, unpacked the
tuples on the next line. What I'm going
to do is paste in this code, right after
the existing code. Alright, so I'll come
down here and I'll paste in the code.
So this will produce the same output. So
we'll run that firstly, to confirm that
it is the case, and you can see we've got
the identical output there. Now it's not
quite as efficient, compared to the
previous loop - the one starting on line ten -
but it has the advantage that you also
have the original tuples available.
Each time around the loop, you can refer to
album, if you need to. Most of the time,
though, you should use the first loop,
where we unpack the tuples on line ten.
Alright, so as well as showing you how
to unpack tuples, we've also seen
that the items in a sequence, can be a
sequence type themselves. So here, our
albums list contains tuples. Notice that
the list is homogeneous. All of the items
it contains are of the same type. In other
words, here, they're all tuples. The tuples
are heterogeneous - each one contains two
strings and an int.
In the next version of this program, we'll make a change to add some songs to the albums.
See you in the next video.