Alright, so let's talk a bit more about nested
indexing. At the end of the last video,
I left you experimenting with indices
in our nested data structure. You should be
able to get the details for any album
and song, from the list. Now if we want
to print the song Mayhem, which I talked
about, we need to start with the fourth
album in the list. That's at index
position three. So go down to our code here.
So we need to change line 47, to access
the fourth album - so we change the
2 to a 3 there. The index for the
songs list stays the same - all the songs
lists for each album, are at index
position three - so we don't need to change that at all.
But Mayhem is the third song, or is the
third item rather, in the songs for that
album, so we use index position 2 for that.
So on line 53, I'll change the 1 to a 2.
The song title itself, is at the same position -
position 1 in the tuple -
so the rest of the code stays the same.
Run the program. We confirm we get
Mayhem printed out. Alright, so let's
see how we can do that all in one go.
So we come down, add some code:
line 57, I'm going to type mayhem is
equal to albums, left square bracket and
3 in it, another set of square
brackets with 3 in it, and another
set of square brackets with 2 in it,
and the final set of square brackets
with 1 in it, and let's print mayhem
on the next line.
Now before running the program,  compare those index numbers with the value's that we've used
on lines 47, 50, 53 and 55. You can probably
work out what will be printed.
If not, my choice of variable name's giving it away.
Let's run the program and see.
We get Mayhem printed out again.
So I said I was gonna take this slow, and I've just thrown
that horrible-looking line 57 at you.
We've seen what it does - now we'll look
at how it's done it. I'll take it step by step,
starting with the first index. Let's go
and add some code: print albums
and in square brackets, the number 3, then closing parenthesis.
Now albums 3 is the tuple for the Imelda May
album. It's got four items, two strings
an int for the year and a list. Let's run
that to confirm, and we can see the
output there, confirming that. So looking
at that, you can see the list of songs
is at position three, and we can add that
index to get just the songs lists.
So let's have a go at doing that.
Alright, so I'll duplicate line 60 again.
I'm gonna go down to the end of the line. I'm
gonna add to the end of the line,
a 3 in square brackets. And again, that's
for the list of songs. Run the program
and we should get the list of songs, and
you can see that is the case down the
bottom there. Alright, back on line 47, we
bound the variable album to albums 3,
and then on line 50, we bound
songs to the item at index position 3
in the album. So looking at the
code, line 61 is producing the same thing
without using intermediate variables. So
now if we want to print the Mayhem tuple,
we can add index 2 to the end.
So let's duplicate the line again,
and come down to the end and add 2 in
square brackets. Run the program again to
confirm what we get. This time, you can
see we get the third item from the songs
list, which you can see above there - that
line of output - the item at position 2.
And that's a tuple, and then we can
index into that to get just the title.
So let's have a go at doing that again,
duplicate the line again. So I'll add 1
in square brackets, on that line. We'll
run it again, and we should see the title
printing out, as you can see, and it is on
the screen there. So each index indexes
into the object produced by the previous
one, as those four lines of code
demonstrate. Alright, so the next video isn't
a video - it's a document giving you
some more things to practice, to help you
get used to indexing into a
nested structure. So have a look at that document,
then I'll see you in the video following that.