So running our high-low game in the
debugger can be a bit slow. The loop is
only going around 10 times, but if we had
a much larger range of numbers, you'd
soon get pretty bored clicking the
Step Over button. When I ran the program
in the last video, things really only got
interesting when the computer guessed 99.
What would be really good would be if we
could get the debugger to stop at that
point, when guess is 99. Luckily, we can do
just that. I'll show you, now, how to do
that with both IntelliJ and PyCharms
debuggers. But if you're using a
different IDE, your debugger may well
have a similar feature.
Unfortunately, the idle debugger doesn't
have conditional breakpoints, which is
what we need here. So if you're using
IDLE, you'll have to step over your code in
the usual way.
So to achieve this, firstly, set a
breakpoint on line eight, which is our
while loop, and we're not interested in
seeing the first few lines being
executed. The debugger's going to stop each
time the loop goes around, which isn't
really what we want. We're really only
interested in what happens once low and
high are equal. So to set a condition on
a breakpoint, right-click the breakpoint
dot in the margin. Now the condition that
we want here, typing into this field,
is low is equal to high. So I'm going to
type low equal high - remember to use two
equal signs, and I'm gonna click Done
once I've done that. So notice that
there's now a little question mark next
to the red dot, as well, to indicate that
it's a conditional breakpoint. So I'm gonna start
the debugger, as we would normally do,
and you saw me right click in the editor
pane and choose debug. I like to do that,
as per normal, because that makes sure
that I'm debugging the correct file,
because you might have a different file
selected up here. In which case, it would
be invoking that file and not this one.
In any event, debugger test per normal,
press ENTER to start. Alright so I'm
going to use the same number as we did
in the last video - 100. So I need to
go through and let the computer pick,
so it's gonna be lower -
I'll just go through and do this. So far, the
breakpoint hasn't been hit yet, but it'll
do that as soon as I enter h now, to go
higher. I do that, you can see what's
happened there. We stopped on line eight
and low does equal high. We can see both
values there, in the variables pane at
the bottom of the screen, for low and for
high. So that means the condition will
now evaluate to false, and the while
loop will terminate. If we click Step
Over, let's just check that that does
happen. You can see that did happen. Basically,
because the while loop terminated normally,
we didn't break out of it. Execution is
continuing in the else block. As you can
see, sitting on line 30. We switch to the
console tab. If I click on resume program now,
you see we've got the last two lines of output
there. So we should do that again, this
time with a number that doesn't cause
low and high to become equal. So I'm
going to set a breakpoint on the break
statement on line 23. Okay, I'm gonna start the
debugger again, enter to start. This time
my number's going to be 250, so I'm gonna
press Enter, which I've done, and I'm going to
lower. This time that answer is correct
so I'm going to press c for correct, and
we've now hit the breakpoint, as you can
see, so the debugger stops on our
breakpoint now, on line 23. We're about to
break out of the loop. So that means that
the else block won't be executed. Go back
to the console tab - we can see that the
computer got it in two guesses. So we use Step Over -
that confirms that the else block
isn't executed. There's no more code and
the program's terminated, as you can see.
Alright, so that's what else does when
used with a loop. Because python reuses
the word else for this, it can be
confusing. It would have been a lot
clearer if Python used something that,
perhaps, made a bit more sense -
something like, instead of else, perhaps
completed. That would probably have made
a lot more sense, or perhaps, no break.
But unfortunately, that's not the case.
It doesn't use either of those - it uses else -
so I'll just undo both of those and go
back to what we had. But at this point,
you do now know what else does when used
in a for or a while loop. You don't have
to use it in your own code, but you may
come across it in code that you have to
work with, and now hopefully, you've
got a good understanding of what it does.
Alright, so in the next video, we're going
to see else used in an earlier example
from this section.
See you in the next video.