In an earlier video in this section, we
had an example of a while loop in
adventure.py. So if we open that file
in the editor, if you haven't already
done so, let's review the problem we had.
So if we run the program now, and type
quit to a break out of the loop, we get
the output Game over which is what we
want, but the program also prints aren't
you glad you got out of there, as well. So
we don't really want to print that
message if the player quits out of the
game. Now you should be able to see that
fixing that problem is going to be
pretty easy. If we break out of the while
loop, else can be used to prevent that
message from happening. So all we really
need to do is add an else here on line
10 : enter, and making sure that the
print is now indented. So the code in the
else block will now only be executed if
the loop terminates normally. It won't be
executed if we break out of the loop. So
let's run the program to test that. Let's
start off by entering up and the loop
goes round again. If we enter quit at
this point, we break out of the loop and
you can see we've got the message Game
over but not the message on line 11. We
should also test what happens when the
loop terminates normally so let's run
the program again, and this time we're
going to enter a direction - I'm gonna
enter east - and now, you can see, we've
got the message aren't you glad you got
out of there showing, which is correct.
Now there are other ways to achieve the
same thing. You don't have to use else
with a loop, but it can be useful and you
will see it being used in code out there.
Alright so that's actually the end of
this section. In the next section, we're
going to look at some data structures
that are built into Python. Before that
though, I want to finish this section
with a brief summary and a challenge.
So I'll see you in the next video.