Alright, so let's continue now with our
mutable.py file, from the last video.
I want to start with a question here - how
many lists are there in this program?
If you're not sure, keep watching. If you
think you can work out the answer, then
pause the video and come back when you
have an answer. Okay, the question doesn't
make much sense. Another way you could
have asked it is, what will be the
contents of another_list? So
pause the video and come back when you
have an answer to that question.
So did you get the answer? Well there's
only one list, and we can confirm that by
printing another_list. So let's
do that on line 15: print parentheses and
another_list. So if we run this now, another_list also
contains cookies, as you can see. So we've
got one list and we've added cookies to it
on line 12 - let's just bring the rest of
the program into view. It doesn't matter
whether we refer to our list using
shopping_list or another_list -
both names have been bound
to the same object, and that object now
has cookies added to it. To labor the
point, let's create a few more references
to our shopping list. I'm gonna start on line 17.
I'm going to type a equals b equals c
equals d equals e equals f equals
another_list. Python allows us
to do that - chain assignments, as I've
done on line 17 -
and that's actually equivalent to the
code I'm about to paste in here,
absolutely identical to that code as
well. But obviously, that's a lot more
typing, so I'm going to delete those
lines because line 17 does the same
thing and it's a lot more concise. So all
six of those names; a, b, c, d, e and f,
are now bound to the same object, as
another_list. That means we've
now got eight references to the same
list. There's still only one list though.
We haven't copied the list -
we've just bound more names to it. We can
use any of those names to refer to the
list, so let's type in some more code.
So on line 18, print parentheses, with a in
the parentheses, line 20, print
parentheses double quotes Adding cream,
line 21, b.append parentheses
double quotes cream - do that in lowercase -
line 22, print c in parentheses, line 23,
print d in parentheses. If we run the
program now, you can see we've got cream
in the list - no matter which of the names
we use to refer to it, we've got cream,
as you can see there. I used b to append cream
to the list, on line 21.
When we print c and d on lies 22 and 23,
we get the same list printed with cream.
So try printing out the other names to
check that they're all the same.
Pause the video and come back when you've
tried that. So there's still only one
list with eight aliases, that we can use
to refer to it. Now having eight names
for the same object, isn't probably
something you'd often do. That's a bit
excessive, but having two or three
aliases can be quite common. You'll see
why that's useful later, when we look at
lists that contain lists. Alright, so I've
promised that we'd look at other things
that we can do with lists,
and we'll start on that in the next video.