in this video we're going to install the
sqlite command line shell for the Linux
computers now if you're using Windows or
Mac refer to the previous two videos
where we actually set up for those
platforms but if you're running linux
you're in the right place so let's get
started so Python includes sqlite
in its standard library so we don't need
to install anything to use sqlite
in our python programs but writing data
base code straightaway isn't the
easiest way to learn about sqlite
and the sql language because if you
get errors you have to work out if the
errors in your python code or the
sql statements that you actually use
so what we're going to do is we're going
to start by using the sqlite
command line shell so that we can create
databases in use sql commands
without having to worry about Python
code at this stage now on ubuntu linux
turns out this is really easy going to
start by opening a terminal session so
i'm just going to use the shortcut on ubuntu
which is control alt t that opens the
windows you can see they're obviously
I could have just come up here and just type
terminal in there to open up that way as
well
alright so installing sqlite3
firstly we check to see whether we've
got it we type...you can see that
it's saying that currently we haven't
got the program installed so again on
ubuntu linux we do...
...
....
and you can see that was really really
quick installation is only a small
program is already getting the
command-line shell not the sqlite
itself this point we can then check to
see whether sqlite is installed
type...you can see instead
of getting an error like we did
previously we can see its showing
the sqlite version number....
...and incidentally you
might see a slightly different version
number what I've got on the screen
but that's ok so long as you can
actually get it working and you can see
that we actually started the sqlite
command line shell your good to go and just
keep in mind specifically with ubuntu
i'm using 14.04 but if you're
using Ubuntu 16.04 you will actually get
a much later version but both versions
will actually work fine with the course
their is no prerequisites for a specific
version of sqlite3
alright so this point we've completed
the installation type...to get
out of the sqlite command line shell
....to close down the terminal
session and at this point we're done so
let's now move on to the next video
we're going to go through a bit of an
introduction on using sqlite see you
in the next video