Let's go over the solution to the
challenge I discussed in the last video.
How did you get on with it though? Did you
manage to change the code, to let the
user go back to the list of albums
without choosing a song? Well there's
only a couple changes to be made. At the
moment, we're breaking out of the loop,
and you can see that on line 25. Now we
don't want to do that, so what we're
going to do is delete the break and the
else, that its in - so these two. Delete those.
So now on line 25, we display the title
of the song. If no song's been chosen,
we don't want to do that. In fact, my IDE,
if we hover over title,
is giving me a warning. It says Name Title
can be not defined. If no song is selected,
title won't have a value. So we
can fix that there, by indenting line 25,
to make it part of the if block. So I can
come down here, indent it. Now, although it
doesn't matter to Python, we can make
the code a bit more readable by moving
line 25 up a line. Control shift up will
do that, on Windows, as well as Linux,
and I think it might be command shift up, but you
can check your bindings on a Mac, if you need to.
By doing that, it makes it pretty obvious
that line 26 isn't part of the if block,
and that's literally all the changes we
need to make. To confirm this, though,
let's test the program again, so
I'm going to run it. This time I'm going
to select option 2, Bad Company. That
displays the songs on the Bad Company
album. First thing I want to do is test
that I haven't broken anything.
So selecting option 2, should play the
track Rock Steady. Let me do that -
playing Rock Steady, so that's working, and
we get the albums list again, as well.
And what I'll do, just to make sure that,
if you're watching this with subtitles,
you can see it. I'm going to change
the View Mode to Window. We've still
got the output, from what we've been
running in this session, so far.
So I'm going to choose option 3, for Nightflight.
This time I'm going to make an
invalid choice - I want to select 0, or
type in 0. As you can see, no song's
played, and we get the albums menu again.
Now we're back to the album's menu.
I can select 0 or another invalid choice,
and the program exits, as you can see.
So make sure you test it more thoroughly, to make
sure it behaves well with all valid options.
At the very least, you should
test the first and last valid choices
in each list, and a choice from the middle
of the lists. The first and last options
count as edge cases, and it's very
important to test edge cases. So if your
solution behaves the same, then well done -
you've completed the challenge.
See you in the next video.