Now we've installed the IDE and the
Python plugin if you installed IntelliJ
IDEA rather than Pycharm, we need to make
sure that it can find Python. Now the
steps here are almost the same for
IntelliJ IDEA and Pycharm and the chances
are that it's sorted itself out,
but just in case it has it I'm going to
go through all the steps to configure
the Python SDK, now from IntelliJ IDEA
first from the welcome screen I'm going
to show you how to do that we could have
come over here click on configure let me
click on project defaults, then project
structure once we've done that we come
over here to the left hand side and
select SDKs and this is where we set up
the Python SDK. Now in pycharm let me
just swing over to Pycharm these
settings slightly different for Pycharm
click on configure and we select
preferences then we come over here to
the left and select project interpreter.
Now I've used the dark theme here
for pycharm just so you can tell at a
glance which IDE I'm showing on the
screen. Now Pycharm got this little cog
icon over here to the right of the
project interpreter drop-down list,
so I'm going to click on that and we're
going to choose add and that gets us to
the screen where we can actually
configure or rather add our Python interpreter,
we're going back to IntelliJ IDEA to get
to that same screen in IntelliJ IDEA
we just come over here and click on this
little plus button at the top of the
screen, we want to come down here we need
to select a Python SDK and that's
because IntelliJ IDEA can of course be
used for a range of languages, so I'm
going to select Python SDK
we've not basically got the same screen
now, very similar to what we saw in Pycharm
now you've got these options down the
left hand side these virtual
environments virtual ends I'm not going
to discuss those just yet because that's
because we're going to be looking at
them later in the course what they are
though is a way of keeping your Python
environments separate so that things you
install for one project don't affect
other projects you may be working on.
Now we're going to be looking at them from
the command line, so I won't be
discussing these options in IntelliJ or PyCharm
this is a Python course after all the
not an IntelliJ / Pycharm course but
once we have explained about virtual
environments virtual env these
options will make more sense, for now
let's get going, the things the steps you
need to take here for both IntelliJ IDE
and PyCharm is to select virtual env
which is selected by default and leave
the new environment selected over here
you want kind of come down here and tick
or check both boxes inherit global site
packages and make available to all
projects, so it's select both of those
now the location should be your home
directory and if you only plan to use
one version of Python you can leave that
here unchanged, otherwise what you can do
is add the words Python and the version
number to the end, so I'm going to do
that I'm gonna put a / on the end of
the path that has been created for me
I'm gonna type Python 3 point 6 so
IntelliJ or pycharm should have found
your Python 3.6 installation or whatever
version of python you're using you've
probably installed version 3.6 of python
going through the steps in this video
but note that python 3.7 is coming out
in 2018 late in 2018 so that's the
version of what they're if you've got
that option available to you, you can see
here that the base interpreter has been
filled out for me, if for some reason
that's blank then you want to come over
here and click on the ellipsis and you'd
never get or browse to the location
where you saw python being installed
previously but here we can see that
that's been found automatically by
IntelliJ and it should be found
automatically by pycharm if you're doing
if you're have installed that so
generally you shouldn't need to change
anything there and the only other thing
you'll need to do is click on ok,
you can see if it's a bit of a pause
there while it's actually looking and
then it's added all these things for us
automatically you can see that we've got
this set up nicely so what I'm going to
do is just swing back over to the python
now I'm going to show you the screen
that's popped up assuming you've
followed the same steps to configure it
just how we've configured this now for
IntelliJ IDEA so here we are back in a
pie chart and you can see that we've got
some configuration here now we've got
something in the project interpreter
drop-down box and I can click on ok and
now you've got it updated path and
interpreter for the first time so we get
that I'm able to complete and will just
quickly go back in just so I can show
you what it looks like, so now if you go
back to configure and select preferences
you can see now in a project interpreter
we've now got some things set up we got
our Python as well as pip and some setup
tools, so basically it's good to go at
this point one, so I'm just gonna go back
down to IntelliJ okay there. Alright so
basically at this point pythons
configured in both IntelliJ IDEA and
pycharm but there's one more change that
I want to make and that's to get the IDE
to show line numbers in our code and
once again these steps are the same for
both IntelliJ IDE and pycharm so I'm
gonna come over here and click on config
and go into preferences they want to
come over and expand editor expand
general then we want to click on
appearance and what you want to do is
make sure there's a check the checkbox
is ticked to the left of show line
numbers. Now if it isn't ticked you'll
want to click it and then click and then
now select ok in my case you can see
that it is selected in older versions of
IntelliJ IDEA when the installation
process was ran we found that this
wasn't checked by default and having a
checked is really handy because you can
see the line numbers in your code and
it's really particularly useful when you
get errors with the error message when
it talks about line 6 for example
if you've got the line numbers showing
you're able to quickly find where that
error is but again as you can see here
that option was set by default but just
to do a check anyway in either IntelliJ
IDEA or PyCharm to make sure that is
selected and then now finally just click ok,
and at this point you're ready now to
start programming in Python so moving
forward now in section
five, we'll write our first program so I'll
see you in section five.