So I feel it's really important that
you type along in this course.
So in other words, don't just watch the videos.
Engage with the videos, follow along, type in the
code as you see me typing it. and you'll
find you'll get a much better experience.
The reality is that watching the videos
only, will only get you so far in your
programming journey. Doing, in other words,
following along and typing as I mentioned,
will really help you master programming.
So typing in the program, running the
program, finding errors, making errors and
fixing them, well that's your ticket to
success and becoming a great
programmer. Basically, by going through
that process, you'll find that your skills
will improve dramatically. So it's really
highly recommended that you do follow
along for that reason, and I'll give you a bit
of an overview here, that what a lot of
students do with videos, is that they'll
actually watch a video once to get the
general feel for what's in the video.
Then they'll go back and watch it again,
and the second time by going through,
what they'll do is they'll actually type
along that second time. So they've got
the general idea from the first view, of
what the video is about, and they'll
follow along with the second. And basically,
as they see me typing something on the screen,
they'll do the same. And actually, typing
the same thing in with their computer
into their own computer, your computer in
other words, again, as I mentioned a few
times now, will help you become a
better programmer, and really helps you
understand the material when you're
actually typing it in, rather than just
watching it. So I know I've said that a
few times, but frankly, I think
it's really important and will
ultimately help you get the most out of your course,
out of this course, by actually doing that.
And keep in mind that I've said that
to watch a video twice, but look, you
don't necessarily have to watch a video
twice. It's just a suggestion, but one
thing I would suggest you do is, if
something is unclear, please do go back
and watch a video a second or maybe even
a third time if you don't understand it,
because watching it a second
time can really help understand.
And the analogy I'll use here is just, if you've ever
watched a movie, and watched it for the second time,
often you'll actually see things the second
playthrough of a video, of a movie rather,
that you didn't see the first time.
And it's much the same with training
videos like this Python course videos,
watching it for a second time,
something else might gel and sink in,
and you go 'oh now I understand that now'
because you've seen it for a second time.
So do that and don't be afraid to watch
a video for a second time,
to make sure you really
understand it. Now as for all that code
that I'm typing in, the source code,
that's available for you to download as well.
Just go to the lecture at the end
of the course, marked, unsurprisingly,
source code, and you can download it from
there. And in some situations  - there's
certain lectures in this course - you
might find that the code's attached to those
lectures as well. So check out the
resources sections with specific videos as well.
So the source code, downloading
it, that can be great to use as a
comparison tool to compare your code,
the code you've entered to your computer,
or into your computer, to the code
that we've gone through in the video.
Alright, enough about source code.
Let's move on now to the next video.