So it's now time to talk about ranges.
Now we've actually used ranges
a few times in for loops, and
we use that to loop
a specified number of times.
So it's time we take a more detailed
look at what they actually are.
So in Python 3 range is
actually a built in type.
But in Python 2,
it was implemented as a function.
So in a simplest form, we can create
a range just by specifying an n value.
So we could do something
like print(range(100)).
And if we actually run that, And
return a range,
which is a range from 0, 130.
It's not really terribly exciting,
but what it does do is show you to get
back a range object with a start of 0 and
a stop of 100.
Printing a range object
like that isn't useful.
And when they come into their own,
you get the most ever, you start iterating
over, for example, to cause the for
loop to repeat a block of code
many times as we've actually seen.
We can also use them to use them to
create another object such as the list.
So, as an example we can come back here
and actually type my under score list,
= listrange(10),
and now if we actually print my list.
Actually run that.
You notice how we've automatically
got these 10 elements through from
zero to nine just by actually
using the range and passing
the end range of 10 and automatically
created those elements for us.
So again, if you're passing a single value
to range the value's taken to be the end
value and the start value defaults
to zero in that scenario,
as you can see that with the first
element being zero right here at the top.
But you can also specify start range,
there's nothing stopping
you from doing that.
So you could do something like,
even = list(range (0, 10, 2).
Or we can try odd = list(range (1, 10, 2).
Print (even), print (odd).
That's just another more
extended use of the range.
And for some reason we've
some extra brackets here,
we'll get rid of those
brackets to make it valid.
We'll try running that.
And we can see now we've got 0,
2, 4, 6, 8, and 1, 3, 5, 7, 9.
So we're creating the list called even,
the first one from a range.
And we put the range of 0 as
the start ten as the end, but
you also use the steps,
that third number there to skip by two.
So we've actually got only even numbers.
By starting on zero and
skipping two with two, four, six, eight.
And likewise with the odd.
We did the opposite there.
We started on one.
Still went to the end range of ten,
but skip by two, and
then went to skip only the odd numbers.
So one, three, five, seven,
nine in this example.
Now Python 3 ranges are very
efficient in terms of memory.
In other words,
if you did something like this,
range[0,10] or range[0, say.
They're actually both gonna use the same
amount of memory, believe it or not.
So that's fine.
But
if we actually change the code up here,
and actually start using large numbers,
like instead of 10, putting 1,000, and
1,000 for both of those, that will
still actually work, as you can see.
Notice there was a slight pause there, and
now we've actually got
a huge set of numbers.
And It's literally going to be
1,000 elements, as you can see,
right through to 1,000 there.
998, 999 were the last elements,
bearing in the mind the last
one's always not used.
So you do need to go steady with
the zeroes though, because if you made
the value say 10,000, it can actually take
quite a while for the lists to be created.
And each list will occupy
a fair amount of memory.
So the range itself is always
gonna return the same amount.
I will use the same amount of space, but
when you're creating a list of that range
then of course the list has to actually
expand out to use all the elements within
that range and it can actually
start taking up a lot of memory.
Kind of interesting in python2 ranges
didn't behave like that at all.
Old bellies were calculated and
returned as a sequence,
remember we talked about sequences
to a degree in this course,
Python 2 also had an x range that behaved
much like the Python 3 range object does.
And Python 3 diversion 2x range has become
range and there's no longer an x range.
So if you're converting path from
two code and you actually see the x
range being used, you can just change
x range to range for pathway three and
it's going to work just fine.
Now ranges don't support
all the operations
that you can perform on sequences.
The reason for that is largely
because they represent sequences
that follow a defined pattern.
And so for example the multiplication
operator to repeat a range is not allowed,
nor is concatenation,
pending in other words.
Other than that you can perform all
the usual sequence operations on ranges.
Now we didn't actually cover the index
method when dealing with two sequences,
when we actually discussed strings and
lists.
But I'm gonna show you
how to do that now and
how you can access individual element
index over sequence using it.
So it's gonna come in handy for our code.
So I'm just gonna select that and
comment that code out.
And let's just top something like
my underscore string equals,
and we'll do all the letters
of the alphabet.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H,
I, J, K, L, M, N, O, P,
Q, R, S, T, U, V, W, X, Y, Z, or Zed.
As we say in Australia.
If I do a print(my_string.Index e).
And if I do a print my
underscore string for,
eventually run that So
the index of the character e is actually
the character position four in the string.
Remember, we count from zero.
So zero was A, one is B,
two is C, three is D, four is E.
So the index, dot index is
actually returning the number.
Pointing to the character position
of whatever you've actually
pass here as the parameter.
So we can also apply indexes.
Though the index function
to ranges as well.
So we can so
something like small underscore
decimals equals range zero, ten.
Then we're gonna do print small decimals.
We can also do print
small decimals.index3.
If we actually run that,
we actually get the value three there,
being the third,
being effectively the fourth position.
Cuz, of course, the counting again started
from ten, so zero, one, two, three.
And you can interestingly enough
also index into the range.
So for example,
if you created a large range,
like if we did something
like odd = range(1,
10000, 2) Print odd.
Bearing in mind this is just a range,
not a list of ranges as we
did earlier in the video.
We can actually do print, Odd, 985.
Run it five.
And you can see that actually gives us
the value from the 985th odd number,
which is pretty handy and
also pretty fast to process as well.
And it's also possible to check if a value
that you pass is actually in a range and
you can use that using the in operator.
So we can do something
like sevens equals range.
We'll start from seven.
Seven.
We can put x equal int, input.
Please enter a positive
number less than one million.
And we can put if x in sevens,
print is divisible using the replacement
field, divisible by seven.
Format x.
So we can actually run that.
Please enter a positive
number less than 1 million.
So you could do something like say, 987.
987 is divisible by seven.
And let's do a number that we
know isn't divisible by seven.
50.
We don't get any error,
don't get any messages,
I should say, because the number
50 isn't divisible by seven.
Because, again, just to confirm, we
started a range starting at number seven,
and went through to a million,
and only actually showing numbers that
were incremented by seven each time.
You can see that ranges can
actually be very powerful.
In addition to that you can also
apply slice ranges as well.
So we can print our small decimals
that we defined above again so
small decimals just to confirm
we're on that same page.
Then we can also do my_range
= small decimals 2, ::2.
Print my range just to see what it does.
Print my range.
And print(my_range.index(4), and
then actually run that after you
just actually answered a question.
So it was 50 there.
There's the two other ranges.
So you can see that my_range has become
the range from zero to ten in steps of
two, by just actually entering ::2 there.
And the index of the value
4 in the range is 2.
And of course the range is 0,
2, 4, 6, and 8.
Things to remember,
is that by not specifying the start and or
stop, it'll actually default to
the start and it'll end on the sequence.
So in other words specifying colon,
colon two as we did here.
What that means is to slice all
of the small decimal elements but
stepping every other value.
So ::2 was skipping one each time.
So just to clarify that
with another example.
Now we'll just comment
some of this code out now.
So if we do something like decimals
equals range, 0, 100 print decimals.
My_range = decimals.
It would be something like
three 43 print my range.
For I in my underscore range.
print(i) and
we can do just to separate it a little bit
put = times 40 so
put a bit of a separator there.
And just add a bit of space here.
And then we'll finish off with a for
i in range(3, 40, 3):, print(i).
Let's get rid of some of those lines now.
Okay, so if we actually run that.
You can actually see what's happened here.
So, the my_range has been created
by taking a slice from decimals
to return a new range.
So as a result of that it shouldn't come
as any surprise that the last two ranges
can actually be tested for
equality and return true.
So in other words we can
actually come back here and
actually do something like this.
print(my_range) Is equal to range (3,
40, 3).
Actually run that.
We actually get the answer true,
because they're actually considered,
well they actually are, technically equal.
So I'm actually gonna
finish the video here.
In the next video we're going to continue
on and go through a few more examples of
range, and then I'm gonna
come up with a challenge for
you to help your understanding of range.
So I'll see you in the next video.