In this video we want to download and
install IntelliJ IDEA for a Linux platform.
Specifically, we're going to be
using Ubuntu 18.04.01.
The reason for that is the LTS, the long-term
support version of Ubuntu, as of the time
I'm recording this video. Now what I want
to do is firstly show you the two
versions that are available. So I've gone
to jetbrains.com. Now you won't need to
do that and that's because the commands
I'm going to be showing you are from the
command line to do the installation. I
just want to show you the two versions.
So I'm going to go into tools here and
click on IntelliJ IDEA.
So that's the Integrated Development Environment, or
editor, we will be using for this course.
I'll just click on Yes to accept that, to
close the cookies declaration.
I'm going to go to Download again, purely just to show
you the various versions. So we've got two
versions there. We've got an Ultimate
Edition, which is a paid tool,
and a Community Edition, which is a free one. In
this course the Community Edition will
do everything you need, so there's no
need to pay for IntelliJ unless you're
doing some more professional things. You
can see over here to the left we've got
JavaScript, Java Enterprise Edition,
Spring and so on and so forth, so if you
need that extra functionality in the
future, you can come back and grab the
Ultimate Edition. You will need to pay
for that, although there is a free 30-day trial,
but I think the Community Edition
will do everything you need to do.
So let's close that page down because I
mentioned we're going to be using the
command line for this.
I'm going to open
a terminal window, clicking on
activities. I'm just going to type the
first letter T, brings this up.
I'm gonna click on terminal. Now there's two commands here. If you want to install the Community Edition,
I'll type in the command first.
So it's gonna be sudo space snap space
install space intellij - idea, being
the name of the IDE - community.
Now replace community with ultimate if you
want to install the Ultimate Edition,
the paid version of IntelliJ, remembering
that you'll get a 30 day trial if you
want to do that. In my case I'm going to
install the free and open-source
Community Edition, so I'm going to leave
the word community there, and then I've got
a space - - classic.
Press enter there. I'm going to type in my password.
That's now going to download and then
install the latest version of IntelliJ IDEA,
directly down to, or into, our Linux distro,
so this version of Linux that we're running, which again, was Ubuntu 18.04.1
Okay, you can see the download is
completed. It's now installing,
and you can see, in this case for me, it's installed the 2019.1.3 version,
which is, as of the time I'm recording this video, the latest version of the IntelliJ Community Edition.
Alright, so we've actually now,
successfully downloaded and
installed that. What we can do is start,
until startup, we can come back to
activities, and we can just type in IN,
noting that we've now got an IntelliJ
IDEA icon there. We and click on that,
and close down our command window.
Give that a moment to start. We're gonna go through some of the settings now, just to
show you what happens here. So
firstly, when we first kick
on and start IntelliJ IDEA for the first
time, we've got an option to
Import settings from a previous installation.
That would be the top option, Config or
installation folder, and that would be, if
you've got an old version you want to
import the settings. Perhaps
you've configured it in a specific way.
If you want to do that, click on that, and
then navigate to that folder. In my case,
this a brand new installation. I'm going to check,
or leave selected, Do not import settings, and click OK.
Next I'm going to agree to JetBrains Privacy Policy by
checking the checkbox,
and click on Continue.
We've got the option to send anonymous usage statistics to JetBrains.
I'm gonna click on Don't send, but obviously,
you can choose the other option if you prefer.
We've then got a choice of theme. Do we want to use a dark background with Darcula, or light.
I'm going to select light, only because
that's better for video purposes,
but generally I recommend Darcula for
developing, and that's from my normal
development machine. I would, or do certainly use dark background.
Click on Next for default plugins.
I'm not going to change anything there.
You've got the options to disable or
remove some options if you want.
Those things are fine, as is. I don't think we need to change anything there,
noting you can always go back later and make these
changes if you want to. I'm not going to
do anything. I'm going to click on Next,
and I've got the option to install these
three things. We won't be using them in the course,
so therefore I'm not going to
change anything there either.
I'm gonna click on Start using
IntelliJ IDEA,
and you can see that's fired up IntelliJ IDEA.
Alright, so at this point we've now successfully
installed IntelliJ IDEA on our Linux platform.
There is a little bit more configuration we need to do, and there's a separate video in the course for configuring
IntelliJ IDEA, and that video is for all
versions of IntelliJ; for Windows, Mac and Linux.
But the good news is that now that
you've got to this stage and IntelliJ is
booted, the interface is pretty much
identical for all three platforms, so
fast forward now to that video, or go
to that video in the course, and do the
remaining configuration and then we'll
be ready to start programming in this course.
I'll see you in that next video.