so moving on although the
pickle module which we just talked about
great for serializing python objects it
really does have a drawback that the
objects all have to be loaded back into
memory into the computer's memory that's
fine for many situations but if you're
dealing with a really large set of
objects for example a single object very
large single object like a large
dictionary for example then loading
that in entire thing to memory may not be a
realistic option so you need to look
at alternatives now Python's got your
back to their and they have an alternative
it and that's to use the shelve module so
the shelve provides a shelve and
you can think of it like a dictionary
but its actually stored in a file
rather than in memory now like
a dictionary the shelve holds key value pairs and
the values can be anything they can be
pickled which as you found out was just
about everything now the keys themselves
must be strings unlike a dictionary where
the keys can be immutable objects such as
tuples so important distinction there now all the methods we use with dictionaries
can also be used for shelve objects so it
can be really useful to think of them as
a persistent dictionary in fact it's a
very easy to convert code using a
dictionary to use a shelve instead because
the values are pickled when saved the
same warning applies about using
files from untrusted sources so make
sure that you keep that in mind
because loading a shelf can also execute
code that's not a reason not to use them because they are very useful but
just don't you shelve files themselves
from untrusted sources so let's have a
look at a shelve in action and just to
get an idea of how they can be use just like
dictionaries were gonna start with same
examples as used in discussing
dictionaries so I'm gonna start by typing
import....
..and we will just copy and paste some of these..
...next one....and next one...
....and last one of course is lime....
...ok and I will also do here, print....
and print....ok so there is the base program, so you can see we are opening a shelve in the same way as opening a
file we are using the width and shelves keep
in mind are read and write by natures so you
need to specify mode but other
than that it looks like just like a
real file so we just run and we got an error and
this is quite useful to know because of
what's happened here the reason you
might think this Attribute shelve module has no open, when I just told
shelve.open is the syntax and the
reason is that I've used a file here
python file called shelve.py and what has caused confusion is the face that
python file name is called shelve we're
trying to import import shelve so
I'm gonna rename this to fix this
refactor it click on shelve.py
right click refactor rename, and will call it shelve.
example.py, refactor so we got the name change there and that automatically
refactor for us which i don't want so I'm gonna change that back to
shelve and so the example should now work
because before when we did something like open we
probably wouldn't found that to come up
with right away because it be looking
in the current Python program for the open method
open function which doesn't exist so this
should now work so keep that in mind if
you get a weird error and using an import make
sure your imported your using and the file name
are actually separate things ok lets
try running it again okay so this
time we actually go it to work and again
just a confirmation, actually I'll closed down
this window because we don't need it for a while so you can see now
that the example work and we got
to things printed out there as well which
is sort of confirmation that we
successfully save that information so we opened the shelve in a very
similar way we to open a file and
as I mentioned shelve are read and write by nature so
there's really no need to specify the
mode but
other than it does really look like opening a file now note that the file is or may be
created with a DB extension automatically so Python actually uses a
database to store the Dada and pickles
the values so that complex Python
structures can be stored as database fields so just open it up again you
can see their ShelveTest.db test so that's the database that has been created
automatically by python now which database
is used depends on the underlying Python
implementation so you may or may not get
the DB file extension automatically
added actually what may happen is that
you shelve might be stored might be stored
in several files now once the shelve is
open we can use it pretty much like a
dictionary
so we can assign values to keys to add to the shelve and we
can access individual values using the
keys as we do in the 2 print
statements that you see on line 10 and
11 and one difference to keep in mind
between the shelve and a dictionary
is that there's no shelve literal so what I mean
by that can probably best shown as an
example and what I'm going to do is just
copy and paste example code
to show you what I mean, and will undo it afterwords so I'll paste it and overwrite it so you can see
the code their now bit of a difference from what we are using before we are now using
key-value pairs their so if we run this
it does seem to work but if you look
carefully at the output here you can see
that the fruits is a
dictionary
and just further proof that we can remove
the indent from lines 10 and 11 over here and run
that and still works so even though the
lines are outside the width block
in other words the shelve itself has now been closed
obviously because we are out of that loop
in that indentation level so what I'm getting
is you can't initialize a shelve
using literal as we could with a
dictionary
so a subtle difference to keep in mind  so will just undo that now and go back to our original code
come down here now and type print fruit....
you can see quite clearly their on line
13 the output over here you can see that
fruit is a shelve rather than a dictionary that we showed previously
and if I go back and try and remove
these back to the  previous
indentation level  like so we should get an
error and we do get an error here in this case
because we're attempting an invalid
operation on a closed shelve, so undo those, so keep in mind
that when using the with statement that
that will automatic close the file
when the with block finishes that's what was
happening in that scenario if you want
to keep the shelve active and happy to
close it yourself manually then you can
use some alternatives to syntax just try your
luck with the file we can do that by
changing line 3 so come up to line 3
and comment out that out , here we can put fruit....
so that being the case we change the
indentation level so come down here and just
do a shift tab to move back to the
previous indentation level because we
are not using with and we can run
that , actually before I do that we could
do is on the bottom add a close statement
so on line 13....
..like so and leave the print statement, so if we run that
its still working like it did before remember it's
your responsibility to close the shelve
yourself manually by doing what i've done
there on line 13 create another examples
so I'm just going to open another file because we're gonna come back to
this one, actually what I'll do is open up
projects being a better way of doing it and right click, Create a new Python module and will
call it a motorcycle again and close it down again
actually what I'll do, i'll double click that so its on the screen, close that one down ok we are going to do something similar as we did before so I'm
gonna do import....
I'm gonna do with, put a separate line in their...and you've seen similar example of this before...
what we are trying to do now is show the
different types of information can be
stored in a shelve, so.....
and will try bike...and I put while there that should be with getting confuse there, and next thing is printing a couple of
things out there lets do a print...ok we should be able to run that and
that it works as you would expect the
same result as the earlier dictionary example with
very similar syntax and we got a new
shelve now so if we open our project window again
we should find that that will appear
shortly be refreshed and should be able
to see that on the screen and
the reasons is not there I'm making the classic
newbie mistake their I need to right click Run
because of course what's happening is
running the shelve program again and it's
not really running the motorcycles example so we run
that one now we get a different example we
actually get the right information shown
on the screen which is correct
and open that file again now we can see bike.db is
showing there on the screen so work just as you would expect
and gives the same result with the
output as expected from the earlier
dictionary example and of course the
syntax is also very similar now before we
move on there is one aspect of shelve that we
need to bear in mind
if we're gonna use it successfully unlike a
dictionary examples so where we could run
the program again and everything started
from scratch
Shelves are persistent files now so
far there has been nothing we've done to
demonstrate some of the implications of
this so lets modify the example and include a type so
you can understand about the
potential problem
first change the name of the shelve to bike2 and line 7
we are gonna change here so its engine size
without an e engine_size as you can see there so you can see clearly there
we are adding engine and we are trying to print it out with an e there so
there should be an error but will run that you
can see we correctly do get an error
but we open up our project again notice that a bike2.db has been created
so the error arose because we attempted to retrieve
engine underscore size, engine
spelled with an e as you can see on line 9 but we
spelled it incorrectly when assigning the
value on line 7 now that's always the easy
fix because we correct the error in
the line 7 and run the program
again and will do that now and run again
that fixes things up but there is actually a
problem in that these two entries for
the engine size 1 spelled correctly and one
misspelt you can verify this by commenting
out all the assignments so we don't create
them again i'll just do that and I'll close the
run window briefly as well so we can see a little better so I'll comment these out so we
should be able to print engine size as
was correct
correctly done a second time but in the
first case without the e and I should be able
to do that and run that and we should be able
to get the values back  from both of them
notice how we got a value back from both
of them in other words both keys exist
in the underlying database the misspelled one
from the first run of the program and of
course the correct one
when I went back and corrected the word
engine to put an e on the end
and this is because shelves persisted to a file so just
just correcting the typo didn't
remove the error from the underlying
database pretty important distinction
there to remember as you carry through
just like a dictionary we can
iterate through the keys in the shelve and print them out
which really confirm that we got a rogue entry in there
so lets do that before we finish this video
and move to the next one so we come back here and
put something like....
..so print....so if we run that, again you can see we got make, colour
engine_size, engin_size, and model, so its added both entries
the good thing is just like a
dictionary there we can use Del remove
items from a shelve so we come down here
let's close this down I'm going to comment out
the for loop because we've already
established that works, I'll just leave
that in there and up what I'll do is
just delete so....
the one with the incorrect spelling, so we run that
value should have been deleted but of course we get
an error because on line 17 we try
to print out the value out so we could
correct that again by removing
to deletion which should already now finish and comment out line 17
and run it once again and you can see that it
works correctly and our engine size
with the incorrect spelling of the word engine has
been removed because of the
deletion that actually occurred
so I'm gonna en the video here on the next video we're
going to continue our discussion of shelve
see you on the next video