The backslash character has got a
special meaning in strings.
It's used to escape the character that follows it, to give that character special meaning.
Now some examples are backslash n, to start a new line, and backslash t to insert a tab.
So let's go ahead and create a new Python file.
I'm going to call this one escapechar.py
Alright, so start by typing splitString is equal to,
and in double quotes, This string has been, and we'll put a backslash n there, and type split over.
Then backslash n several backslash n lines,
and to confirm what this looks like, we're going to type print, and in parenthesis, splitString, like so.
Now before I run this, remember to check what your IDE thinks you want to run.
Now we haven't executed this code before, so we have to right click in the editor to run it from there,
and you can see in the top right hand corner,
it's going to run strings if we just click on this button here,
which is not what we think should happen.
So I'm just going to close that off. I'll  just type in the answer there, close that off.
So again, what we need to is right-click and select run.
Alright, and now we can see those backslash characters and what they're doing.
You can see how the string has been indeed spit over several lines in the output.
So whenever the print function sees backslash n in a string,
it causes it to start a new line.
Many IDEs will color escape characters differently in the code,
as IntelliJ IDEA is doing on my screen. You can see that on line 1, the various backslash ns there.
Alright, so that was backslash n. We can also tab the output.
So using backslash t causes Python to tab to the next stop before printing. So let's go ahead and try that.
So I'm going to type tabbedString is equal to, and in double quotes I'm going to type 1\t2\t3\t4, you guessed it, \t5.
Alright and then print that out to print and in parentheses, tabbedString this time, and we'll run this.
We can see the numbers 1 to 5 are printed out, tabbed across the screen.
Now different consoles have different tab stops. In IDEA, the tab stops are every four characters.
But if you run this program from, say, a terminal or a command prompt,
the tab stops will probably be set to eight characters, so keep that in mind.
So the backslash can also be used to escape special characters, such as quotes and double quotes,
and that can be useful if they you've got a string containing both of those characters.
So to see what I mean, let's type some more code.
So I'm going to type print parenthesis and single quote,
and I'm going to type The pet shop owner said, and then double quote, No, no, and a space, we're gonna put a
backslash single quote, bear with me here, e backslash single quote again, s then r.
Hopefully you're recognizing the reference here, and three periods, he backslash single quote s resting,
and closing double quote, a period and a single quote which is already there, and the right parenthesis.
So that's one option, or what we can do,
is we can come back and also try another version of that,
and we can put, and I'll put a comment there, hash or. We can do it another way print, and put a double quote this time,
The pet shop owner said, space backslash double quote
No, no, space single quotes e, and we're putting the e in single quotes there,
s for e's uh comma three periods, he's resting.
Then we want to put a backslash double quote a period,
then we've got the closing double quote from the start of the line, and the right parentheses.
Let's just run this first.
So you can see now that what the pet shop owner said is in double quotes, but his statement includes apostrophies,
and that means that we have to escape one or the other.
So on line 7, the string is delimited with single quotes, as you saw,
and we have to escape any single quotes that appear in the string.
However, on line 9 what we've done, is we've delimited using double quotes,
and that means the double quotes inside the string must be escaped.
Now another alternative is when you use
triple quotes, which we'll do now,
there's no need to escape any quotes inside the string. So I'm going to type print
left parenthesis and three double quotes, and noting that IntelliJ added the last three for us automatically,
and I can type The pet shop owner said,
then a double quote. Notice we're not using the backslash now for escape characters, no, no, single quote,
e single quote, s for e's uh semicolon three periods, he single quote he's resting.
Then we've got our double quote to close off the quote, from the start of No, no, he's uh, ... he's resting
and we want to put a period there, and we'll just put a space and the three double quotes on the right-hand side.
Close off the print line with the right parenthesis.
So basically, when we're using triple quotes there, there's no need to escape any quotes inside the string.
Python knows that the string doesn't end, until it finds those matching triple quotes at the end.
And just to confirm this we'll run it,
and as you can see, we've got exactly the same output.
So another reason we might want three consecutive quotes
is because of a feature Python provides, to make strings spanning lines more readable.
So the string that we split over several lines earlier, is not easy to read because of the embedded backslash ns.
but Python allows the string to be split over several lines without doing that, by using triple quotes
So to see what I mean, let's type some code in.
We'll do this on line 13. So I'm going to type anotherSplitString is equal to, three double quotes,
This string has been, I'm pressing enter there, split over, enter, several, enter, lines.
Then on the next line, which is the line after, just to make it clear, and I'm gonna print another string, anotherSpitString.
If we run that,
and you can see This string has been split over several lines.
So we're basically getting line breaks in the output.
Now if you want to lay out a string with breaks, but don't want every one to start with a new line when printed,
then what you can do is escape the end of a line with a backslash.
So to see what I mean there,
we can come to the end of the line. We'll
come up here to line 13, has been been space, we'll put a backslash there.
On the next line, do the same, space backslash several backslash after the space,
and now if we run this, you'll see the difference in the output.
The string has been split over several lines, is actually no longer true.
It's now all on the same line because we've used the backslash to escape the end of the line.
Alright so let's finish the video here.
See you in the next video.