Hello and welcome to UpWork freelancing,
your guides of finding remote freelance clients.
My name is Christopher Dodd and for the last almost three years now,
I've been using UpWork to find
remote freelancing jobs that allow me to work from literally anywhere in the world.
You see before I got started on UpWork,
I used to rely quite a bit on personal networking to find my freelance clients.
But the great thing about using UpWork is that whether I'm working from
the beach in Thailand or from an apartment in Brooklyn, New York.
I can both find the work and perform the work from literally anywhere.
All I need is a computer and an internet connection.
In fact, I've used UpWork extensively as one of
my major tools in order to enable my current nomadic lifestyle,
which has seen me travel to over 21 countries in search of Wi-Fi and adventure.
So in this course I want to take you through my story with UpWork, but more importantly,
share with you a system that I've refined over the last two years to attract
better clients and more money with
UpWork countless hours I used to spend sending out proposals.
So if you're ready to get started,
click on the next video and I'll see you on the inside.