All right, we've talked about your title and your headshot.
Now let's talk about your overview,
which for those of you who didn't know is this section right here.
Sometimes it shows up condensed,
but you can just click the more link here and you'll be
taken to the full overview of any freelancers profile.
There's a few theories about how to write your overview but for me I keep it very simple.
Again it just goes back to what we talked about in
the theory lessons basically what's your pitch?
What audience are you speaking to?
Essentially, the overview is a place
for you to talk about the different selling points of
yourself that you think clients and your audience would be
interested in and help them make a decision about whether to hire you.
I know that's quite vague.
I'm actually going to share with you a bunch of tips that I've learned
from other resources online that you may want to try but
before that I'm going to go through
my own profile just to share with you the parts that I
think are particularly important and also share with you what not to do.
Let's go over that right now.
One thing that I've tried myself that I wouldn't necessarily
recommend is going super salesy in your overview.
I've learned this from some courses that have this salesy tone in their overview.
You don't want to be talking like say for instance,
if you're a web developer,
talking in the salesy tone, that's something like,
hey are you at your desk struggling with this website and you just almost given up hope,
well, never fear because I'm here.
I'm this expert developer who's had
all these years of experience and I'm going to solve your problem,
your life is going to be so much,
but you don't want to give off that tone of being a sleazy salesperson.
It does work on certain contexts on the web really well.
There's a lot of sales letters that are written like that but for this purpose,
for LinkedIn and for Upwork,
they're pretty much the same thing they're professional network.
You don't want to give off too much of a sleazy salesperson vibe.
That's all I'll say on that one.
I think that's pretty common sense but basically to go over my overview here,
if we look at the first line,
I state again what I do.
I state that I'm from Australia.
Again, that's going back to targeting my audience.
I've found an audience of Australian clients who like working with other Australians.
I make sure to reiterate that in the first line of
my overview and I enjoy working with clients who appreciate quality.
Who doesn't appreciate quality?
I just go into a story of what I've been doing,
how long I've been doing it and I make sure to mention
that I've done small websites with WordPress,
but I've also worked on large web applications.
I talk about why I specialize in WordPress,
but I tell them that I also contract as a front end web developer and I
list a few of the technologies I'm familiar with and can use proficiently.
I also talk about kind of broader experience here.
I can advise the basics on SEO, content, marketing,
social media and I reference my experience through my personal brand and blog,
Crystal freelancer for that.
They can actually go to that website and see those skills demonstrated.
I talk here about other services that I offer clients.I actually had an overview
that targeted all these different things in the one and it was confusing clients.
I actually had one client reach out to me and say,
your title says you're a WordPress developer,
but you've got marketing in here,
you've got video editing,
like what is it you do?
You want to make it super clear.
What do you do?
I mentioned that I can do video editing,
YouTube marketing consulting, which is something I've done before.
I've edited podcasts for people before,
and I've done voice-over work.
I just mentioned that as just t one sentence at the ends
because I want to tell people that I have that in case they need that later,
but I don't want to confuse them with I can do all these different things.
The final part of the overview and this is something I
recommend for everyone is a call to action.
For me this came naturally because I'm like how else am I going to end off
the overview but if it didn't come naturally to you,
make sure to give them a call to action.
Which is basically tell them what option
you'd like them to take up after reading your overview.
That's kind of my overview and my thinking behind it.
It's working for me and I feel like I'm not an expert writer.
I could probably write something better or hire somebody to do it
but I think that this covers all the important points.
I'm just going to go over a few of the other tips that I learned
from different other resources that I learned Upwork marketing from.
One of the other things you might want to do is develop a point of difference.
Maybe you have a unique offer that nobody else has.
Maybe you have this unique experience that nobody else has.
It's always good marketing. If you have a point of difference, share that.
Another tip is study
other successful freelancers and see what they write in their overview.
If they've done over 10-K,
20-K on the platform and they have a top rated status.
Look at what they've put in their overview and
evaluate the different themes or different things that each of them are doing.
Obviously you want to format your overview.
So if I didn't use paragraphs here and had it all as one paragraph,
not only would that be hard to read,
but it doesn't show I'm very professional when I
don't even know how to break up my profile,
breakup sentences into paragraphs.
Make sure your formatting is done.
It's pretty simple, I don't know if you can even bold on this,
but you want to at least use paragraphs.
Another tip I've heard is stating who you want to work with,
like who is your audience.
I think I've done it kind of implicitly here.
I'm from Australia and I enjoy working with clients who appreciate quality.
That's vague in the sense that everyone appreciates quality but
basically what I'm saying with this line is I'm from Australia.
Your probably from Australia as well,
from maybe the United States or the UK.
You're going to be talking with another westerner who understands
English fluently and who's going to give you a high-quality.
Some people have actually been banned on Upwork,
working with people who have
poor communication skills that may be charge a really low rate,
but just ends up producing low quality work or wasting the client's time.
They want to avoid that and I think with this I'm implicitly stating, I'm from Australia.
I have that Australian professional experience and
I enjoy working with people who appreciate quality.
The final tip I have here is just don't treat this like a resume.
Don't list a bunch of things you can,
list your skills and things that you can help with,
but don't make the whole thing a list.
Essentially you just want to write in a simple but professional tone,
what it is you do,
what are your experience is and your selling points.
The principles are the most important thing here.
You want to make sure that you're appealing to your audience.
You want to know what your pitch is and you want to
communicate that through your overview.
I hope that helps you out with how to write your overview.
There's a bunch of resources I'm sure online to help
you create a template around it but essentially everyone's story is different.
Everyone's preference is different.
Everyone's skills are different.
It's going to be slightly different for everyone.
I think again keep those principles in mind and I
look forward to seeing what your overview looks like in the class projects.
Thanks for listening. In the next video we're going to cover ricing.