All right. Guys, welcome back.
By this stage, you should now have your profile
completed and be ready for the next stage,
which is to now actually go and find some work.
If you're currently logged in, which you should be,
you can click right here on the Upwork logo,
and that'll take you to the Find Work page.
You can also get to this page by clicking this link.
But the place I would recommend you to look is in
a different section that you can find by clicking on this magnifying glass here.
If this view, you can actually see
all these different listings like you would in the Find Work section,
but what you have is these really awesome filters,
and these filters will allow you to filter by any number of these different attributes.
The experience level desired,
the budget, category, client location.
It's very powerful to use these filters.
Whereas if you go into the Find Work section,
there is a link for advanced search,
but it's pretty much an advanced text level search.
You don't get those selection boxes,
you don't get those check boxes,
and basically you're searching the title and the skills here.
I definitely recommend you go and use this one over here,
and the reason why we want to use
filters is because there are simply too many jobs on Upwork to look at.
I mean, we can't just sit here all day filtering through 100,000 jobs,
many of which are going to be irrelevant to you or not a right fit for you.
This is essentially how it looks,
but we can filter these results by using these filters up here.
Now just a word on filtering and choosing what jobs to put into your search.
You don't want to take an approach like I just mentioned,
where you're sifting through lots and lots of jobs that aren't going to be right for you.
You want to be strategic with your filters to make sure that you're being efficient.
But of course you don't want to filter out anything,
any opportunities that might actually be a good fit for you.
When you're starting out,
what you want to do is start a bit more broad.
Look for opportunities, maybe jobs that are a little bit smaller,
maybe for small amounts of money.
But as you build on the platform,
you're going to get more fussy,
determine what you like,
what you're willing to work for,
and your profile is going to be more valuable over time.
It makes sense to go bidding for those bigger jobs,
for those higher paying jobs.
But again, it depends on where you are in your Upwork journey, of course.
For me, for example, who has had a few years and the platform now,
I'm not looking for anything entry-level,
so I'd be filtering via intermediate and expert.
By that, I'm able to filter out 27,000 jobs.
I wouldn't work for any less than $100.
That's actually less than $100.
But if I go down here and set a minimum,
any project that is less than $100 is simply not worth my time.
In fact, I would probably choose a higher number than that.
Even $100 is a little bit small for me.
The other thing is category.
I make sure to filter by a category that should go without saying.
Obviously you don't want to have in the search results
all these different jobs that are completely different fields and skill sets to you.
You want to filter by category.
As I've determined in my audience,
I'm looking for Australians.
If I apply all those filters and then close that box,
you can see I've significantly cut down the amount of jobs in that criteria.
If 700 jobs sounds a bit small,
remember, as you get more mature on the platform,
you go for a more sniper approach than a shotgun approach
of just sending out tons of proposals and hoping to get something back.
Now I'm at the stage where I'm not willing to just work with anyone who pay me.
I want to work with high-quality clients that are paying well,
but when you're starting out, again,
you want to find as much work as possible.
You still don't want to work with bad clients,
which we'll get to in a sec,
but you want to work on as many jobs as possible,
and if those jobs are small budget,
maybe that's good just to get experience on
the platform so you can get to this point where you're more targeted.
I'm going to clear those filters,
go back to the over 100,000 jobs and I'm just going to go back
to filters now and talk about some of the filters that you might want to use.
Experience level is one of the more important filters,
and that's because it's not only dependent on your skills as a freelancer
but also dependent on what the budget of the client is.
As you can see here,
they've not only got expert, intermediate,
and entry level, but they've got these $ signs next to it.
If you're trying to earn a lot of money per hour,
you really don't want to be looking at
these entry level jobs because as we've discussed earlier,
when the client goes to make a project,
they look at the skill level that they desire and they're given a range of values.
They might get entry level,
you're looking at below $20 an hour and they might look at expert,
you're looking at more than $40 an hour.
They have an expectation of how much it's going to cost
them as well as their intended experience level.
Price is a big factor in this as well.
If you're just starting out and you don't mind taking a few jobs at entry level,
you don't want to filter that.
Maybe you want to filter out expert level jobs
because you might find a lot of jobs that are just too expert level for you.
Maybe you might want to do the opposite of
me and just look at entry level and intermediate.
Intermediate, I pretty much always use because it's somewhere in the middle.
I definitely am not looking for entry level and maybe you're definitely not looking
for expert but intermediate adds in a little bit of a buffer.
Moving onto client history, of course,
it's better to work with clients who have worked with other freelancers in the past.
It gives you more data to work with in terms of seeing how they've paid
other clients and also shows you that they have experience on the platform,
so they're just more reliable as a client.
But I still don't filter people out based on their client history because they might
be a new client to the platform
and they may have hired freelancers in the past and be a really good client.
This goes hand in hand with payment verified as well.
I wouldn't start a contract with anyone who isn't
payment verified but to begin with searching for jobs,
I don't mind applying for jobs where the client isn't payment verified.
I just make sure that they are payment verified by the time we start our contract.
The reason why I feel strongly about this is because my friend Denise,
one of her biggest clients, ever,
wasn't payment verified when he came onto the platform.
She looked at that, she thought,
they are not payment verified,
that's seems a bit dodgy but then she
brought it out with the client and the client was okay,
sorry. I'm new to Up-work.
He verified his payment and that client was worth thousands and thousands of $
to my friends Denise over the span of many months.
You don't want to choose your filters too harshly.
I would make sure your clients are payment verified by the time you start
your contract but I don't filter by these personally.
Moving on to the number of proposals,
you may want to filter this just so that you can apply
for jobs that are less competitive but I don't
think you should shy away from any job that you feel is
a good fit based on the level of competition.
In fact, I do sometimes look at the number of proposals but
that's always a last stage though when on the fence about a certain job,
am thinking, I don't know if I can position myself.
If they've got over fifty proposals already,
maybe that's a sign for me to say,
I'm not sure about this job,
plus they got a hip proposals already.
I'm going move on. But in terms of the preliminary search,
I wouldn't filter out by that.
For budget, obviously, it's up to you how much you want to work for.
Like I said, you want to build up experience on the platform in the beginning,
so I wouldn't necessarily filter by this in the very beginning but of course,
as you get more experienced and you can start to be more choosy,
think about the minimum job that you would be willing to do and filter by that.
The other ones here are related to time and honestly,
I don't ever filter by this because
the client sometimes doesn't know how long it's going take or
how many hours of a week it's going to be
and you don't know where you're going to be necessarily.
I always just suss that out by actually talking to the client,
I don't use it as a preliminary filter.
Finally, you've got these select boxes down here.
You want to make sure that you're filtering via your category,
if you're in web development,
obviously you want to filter out skills that you don't have,
you're probably not an interior designer or a contract manufacturer,
so you want to make sure that you're filtering out all
of those jobs that aren't in your category.
That one is a very important one.
In my case, I look at certain locations,
that's just a personal preference,
I guess that I've developed over time,
you don't necessarily need to filter by location.
Maybe time zones are consideration for you,
you only want to work in locations that are on the same time zone as you but otherwise,
you can just leave that blank.
If I close the filters,
you can see here that we've already cut out
80 percent of the jobs that we were looking at before.
Very important to use at least some filtering, otherwise,
you're going to be sitting there for hours scrolling through a ridiculous amount of jobs.
Even still 16,000 is a lot.
A lot of them are going to be older jobs,
so I recommend only looking within a 24 hour period of posting.
Sometimes I push that a little bit but I usually don't
apply for jobs that have been up for more than a day.
The reason for that is,
Upwork is not really like a normal job board.
People post jobs really quickly and there's so much volume of applicants that come in,
so I usually makes sure that I'm only applying for jobs that are as recent as 24 hours.
I've heard from other freelancers that they
recommend applying within four to eight hours.
So maybe you want to do this as a twice daily routine,
for me when I'm in finding work mode,
I do this as a daily routine and so each
day that's a 24-hour difference, I'll go through,
look at all the jobs that have been posted in the last 24 hours and then
the next day I'll go through look at
all the jobs that have been posted in the last 24 hours.
By the time I get to Friday,
I've looked at every job that's been posted from that Monday to Friday period.
That's what I'd suggest for you and suggest getting
into a routine with it and choosing how many times you're going to
look for this search results per day and what times you're going to do it
because if you are trying to go for that four to eight add gap,
maybe you want to check three times a day.
It's up to you. I think once a day is a good balance for me and
I like having a daily routine. That's how I do it.
The final step in this whole process for me,
is going through the listings and actually opening up these job adds in a new tab.
With the computer I'm using now, this mac book,
I'm able to hold down "Command" and click on the link and that'll open up
a new tab without having to transition over to that page.
This is how I like to do it.
You can also right-click open a new tab up here,
it's off screen but a new tab is opening and I can click over to that job right there.
Okay. If I go back here,
what I do is I just quickly evaluate these jobs.
I'm going to talk about evaluating jobs in
the next video but what I do in my preliminary search,
I just go through and I'm not very fussy,
I just pick at every everything that could be relevant.
I could make a travel agency website.
I'm looking for an expert developer.
Okay. Responsive one pager.
I were to click on this but the budget is less than 50 and so I'm not going to.
Now there's senior PHP developer.
Okay. Let's have a look at that WordPress expert.
Maybe this is a good video to watch in
conjunction with the next one about evaluating jobs
but all I'm doing here is a really preliminary evaluation on these.
I'm just trying to filter out anything that is
definitely not going to be relevant or definitely not something I want to do,
otherwise, I go through and open them up in new tabs.
We've got WordPress expert here,
budget's too low but apart from that,
it might be something I'm interested in.
Then what you'll get at the end is a bunch of tabs.
If I just bring this down,
you can see here that we've got all these tabs now.
Depending on whether it's a good day within those filters,
I might have a long list of tabs here and then I go through and evaluate them one by one.
If you're not sure about whether it's the right job or not,
just my thinking is give it the benefit of the doubt,
open it up in the new tab and have a look at it in more detail.
This section here, as you're scrolling through,
is to just pick out the opportunities that
might be of interest to you and then you can get
to the different tabs here and evaluate them with more information.
All right. That's pretty much the finding work,
at least getting to this stage,
where you're actually on the job page.
That's where we're going pick up in the next video.
So I'll see you in that one.