In this video, we're going to talk about actually sending proposals,
what to include in your application and honestly all of
these different videos or different parts
of the finding work and applying for work section,
they all blend into each other because you should know what your pitches,
what you're looking for,
and that will dictate all the way from your job search to actually applying for the job.
But in this video, I got rid of those previous examples because those were just
from that short period of time searching and I
found some other examples here for us to look at,
and let's talk about how you might position yourself for these jobs.
Here you've got a very simple job.
The budget might be small,
but it might be what you're after and they're
looking to mobile optimize a WordPress website.
They've only got really one requirement here,
and that is that they want it mobile optimized.
If you have anything in your experience or anything that you can
show them of how well you can make mobile first websites,
then definitely that's something that you would want to address.
That's one example. In this job,
you can see here that they've listed a whole bunch of
things that they want the developer to do.
Number 1, adding a live.