All right guys, welcome back to the course and in this video,
I want to talk about the Upwork job success score.
So if we look at the computer,
you can see my profile here,
and in the top right corner,
I've got 100 percent job success,
and I've got top rated status.
If we hover over job success here,
we can see a little tool tip appear says that the job success rating is
the percentage of this freelance jobs that resulted in a great client experience.
So what you might think from this job success score is that it's simply a measure of
the number of successful jobs over
the total number of jobs that I've done on the platform.
Actually, it's a little bit more complicated than that.
The reason why I know for sure that it isn't as simple as that,
is because my job success score at its lowest point was 89 percent.
Suddenly, after I fixed up a few things on my profile,
my job success score went up to 100 percent again.
Actually it went to 91 percent,
I think first and,
then shot up to 100 percent.
If my job success score is related to
the number of successful jobs over the number of total jobs,
then theoretically, I can't go from 89 percent to 100 percent.
I could get to 99.9 percent,
but technically I could never get to 100 percent job success score
if I had even just one job that didn't succeed.
So some people get frustrated about the job success score,
think that, "Oh my God,
I've done one job bad.
Am at 80 percent now."
Or maybe they've done every job well and they've got a low job success score,
and they're thinking like, "why is Upwork punishing me like this."
It can be a bit of a mystery and actually Upwork does provide a document here.
I'll bring it up right now on the job success score.
So it'll say down here how my job success score is calculated.
Here it says at a high level,
we look at job success score this way.
So that's how initially I thought of it as well,
but if you look down here,
there's other factors that affect the job success score as well.
There's all of these different things that can boost your score.
They even understand that some projects have bad outcomes,
because the client is difficult to work with.
So the fact that one client marks your job is unsuccessful does
not mean that that's going to negatively affect your job success score.
Then they say here explicitly,
we don't reveal the exact calculation for your score.
Doing so would make it easier for some uses to artificially boost their scores.
We need to maintain some privacy with this metric to ensure fairness and accuracy.
Then you can go down to here and about how it's all calculated.
I definitely recommend you go and read this article,
at least to get an understanding of what Upwork is telling you,
but essentially the Upwork success score,
the main thing to realize with it is it's not simply
a measure of the number of successful jobs you've done over the number of jobs.
If you have a unsuccessful job,
it doesn't mean that you can't get to 100 percent job success.
As I mentioned before,
I lost my top rated status at one point.
It was down to 89 percent and I thought,
well that's it, I won't ever get back to 100 percent.
Then I got there, and actually I went to a rep and ask why my job successful was lower,
and I asked how I could get it better,
and then he told me a few factors that I could do to improve my profile,
which I implemented straight away and got to 100 percent.
So unfortunately, I've lost that conversation,
I don't have a record of it,
but what I will say,
is the things that I did to fix my profile and fix my jobs success score was number one,
close any idol contracts.
So oftentimes clients will start a contract with
you and as long as the work is performed and they've paid you,
which if you're in an alley,
they'll have already paid your time sheet,
or if you're on a project,
they can pay you a milestone without closing the contract,
they may just leave the contract open,
because they don't really care.
You've been paid, the job has been completed,
but you want to make sure that if you finish the job,
and they don't want you to do any more work on that contract,
that you close it as soon as possible.
This I've found has directly impacted my job success score.
So I call this cleaning up your profile,
but you want to make sure that any contracts you have open,
that you're actually communicating with the client,
and following up at least to see if there's anything else they want done.
If not, encouraging them to close the contract.
This is one of the biggest things and easiest things you can
do to help increase your job success score.
The obvious one of course,
is to just deliver a great customer experience to your clients.
So that goes back into what we talked about in
the previous video on managing the client relationship,
but in this video,
I just wanted to share that the job success score isn't what you might think it is,
and you can actually improve it,
and make sure to manage the client relationship smoothly,
and provide a great service for your clients,
but also do things on the platform that make Upwork happy.
Close open contracts, complete your profile,
respond to invitations quickly,
respond to client messages quickly.
Don't just leave the platform for
a week without touching anything unless you go on vacation mode,
so you want to be constantly maintaining your Upwork profile and your Upwork account.
All of these factors,
I think will contribute to making sure that you have a good Upwork job success score.
So that's all I wanted to cover on the job success score,
as I mentioned, the article is there on the Internet for you to check out,
but just make sure to not be too discouraged if you
start off with a job success score of not that great.
You can always get it to 100 percent.
It's not over. So that's the job success score.
In the next video,
we're going to talk about my secret tactic,
which is not so secret anymore, it's video proposals.
So I'll see you in the next video.