Before we get started with all the lessons,
I just wanted to share my personal story,
in order to explain how I came across Upwork and how I managed to
overcome many of the challenges that I first experienced on the platform.
To briefly cover my story,
I started out working here in Brisbane,
Australia at a co-working space called River City labs.
Through that co-working space,
I was able to meet people that would ultimately hire me to work out of
the co-working space with them or at their own private offices.
It was great. I got to work on some good projects, but in 2016,
when the lease ended on my apartment,
and I wanted to go traveling,
I needed a way to find clients remotely,
and that's where Upwork came in.
As the biggest marketplace for finding freelance work online,
I saw it as my best opportunity to find work while on the road.
Starting out, however, we have
no previous clients for IT or of what I was doing on the platform,
I really struggled to find work.
It was a real wake-up call for me and something I really want to stress in this course,
and that is, you don't just need the skills to perform the work,
but also the skill of selling them.
In other words, you can be the best programmer,
the best designer, the best writer in the world,
but if you don't know how to sell your services,
you won't have too much luck convincing clients to work with you.
I realized that I had the skills to do the work,
but I needed to learn more about sales.
That is when I started to take some courses on how to better market myself on Upwork.
Honestly, some of it worked and some of it really didn't,
and I couldn't tell whether it was my strategy or my patients that was wearing out,
but it just wasn't working.
I kept going and occasionally I would get
a good client who would pay me and treat me well,
but it wasn't until about six months ago that I decided to look
back on the previous two years and figure out what was working and what wasn't,
and then I started to get a grip on Upwork.
I stopped doing the things that weren't getting me results,
and I started doing the things that did.
Plus I went back to the Internet to search for the freshest information
on how to succeed on Upwork and found one tactic in particular,
that is really supercharge my results.
In this course I'll be sharing that one with you also.
Today I have a pretty good profile on Upwork,
I have a job that says score of over 100 percent.
Top rated status and a bunch of five-star reviews, and let me tell you,
regardless of whether you are able to make good money from day one on
Upwork or it takes you a little while to build up your profile.
What you have at the ends over the long-term is an asset that sits
on the web and starts to feed you work without you even having to look for it.
That is the big reward that you'll get from putting in that initial effort.
That's a little bit of my story.
In the next video, we're going to go into the nuts and bolts of the course.
I'll see you on the next one.