In this class, we're going to cover how to build
your profile and how to actually find work.
But in recent years,
Upwork has added in another step.
Now, if you sign up to Upwork,
your information will go through an approval process that could see you
getting rejected before you even get to apply for any jobs.
But don't worry, if your profile does get disapproved,
you can always try again until you get on the inside.
Now, I have to admit I don't have any personal experience with
this as I got into Upwork before this whole approval process started.
But if you do a little bit of a Google research, like I just did,
you can start to find a bunch of different tips that might help you to get approved.
This article here by Freelance To Win has a bunch of really good tips on it,
as does this one by Fulltime Nomad.
You can also check out the list of
the most in-demand skills published by Upwork themselves,
by searching for Upwork,
fastest-growing skills in Google,
and finding the article in the search results.
Chances are that if you're applying for work in any of these fields
that your profile would be much more likely to be approved.
One thing I've heard from a friend whose profile was initially disapproved
was that when she changed her title and skills to something more in demand,
she was able to get approved,
and then she changed those skills when she got on the inside.
I don't know if I would necessarily recommend that approach, though,
because I have heard stories of accounts being suspended,
which goes to show that Upwork is still monitoring you once you're on the inside.
A general idea to remember when making your first application to Upwork is that
Upwork is trying to provide the best experience possible for the clients on the platform.
Try and be as professional and complete in your application as possible.
Once you do get approved,
you'll be thankful that Upwork actually weeds out competition for you,
meaning a high chance that you actually be able to find work.