Before we get started with the actual mechanics of Upwork,
I wanted to make sure you have a very important step taken care of.
This step is deciding what it is you're actually going to freelance in.
So if you've already decided what you're going to do,
feel free to skip this video.
Otherwise, let's go into some of the things you may want to consider.
Like we mentioned in the previous video,
there are certain fields that are more in demand than others,
and certain fields that are much more lucrative.
To use myself as an example,
I am predominantly a front end web developer,
but I also am skilled at creating videos.
So early in my Upwork journey,
I actually experimented with bouncing back between those two disciplines and over time,
I realized that video editing as a service,
in general was a much less in-demand skill than web development.
In fact, if you just look at the statistics or login as a client on Upwork,
you can see that video editing has a lower rate than
web development and has much fewer jobs.
This is something to take into consideration if you're
tossing up between two or more disciplines.
On one hand, you may have a skill that you enjoy more than the
other and have maybe even a portfolio of work already around it,
but then on the other hand,
a skill that is much more lucrative and perhaps less exciting to you,
or something that you don't have a big track record in.
The important thing to remember here is that you can change
your profile to whatever you want, whenever you like.
This allows you to test out certain disciplines and
specializations without the risk of being locked
in and the best part about this is that any work
you do on Upwork will earn you a higher job success score,
a high rating, and more reviews.
So you can always choose something to get started and then update
your profile details into the more difficult fields later.
In this class, we're not going to go into a lot of career advice
on which path you should pursue but in the context of Upwork,
specifically, what you should consider when making your decision is the market on Upwork.
My recommendation would be to head over to
the the find work area on Upwork and starts searching for opportunities.
How many projects are out there that fit your skill?
Do they sound like something you might be interested in and are
they opportunities that you think you could realistically be hired for?
These are some of the questions you should ask yourself during this process.
But again, if you've already made up your mind about what you want do,
I don't want you to start second guessing yourself.
Ideally, you should have already decided what field you
want to work in before arriving in Upwork.
But if not, have a look at what's going on,
and remember you can always change your profile later.