In a few videos, we're going to start setting up your profile.
Before that, we need to cover some basic freelancing theory.
This lesson is going to be on determining your pitch.
What exactly is a pitch?
A pitch is just a short summary of
the offer that you're going to bring to the marketplace,
and this is something I learned from my good friend and fellow freelancer, Sergio Sala.
The four steps to finding your pitch are: One, what's your skill?
Two, what's your focus?
Three, who's your audience?
And four, what's your solution?
In Sergio is case,
he's a web designer who creates custom WordPress themes with
the Genesis Framework for online entrepreneurs
slash professional bloggers to generate more sign-ups,
get more sales, and establish a better personal brand.
Of course, the obvious part and the one that we covered in
the last video is your skill itself,
but if you have a focus, an audience,
and a solution, your pitch will be ever more compelling.
Now, while having a focus audience and solution is awesome in theory,
for people just starting out,
it may be hard enough just to choose a skill and a specialization,
so I don't expect everyone to answer these questions straight away.
What I will recommend is that you seek to refine your message over time.
If you're just starting out,
of course you need to know what your skill is.
If you have that figured out,
then you should seek to find a specialization or focus,
then determine your audience, and finally,
if possible, get really specific on what solutions you can provide to them.
This is a process I believe should happen naturally as you
gain more experience and reflect on the work you've done over time.
For example, as a web developer,
one of your first gigs might be building a WordPress website.
Once you've built one of them,
maybe somebody else sees your work and wants a WordPress website as well,
and suddenly, you're starting to form a specialization.
Let's take that example one step further and say that most of
your clients that you've worked with happen to be in the financial services industry.
Suddenly, you've found yourself an audience, and finally,
you might find yourself producing a similar solution
or grouper solutions to each of these clients,
and now you've naturally come across solutions that you can offer to others.
Do you see now how your experience can lead to answering these questions?
This doesn't just have to be freelancing,
your experience could relate to a specialization and
an audience that you worked with in a previous, say, corporate job.
Once you've done one job working in a certain specialization for a specific audience,
then you can reference that experience when applying to work
in that specialization again with that same audience.
Again, it's a good idea to hold these questions in your mind,
but don't let it hold you back to start with.
Just know that specificity will work to help your marketing message.
Anytime you can be specific with what you can do for clients,
let that come through on your profile and in your proposals.