I wanted to bring up a completed profile as an example for
you guys and we can go through the different parts of the profile,
and what better profile to bring up than my own.
This is how the client will see me on Upwork,
and as you can see, we've got a first box here that sits above the fold,
and then as you scroll down,
work history, portfolio, skills,
certifications, employment history, education, and other experiences.
If I scroll back up to the top,
this box is what the client sees first,
and so this is your first impression.
I count this box as the most important parts of your profile to get right.
As you can see, we've got your name, your headshot,
you're registered location, we've got a title,
we've got an overview, hourly rate,
number of jobs completed or in progress,
number of hours worked and you've got your job success score up
here and I've got my top rated badge right there.
This information is also what comes across in
the preview box when clients will search for freelancers,
so if I go up here and do my own search and type in WordPress developer,
and I'll search for somebody like me,
somebody who does WordPress.
As you can see here,
this is what some people have referred to as the preview box
and you can see that it's got the name,
the headshot that title, the hourly rates.
It's also got amount that has been earned in total on the platform,
where you can hover over and see the number of hourly jobs,
the number of fixed price of jobs,
the number of hours worked.
You've got the job success score with a big badge and you've got the location,
which is a bit broader than a specific suburb or city,
it's got the country.
Then you've got the first line of your overview here.
If I was to look up myself by going into filters and filtering by Australia,
this should bring up my preview box.
If we scroll down,
we can find my profile here.
Honestly, I think it's pretty on point we've
got all blue here with the jobs that says score,
we've got the badge right next to it,
and pretty happy with how this is showing up.
If I go back to my profile now.
Remember, everything that you put in this box will also go in
the preview box when people searching for your profile.
This is really the most important part of your profile.
Obviously some of these things and not directly
editable like the job success score and the badge,
the amount of jobs I've worked and the hours worked,
so if you're starting out,
you're not going to have a job success score,
you're not going to have a badge to start with,
and you won't have this work history.
But what you can control,
is your headshot, your title,
your overview, and your hourly.
What we're going to do in the next few videos,
is we're going to go through and cover each of these in
its own video and then we're going to go cover the rest of the profile down here.
I'll see you in the next video.