In this video we're going to talk about the profile picture specifically.
This is mine right here.
If I open it in a new tab and have a look at it,
I can increase it a bit,
it'll still be pixelated,
but literally this is the highest resolution that your prospective clients will see it.
You really don't have to have a photo that looks amazing in
a high resolution or a high screen size because this is basically the highest resolution.
I have this as it's super high res photo on my desktop,
but once it goes up to Upwork,
this is as big as anyone's going to see it.
Any of the small details like you have
a blemish on your face or anything it doesn't really matter,
the important thing is that you get the basics right.
When I say the basics,
I mean your attire,
your look on your face,
the background, and the composition.
First of all my biggest tip,
and this is not going to work for everyone.
But as you can see,
this is a pretty professionally done photo and actually had
the help of a professional photographer that take this.
There was a special deal going at
the co-working space I used to work out of back in 2015.
A really good photographer came in,
and was just taking headshots all day.
I got this pretty cool headshot,
which has lasted me up until now.
It really is a good investment if you want
to hire somebody or even have somebody who you know,
who's good with cameras,
who can take a good shot,
come and take a photo of you.
It's a great asset to have and it's not just for Upwork.
You can use it for LinkedIn,
you can use it for all things.
The reason why I mentioned that upfront is because the photographer is going to make
sure that your photo is not only professional looking,
but it's going to make sure that you've got
all these points covered in terms of the lighting,
the composition, the attire hopefully,
and your expression on your face.
Let's just go over those right now in case you
don't have a photographer and you're doing it yourself.
The first thing is attire.
I'm wearing a dressed up button up shirt,
but I'm not wearing a tie and I think that's a good balance of
professionalism without looking like you're some corporate dude.
We are freelancers on the platform,
so we're not expected to be
this corporate person unless maybe that's your niche or that's your audience.
Again, it has to all match with your audience, but for me,
I think having a businessy type shirt,
but buttons open, no tie is the good balance.
The second thing is I got a smile on my face.
Don't put a photo on there of you being angry or anything like that.
I mean, it should be common sense,
but you want to look approachable and
people have to get the sense that they're going to enjoy working with you.
Don't obviously put on a silly face because you want to be professional,
but you can be professional,
and be smiley and happy at the same time,
I think I got a pretty good balance in this profile photo.
Next one is no distracting background.
As you can see, the background is pretty much plain gray.
If you don't have a nice plain background,
it's pretty easy to find.
I think just looking around here I can see some pretty plain walls.
But if you do have a distracting background that you're shooting on,
maybe blur it out or just in Photoshop,
try and lower that contrast because you don't
want anything to take away from the photo of you,
then of course, the lighting.
It's all very even in this photo, as you can see,
I think from memory,
the photographer who did this had a flash.
It's always going to be even lighting when
the photographer is using professional lighting.
But for yourself, I don't know,
maybe step out into a sunny area,
right here, for example,
I've got the sun on my face because I'm looking out off this patio right here.
Maybe right here would be a good place to do a headshot.
Essentially, you just don't want your face to be dark
or it to be hard for somebody to make out your face.
I mean, again, putting this down to 100 percent,
this is what the size is going to come out to when your client looks at it.
If your face is not easily distinguishable,
they can't figure out what's going on in the image
from looking at it for a split second at this image size,
then you've already lost the battle.
That brings me to my last point is the composition.
I think I've got the composition pretty bang on here.
I've got my head in the middle.
I'm showing a bit of showed,
it's not to close on the face like I think if you had it about here,
maybe it'd be a bit close up, a bit intimidating.
But I think having it here showing a bit of the
shoulder's it's at a good distance so that you can actually see my face,
but you're not right up in my face.
I think, aim for this composition and you'll be fine if we want to go through
the search results and find a few examples,
let's just do WordPress developer again.
Going through the results here,
you don't have to have a background that is neutral necessarily.
You don't have to necessarily be wearing a business type shirts.
The important thing and I think this profile right here is all right one.
The composition is pretty perfect I think.
You've got his face. It's not too close.
Maybe he needs to smile a bit more or maybe that is his smile.
But, one like this where you're wearing a cap and
a hoodie and it's super close into the face.
I wouldn't say that that would be the best look.
Here, you can see it looks like a professional photo shoot.
But what I don't like about this photo is the composition that
doesn't need to be a lot of his body in the shot.
I think if we just did a front on shot with his face,
that would look a lot better.
Muhammad is looking good here.
For [inaudible] I like his composition,
but the lighting is not perfect.
It's a bit dark on his face.
Pretty easy to fix that up in photoshop if you've got
some photo editing skills, otherwise,
invest in a light or find a light source in your house and put that close
to your face because you want your face to be bright and clear in the frame.
I just thought I'd share some thoughts with that.
Another resource you can use if you're iffy about whether your photo is
actually really good on that is a website called photo feeler.
I learned this from my friend Lewis.
It's just photofeeler.com.
When the page loads,
I'll be able to show you what it does. Here you go.
What you do is you add in your photos,
you say what it's for.
In this case it would be business and you get a rating on certain aspects.
Essentially, if you have a bunch of photos that you've
taken and you can't tell which one is the best.
You can put it into a tool like this called photo feeler.
You can let other people decide basically.
You can see here,
if you scroll down more about how it works.
But basically your crowd sourcing and answer to is my profile picture good?
Or which one of these profile pictures is the best?
That's if you want to take it the step further.
Honestly, the same principles apply.
If you were going to do a LinkedIn photo,
you just want to have good composition.
Honestly, I think if you try and follow what I've done in terms of my profile,
I think you'll be pretty sweet.
That covers the profile picture.
In the next video,
we're going to go over choosing a title. I'll see you in that one.