All right guys.
Welcome to the Bitcoin Ticker app module and this module is going to be half tutorial and half a challenge.
So what we're going to build by the end of the module is something that looks like this.
So it's a app that is going to tell us the current price in various currencies such as euros or pounds
or dollars for various cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin, Ethereum  and Lite coins.
And through making these apps, we're going to be revising a lot of the concepts that we learned in the
last modules such as networking, async await and also getting live data off the Internet using APIs.
But we're also going to be learning how we can implement a different user interface for different platforms
so that on Android, we have a drop down menu to select the currency and on iOS we're going to have this
iOS style picker view.
So we're going to be learning all of that and you're going to be challenged also through building this
app.
So once you're ready, we're going to head over to the GitHub page where the starting code for this module
is hosted.
Now first things first, we're going to download the project stub from GitHub,
so londonappbrewery/bitcoin-ticker-flutter. And we're going to clone it into our local system using
Android Studio.
So as per usual, we paste in the URL that we want to clone from and then we're going to open up our project
inside Android Studio.
And then we of course get our dependencies and wait for everything to load.
Now the first thing, we're going to do is we're going to run our app and see what it looks like. So to
begin with, our app looks incredibly simple.
It's got a single card inside the scaffold body which is going to eventually tell us how much one Bitcoin
is worth in US dollars.
And this is all we have to begin with.
So take a look through the price_screen.dart, the coin_data.dart
and the main.dart to see how we've actually laid out the screen so far.
And there's nothing really particularly new.
And we've kept the user interface relatively simple so that in the coming lessons when you're attempting
the challenge, it won't distract you from the code that you have to write. Now
once you're ready, we're going to get started creating a dropdown button right here so that we can start
selecting various different currencies to check the bitcoin price for.
So for all that and more, I see on the next lesson.