Welcome to the best course on Flutter built  in collaboration with the Google Flutter team.
My name is Angela
and to date I've taught over 200,000 students worldwide, in-person and online. Graduates
from my courses have gone on to work for companies like LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter and others have created
top 10 apps that have been featured by Apple and Google.
Without a doubt, this is the best course that I have made to date.
You'll learn Flutter from scratch to build fast, beautiful, native quality, iOS and Android apps using
just one code base. And you'll build tons of beautiful apps and projects to add to your portfolio. By
the end of the course,
you will be a fully fledged Flutter developer by mastering things such as stateful and stateless widgets,
declarative programming, Lisp views, animations, streams, futures and much much more.
Companies like Ali Baba, The Hamilton Musical, and of course Google themselves are already using flutter
in their production apps right now.
Flutter lets you build iOS, Android and even Web Apps using just one programming language -  Dart.
So instead of learning Java or Kotlin to build Android apps and then learning Swift or Objective C to
build your iOS apps, you can do it all in one go, with Flutter.
I've spent months building out the curriculum with the Google Flutter team to make sure that it covers
all of the key components involved in Flutter development. So whether if you're new to Flutter, or if
this is even the first time you thought about making mobile apps, this course will turn you into a skilled
Flutter developer with a beautiful portfolio of Flutter apps.
So what are you waiting for.
Jump into the course and let's get started.