Now in the last lesson we implemented the geolocator package to be able to fetch our current location
both for Android and iOS.
And the code is super simple.
It's basically a single line that fetches us the current location of the phone depending on which location
accuracy we want.
However there are two key words that we're using in this code that comes from the documentation for
the package that we've never really seen before.
So in order to understand this, we have to first learn about asynchronous programming and why it's useful.
Now when we're writing code, there are lines of code which take a very short amount of time to execute.
For example if we wanted to run a print statement, it's a single line statement prints the word hello
world into the console.
And this takes fractions of a second to complete.
But sometimes there are things that might take more time.
For example if we wanted to load a large image from the Internet. Even if we're doing it in a browser
and if your internet is slightly slower, you might see this painful loading of the image where it takes
absolutely forever.
And this is because there's a lot of data that we're trying to transfer through cables under the sea
literally trying to get data. And the larger the amount of data the longer the time it takes for it to
load. Now
consider if we made this function. It's a function that returns nothing. So it returns void but, it has a
body that is composed of three steps or three things that it tries to do.
And the first thing is to simply print 'Hello moon' to the console.
This is pretty quick to execute.
So we see the result pretty much immediately.
Now the next thing is to load an image from NASA of the moon. And I don't know how often you've
done this but they're huge and that can take a long time.
But because our function goes from top to bottom, our third Step can't execute until the second step
is done.
So it's only once this image is loaded that the computer will actually run the very last statement, which
is to print the word 'Hello Jupiter' into the console.
Now this behavior is what we would call synchronous.
Everything happens in synchrony.
Step 1 happens, then step 2 happens and only when step 2 has concluded or has finished and we've
gotten the image back does step 3 actually execute.
Now what would it look like if this was asynchronous?
Well step 1 would execute as usual no changes there. But step 2, let's say that we're now loading
our image from NASA asynchronously.
Well in this case while the image is loading and we're trying to wait on that data to come back, we can
already execute step 3. And we don't have to wait for this to finish before we continue in our code.
Now why is this actually useful?
I want you to imagine that come Monday you're going to work and your boss tells you to get me 100 passport
numbers.
Get them to me right now.
So you have to call up all of the customers one by one and ask them what is your passport number.
So you have this checklist and you're going from the top to the bottom one by one calling up each customer.
Now it's not so straightforward right?
Very few people remember their passport numbers off the top of their head.
So you have to start the call ask them for their phone number and then they have to rummage around their
house and to actually find their passport to be able to give you that passport number.
And this can take anywhere from a couple of seconds to a couple of minutes depending on how well they've
stashed away their passport.
So what are you doing while all of that is happening? Let's represent this process using a graph. On the
horizontal axis is time and we have a couple of units of time, you can imagine each square as a second.
Now let's say that it only takes you maybe a second to ask that customer, 'Hey can you give me your passport
number?'
So your job is kind of done now.
The next step is waiting for the user to look for their passport and give you that number. And all of
that time you're just sitting there twiddling their thumbs on hold on the call. And you're not really
being productive right now
right?
But once they've given you their passport number you can finally spring into action again and you can
go and call the next customer, and then the same process repeats on and on again until you've gotten
to the end of that list and you've reached 100 customers. And nobody likes being on hold waiting
on a call,
right?
And if that is the majority of your day then it's not going to feel great.
Now you might have realized that there's a different way of doing this.
You could in fact have just drafted individual e-mails, say you wanted to keep it personal to be able
to persuade your customers to give you the passport numbers, and you could have simply sent these e-mails
off to all of your customers one by one. Now afterwards
this leaves you free to do any other tasks that you need to do.
And as the replies come in, you can respond to them. So you no longer have to be there on the phone waiting
for their response.
Now if we were to represent this in the same graphical style, then your day might look more like this.
You send each customer an individual email but it doesn't really matter how long it takes them to respond
because you're able to continue onto the next task,
send the next e-mail or do the next thing and they can take their time finding their passport and only
once they have their passport number do they respond to you and you get that email response back. And
it's in that moment that you can actually act on it and you don't have to be on hold waiting for them
to fetch the information you need. So now your day looks more like this.
You're using every chunk of the day doing something productive and you're responding to the e-mails
that you've sent out as and when the responses come in.
So compare these two side by side where in one case you're doing something, waiting, doing something, waiting,
doing the next thing and waiting.
Well this is synchronous programming. Whereas in the other case you're basically initiating a task and
only once that task is complete
do you get notified and act on it.
So this means that we're able to use only five units of time instead of nine units of time to achieve
the same thing.
This is the difference between synchronous and asynchronous programming.
Now notice how this is all being done by one worker, you. It's not that you have 10 people trying to
get 100 passport numbers from 100 customers. It's actually still one person doing that
task but it's just done more efficiently because you're letting the customer take their time finding
those numbers and only getting your attention once they have the results.
So let's build out a real example and take a look at what it would look like if we were to write it
in code. Inside your clima project, you're going to right click and you're going to create a new Dart
file. And we're going to call this file simply just a scratch file.
So it's going to be scratch.dart and it's going to be created inside your main project right here.
Now inside this file, this is completely separate from our project, and it lets us test out some Dart
code.
But unlike DartPad, we're able to tap in to all of the available Flutter and Dart libraries.
Now if you head over to this link which will be in the course resources for this module, then you can
see that there's a little bit of code that I've already written as some starting code for you.
So go ahead and copy all of it and paste it into your scratch.dart.
So all that we have here are three functions, task 1, task 2 and task 3. And they're called in sequence
inside a function called performTasks. And then in the main function which is our entry point to this
particular file, we call performTasks.
So right now, you can run this scratch.dart without running any of the rest of our code by simply
right clicking on the file and clicking on run scratch.dart. And you should see your console pop up
and you can see that this is an isolated file that you can run without having to take all the time to
load up the UI and build it onto an app.
So this is where we're going to experiment with our Dart code.
And you can see that as expected, all that happens is we print T'ask 1 is complete', 'Task 2 is complete',
Task 3 is complete.'
But the important thing to notice is that they happen in sequence because inside our method perform
tasks we said to do 1 then 2 then 3, in this order.
These functions are getting called sequentially.
Now let's say that task 2 was actually a really time consuming task, like downloading a picture of the
moon off the NASA's website.
Well let's simulate something taking a long time.
We can create a new duration object called threeSeconds.
And this is going to be equal to a new duration object.
And here we can specify the amount of time
so microseconds, milliseconds, seconds, minutes, hours, days.
I don't want you guys have to watch this video for days to be to see this example.
So we're going to keep it short to maybe let's say a delay of three seconds
right?
So now to be able to enact this three second duration delay, we're going to use a function called sleep.
Now the important thing about sleep is that this is a synchronous operation.
So we will have to finish before the next line can be executed.
And it takes a single input which has a duration object and we can simply put our threeSeconds in here
as the amount of time that we want to pause for.
So when we call task 2, it will set a duration of three seconds and it will sleep our program for three
seconds. And then and only then, do we get to print 'Task 2 complete' into the console. And because task
3 comes after task 2, then theoretically it should also come after three seconds delay.
So now let's go ahead and click run again.
So notice scratch.dart is currently selected as the thing that we're going to run.
And now you can see that task 1 complete, 1 2 3, task 2 task three. So if you're watching this
video on double speed or half speed might be a good time to actually put it back to normal speed because
I'm going to try and show you what actually happens with these delays.
Let's just run that again and notice Task 1, 1 2 3, Task 2 Task 3.
So we know that each of these tasks printing a single string into the console basically takes a negligible
amount of time. All that's causing the delay is this artificial delay that I've put in here using the
sleep method which comes from dart:io. Now because there are a lot of cases where things can take an unpredictable
but usually a long period of time to complete such as downloading something or reading something from
a file or even doing complex computations,
it all takes a large amount of time.
And what we don't want to happen is for everything else, every subsequent task, to be held off until this
task is complete.
So what if we could say that, you know what? Let task 2 do its thing in the background but continue forward
and do the things that you can do right now.
And once that long task is completed well, then we'll deal with the results once that actually happens.
In this case we would be using an asynchronous method instead of a synchronous one.
So let's simulate a asynchronous delay.
We can do this by instead of using sleep,
we can use a method called Future.delayed. So it has two inputs,
one is a duration and the second is a computation to run after the delay.
This is what we need.
So the first input is going to be a three second delay and then I'm going to add a callback to specify
what should happen after those three seconds are up. And it's namely creating this result and printing
that task 2 is complete.
So I'm going to cut that and paste it into that.
Now the way that our code is going to run is this is a asynchronous method. And we know it's an asynchronous
method because it returns something called a future.
So whenever you see a future in the documentation, you'll know that the method is something that will
happen asynchronously. And it will delay by three seconds but it will allow other lines of the code to
run if they can.
Now once these three seconds are up, then it triggers the computation in the callback.
And in this case it's to create the result, task 2 data and the print task 2  complete.
Now if we run our code again, let's watch the console and see how it works this time.
Remember that at the top here where we say perform tasks, I haven't changed that order at all.
It's still task 1 should perform, then task 2 then task 3 gets called.
But now let's see what happens down here.
Task 1 task 3 completed almost immediately, and then task 2 complete after a three second delay.
So this is asynchronous programming in action.
We saw that because task 2 took a long time.
We were waiting for it to happen but we continued. We plowed ahead with the things that we can do right
now.
And once task 2 completed, it's then and only then, does it actually get executed and printed into the
console now.
That's all very well and good for things like downloading images from the Internet or doing time intensive
tasks.
But sometimes we need the results of the tasks to be able to continue to the next task.
So for example let's say that our task 3 actually required an input that comes from task 2.
So let's change task 3 to take a string input
that's called task2Data. And then let's use that inside  3, so task 3 complete with and then
we'll add all task 2 data inside this function.
Now task 3 relies on something that comes from task 2.
So that means we have to return something from task 2 to be able to do that.
So let's output a string from task 2 instead of nothing.
And we're going to output this result right here.
Let's create a new string up here
called result.
And let's set it to nothing to begin with, but only after our asynchronous method has delayed by 3 seconds.
So let's say we're fetching some data from the Internet. Only once that's completed
do we assign result to a value.
And finally at the very end do we actually return this result as the output of our task 2.
So now that task 2 has a output we can assign that to equal a new string called task2Result, going
to equal to the output of task 2. And then we're going to use that inside task 3.
So task 2 result is going to be the input for task 3.
So the entire order of things is task 2 will execute asynchronously so it can take as long as it wants
in the background.
Now once it's done though, it's going to assign some data to a string called result and then it's going
to print that it's completed and also output result.
Now at this stage, we're going to take that result and bind it to a new string and then use that as the
input for the next step which is inside task 3.
What do you think will happen given that we know that task 2 is asynchronous and it can complete at
any time at once and our code will actually skip ahead to try and do the things that it can't right
now?
So if we take a look at running our code, you can see that task 1 and task 3 complete almost immediately
and task two is taking its three second delay to complete. But because task 3 relies on some data
from task 2,
so if it executes immediately then it won't actually have the information to hand.
And so that's why we're getting task 3 complete with null
at this point because task2Data isn't available until the task 2 completes.
So how can we fix this?
Well we can make our code actually wait so we know that this is an asynchronous method and we allow
other code to continue on and not have to wait for this to finish.
But in this case because task 3 relies on this second task to complete, what we can do is we can make
our code wait for it to complete before we call the next task. To do this
we can change this into a async method.
So this is called a modifier and we add it just before the curly brace.
By adding that async keyword, we can now have access to the keyword
that's await.
And we're going to put it right in front of task 2.
So before we call task 2, we're going to wait for it to finish. Now inside task 2, we have to make
some changes too. Instead of returning a string,
we have to return something that's called a future.
Now a future is something that will exist in the future.
Right now it's nothing because our task hasn't completed. But once our task has completed then our future
will be an actual thing like an actual string or an actual integer. Now we have to also mark this method
as asynchronous to be able to say that we have to wait for this Future.delayed method to complete
before we can output our results.
So now with this updated code with our async and await where we're waiting on the parts that need to
complete in order to give an input to task 3,
now if I hit play and run my code, you can see task 1 complete happens first. And then task 2 happens
after a delay and then finally task 3 happens using the data that comes back after task 2 is complete.
Now we've talked a lot about futures
when we were writing our code in the demo. What exactly are futures?
Well they're kind of similar to receipts.
Let me explain what I mean.
Let's say that you go to the coffee shop and you order a cup of coffee.
Now at this point you'll get a receipt with an order number. And you can go away and do something else
or check Instagram or check Facebook while your coffee is made.
You don't want to stand there waiting for it to be done.
So then once the coffee is done, they'll shout for your order, 'Order number 1 please come and collect.'
And now you'll show up and you can actually claim your coffee based on your order receipt. That receipt
is the same as a future in Dart.
It's not the actual thing that you want.
It's just a promise that you will get something in the future. If you come from JavaScript and you've
heard of promises, then it's exactly the same.
It's something that doesn't exist right now but after it's completed its thing, after it's gotten the
image or after it's downloaded the text, then your future will actually materialize into a real object
like a real string or a real integer.
Now you can be more specific with your futures.
You can specify that this is going to be a future string or this is gonna be a future integer, and we
do that by using an angle bracket.
So in this case we can change our date type from just a generic dynamic future to something that is
a specific data type.
So it could be a future string.
So this means that we're expecting a future string
when we call this method task 2. And right now if I decide to comment out this line and try to print
what task 2 is equal to, then you can see that it's a instance of a future string.
It's not an actual string yet. It's only once task two is complete
does that future string materialize and change into an actual string. Now asynchronous programming is
not the easiest concept to grasp. But I hope through reviewing and re-reviewing this lesson and also
completing the modules that are ahead of you, where we're going to be using async and await and
futures in a lot more places, you're going to steadily get used to this idea of asynchronously doing
something. Instead of doing everything in sequence which is synchronous programming,
we're trying to be more efficient with our time or with the computer's time by trying to asynchronously
do our tasks so that things don't necessarily happen in the order that we programmed it to, but we end
up completing our tasks in the quickest way using the shortest route.
So this concept is going to come up again and again.
Don't worry if this hasn't completely settled in your mind yet. We're going to be reviewing this a lot
more in the future. But in the next lesson we're going to get back to making our app and getting our
location data as soon as we load up the screen.
So for all of that and more, I'll see you on the next lesson.