All right. So in this lesson, we're going to show you how to install and set up Android Studio for Flutter
and Dart.
So if you have Android Studio already installed, be sure that you updated to the latest version and follow
along with the rest of this video lesson because we're going to show you how to add the Flutter and
Dart packages to Android Studio.
Now if you don't have Android Studio installed, be sure to click on the link in the Flutter installation
instructions and go ahead and click on Download Android Studio. And once it's downloaded, simply go ahead
and install Android Studio onto your Windows machine.
Now once you've installed Android Studio,
be sure to go through the Android Studio setup wizard.
This installs the latest Android SDK, Android SDK platform tools, and Android SDK build tools which are
going to be required by Flutter when it's building your Android app.
Now it's kind of strange that you download a software and then you have to download some more stuff.
But this is how Android Studio works and you'll start to get used to it.
But once you're done, then you should be able to open up Android Studio and you'll see the welcome screen
like this. And you're gonna go to configure and go to settings, and we're gonna go to the plugin tab.
Now in order to install Flutter and Dart plugins, you're going to go over to browse repositories, and
you're going to search for Flutter.
And it should be the one that has simply just the name Flutter in it and you're gonna go ahead and click
on install. And be sure to accept any popups that come up. Now when you install the Flutter plugin.
It's also going to install the Dart plugin together. So you can go ahead and click yes for that pop
up too. Now,
once it's done, you have to restart Android Studio for the effects to take place. So be sure to click
restart when it prompts you to restart Android Studio and activate the changes in our plugins. And now
once that's done, you'll be at to see a new menu item in the welcome screen where it says to start a
new Flutter project.
So if you can see this in the welcome screen then consider this lesson successful. You're now set up to
use Flutter and Dart to develop Flutter apps for Android.
So in the next lesson, I'm going to show you how to setup the Android emulator and build a new Flutter
project to run it and test it out.
So for all of that and more, I'll see you on the next lesson.