Now Previously we saw how we can use different types of animations custom or out-of-the-box hero animations
and we can see how we can control all aspects of the animation by digging deep into the animation controller
and the animation objects.
Now in this lesson, I want to show you that there's also prepackaged animations. So if we head over to
our Flutter packages and if you search for animate, you'll find a whole bunch of things that you can
use to add instant animation into your app. So there's the flutter_sequence_animation for you to
define
whole bunch of animations that should happen in the sequence, so change color then change shape then
change size etc..
There's also animation that can be applied to widgets or components like this elastic bottom menu that
you can implement. There are springy animations like the sprung package which are easily implemented
and calculated from complex physics.
Now the package that I want to show you in our case that we're going to implement is something called
the animated_text_kit. And it has a series of beautiful text animations that pretty much are just add
water animations. They're so easy to use and you instantly get these really cool effects like the typewriter
or the scale change or the colorize etc. So let's go ahead and implement this into our code and see
how we're going from both ends of the extreme of animations, from fully customizable to using something
that's already prepackaged and ready made.
So let's go ahead and depend on this animated text kit.
So let's go into our pubspex.yaml and below cupertino icons, let's add our animated text kit. And let's
make sure we run packages.gets so that we grab that package and now we can import it wherever we
need it.
So we're going to import it at the top of our welcome screen and it's called animated_text_kit
.dart.
So now right here where we have our text in our Flash chat text widget, we can change that from a normal
text widget to a animated text widget and we can choose the type of animation we want.
So in my case I'm going to choose the typewriter so I can now replace that text widget with a Typewriter
AnimatedTextKit. And TypewriterAnimatedTextKit expects a list of strings which is going to come under
the text property.
So instead of having just a normal string, I'm going to create a list of strings and it's only going
to be a list of one string in this case.
But of course you can have more if you want it to,
and the property name is called text. So if you had  four lines of text for example then you could have
a list of  four strings, each of which is going to be printed out one by one using the typewriter animation.
And the last thing we have to change is that the style property is the same as the style property for
the text widget, but it simply has a different name it's called TextStyle and we can still apply our
TextStyle widget to the text that's being animated. And that's it. That's all we have to do to implement
that animation and we can now check it out. And so this is what it looks like. It'll type out the text,
it'll flash a few times before it goes back to type out the text again. And I think this looks really
really beautiful and I just wanted to show you how
there are lots of ready made animations that you can simply apply to your Flutter apps because brilliant
developers have created things and they've shared it with us on the Flutter packages. And we've also
got our fully customizable animation controllers and animations that we can build ourselves.
And this is where you have the most control over how it looks, how it behaves, what it does and you can
have a lot of control.
So those are the two sides of the coin and I hope that our deep dive into Flutter animations is going
to get you excited about putting animations in your next app.