In this video,
we'll cover testing using reflection.
Now there are some special cases during testing.
We may need to access some non-public fields.
For example, if you're using Hibernate JPA,
you may have some private fields for the ID
and you may want to set that using testing,
or you may have some fields that are auto wired,
and you'd like to set those manually
or retrieve those manually in your actual test.
You also may have a non-public method
that you'd like to test.
So, our next example,
we have a method called generate tracking number.
It's a private method,
but we'd still like to write a test for it.
Now you may wonder, well, why worry about
those private fields of methods?
Why not just make them public?
Well, that's one possible approach.
Well, you may be testing legacy code
and you can't change the code due to corporate policy.
And me personally, when I go into an existing code base,
I like to write the given test
and I want to try and minimize the amount of
existing code that I change.
For example, I don't want to go through
and touch any number of files that I don't have to
because now your name is on record
and if something with that existing code changes or breaks,
then you're responsible,
because you're the last person that touched it.
So, I don't like to go through
and change access modifiers on code.
I kind of like to leave the code as is
and simply write the test.
Now, I would be remiss in not mentioning this
but, in general, testing non-public fields
but in general, testing non-public fields
and methods is a bit controversial, all righty? .
So if you go online,
you'll see a number of discussions or arguments
debating saying, hey, you should never test private fields,
you should never test private methods.
That's a code smell. That's a bad practice.
And then on the other side, you'll see folks that say,
well, there's certain use cases
where it's okay to access private fields
or invoke private methods. All right.
So, you'll see debates and arguments
on both sides of defense.
So it's kind of like politics, right?
There's no right answer or right side.
You have to kind of make your own decision here.
So, I like to say, use this approach sparingly.
And if you are doing this,
make sure you have a really good justification
for why you're doing it
because other developers on your team
may question you about it, all right?
So, it's not bad, but just use sparingly.
And the spring framework actually provides a support class
for testing using reflection.
Spring has this utility class called ReflectionTestUtils
and this class allows you
to get and set non-public fields directly
and also allows you to invoke non-public methods.
So, this is part of the spring framework.
It's documented in the spring reference manual
and they also have JavaDocs for it.
On the slide, I have a link that'll redirect you
to the official JavaDoc for this given class.
And you can read about the additional use cases
and also read about the examples
and all the different methods
that are available in this class.
Let's go ahead and look at an example
of reading private fields.
I have this class, CollegeStudent,
it has a field called ID, it's a private field.
And I like to use that in my test.
So, at the bottom here,
I have this student that I get from the application context
and then I make use of reflection utils
and so, this is from this spring framework,
I say ReflectionUtils.getField
and I give the actual target object that I'm calling.
So, in this case, it's the student.
And then I specify the field that I want to access.
In this example, id.
And so that'll retrieve that field
and I can use it to print line
or use it in my assertions or whatever else in my unit test.
But this is the basic code here for reading a private field.
And we can take it a step further
of setting a private field.
So we have our CollegeStudent up top.
And then at the bottom here,
we make use of ReflectionTestUtils.setField
and then we give the actual target object,
the student, the field, ID
and the actual value of 1.
And we can give whatever value that we want here
that that given field will accept.
And here's to code for invoking your private method.
In our class, college student,
we have a method, get first name and ID.
It's a private method.
And then in our unit test,
we grab the student and then we make use of
ReflectionTestUtils.invokeMethod,
we give the target object of the student
and then the actual method name
and that'll call or invoke that private method.
They also have versions of this method
where you can actually pass an arguments
and you simply just pass the arguments
as a comma to limited list.
All righty, this looks really cool. I'm excited.
Let's go ahead and move into the next video
and let's start writing some code.