In this video, we'll cover
"Spring Boot Support for Unit Testing."
Now, what do you need for Spring Boot unit testing?
Well, you need access to the Spring Application Context,
you also need support for Spring dependency injection,
you also may need to retrieve data
from the Spring application.properties file.
And you'd also like mock object support
for web, data, REST APIs, and so on.
Well, Spring Boot provides rich testing support,
Spring Boot provides a sanitation Spring Boot test,
the sanitation loads the Spring application context,
it also has support for Spring dependency injection,
and you can also access data
from your Spring application.properties file,
and many more features.
And I'll show you some of the key items here in this video.
Let's take a look at the Spring Boot starter
for testing support.
In our Maven pom.xml file,
we add the Spring Boot starter test.
Now, a really nice thing about this starter
is that it includes a transitive dependency on JUnit 5.
So that means we get JUnit 5 for free
without having to explicitly list it here.
Now, a bit more here on the transitive dependency.
So we can actually verify this.
So in our IntelliJ,
we can look at the Maven dependencies,
and we can expand the item here
for a Spring Boot starter test,
and we can move down a bit,
and we can see that there's a reference here
for org.junit.jupiter, so that's JUnit 5.
So again, we get this transitive dependency for free.
We don't have to explicitly list it.
It's part of the Spring Boot starter test.
And if you're not using an IDE,
you can also verify this at the command line.
So simply type mvn dependency:tree,
it'll give you a list
of all the dependencies for your project,
and then you can kind of scroll down
and pick out the reference here
for Spring Boot starter test,
and you'll see a reference here for org.junit.jupiter,
again, JUnit 5 support that we get for free.
Let's take a look at an example.
On our test class, we simply annotated as Spring Boot test,
and then we can write our normal JUnit test.
Now here, the Spring Boot test,
behind the scenes it'll actually load
the Spring application context.
And then once the application context is loaded,
then we can actually inject some Spring beans.
So say for example we have this student-grades component,
it's a Spring bean,
and then in my test, I can simply inject that component.
So here I have auto wired student grades,
and I give a reference to it.
And so now that it's injected or auto wired,
we can use that component in our unit test.
Let's take a little look at another example here
of accessing the Spring application properties.
So we have our application.properties file,
all of our different name-value pairs there,
and then we can simply reference those properties
by making use of add value.
And you simply give the name
of the property that you want to access.
So again, very similar to normal Spring coding,
we're simply doing this inside of a unit test.
And we can use these values
later on in our actual unit test
to perform some asserts or so on.
And now you may have a scenario
where you actually want to
access the Application Context directly,
and then do some get beans and so on.
Well, you can simply just auto wire
in that Application Context,
you can reference it and use it in your JUnit test.
Let's discuss Spring test configuration.
If we follow the approach of placing our test class
in a test package that has the same name
as our main package,
then everything's a, okay.
So if those package names match up,
then this will implicitly define the base search,
and we can leverage some default configuration here.
So there's no need to explicitly reference
the main Spring Boot application class,
it'll find it automatically.
As an example, here we have
our main Spring Boot application class.
And as you know,
it automatically component scans all the sub-packages.
And notice here on our test and our main,
both of those package names are the same.
So no additional configurations required.
Our Spring Boot test will find the main Spring Boot class,
and automatically do the scanning and so on.
So everything is ready to go out of the box.
This is the easy case.
The default configuration is fine
if everything is under com.luv2code.component.
But, what if the test class
is in a different package like com.luv2code.test.
So in this diagram here,
we have our main package, com.luv2code.component,
but our test package is called com.luv2code.test.
Ooh.
So in this scenario,
we have to do some additional configuration here,
and we have to explicitly reference
the main Spring Boot class.
So in that Spring Boot test annotation,
we need to say class is equal,
and you give a reference to the main Spring Boot class,
and then everything else will work as desired.
So let's discuss our sample project.
We have a student grading system,
this code was created by our previous employee.
The code doesn't have any test, gasp, yikes!
And we've been tasked with developing the unit tests.
So I like to say, "Yay! We're excited."
We have an existing code base already,
for models, they have a college student, student interface,
student grades, MVC testing example application,
but no test code.
So we're going to code to perform the unit testing
for this example.
All right, so I'm excited.
Let's go ahead and dive into the next video
and let's get started.