In this video we'll cover Mocks with Mockito
and Spring Boot.
Now here's our typical application architecture.
We have our main application.
We have a service.
We have a DAO, and we have a backend database.
Now the question is, how do we test the service?
And I'd like to test the service
with only minimal configuration of dependencies.
So, you know, minimal DAO DB stuff.
I want to kind of keep that simple,
but in our current scenario,
this is tricky because the DAO communicates
with the database
and then getting a database configured, username,
password, tables, rows, data, and so on, really tricky.
And then also testing with the database
is not really unit testing.
This is actually called integration testing,
and we'll cover integration testing later in the course.
But at this point I simply want to kind of focus in on
how can I just test the service in isolation?
Well, one approach is that I can make use of a test double.
So I have my main application.
I have my service.
And then instead of using DAO
that communicates directly with the database,
I can make use of a test double.
So I can make use of a stand in for the real person.
So kind of like in the movies,
you have like a, you have the main movie star
and then you have like a stunt man or a stunt woman,
or in the theater world,
you have your practicing or rehearsing for a play
and you may have a stand in for a given person
who's not there during rehearsals.
We'll make use of this test double.
So here with the test double,
we set expectations with mock responses.
Basically what we mean here is that
when method ABC is called, then return XYZ.
All right.
So again, kind of going back to our real world analogy
with the theater,
we had this stand in actor during rehearsals.
So you could say hey, one of our cast members,
they couldn't make it to rehearsal
or practice today for our play.
Let's grab somebody who can just kind of stand in
and let's give them the dialogue or give them the script,
and they you'll tell the person hey, I'm going to say my line.
And then you simply read what you see on the paper
for your line.
All right.
So again, they're kind of just a test double.
They're kind of standing in,
they already know the responses to make
when we say our line
because they can simply read the script
and respond with their given line.
So that's kind of the idea of using a test double.
Now this technique of using test doubles
is known as mocking.
So you may have heard the term a lot in the industry,
different frameworks and so on,
and we'll actually look at how we can use mocking
in our example.
What are the benefits of mocking?
Well, mocking allows us to test a given class in isolation.
It also allows us to test the interaction
between the given class and its dependencies,
and what this does is that it minimizes the configuration
and the availability of those dependencies.
So for example, if we're going to test a DAO
or a database or REST API,
well for the DAO,
we can mock the DAO for a given response saying hey,
don't talk to the real database.
If they simply make a call for get customers,
then we'll simply give them a canned list of customers.
Or if they say hey, perform an update on a given object,
then we'll simply return that given object.
We'll kind of fake it out
as far as what's actually going to happen
on the backend database side.
So again, we're making use of that test double
to kind of give some mock responses,
and a similar thing for a REST API.
So if we're call some external REST API
we may not be able to access the REST API
because maybe it's in production or it's in test
or we don't have the license or a developer API or token.
Then we can simply set up a mock response.
So we could say hey, if I call this external API,
then I know it should return a given response.
So we can kind of mock those response up front.
And again, going back to our real world analogy
in the theater,
we have this stand in actor during rehearsals.
So we can say our line, they can simply read the script,
or read the mock response or say their given line.
Now, as terms of mocking frameworks and the Java ecosystem,
there's a large number of mocking frameworks.
And these mocking frameworks
provide the following features.
They minimize the hand-coding of mocks
by leveraging annotations.
You can set the expectations for the mock responses.
You can also verify the calls to the methods,
including the number of times a method's been called,
and there's also programmatic support
for throwing exceptions.
And we'll actually see examples of all of this
in the upcoming videos.
Now in terms of mocking frameworks,
well there's a lot of them out there.
So one is Mockito and another one here is EasyMock,
and there's also JMockit.
And then there's a number of others out there.
You could keep searching for days and days,
but to make things easy,
we're going to make use of Mockito
because Spring Boot has built in support for Mockito.
Out of the box, Spring Boot has support for Mockito.
and let's take a look at this.
So the Spring Boot Starter has a transitive dependency
for Mockito.
So in our pom.xml file,
we simply make use of Spring Boot Starter test.
And if we look at the dependencies here,
then we'll see that this starter
includes a transitive dependency on Mockito.
So we get it for free.
Built in support,
we get it out of the box.
Now, unit testing with Mocks.
So unit tests with Mocks have the following structure.
You start with a setup, then we execute, we have assert,
and then we verify.
During setup,
we set the expectations with the mock responses.
So again, kind of like that idea of the test double
or the stand in actor.
Basically you say, I'm going to say this
and you respond with that.
That's the idea of setting expectations with mock responses.
Then we execute.
So we call the method we want to test.
Then we do an assert.
We check the result and verify
that it is the expected result.
And then finally verify.
And so this is optional.
We verify the calls.
We can see how many times a given method was called
and so on.
Now here's our testing plan.
So we have our main application, we have our service.
And so instead of using the DAO
that communicates directly to the database,
we'll make use of this DAO test double.
So we'll actually test our service
and then we'll create a mock for the DAO.
Now let's review the code
for the service and our application DAO
that we'll use in these examples here.
So we'll start with ApplicationServices.java,
it's simply a class.
We have a field here, ApplicationDAO,
that's our dependency that we're going to auto wire.
And then we have a couple of methods here for this service.
Add grades, find grades, check null.
Then for the application DAO, that's our dependency.
It's a class and it has these three methods,
add, find, and check null.
So application DAO is a dependency
on the application service.
And what we'll do is we'll actually mock the application DAO
and we'll inject it into the service.