In this video will set up the SQL scripts
and properties files.
Now, currently in our application the SQL
for the sample data is hard-coded in our tests.
And we like to move the SQL to our properties file.
Now let's look at the code that we currently have
using the BeforeEach and AfterEach and the BeforeEach
we have the SQL for inserting sample data
and the AfterEach we have the code
for deleting sample data, but this is all hard-coded SQL.
I'd like to take this, remove it
from the code and put it into a properties file.
Here's our development process.
The first thing that we'll do is we'll add the SQL
to the application.properties.
Then we'll inject the SQL into our test
using the value annotation.
Finally we'll refactor the BeforeEach
and AfterEach methods to make use of the properties.
Now let's take a look
at step one of adding the SQL to application.properties.
We'll take that SQL that we currently
have in our test class
and we'll move this over to an application.properties file.
At the moment here, I have an example
for creating student and also deleting the student.
Then in step two, we're going to inject the SQL
into the test using the value annotation.
Here's my coding here for my test.
And then notice here
I have value and I give the name
of the actual property that I'm going to inject.
Here we have sql.script.create.student
refers to the actual property
from the application.properties file
and a similar thing here for deleting the student.
Now in step three, we can refactor
the BeforeEach and AfterEach annotations, these methods here
and the BeforeEach, we can simply make use
of that string jdbc execute SQL add student
and a similar thing for AfterEach,
jdbc execute SQL delete student.
So this looks pretty good.
We've accomplished the goal of removing the hard-coded SQL
from our Java code and putting it into our properties file.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and swing
into the next video and let's write the code for this.