In this video we'll cover MVC Tests
for Student Information.
We'd like to have MVC tests for student information
to cover these cases.
If we have a valid student ID,
we'd like to return the view name, 'studentInformation',
or make use of Thymeleaf templates,
and this will map over to studentinformation.HTML.
If we have an invalid student ID,
then we'd like to return the view name of, 'error',
and this will map over to our Thymeleaf template,
error.HTML.
And now, we have some basic functionality
in place right now for student information,
we can view this in our Gradebook Controller.
Down near the bottom of our Gradebook Controller,
we have this method here,
'studentInformation', basically reads information
and simply returns student information.
But at the moment, it doesn't really populate any data,
any attributes, it's kind of just blank right now.
Now to test this, we'd like to write a failing test first.
So if we pass in a valid student ID,
we should get 'studentInformation'.
If we pass in an invalid student ID, we should get 'error'.
So let's go ahead and write our failing test,
and then we'll go back and enhance our code accordingly.
This is the first test of our valid student ID.
And our tests here,
the first thing we want to do is 'assertTrue',
so we want to make sure that the student exists.
So we're doing a 'findById' of one.
And then we actually perform the HTTP request.
So we do a 'GET' on that student information slash ID,
or pass in an ID of one.
And you've seen this code before.
We're simply making an HTTP request.
And then we'll retrieve the 'ModelAndView'.
And now we'll assert the view name to make sure that
we have the view name of 'studentInformation',
because we passed in a valid student ID.
Alrighty, so this code looks pretty good.
Now let's go ahead and write a test
for the case of an invalid student ID.
And the first thing we want to do is 'assertFalse',
so we want to make sure that the student does not exist.
So we're doing a 'findById' of zero,
so zero's an invalid student ID.
And we'll perform a similar HTP request, like we did above.
We pass in the invalid student ID of zero.
Next, we get the 'ModelAndView',
and then we assert the view name.
So in this case with an invalid student ID,
the view name should be 'error'.
Let's go ahead and run our test.
One of our tests will fail, student information
for the error.
Here, we gave an invalid student ID,
but it returned 'studentInformation'.
We expected it to return 'error', but at the moment
our code doesn't really check for invalid student ID's
for student information.
This is fine.
Failing tests first, we'll go and modify our code
to make it work, and then we'll come back and test again.
We'll cover that portion in the next video.
So I'll see you there.