In this video, we'll look
at our course project and a testing overview.
We'll start with an existing student grade book application.
The app was created by a previous employee
but it is unfinished. Yikes.
Our job is to add remaining functionality to save data
in the database and also add unit test and integration test.
Now, let's talk about the student grade book application.
This application will be used
by an instructor to keep track of grades for a student.
The grades are tracked for the subjects
history, science and math.
And the instructor can add grades
for a student for a specific subject.
And here's a little screenshot of the app
and I'll show you a demo of the app in a second.
Now here's the technical stack for the application.
Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Spring MVC,
Thymeleaf views, CSS and JavaScript.
Now the Spring Data JPA portion it's listed
in the Maven pom file.
However, the previous developer
didn't actually do any of the database work.
We'll actually focus on doing database work
and we'll also add additional functionality
as we go through the application.
Now here's a quick demo of the application.
This is the final version of the application.
So we have all the database stuff working behind the scenes
but I want to simply show you the app real quick
just so you can understand how the application works.
And we can go ahead and add some sample students here.
So I'll add something for myself.
Also add something for Eric.
We can select a student and then we can go in
and we can actually add some grades for a given subject.
So here I'm adding grades for a math assignment for myself
and then we can do a similar thing here
for science assignments.
So we're just adding grades and then notice here
it'll kind of, it keeps track of the average
the overall average for the grades for a given subject.
Then a similar thing here for history assignments.
So effectively here for a given student
we can track grades for a given subject.
We can also go through and remove grades if we needed to.
We can go into home and we can just drill
down on a given student and check their grades and so on.
So my previous grades are still there and we can go through
and we can add some grades here for Eric.
All right. So that's kind of the basic layout here
for this application for our GradeBook app.
And so we have some of the functionality in place
but we'll have to add additional functionality to
allow it to save to the database.
So this is kind of like a demo of the
of the actual end result.
All righty, good stuff.
Okay, great.
So that was a good demo of the application.
Now let's look at the existing code behind the scenes.
We have controller, model and a view.
So this kind of follows the standard Spring MVC approach
spring model view controller.
Taking a look at the controller, we have this
GradeBookController.java.
At the moment it's a very simple class.
We'll see the code for it in a second.
And then we also have the model.
So the models of collection of classes
that we'll make use of, CollegeStudentGrade, so on.
I'll talk about those in a bit.
And then we also have our Thymeleaf views.
So we have the main index.html page
a student information page
and also supporting CSS and JavaScript code.
Now let's take a look at the
existing code for the model classes.
We'll have this interface for grade, we'll have an ID
a student ID and a grade.
Then for that, given interface
we'll have classes to implement that interface.
So we'll have a class for a history grade,
math grade and science grade.
So they all implement the grade interface.
Then we also have this interface for a student.
So we have this field for student information
and also full name.
We have a class that implements the interface
called CollegeStudent, and then we extend
off of that CollegeStudent.
We have a subclass called GradeBookCollegeStudent
and this has a reference to the student grades.
And then over on the far right, we have a GradeBook.
So a GradeBook is basically a collection of students.
So here we have students, list, GradeBookCollegeStudent.
And then we have this class StudentGrades.
So this actually contains the list of history grades,
math grades, and also science grades.
Now notice the relationship between the
GradeBookCollegeStudent and StudentGrades.
So a GradeBookCollegeStudent has StudentGrades.
And then if we look at the top right
a GradeBook has a collection of students.
So think of it like in the old days in the classroom, right?
A teacher had a grade book that had a list
of all the students.
And then for each student, you had grades
for each subject, history, math, science, and so on.
And we'll see all the source code for this in a bit.
And when we go through and explore the project.
Now as far as the code that we will develop currently
the app does not store information in the database.
And so we'll add DAO database support.
We'll also add a service class.
And also during the development process
we'll add unit test and integration test.
And once we're done, our final architecture looks like this.
So we'll have a GradeBookController that communicates
with a StudentAndGradeService.
And then we'll also have DAO's for students, history, grades
math grades, and also science grades.
And that basically is our interface to our backend database.
And as we go through the whole process
we'll actually write unit test and integration test.
So we'll test our code as we're developing it.