In this video,
we're going to cover how to create grades.
Now, we have some work to do.
Currently, the application does not keep track of grades
for a given student.
At the moment, the UI is really just hard coded,
so the data that you see for a given student,
it's just hard coded data right now.
What we'd like to do is add support for tracking grades.
So for a given student, we'd like for them
to be able to go through and add grades for a given student
for the different subjects, for math, science, and history.
And for this grades functionality,
we'll apply TDD to add this new functionality.
What we'll do is we'll update the StudentAndGradeService
and some DAOs to track the actual student grades.
At the moment, we have one student DAO
and we'll create additional DAOs for history grades,
math grades, and also science grades.
And we'll pull this all together,
and we'll apply TDD as we go through the whole process.
Alrighty. So this looks pretty good.
I'm excited.
Let's go ahead and move into the IDE, and let's get started.
All righty.
So let's go ahead and move
into our StudentGradeAndServiceTest.
And what we'll do to get started is that
we'll add a new test, and this will be a failing test.
And this is creating a grade using a service.
Let me move in here,
and I want to write some quick comments to myself,
just to keep myself on track.
So taking a look here at our comments
where in create the grade,
get all the grades we've given studentId,
and verify that there is grades.
Now, let's go ahead and do an assertion here,
and I'll make use of my student service.
And I'll create a grade,
I'll pass in the actual grade,
I'll pass in the studentId,
and I'll also type, pass in the type of grade.
So ideally, this should create a math grade
in the background of 80.5 for studentId of 1.
And now, I'll go ahead and get the grades
with the given studentId.
I'll make use of the mathGradeDao.findGradeByStudentId.
Now, the things here in red,
that means that these items don't exist.
That's fine.
We'll actually use the test to drive our development here.
And then finally, we want to verify that there are grades.
And then, I'll make use the mathGrades.iterator.hasNext.
That means that we have some grades here,
and then I'll say that,
"Okay, this given student has math grades."
And we can do some more things later,
but at this point, this is enough for our test.
Let's go ahead and run our test.
This test will fail because it doesn't even compile.
We don't have a method createGrade,
and we also don't have a mathGradeDao,
so we need to do that.
Well, first off,
let's go ahead and move into our StudentAndGradeService.
And then, we'll add that method here for creating a grade.
And remember, we can also use the IDE
to generate the method steps for us,
but right now, I'll just kind of write it out long hand.
But you can do it, either way.
I'll create this method here, createGrade.
I'll be passing the actual value of the grade,
the actual studentId, and the actual type of grade.
And this method will return a Boolean,
meaning that it was successful.
Now at the moment, I'll actually say return false.
Again, this code's failing,
we'll have to do some work to make it pass over time.
But at least this kind of gets rid of the compilation error
we had for StudentServiceCreateGrade.
The next item that we have here is the mathGradeDao.
This one doesn't exist,
so I should need to create this given Dao.
And let's move over to our repository,
and let's create a new interface.
So repository, and be sure to select Interface.
The name of this interface is going to be MathGradesDao,
make sure interface is selected,
because we're using Spring Data JPA.
And here, for MathGradesDao,
we see extends CrudRepository.
We give the entity type of MathGrade, the type
for the primary key, Integer.
And we'll also add a custom finder method here.
And this will be findGradeByStudentId.
And this will return the math grades for this given student.
All right. Now, swinging back over to our test.
Then this Dao should get resolved.
Well, not yet.
We actually need to autowire this Dao.
So let's move up to the top,
and autowire in the MathGradesDao.
All righty.
So this is better, looks better.
If we scroll back down, then mathGradeDao, great.
It's no longer red.
Now, we can go ahead and run this test,
and this test fails as expected, right?
We haven't done any real work yet.
We need to go through and actually write code
for making this test pass, but don't worry.
We'll move into the next video,
and we'll continue writing the code for this.