Okay, so let's go ahead and move into our IDE.
And what I'd like to do is create a new test class.
So I'll move down into my test section into this package,
com.luv2code.springmvc
and I'll create a new class
and the name for this class.
I'll call it GradebookControllerTest.
All right, here's my class.
Let me expand my window for a second.
The first thing I like to do is set
up the test property source, application.properties.
I'll also Auto configure the MockMvc
and make sure you choose the correct annotation here.
AutoconfigureMockMvc.
And then we simply make use
of the spring boot test annotation.
Let's go ahead
and inject some supporting fields here.
We'll use these later in our examples
but I'll just go ahead and get things set up.
So I'll make use of the jdbc template.
We'll also inject the MockMvc
and then I'll also set up
a mock for my student and grade service.
And again these are simply some supporting fields
that we'll use in some of the following tests.
Let me just stretch out a bit
get myself some room to work with.
I'll make use of a before each annotation here
to kind of do some initial setup for my test.
And I'll actually just copy some
of the code from our student and grade service test.
Let me open that one up and I'll just kind of
copy the same thing I had before just adding a new student
to the database for each one of the tests.
I'll just copy this move over here
to my GreatbookControllerTest and paste it in
and I'll do a similar thing for the after each
let's move over to our student in grade service test
and let's just copy that and move it over.
Okay, excellent.
So we have our basics in place here
and this some good infrastructure that we have in place.
And we'll use this in some of the following videos
but at the moment, this looks pretty good.
I like it.