Alrighty, so let's get started
with our development process, writing a test,
making code pass, refactoring it,
and also repeating the process.
And let's do some setup work here.
First I want to go ahead and create some packages
under my test section.
I want to create a new package here.
So test, Java, New Package,
and I'll give it com.luv2code.tdd.
Okay, so that gives us that new TDD package
under our test section,
and I want to do a similar thing here under the main section.
So here under main Java,
let's create a new package and we'll give it the same name.
All right, so let's move back into our test section here
and we'll go ahead and do some setup work
for our test under the TDD package.
And I'll just create a new class.
And for the name of this class, I'll call it FizzBuzzTest.
And there's no requirement that our tests have to be public,
so I'll simply just remove the public keyword there.
It's fine either way.
And what I'll do here is I'll just write out the spec
or the rules here for FizzBuzz
just to kind of keep myself on track.
Okay, so this looks pretty good.
Let me expand my window here
and kind of get down the business.
And so I'll just write my first test
and I'll just kind of put all the, you know, the template
or the structure in place for the test for right now.
Here, I'll test for visible by 3,
and I'll just stub it out.
I won't actually write the implementation code.
I'll just make it just a failing test at the moment.
So I'll use fail and just give a fail message.
So this is an assertion
that you can use just for doing an initial fail.
So we, again, we want to fail first
and we'll flesh this out a bit.
I just want to put this in there for right now.
Make use of the test annotation.
I'll set up a display name
and I'll also use an order because I want the test
to run in a given order mainly for a display
and reporting purposes here.
And I'll simply add the annotation up top
to handle method orderer by the order annotation.
And we've seen all this stuff before
in some of the previous videos.
Just applying what we've learned.
And we'll simply go through
and run this test and it fails as desired.
Okay, so at least we have all of our basic stuff
in place right now, and then we can kind of get down
to business and start doing some real coding,
but this looks good so far.