In this video,
will get started with testing REST APIs
for the Spring REST controllers.
Now, here's the problem.
How can we test REST APIs developed
with Spring RESTs Controllers?
Also, how can we create HTTP requests
and send them to the Spring REST Controllers?
And how can we verify the HTTP response?
For the response, I'd like to check the status code.
I'd like to check the content type.
And also, inspect the JSON response body.
So I'm at a loss here.
How can I achieve that?
Well, Spring provides testing support,
so we can test Spring RESTs controllers using MockMVC.
And we saw MockMVC in some of the earlier videos.
This provide Spring REST processing
of requests and response.
And the nice thing here is that
there's no need to run a server, embedded or external.
We're mocking everything out.
In general, the process is very similar
to Spring MVC testing.
There's simply some slight differences
for checking the content type,
and also checking the JSON results.
But don't worry,
we'll cover those differences in these videos.
Let's take a look at the preliminary setup.
For our GradebookControllerTest,
we need to stub out the test class,
and we also needs to define the fields that we'll use later.
Like the MockMVC, the Service, the DAOs, et cetera.
And also, we need to add some setup and cleanup code,
so that's using the @BeforeAll, @BeforeEach, @AfterEach.
And we used a lot of these development techniques
in some of the previous videos,
and we'll simply apply the same approaches here
for the REST API testing videos.
And now, here's an overview
of what our GradebookControllerTest will look like.
Up top, we'll have the annotations
for the test property source.
We'll auto configure, the MockMVC,
and we'll make use of the SpringBootTest annotation.
We'll have our test class, and then we'll go through it,
and we'll actually inject the supporting utils like MockMVC.
We'll inject the Service and the DAOs.
We'll inject our SQL strings.
And also, we'll set up the annotations here
for the setup and cleanup code
using the @BeforeAll, @BeforeEach, @AfterEach.
So that's the big picture,
and then we'll go through,
and actually write the appropriate coding for this.
All righty, this looks really good.
I'm getting excited.
Let's go ahead and swing into our IDE and let's get started.
I'll zoom in here, and I'll just collapse
some of the packages.
And I'll move down to my test section.
And I will add a new test class.
And the name of this class is GradebookControllerTest.
Let me expand my window here for a second,
and I'll start off here with my annotations
for test property source.
I'll reference my application-test.properties.
I'll auto configure the MockMVC.
I'll also set up the SpringBootTest annotation.
And one of the item that I'll add here
is the transactional annotation
because we'll make use of the JPA Entity Manager,
directly in this test,
and so we need to have this annotation, in place for that.
I'll go ahead and set up some of my test items here.
We'll make use of a mock servlet request.
I'll also inject the JPA Entity Manager,
like I mentioned earlier.
So we inject that using the PersistenceContext.
I'll set up a mock here for my StudentAndGradeService.
So there's some scenarios
where I'll make use of this mock in our test.
Let me stretch out here at the bottom a bit,
I'll give myself some room to work with.
And now in this next section, what we're going to do is that
we'll actually leverage some code that we've written before.
In our StudentAndGradeServiceTest,
there's a lot of good code over there,
and we'll simply copy some of that code,
and we'll move it into our GradebookControllerTest.
Again, we wrote a lot of this code
in the previous set of videos,
and so you've seen this code before.
We're simply going to leverage this code,
and use it here in our GradebookControllerTest.
So we'll do a little copy paste exercise
in the next section here.
So follow along with me.
And what I'll do is
I'll open up my StudentAndGradeServiceTest.
And the first thing I want to do
is I want to grab the JdbcTemplate, the DAOs,
and the services.
So let's just kind highlight the code here,
starting at JdbcTemplate,
all the way down to the student service.
And we'll just go ahead and copy these lines.
So this is in our StudentAndGradeServiceTest.
Let's copy this code,
and then we'll move over to our GradebookControllerTest,
and then we'll paste in that code.
Alrighty. So that looks pretty good.
Now, let's move back to our StudentAndGradeServiceTest,
and let's go ahead and grab all of those SQL scripts
that we injected.
So I'll start here with the SQL for add student,
all the way down to delete history grades.
So all of this code here that we have highlighted,
let's go ahead and copy that.
And this is from the StudentAndGradeServiceTest.
Let's copy this code and then move back over
to our GradebookControllerTest, and paste that code.
So we're in GradebookControllerTest,
now let's go ahead and do a paste.
Okay, great.
Now, let's swing back over
to our StudentAndGradeServiceTest.
And let's grab this setup code here for @BeforeEach.
So let's go ahead and copy this
from StudentAndGradeServiceTest,
and then we'll move over to GradebookControllerTest
and paste it in.
Excellent. That looks pretty good.
And then, one last thing, in StudentAndGradeServiceTest,
we're almost done, all the way down there at the bottom,
let's grab that cleanup code that we had, the @AfterEach.
Let's copy this from StudentAndGradeServiceTest,
and let's swing over to GradebookControllerTest,
and paste it.
Okay, looks good.
And again, this is all the code
that we wrote in the previous videos.
So there's nothing really new here.
We're just simply reusing code that we created earlier.
And now, one thing I'd like to do
is just set up a little placeholder test
that just does nothing.
I just want to make sure I can run this test class.
So just a very basic placeholder test does nothing here.
And we simply need Test annotation in place.
And now, let's go ahead and run this placeholder test.
And I just want to make sure
that we have all the infrastructure,
all the mechanics in place here, for this example.
And excellent.
So this test runs,
that means that we can do all the injection,
all the properties and so forth, that all works.
And we can actually get down and start writing
some real tests later.
But I just wanted to have a little litmus test here,
to make sure that our infrastructure is set up properly,
and it is.
So this is great.
I'm happy.