In this video, we'll cover JUnit assertions.
JUnit has a collection of assertions
and they're defined in the class
org.junit.jupiter.api.Assertions.
And so here's a list of some of the methods.
So we already saw this first one here assertEquals,
it basically asserts that the values are equal.
They also have the assertNotEquals
so asserts that the values are not equal.
And then there's also the assertNull
and assertNotNull, and these are all very self explanatory.
Now let's look at some examples here with assertEquals.
So we saw from the previous slide assertEquals
the first parameter coming in is the expected value,
and then you have the actual value
after executing the method under test.
And then you can have an optional message if the test fails.
There's also assertNotEquals.
Here the first parameter's the unexpected value.
And then we have the actual value
after executing the method under test.
And again, the optional message if the test fails.
So let's kind of pull this together with an example.
So we have our DemoUtilsTest.
We'll set up this test, testEqualsAndNotEquals.
In the setup, we create an instance of the class to test.
Then we set our expected value, our unexpected value,
and then we execute, so demoUtils.add 2,4.
And now we perform our assertion here.
So we have assertEquals expected, actual,
and then we have Assertions.assertNotEquals
unexpected, value.
So here, I'm checking the actual result
and verifying that it's not the unexpected value.
So here I'm basically saying 2 + 4 must not be 8.
Now we can also make use of this static import.
So a static import is basically a shortcut
for referencing static methods and fields in a class.
So earlier we had Assertions.assertNotEquals,
so we have the class name, dot, the method name.
The standard approach
for calling a static method in a class.
However, we can make use of the static import
to kind of clean things up a bit.
So up top, we can say import static
and give a reference to the actual class, dot, method name.
And then, this will give us a shortcut
where we simply just give the method name
from making the call.
So no need to do the long hand approach here,
we can simply give the method name for making the call.
So now we can simply say assertEquals or assertNotEquals.
And then we can even take this a step further
by making use of wildcards.
So instead of having to list
each one of the methods individually,
because there may be a lot of methods in a given class
that we need to use,
we can simply just make use of the wildcard, the star.
So here I can simply say import static
and then assertions.*
and then I can simply use the methods as needed.
So you'll see this approach used commonly
on unit testing examples that you'll see in the real world.
And now we can kind of pull this together
with a code example here.
So notice up top, we're making some static imports
and we're using a wildcard.
And so, now we simply have to just give the method name
for making those given calls.
And we can also kind of restructure our code a bit.
So in our class DemoTestUtils
when we create our methods, we go through the setup process
but then we actually kind of restructure things
and we combine the execute and assert together
in the same line.
So here I have assertEquals,
I give the expected value of six,
I call the method and get the actual results here.
And I have the optional message here.
Now you may wonder, why are we taking this approach?
Well, it just kind of minimizes the amount of code
that we have to write, and also if we have multiple asserts,
we can easily perform a lot of operations
in a smaller number of lines.
And so, this will be very useful for us
as we go through testing our code,
we can kind of minimize all the intermediate steps
and just go directly
with doing the execute and assert together in one line.
And so, here, this helps us out
by going through doing another step here
with assertNotEquals the different values accordingly.
Now let's take a look at another example here.
So here's our code to test with our DemoUtils.
We're going to test this method here checkNull.
So if they pass on an object,
I want to see if that object's null.
If it's not null, I'll return the object.
If it is null, I'll return null.
And this is really just a academic example here,
we're simply just showing you
how to make use of JUnit testing.
So we can make use of our assertions here
for Null and NotNull.
So the assertNull asserts that the value is null,
and NotNull, of course,
asserting that the value is not null.
Let's go ahead and set up a unit test for this.
So I have the test Null and NotNull.
I create an instance of DemoUtils,
I set up some variables here for String 1, it's null,
String 2 equals luv2code.
And then I do an assertNull on checkNull String 1,
the object should be null.
So that's the actual value after executing the method
that's under test and our optional message.
And then we do a similar thing for assertNotNull.
So we pass in checkNull on String 2,
and here we say this object should not be null.
Then we run this one, our test results, the tests pass,
we get the green check mark
and everything works out fine
so know that this piece of code is working just fine.
And now we can also combine our tests.
We can actually have multiple tests in one class.
So in this example here,
I can have my testEqualsAndNotEquals,
and also my testNullAndNotNull.
So they're part of one class
and I can run this as a given unit test
and it'll show me the results.
It'll say, hey, both tests passed,
and it'll also tell you how many tests were executed.
And now, if you'd like to get more details
here on writing tests, this is just kind of the basics,
you can take a look at the JUnit User Guide
and you can access it at the link
that I have here on the slide.
All righty, so this is all really good information.
Let's go ahead and dive into the next video
and let's start writing some code.