And we're making some really
good progress here.
In this video we'll cover step two
of injecting the SQL into our test
using the value annotation.
Let's swing over to our code
for our student and grade service test,
and we'll make use of the value annotation
to inject those values.
We reference the actual name of the property,
and we'll assign it to a string SQLaddstudent.
And then we simply repeat the process
for the other fields here.
So I'll kind of go on quiet time right now
and just crank out this code,
so just follow along with me.
Okay, I'm back.
Alrighty, so this all looks really good.
So we have the code in place for injecting the SQL
from the properties file into our test.