Okay, so we're making
some really good progress here,
let's go ahead and start writing some tests.
I'll add a new test here, "getstudentsHttpRequest."
I'll set up some sample objects that I can use here,
so I'll create a studentOne for Eric Roby,
and then I'll just do a quick copy paste here
for studentTwo, and then I'll just update for Darby.
And now let's go ahead and add these two objects
studentOne and studentTwo to a list.
And now I'd like to set up the mock here
for the studentAndGradeServiceMock.
So I'll say, "when,
studentAndGradeServiceMock.getGradebook."
then I simply want to return the collegeStudentList.
And let me fix a little typo I have here, "thenReturn."
And now just create a very simple assert here,
just making sure these two lists are the same
or these iterables are the same here.
So assertIterableEquals, I give collegeStudentList
and then I'll call this studentAndGradeServiceMock,
getGradebook, again, just a very basic test
just to make sure we have
some basic infrastructure in place right now.
Now, let me go ahead and run this test
and this test should run and should pass A-OK
because all we're doing is just playing around
with the mock object and comparing list,
so very simple, very straightforward.
We're not really doing anything with web yet,
we'll get into that in a second.
Now let's go ahead and move up to our controller,
our GradebookController, and I'll just set up
some preliminary work here in the GradebookController
to kind of set us up for some of the following videos.
So right now I'm in GradebookController,
I'ma expand my window here for a second,
I notice here that the code's not formatted properly,
let me just do a quick format here.
I know eventually I'll need the studentAndGradeService,
so let me go ahead and auto wire it right now.
I'll set up my collegeStudents here,
studentService.getGradebook
and then I'll add that as a model attribute.
All right, so this is pretty good,
again, just some preliminary setup work.
We'll get into more way up testing in a bit
but I at least wanted to kind of get this code in place
and then we'll make some more progress in the next video.
So hold tight and I'll see you in the next video.