So let's go ahead and move in here
and we'll start off by opening up our project.
So let's move to our main directory here,
spring boot unit testing main.
And inside of this directory
let's open up the 2.20 starting project.
Okay, excellent.
This is great.
So we're in the 2.20 starting project.
Let's take a quick look
at our application architecture here.
So what we'll do is we'll have this main application,
we'll have a service and we'll have a DAO and so.
The service will have a dependency
on the DAO and we'll actually mark the DAO in our example.
So here's our DAO,
application DAO just a very simple class
that has three methods.
Add grade results, find grade point average
and at the bottom check null.
That's it.
And then for our application service
we'll open this one up.
So application service has a dependency
on application DAO so note the auto wired here
and then it also has three methods
and we simply delegate those calls off to the given DAO.
So there's methods here for add grade results,
find grade point average and check null.
Again simply delegating it to the DAO.
And then here's our main application.
And in our main application we have some new entries here
for this setup, can expand the window here.
So we have a new entry here for the application service
and a new entry for the application DAO.
So we're simply using the app bean annotation
to manually create those beans.
And we could have used other techniques
for creating the beans but this is kind of the code
that the previous employee created for us.
All right, let's go ahead
and take a look at our pom.xml.
And we can see in our pom.xml
we have the spring boot starter for test.
And since we have that starter for test,
we have built in support from mockito
and we can verify that looking
at our Maven panel and looking at our dependencies
and looking for the section under spring boot starter test.
And then we can see there is support there for mockito.
So again, spring boot starter test has built
in support for mockito.
And so if you're not using an IDE
you can also verify this at the command line
simply your project directory type Maven dependency tree.
And just looking through the results,
we can see that there's built in support from mockito.
Okay, so this all looks pretty good.