All right.
So there's some additional setup code
that I want to do here for this test.
And so we'll kind of walk through the steps here.
One thing I'd like to do
is make use of the before all annotation
to do some initialization work on the mock servlet request.
I'll create this method here called setup
and I need to create this mock servlet request.
And I want to initialize it or populated
with some initial data.
I'll set the parameter for the first name.
I'll also set the parameter for the last name.
And finally, I'll set the parameter for the email address.
Alrighty, let me swing this window open a bit
so you can see all of the code on one screen.
Alrighty, this looks pretty good.
I'll just run this test real quick,
just to make sure everything still runs.
Alrighty, green check marks.
That's fine.
I want to set up a couple of more items here.
I want to go ahead and auto wire in, the mock MVC
and we'll use that later
and also auto wire, the object mapper
and we'll use the object mapper later
when we go through and do some of our rest API test.
So again, we're just doing some setup work here.
I also want to set up a variable here for the media type
and we'll use this application JSON constant
when we verify the actual JSON response.
So I'll just set this up as a constant here
and I'll set it to media type .application_JSON.
So be sure to choose the one that I have selected here
on the screen.
And again, we'll use this later
when we actually start writing some of our test.
Alrighty.
So all of our coding's in place here
for this great book controller test,
as far as the initial coding,
I'll run this test one more time
just to make sure everything runs through successfully
and everything does.
And then the following videos,
we'll actually start getting down and dirty
and we'll actually start writing
the actual implementation test for this example.
So at the moment, I'll go ahead
and grab this place holder test.
We don't need it anymore.
And I'll go ahead and remove it
from the test because it doesn't do much.
We'll actually add some real code
for it in the next set of videos.
All righty.
So at the moment we have everything
kind of set up and we're ready to go
and we're ready to start doing some real work.
So this is great and I'll see you.
And the next video.