Alrighty so, we're making some really, really
good progress here, so let's go ahead
and do a similar process for science grades.
And as usual, we start with the test first.
So we'll simply enhance this existing test where we did it
for math grades and we'll do a similar thing here
for science grades.
So everything here is almost the same
except for the grade type is science.
We'll also get all the science grades,
using our science grades DAO.
And then finally, we'll verify the grades accordingly
for these science grades.
Again, just using the same approach that we use
for math grades.
At the moment, the science grade DAO is red.
So that means we need to create a DAO.
So we'll create this DAO in our repository.
And the name here is science grades DAO.
Alrighty so here's our interface for our science grades DAO,
extends credit repository,
and we give the entity type of science grade
and we give the primary key of integer.
You're getting used to all this now
this is a similar process to what we did earlier,
and we'll also add our custom finder method.
All righty here so this looks pretty good,
So now that we have our science grade DAO
that should resolve this issue almost,
we still need to inject it or auto wire into our test class.
All right, this looks good,
we have our science grade DAO in place.
And then if we scroll down, we see that
that resolves the syntax error that we had earlier.
Now we can go ahead and run our test.
And we see that the test fails and that's expected, right?
Cause we're doing this whole test driven development.
We have a little bit of work to do
in that student and grade service.
We basically need to update the code here to handle
for the type of science grades.
At the moment here I have simply return true
and then scrolling up top I need to auto wire,
the science grade.
And I also need to auto wire in the science grades DAO.
All righty so this looks pretty good so far.
Scrolling back down, and then I can go ahead
and add the appropriate code here for setting
that science grade, the ID, the grade, student ID
and then performing a save very similar
to what I did for math grade.
All righty so this coding here looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and swing back over
to our test and let's run it again.
And we have success, Oh yeah, this is great.
So now looking at the console, we see that we have an insert
into math grade and also an insert into science grade.
So greate, so we're actually inserting
that data into the database I like it.
And we also have the verifications in our test to verify
that those grades were actually added so good job.
I like it.