Alrighty. So we're almost done.
So our final step here is refactoring
the before each and after each to make use of
the variables instead of the hardcoded SQL.
So let's move down here to the before each.
So we have all of that
hardcoded data and we can remove that data.
So just delete all of that.
And now we'll simply make use
of the variables that we've created.
Here I'll make use of JDBC Execute,
SQL add student.
And I'll do a similar thing here for math student.
And actually let me change that.
It shouldn't be math student.
It should be math grade.
Quick little Refactoring here.
Okay, good.
That looks better.
Okay.
I like that.
And now let's just kind of repeat the process here for
science grade and also history grade.
So we remove the hardcoded SQL
and now we're making use of the variables.
I like it.
Now, let's go ahead and move down to the
after each and do a similar thing.
So I remove all of the hardcoded SQL
and I'll simply make use of the variables.
Here, we'll say execute SQL, delete student,
and SQL delete math grade and a similar thing here
for science grade and history grade.
All righty.
So this code looks really good.
Let's go ahead and run this test.
And we're running the test and,
oh, this is weird.
Test failed.
Huh?
Interesting.
Let's see here could not resolve placeholder
SQL script create student.
Oh, oh, okay.
So I might have a mismatch or a typo on the names.
Hmm. Okay.
Let's go double check this.
So this person says SQL script create student,
looking in the, ah, okay.
Typo and application and properties.
Notice here it says SQL scripts.
There's an extra S after the script.
Ah, let's remove that, right?
Now we save that and now we can
run our test and
yes, everything passes now.
All is well with the world.
Ah, woo.
That's scary there for a moment.
So, small typo that we have there and our tests fail
but we're able to resolve it.
And now all of the tests pass.
So I like this.
Very good.
And now there's one other thing I want to do here
is I want to make the same SQL modifications
to the grade book controller test.
We've covered it for the student grade service test.
Now let's do a similar thing
for the grade book controller test.
And what we'll do is we'll actually just copy a lot
of the code from our student
and grade service test and we'll paste it
over into great book controller test.
Starting in student and grade service test.
Let's go ahead and copy this code.
And now let's move over to our great book controller test
and let's paste in this code.
Excellent.
And then we also need to copy the coding
from before each and do a similar thing.
So over in student and grade service test, copy,
move back over to our grade book controller, test and paste.
And let's just repeat the exercise here
for the after each,
copy from student
and grade service test,
move over to great with controller test and paste.
Excellent.
Now we can kind of step back
and we can just run all
of our tests and see how things work out for us.
And as we can see
there's a lot of green check marks here, everything passed.
So in really good shape.
So, we've accomplished our goal here of
removing that hardcoded SQL from our test,
putting in a properties file and then
refactoring our code accordingly.
So I like to say,
good job, my friend.