All righty. So we have the failing test.
Now let's go ahead and write the code
to make this test pass.
Let's go from red to green.
I'll move into my grade book controller and I'll go ahead
and add some new coding here for this.
In particular, we need to add code here
for the post mapping.
We'll set up this method here for create grade.
We add code to handle
for the different parameters coming in,
grade, gradeType, and studentId.
And the first thing we'd like to do here is that
if the student doesn't exist,
then we simply want to return error.
All righty, that code looks good.
Next, we want to actually create the grade
using our student service.
And then we pass in the parameters.
Now we'd like to check if there's a failure
for creating the grade, then we want to return error.
Let's go ahead and retrieve the student information.
And give me a second here.
I'd like to reuse some code
to populate the student information in the model attributes.
I use the words reuse lightly
because at the moment, please forgive me,
I'm going to copy, paste the code for now.
It's kind of dirty, ugh, but we'll actually clean this up
in some of the upcoming videos.
So don't worry.
So kind of work with me for now.
In some future videos, we'll kind of refactor our code
and make it pretty and make it clean.
But we'll go ahead and just do the copy, paste for now.
I'll move up here to this one section of code,
where we did all the work for the model attributes.
Let's just go ahead and copy that code.
And then we'll move down here into our method
that we're working on and we'll simply paste it.
All right, so that adds all of the averages
for the grades to the model attribute.
All righty, let's swing over here and run our test.
This test passes.
Awesome.
So we were successful here in creating a valid grade
by sending over data to that given endpoint.
Now as promised, in the next video,
we'll go through and we'll clean this code up a bit,
and making it a bit more pretty.
But at least we have our tests working.
Good job.