Let's start with our development process.
So in this video, we'll cover step one
of adding the Maven Dependencies for JUnit.
And before we get started,
let's go ahead and download some starter code
for this given project.
So visit the link that I have here on the slide
and it'll download a zip file to your computer.
Let me swing over to my file system here
and move into my downloads directory.
And so here's the file that was downloaded,
spring-boot-unit-testing-main.zip.
Let's go ahead and unzip this file.
And now let's go ahead and copy this folder
to anywhere in your file system.
I'll just move it over here
and I'll just drop it into this luv2code directory
but you can put it anywhere you want on your file system.
And if we move into this directory,
we'll see that there's a number of projects out here,
and the one that we're going to use for this video series
is we'll start with the 1.0 starting project.
So that's the one that we're going to use for this example.
So let's go ahead and start up our IDE,
and then we'll open up that project or import it.
And I'll simply open a project that's located
in spring-boot-unit-testing-main,
the 1.0.0 starting project.
Move into that directory and select open.
It may prompt you if you want to add the files to Git,
and you can say don't ask again.
And there may be some other prompts,
just kind of work through them accordingly.
All righty, so the first thing we need to do here
is add the Maven Dependency for JUnit.
So I'll go ahead and open up my pom.xml file.
So I'll make use of the IDE
to help me with this given dependency.
So the IDE can actually find the appropriate dependency
that I need and actually insert it into my pom file.
So I'll go to this menu option here,
hold generate, then I'll choose dependency.
And then I'll type in the dependency that I need.
So I need the junit-jupiter dependency.
They'll give me a list of options here
and I'll choose the one that's called junit-jupiter
and choose whatever version that they have here.
And your version numbers may be slightly different,
just choose the appropriate version.
All righty.
So let's take a look at our pom.xml, and great.
So they added some new entries here,
so a new dependency section with the given dependency.
I'm going to go ahead and move it down below properties.
Just kind of the way I like to line up my file
to structure it.
You could do it either way
but I like to have dependencies here at the bottom.
And so there's the dependency here
for junit-jupiter with the appropriate version.
So this is great.
Now I'd also like to add the scope here.
So I like to set scope for test.
And remember with test scope,
the dependency is only for test purposes.
The dependency is not required for normal execution
of the application.
So I set the scope here for test.
All righty, so this looks pretty good so far.