Let's move back into
our StudentAndGradeServiceTest.
And what we'll do is we'll start
off by creating a New Package.
And this is a Package for the Service.
And then I'll create a New Class here for the Service.
So New Class and the name
of this class will be called StudentAndGradeService.
Zoom out for a second.
Up top, we'll make use
of the Service Annotation and Transactional,
because we'll allow Spring to manage the Transactions
for us in the background.
And now we need to define that method, createstudent.
It takes in three parameters for,
the first name, last name and email.
And then we'll go ahead
and create a new instance of the CollegeStudent.
I'll set the ID to zero since this is a New Student.
And then I'll call StudentDao.save
and I pass in the Student.
But now we have a small problem here
because we really haven't defined the Dao yet.
So, we need to go ahead and do that now.
And I'll put the Daos in a Package called, repository.
So I'll create a New Package
and the Package name is, repository.
And then inside of this repository Package,
I'll create a new Interface for the StudentDao.
So new, I choose, Java class.
Be sure to choose, Interface here.
Okay, make sure Interface is selected
because we're using Spring Data JPA.
The name of the Interface is called StudentDao.
Now in this, Dao I give the Annotation here for, repository.
And this given StudentDao is going to extend, CrudRepository.
Remember with the CrudRepository in Spring Data JPA
you get the Crud methods for free, automatically.
No need to explicitly declare them.
So, the Entity Type, comma Primary Key Type.
Now, if we switch back over to our StudentAndGradeService
we have our StudentDao, that's okay
but we haven't declared it as a Field yet.
So I need to go ahead and Autowire, the StudentDao.
Excellent, I have the StudentDao Autowired.
Now we can move down here
to the StudentDao.save and there's still a problem.
Hmm, what's up?
Inferred Type S.
Oh gosh, typo.
So that the Entity Type is not Collection.
The Entity Type is CollegeStudent.
Okay, so we get the Entity Type comma
the Primary Key CollegeStudent comma Integer.
Okay whoo, that was close.
Do some minor cleanup here on this file.
All right, so that takes care
of it there in the StudentAndGradeService.
So that's A-okay, we're good to go.
Now, moving back over to our Test.
Okay, so right now we're in our Test Class
and the method createStudentService
and we need to Autowire
in the StudentService inside of this Test.
Okay, so inside of our Test
we need to Autowire the StudentService.
Excellent, so this solves that one issue
that we have with the StudentService.
So this looks pretty good.
We still have some more work to do
but at least we're at a nice little checkpoint.