All righty, so again, rinse and repeat.
We have some of the work in place.
Let's work on this next one here.
So divisible by three and five.
Or just copy one of our previous tests.
And then we'll zoom in here and update the names.
So divisible by three and five.
And we'll also update the order.
It's our third test.
And now based on this logic, here are the rules.
This should print FizzBuzz.
So we expect FizzBuzz and we'll enter a number
that's divisible by three and five.
One example is 15 and we'll update the message
should return FizzBuzz.
Now, when we run this application
our first two tests pass, but our last one fails.
We expected FizzBuzz, but it returned Fizz.
Okay, that's our failing test.
Let's go back and modify our code to make the test pass.
In this scenario we need to check the comparison earlier
for three and five.
So just one possible solution here, but I'll say
if "i" is divisible by three
and "i" is divisible by five,
then we'll return FizzBuzz.
All right, so we're just kind of using the logic
that we have here to return FizzBuzz, Fizz, or Buzz.
And let's test this out again by running our test.
And excellent, great, so our first two test pass
and also this new one here divisible by three and five,
that one passed, it gave us FizzBuzz as expected.
All right, good stuff here, good stuff.
And now let's handle this last case here.
If the number is not divisible by three or five.
So we'll move down here, drop in our comment.
We'll copy that previous test again.
Alrighty, so in this case, not divisible by three or five
then we simply want to return the number.
So in this example here expected of "1".
I do FizzBuzz compute of "1".
It should simply return the number in this case "1".
We'll run our test, of course,
this is a failing test, right?
So we expected one in this scenario
and the actual value was no.
Okay, no problem.
So hopefully you're kind of getting a feel here
for this whole test driven development
writing a failing test, first,
then we go back in and we modify our code
to make the test pass.
I'll zoom in here for a second.
And this is basically the last case here.
So I'll just say else return the number.
So whatever the number came in as "i" I simply return that.
But since we're returning strings
I need to wrap this as a string
and I'll say integer dot two string, the value of "i"
and then also at the bottom, I remove the return, No.
And so this is the code here that should work
for this FizzBuzz scenario.
And there we go, everything's green,
all green, everything passed.
So not divisible at three or five
that test case worked out for us as desired.
So, a sense of accomplishment, excitement
and I'm happy over here, doing my little happy dance
because we did some test driven development with FizzBuzz.
So I'd like to say good job, my friend.