In this video,
we're going to test the Get Students Endpoint.
Now the Get Students Endpoint
will get a list of students as a JSON array.
We simply visit our app at localhost:1500/
The web browser will send over a GET request
and it'll return this JSON array.
So note here, the square brackets means that's an array.
And then we have an array of these JSON objects
here for a student.
ID first name, email address, student grades, and so on.
And here's the actual Gradebook Controller
that'll generate that output.
So we have this rest controller.
We have our dependencies
we have this request mapping for our value = "/"
and method = RequestMethod.GET
so a GET request.
We basically use the student service.
We get the grade book and in using a grade book
we get a list of the students.
And this will return to JSON array of those students.
Now, what we'd like to do is write a test here.
We want to verify the HTTP response, but we have a question.
How can we verify the response such as
how can I verify the status code, the content type
and also information about the JSON response body?
Well, for verifying the status and content type
we can make use of this little code snippet that I have.
And to verify this information inside of our test
we can make use of this andExpect(status)
And it's a static import from above
and here we can check the status of 200 (OK).
And then for the actual content type here we can say
andExpect(content)
and we can check the content type against application JSON.
And this allows us to verify the HTTP status
and content type.
Now what about verifying the response body?
So maybe we want to access a specific JSON element
or some nested elements
or we'd like to verify the size of the JSON array.
One solution we can use is JsonPath.
JsonPath allows you to access elements of JSON.
And this JsonPath is an actual open-source project
that's available at this GitHub link.
Now the really nice thing about JSON path
and Spring Boot is that there's a lot of synergy.
So Spring Boot test starter includes support for JsonPath.
Normally you would have to add the maven dependency
for JsonPath manually,
but in this case since we're using
the Spring Boot test starter,
it already has built in support for it.
So that's really, really nice.
And we can verify this in our IDE.
We can simply look at our project, look at our dependencies.
We see the Spring Boot Starter test dependency
and we can see that it has a transitive dependency here
for JsonPath.
So this is great, I like it.
Now let's go ahead and take a look
at some JSONPath examples.
And for the JsonPath
we can give the $.
This basically references the root element to query
and this actually the start of all path expressions.
And so here, this is the root element here
of this actual JSON object.
Next we can make use of the $.id
allows us to access the ID element
of the JSON.
And then likewise
if we want to access another element here
we can still use $.first name to access
the first name element of the JSON
and so on and so forth.
And so whatever name you have here,
dot email address dot student grades, and so forth.
If you'd like to see more examples,
go to the GitHub link to have the full docs
on all the various JsonPath options out there.
And we can also use JsonPath to verify the array size.
All right, so here's our test.
And then over on the right hand side
here's the JSON output, and this is actually a JSON array
so note the square brackets here, the notes on array.
And then we have these JSON objects here
and then down in our test, the line that's in bold
that's a new line here and expect JsonPath.
So going to make use of JsonPath here.
We reference the dollar sign, the root element.
And then we use hasSize.
to actually check the size of the array.
So we're going to verify the JSON array size is two.
In this example, we have two elements of the array
and this given test will pass accordingly.
So just some quick examples here on using JsonPath.
You'll see more examples of JsonPath
as we work through the videos,
but at least this is enough to kind of get us started
and help us out with the fundamentals.
Alrighty, so I'm getting pretty excited about this.
Let's go ahead and move to the next video
and let's go ahead and write a test.