Okay, so let's pick up where we left off.
So we should be,
in the Grade book Controller test at the moment.
And let's zoom in here for a second.
So let's go ahead and write some web related testing.
I'll make use of this MVC result.
And I'll use my mock MVC
and I'll perform a web request.
So I make use of those,
mock MVC request builder.
And I'll make a Get request,
to slash some colonist
slash
on that
Grade book Controller that I have.
And then I expect the status to be okay.
And then I return.
So effectively here,
I'm performing a web request
and I'm setting the expectations.
And remember in our controller,
we have the request mapping for slash
so that I'll call the Grade book controller.
And returns the view name of index.
Now, with this MVC result
I can actually get the results here.
I can actually get the model and view.
Sorry retrieve the model and view
from the MVC result,
get model and view.
And now that I have the model and view
then I can perform some asserts.
and I'll simply assert the view name
so I pass in the model and view.
And then I assert the view name of index.
And remember in our,
Grade book Controller it returns
the view name of index.
Get rid of some extra blank lines.
All right.
So this code looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and run the test.
And this test runs successfully.
So the test passed.
So we actually made a call.
The given controller,
we got the model and view.
We did an assert,
and the view name was index.
So we're actually making a call,
to that controller using Springs mocking support.
This is great.
I like it.