All right, so just moving along
with our development process.
In this video, we'll cover steps two, three, and four.
Creating the test package, creating the unit test,
and also running the unit test.
I go ahead and create my test package here.
And first off, I'll just take a look
at what our main package name is,
and that's com.luv2code.junitdemo.
So for my test package, I'll move underneath test, java,
and then I'll create a new package.
And the new package name,
I'll call it com.luv2code.junitdemo.
Again, we're following the convention
where our test packages are the same as our main packages.
Not a hard requirement,
but that's the normal convention that you'll see.
Now in step three, we'll create our unit test.
So on our test package that we have here
we'll create this new class, called DemoUtilsTest.
And if they prompt you about adding something to Git,
you can simply hit Cancel.
And with our test classes, they don't have to be public.
So you can simply remove the public.
You can leave it there if you'd like,
but in general, your test classes are not public.
So let's take a quick look at the DemoUtils class.
That's the code that we're going to test.
And let's move down to this add method.
And we currently have this add method,
takes two numbers that returns the sum of those numbers.
And this is very basic, very simple,
but what I'd like to do is to make this thing really works
is that I want to kind of break it on purpose, all right?
So I'll say, the sum is a plus b plus b.
Again, I'm breaking it on purpose,
because when I run my test I want to see a failing test
and then I'll come back and fix the actual code.
So I simply made this update here to break it on purpose.
Now let's swing over to our test, DemoUtilsTest,
and I'll create a new method here.
I'll call the method testEqualsAndNotEquals,
I'll annotate the @Test annotation.
And remember, the test method can have any name.
As long as we have the test annotation, then we're A-okay.
I'll go through and perform the setup here,
so I'll create an instance of the class that I want to test.
And then I'll perform an assertEquals.
I'll pass in the expected value of six.
And I'll call the method that we're testing,
demoUtils.add, two, comma, four.
And I'll also give a failure message
in the event that the test fails.
Just swing over here and fix the imports.
And there we go. So that's for the assertequals.
And I can do a similar thing here for notEquals.
So just a quick copy-paste here, assertNotEquals.
And then I'll say six, and then I'll add one, comma, nine.
So one plus nine must not be six.
All righty, so this code looks pretty good
and it's ready to go.
I'm ready to test it.
So here's step four, running our unit test.
And our test failed.
And we know why it failed, right?
Because we broke the code on purpose.
But it failed here, two plus four must be six.
Expected, six. The actual was 10.
And the reason is because of the code
that we broke earlier, right?
We added the a plus b plus b. That's why this failed.
Let's go ahead and fix it.
And it's just a plus b.
Excellent, excellent. This looks good.
So now when I swing back over, I can run the test again.
So I can rerun DemoUtils.
Test. And there we go, all green.
So everything worked out as desired. Great.
Now I'd also like to test another one of my methods here.
And I want to test this method here called checkNull.
So they pass in an object.
If it's notNull, we return the object.
If it is null we simply return null.
But just like we did earlier,
let's go ahead and break it on purpose.
So this method's going to return null all the time.
I'll simply just do a return null.
So regardless of whatever you pass in,
I'll simply return null.
And now let's go ahead and write some tests
for testing null and notNull.
And I'll just copy some code from up top.
And then I'll set up some variables here
for string one and string two.
And I'd like to do is set up some setups and assertions here
to check to see if string one's null, string two notNull.
So I'll have a certain null.
And I'll call the appropriate method.
So demoUtils.checkNull.
Pass in string one.
And my error message in case the test fails.
I'll do a quick fix here on the imports
and then I'll do a similar thing here for checking notNull.
So I'll pass in string two.
And then the object should not be null.
Let's go ahead and run this test.
And one of the tests passed, but one failed.
So this testNullAndNotNull, that test failed.
So here, the object should not be null.
We expected a notNull, but we didn't get it.
So we looked at the code.
Remember, we broke it on purpose, so let's fix it.
Let's remove the return null for everything.
And let's add our conditional logic back in place.
There are a number of different ways
you can write this method to make it simpler and easier,
but that's not the real point here.
We're simply just going through the mechanics
of unit testing.
But we've made that change here
and we can run the test again.
Okay, this looks really good.
So we have our test up and running. Good job.