Let's clean up the ugly copy paste code
from the previous video.
Okay. Remember I said we had some ugly code
and we'd actually clean it up and
now's the time to do that.
What we'll do is we'll refactor the code
for student information.
We'll move the configuration of model attributes
for student information to the service class.
Let's move into our student in grade service.
This is where we're going to place
the new refactored code.
What I'll do right now is I'll simply set
up a stub method right now.
I'll call it configure student information model.
I'll have an ID
and the actual model.
Right now, this code is empty.
We'll actually add code here in a second.
Now let's move over to our grade book controller
and let's grab this section of code
that we did the copy paste on earlier.
And let's go ahead and cut this code.
Now, moving back over to student in grade service,
then we'll actually paste in that code.
And up top here for a student service
dot student information,
we'll simply remove that.
We'll simply have it as student information
and we pass in the ID.
But this is effectively
the refactored code that we grabbed from our controller
and we put into this student in grade service.
Now let's move back
to our controller and let's call this method.
Here I'll say student service dot configure student
information model.
I pass in the ID and I pass in the model.
All righty, this looks really good.
So we simply refactor the code.
We grab that code.
We put into a method and the service, and then
we're simply calling that service method
from the controller.
Excellent.
Now let's scroll up a bit and there's another
section of code that we did the copy paste on
in the previous video.
Here, we want to actually remove it and then make use
of that method that we just created.
Here's the section of code we're in grade book
controller right now.
Let's go ahead and delete this code
and let's call that method in a service
that we just created.
Student service dot configure student information model.
We pass in the ID and the model.
Okay, this looks really good.
Now you see how we've cleaned up the coding.
Previously, we had those copy paste examples
that was pretty ugly.
We kind of refactored that code, put it into the service.
And now the controller is simply making that call.
This is much better, much cleaner.
And uh, I like it because what we had
before was pretty ugly.
Now as a sanity check
I want to go through it and run all of my tests and
make sure everything still runs.
I want to make sure that I didn't break anything.
Oh yeah.
All I see are green check marks.
That means that all of our tests have passed.
So, we didn't break anything.
We refactored our code, we cleaned it
up and now everything is still working.
That's awesome.
I'm really happy.