All right,
so we're making some good progress here.
So, in this video we'll cover step three
of setting up the expectations,
step four of calling a method under test
and then step five, verifying the method calls.
Let's go ahead and set up a test.
So, this will be for assertEqualsTestAddGrades.
And also just as a quick review,
just remember the structure of the test
when we're making use of mocking.
The first thing that we'll do
is we'll set up the expectations.
We'll execute the method, we'll perform an assert
and then we'll verify the results.
So that's the basic structure that we'll use here
for this method.
Let's go ahead and set expectations with mock responses.
So we have when, our application code,
applicationDao.addGradeResultsForSingleClass,
then return 100.
And then I'll go through and I'll set up my asserts here.
So I have assertEquals 100 comma application service
add grade results for a single class.
And then let me line things up
so we can kind of see all of this on one screen.
Too much stuff is scrolling off to the side.
Okay, so that looks better now just kind of recap here.
So, when method add great results
for single classes called then return 100.
And so what we're doing here is we're just setting
up the mock response, just like in theater
I'll say my line, then you can respond with your line.
So we're setting up information here for our discussions
or our rehearsal.
All right so let's go ahead and run this test.
And we can see that the test passed
the test was successful when in verify
passed AOK, no problems.
Let's go and break the test
so that can responses here.
So instead of returning 100, we'll change it to return 300.
And then when that runs it's going to fail.
Let's go ahead and swing it back to a 100
sticking to the script,
and then we can save that and run it.
And then this test will run successfully
and pass with no problem.
Great, so this is a really good example here.
We set up a mock for the DAO.
We use it in our service, and then we set the expectations
and we're getting test results.
So we're making use of that test double here
for our testing environment right now, which is really cool.
And so the next thing I'll do is I'll verify.
So I'll verify that a given method was called
during this whole testing process.
This coding hill will verify that the DAO method was called.
Now, let's go ahead and run this test
and this test passes okay with no problem.
There's another version of this verified method
that you can use.
You can verify, you can ask how many times
was this method called?
Was it called once?
Was it called five times?
Was it called 20 times?
So in this example, I'm going to say times three.
So basically I want to know was this method called
three times during this given test.
And what we know is that we really only called
this method once, okay.
But here I'm testing it for three.
I just want to run this to see if this will break.
And it does break it fails.
Looking at the results here says for this method
we wanted three times,
but it was only called one time.
Great, so we really only called it one time.
So, that's okay.
And we can simply change the times there to one
and then we run the test again
and we see that this given test passes okay.
So, this is really good.
And I'll line the code up here
just so it shows up all on one screen.
Okay, so this is a good example of writing a test
using mockito.
You made use of expectations.
We did some asserts and also some verifies.
So I say, good job, my friend.