Okay, so here's our gradebook controller,
and we're going to write a test here for this method,
get students.
So that's the request mapping,
value of slash, request method of get.
And it simply returns a list of college students.
I'll move into my gradebook controller test,
and I'll add in a new test.
I'll make use of my MockMvc and I'll perform a get request.
So get request to the slash.
And now I want to verify the status code that is successful
so, and expect status is okay.
And then I also want to verify the content type.
And I want to make sure the content type
is application/JSON.
Now let's go ahead and run this test real quick.
And that looks really good.
So the test passed and we're okay.
So, just kind of covering the basics.
Let's drill down a bit
and let's verify the JSON response body.
So add this new line of code here and expect,
I make use a JSON path, and I reference the root element
which is the dollar sign.
Then I give, hasSize of one.
So verify the JSON array size is one.
Let's go ahead and run this one.
And that's all green there.
So that looks good.
So that test passed.
So we're in good shape.
So currently we only have one student in the database.
Let's go ahead and add another student to the database.
And then we'll kind of check out the size.
The size should be different now.
And what I'll do here is in my test,
is I'll make use of the entity manager
and I'll add a student directly using that entity manager.
So first off let me just set some values here
for the student.
And now I'll use that entity manager,
our JPA entity manager,
and I'll actually save this to the database.
Now, when we run our test again,
it should fail because now we have two students
in the database.
And yep, sure enough it fails.
So notice here we have this assertion error
for JSON path, expected a collection with size of one,
but the collection size was two.
Because we have two students in the database.
No problem.
We can easily fix this right now,
but at least we know
that it's actually checking the size of the array
that's being returned.
So here I'll simply say size of two,
and then I run my test again,
and excellent.
All green, this test passed.
Why aren't you going to use more examples
in some of the following videos,
but at least we have kind of the basics in place here
for testing a REST API.
So this looks really good.
I'm happy.