Now we can go through
and we can uncomment that previous code that we had.
So uncomment the code for the college student = studentDao.
Now I need to simply auto wire in the studentDao.
And then notice here, findByEmailAddress,
that method is not defined.
That's a custom finder method
so we need to go ahead and this method
inside of our studentDao.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
So I'll simply create this public method,
findByEmailAddress, and then we pass in
the email address as a string.
Excellent, and so remember behind the scenes,
Spring Data JPA will automatically perform the query
on the database for us.
And then we have our asserts.
We can uncomment this code for asserts.
And we basically want to check to see if the email address,
the expected email address matches with
the actual student that we retrieved from the database.
All right, let's go ahead and run this test,
and we'll see that this test passed,
which is really good, I'm happy about that.
And this part is working so far.
Now, one thing you may wonder,
well, what about the database connection?
Because in our application properties,
the DB information is still commented out.
I never really said, "Here's the database URL
the user ID or the password."
That's all commented out
in our application at properties file.
Well, here's some fun stuff.
In Spring Boot, if an embedded database is
listed as a dependency in your POM file,
then Spring Boot will auto configure
the database connection.
Our project has H2 as a dependency,
So Spring Boot will auto configure a connection
to the embedded H2 database.
So remember this H2 database is an embedded database
that's in memory and Spring Boot can connect to it,
use it just like a normal database that you would have
doing selects, updates and so forth, inserts,
and getting the data back.
So we have a database that we're using.
It's simply an in-memory temporary database.
And like I mentioned earlier,
these embedded H2 databases are very useful for testing
because there's no network latency,
minimizes the setup and so on.
So that kind of explains
the magic behind this auto configure
with Spring Boot and embedded databases.