All righty, so we're moving right along.
There are some other cases that I want to check for.
So I want to check for the failure to create a grade.
This can happen if we have an invalid grade,
so outside the range of 0-100,
also if they pass in an invalid student ID
or if they pass an invalid subject.
For these cases we should return false,
a failure to actually create a grade.
Now let's go ahead and swing into our IDE
and let's write some tests for this.
This test will be create grade service returns false.
So this is the case where we couldn't create a grade
because it didn't pass some of our checks.
Here, I'll say assert false student service create
grade of 105.
All right, so that means it's outside of our range
so that it should return false,
outside of the range of zero to a hundred.
We'll also do another example here
assert false student service create grade of negative five.
Again, that's below zero.
Doesn't work for us, so that should return false.
And let's also do a student service create grade.
We give a regular grade of 80.5
but we give an invalid student ID of two
cuz we don't have a student ID of two,
we only have a student ID of one based on our sample data.
And then finally here I'll say
assert false student service create grade
80.5 student ID of one.
And here I'm going to give an invalid subject, literature.
We only have math, science and history,
we don't have literature,
so that should return false also.
All right, let's go ahead and run this test
and see what our results are.
And excellent, so this test passed just fine for us.
So we know that we have coding in place to handle
for these different edge cases.
So this looks really good.
I like it.