In this video,
we'll cover database integration testing.
When we are performing integration testing
with the database, each test should run from a known state.
Before each test, we want to perform initialization
like inserting sample data and then also after each test,
we want to perform a cleanup such as deleting the sample data.
Now in terms of our testing approach,
we want each test to run from a known state,
so we know what's in the database.
To help us accomplish this,
we can make use of the annotations
before each and after each.
Before each test, we want to insert sample data,
then we run the actual test method and then after each test,
we want to delete the sample data.
And we'll apply this for each one of the tests
by making use of those before each
and after each annotations.
And so again, this will basically make sure
that we know what's in the database
and we also clean up the database after each test.
Now here's a coding example for this.
We'll make use of our Student And Grade Service Test,
we'll add a new entry here for the JDBC template.
Now, the JDBC template is from the Spring framework
and allows us to execute JDBC operations.
As an example here for this before each,
we'll have this method set up database.
This is where we can insert data before the test is run.
Here I'll make use of JDBC execute
and then I do an insert, enter student and values one,
Eric Roby, and then Eric Roby's email address.
So we're adding this one student to the actual database.
And then we can do our work and then after each test,
then we have delete from students.
So we have work that'll run before each test,
we insert sample data, and then we have work
that'll run after each test where we delete the sample data.
Again, making sure that our database
is in a known state when we actually execute our test.
Now let's kind of fill in the blank here.
We have our Students And Grade Service Test,
we have the before each,
we have the after each already set up,
now we can put in a real test that will actually execute
and in this test will say is student no check,
and we'll make a call to the student service,
we pass in a value and we can assert true or false.
Based on the initialization work that we've set up,
this first statement here, assert true,
this will return true since id one exists in the database.
And the other item here will return false since id zero
does not exist in the database.
Again, you can see how we can initialize the database
with some data, run our tests
and then once everything's done,
we can clean up the database.
All right, this looks really good.
Let's go ahead and move into the next video
and let's write some code.