In this video we're going to have an MVC test
for creating a grade.
This will actually test for creating a grade
when the student does not exist.
Basically an invalid student ID.
Let's go ahead and move in here
to our grade book controller test.
And let's go ahead and add this new test.
We're going to attempt to create a valid grade
when the student does not exist.
The first thing that we'll do
is we'll perform the HTTP request,
we'll make use of a post to that end point, grades.
And then we'll pass in those three parameters
for grade, grade type, and student ID.
And then notice here,
for the student ID we'll pass in the value of zero.
The student actually doesn't exist.
That's an in invalid student ID.
And then we simply wrap it up with a normal coding here.
We'll get the model and view.
And then we'll simply assert the view name
and we'll make sure that we have the error name.
So this interaction should return the error page
because that student doesn't exist.
Let's go ahead and run our test, real quick.
And we'll see the at the test passed.
So this is great.
Now you may wonder, how did this code pass?
Well, if you remember in our grade book controller,
we already have a method, we had grade,
that already performs this check.
We have code that checks if the student does not exist.
If they don't exist, it returns error.
This is great.
We already have the code in place.
We simply wrote a test to handle for that edge case
and that test passed.
So we have some really good coverage here.
This looks really good.
I'm happy.