Let's cover some other scenarios here ,
we'll make use of assertTrue, assertFalse,
and also assertNotNull.
I'll add a new test here to compare grades.
We'll check to see if the grade of 90
is greater than the grade of 75.
We run that and we see that the test passes as desired.
Then we'll do a similar thing here
and we'll check for false.
AssertFalse, student grades that is greater. 89,92.
We execute this test and this one passes also.
And then we'll add one more test here
for checking null values.
If not coding here we say assertNotNull, student grades.
Check null.
And then we execute this test, and this test passes A-Okay.
Good job.
All right, so this looks good.
So just a quick example of using assertTrue, assertFalse
and assertNotNull.