Alright, so we're moving right along.
So, let's go ahead and fix our failing test
and we're going to implement the POST mapping
in our GradebookController.
And it'll make our failing tests go from red to green.
All right, let's dive in.
Let's move over here to our GradebookController.
And we're going to add a new POST mapping.
So let me zoom in here.
So I'll add this POST mapping
forward slash.
And then we'll set up our method here to create the student
and we'll read the data that's being passed across
and so we'll read this data as a model attribute.
And then we give a reference here to the model.
And what spring will do in the background is that
when those parameters come over
then it'll actually map those parameters
to a given college student.
So the college student will be populated
with those parameters coming across.
All right, so let's swing back over into our test
and let's run our test.
And then we'll see that the test is running
and that we have the assertion that we get the view index,
the view name.
But, that's not really a full test
because we really haven't done anything
with the database yet.
Let's go ahead and write some code
to kind of verify the student was added to the database
and we can use the DAO to actually query the database.
So I'll add a bit more here to this test
cuz right now it's very basic.
It's only checking the view name
not checking any real data.
I'll set up this CollegeStudent,
verifyStudent = studentDao.findbyEmailAddress.
And I give the email address of the student
And I need the student DAO
I don't have it in this test.
So let me move up a bit to the top
and let me simply auto wire in the student DAO.
So this effectively gives me access to the database
and I can querry the database for given students.
I'll just make this private.
Okay, great.
So our DAO is auto wired.
And so that takes care of that issue in the test.
Now, let's perform an assertion, assertNotNull.
So we'll check that verifystudent to make sure
that this person is not null.
If that data is in the database
then we should get a valid object or a not null object.
But it, in this case, if they couldn't find it
then we'll get a null object.
So we're simply asserting for not null.
Now let's run our test again.
And now this test failed.
Okay, interesting.
So we can scroll down a bit
to the bottom and see why the test failed
It said the student should be found,
expected not null but effectively
that object was null.
And the reason that it fails
is because our controller method doesn't really do anything.
I mean, look at the code, our controller method
all it does is simply return index.
It does nothing with the service,
does nothing with that student that's being passed in.
Alright, well, we can fix that.
So let's use our student service
and let's call this method create student.
And then we pass in the information for that student
three parameters, the first name, last name and email.
And we can retrieve all of that
from this college student para that's being passed in.
Alright so this looks pretty good.
First name, last name, email.
Alright, so now that's in place
now let's kind of swing back over
and let's run our test one more time.
And now yes, we have some success
so we can see that this test passed.
So now we've verified
that we can actually create the student
put them in the database and then verify that
hey, we actually have that student
in the database with our test.
So this is really good.
I like it.
Good job.
My friend.