In this video we'll discuss
the Spring Boot MockBean annotation.
So here's the code that we saw a little bit earlier,
as far as creating a mock
and injecting the mock dependencies.
And remember I said that this will only inject dependencies
annotated with Mock or Spy annotation.
So this is the part, we'll talk about this right now.
We'll discuss this limitation and how to resolve it.
Now instead of using a Mockito, Mock, and InjectMocks,
we can make use of the Spring Boot support,
the annotations MockBean and also the Autowired annotation.
So Spring Boot has the MockBean annotation,
so this annotation includes the Mockito Mock functionality.
So that's already built in, it has that support.
It also adds the MockBean to the spring application context,
so if an existing bean is already there, it'll replace it.
If there's nothing there, it'll add the new MockBean
to the Spring ApplicationContext.
And this is really important
because now this makes the bean available
for injection with Autowired, and it basically removes
that limitation that we discussed earlier.
So you may wonder, well
when should I use this annotation?
Use the Spring Boot MockBean annotation
when you need to inject mocks and you need to inject
regular beans from the application context,
and you want to avoid that given limitation
that we had earlier.
Here's the code that we had from before,
and now here's the new code using the Spring Boot support.
So one thing the imports so we no longer need
the Mockito mock or InjectMocks.
Instead we'll make use of the
Spring Boot Mockito MockBean annotation.
The next line here, Mockito InjectMocks.
We no longer need that.
We can simply use a regular spring Autowired.
Here, where we actually create the mock for the DAO,
so instead of using the mock annotation from Mockito,
we'll make use of the MockBean annotation from Spring Boot.
So that'll basically create the mock for the DAO.
So instead of making use of InjectMocks from Mockito,
we make use of our regular spring AutoWired,
so this'll basically inject this given application service
and it's given dependencies will be resolved.
They'll be AutoWired in automatically
and then we'll have that support.
The nice thing about this approach is that
there's no longer a limitation.
We can inject any dependency.
It could be a mock dependency or a regular bean,
it'll be injected with no problem.
So this is a really good approach here.
If you're making use of Mockito with Spring Boot testing.
All right, so let's go ahead and move into the next video
and we'll make this update to our application.