In this video,
we'll cover JUnit lifecycle methods.
When you're developing tests, you may need to perform
some common operations.
Such as before each test, you like to create objects
and also set up test data.
And also after each test, you may need to release resources
and clean up test data.
JUnit provides lifecycle method annotations.
We can make use of @BeforeEach.
So this method is executed before each test method.
Again, it's useful for common setup code
like creating objects and also setting up test data.
You can also use the annotation @AfterEach.
So this method is executed after each test method.
And this is useful for common cleanup code,
such as releasing resources and cleaning up test data.
Now let's kind of look at the big picture here
as far as the execution sequence.
So, the @BeforeEach annotation will be executed
before each test method.
And the @AfterEach is executed after each test method.
So if you have multiple test methods,
then the @BeforeEach will execute
before each one of those methods,
and @AfterEach after each one of those methods.
Let's look at a coding example,
and we'll look at the before code
that we had previously in the videos.
In the setup, we create a new instance
of the DemoUtils for each one of the methods.
But now the revised version here
is that we'll simply define DemoUtils as a field
in the test class.
And then with this annotated method @BeforeEach,
then we'll actually create the object before each test,
and then we can use it in a given test.
The key thing here is that this will be executed
before each one of the test methods.
And this is really good, because you want your object
to start from scratch with no previous state
or no previous data.
And then later on in our test methods here,
there's no need to create the object,
it's handled automatically by the @BeforeEach annotation.
And this applies for both of the methods here,
test equals and not equals, and also test null, not null.
No need to create the object,
because it's already been created.
And the key here is that this object
is created before each test.
And we can also take a look at the @AfterEach annotation.
So here, this is where you do any comment and cleanup code.
In this example, there's nothing to really clean up,
so I'll just put a print line here, just to say,
"Hey, we're running the @AfterEach method."
And so again, remember,
this runs after each one of the tests.
And then also in this example,
I'm going to add in some print line statements,
just for diagnostics, so we can see
each one of the test methods running,
and we'll see a print line,
and we can then look at the logs
and verify that hey, the execution sequence
is working as desired.
All righty, so remember, @BeforeEach, @AfterEach
executes for each one of the test methods.
So we can run the unit test,
and we can see the output here.
So it says, @BeforeEach executes before each method.
We run the test, test null or not null,
and then running @AfterEach.
And then a similar thing here for the other tests here,
test equals and not equals.
This is all based on the code that we created
with those annotations @BeforeEach and @AfterEach,
and also the print lines that we have in place.
And then also, one thing that you may notice here
as far as the order.
So we have one test that appears before the other.
Don't really worry about the order
of the test methods right now.
We have separate videos coming up later
where we'll get into all the details
on how to order tests explicitly.
So don't worry about it for now.
There's also some additional lifecycle methods you can use.
So you may need to perform some one-time operations,
such as one-time set up
that you like to run before all tests,
such as maybe getting a database connection,
connecting to remote servers.
And then also you may have some one-time clean up
after all tests.
So maybe releasing database connections,
disconnecting from servers, and so on.
So JUnit provides annotations for this.
You can use @BeforeAll.
So with this annotation, the method is executed
only once before all test methods.
And then the @AfterAll, the method is executed
only once after all test methods.
And here's a diagram here of the execution sequence.
So we have the @BeforeAll and then we have
all the test methods that'll execute.
And then we have @AfterAll.
So notice here @BeforeEach, @AfterEach.
Those execute for each method.
@BeforeAll is for all tests,
@AfterAll executes after all tests.
And we can pull this together with a coding example.
Here we have @BeforeAll, it's executed only once
before all test methods.
And then @AfterAll, executed only once
after all test methods.
And I have the little print lines in there
for diagnostics for us.
And then also by default, these methods must be static.
Now if we actually go through and run this,
we can verify the execution sequence.
And so notice here over on the right,
we have the @BeforeAll message
and then we have each one of the @BeforeEach, @AfterEach.
And then finally at the end we have the @AfterAll message
that's being displayed.
And again, this is all based on the information
that we had in our system out print line statements.
All righty, so this looks really good.
Let's go ahead and dive into the next video
and let's write some code using these annotations.