All right, so let's get started
with some of our test lifecycle methods.
And let's move into our demo utiles test
and I'll simply add
some print line statements for diagnostics
because we'll use this later when we actually run our test.
I'll add a print line here for our method test,
equals and not equals.
And I'll also do a similar thing here
for test null and not null.
Then I'll run the test real quick
just so I can see the output.
Great, so our diagnostics are working out just fine.
And now I'll add the Before Each.
In this method, I'll use it as common setup code
for creating objects.
The first thing I'll do is I'll define demo utils
as a field in this class
and then I'll delete the line
where I actually construct a new instance of it,
inside of the method.
I'll delete this.
And I'll move down and I'll do a similar delete
in the test null and not null method.
And now I'll add this method here, Before Each.
I'll construct the object here,
demo utils equals new demo utils.
I'll add this print line statement here as a diagnostic
and I'll annotate this method accordingly, Before Each.
So in this method here,
we create the object before each test.
I'll run this unit test
just to see what happens in the background
and I'll see that, okay, great,
this Before Each executed twice because we have two tests.
So before the test of null and not null
and also before the test of equals and not equals.
Okay, this looks good.
It's working as desired.
Now let's go ahead and add support
for the After Each annotation.
I make use of After Each,
this will basically run after each test
and there's not much to tear down in this example
because it's pretty simple.
Normally you would clean up some resources
or clean up test data.
But in this example,
I'm simply just going to do a system out print line
just as a diagnostic, just so that I know that it's running.
And now we run this test.
And we'll see Before Each running test
running After Each, good.
And a similar thing here,
Before Each running test After Each.
Great, so this matches up with the execution diagram
that we saw earlier.
Now what I'd like to do
is make use of Before All and After All
as one time set up and tear down.
So remember, Before All runs before all of the tests
and After All runs after all of the tests
and they run only once.
Let's go ahead and set up a method here for Before All.
This method here was executed only once
before all test methods,
that's the annotation Before All.
And then we'll do a similar thing for After All.
And this will be executed only once after all test methods.
And then also remember, by default,
the methods must be static.
Now, if I go ahead and run this test
and then we'll see Before All at the beginning
then we have each one of the Before Each running
and After Each.
Before Each running after each
and then finally at the end, After All.
And this matches with the execution sequence
that we saw earlier.
So this all looks really good, so, good job.