In this video, we'll write a test for deleting a student.
We'll create this test by sending
over a delete request to this endpoint.
So we'll say delete/student/ID
and ID refers to the student ID.
And then we'll make sure that
that student was actually deleted
from the backend.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and swing into our IDE.
So we'll get started here
on our grade book controller test
and we'll write a new test.
And this is the test for deleting a student.
And what I'll do here is
I'll make sure the student exists
before I actually delete them.
So I'll check to make sure
that the student ID of 1 is present.
And now I'll delete the student
by performing a delete request to /student/ID.
I'll pass in the ID of 1
and then I'll verify the results.
Here I'll expect the status is okay.
And now I'll verify the size of the array.
We initially had one student
but we just deleted the student.
The JSON Array should now be zero.
And also I'd like to just double check this
by checking the DAO
and seeing if that student ID of 1 is out there.
So we want to confirm
that student ID of 1 was deleted.
All right, let's go ahead and run our test
and the test passes.
So this is great.
So we know that we've deleted the actual student
from the backend database.
This is great.
I love it.