All right, so let's go ahead
and move into our code
and let's make the updates here for the Mock Bean
and the Autowired.
So this is currently the code for creating the mock
and also injecting the mock.
And using the information that we learned before,
we can make some small modifications here.
So instead of using a Mockito Mock,
we can make use of the Spring Boot Mock Bean.
So this provides the Mockito functionality of mocking
but also it adds the given Bean to the application context.
And so since it's in the application context,
then I can simply make use of Autowired
and that given Bean will be autowired or injected
into the given application context.
And this is kind of the preferred approach
of using Mockito with Spring Boot.
And that's the only modification we had to make there.
Everything else will run exactly the same.
So we can run our test
and we can see that the test results work out
just like they did before.
Alrighty, so the mocking works like before
and also the autowired.
So we're making use of the Mock Bean.
So we mock the bean and add it
to the spring application context
and then we can pick it up there with the autowired.
And that kind of handles
the shortcoming that we had earlier,
where the Inject Mocks only worked on @Mock and @Spies.
Now this whole idea of injection,
it can inject our normal dependencies
and also our mocked dependencies.
All right, so we've taken care of that work.
Let's go ahead and just add another test here
for this example.
So this is a test for finding a GPA.
So I'll set up my expectations here.
I'll say when application DAO find grade point average.
Then return with 88.31.
And I can do some asserts here.
So my expected value is 88.31,
application service, find GPA.
Student one, student grades, get math grade results.
Now I can go ahead and just run this test
and I can check the results
and we can see that this given test, find the GPA,
passed with no problems.
Good job.