All righty, we'll get started
by creating some parameterized tests.
And the one thing that we'll do is we'll create a CSV file
that'll actually hold our data for us.
I'll move into our test section
and I'll create a new directory.
The name of the directory is resources.
And then in this resources directory,
I'll create a new file.
I'll give the name, small-test-data.csv.
Now let's go ahead and add data into this CSV file.
So we'll basically make use of that sample data that we have
over on the far right,
and we'll just enter the data right here.
So we'll have the value and the expected value.
And I'll go a little bit further than seven,
I'll actually make it all the way up to 15.
And don't worry if you make a mistake in this file,
our test will actually catch it if we do make a mistake.
So don't worry. (chuckles)
Okay, so this file looks good.
Now let's go ahead and add a new test
that'll actually make use of this CSV file.
I'll update the display name
to say testing with small data file.
Update the order and also the method name.
And remember, since this is going to be a parameterized test,
we have to replace test with parameterized test
because we're going to pass in some parameters
to this given test.
And I'll also set up the actual names,
the actual display that we'll see
for each one of the invocations.
So I use value equals curly brace zero,
expected equals curly brace one.
So the zero index and the first index.
And then I'll also reference the actual CSV file
that I want to use.
And we'll reference that small-test-data.csv file
that we just created.
I'll just clean this method up.
I'll go ahead and define some method parameters.
So value expected.
I'll perform an assert equals, I'll say expected comma.
And then I use that FizzBuzz.compute,
and I pass in the value.
And remember behind the scenes,
JUnit will actually call this test
multiple times using data,
we're providing data from the CSV file source,
and then we'll get the results
and it'll be part of our actual unit test results.
And also JUnit handles all the looping work
for you in the background.
All right, so let's go ahead and run our test.
Looking at the results, and great.
So testing with small data file,
and then we see the actual entries
for each one of those invocations
and all this data passes just fine.
So this is pretty good.
And let's go ahead and just break it.
So remember earlier I said, hey
if you PA entered some bad data here,
our test would catch it because we know
that our FizzBuzz.compute method works, okay?
But here, let's add some bad data.
I'll say one is fizz and we know this should fail.
When we run it, it does fail.
And it tells us exactly why it fails.
So expected fizz and the actual was one,
but that's because we're passing in bad data.
Go through and fix it,
and then everything passes as desired.
So anyway, good way of having
some checks and balances in place.
And this is really cool.
So now we have a very basic CSV file.
We can also pass in some much larger files
and test those out
and we'll let you do that in the next video.
So, stay tuned.