Alrighty, so we're making
some good progress here.
Let's go through and add another test.
And this test will be for deleting a student
using the service.
What I like to do is first retrieve a given student
from the database.
Then I'd like to delete that student
and then perform a test to make sure that I actually
deleted that student.
First, I'll start off by grabbing a student
using StudentDao.findById of one.
And then just making sure that this given student is present
meaning that we found them during the first call.
So we know we have the student at this point,
we retrieved an actual student from the database.
Then I'll make use of the studentService.delete,
and I pass in the given ID.
And once I've delete student from the service,
then I'd like to attempt to retrieve the student again
and then check to see their results.
I'll make use of the studentDao.findById.
And then I'll assert false
and make sure that they're not present
or make sure it's empty.
So here I'll say deletedCollegeStudent.isPresent.
That should turn false.
Now we have some problems here, when we run it,
we'll actually get an error because we have a method
that's not defined in the service.
So this deleteStudent method is not defined in the service.
Let's go ahead and create that now.
I'll simply move into my service and write this new method,
deleteStudent, pass in an ID.
I perform a quick check
and then I'll say studentDao.deleteById,
and I pass in the ID.
All right, this looks pretty good.
Now we can swing back to our test
and now we can run our test
and hopefully our test will pass.
Excellent, our test passed as desired.
So we retrieved the student, we made sure we had them.
We deleted the student and then we also did another test
to make sure that the student really was deleted.
So, this works out as planned, I like it.
Good job.