What I'd like to do is go ahead
and run our application real quick.
So you can either run the application by opening up
a command-line and doing mvn spring-boot:run
or you can simply run the MvcTesting application directly
in the IDE, totally up to you.
But once the app is up and running,
then go to localhost:1500,
and then we'll see our output here.
Now, the one thing to notice here
with this web of interface
is at the moment, the UI is hard coded.
It doesn't really do anything.
So even if you entered student information
and hit submit, nothing happens, nada, nothing.
And all those students that you see there
they're simply hard coded students.
There's no real dynamic data.
So we need to go ahead and make some changes here
and make this user interface dynamic.
I'll go ahead and stop the application.
And I'll move into my resources templates
in the index at HTML.
This is where we have our webpages,
our Thymeleaf templates, actually.
And all we have code here,
I'll simply uncomment the code.
And so this is code that we gave you
for actually doing the dynamic portion of it.
And this other section here,
we'll actually delete this section
because that's the hard coded section.
All right, so we have this section here
and we simply need to update some of the labels here.
So instead of name, we say first name
we do a similar thing for last name
and then a similar thing here for email address.
And so this will actually submit the data or post the data
to our backend controller, the slash endpoint.
We also have code in here
for you to actually loop over the students.
And so you can simply uncomment that.
And then we have these three table rows there.
We can go ahead and delete those three table rows.
All right, so we kind of helped you out here
by giving you some code where you just simply uncomment it
and then make use of it.
All right, so this is what you should have here
for your students.
So we have the table, the TR, the TH,
those are the table headers,
grade book, first name, last name and email
and then the TRs with all the TDs.
And so the TRs, we have th call them each,
that's for Thymeleaf to loop over a given model attribute.
And so here, the model attribute is students.
And then we have the temp item called student.
We also got a reference for the iterator,
allows us to keep track of the number of the index
as we're moving through that given list or collection.
All right, so let's go ahead and run our application again.
Now you can run it from the command line
or you can run it directly from the IDE, your choice.
And once the app is up and running,
we need to go and just do a reload,
so we get the latest version.
All right, so this has an empty list.
There's nothing in the database.
We can add a new student for Eric Roby,
and then we can submit that data
and then success, our UI is dynamic.
So we're adding the student to the database
and also retrieving the students from the database.
All right, so let's add one more student here for Darby,
just to verify this thing is really dynamic
and that works too.
Great, so you can continue adding more students and so on.
They're being saved in the database.
We're retrieving that list of students
from the database and displaying them there in our UI.
So I'd like to say good job, my friend.