Now let's cover one more test case.
Let's delete a student id that doesn't exist.
In this test, it should return a status code of 400
or in the 4xx series
because that given student was not found.
Alrighty, in our GradebookControllerTest,
let's go ahead and write this new test.
It's the test for deleting a student.
And first, I just want to give a student id
that doesn't exist,
so student id of zero.
I'm going to assertFalse,
make sure that this student id is not present,
so we know that this is a invalid student id.
And now I'll go ahead and perform my delete request
for that student id of zero.
We're passing in that student id of zero.
That does not exist.
And here we're going to expect the status code
is a 4xxClientError.
So something in the 400 series of a ClientError.
Also, in this case, our REST API
will actually return a JSON error message
and so we can actually inspect this error message
and get some details on it.
So it'll have the status, the error message
and even a timestamp.
And I have this piece here of checking the status.
We're making use of this method is
but it comes up red right now.
What we need to do is move up to our import section
and add the following import.
We need to add import static org.hamcrest.Matches.is.
And so go ahead and pause the video for now.
Scroll to the top and add this and then come back.
Alrighty, so once that's taken care of,
then that should go away.
Now, we're actually going to access the contents
of that error message that's returned
by our REST API.
Here we see that we have these three fields,
status, message and timeStamp.
I want to check the status field,
so I use the $.status, all right?
And then I compare that to the value of 404
because hey, this person was not found.
And then also, we can do a similar thing here for message.
So let's just scroll down here
and write some additional code here for checking the message
of that response.
And again, this is the error message
that's coming back from our REST API
when we try and delete a student who doesn't exist.
So to access the message,
we use the $.message, is
and then we can give the string
that we're trying to match on.
So the $.message matches
with the actual JSON response there.
Again, making use of all this cooler stuff with jsonPath.
Okay, this looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and run this test.
This test passed. Awesome.
We covered the test case of trying
to delete a student ID that doesn't exist.
Good job.