In this video we'll learn how to delete a student.
All right. So we have some work to do.
And this is for deleting a student.
What we'll do is we'll apply test-driven development.
We'll start by creating a failing test
and then we'll add code to the grade book controller
to delete the student and make the test pass.
We'll also add code to the grade book controller
to check for the error page and also make that test pass.
Now, taking a look here
we see that we have our grade book application.
We have our backend controllers.
We'll click on the X icon to actually delete the student.
Now, the UI HTML code is already in place
and we'll focus on the backend functionality.
So we'll write a failing test first
and then we'll update our controller code
to make the test as pass.
Okay, so we're in a IDE and what I'd like to do is
write the code for deleting a student
and we'll make use of test-driven development.
We'll write a failing test first.
Let's go ahead and open up our grade book controller test.
And we'll add a new test here for deleting a student.
We'll set up the assert true
and we'll make sure the student exists first.
Here, I'll make use of studentDao.findById of one.
And I'll see if this given item is present.
Making sure this is true.
Now, again here, we're making sure the student exists first.
Now you may wonder, well, what about a student ID one?
How did it get there?
Well, remember from our before each,
that's the piece of code that runs before each test.
We do a little set at work and we actually insert
the student into the database.
And so we insert the student Eric Roby
that has the ID of one.
So that we know that by the time this test runs
in this portion of code, we have a student in our database
with the ID of one.
So right now, simply just using a sanity check here.
And now what I like to do is make a call
to that given endpoint to actually delete the student.
So I'll make use of this MVC result
equals mockMvc.perform.
I'll make use of this mock MVC request builders
and I'll perform a get request, to a given endpoint.
And the endpoint that we'll use is delete, slash student,
slash a given ID.
And then we'll pass in the idea as a parameter here,
the student ID one.
Effectively, right now,
this code will actually do a get request
to delete the student ID of one.
And I'll also set up my expectations here.
I'll make sure the status is okay.
And then I'll make use of the end return.
Excellent. So now we have this MVC result.
We can actually get the model and view from this MVC result.
Next we can actually go through and assert the view name.
And we'll assert that the view name is index.
And then one last we'll do is we'll assert
to make sure that the student was actually deleted.
Here I'll make use of assert false
and I'll attempt to get that student from the database.
studentDao.findById of one, is present
and this should come back as false.
That means that the actual student was deleted
from the database.
All right. So let's go ahead and run this test.
And the test failed but that is expected, right?
Because we're doing test-driven development.
We wrote a failing test first
and then we'll modify our code or refactor our code
to make the test pass, so no problem.
We just have our work cut out for us right now.
All right. Let's dive in.
So diving in here, I'll move up to my grade book controller
and I need to add a new mapping for deleting the student.
Here I'll make use of get mapping.
And this is for a delete student ID.
And ID's going to come in as a path variable.
I make use of the annotation for path variable
to map ID to a given method parameter
and also pass in the model.
And then I'll make use of studentService.deleteStudent
and I pass in the ID.
And just like we did last time,
I'll get a list of students from the service.
Basically the updated list
and I'll add it as a model attribute.
Here I'll say,
college students equal studentService.getGradebook
and then m.addattribute, students comma college students.
Again, just like the code that we wrote earlier.
Just getting an updated list of students.
And then I simply return the view name index.
Okay. This looks pretty good.
So let's go ahead and run this test.
Awesome. So this test passed.
So we have the functionality in place.
We initially had a failing test up front.
We added some code in our controller
and now our test passed, so good example of TDD.
I like it. Good job.