In this video we'll cover a test
for student information.
So we'll create a test to retrieve the student information.
We'll get the student's name, email address
and student grade.
And we'll basically send over a get request
that is slash student information slash ID
and we'll pass in the student ID.
Okay, let's go ahead and swing into our ID
and let's get started.
So I'll write this new test here for student information.
And the first thing what I'll do here is I'll actually
retrieve the student from the DAO.
So I'll retrieve student ID of one
and I'll make sure that that given student exists.
And then I'll use the mock NBC to perform a get request
to that slash student information endpoint
and I'll pass in the student ID of one.
So for the variable here are passing student idea of one.
And then I want to check that the status is okay
meaning that everything is successful.
And also check the content type.
And let's just do a quick run of this
just to kind of make sure this piece works.
So there's more work we're going to do
but let's just do a quick test.
All right, so we know that we're getting a success code.
That's coming back, that's fine.
But now let's go ahead and get some details here
on the actual JSON that's returned
or verify the JSN that's returned.
I can make use of JSON path to go ahead
and check for the actual student ID.
So I use the dollar sign dot id.
Is one, again we're just using JSON path
here to verify the contents of that JSON response.
Dollar sign dot first name
Eric
and then a similar thing here
for the other field's last name and email address.
All right, so this is great.
We can use JSON path to actually verify the contents
of that JSON response.
Okay, let's go ahead and run this test.
And excellent, everything is green here.
So this test passed, so we were able to verify
That we can get the student information
For a given student ID
And also verify the actual JSON response.
Good job.