In this video, I want to test for deleting a grade.
I'm going to cover two specific edge cases.
One is the case of deleting an invalid grade id,
and the other case is deleting an invalid subject.
In these cases, both should return zero,
because there is no student id
that can match with these given scenarios.
All right, let's swing into our IDE.
Let's start writing our code.
Let's open up our student in grade service test
and zoom in for a second,
and we'll define a new test method.
The test method is delete grade service
return student id of zero.
Let me scroll up a bit.
Okay, great.
Now do an assert equals zero,
so, the student id should be zero.
And then I'll make use of student service delete grade.
I give the grade id, and then the actual subject.
So, a grade id of zero, subject of science.
In this scenario, a student should not have
a grade id of zero for science.
Now, let's go ahead and write our
other test here for an invalid subject.
So, here is student service delete grade id of 1
grade type of literature.
In this case, it should return to student id of zero,
because no student should have a literature class,
because it's an invalid subject.
Okay, so the coding here looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and run this test,
and we can see that the test passed.
This is excellent.
So that we know that our code can handle
those edge cases of an invalid grade id,
and also an invalid subject.
So this looks really good.
I like it.