All right.
So we're kind of moving right along here.
And what we'll do is we'll write a new test
to retrieve all the students from the database.
And then, we'll compare the size of the number
of students retrieved.
Let me move in here and set up a new test.
And we'll call this test, getGradeBookService.
And what I'd like to do is get a list
or a collection of all the students from the database.
So I'll set up this Iterable CollegeStudent.
And I'll say studentServiceGetGradeBook.
So effectively,
I want to get all the students from the database.
And we see this get grade book it's red,
that means we have some work to do,
but for now, let's just kind of write this out,
and we'll come back to that.
And then, I'll set up this CollegeStudent list
as an empty ArrayList.
And then, the next thing I'll do is I'll simply
do a for loop over that Iterable CollegeStudents.
And I'll grab each student and place it into my list.
Here, I'll just say, collegeStudents.add,
collegeStudent, singular.
And then, I'll do an assert.
So I'll assert expect it,
meaning how how many students I expect to find,
1, and then, collegeStudents.size.
So here basically, based on the actual size
of that collection or that ArrayList.
So when I run this,
then it fails, right?
Because I still have some work to do.
I didn't write the code here
for that studentService.GetGradeBook method.
So let me swing that over into my service,
and let me write the code for that method.
And you can also use the IDE
to help you generate the method stub.
That's one feature that's available in the IDE.
But here, I'll just kind of write it out, plain vanilla.
Here, I'll say collegeStudents = studentDao.findAll.
That returns in Iterable of the college student.
And I simply return that to the calling program.
And now, when we swing back over to our test,
we see the code is no longer red
because we have that method available.
And now, let's run our test.
And we see that the test passes
because we only have one student in our database.
So the size of one matches up just right.
And that's based on the work that we did earlier,
and that before each to add student to the database.
All righty. So this looks really good.
I like it.