Okay, so let's go ahead and move in here
and let's go ahead and add a new test.
And I'll set up a new test
for throw runtime exception.
In the first line, I'll go ahead
and retrieve a college student
from the application context,
and I'll set up the expectation to throw an exception.
And this line of code means that we're going to an exception
when a given method is called.
When we make a call to check, no,
we'll actually throw a new runtime exception.
And then we'll perform an assertion.
And here's where we assert
that the exception was actually thrown
for that given method, call app service check no,
and remember the application service
has a dependency on the application DAO,
and the app service simply delegates the calls to the DAO.
All right, let's zoom out a bit
and let's go ahead and run this test,
and oops I have a syntax era, semicolon expected.
Let me go ahead and add that semicolon at the end of line 93.
Save that and now let's run it again and okay, great.
We pass the syntax error,
and the actual unit test passed also.
So good job.
Woo, scary.
Now let's go ahead and do one more thing here.
I'd like to verify
that a given method was called X number of times.
So I want to verify on the application DAO
that the check no method was called one time.
All right, go ahead and run this test,
and then we see that this test passes as desired.
Good job.
Let's go ahead and move forward and let's add one more test.
And this will be a test for making multiple calls
or making consecutive calls to a given method.
Let's go ahead and set up our expectation here.
When we make a call to application DAO check null,
then throw exception.
So this is for the first call for that given method,
then return a given string here, do not throw exception.
Now again, for the first call,
we're going to throw an exception,
for the consecutive calls,
do not throw an and just return a string.
This could be a string in the object,
whatever that given method can return.
Okay, that looks good.
That's our expectation.
Now let's go ahead and do our assertion.
Let's make our first method call
and we know that the first method call
should return an exception.
So we say assert throws
and we place this code inside of lambda,
application service check null.
That's the first call and now we'll do another assertion,
actually making another method call here.
We assert equals that string
and then we make that second method call,
application service check null,
and pass in the value.
For the second call, it should return just a string.
And we'll also verify method was called two times.
Okay, this looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and run the test and excellent.
So we see that this test passed as desired.
So this is a really good example.
So we showed one example of simply making a call,
a single call for a given exception,
and we also saw an example of making consecutive calls
where the first call will throw an exception
and the remaining calls will not throw exceptions.
So I like to say good job, my friend.