In this video we'll cover
assertions for same and true.
So testing for Same and NotSame.
The assertion method name is assertSame,
asserts that items refer to the same object.
And then the NotSame assert that items
do not refer to the same object.
And in particularly here, they're referring
to the object reference.
Here's the code that we want to test.
In our demo details class
we have two fields here, academy and academyDuplicate,
and on a check to see if these refer
to the same object, in terms of object references.
And then we have the supporting getter methods
for retrieving these given items.
So then I can define a test here
for test Same and NotSame and the top right
we have the actual code that we're testing,
just as a reference.
And here as I assertSame
demoUtils getAcademy that's object one,
and then demoUtils getAcademyDuplicate that's object two.
And then the object should refer to the same object.
And then we have a assertNotSame.
And then for object one, we make use string,
that's something that we defined up above
equals luv2code.
And then object two is demoUtils getAcademy.
In this case, the objects should not refer
to the same object in terms of object references.
Now we run the actual test and we'll see our test results.
So Same and NotSame this test pass.
So this works out as desired.
We can also take a look at some other assertions here
for testing for true and false.
The assertion method names assertTrue asserts
that the condition is true.
Likewise assertFalse asserts that the condition is false.
And here's the code that we want to test.
In our class demoUtils we have a method is greater.
Basically we've take two numbers and return true
if n1 is greater than n2.
Now this is really just for academic purposes,
you notice the code here is pretty simple.
We can actually refactor this
to make the code a bit simpler.
And here instead of using the if statements,
we simply return n1 greater than n2,
but again you could write the code either way.
Let's go ahead and write a test for this,
in the top right we have the actual code
that we're testing just as a reference.
So I have a testTrueFalse, have grades one and two,
10, five, then I use assertTrue pass and demoUtils greater,
and then I'm passing grade one or two
it'll return a boolean
and this should return true
because 10 is greater than five.
And then we have assertFalse demoUtils.isGreater
gradeTwo comma gradeOne.
And so here, we're checking to see
if five is greater than 10, and that's going to return false.
Now we'll run the actual test
and we'll see our test results,
this test pass.
So this works out as desired.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and move
into the next video and let's write some code.