In this video we'll cover another MVC test
for deleting a grade.
We'll create a test for deleting a grade
when the grade id is invalid.
Okay, let's swing into our IDE and let's move in here
and let's go ahead and write this new test.
The first thing I'll do is I'll attempt to retrieve a grade
and what I'll do here is I'll make use of a grade id
that does not exist.
So in this scenario here,
the grade id of two does not exist.
And then I'll actually confirm the grade id doesn't exist
by doing an assertFalse.
Now I'll attempt to delete the grade via the HTTP request.
I do a get on grades, passing the id and the grade type.
And note here, I'm passing the id of two.
So this id does not exist.
So it's an invalid grade id.
I'll retrieve the model in view
and then I'll perform an assert on the view name.
And so I'm asserting here that the view name is error.
So it should be error.
Let me move to the top
and just fix a quick typo there, remove those two parens.
And now this coding here looks pretty good.
I'm happy with it.
So let's go ahead and run our test and check the results.
Excellent, this test passed.
This was really good.
So we covered the case for deleting a grade when
the grade id invalid or the grade id doesn't exist.
Good job.