In this video, we'll cover tests for create grades.
So we'll develop a test for creating grades.
And what we'll do here is we'll actually send
over a post to /grades
and we'll pass over three parameters.
We'll pass over the grade,
the grade type and the student ID.
All righty, looks pretty exciting.
Let's dive in.
All righty, swinging into grade book controller test.
Let's go ahead and write this new test.
What we'll do here is use our mock MVC,
we'll perform a post /grades
and we'll pass over these three parameters,
grade, grade type and student ID.
And then once that's processed in,
then we simply expect that this will successful.
So the status is okay.
Then we also check the content type
and then we can verify the actual JSON response here
by making use of our JSON path.
So a similar technique that we used
in some of the previous videos.
So $.id and a similar thing here
for first name, last name and email address.
And then also we can access the student grades
for math grade results.
Now we initially had one math grade.
The test just added a second math grade.
That means that we should now have two math grades.
All righty, let's go ahead and run this test.
And excellent.
All green here.
So this test passed.
So we were able to successfully create a new grade
and verify it using our test here.
Good job!