Let's go ahead and create another test case
for the scenario of trying to create a grade
for a student ID that doesn't exist.
And then we'll check for the status code in the 400 series.
Basically not found.
All righty, let me zoom in here
and I start writing our new test.
And this is the test
for creating a valid grade, but the student does not exist.
And what I'll do is I'll perform a post of that endpoint
for creating a grade.
I'll pass in those three parameters,
for grade, gradeType and studentId.
And now note here for student ID I'll pass
in the idea of zero, that student ID does not exist.
So we should get some type of error in this case.
So I'll expect a client error coming back in the 400 series.
And also that rest API will return a JSON response
with details on the error message.
And we can check the actual status and the message.
And we've seen similar coding like this before.
Okay, this looks good.
Let's go ahead and run this test.
And we see that this test passed a okay, so this is great.
So we've covered the case here
of trying to create a grade for a student ID
that doesn't exist.
Good job my friend.