Okay, so let's take that failing test,
and let's make this test pass.
Let's go from red to green.
I'll move into the student and grade service.
And that one method here, studentInformation,
where we simply return null,
I'll remove that, and let's sit down here,
and let's write some real code for this functionality.
(silence)
The first thing I need to do,
is retrieve the student from the database,
using the studentDao.findById.
(Silence)
And then I'll get a reference to the math grades,
for this given student ID.
So here I have mathGradeDao.findGradeByStudentId,
and then I'll do a similar thing here for science grades,
and also for history grades.
(silence)
And the next thing I'll do here is,
I'll actually take this Iterable,
and I'll actually convert it to a list.
(silence)
So this is the code here,
for converting the Iterable to a list.
I created an empty list first,
and then I make just a Iterable, mathGrades.forEach,
so this will kind of loop over the math grades.
And then I'll say mathGradesList::add.
What this does is behind the scenes,
it'll call the add method on the math grades list,
for that given item.
So I'm basically looping through,
the Iterable and then adding each one of those items,
to this math grade list.
And I'll simply repeat this process here for science grades,
and also history grades.
Again, simply converting the Iterable to a list.
(silence)
Okay, so that coding is in place.
Let's go ahead and make use of student grades.
And at the moment I don't have student grades,
let's go ahead and autowire in the student grades.
So I'll kind of scroll up top.
(silence)
Make use of this autowired for student grades.
And then I can set the values accordingly here,
for math grades, history grades, and science grades.
(silence)
And then the next thing I can do,
is create an instance of this GradebookCollegeStudent,
and then populate it with the appropriate data.
(silence)
Here I'll pass in the student ID, the first name,
the last name,
and the email address.
I'll also give a reference here to the student grades,
which is a collection of the math, science,
and history grade results.
And then I simply return that gradebookCollegeStudent,
and that's the basic coding here,
for getting the student information.
We simply access the information from the database,
and we package it up into the appropriate format,
or a gradebookCollegeStudent,
and then we return that given instance or that object.
Now let's swing back over to our test,
and let's run it and see how this works out for us.
And this is great.
The test passes.
So we're able to retrieve student information,
from the database, and then verifying it with our tests.
So we verified information for the student ID,
first name, last name, email,
and also the math, science and history grades.
This looks really good.
I like it.
I'm happy!