Alrighty.
So in preparation of connecting to the MySQL database,
let's go ahead and set up a separate properties file.
And this will mainly just be a copy paste exercise
on our existing properties file.
Let's go ahead
and do a quick copy paste here on application.properties
and we'll have a properties file specifically for testing.
So I'll call this one, application-test.properties.
Okay. So here's my application test properties, it has all
of our test work that we did previously.
And I want to update my test to use this application
test properties.
Let's go ahead and move over to our source test
and open up our Grade Book Controller test
and we'll modify it to use application-test.properties.
I'll move down here to my test property source
and I give the name application test property.
So it's pointing to the name
of that file that we just created.
And of course, I need to do a similar thing
in our Student And Grade Service test.
Again, moving down to my test property source,
I make use of application test properties.
Excellent. This looks pretty good.
Now let's go ahead
and run our test to make sure we didn't break anything
and make sure it's using our properties file.
Alrighty. The test passed, all green check marks.
That's excellent.
And let's go ahead and run our full test suite
and let's make sure all of our tests still pass.
And this looks really good.
I see a lot of green check marks here.
So this is great.
So all the tests passed.
This is awesome.
I like it.
So that was just a quick little update here just to move all
of our test props into a separate file
and then we can use application.properties
for our real database connection, communication work
and we'll cover that part in the next video.