We've made good progress so far
with student information.
I want to add one more test.
And this is for testing for a student ID
that doesn't exist.
Alrighty. So we're in our IDE.
And I'll add a new test for this scenario.
This is for the test
of StudentInformationServiceReturnNull
for a student that doesn't exist.
I use my student service
and attempt to get information
for a student that doesn't exist.
I'll pass in a student ID of zero
so this ID doesn't exist,
so this method should return null.
Here I'll make the assertion of assertNull
on gradebookCollegueStudent.
Now let's go ahead and run this test.
And we see that the test fails.
So it has the error
of NoSuchElementException: No value present.
So there's some additional code that we need to do
to make sure that it returns null
for this given scenario.
Let's go ahead and move into our student and grade service.
And right at the beginning here,
I want to perform a check.
So I want to check if the student doesn't exist,
then return null.
I pass in that student ID.
And here I have return null.
Alrighty, this code looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and run our test again.
And the test passed a success.
This is really, really good.
Now we've covered that case
of trying to retrieve student information
for a student that doesn't exist.
In this case our code returns null, as desired.
Good job.