All right, so let's cover another scenario.
Let's try and to delete a grade
for a grade ID that doesn't exist.
And we'll check for the HP status codes in the 400 series.
Basically, not found.
I'll zoom in here and I'll start writing this test.
And what I'll do is I'll use the mock MVC to perform
a delete request to grades ID slash grade type.
And I'll pass in values here of two comma history.
Two refers to the grade ID and that's the grade ID
that does not exist, so this should give us an error.
So we'll just check the status here to make sure
it's a 400 series client error.
And then we get this JSON response
from the rest API and we can go through and check
the status and the message.
Okay So this coding here looks good,
lets go ahead and run our test.
So we see all green here, that means
the test passed and we're in good shape.
So good job.