Okay, so let's go ahead and get started.
In this video, we're going to configure
the JDBC connection properties
for the MySQL database.
This video assumes that you have already installed
the MySQL database server and also the MySQL Workbench.
If you haven't installed those items,
please install those items now
and then come back and continue with the video.
All righty, let's go ahead and dive in.
The first thing we want to do
is edit our application.properties file.
Let's remove all of this test information.
We don't need that.
This is for our main application.
So remove all the test stuff,
and we're going to add in the actual
JDBC connection properties here for our database.
We'll set up the driver class name
to make use of the MySQL database driver.
We'll also set up the datasource URL.
I'll set up the datasource username
and the datasource password.
Now this area will vary depending on the configurations
you set up with your database.
You may have a different root password.
So be sure to set that accordingly.
Or you may have a different user account
you want to use other than root.
So again, username and password,
you'll need to set that up accordingly
based on your own configurations.
I set the initialization mode to always.
And I set the ddl-auto to update.
Okay, this configuration looks really good.
I like it.