One thing that we need to do
is we need to create the database schema here
for this example, mysqltutorial,
and we do that using an SQL script.
So let's go ahead and move over to MySQL Workbench
and let's kind of get started with that part of it.
Alrighty, so I'm in MySQL Workbench,
let's go ahead and connect,
be sure to use the root password for your environment.
And now, once you're logged in,
you'll see over on the left-hand side, the SCHEMAS.
We need a new schema here for mysqltutorial.
I can create this schema by using an SQL script,
and we provide this in our course directory.
Simply move into your Spring Boot Unit Testing directory.
And there's a file here called Create mySQL database script.
And it's just a very basic SQL file.
It's simply a dump of a database.
It creates the tables and it also inserts some sample data.
Now in your toolbar,
go ahead and click the yellow lightning bolt here
to actually execute this SQL script.
Great, so that's complete.
Now move over to the left-hand side
and just do a refresh in your SCHEMAS,
and you should see a new schema, mySQLtutorial,
and it has four tables for history_grade,
math_grade, science_grade and student.
The SQL script actually populated some sample data
into these tables
and we can go through and view this data now.
So I'll take a look at my students.
We have five students at the moment.
There we have some science grades, math grades,
and also some history grades.
Now let's go ahead and run our application.
Our app is up and running, and we see at the homepage
we have those five students already prepopulated,
which is really good.
We can move in here and add a new science grade
for a student, David Adams,
Submit, and then we can swing back over
to the MySQL Workbench, and we can view the science grades.
I'll click on the tab for science grades
and I'll run this SQL query again,
to kind of refresh the results.
And we see we have a new entry here for 100.00.
I can also delete the grade of 80 for that student,
swing back over here and do the query,
and the grade of 80 has been removed.
The nice thing here is that we're actually confirming
that we are saving data in MySQL and so forth.
So we know that our app is really connected
to the MySQL database at this time.
And we can play around with some other features
of the application and so forth,
but we have a connection to MySQL database
and we're storing and retrieving data from the database.
So I'd like to say, good job, my friend.