All right, so let's write some code here
to run our test in order.
So, first off, I'll just go ahead and run the example as is
and look at the output of the actual test results.
And to start, I'll make use of our Test Method Order.
I'll define this at the class level,
and the Method Order that I'll use here.
I'll say order by MethodName.class.
And then I'll go ahead and run this test.
So it's sorting by MethodName
but we're only seeing the DisplayName.
So ideally we really don't want the scenario.
Like I mentioned in the previous video,
when we sort by MethodName,
we don't want to use a DisplayName,
so we kind of need to make a modification here.
And we can simply modify this
by saying instead of MethodName,
let's go ahead and sort by DisplayName.class.
All right that looks good.
Now let's go ahead and run this test again.
All right so now everything works out just fine
and sorting by DisplayName.
So we're kind of A okay, over here.
Now I'll switch gears here
and I'll make use of a different MethodOrderer
and I'll use the OrderAnnotation.class.
In this scenario,
we need to actually use the OrderAnnotation
on a specific method that we like to order.
So here, I'll start at the top
with the test equals and not equals.
I'll use the OrderAnnotation
and then I'll give the value of one.
I'll do a similar thing here
for test null and not null,
give the value of zero.
And remember, the lowest number has the highest priority.
Let's go ahead and run this test.
Based on these results here we have null and not null,
and then equal and not equals.
Let me resize the screen for a second
so we can see everything.
So null and not null has the order of zero.
And then, test equals and not equals has the order of one.
The lowest value has the highest priority.
So that's why we see test null and not null first.
Now let's go ahead
and add some additional OrderAnnotations.
So on the test, true and false, we give the value of 30.
And then for test lines match, we give the value of 50.
And then we'll run this and we'll see the results.
So we have null and not null, equals and not equals,
true and false, lines match.
So true and false has the value of 30,
lines match has the value of 50.
Remember, lowest number has the highest priority.
That's how we have these given results.
All righty, this looks really good.
So we saw different ways of ordering our unit tests.
I like to say good job, my friend.