All right, so in step 4,
we're going to generate the code coverage reports.
And what we'll do is we'll make use
of this free code coverage library called JaCoCo.
So, JaCoCo provides a Maven plugin
to generate code coverage reports.
And it'll give you a report similar
to what we show here on the screen.
So it'll give the actual Element,
Missed Instructions, Missed Branches, Coverage,
Percentages and so on.
You can get more information about JaCoCo
at this website here, jacoco.org.
And then you're probably wondering
what's up with the name JaCoCo.
I mean, how did they come up with that?
Well, it stands for Java Code Coverage, JaCoCo.
All right.
Anyway, that's the name there.
So now, how do we make use of JaCoCo?
Well, in our pom.xml file,
we'll make use of this plugin,
jacoco maven plugin
and then we have this execution section.
So the first item here is that we prepare the JaCoCo agent.
This goal is bound by default to Mavens initialize phase.
This does some initialization work
in the background for JaCoCo.
And for the next execution entry,
during Maven's test phase,
we want to execute the plugin goal,
jacoco-maven-plugin:report.
All right so, during the testing phase,
let's execute the goal, report.
Now we can test this out
as for as generating our code coverage reports.
So at our command line, we say mvn clean test.
And so remember JaCoCo report generation
is attached to the test phase
so the reports are automatically generated
when the unit tests are executed.
And we can kind of follow along with the output here.
So the mvn clean plugin,
then we prepare the JaCoCo agent,
we run our test and we run the report
using the JaCoCo Maven plugin.
And finally we have build success.
So then we can actually view these code coverage reports.
They're in this directory here,
target site jacoco index html.
We can open it up and we see our report here.
As for as the code coverage, we can go ahead and drill down
into some of the links and we can get a list
of all the methods in the given class,
which ones are covered and which one isn't.
This is all really good stuff.
So I showed you how you can make use of unit test reports
from the command line with Maven
and also code coverage from the command line using Maven.
And if you'd like to get more information
about the Maven plugins here,
you can visit the link that I have here on the slide.
And if you'd like to get more information about JaCoCo,
you can use the link that I have here on the slide also.
Alrighty. Really good stuff.
I'm excited.