All righty, so let's go ahead
and get started.
So here we'll cover
Code Coverage and Test Reports with Maven.
And before we get started I want to go ahead
and just do some housekeeping.
I want to delete some of the previous folders
that were out there.
So when we ran these reports inside of IntelliJ,
we had some folders.
I want to go ahead and delete those now.
So let's go ahead and delete the coverage-report folder.
And also delete the unit-test-results folder
because those are the folders that were created
when we ran all those reports from within IntelliJ.
Okay great, because we don't need those
because we're running everything
from the Maven command line.
All right, so let's go ahead
and use things from command line.
Now, if you're using IntelliJ,
you can actually make use of the terminal
that's built into IntelliJ.
So you can make use of this option if you'd like.
So here, I'll simply just make use of the command line
that's available with my operating system.
So if you're using Mac or Linux,
you can simply open up a terminal window.
If you're using Microsoft Windows,
you can simply open up a command prompt window.
So, the main idea here is make it to the command line
and then we'll run our Maven commands here.
And just as a checkpoint, I'll make sure
that I have Maven installed here.
So just do a Maven dash version.
It'll give you the Maven version number.
You don't need the exact same version
that I have here as long as you're using Maven 3.6
or higher, then you're okay.
So now we want to do is simply move to the directory
where we have our source code project.
So we'll move over to the spring-boot-unit-testing-main
slash 1.0-starting-project.
All right, So I'm in the spring-boot-unit-testing-main
directory.
And then I move into the 1.0-starting-project directory.
And there we go, so we should
simply see a pom.xml source and target directory.
So again, as a checkpoint,
make sure you're in the correct directory here
for this part of the video.
All right, so now what I want to do is simply
just run the Maven test.
So I'll just do a Maven clean test.
It'll go through the process
and notice here at the end it says for test run zero.
So no tests were found.
So remember, by default
Maven will not find JUnit 5 test classes.
We need to do some additional configuration
to make this happen.
So let's swing back over into our IDE
and let's simply open up our pom.xml file.
We'll add support for the Maven Surefire Plugin.
And so right after my dependency section
I'll add a new build section.
So we're adding some custom functionality
to the Maven build process.
And I'll set up plugins
and I'll define the Maven Surefire Plugin.
So for the group ID, we'll have org apache maven plugins.
I'll go ahead and fix the artifact ID.
It should say maven surefire plugin.
And then I'll give the appropriate version
to use for the Surefire Plugin.
Okay great, so let's move back over
to our terminal window and let's run our test again.
See if it can find the test now.
And then we're taking a look
at the test results and success.
Great. So it found the test.
It ran those 10 test and everything worked out fine.
So this is really good.
So we've made the configuration on Maven,
we've added support for the Maven Surefire Plugin.
So now, we can access or run those JUnit 5 tests.
Good job.