Okay. In this video, we're going to add the
Maven Surefire Report Plugin to
generate HTML unit test reports.
So let's move in here in our pom.xml.
Let's go ahead
and copy this existing plugin section and paste it.
We'll make some small modifications to it.
So we have everything here looks about, right.
Instead of the Maven Surefire Plugin.
We're going to say the Maven Surefire Report Plugin.
And that's really the only modification that
we need to make there.
So you can keep the same version and everything,
just Maven SureFire Report Plugin.
And we also need to do some configuration here
for the actual execution of this plugin.
So during Maven's test phase,
we want to execute the plugin goal
maven-surefire-report-plugin:report.
So I'll set this up here in this part of the file.
So an execution I give the phase of test,
and then I tell it which goal to execute
during this given phase.
So again, this configuration says during Maven's test phase,
execute the plugin goal
maven-surefire-report-plugin:report.
And that's how we configure this accordingly.
And we're simply just adding some custom build functionality
during the Maven process.
Okay. So let's go ahead and test this out.
Let's swing back over to our terminal window here.
And then I'll do a Maven clean test.
So this will run the test and executes the
Surefire Report Plugin that'll generate the HTML reports.
And this is based on the configuration
that we just set up on that pom.xml file.
So to go ahead and do its work
and we have a build success at the end.
Okay. That's great.
I like it.
And then we need to do one other command here
to give us access to some of the CSS resources.
So here I'll say Maven site
dash degenerate reports equals false.
The Maven site,
that'll add the web site resources for images, CSS
and so on.
And then the dash degenerate reports equals
false basically says,
"Hey, don't overwrite the existing HTML reports",
because we did that in the previous step already.
And this is really just a workaround that we need to do
in order to get access to those images and CSS.
Okay. So that's complete.
So that's awesome.
We're in good shape here.
Now let's swing back over to our file system
and take a look at these new files.
So let's move into our project directory,
spring-boot-unit-testing-main.
I'll open up this directory here,
1.00-starting-project.
And then I want to move into this directory here,
target/site/surefire-report dot HTML
It's under target/site
surefire-report dot HTML
That's step files.
Let's go ahead and open this up on our web browser.
Okay. This looks great.
So this is an HTML report of our unit test results.
So it'll tell you how many tests passed,
if any failed, the actual package list
and some actual details on the test cases
as far as each test case that ran
and the result of that.
This looks really good.
I'm happy with this so far.
And again, the nice thing about it,
the reason we're doing all this is
that now we can view these reports outside of the IDE.
There's no need for us to run IntelliJ or any other IDE.
We can run this independently
of those tools from the command line.
This is very useful in the Devop's process
if you're doing continuous integration,
continuous deployment.
This given document,
you can share with your management team, QA team.
So on.