We're making some good progress here,
but one other thing we need to do
by default, the Maven Surefire plugin will not show
the display name in reports.
It'll only show the method name of the test
and we don't want that.
We actually want to change it
to have support for display names.
So, just looking at the report here
you see all of the method names,
but some of our codes is actually using display names.
And those display name annotations are not being honored,
they're not being recognized at the moment.
And we can verify this by
simply moving back into our Demo Utils Test,
and then taking a look.
We can see that this test multiply has a display name
and test equals and not equals.
And a couple of others here.
They're all making use of display names,
but none of those values are showing up
in the actual report.
And so what we need to do is add
an additional configuration here.
And it's actually a pretty scary configuration,
and I it's a lot of information.
So, I'll show you how you can find this info
and figure it out on your own.
So, let's swing over to our web browser here,
and let's visit this site, maven.apache.org/surefire.
This is where we can get documentation
on the surefire plugin.
Okay, excellent. So we're at the Maven surefire page,
scroll down a bit.
And over on the left hand side
we'll choose Maven Surefire Plugin.
And then on this page, we'll actually scroll down
to a section for JUnit 5.
So, down here under examples,
they have a a link here for using JUnit 5 platform.
And they have different configs
that we can use here for JUnit 5.
I'll scroll down a bit further on this page,
and I'll find the section here Surefire Extensions
and Reports Configuration for @DisplayName.
So, they basically say, Hey, these
this is a new feature that we've added
and this is how you configure it.
So, I'd like you to just kind of copy paste
some of this configuration and add it to pom.xml file.
So, I'll grab this section here
for the stateless test set reporter
and then I'll just copy this little snippet.
And then I'll swing over to my pom.xml file.
And I'll add this right here in this configuration section.
Now, there's a lot of stuff in here that we don't need.
And so I'll actually delete some of it.
So, I'll get rid of the disable, the version
and then the first three, use phrased items.
Select those items and delete them
because I don't need those for this example.
And the main thing is, make sure you're left
with use phrase, test case method names
and we want to have this value set to true.
This will actually show the display name
in the unit test report.
So, this is the kind of the the key item
that you need to have here for this configuration.
All right, so this is how the coach
should look as a checkpoint.
Now, let's swing back over to our terminal window here
and let's simply run the test again, Maven clean test
and then also let's run our Maven site command again.
All righty, that looks pretty good.
Now, let's swing back over to our web browser
to our surefire report and let's reload.
And again, we wanted to make sure
that it used our actual display names.
And so we have success now.
So, now it's showing @DisplayNames.
It's not showing the actual method names
for those test cases.
So, this is really good I like it.
And, and we're successful
in getting that set up and configured, good job.
And now one other thing I want to do here just as housekeeping
and clean up, I want to remove the failing tests
or those broken tests that we created
just so I think we'll compile and run,
you know without any failing tests.
So let's just swing back over to our IntelliJ IDE.
Let's move back into our DemoUtills at java,
that multiply method that we broke
and let's go ahead and repair it.
So, instead of the B time speed, tone, speed
just for replace it with just normal, A time speed.
And then I just want to make sure everything works as desired.
So, just do a quick clean test here.
And oh gosh, this looks ugly.
Oh, I forgot.
I forgot to run that Maven site command.
Remember we need that for CSS and images,
that little workaround.
So we, we really do need that command.
(Instructor laughs)
So, I ran the site command swing back over
and now I do a reload and okay, excellent.
Great, so I'm getting into CSS styles
and I'm also getting into images.
Okay, that was a nice little exercise
that was kind of unplanned,
but it helped us verify
that we really do need the Maven site command.
All righty. So this is all really good stuff.
All of our tests are passing.
There's no failures and we're kind of in good shape here.
So, good job again for all of your hard work.