In this video, we'll cover conditional tests.
Now, there may be some scenarios
where we may not need to run all of the tests.
And you're probably wondering,
"Hmm, what are some use cases for this?"
Well, here we go.
You may not want to run a test
because the method to test is broken
and it's a known issue, all right?
So there's a certain feature of your application,
there's a bug, we know it's a bug.
We're waiting on the developers to get a fix for it.
Maybe we need to have some senior developers
jump in and help, but they're on other projects.
We can't fix it immediately, but we want to go ahead
and just, you know, disable it or not run that given test.
You also may have a scenario,
where a test should only run for a specific version of Java
or a range of versions.
So you could say, "Hey, this set of unit tests here
"should only run on Java 17 or Java 18."
Or you could say "This test should run on Javas 13
"up to Java 25" or whatever.
You can specify the range for those tests
because maybe they're using certain coding
and features that are only available
in those versions of Java.
You could also have a scenario,
where you only want to run a test on a given operating system.
So maybe you have some special test cases
to test for items on Microsoft Windows
or something Mac-specific
or something that can only run on Linux.
So instead of having those tests fail,
we could say, "Hey only run this given test
"if we're on a given operating system."
And then there's also the scenario
of you only want to run a test
if a specific environment variable is set
or certain system properties are set.
So maybe you have some tests
that only should be run in the dev environment,
a separate set of test to run in a QA environment,
and another set of tests that run in the UAT
or a production environment.
So different tests based on environment variables
or system properties.
Now you may wonder, "Well, if we'd have tests
"that we don't want to run, why not just comment the code?"
(chuckles) Well, we could do that,
but then the test will not be displayed in the test reports.
It's easy to forget about the broken test
because if they're no longer on the list, then I don't know,
we forgot about 'em.
And also, there's a manual process
if you need to enable or disable tests
for a given operating system or given environment.
It's just clunky, not really automated.
So it'd be cool if we can have this process automated.
And then the main item here
is that we want to report the test,
such that the management and the QA team
are aware of the issue.
So, hey, we have some tests and these tests are enabled
or disabled based on various conditions,
but we are reporting on them accordingly.
Okay, so let's go ahead and look at some annotations
that we can use here.
So the first two are disabled.
We'll basically disable a test method.
And then enabled on OS will basically enable a test
when running on a given operating system.
And these annotations can be applied
at the class level or the method level.
All right, so here's a code example.
So we have this example, ConditionalTest.Java.
So here's our class.
So the first example here at the basic test,
we're making use of disabled.
So here we say, disabled,
don't run until JIRA #123 is resolved.
So we're saying, "Hey, we know that this is a broken test,
"so don't run it until we actually resolve
"this given issue."
But the key here is that the test will not execute
but it will show up in the test results
as being an ignored test.
The next example here is EnabledOnOS.
So this example is enabled on Microsoft Windows.
So this given test will only run
if it's being run on Microsoft Windows,
and we could do a similar thing here for enabled on OS.Mac.
So again, this test will only run on Mac.
We can also have a combination here,
so we can set up an array.
So this give and test enabled on OS Windows, OS Mac.
So it'll run on Windows and Mac.
And then finally at the bottom here,
EnabledOnOS, OS.Linux, so this given test
will only run on Linux.
So now we go ahead and run the test.
We'll see, in this example, if we're running it on Mac,
then the basic test is disabled.
The test for Linux is disabled.
And the test for Windows is disabled.
So disabled tests will never execute.
So the code inside of that method will never be executed.
We can look at a similar scenario
if we ran these tests on Microsoft Windows.
So the basic test is disabled.
The Linux test is disabled.
And so the Mac test is disabled.
But the ones for Windows and Windows and Mac will run.
And then finally a similar thing here for Linux.
So basic test disabled, and then the other ones here,
Windows and Mac, Mac, and Windows,
those are disabled because this given test was run on Linux.
Now let's take a look at some other annotations here.
So we have EnabledOnJre, so we can enable a test
for a given Java version
and we can also make use of EnabledForJreRange.
So we'll enable a test for a given Java version range.
And then in this example, here, we can see the first test
EnabledOnJre, we give Java 17.
So this test will only run for Java 17.
We can give another example here, Java 13.
So again, only run on Java 13.
We can also make use of ranges.
We can have a minimum range and a max range.
So this given test will run on Java 13,
all the way up to Java 18.
We can also simply just give a minimum.
So we could say, "Hey, EnabledForJreRange,
"min equals JRE Java 11."
So, it'll run at Java 11 and higher.
Now in this example here, if I run it on Java 17,
then we'll see the test only for Java range,
that one executes.
The test only for Java 13, that one is ignored
or disabled because you know, we're running at Java 17.
The one for Java 17 runs,
and the Java range min, that one executes also.
Let's take a look at another set of annotations.
So we can enable a test if a given system property is set
and we can also enable a test
if a given environment variable is set.
So in this example here, the first test,
we say EnabledIfSystemProperty
and we give the name of the property, LUV2CODE_SYS_PROP,
matches, in this example, CI_CD_DEPLOY.
So we can have any name for the system property,
you can just totally make it up.
And then for the regular expression,
you can give an actual value to match,
or you can make use of a regular expression
with the fancy matching characters and so on.
Now you may wonder, well, how do I set a system property?
Well, if you're using IntelliJ,
you can set a system property here
by simply moving into this area,
and then you could set dash D,
and then you specify the name value pair.
So we give LUV2CODE_SYS_PROP equals whatever CI_CD_DEPLOY.
So that's how you can do it in IntelliJ.
Now the next example here,
is for setting up environment variables.
And so I could set up an environment variable,
name matches, again the name can be anything
and match whatever regular expression that you want.
Now to run this with the given environment variables,
we simply set up that name value pair,
Luv2Code environment equals dev.
So we run this one in this scenario,
we've set those environment variables accordingly,
and then those tests will execute.
All righty, so this all looks really good.
I'd like to go ahead and move into the IDE
and test this out.
So I'll see you in the next video.