All right,
let's go ahead and move into our IDE.
In this video, we'll cover @Disabled and also @EnabledOnOs.
And in this example, I'll actually create a new test class.
So I'll move under test,
I'll move into my package here, junitdemo
and I'll create a new class.
And for the name of the class, I'll call it ConditionalTest.
All right, let me go ahead and expand my window here
for a second.
And what I'll do is I'll start off with a very basic test
just to kind of get things moving.
For the actual test method I'll just put a comment here
and I'm not going to get into any real testing code here.
The main focus here
is just testing these unconditional assertions.
So let's just go ahead and run the test real quick.
And it executes, okay?
That's awesome.
And now what I'd like to do is make this a conditional test
or actually disable the test.
So I'll disable the test and then I'll give an actual reason
why this test is disabled.
So I'll say, hey, don't run this test
until we fix JIRA one, two, three.
And now we run the actual test
then we'll see the output and we'll see basic tests
so that means that this given test is disabled, all right.
It's not running because of that
given annotation that we set up.
Okay, let's go ahead and add some more tests here
and I'll just kind of copy this section,
move down a bit and paste it.
And I'm going to test for operating systems here.
So I will only enable this test for a given OS.
So I'll say EnabledOnOs,
and then I'll give the actual OS.WINDOWS.
So this given test will only execute
if we're running on Microsoft Windows.
And also just up top here, just double checking
make sure you have the right imports here for those items.
And small little typo to fix.
All right, that looks good.
All right, so here's our test.
This give test will only run on Microsoft Windows.
Now on my computer right now, I'm recording this on a Mac.
So when I run this this give and test will be ignored
or disabled.
And that's correct here, testForWindowsOnly disabled
because I'm on a Macintosh.
Okay, good.
Now let's go ahead and copy this test and paste it.
Make some slight mods here.
So this should run for Mac only.
Do Mac, save that.
Let's go ahead and run our test.
And great, so that test executed
because we're running on a Mac.
So again, conditional tests
based on the given operating system.
We can play around with some other scenarios here.
I can say Mac and Windows and simply set up an array.
So Mac, Windows,
and then run a test again.
And there we go, so good.
So we see the tests from Mac and Windows only.
That's fine, excellent.
And let's do one more example here for Linux.
Okay, so this one's running
and so the test for Linux only it's disabled
and because we're not running on Linux.
Okay, good, good.
So this is pretty good.
So good examples here of making use of conditional tests
based on operating system and so on.
So good job.