All righty.
So we're making some really good progress here.
So in this video, we'll cover EnabledOnJre
and EnabledOnJreRange.
So we'll basically check the Java versions.
We're just move in here and copy one of the test methods
and paste it a couple of times.
So I pasted it twice.
So zoom in here for a second,
let's testOnlyForJava17.
I'll update the annotation here.
So EnabledOnJre and then I give the actual JRE version.
So in this example, Java 17.
I'll just copy this annotation paste it down here
and I'll test it for Java 13.
Okay, great.
So these given test one will run only for Java 17
the other one will run only for Java 13.
Go ahead and run it.
So at the moment I'm running on Java 17
this one is disabled for Java 13
and the one for Java 17 of course will execute.
And let's play around with range and also minimum use here.
So we'll have this one set up for EnabledForJreRange.
We can give a minimum and a maximum.
So I'll say man of 13, max of 18.
And then I'll copy this one and paste it
and I'll do a slight tweak on it.
Just have minimum, I'll remove the max part of it.
So min Java 13, actually I'll change it to Java 11.
Minimum of Java 11.
So this will work on Java 11 or higher.
So those are the two new updates
that we added for this section.
Zoom out for a bit and run our test.
All righty, so this looks pretty good.
So we see for the range portion of it.
So testOnlyforJavaRange, that one executed good.
Good because it met the requirements
and then test only for Java range men
that executed also
because it met the requirements of a minimum of Java 11.
All right, so this part worked out for is pretty good.
So really good examples here
of conditional testing with Junit.
All righty, good job.