All righty, so we're almost done.
So here, we'll wrap it up with EnabledIfSystemProperty,
and also EnabledIfEnvironmentVariable.
So let's just copy this test
and paste it down here for a second.
And I'll update the method name here, so it's unique.
It's OnlyForDevEnvironment.
I'll EnableIfEnvironmentVariable is set.
So I give the name of the environment,
so named=.
And I'll call it, LUV2CODE_ENV.
We can give any name,
and I'll say matches on a given regular expression,
so here I'll just have a direct match, I'll call it DEV.
So that's our environment name, DEV.
And I'll just copy this test and paste it one more time.
And for this one, I'll make use of system properties.
So, system property.
And the name of this system property
I'll call it LUV2CODE_SYS_PROP.
And then I'll give matches and I'll just make something up
as far as like CI_CD_DEPLOY or something.
I'll just update the method name here to system properties.
So these are the two methods here
checking for our environment variable
and also checking for system property.
Now let's zoom out for a bit and let's execute the test.
And then we'll see testOnlyForDevEnvironment.
We'll see that fails because the environment doesn't exist
and system property that fails
because that given property doesn't exist.
Okay, that makes sense, right?
because we haven't really done anything.
(chuckles)
We just wrote some tests where we didn't configure
our system accordingly.
So you may wonder
how do we set these actual properties here?
We can simply update our run configuration in IntelliJ.
So I'll just modify the run configuration.
And for environment variables
we simply give a name value pair.
So LUV2CODE_ENV=DEV.
That's a name value pair.
That matches with the actual item
that we have for the annotation here in this code example.
And based on this when we run the test,
then it should execute that given test method.
So let's go ahead and test it out.
And we see that we have some success here.
So testOnlyForDevEnvironment that executed
because that given environment variable was set
and it matched.
Awesome.
Now let's do a similar thing here for a system property.
So again, we're modifying the run configurations.
So for our system properties,
we make use of it right here on the command line with a -D,
that means a system property,
and then you give the name value pair.
So the property name is LUV2CODE_SYS_PROP=
and in this example CI_CD_DEPLOY.
Again, matching with what we have on that given annotation.
All right, so go ahead and zoom out real quick
and let's hit okay.
And let's go ahead and run this one.
So at the moment, the property is not set,
then we execute it and then everything's A-OK.
So that new run configuration was applied
and that system property set.
Okay, excellent, great.
So, in this video, we saw some good examples here
of running tests based on environment variables
and also running tests based if system properties were set.
So I'm pretty excited here
and I like that we've covered some really good stuff.
Good job, my friend.