We're getting closer to finishing up this application
we worked on thus far,
our shop here. In the last section, we made sure that we can store data in the web on a server
and I use Firebase there as an example but it hopefully became clear that you could work with any API
and that I just showed you in general how to send requests from inside your Flutter app to the
back-end.
In this module, we'll now have a look at authentication,
that means we'll make sure that the users of our app are no longer anonymous and can just use it like
this which for a shop for example doesn't really work because orders have to be stored for a specific
user and not in general.
So we'll learn how to add users now and that includes things like adding a user sign up and login, making
sure that we attach orders to a user
but also products created by a user to that user and that we also managed the authentication status
of that user, so that when the user closes the app and comes back, we try to log the user back in.
Therefore in this section, we'll have a look at how authentication works in Flutter apps,
that's an important part obviously, how does this generally work?
What's the theory behind that? Then we will implement user sign up and login and we'll then start managing
that user session and that will also include things like making sure that orders belong to a user but
also making sure that when the user closes the app and opens it again, that we try to log the user back
in and don't require the user to enter his credentials every time he restarts the app.
These are all the things we'll have a look at in the section.