Thus far in this course and in the apps we built in this course, we only covered this scenario that
we have essentially one page in our application and of course in most applications, you actually have
more than one page or screen as it's also called. You might have a user profile page, a page with all
products,
then when you tap on a product, you see the details for that product
on a separate screen and you can navigate between these screens with the back button, by swiping back
or maybe you have some tabs at the bottom or a drawer which you can open with a hamburger icon in your
top navigation bar
and that's exactly what we'll have a look at in this section. In detail,
we'll have a look at what navigation and screens are, what these terms mean and what they mean in Flutter
apps and how you can add navigation to the Flutter apps.
We will learn about pushing and popping pages and what this means and how it works in Flutter.
We'll have a look at adding tabs and drawers to add an application, so that you have different ways of
switching between different areas of your app.
And last but not least, a super important topic of course, you will also learn how to pass data between
your screens, so how you may for example pass the data about a selected item into the detailed screen
that opened up for that icon.
These are all things we'll have a look at in this module now. Throughout this module, we'll build this
application here,
this application where we can browse meals by category, mark them as favorites if we like them, set
filters where we can decide which kind of meals we want to include, so that I now for example only include
vegetarian meals like this one,
gone is the toast and the burger and we can of course also use tabs here to then for example see our
favorites.
Now as you can already tell, you learned a lot about navigating around, going back and forth, using tabs
and using the side drawer and even many things which you don't see here on first look
and as a side effect in this module, you also learned how to build a beautiful application with many new
cool features and widgets which we haven't used thus far in the course.