Now for the image, of course you could think about using the device camera and I'll have a whole module
where we dive into how to use the device camera.
Here, I want to focus on getting user input and therefore here, I'll simply add a text field where the
user has to enter a URL.
Now again, we'll later learn how to use the device camera nonetheless.
Now I think for something like the image, it would be nice if we don't just have a text input where the
user enters a URL but if we also show a preview of the entered image so that the user can quickly check
whether that image is correct and so on.
So therefore now as a new input here, I'll not directly add a text form field but a row since I want
to have two items sit next to each other
and that's also something you can do. Inside a form,
you're not restricted to just having text form fields and actually we already have a ListView in there,
you can use any widget you want, form then just works together with text form fields,
it ignores other widgets
so to say. Therefore here, we can add a row and in that row, I want to have two things - I want to have a
container which should in the end show a preview of the image the user chose
and then I want to have the text form field which allows the user to enter a URL.
Let's start with the container,
I'll give it a width of 100 and a fixed height of 100,
so that will be the box in which the image should be previewed
and I'll add a margin here of EdgeInsets.only because I want to have some margin to the top of let's
say 8 and to the right of 10 and on the right of that container will be the text input
and on top of it will be the prior text input here. So with that distance added to the surrounding elements,
I also want to add a little decoration here, a little border to be precise.
You learned that you can create a decoration for a container by setting the decoration argument here
to a box decoration object and on there, you can add a border with the border argument and then simply
create a border on all sides with Border.all,
give it a width of let's say 1 and a color maybe of Colors.gery to have a light grey border around
that container and the child
now of course should be the image.
That's something I'll do later, for now I'll just render an empty container so I'll not render anything
because we first of all need to work on the text form fields to have an image to show there.
So on this text form field, the decoration now will be an input decoration where I set a label
text of imageUrl, to make it clear what the user should enter there.
Now besides the decoration here, I want to have a keyboard type which supports entering a URL because
I want to have a text input type of URL which gives us a soft keyboard that is particularly well
suited to entering URLs. I also want to assign a text input action and here, the text input action
should be done, so it should show this done text or this checkmark which makes it clear that when you now
hit enter, you try to submit that form. Of course you don't have to use that there but I think it makes sense
for the last input we have. Now I won't to add a focus node here because we can't go there from the previous
input because that was that multiline input here and therefore we're done with this but I want to
do something different here on that text form field. Now in general, the form manages our values, we're
not using that yet when we submit everything but in general, you can rely on that being the case and
you don't need to add your own text editing controllers to get access to the values of your inputs, that's
good but here for the image text form field, I actually do want to get access to the input the user entered
before the form is submitted because I want to show a preview here in that container.
So for that text form field down there, for the imageUrl text form field, I do want to add my own
text editing controller, so I'll add a new property which is my imageUrlController
where I create a new text editing controller like this and just as with the focus node, you should
by the way also dispose of that here in your dispose method, so of the imageUrlController.
So the imageUrlController is now something I can assign here to the controller key on the text
form field, like this.
Again, you don't have to do that if you just want to get the value when the form is submitted
but here I want to have it before the form is submitted and therefore I do need to add it here.
Now that imageUrlController here is updated when we type into the text form field, so we can
now use it or the value stored in it here in our container where we want to preview the image.
Therefore here instead of showing an empty container, we can check if the imageUrlController text
is empty which means we don't have a URL yet
and if that's the case, we maybe show a text widget where we say enter a URL but otherwise if
it's not empty,
so here in the else case, I want to render a fitted box here which contains my image as a child
and here I'll create an image widget with image network because I expect an imageUrl, so image
network is the right way of creating an image and there, I then take the imageUrlController text
which we checked that it's not empty.
Of course it could be an invalid URL but we'll simply not render an image here,
that's okay here.
Of course you could add an extra check here and check whether it is a valid URL but I'll leave that
out for now.
I want to add my fit here on the image widget which we're creating and set this to BoxFit.cover
now. With that if we save that
and I go to creating a new product here, we actually don't see anything on the screen.
The reason for that is that we have an error and if we scroll to the top of that error,
we learned that an input decorator which is created by a text field cannot have an unbounded width.
So we have the problem with the width of some text form field,
obviously it has to be that field because before we added that, everything worked and indeed the problem
here is that the text form field sits inside of a row and something you didn't know before
because I haven't told you is that the text form field by default takes as much width as it can get
and the problem with that is that if it's inside of a row as we have it here, a row has an unconstrained
width. So normally, the boundaries of the device width are the boundaries of the text form field
but the row doesn't have these boundaries, it doesn't have the device width as an internal boundary,
therefore text form field tries to take an infinite amount of width. Solution is simple - we can wrap this
with a new widget and there for example, we can take the expanded widget if we want to. If we now save this,
now here we see the imageUrl and next to it, we see a box which should eventually show a preview.
Now I also want to change how that is positioned and for that, I'll go to the row and I want to align
items differently on the cross axis which on a row is from top to bottom,
I want to set the cross axis alignment here to end, to move it all to the end.
So now if you save that, the imageUrl thing here is simply pushed down to the end of that box and aligned
with the end of our container which looks better in my opinion.
Well and with that, let's try adding a URL now and for that, I simply grabbed some URL, you can do
the same with the help of google image search or anything like that,
copy that and then simply long press here to paste it and if we confirm with the checkmark, this is shown.
So now we see our preview here,
now important of course, this didn't update with every keystroke here but only after we submitted this
with the checkmark which closes the keyboard, which of course is fine
here, it gives the user time to enter the full URL.
Now one thing you could want about that imageUrl is that you actually don't need to hit this button
here at the bottom right to see the preview but that you also see the preview if this loses focus,
so if you go to another input for example, I think that would be an expected behavior of this app.
Now Flutter doesn't have a default listener for when this loses focus but you can set up your own listener
with the help of focus node.
So let's add a new focus node here for the image, an imageUrlFocusNode which we create here
with the focus node class
and of course just as before, we have to dispose of that when the state object gets destroyed,
so here is my imageUrlFocusNode and I call dispose on it inside of the dispose method
and now we can use that imageUrlFocusNode not to request focus for it
once we're done with the description as mentioned before, that's not really possible but we can nonetheless
add this focus node here to our text form field for the imageUrl because we can now set our own
listener
and when this loses focus, so when the user unselected it, then we can react to this
to make sure that we updated the UI and use the imageUrlController to show a preview.
So for that, we need to set up our own listener to the imageUrlFocusNode. It's attached to that
text form field down there and therefore, it keeps track of whether that's focused or not,
so we just need to listen to changes in that focus. For that, initState is a good place to set up that
initial listener.
So here in initState, I can set up my
imageUrlFocusNode
add listener, so with the add listener we add a new listener to that focus node and we point at a function
here that should be executed whenever the focus changes.
For that, I'll add a new method here which doesn't return anything which I'll name
updateImageUrl,
_updateImageUrl and I point at this _updateImageUrl function here with add
listener. I don't execute it here because I don't want to execute it when this gets parsed, when this gets read,
I just want to use the pointer at this function to tell Flutter that I want Flutter to execute this
_updateImageUrl function whenever the focus changes here. Now important, we also have to clear that
listener when we dispose of that state, otherwise the listener keeps on living in memory even though
the page is not presented anymore and that again creates a memory leak.
So in this post, to be super safe before you dispose of the imageUrlFocusNode,
I would recommend that you call remove listener and simply also point at _updateImageUrl
and therefore it will remove that listener that uses this function from the imageUrlFocusNode.
Well with that, in the _updateImageUrl function,
we simply have to check if we're not having focus anymore,
so if the imageUrlFocusNode does not have focus and this will be fired if it had focus and we then
click somewhere else and if we don't have focus anymore, so we lost focus, then we want to update the
UI and use the latest state stored in the imageUrlController and for that we can simply
call set state like this. It's a bit of a hack because we don't update the state ourselves
but we know that the state has updated, that we have an updated value in
imageUrlController and we want to rebuild the screen to reflect that updated value in
imageUrlController since that value in imageUrlController is the image you want to preview.
So with this change, if we go back to this page, now if I tap in there and out of there, you see no update because
we entered nothing
but if I now pasted my URL and I then tap into a different field, you see that preview,
so now we get the preview when we lose focus which I think is closer to the expected behavior.
And with that, we finish the inputs, they generally work correctly
but of course we're not submitting them, we're not getting their data and we're not validating them.
So these will be the next steps.