Before we continue implementing features in this application, let's come back to that then
catch error syntax. We're using then and catch error because these are methods defined on that future
object based on that future class which is built into Dart and it's a very important class as you can
probably already tell,
it helps us deal with asynchronous code and asynchronous code is really just code that executes whilst
other code doesn't wait for it to finish, as it would be the case here for our post request.
You can absolutely work with futures like that but there is a more concise, a more readable syntax
which I personally prefer and which I therefore want to use from now on and which I'll therefore introduce
now
and that's a syntax called async await.
You'll also have that in JavaScript for example if you're familiar with that and you can simply handle
futures with that in a more elegant way, technically behind the scenes, they work in exactly the same
way as you learned it.
You use that syntax by using the async keyword, by adding the async keyword after your parameter list
before your curly brace on a function or a method,
so you need to do that on a method or a function and then you add async here between arguments and curly
braces.
By doing that, one important thing happens, all the code you have in there automatically gets wrapped
into a future,
so when using async here, the function or the method on which you use it always returns a future and
that future might then not yield anything in the end but it always returns a future because this now
is all wrapped into a future.
Therefore here, we don't have to return our future anymore because we automatically have this all wrapped
into a future and that future will also be returned automatically,
so that's some magic happening behind the scenes.
Now the idea with the async keyword is that we can now get rid of then and catch error, instead
we can now use another keyword here,
the await keyword and that tells Dart that we want to wait for this operation to finish before we move
on to the next line in our Dart code.
Now important, with that we don't change the rules of how Dart works. Behind the scenes, it still transforms
this to this future syntax with a then method,
so it's still simply wraps the code which comes in the next line into a then block,
it doesn't pause code execution but to us, it looks like it does and it simply turns this into a more readable
code which is more similar to the code we wrote thus far where we also had the situation that line after
line executed.
So here with await, we're telling Dart that it should wait, in quotation marks, for this to finish or
in other words, that it should wrap all the code that comes after this into the then block that it invisibly
adds.
It means however that we can get rid of then here and although we can get rid of catch error, like
this here.
So let's get rid of all of that,
let's comment that out for the moment here and with that, of course the question is where do we now get
our response from?
Well we can now actually use this here as if this would be a synchronous method,
so a method which finishes immediately, which doesn't continue in the future and eventually finishes
and therefore, we can simply store the result in a variable or like here, in a constant. So we can now assign
a result of this operation to a constant with the help of the await keyword which is available because
we use async here.
So with that, we're storing the response in the response constant and now the code, in the next line so here,
will only execute once this is done because the code in the next line is invisibly wrapped in that then
block.
So in here, we have the response constant available of course due to this syntax here and now all that
code runs just fine as before.
Now with error handling, we of course have no catch error method anymore now but you can use an alternative
approach,
you can use an approach which is also built into Dart which we haven't used thus far but which you can
use on any synchronous code,
so normally on everything but futures and since this now is written like synchronous code, you could
use it here as well,
you can use try catch. With try catch, you add a try block with the try keyword and curly braces around
the code which might fail.
So I added try and then a curly brace and then before my closing curly brace here,
so inside of the curly braces, I have all the code which might eventually fail
and there, you should not put your code which could fail because you were lazy to properly test it but
code where you can't rule out that it fails at runtime,
for example code that depends on user input or that depends on an internet connection which might not
be there, hence HTTP request is a great candidate for trying it because you can't guarantee that it
will succeed because there are too many factors beyond your control.
Now try doesn't work like that,
instead you need to add something else, you need to add a catch class here with the catch keyword
and then between parentheses, an error object which you catch and then you have another pair of curly
braces and between that, you put the code which should run when this throws an error.
So here, I can now actually take that code and move that into my catch block here and use that error
which is passed as an argument so to say into this catch block.
So this will now run if the code between try causes an error,
now this code here of course also should only run if we have no error,
so I'll also move that into the try block because all this code here depends on this succeeding so I'll
move it into the same try block here.
And with that, we have a setup where we can use this try catch feature which again is available in Dart
in general and you can use it anywhere in your Dart code, not just when working with async await or when
working with HTTP, you can use it on any code where you have reason to think that it might fail and
you can't rule that out during development and then you can write code that should run when this fails
and write code that should run when it succeeds or which you want to test whether it succeeds and that's
similar to then and catch error of course.
So with that, we have this set up here in add product and I'm using async await here.
Now just because I'm using it here doesn't mean you also have to use it in edit product for example,
there we're also using that add product future and remember, due to us using async here,
this automatically returns a future here. So in edit product screen, we now get back that future and
we can still work with catch error
and then there if we want to but we can also use with async await there.
So here, I can also add the async keyword after my parameter list before the curly brace, this therefore
here also yields a future which eventually yields nothing
which isn't a problem here for the rest of our code,
that's fine
and then here we have all that code, this here is still synchronous code,
all good but here, we have async code because add product returns a future
and here we can therefore also of course add await, instead of using then.
Now we could store the result here in some variable or some constant but actually add product doesn't
return a result, it returns a future which yields nothing and that nothing certainly is not something
we wouldn't want to store.
So I'm just awaiting here but of course, now I'm not using catch error anymore but I'll again wrap this
into try catch here. So I'll take that code, move that into try, like that and then catch my error here,
get rid of that catch error class there and instead now take that code, that dialog code here, cut that
and move that into catch.
So with that, I'm catching my error here now and then showing that dialog if an error should occur and
we can also get rid of that closing parentheses here. Now this code here, setting the state and popping
should always run no matter if we succeeded or if we then ended up in the error block and for that, on
try catch,
you can also add a finally block, another keyword, only works in conjunction with try and catch and
that defines some code which should always run no matter if you succeeded or if you failed.
So here, we can now move our code here which should always run into finally but important, show dialog
returns a future which will resolve as soon as the user press this button or in other words, it will
resolve as soon as this dialog is popped off the screen which happens when the user presses this button
and therefore here, I actually also want to await for this result before we continue to finally.
So with that, we're using async await and the app should work just as before and for that, I'll actually reintroduce
that error here so that we can see whether that's the case.
So let me refresh the app with that error, reintroduce that and let's see if it still fails,
if we go to manage products here
and we then try to add a new product,
this should fail of course because I still added that error and hopefully, it should still be handled.
So if we now press the save button here, we get the dialog,
we don't navigate away until I click OK
but then we do. So we have the same behavior as before but in my opinion, async await is more readable,
you just have to be aware that behind the scenes, we're still working with a future and this still gets
wrapped into then and so on.