Almost there,
what's missing now is the orders, the orders should also belong to a user.
For that, I'll just store them like the favorite status of a product,
I'll give them a separate node in my database so to say or I'll add separate nodes inside of that orders
entry in the database
or I'll add separate subnodes here under orders instead of directly storing the orders here. For this
to work,
besides the authToken in the orders class here, in the orders.dart file, we also need to get the userId
of course and therefore this should be provided in the constructor
and for that to work, we need to go back to the main.dart file because here, we do pass data into our
constructor and there, we should now also forward the userId. With that done, we can go back to orders,
now we have the userId available there and for example here when we fetch the orders, I expect
to get them from orders but in there now from a subfolder which actually is my userId and for that
of course when we store orders, we have to make sure we store them in such a subfolder by also adding
that here, that should already be all. With that if we save this and we go to orders, we shouldn't fetch
any
because for this user, we have no orders, we have no orders in such a subfolder. Now here,
let's log back in and I was logged out here by the way automatically because my token expired and that
therefore led to this logic in the main.dart file where we check isAuth which does some token expiration
date validation, led to render the AuthScreen
so that's good but now that I logged back in, let's add a couple of items to the cart here and place the
order. Let's now go to orders and now we can see that order here because now in the orders folder, we
have a separate subfolder for that user with our own order data in there and if I delete all the other
orders which belong to no user
thanks to that new structure, we can also try logging in with a different user and we shouldn't see that
order then.
So if I do a refresh and I login with the test2@test.com user, we now actually shouldn't
see our order here.
So let's do a quick login here and go to the orders screen, no orders here
and yes we could show some text here which says no orders found but for now this will do.
The good thing is that now, we're scoping all the data or we're attaching all the data to users and that's
of course how it should be. We're making sure that every user has its own data.