So let's move on to the price input an add validation there as well.
For that, I'll add the validator, again
here we have that function which gets a value and should return a string or null and now in here, we're
validating the price.
Now what should be true about the price?
Well I want to check if it is empty, in which case it's certainly not valid.
So in that case I would return
please enter a price but if we make it past this if check, it is not empty but it still might be an invalid
number.
So here I want to check if double.parse succeeds,
tryParse
is the perfect solution for that because tryParse unlike parse does not throw an error if it fails
but return null if it does fail and therefore, if we compare this to null and of course I try parsing
my value, then we know that parsing failed because tryParse returns null if it fails.
So then we could return please enter a valid number because now we know that the user did enter something
but it was not a valid number. Now maybe parsing succeeded but the number is smaller or equal to zero
and of course a valid price should be above zero or above any threshold you have.
So then I want to parse this,
I know now that parsing will succeed because we made it past this check which checks for invalid numbers
but here I want to parse the value and check if it's smaller or equal to zero
and of course your threshold could also be 1, 100, whatever your minimum price is, you should just tell
the user about your minimum price at some point.
So here, I would then return please enter a number greater than zero or anything like that
and if we make it past all these checks, I return null because then we have a valid number.
So with that, now here if I hit save, this succeeds.
If I enter nothing here, I get please enter a price, if I enter zero, I get please enter a number greater
than zero and if I enter hello, I get please enter a valid number,
so we give the user various hints on what's wrong depending on what the user entered.
Now let's move on to the description. There, it's a bit simpler, I'll also add my validator of course, get
my value and you can name this argument however you want, of course it's passed in automatically
but you're receiving it here, so you can name it however you want
and here I want to check if value is empty, in which case I return please enter a description and that's
just an arbitrary condition
I also came up with. I want to make sure that if it's not empty, the length is greater than 10
so that we have a description that is at least 10 characters long and therefore here, the check should
be a bit smaller than 10 because if it's smaller than 10, then I return should be at least 10 characters
long or anything like that
and if we make it past these checks, I just return, I just return null I mean.
So now with that, if we save this and we go back here, submitting this works.
If I remove a couple of characters, now it's too short and if I remove all characters, we get please enter
a description.
This is long enough however, well is indeed long enough and we are able to submit it. Now last but the least
for the imageUrl, you could come up with a complex validation using regular expressions
and after this lecture, I'll have a text lecture with more information about regular expressions.
They are a bit more advanced, a bit more niche but can be useful,
therefore I have them in a separate lecture. Here we'll add a quite basic validation to that imageUrl
input,
we can also have validator argument and create our function here,
again an anonymous function in my
case here and now in there, I'll have a relatively simple validation, I'll check if the value is
empty and if it is empty, I return my good old please enter an imageUrl message here, if it's not
empty, it might still be invalid because I want to check if the value starts with and that's a method
Dart provides on strings, if it starts with http or if the value starts with https or to be
precise, if it does not start with that.
So if it does not start with HTTP and it does not start with https, so neither of the two is correct, then
I know this can't be a URL so I'll return please enter a valid URL. if you make it past this,
I return null and of course, you could still have a URL that does not yield the image, even if it is
a valid URL, you could have a URL to google.com which is not an image but a webpage and in such
cases, we still would have an invalid image, that's something we don't capture here. You could of course
think about more elaborate rules where you also check whether the link ends with .jpg or
.png to improve the likelihood of that being an image.
So actually let's do that,
so if the value does not end with .png and it also does not end with .jpg and also does not end
with .jpeg with an e in there.
So if we have neither of these,
then let's say I know it's not a valid image,
so then we could return
please enter a valid imageUrl.
Of course, that's still not the perfect check, it leaves out some formats which you might want to accept in
your application
and just because something ends with .jpg also doesn't ensure it's necessarily an image
but it's good enough here,
we have various checks now and with that, we have that validation in place too.
Now one thing we could now also do is we could take these checks and bring them into our updateImageUrl
function here
and then when we have a changed focus here, we could add these checks and instead of value, we could use
the imageUrlController text value which is the value the user entered
and if this is empty or this value, so imageUrlController text does not start with
https
or concatenating these conditions as well,
the value does not end with png or jpg or jpeg like this,
then here we could just return and not continue because in the end what I have here is a long check
where I check whether this is empty and if that's true, we return or if it does not start with http and not
with https, so I'll wrap this into extra parentheses to make it clear that these two belong together.
If this condition overall is true, we also return,
so if it's not starting with that or here, these three are also making up one block altogether, so if
that ends up being true, so if we don't end with one of these extensions here, then I also want to return and
with that, I make sure that I don't show a preview if we have an incorrect URL. With that let's go
there
and if I now tap into a different input and I submit this, this seems to work, I get my output there.
Now if I remove .jpg here at the end, like this,
you see this preview doesn't update and we don't get an error,
so our check here in _updateImageUrl seems to work
and if I submit, I get an error message here
Now if I re-add .jpg here and I tap somewhere else, then this is updated and I can now save this
again.
Now if we then go all the way to the left here
and I remove https at the beginning, tap somewhere else,
it's not updating the preview and I get an error if it try to submit it and if I now delete everything
here, so select all the inputs there, so if I clear this entire input and I click somewhere else, again
this is not updated which is good and
of course you might say if it's empty, then maybe you want to clear this as well but I get this error
message here and yes actually if it is empty, I'll remove this check, if it is empty,
then I don't want to return,
instead I want to call set state and indeed update this preview with the enter a URL text.
So with that, we added validation to all these inputs which is great, which works as it should here now.
The missing piece for adding a product now of course is that we do actually create a new product and
add it to our product list which we can see here
once we're done editing here.