With that, back to our application here and before we continue working on the user interface where we
of course still have lots of work left to do,
let me actually first work on the data we're outputting.
With that, I mean this price here which doesn't really look like a price,
there is no dollar sign in front of it for example
and I also mean the date, I want to change the formatting or the content of these two pieces
of data which were outputting here. Now for that, let's start with the price, with the amount we're
outputting
and there I have a special syntax or I want to show you a special syntax you can use in Dart, not just
in Flutter, to output values in a text or as a text.
Right now I'm outputting the amount here with the help of to string and that is the perfectly fine way
of doing that
and this is actually all we need
if all we want to output is the amount value here as a string.
But if I want to add a dollar sign in front of that, I actually can also concatenate this string together
with another string,
I can add dollars sign here and then add a plus to combine these two strings.
And normally this would work, here
however, Dart doesn't like this for some reason.
Now let's first of all try an alternative which will work if I add simply a colon for amount or whatever,
so a colon and then a whitespace
and then I have the plus and then the amount to string and I save this and here we see a colon empty amount.
Now that's nice but I don't want to show a colon but a dollar sign.
So what's special about the dollar sign? For this, let's first of all understand how we could shorten
this here. Concatenating strings like this with a plus is perfectly fine
but Dart actually has a more concise and shorter syntax for that. Instead of combining strings with a
plus, which gets especially cumbersome if you have very long strings with a lot of different segments,
you can use a special syntax where you use the dollar sign, which actually has a special meaning in Dart
strings, which is why we had this error before and after the dollar sign, you can reference a variable
or a property name to output that here.
So here we could type tx and now it would try to inject the value of tx here in that place.
So if we now save that and we go back, we see some strange error here on the right,
that simply is shown because we're exceeding the boundaries here,
let's ignore it for now.
More interesting is that we see instance of transactions, so indeed we are outputting our transaction
here.
An instance of transaction is simply what you see when you call tx to string
and that's called for you here automatically.
Now the more interesting thing is that of course here I don't want I'll put my entire transaction but
my amount and therefore we can also use .amount here,
however if you are trying to inject or to interpolate as it's called more, than just the variable itself,
so if you use more than just a variable name, like here where I also use the dot notation, then you have
to wrap that expression which you're trying to interpolate into curly braces.
So then you have dollar sign and then curly braces and between the curly braces, you have your expression
which should resolve to a string or to something where to string can be called on, which will then be
called automatically by Dart
so that this string gets now added in this place here.
So now I've actually remove txAmount to string here at the end and I just have this syntax,
if we now go back, we indeed see our amount here again but now using a feature called string interpolation
and that's a very handy feature since this is obviously shorter than combining multiple pieces of text
together with a plus.
We also don't have to call to string here because Dart does this for us when we use this string interpolation
syntax.
Now that's all nice
but of course I wanted to add a dollar sign here and not a colon and a whitespace.
However the dollar sign as you can tell is a reserved character,
the dollar assigned to Dart means that
you plan on interpolating some value
but what if you want the dollar sign as a character?
Well you can do something which we already did earlier when we wanted to output a quote.
Then you might remember we added a backslash in front of it to escape it,
so to tell Dart that this should not be treated as a language feature, to close a string but instead
as a normal character and you can do exactly the same with a dollar sign. If you don't want the special
meaning it has to Dart but you want the character dollar sign, then you add a backslash in front
of it and you simply add the dollar sign after the backslash.
So now this dollar sign after the backslash here will just be output as text,
this dollar sign here however, since there is no backslash directly in front of it, will be treated as
the beginning of a string interpolation
and with that if we save this, we have the dollar sign in front of the amount. That was a lot of talking just
to add a dollar sign
but the core takeaway of course is not just that you can escape it but that it has a special meaning
and that you can use it in string interpolation.