So that's all nice,
we have a responsive application on Android
but now what about iOS, for example in landscape mode? This switch here is a material design switch and
it will look the same way on iOS.
The same for our appBar and the floating action button here at the bottom for example is a UI pattern
that doesn't even exist for iOS,
so rendering it there might be confusing to iPhone users who are not used to having such floating action
buttons and therefore now, we'll dive into creating adaptive user interfaces where we still work in one and
the same codebase but now we do it such that we actually build a different user interface regarding
its styling and the look and feel for iOS.
For that, let's first of all bring up an iOS simulator which you can do with open -a simulator.app
on macOS only, this does not work on Windows PCs because you can't build iOS apps there and
therefore you don't have Xcode installed but on macOS, you can now bring up that iPhone simulator so
that we can see how our app looks like on an iPhone, which is of course an important first step to optimizing
it for iOS and an iPhone. With that emulator being up,
let me launch my app on the emulator by quitting my current process, selecting the iPhone emulator here
in the bottom right corner and then rerunning the app here with the help of the debug start with that
debugging command in Visual Studio Code
and now this is built with Xcode for iOS and we'll launch the app on that iPhone simulator.
So let's wait for that to launch and have a look at it there
and this is how it looks like,
not too shabby, certainly not bad
but now as I just mentioned, this looks very Android-like. Now you might or might not want this,
it depends on what you think your users will like
but I will certainly change certain things.
Now for some widgets, it's really easy to adjust the look, like for the switch here in landscape mode.
If you have that switch there, you can easily get the iOS look by going to the place where you're using
the switch,
in our case in the main.dart file here and for some widgets, like the switch and the official docs tell
you when that is available, you can use a special constructor,
the adaptive constructor. It takes the same configuration as the normal switch
but the difference here is that it automatically adjusts the look based on the platform.
So now you see we have that iOS switch here on iOS and if I would run this on Android again, we would
have the Android look again.
So that's pretty neat because that is a quick and easy win we can get to well have an item or have a
widget that looks more iOS-like on iOS and doesn't have the default material
look. Of course by the way,
you can also change the color here and you could set the active color here to theme of context and then
use the accent color to still use that accent color if you wanted that because you might want to keep
the general color theme.
There is no need to swap that as well if you like that in general,
you can definitely use these material colors,
it's only about adjusting the parts of your app that you do want to adjust,
so now for example, I have that yellow background color. So that is nice,
what about that floating action button though?
We don't want that on iOS at all,
it shouldn't be there.
I don't care about its look,
it shouldn't be there because it's not a default
iOS pattern to have such a button. Well just as you can find out which width you have or which orientation,
you can also find out which platform you're running on
and here in the main.dart file, we are of course rendering the floating action button,
we can simply not render it if we are on iOS.
To do that, you first of all need to add an import at the top, the very top,
that's just a convention,
you can import dart:io and it's just a convention that you have all your Dart imports
at the very top, then all packages like Flutter but other third-party packages as well in the next block
below that and then below that, your own imports.
So from dart:io, I import a core feature that's baked into Dart, not just into Flutter,
I can find out on which platform my app is running with the help of platform. and then for example
you have isIOS to check if you're on iOS and if I am, this will give me a boolean.
So if this is true, I'll use this ternary expression to render an empty container,
so basically not render anything, otherwise I'll render my floating action button.
So with that, I ensure that if I'm on iOS, I have no floating action button down there
and there's also nothing invisible you could tap.
You can now only open that modal sheet here with the help of the plus up there.
So the platform is check here is very useful and it allows you to check for a broad variety of platforms,
you can check for Linux, macOS, Windows, if you would run your app somehow on an operating system like
this.
You can check for Android, for Fuchsia which is also another mobile operating system developed by Google,
not currently used and so on.
So this is what you can check
and this of course allows you to easily swap or render different widgets based on the platform you're
running on.