So having the button is good but of course we want to actually add a new transaction when we press
it and for that, we first of all need to collect the user input.
It's good that we have these text fields but how can we get access to what the user entered?
There are two ways of getting access,
it's up to you which one you choose, it also depends on the complexity of the form you're building.
The first way of getting access is that you simply save the user input with every keystroke, that you
save it in a property.
Now for that, we need a property in which we can save it and we can add it here to our widget
but keep in mind that this is a stateless widget and what does this mean?
It means that any data we have in there, like the transactions property, is immutable,
we can't change it.
Well technically we can change it but our changes will never be reflected on the user interface.
Now actually here that wouldn't be a problem because with every keystroke, we could save the data
the user entered and then only do something once we hit a button.
So it's actually okay if we just save these changes without updating the user interface because there
is no update we want to perform with every keystroke,
we just want to save the data behind the scenes and we can do that because a stateless widget is still
an object, still a normal class, so we can have properties in there which we can change, we just can't
rerun the build method, we can't use set state here
but again, that won't be needed.
So what you can do therefore is you can add new properties here to your class, maybe a string title input
and another string, amount input, that's by the way important, the input values are always strings by default,
if you need a different value like a number here for the amount, then you need to convert it manually.
So we have these two strings
and now if we go down to our text fields, there you can add the onChanged listener. Now onChanged will
fire with every keystroke. As you see, you have a couple of other listeners too, onEditingComplete is fired
when the user presses the done, go or next or whatever it is button in the soft keyboard,
so that would basically be that button on the bottom right corner, that can have a different look and
meaning and you can configure that actually. By the way, you can ignore this here for now,
this strange yellow thing here. So that is onEditingComplete and it's fired when that button is
pressed. onSubmitted is kind of related but this fires whenever the done button is pressed, so not
on every button in the bottom right corner basically but only for that done button and if you configured
your text field to show a different button there, then it would not fire
and onTap is fired whenever you tap into the text field.
Now here, we need onChanged because onChanged fires for every keystroke. onChanged then requires us
to pass reference, a pointer at a function which takes a string value,
so not a function that has no arguments but a function that accepts exactly one argument which is of
type string and that then returns nothing.
You can use a named function here or you define an anonymous function,
however as I just explained, it needs to be a function which takes a value.
You don't need to add the type here because Dart is smart enough to infer this because onChanged expects
a function that takes a string argument, Dart automatically understands that value here will be of type
string.
You also don't have to name this value, you can name it val, whatever you want.
So now we get this, we have this function, it will be triggered for every keystroke and then in here since
we're editing the title here, we can set title input equal to val.
So that means we overwrite the current value of title input with the input the user chose here,
so with the current input of that text input, of that text field. We can do the same for the amount, add
onChanged, here get the value and then we can also use that shorter notation with the arrow because
we have only one expression, there we can set amount input equal to val. With that, we have a setup where
we register every keystroke and now we save that in our title input and in the amount input.
Again, the UI won't be updated because we're not calling set state and we couldn't call it because we're
in a stateless widget but that's not required here. To prove that it worked here when we press that
add transaction button, I will print the title input, so the value we stored in there and also the amount
input. Let's save all of that and again, you can't ignore this yellow black thing here at the bottom,
I will explain what's up with that later
and for the moment, we can enter some amount here, like 12.99
and here, we can enter a title like test and you could use your physical keyboard for this too.
If you then hit add transaction, you see test and 12.99 output here because these values were saved
with every keystroke and therefore, we can also use them,
the only thing we can't do right now is update our user interface based on that. Registering the input
on every keystroke is perfectly fine,
however here Flutter actually complains or gives us a warning that this MyHomePage class, which is
marked as immutable,
that's basically a flag the stateless widget sets, has a field, a property which changes or which is
not final and that's true, title input and amount input are not final,
they can change and actually the case we have here is a pretty niche case.
Normally you don't have changeable properties in a stateless widget because you can't update the UI based
on these changes anyways.
This is one of the rare cases where we save some data and where we are perfectly fine with that having
no direct impact on the user interface.
Still, you might consider using a stateful widget here to get rid of that extra warning and to avoid
using or writing suboptimal code,
though technically this would work here and it also wouldn't be a horrible mistake.
Now we'll have a problem
anyways, I of course don't just want to print my results here,
I want to create a new element or a new transaction
and that in the end should then almost lead to some output on the screen because transactions, our list
here should then actually change and hold that new transaction,
so we'll have to switch to a stateful widget some point anyways. Before we do so
however, let me first of all show you an alternative to registering this manually on every keystroke.
Whilst you can do this
and whilst this is especially useful if you have more complex logic that you maybe want to run on every
keystroke, Flutter actually has a built-in mechanism that allows you to listen to every keystroke and
then get the finished value once you're done.
For that, I'll comment out the title input and amount input and I'll add two new properties which now are
final
and that is the title controller, which is created with a value of text editing controller and it's the
amount controller which is also a text editing controller. Text editing controller is a class provided
by Flutter and you can assign such a controller to your text fields with the help of the controller
argument.
So now to the title text field, I add my title controller and to the amount text field here, I'll add
my amount controller.
Now what do these controllers do?
Flutter automatically connects the controllers with our text fields and these controllers in the end listen
to the user input and save the user input and therefore here in onPressed, we can then print title
controller.text to get access to that saved text. Hence
now if I go back and I type something here and I hit done and I then add transaction, I see test here.
So this is of course a more convenient way because you don't have to manually write a function that
takes a value and just saves it in a property and in addition as an extra benefit, this is now also a
solution because these properties are final and the heavy lifting of saving stuff is done by Flutter,
this is now a solution Flutter also likes in a stateless widget.
Nonetheless,
the days of us using a stateless widgets or at least of only using stateless widgets are coming to
an end because we will have to change this to a stateful widget in order to update our list of transactions
and reflect that change on the user interface, where of course for every new transaction, a new transaction
card should be output down there.