Now for this module, I'll again come back to this personal expenses planner
we wrote over the last course sections. We'll not add any new features to this application but we'll use it
as a dummy or as an application to explore a couple of under the hood things and a couple of advanced
things
as I mentioned in the introduction to this module. And the thing I want to start with is how Flutter
actually draws the content you're seeing here on the screen and what it really means
when I said that Flutter executes the build method because as you probably already noticed and as I already
mentioned, build gets executed relatively often and every widget in our application has a build method.
So does this mean that whenever build runs, Flutter actually redraws the entire screen and therefore,
running build is actually bad because as you can imagine, whenever Flutter has to really redraw the
screen and redraw the pixels on the screen and rebuild all your your widgets, your elements,
that sounds like a performance impact and actually, it would be. The good thing is Flutter doesn't redraw
or recreate the entire UI on every build call but let's simply have a look at what Flutter really does.
The first important thing to realize is that Flutter aims to give you a 60fps application, so it updates
the screen 60 times per second and that of course means that it does indeed redraw the pixels 60 times
per second.
Now this however is not bad,
that's how all apps and all the games that run at 60fps or more work
and of course also for lower FPS rates. In the end, the FPS measure really just means frames
per second and that means that the screen or what you see on the screen is repainted X amount of
times per second,
so in a 60fps application, that means 60 times per second.
Now this would only then become inefficient if Flutter would have to recalculate the entire layout here
60 times per second because when Flutter draws something onto the screen, for the first
time, when it draws it for the first time, it needs to figure out the position of every element, the color
of every element, the text of every element, so it needs to configure every single pixel on the screen. For
subsequent draws,
so for refreshes of the user interface, if nothing changed, Flutter takes the old information it already
derived and paints that on the screen which is super fast and very efficient.
So the refresh rate itself is not a problem,
it would only be a problem if Flutter would have to recalculate everything on the screen with every
refresh. And now that of course leads to the question, is that what's happening when build is called?
Does that mean that Flutter does have to re-build, recalculate this element and all its child elements?
For this, let's dig a bit deeper and understand what build really does.