Now for this approach of adding tabs, we of course wouldn't have needed a stateful widget here though,
a stateless widget would have done the trick because we're not managing any state. That will change when
we add tabs at the bottom because that simply works a bit different.
Why?
Well simply because the Flutter team wants it to work like this.
There, you won't use the default tab controller, instead
now we'll remove the default tab controller here and therefore return the scaffold in the TabsScreen,
that's where I am,
return the scaffold here,
remove the redundant parentheses, the closing parentheses
and now on that scaffold if you want to have tabs at the bottom, you don't add them here on the appBar,
so you get rid of that bottom argument here on the appBar where you added the TabBar, that's removed
and you also don't have a TabBar view as your body.
Let's ignore the body for now, I'll come back to that,
instead you will add a bottom navigation bar,
that's what a TabBar at the bottom is called
and for that, you have the bottom navigation bar widget which you can add, like this.
It's also built into Flutter and it adds a navigation bar at the bottom as the name suggests.
Now this navigation bar needs some configuration to look good and to work correctly,
for example you can set the background color of the bottom navigation bar and here, I'll use my primary
color for that,
so primary color like this.
Now of course, you also want to add your items here and items now are the tabs.
So items now are bottom navigation bar items and whilst the name sounds strange, that in the end is just
a tab.
Now just as the tabs we had before, you typically have an icon there which takes an icon widget which
then uses the icons collection here
so to say to select an icon and here I will use category and you assign a title which now is a widget
and not plaintext but typically here you use a text widget of course to set the text you want to display
on that tab
and here I'll have categories.
Now of course, we'll not just have one navigation bar item but two,
so let's add a second one and there,
I'll use the star icon and say favorites as a text.
Now we have two bottom navigation bar items in our bottom navigation bar
and now comes the part
that is the biggest difference compared to the tabs we added at the top below our appBar. For
the bottom navigation bar,
you manually have to control what the user selected and which content you want to display.
So for that on the bottom navigation bar itself, you register an onTap listener and that is triggered whenever
an item is selected. Now onTap should execute a method
and I'll add a new method here,
of course you could always use an anonymous function if you wanted to but I'll use a method here which
doesn't return anything which I'll name select page, _selectPage because we're in a private
class here and select page here will receive the index automatically that's passed into this method
by Flutter, of the tab that was selected. So we now bind _selectPage to onTap and that tells
Flutter that select page should be executed when a tab is selected
and as I just said, Flutter will then automatically give you the index of the selected tab, so that you know
if it was the first or the second or the third or whatever you have tab. Now you know what was selected
but now you need to control what's displayed and for that, you should manage your own list of widgets
which you want to render. So for that,
I'll add a new property, a list of widgets up there and I'll name that pages, _pages, you can name
this whatever you want and in there,
I want to have the two, in my case in this app here, two widgets which should be shown
and that's of course the categories screen which I want to create here
and that's of course the favoritesScreen which I want to create
and I just noticed that the import for the favoritesScreen is not in the format I wanted,
so let me quickly fix that,
okay.
So now we have that pages list here with the two pages I want to have
and we can set this to a final list of course because I'm not going to change that
and now one other piece of information is which page was selected because this is basically giving us
the data we want to use
but we also need to know which data to use.
So I'll add another property, not a final one though, an integer which is selected
page index which is 0 initially let's say
and here in _selectPage, in this method, I call set state
and now here that's why we need a stateful widget because we will manually switch that index and we
want to update what's shown on the screen whenever that happens because we want to switch the widget
that is displayed.
So here in set state,
I'll set selected page index equal to the index I'm getting as an argument here,
so equal to the index of the tab that was clicked.
So with that we can now use the pages and the selected page index here to display a content in our
body
because in the body we can now use pages
and that's a list and there we simply access the selected page index like that. And remember, pages
is simply a list of widgets, instantiated widgets.
So we do
output our widget here then in the body depending on which tab was selected.
Let's give it a try and let's restart this application and now we see one tab here, if I click on it,
indeed we go to the favorites and if I click on the left here, indeed I also see that other tab here,
it's just having the same color as the background.
So we'll have to do some styling but in general, it works,
in general we can switch between our tabs here at the bottom.
So let's now work on the styling,
so on that bottom navigation bar, we set the background color for the overall bar.
You can also set the unselected
item color and set that to colors white for example. If you do that and you restart the application, you
indeed see that now favorites is at least a bit easier to see but still, one problem we have is that
when I select it, somehow it's not treated as selected, the other one does not get visible and the
selected item would be nice to see anyways.
So back in our configuration, we can of course also add a color to the selected item with selected item
color and there I want to use my accent color, that setup in the theme. If I save this, now categories
is a bit more visible because now we have that yellow look.
Now still it would be nice if favorites would actually be marked as active when I click on it though
and for that, you need to pass some additional information to the bottom navigation bar. Since you managed
the selection manually, you manage the tabs manually,
you need to feed that information which tab is selected back into the bottom navigation bar and that's
done by setting the current index.
This tells the bottom navigation bar which tab is actually selected.
So here, I set this equal to selected page index of course
and now with that, we can actually switch here and we do see changes
and you see you get a nice little effect here automatically where the font size also increases when
you select an item. You can of course also control that effect here with selected font size and
with and unselected font size, set these two equal and you will see no change in font size. One other
effect you can add to these tabs here is you can set the type of that bottom navigation bar and you
can set this to bottom navigation bar type shifting. If you set that to shifting, you see the style changed
and now we have a nice animation here though.
Now when you have a shifting bottom bar, you simply need to style a couple of other arguments or with
the help of a couple of other arguments to get the same look we had before. When using type shifting,
then you actually need to style your bar items on the bottom navigation bar item itself by giving that a
background color which now could be your primary color here and of course do that on both bottom navigation
bar items and with that, they have their background color back because now every item needs to be styled
separately and with that, you can also use this shifting set up where you have no labels on the
unselected item and only see them on the selected items
here with that little effect.
Now it depends on what you prefer,
I'll not use shifting here,
instead I'll either reset it to fixed but that's the default so I'll just comment that out and therefore
just go with
the static approach here where we have these tabs and that's the other way of adding tabs. Here
we control the indexes on our own,
what's the same as with the tabs in the appBar however is that the content we display here is essentially
now just an embedded widget
I still call these widgets, the favoritesScreen and the CategoriesScreen, screens because they control
the majority of the screen, the main content but they don't control the entire screen anymore,
for example the appBar and the TabBar of course importantly is now controlled by our TabsScreen.
Now if you navigate here, of course you still have the same behavior as before though
but on that overview screen, you now have the tabs. To finish this off,
let's make sure we also change the title up there though depending on which tab was selected. You can
do that here in the TabsScreen by simply tweaking our pages list a little bit. Instead of just storing
a list of widgets,
why don't we store a list of maps here where we have string keys and then we have dynamic values, which
means we don't know the exact type or object values which also basically means we don't know which kind
of object
and therefore now here, we have maps where we have a page key that holds our widget but where we also
have a title key which holds the title we want to show in the appBar and that could be categories here
and for the other widget, we also have page of course but then here, we have title and there, we could
say your favorites and close that of course as well.
And now with that, we have our list of maps up there
and when we now select a page here in the body, we of course don't output the pages, selected page index
because that would be a map but instead on that map, we access the page key because the page key is in
our map
what holds the widget
and we now can also use the title here in our appBar title. Instead of having hardcoded meals here,
we can use the pages property, access the selected page index and then there, the title key which holds
our string title.
And with that if we save this and this restarts, we now have a setup where if you watch title at the
top,
this title changes as I switch the tabs.
So this is how you could also update the title dynamically and of course, you can store any data you
want in this map.
So if you also would want to add some action buttons dynamically to the appBar, you could add an actions
key here which holds your list of widgets which are all the flat buttons or whatever you have you
want to add as action widgets in the appBar. So you can really add whatever you want here and then
therefore load the data and use the data down there that you need to load and use based on the selected
tab.