The app we built thus far works but there is one thing which we can change or which I at least want
to have you think about. On the orders screen,
we change this to be a stateful widget simply because I wanted to use initState here
and by the way as I mentioned in a couple of annotations at the top of the video during the videos, if
you are using listen: false as we're doing it here, you don't even need that hack and you would be
fine running that code without that future delayed around it. So you could actually get rid of all of
that,
of course you then can't use await though because you're not in an async function and
turning this into an async function is not what you should do
but of course you could then use then here to run your code that should run once the future is complete,
so you could move that set state call here into here and this first set state call is obsolete
because we don't need that,
this will run before build runs without that future delayed work around.
So we can just set isLoading to true, then have this here and this will work as well
if you use listen: false here and that's also the difference to ModalRoute.of and so on which didn't work
here in initState, there we simply don't have such a listen option.
The provider package simply internally gives you an option to opt out of certain functionalities that
would normally be connected with the inherited widget and this tunnel which is established with the
help of context and with these missing features which you deliberately opt out of with listen: false,
you can use provider of context here because you basically use only a limited set of the features of
that inherited widget thing behind the scenes. So you could do that here, you could do this in all places
with provider of,
you can't use listen: false on things like ModalRoute and so on, that's not supported there but that's
not the main thing I wanted to focus on, it's just something I again wanted to mention here.
The core thing I wanted to mention is that we are building a stateful widget here simply such that
we can use initState to initialize our data and I think that makes sense because we want to have a
place in our app where we can make that call which only runs once when this screen gets rendered.
For example making that fetch in the build method would be horrible because that method runs way too
often
and actually, we would even enter an infinite loop if we start calling set state in there or if we then
fetched our orders and build runs again and we start fetching again and so on,
so making the fetch and build certainly is not an option.
There is however an alternative to turning this into a stateful widget and using initState and
it's that alternative which I now want to show you.
So let me comment this out here in initState and therefore we have an empty initState method which
we of course could also remove,
now let me show you that alternative. Here in that body, in the end, the content we render depends on the
question whether we're still fetching data or whether we already got a response, right?
So what we can do here is we can use a special widget which is built into Flutter and that's the future
builder widget. The FutureBuilder widget takes a future and then automatically starts listening to that,
so it adds the then and the catch error methods for you
you could say and it takes a builder which will get the current snapshot, the current state of your future,
so that you can build different content based on what your future returned.
So here, we can set up a future and our future of course is the future returned by provider of fetch
and set orders. So we can copy that line here and then go down here and configure that as the future
because fetch and set orders of course does return a future.
So that's the future for our FutureBuilder,
now with the future set up, we also have to define a builder and that's a builder as you generally already
know it,
it's a function which gets executed on your behalf. It receives the context and here, you also receive
an extra argument and that's the data currently returned by your futures,
so a data snapshot
you could say. This should then return the widget you want to build and now the widget you want to build
of course simply depends on the state of that future.
So let's actually use the more complex or the longer function definition without that arrow so that
we can write a multiline function body
and here, we can first of all have a look at the data snapshot to find out what's in there.
The data snapshot here is of type async snapshot
and if you add a dot after it, you see that there you can find out if you have an error object or the
data which you retrieved and also what the current connection state is and that tells you what the future
is currently doing.
You can compare this to connection state and for example there, you can find out whether it's currently waiting,
so where the future hasn't resolved yet or whether it's done and when it's done, you will have to check
whether you've got data or an error.
So here, we can check if data snapshot connection state is currently equal to connection state waiting
which means we're currently loading.
So in that case, of course I want to return this centered widget here, so I will return this here,
else I know we're done
and then you could check if data snapshot error is equal to null, in which case you know you have no error
or the other way around if it's not equal to null in which case you have an error and then you want to
do error handling stuff here, which I'll not do here
but which you could do. Alternatively, else you know you have no error
and then here, I want to return that ListView.
So let's get rid of that down there now,
we don't need isLoading anymore.
So here I'll just return the ListView.builder and in case we should have an error,
I'll just return a centered widget with a child where I say text, an error occurred, just to have something
on the screen and return some widget
in that case
but I focus on the success case and here we return our ListView
builder with the order data which should now be available because we're done fetching our orders.
Now one important note about this setup though, right now, we would enter an infinite loop here because
when this is done fetching and setting the orders, it will notify listeners
and since we set up a listener to orders here, our whole build method would run again,
we would build a new FutureBuilder here and send a new request and that would keep on going.
So the solution here is to not set up that listener up here for the order data because we don't need
the order data up there but simply use a consumer of the order data in here,
in that case here because only here, I'm interested in order data.
So here we can set up a consumer of our orders where we in the end define a builder where we get the context
and our order data then and now here it is where I actually want to render that ListView because that's
now the place where we actually need our orders and where we want to set up a listener and
important of course here, you have
the third argument, that static child which never changes which you could use.
Now we should have a setup which actually works and fetches our orders without entering an infinite
loop
and just to check this, I'll also add a print statement here in the build method,
building orders.
So this should now not run all the time
and let's now see whether that works.
So here, I'll go to my orders,
we see the spinner, we see the orders and back here, we see that this was only executed once and this
is now the more elegant alternative to using a stateful widget just to fetch orders and show a loading
spinner
and the advantage is also that we don't just save that useless transformation to a stateful widget,
we also don't have to manage the loading state on our own because we're letting the FutureBuilder do
that by checking the connection state.
So now what we can do here of course is we can get rid of initState and of this isLoading property,
get rid of our state class and convert this here back to a stateless widget as it was before and now
this is a very lean widget
of course and we can do a hot refresh to have the same application as before
but now with a more elegant setup for our orders. And obviously, you could use such a FutureBuilder as
we're using it here in your other widgets too, either to turn them back into stateless widgets or if you
had reasons for making them stateful widgets, even in such cases, to not manage the isLoading variable
on your own but instead, let the FutureBuilder do that.
I'll leave that here and I'll also leave the other approaches in this app, so that you can see and check
both but using the FutureBuilder is definitely the approach I would recommend because it's so elegant
and it utilizes the tools Flutter gives you. As a side note,
it of course also avoids rebuilding this entire widget tree here just because the loading state changed,
instead it will really just rebuild the parts that do need rebuilding,
so that's another benefit we get here.