So we added our tabs in our drawers
but what we mostly did thus far is we went forward.
I showed you how to go to new pages, obviously because that is an important part
but sometimes you also need to go back programmatically, so not just through that back button which is
added automatically but because something happened and sometimes you also need to pass some data back
to the previous page.
Let's imagine here when we're on the recipe detail page, we want to have a button that actually allows
us to delete this recipe, not permanently but only such that we go back and in that list of recipes, we
don't see it anymore,
maybe because we were in a list with a couple of recipes, we checked out this one,
we didn't like it and we want to go back but we don't want to see this one for now.
When we then go back and go back here, we would see it again but temporarily, I want to get rid of it.
Of course that's a bit of a made up use case but it's a good use case for showing how you can go back
manually in code and how you can pass data around.
So for that on the recipe detail or on the meal_detail_screen here, let's make sure that we have some
button to go back and delete this recipe and I think a floating action button is a good fit here.
So I'dd a floating action button, a new floating action button widget therefore and as a child, I'll just
set
an icon here, the delete icon, this trash bin here
and when we now press this button, so onPressed, that's the interesting part, there.
I want to go back.
Now you can go back with help of the navigator and there not with push but with pop.
Now we also saw pop before in the course and of course you need to use of context here
by the way, we saw pop before in the course to close our modal bottom sheet for example. Pop removes screens
that are on top of the stack and things like dialogs or this modal bottom sheet are behind the scenes
also managed as screens, only though they only make up a part of the overall device screen
but still they are treated as overlays to the current page and therefore can be popped off to remove
them
and the same is true for entire screens, like we have them here.
So pop removes a screen, if I just call it like this,
watch what happens when I click this floating action button, I'm taken back, that happens.
So it's the same as if the user would press this back button here or on Android, this back button down
there.
Pop can be very useful if you have something in your code that requires you to go back or to remove
a dialog or some other overlay from the screen in code.
Now besides pop here, you also have popAndPushNamed which does just what it says,
it pops the current page off and thereafter, it pushes a new named page.
You also can check with can pop whenever there actually is a page to pop, for example if you navigated
to a page with push replacement, then you replaced the existing page in the stack
and therefore popping the new page wouldn't be possible because there would be no page to go to,
right
because you replaced the existing page. So running can pop to check whether you actually can go back
before you do call pop might be a good idea if you're not sure whether you have another page in
your app. Here,
we of course can be sure and therefore we can call pop like that.
So this takes us back but what if I now want to exclude that recipe we're coming from in my meals overview
here after going back? For that, we can also pass some data to pop. Passing data is optional but here, you
can pass any data you want, a map, a list, a string, a number, an object, whatever you want
and here I want to pass my
meal ID here. So down there, I will forward meal ID or backward
so to say, meal ID to the page we're it coming from.
Now on the page we're coming from, the question of course is how do I get that information?
Well the place where we pushed this page, this MealDetailScreen, is the meal item. There we have
select meal and there I have navigator of pushNamed. This pushNamed method led to the meal detail
screen being displayed.
Now this pushNamed method returns a so-called future, I mentioned futures earlier in the course already.
Futures are objects that allow you to specify a function that should execute once they're done with
a certain operation and one such possible operation, in this case it is the operation at hand, is displaying
the page you're going to. So MealDetailScreen is the page that is displayed when pushNamed is done.
Now once the user goes back from MealDetailScreen, pushNamed is fully done with its operation because
then it has not just displayed that screen but the screen is now also not needed anymore.
So the future return by pushNamed lets you know once the page that you push to is not displayed anymore.
So you can add then here to get that result, this page you are coming from gives you.
So if you're passing any result to the pop method as we are doing it here, then you get that result here
in the function you pass to then and for now I'll just print it.
And that's really important because it's easy to
think that this function here is executed
once you reached the new page right because you push a named page and then once this pushing is done
and once you see the page, this function executes but that's wrong.
Instead you push a page and when this page is popped, then this function here is executed and then therefore,
you get the result that might have been passed to pop. So for now, I'm just printing that result, let's
see whether that works. If I go here to my spaghetti and I click this trash icon, we're popping and indeed
here I see m1 which was the ID of that meal. If I go to the spaghetti and I use this back button
here, then I see null because that still trigger this function we did pop after all, using the back button
does nothing else than use navigator of context pop but of course there, no data is passed along.
So now here, we would have to find out whether we have a non-null value and if we do, then I want to remove
that meal from the list of meals that is displayed.
The problem with that of course is that I'm here in the meal item. The solution can be that in the meal
item in the constructor, I get one extra argument which is required and I want to bind this to a variable,
a property here which is of type function
and that's the remove item function and I bind to remove item here
and now I can call remove item down there if result is not null.
So if result is not equal to null, then I know I have an ID of an item I want to remove
and then we can call it remove item and forward result which will be that ID. Now remove item is a
function
I expect to get in the meal item,
so in the category_meal_screen where we setup that meal item widget, we now have to pass such a function
and that of course means we first of all have to create one.
Now it's a stateless widget which will be a problem because now I suddenly want to change it's state,
I want to change the meals which I display.
So let's first of all convert this into a stateful widget with the refactoring tool here and then
here in the state class, we can add a new function which returns nothing but which I'll name remove meal
where I expect to get a meal ID and then here, I want to update my meals and remove a meal with that
ID from the list. For that first of all, we have to make sure that we don't derive our meals here in
the build method but actually a bit earlier and initState sounds like a great place for that.
That's a perfect use case for initState because when this page gets loaded, when that state gets
created, then we want to load all meals that are based on the ID of the category we're getting.
So all that code here for deriving our meals can be cut out of the build method and be moved here into
initState.
One important thing however is of course that I now need to add a couple of properties here, a string
property category title which is mutable, so which is not final and a list of meals which are my category
or my displayedMeals here
and for that,
we need to import the meal model, so let's import meal.dart from the models folder. With these two
properties added, here where I derive my category title, I do this without final so that we actually use
this property and store the value there and here for category meals, instead here I'll set my displayed
meals with the same logic as before.
We don't need to call set state here because this will automatically run before build runs the first
time and now we'll load data when this component or when this widget is created and we can therefore
now also manipulate our data and update the user interface because we're in a stateful widget now.
So here with remove meal, I'll call set state and I now want to remove an item from displayedMeals.
So I'll reach out to the displayedMeals here and then use remove where which will remove all items that
fit or match a certain criteria and that will get a function that runs on every item in displayedMeals
and there I check if meal.id is equal to the meal ID I got
and if it's equal, then this item will be removed,
like this.
It's in set state so displayedMeals will update or it will update but this will also update the view
and now here instead of using category meals in all these places, we just use displayedMeals.
Now we can also forward a reference of remove meal of that function we added here to meal item.
So there, we have to add remove item argument it expects and there I pass a reference, a pointer at
_removeMeal. If we do a full restart because we turned this into a stateful widget, that typically requires
a full restart,
let's go here and now we get a problem.
The problem is that this call here which I'm doing here with modal route of is not liked in initState
because this taps into this behind the scenes context setup with the inherited widget and so on, all this
behind the scenes wire up work
and this does not work here because context generally is thankfully a property that's globally available
in our state object but not inside of initState because initState runs too early, it runs before
our widget has been created or fully created
and before we have a context for our widget.
So at this point of time, I can't retrieve my route data unfortunately.
Now what's the solution for that or how can we work around that?
There is another lifecycle hook which I haven't mentioned before and that's didChangeDependencies.
You don't reuse that that often but here it's really useful because this will be triggered essentially
whenever the references of the state change,
which also means it will be called when the widget that belongs to the state has been fully initialized
and we can tap into context,
this will still run before build runs.
So in here, I can now put my code which I had in initState, initState would have been great if
we wouldn't have required to use modal route of context in here,
so any of context stuff which you need to do in here will unfortunately not work but in
didChangeDependencies, it should work.
So now if we do a full restart,
this looks way better and we go here into quick and easy,
this looks better and now if I delete this here, still there. Reason for that is that
didChangeDependencies runs a couple of times after the initialization of that state,
that's the difference to initState of course.
It runs whenever the dependencies of this state change and that's also the case when the attached widget
changes, which unfortunately is the case when we call set state here.
So the state we set here where we do delete a meal is basically overwritten when didChangeDependencies
runs again and we basically load all meals again. A way around that is to simply leave a little mark
that tells us that we are done initializing.
So here we can add a bool, loadedInitData and initially that's false
and of course therefore we don't have to use bool here, we can use var here
and here at the end,
I will set loadedInitData equal to true and now here before we run that code, I'll check if
loadedInitData is equal to false or actually the shortcut for that,
you could use that but the shortcut is that you simply add an exclamation mark in front of this.
So if this is false,
if we haven't loaded the initial data yet, then I will run this code so I'll move all of that, including
my change here to true inside of this if statement and therefore this code will now really only run
for the first time.
So with that if we now do a full reload, we should have the behavior we want,
this app reloads now and then here when we go to a recipe and we declare it,
you see it's now gone from that list, if I do the same for toast hawaii,
that's also gone.
If I go back and then go again back to quick and easy, they are all back here because once we click
the back button here on our list of meals, this page is totally dumped and removed and the state object
is cleared
therefore and hence the next time we click on a category and go back into that list of meals, a brand
new page, a brand new widget and a brand new state object is created and therefore, we again start with
loadedInitData set to false.
So that whole loadedInitData part and didChangeDependencies is a little bit of overhead
we had to add here for this specific use case where we depend on the ID we get through modal route
of context.
The core takeaway nonetheless is that you can pass data around when you're popping by passing the data
you want to pass back to the pop method and then you can retrieve it with the then method on pushNamed
or push or whatever you used and the function in here runs
not when you're done pushing but when you're done with that page you pushed to,
so when that page you pushed to is removed, that's really important.
So a lot of work here but I find it important to also understand how you can pass data back and use
that data and the additional knowledge of didChangeDependencies and how to initialize your data in
a stateful widget, that also can't hurt.