So now that we're passing data back and forth, let's populate our pages with more life and let's start
with the filters for that,
so that we can set some filters here on the FiltersScreen which actually impact the meals we see here
on the other screens,
so that for example when I set my filter to vegetarian, I don't see the hamburger because if you check
the dummy data, all these meals should be set up such that for example if we search for the hamburger there,
the classic hamburger, it has the isVegan and isVegetarian flags set to false,
so we should not see that if we have a filter to exclude non-vegetarian food. So let's go to the filters
screen and work on it. As a first step,
we can convert the FiltersScreen to a stateful widget because actually, we'll have to manage which
filters the user set or not. We'll also manage that globally in the main.dart file later
but we also need to manage it in this screen to update the values we show on thes switches
we're going to show on the screen. So here in my FiltersScreen state,
I'll start by initializing four boolean properties, gluten free which initially is set to false, vegetarian
which initially is set to false, vegan which initially is set to false and also lactose free which is initially
set to false,
we'll need that data later on.
Now let's go down to our body here and in that body, I think it makes sense to have a column because
we'll have multiple switches that should be shown above each other
and therefore here of course, we'll register a couple of children. As a first child,
I'll add a container where I essentially want to set up some padding with EdgeInsets.all 20 and then
add a child which is just some text that tells us that we can adjust our meal selection here,
so we say adjust your meal selection. We can also give this text some style of course
and for that here, I'll here use my default title text theme here. So that's the container that simply
displays a title, below that title,
I now want to have all these switches and we can actually use a ListView here, since we're in a column
however, we can't add a ListView like this,
instead we would have to add a container or what we can also do, we can take expanded, if you remember
that's a widget which will ensure that its child widget takes up as much space as it can get in the
surrounding column or row,
so it will take all the remaining space between container and the end of the screen. So we can use
expanded here and add our ListView in there
and now since I have a fixed amount of elements here, I'll not use the builder constructor but the children
argument here in the normal ListView constructor and now there is a specific ListTile which we can
use here which looks really good and that's the switch ListTile. Again that's built into Flutter, we
haven't used that before,
it works really well in a list and allows us to show a switch with some text next to it. The switch list
tile requires a title and I'll set the title here to a text widget where I say gluten free,
that's my first switch.
Then we need to add a value, that is, just as for the normal switch which you already learned about, there to
tell Flutter in which state this switch should be because it doesn't manage that state internally, we
have to manage that.
Now that's why I added these booleans, we'll change these when the user clicks the switches and we'll
pass the data back into the switch then to update what's shown on the screen.
So here, I'll set the value to gluten free, _glutenFree. We can also add a subtitle if we want
to with another text widget where we say only include gluten free meals to make it really clear what
this switch does.
Now of course, we also need an onChanged listener, so a function that executes when the user taps this
switch and there, we get the new values,
so the new value the switch should have after being tapped and therefore in here, we can now use set state, hence
the stateful widget where I set my gluten free boolean equal to new value, to reflect the change the
user made here. If we save that and we go to the filters page here,
this is what we see
and I can now use that switch which is pretty neat.
Now of course, we don't just have gluten free meals,
we have a couple of other switches.
Now I'll repeat this ListTile a couple of times and therefore, we can of course extract this into a
separate widget or put it into a builder method and I'll go for the good old builder method here which
returns a widget, _buildSwitchListTile sounds like a fitting name, return
the widget and we need a couple of pieces of information here,
we need the title text, we need the description text for the subtitle basically and we need to get a
boolean value which is the current value
and I want to get a function which updates the value, so update value, something like that. The title is
then what I use here in my title text widget, the subtitle text widget here takes the description,
here for onChanged, I'll point at update value and the value we pass to value here should be the current
value.
Now when we call
_buildSwitchListTile down there,
we therefore have to pass all that information.
So here, that was gluten free, here I said only include gluten free meals,
current value is our gluten free boolean and the update value function is what I cut out of my
old switch list tile,
so it's this function here where we call set state and update gluten free. So it's not much shorter but
a little bit
and now we can use that _buildSwitchListTile method and repeat it to also here build a switch tile
for lactose free to only include lactose free meals and of course therefore the current value we pass in
is lactose free and set state should update to lactose free value here. Then we add another list tile,
here we're talking about vegetarian food, so only include vegetarian meals, we pass the vegetarian boolean
in as a current value and that's also what we of course update when the user clicks the list
tile. And then here last but not least, we have the vegan ListTile, only include such meals and then
here therefore, we pass in the appropriate boolean property. If we save all of that and we go back, this
is what we have and now here, we can set all these switches. Setting it here of course is nice, that should
now also be reflected back into our meals and that means we have to wire up what we set here with what we
output here in meals.