We need a drawer to switch between our orders screen and our products screen here, our ProductsOverviewScreen
and I want to use the same drawer in both widgets and
therefore I'll add a new widget which I'll name app_drawer
but of course you can name this however you want. In there,
I'll have a stateless widget, app drawer and as always, import material.dart.
Now it's totally up to you how you build that drawer,
it typically should use to drawer widget though with which Flutter ships because that gives you the
general look and the background, the overlay effect and so on,
so that is something you should use
but what you have in there, that's totally up to you.
Now here I'll add a column with a couple of children, a couple of child widgets and one thing I will add
here which we haven't done before and therefore it's absolutely no problem if you didn't do that,
there is no way you could have known that,
I will add an appBar in here.
You could also build your own complex container as we did in the navigation section
but to save some time, I'll add an appBar in here with a title where I say hello friend, whatever you
want and important, I'll add automaticallyImplyLeading and set it to false.
What this does is simply means it will never add a back button here because that wouldn't work in here
and therefore, it should never display one,
even if it thinks that you can go back, it shouldn't show one. So that's the topmost widget in my column here,
below that I'll add a divider,
this nice little horizontal line and then add a ListTile which is an entry in that drawer. The first list
tile will get a leading element or a leading widget which is an icon widget with an
icon of the shop
icon here because it should lead us back to our ProductsOverview page.
So here, I'll add a title of shop because that is indeed where we will go.
Now on tapping this, I want to use my navigator
and indeed go back to the root route which is just slash if you remember, pushReplacementNamed is correct
then.
So I just want to go back to the root route to MyHomePage so to say. Now I'll repeat that pattern of
having a divider and a ListTile and the second ListTile here actually gets a payment
icon because that should take me to my orders. So there, I'll say orders and that will go to
a new name which we have to add to the orders screen.
So on the orders screen there, we can add a static const routeName which could be just /orders for
example, as always this name is totally up to you
but now assigning this name here in the orders screen allows us to use it here when we push to it
and of course for that, we have to register it here in the main.dart file too.
So let's start with registering this, let's import that screen from the screens folder, the orders screen
and now in the routes table, in our main.dart file there, we can use the OrdersScreen.routeName as the key
and then here, we'll build that orders screen, like this and we can also now use it in the drawer.
So in the drawer
indeed, I now want to import from the screens folder my orders screen, so that I can use its routeName
here.
So when I want to push to it, here I use OrdersScreen.routeName.
So this is it,
this is what I want to add to the drawer for now,
yours very likely looks totally different but that's fine too of course
and now let's use the drawer,
that's the interesting part of course in the ProductsOverviewScreen and the orders screen. In the
ProductsOverviewScreen, here we have the appBar and below the appBar, before the body maybe but the
order doesn't matter here,
I add my order and I refer to my AppDrawer which is that new widget I worked on, which you have to import
here therefore.
Now my IDE added it but not in the way I want it.
So let me use a relative path there,
go to the widgets folder and import app drawer
and with that imported, we got it here.
Let's do the same in the orders screen, there
on the orders screen, I also want to add the drawer here
and for that, add an import to this newly added widget, the app_drawer.dart file here in the order screen
so that we can render it here. With that, if we do a full refresh, we see that drawer
icon here and we can go to orders, we can go back to the shop. And if I
now add items here to the cart and I click order now, if I then go to my orders, indeed here I see information
about that order.
We can now also expand this but this doesn't work yet,
so this is the next piece of functionality I want to add of course and I also want to add some slashes
here in the date,
let me actually do that first real quick, in the order item here, add slashes, like this and you can also
switch month and day if that's more convenient to you of course.