Now let's start with the responsiveness and for that, if we have a look at this application,
I would say on phones, this looks and feels pretty good.
We have the overall scrollability here on our general page and we can scroll this ListView here which is
also nice.
Now we face a problem
however as soon as we rotate this. In landscape mode, the general look and feel might be okay, though
you could argue that maybe we can shrink the width of this chart a little bit,
maybe it doesn't need to stretch the full width of our device here and we certainly face a problem with
the list down there.
I can kind of scroll the list here but if I scroll the overall page which I can also do, then I actually
can scroll the list but I have a hard time getting to my chart, I actually can't scroll up anymore because
my list occupies the full page and that by the way stems from our setting here in the transaction list
where I give that container with the list a fixed height. This fixed height,
if you remember, was fine tuned to work really well on portrait mode and therefore here on portrait mode,
we have no problem with it because this container with the list kind of fits nicely at the bottom of
our overall height of the screen and therefore we can scroll both the list and the general page. If we
go into landscape mode,
that changes because now the container with the list still has a height of 450 which is too high,
it stretches below the boundaries or outside of the boundaries of our device because we have
less height available in landscape mode and therefore, since this container has a fixed height and this
transaction list is in the end just part of our overall column which has a SingeChildScrollView,
we can scroll our general page to bring that 450 high container into view
but as soon as this container is inside of the view, we can scroll the list items in there because in
our transaction list container, we have a ListView which is always scrollable but then we have no
handle to scroll the overall page because wherever we're clicking, we're just inside of the ListView,
we're scrolling the ListView and that's of course bad.
Now here a solution would be to restrict the general height of this container and calculate it dynamically
based on the size of the device we're running on and then we could also get rid of that overall
SingleChildScrollView because we could always size our chart and our transaction list such that they split
the available height and never need to be scrollable because neither the chart nor the list extends
out of our page view,
instead only the list itself then scrollable inside of that space we reserved for it. In case that's
not entirely clear what I mean,
we'll implement this in the next lectures.