So instead of manually managing our animation here with the listener, I still want to get rid of the controller
by the way but instead of manually managing the listener and calling set state and therefore running
the full build method here of that widget, of that auth card here for every change, we can fall back to
a built-in widget.
In the end, it's the container here which we want to change for every change in our animation or
for every frame on our screen so to say.
So here we can use another widget that's built into Flutter and that's the animated builder.
Now you know these builder widgets by now, we have the future builder
and we had other builders as well.
The idea always is that Flutter executes something for you and then rebuilds a part of the user interface,
a part of this widget tree when that something is done or when that something changes instead of the
entire widget tree
and here indeed, you give the animated builder and animation and that here would be our height animation
of course and you give it a builder function to decide what to re-render whenever that changes,
so in this case for every frame. In that builder here, you get build context and then also a child
widget and then you re-render a part of your tree.
In my case here I want to re-render that container and now something interesting will also happen
in a second.
I'll add this container in here and please note that I only cut the container until the child key here
because to the animated builder, you can also pass a child argument,
so besides animation and builder, you can pass in a child argument and that can be and a part of that
widget tree which should be nested into that widget tree you are rebuilding with builder which then
actually won't be rebuilt
and I covered this pattern earlier in the course already.
So for example at the moment, our form here and everything that's in the form,
so let me grab all of that,
that does not change when we animate the container.
So I want to pass this as an argument to child here on my animated builder like this
and then this is made available on this child
argument here which you could also name just ch to avoid confusion which is passed into that builder
function, passed automatically, so that's this static child I defined here and this is what I'll now set
up here as a child of the container which I animate.
So the thing inside of the thing which I animate will not be re-rendered on every frame and that's
of course far more efficient than re-rendering the entire widget tree, even if only the container changes.
Now in the container,
I still use height animation value height to change my height because that hasn't changed and I just
need to get rid of one extra
closing parentheses down there and now we should have the same effect as before but without manually
setting up a listener to the animation and behind the scenes also in a more efficient way because everything
inside of that container,
so the text form fields and the buttons and so on will not re-render for every frame, will not be rebuilt
for every frame but instead, only the container,
so the height therefore will change on every frame and that's more efficient than re-rendering everything
and we don't have to manually set up a listener for our animation. So animated builder is already a very
useful built-in widget Flutter ships with that helps us with efficiently controlling animations on a part
of our screen.