We had a look at some of the widgets we can use and at the widget catalog and of course throughout the course,
we'll use loads of the widgets you saw there,
so no need to learn it by heart right now. For the moment however, I want to move on by now also moving
my buttons here, my answer buttons into a separate widget, into a custom widget.
Maybe change the styling a little bit, maybe to give them a blue background and make them take the full
available width but that won't be the the focus here,
instead what I want to make sure is that
we have real text on these buttons, so that we have text that fits to the question we have here,
so that we continue working on this first basic application. And for this, let's create a new answer.dart
file which should hold the answer widget
and there we need to create a widget now.
Now you could think that you need to create a stateful widget now,
right
because here in main.dart, on a button we of course have that onPressed argument to which we pass a
pointer to the answer question function.
Now just because we register a function here for an event does not mean that the RaisedButton has to
be in a stateful widget.
Of course we want to change some data when this event fires, when the user presses the button
but as it turns out, we can also trigger a function in another place of the app even if this button lives
in a separate widget
and that is a core concept and a core pattern which you will use a lot in Flutter and therefore it's exactly
the pattern we'll dive in right now.
So here in the answer.dart file, I'll create a new stateless widget here actually and I will name
it answer
and just as in the question widget, we need to import the material file from the Flutter package because
that unlocks stateless widget and so on.
Now in here, I will leave the container because as a child of that container, I want to have my button
and I keep the container because that will allow me to control the width.
So here, the child is the RaisedButton here,
the text will soon be received from outside
and I'll come back to that and onPressed as I said should change something but will also make that
change in another widget and how that works is also something I'll show you in a second.
First of all, let's adjust the width and I'll set it to double infinity again, which is a helper property
on the double object.
Remember, everything in Dart is an object,
so are doubles and that is the core double type which at the same time is basically the class
for the double value you could say
and on this class we have an infinity property which basically gives us a value which tells the container
to take as much width as it can get, which is the width of our device.
So that's the width of the container,
now for onPressed I'll temporarily use null again so that we don't get an error and that we now can
use this button as it is.
I also want to set the color of the button here and I will set it to a color by accessing colors and
colors actually is a class which also has some so-called static properties,
these are properties which you can directly use on the class itself without instantiating it first
and there you have various preconfigured colors and I will simply use blue.
Now this can look strange because we haven't used that before, a static property in the end simply as
I said is a property which you can use without instantiating class.
If we have a look at the source code here, we see that the class here has these static const values, const
is something we haven't seen before,
let's ignore it for now, these static const values here, like black and then a different shade of black
and so on
and then if we scroll down, also different shades of white.
So these are simply properties, normal properties on the class,
the only difference is that you can access them without creating an instance of the class first and
such properties exist because we need that value here, right
and therefore, this is like a utility feature of Dart
you could say, that we can get easy access to such a value without having to create a new instance. Instances
of classes typically makes sense if you want to create multiple different objects based on one and the
same class.
Here of course we want to have multiple different colors but each color is just a value, like a
simple text or so on and therefore of course technically, it's also an object but we don't need
the complex colors object for that. Colors in
the end is just like a group of predefined single colors
you could say, so this colors class here exists not to be instantiated because colors itself, this object,
that doesn't do anything, it just exists as a grouping mechanism around preconfigured values. A little
bit like an enum but an enum simply gives numbers 0, 1, 2, a label, a human readable label. Here, the idea
is to have a human readable label for a more complex value you could say because the value here is not
just a number but actually the hex code or the binary representation of a color.
So that is what we're doing here, we're getting access to this static property here on the colors class
and this will give us the internal color value which Dart and Flutter can use to color this button
and with all of that, we can use the answer widget here in the main.dart file. For that,
let's first of all add an import,
you always need to import what you want to use in a file because since the answer widget lives in a
different file, in order to use it in the main.dart file, we have to import it there
and then with it imported, we can replace our RaisedButton here with answer
and now here of course we create concrete instances of our answer widget class because we want to create
widget objects, multiple different widget objects, which we can use here
and that should be an answer not answers here.
Now with that if we save this, we now have our buttons there. Now
they are greyed out because at the moment, they're all locked, disabled because I haven't assigned a real
function to onPressed and that will be the next step and here,
the tricky thing will be that this function which I want to assign here actually lives in the main.dart
file because that is where I manage my question index and I have to manage the question index there because
I also have my questions in here and I need to have my questions in here because I want to pass them
down to the question widget which has no direct connection to the answer widget. So we can't manage the
question index in the answer widget because if we would do that, then we would have the value in here
but then again we couldn't use it to select a question here which we want to forward to the question
widget.
So our main.dart file is the common denominator you could say, the shared widget between the answer and
the question widget because our main.dart file and the widget in there, the MyApp widget, that is the
parent widget of question and answer, it is the widget that instantiates and uses question and answer
and therefore we want to manage our state which both components need or which both widgets need, we want
to manage that state here in the MyApp component or in MyApp widget and therefore also in MyAppState
which is connected to that widget.
This concept is called lifting the state up, you manage the state on the shared, on the common denominator
of the different widgets that need this state and that is the direct parent of these widgets that need
the state.
So since we manage the state in here, we also have the function to change the state in here, in the MyAppState
class
but how do we now get access to the answer question function in our answer widgets here?
The answer is pretty simple. Just as we can pass text to a widget, we can also pass a pointer at a
function to a widget.
So answer question,
my function here can be forwarded to the answer widgets, without parentheses because I don't want to
execute my answer question function immediately when Dart reads this,
instead I want to forward the pointer at this function to my answer widget. And now in the answer widget,
we of course need to accept this as our argument to the constructor because the answer widget here, that
in the end is just a class right and
therefore it can have a constructor.
So here, we can add a constructor by repeating the class name and I'll use that shortcut for the constructor
and I will also add a property here,
a final property, the type now is function which is built into Dart and as the name suggests,
this means that the values stored in this property has to be a function or a pointer at a function
to be precise
and therefore here now, you can give this any name you want, I'll name this selectHandler, whatever you
want to name it
and in my answer constructor, I now store whatever I get here in selectHandler.
Now what I do get in here
in my answer constructor is a pointer at the answer question and this pointer is stored in this property.
in my answer class and function simply means that what is stored here has to be a pointer at a function.
And now since we have that pointer at a function, which is exactly what I need down there, I can use select
handler here. Again, without parentheses because the same thing as explained earlier still applies,
we don't want to execute this immediately and hence now we should have a setup where we can trigger
a function that's actually defined in a different widget from inside our answer widget because we pass
a reference to that function down to the answer widget here in our MyAppState. So with this set up,
we should be able to save this
and now if I press a button here, indeed our text here changes, which means that this communication
between parent and child works.