Now that we added this user interaction,
let's work on that new page which I wanted to add, a new page where we are able to manage our own products
and that of course means that we can add, edit and delete them there. For that,
we obviously need a brand new screen and that will be the user products screen, hence the file could be
named user_products_screen.dart
and it'll be a stateless widget with our user products screen widget in there or as
a name
and of course, we import material.dart from the Flutter package.
Now the idea on the user products screen is to show a list of all the products of the user
and for now, that will be all the products we have in this app.
Later once we added authentication and users, we'll be able to differentiate between products by user,
for now we only have one user who owns all the products
and I want to show a list of the products here and on every product, we should be able to edit or delete
it
and of course, I also want to have an option of adding a brand new product.
So since this will control the entire page, I'll add a scaffold here because I want to have
an appBar and I want it for the background color and so on and here on the appBar argument, I add the app
bar widget as we did it a couple of times already and we can add a title here which is a text widget
where we say your products or anything like that.
Now of course beside that, we also might want to have some actions here or namely at least one action,
a plus button which allows us to go to a new screen where we are able to add a new product.
So here, I will add an IconButton and that takes an icon as an argument, so an icon widget and the icon I want
to use from the icons package is the add icon.
Now of course, we also have to do something when this gets pressed and that something will be to navigate
to the new product screen,
we'll work on that in a second.
First of all, let's continue working here on this page and therefore in the body of that scaffold,
I now want to present that list of products in the end. I want to have a little bit of padding around
that, so I'll
first of all add a padding widget with a padding of EdgeInsets.all of 8 maybe,
of course that's always up to you
and then as a child in a padding, have a ListView. Now since we could theoretically have an infinite
amount of products, I'll use the ListView.builder here to have possible performance improvements for
longer lists
and you know to use that, we need an item count and we need an item builder. Now the item count
here of course should take the amount of products we have. Now for the moment, that simply are all the
products we have and we get them from our products provider, from our provided products object to be
precise.
So here, I want to set up a listener and therefore first of all, we need the provider package and there,
the provider.dart file
and then of course we need to get access to the products class and we get that from the providers folder
and there, products.dart.
With these two imports added, we can set up a listener here and we can get our products data here with
the help of provider of as we did it before in this course, where we then of course have to add this
generic annotation with the angled brackets and let the provider package know that we want to tap into
the products object, the nearest provided products object and get access to that.
So now we're storing that in products data and here, I also do want to listen of course because if we
for example delete a product, I want to rebuild that list and obviously of course, you could therefore
also use consumer and only wrap the ListView with that, instead of the entire widget because wrapping
the entire widget will rebuild the entire widget even if the appBar doesn't really depend on the products
but of course for one, you can work around this with a couple of const improvements here like this, then
these widgets will not get rebuilt because Flutter is able to detect that they can't have changed
and in addition, this is not too bad,
the majority of the page will rebuild, it won't hurt too much if that also rebuilds
but you could use consumer down there if you wanted to.
I'm using provider of here, get my product data and then with the product data, from there, the items
is my list of products,
so the length of that list determines how many items or how many list entries I want to render here.
The rendering then as you learned is done with the item builder of course and that gets the context which
I don't need here,
hence I add a blank, an underscore and then the index for which it's building that entry.
Now of course the question is, how should a single product look like?
Now we have our product item widget of course but that's a grid item and not the list item I want to
have here.
So I'll add a new widget here which will be a user product item
and that as so often will be a stateless widget, user product item and there, let's import material.dart
and now here, we can determine how a single item should look like in our list of items.
And as always, you are totally free to build this
however you want,
I will use the ListTile widget which is built into Flutter and there, set a title which should display
the name of the product.
So for that, let's say first of all define which information we want to get here in this widget from
outside and outside will be our user product screen here in the end. Well I definitely want the title,
I also want to show the image,
so I want to get the imageUrl here and that actually is already
all I need here I think.
So let's then add the constructor, user product item and set this either with positional or named arguments,
up to you
and then we can use the title down there in the title argument or in the title place on the ListTile
and I also want to add a leading widget or a leading entry here to the ListTile
and there
I want to use the CircleAvatar but now not to show some text but actually, to add a background image,
so an image that should be shown inside of that avatar and that will now be my
imageUrl.
Now here's something which we haven't done before,
background image does not take a widget but an image provider.
So it does not take Image.network which would build a new widget but instead, a provider that yields
a NetworkImage,
sounds strange but such providers are built into Flutter as well. Instead of Image.network,
you use NetworkImage, one name and one class.
Now of course, there are equivalents for asset image for example in case you have an image which is included
in your app.
Here we use NetworkImage
and that simply takes the URL as an input and the URL here of course is simply imageUrl.
Now on the NetworkImage, you can't set up a fit or anything like that because it's not a widget, it's in the
end just an object that does the fetching of the image and then forwards it to CircleAvatar through
that background image argument and CircleAvatar will do the sizing and so on to size the image into
itself.
So with that, we also add the image here. The missing piece is a place for us to interact with that item,
so edited or deleted
and for that, I'll add the trailing argument, I in the end want to have a row here because I'll have two
options and in that row, I'll add two icon buttons. The first button will show an icon which is an icon widget
which should be added icon which is this pen icon here
and when we press that, I in the end want to start editing this product.
The second IconButton uses the delete icon, this trash icon
and there of course unsurprisingly, I want to delete that product.
Now we can also set some colors for these icons and on the delete IconButton, I'll use theme of context
and then use my error color which is some red color and for the first button here, I'll use theme of
context and then simply the primary color.
Now let's use that user product item here in the user products screen widget.
So there, we first of all need to add an import where we go to the widgets folder and then
user_product_item.dart
and then here, let's create a user product item widget.
Now here we need to forward the title and the imageUrl because these are the two arguments we expect
here in our user product item widget
and of course we get that from productsData.items which are our products for the index for which
this list item is being built
and then here, simply access the title and of course do the same here for the imageUrl
and with that, we're building a user product item there.
Now we just need to be able to go to that user products screen and I again want to use named routing
for that,
so I'll add the good old static const routeName here where I say or where I have user products,
/user-products as a name, as always this is totally up to you
and we can now register this here in the main.dart file. For that, let's import screens/user_products_screen
and let's then go down to the route table and use the user_products_screen.routeName as a key
and then we have that builder created by Flutter or called by Flutter which builds a user products screen
widget
and now we can navigate to that
and of course I want to add an entry in my drawer for that.
So in the app drawer, I'll simply copy a ListTile with a divider above it and add it after the last ListTile
here, after the orders ListTile. Here I'll say manage products
and maybe use the added
icon here as well next to it
and then here, we of course don't go to the order screen but instead, we import the user product screen
from screens here and then navigate to that by using user_product_screen.routeName, so not by instantiating
it but by using the routeName
constant here. Back in the application, now we see that new entry here in side drawer and if we tap it,
then we're taken to that user product screen.
Now what's obviously missing here however are our products and also a way to go back,
so a side drawer. Now let's have a look, what's wrong about the products here.
We're getting an error and the error I'm getting seems to be related to sizing, the sizing of something
and actually that should be a problem here in the user products item widget, in that row of icon buttons,
this row takes as much space as it can get and trailing the place where we insert this into the
ListTile doesn't restrict that size, so that should cause the error and
we can simply get rid of that by wrapping this with a container where we set a fixed width here and a
fixed width of 100 pixels should suffice.
Now if we do that, now we have our items here and that looks now way better
and you see on every item we have the pen and the trash icon. You also see that image and if you of
course wanted to, you could add a card behind that ListTile to have a little bit of a background color
and a drop shadow or anything like that.
I rather will add a divider between these items and still add the drawer to go back.
So to start with the divider in the user products screen where I render the user product items here,
in the end I think it's nice to have a little divider after every item. So we can wrap this into a column
here,
the user product item, like this and have a divider after every user product item, like this.
So that's a little optical thing here,
nice little horizontal lines.
Now to also add that drawer on the user products screen,
we of course simply go to the scaffold widget there and anywhere on it, as the first, second or last
argument, doesn't matter, you add drawer
and now here I want to use my app drawer,
so let's import that from the widgets folder, app_drawer.dart. With that import added, let's create our
app drawer widget here and now with that, we also have a way of going back because now we can open the
drawer here too,
we can go back to the shop and then back to managed products and so on.
With that, we have the products page,
let's now work on the add and edit product page and of course make sure that the delete button also
does something.