So let's now work on the category items, we need to output our category items here.
We've got the category data but of course that's just some data,
we need widgets though,
we need a list of widgets here in the GridView and for that, we could certainly add the structure of
each item here and manually map our list of transactions into that structure
but I'd rather create a separate file,
the
category_item.dart file with a category item widget.
This will be a stateless widget
and I'll name it category item because it will output a single category item in our grid of categories
and as always, here you need to import flutter/material.dart.
Now this category item here will be used in our categories screen
here in this GridView.
So how should a single item look like then, what should we return here in the build method?
Well first of all, which data do we expect here?
Well we probably want to output the title of the category and use its color, remember that every category
has a color, to color the background
of the grid item.
So here we need at least two properties, a string which is the title and also a color which is the background
color.
Of course, we then also should add our constructor to assign values to these properties here
and again you can use named arguments here or as I do it here, use positional ones for title and color
and now we want to output the title here on a nice card where the card should have this background color.
Now we could use the default card and try to adjust this
but I'll rather build my own one by using a container. That container here should have some padding
and for that, I'll use EdgeInsets.all 15
and of course you can tweak this value and find a value that best suits your needs.
Now important, EdgeInsets.all actually is a class and an object is created here
and as you learned in that Flutter and Widgets deep dive module, you can optimize the build process a
bit by using const here in front of this
because then when this build method reruns, this object here will not be recreated because Flutter
detects that it's constant, that it can't have changed and therefore, that it should use the old one.
So that's the padding on the container,
now besides the padding, we of course also want to have a child in there and the child for a category
can be really simple,
it should be some text and the text of course should be the title of the category which I want to output.
Now we'll certainly revisit this title to give it some styling
but for now, let's use like this and let's work on the general styling of the container and there, we
could simply assign color which sets a background color to color which now refers to this color property
but I want to have a bit of a more complex background by using a decoration which takes a BoxDecoration
object and in that BoxDecoration here, I want to use a gradient.
We haven't worked with gradients thus far in this course but often gradients can provide a nice look,
so here's a good opportunity to add one. We add a gradient by instantiating the LinearGradient class
which is provided by Flutter,
by the way there also are other gradients, if you just type gradient you get an overview, you have a
RadialGradient, a SweepGradient and as always, the official docs are a great resource to learn how to
use these if you need a different gradient for your app. Here and in a lot of apps,
the LinearGradient is perfect and the LinearGradient
now of course needs to be configured.
We need to set the colors between which you want to transition and that's a list of colors
and then you also can define the direction over which it should transition.
So let's start with the colors, there
I want to use my color which I get here as an argument but in a slightly more transparent version and that
can be achieved by calling withOpacity on it. withOpacity is a method provided by Flutter on its
color class and there, we could set this to an opacity of .7 to make it slightly more transparent
and then I want to go from that slightly more transparent version of that color to the totally not transparent
version of that color by just providing color like this as the end value of that gradient. Now for
the direction, we can control this with a begin and an end argument and the begin argument here takes
an alignment geometry, such an alignment geometry can be created with the alignment class which gives
you a couple of static properties with basically default coordinates for which this gradient then
will start at and there, we could start in the top left corner and then go to the bottom right,
so as you see, it's really simple to configure such a gradient with the help of alignment and this colors
list here. So with that, we have the gradient,
I'm not done with the BoxDecoration though. In addition to the gradient, I want to set a border radius
to have rounded corners and I'll set this to BorderRadius.circular and then maybe 15,
so now this will use a radius of 15 to round our corners.
BorderRadius.circular is a class constructor provided by Flutter to give you the setting for border
radius which needs a border radius geometry to round off these corners.
Now please note that here, you can't use const because border radius, if you inspect that, does have a constant
constructor on all but the circular constructor is actually not marked as const,
so here we can't use const. So that's the general look of a category item,
now we can use the category item here in the categories screen. First of all, let's import our dummy data
here,
so let's import from the dummy data file and that unlocks that dummy categories list which we have in
there,
all capital case to mark it as
dummy data which is application-wide global which we can't change, which is just acting as a dummy
data source and in the categories screen,
I now want to use that dummy data here because here, we can now use a pattern which we used before,
we need to provide a list of widgets,
so let's take our list of data and map it into a list of widgets.
So here we can refer to our dummy categories and call map on that because it is just a list and call
to list in the end because map gives us an iterable and not a list
and now we have a function that executes on every item in that dummy categories list and that function
therefore gets our category data,
I'll name it catData, you can give it any name you want and it should return a widget which we want
to render for every category in that dummy categories list and that widget
now of course is my category item widget which we just created in the category_item.dart file.
So here, we can now create a category item widget and to that widget,
we have to pass the title and of course, the color. We get that from catData and there we extract the
title and also the color, just like this.
So with that, we got our categories screen and now it would be interesting to see whether that works.