With that deep dive at how Flutter manages all of that,
let's see which build methods actually get called for
which actions. For that, let's go to the main.dart file and there in the build method of the
MyHomePageState class, I'll add a print statement where I simply print build MyHomePageState, so that we can
see in the log when this method executed. I'll do the same in the transaction list widget, in the transaction
list.dart file, there in the build method, I'll also run build for transaction list.
The same for the chart here, there in the build method, I'll print build chart and for the chart bar,
there in the build method, I also want a print chart bar. You could also add to the adaptive_flat_button
if you wanted to but I'll print it for these widgets.
Now with that, if you have an emulator up and running and connected, do a full restart here with that
green arrow in the top right corner here and let's see where build now gets called in our app. Before
we touch anything, let's already go back here to the debug console and what we see here is that build
gets called in MyHomePageState, then it gets called in chart, then in the chart bar and then actually
this means that it is called five times more in the chart bar,
so we would have the same output as we have here five times more
which is why the the debug console kind of wraps this together it into one log.
But we would have five times and overall with this log here, six times chart bar being logged and then
the transaction list build method runs. Now let's refine this actually a bit by going to the chart widget
here and there for the constructor,
I'll remove the semicolon and actually add a constructor body,
you can still use this shortcut with this and then the argument name which matches your property name
but here I will now also print constructor chart, so that we also see when this constructor runs.
I only did it here for the chart, you can of course do it for the other widgets too.
So again, time for a restart
and now let's see what happens in the debug console. We see MyHomePageState gets called, then the constructor
of chart gets called, then the build method of chart and then the build methods of chart bar and transaction
list.
This output makes a lot of sense of course because the main.dart file is our entry point, there we run
app with MyApp when the app launches, MyApp is a stateless widget which in the end simply instantiates
the MyHomePage widget there,
so MyHomePage is created here, that creates its state and when the state is created, the build method
in the state runs and that is why we see MyHomePageState first.
Then this build method executes and therefore, Flutter instantiate all these widgets here, all these Dart
classes here and therefore, since we added our logs to for example the chart widgets, we see output regarding
that. We're not in landscape mode, so hence we see here that we render a container with the chart and
then we render our transaction list widget. So here, the chart gets created, an instance of the chart class
which is why the constructor of chart is executed and then since this also is a widget, Flutter goes
ahead and calls the build method in chart.
Now inside of chart and its built method, there of course we see that all these chart bars get built
in the end.
Of course we have a bunch of other widgets getting built as well but we didn't add any print statements
in there, which is why we see no output for these but the chart bar here gets created
and of course we create this chart bar seven times, not six times as I said before,
of course we have one plus five plus one output, so seven times chart bar here because we have chart
bars for seven days. Now once these chart bars are created and once this part of the widget tree is done,
Flutter actually goes back because here it isn't done,
it now built the chart with all its child widgets.
Now the next line is executed,
if we're not in landscape mode, this is this line here
and then we build the transaction list widget which is stored in a variable up here and there, we in the end
build our transaction list widget and therefore we see build transaction list because in the transaction
list widget, the constructor gets executed,
we have no log for that which is why we don't see that in the log down here
but we have a log and a build method and that is executed when a new instance of transaction list is
created.
So this is how build runs when the app starts,
now let's do something.
If I open that overlay here for example, nothing changes here, nothing rebuilds.
Let me clear the debug log with this button, so that we can see fresh messages easily
and now let me tap into title here. Without typing anything, you see that now MyHomePageState actually
was rebuilt. On first look, that could be strange because when you tap here into an input field, we certainly
don't call set state
but remember that earlier, I said that build is not only executed when you call set state but for example
also when the media query or when the theme changes. Now the theme hasn't changed of course but the media
query did, the media query also hold information about the view insets.
That's something we take advantage of in new transaction,
here, we're referring to the viewInset status stored in a media query to find out how much space is
occupied by the soft keyboard so that we can actually move our content up by that space.
So since this is part of the media query, the media query object changes and this is a special kind of
widget to which I'll come back which automatically triggers rebuilds of all the widgets that refer to
it
and just because that is important, it doesn't care about whether you actually are only interested in
the view insets or in something else,
any widget which uses media query of will rebuild no matter which data you then access from there.
So this is why the build method of our my app or MyHomePageState component rebuilds or reruns because
there, we are using the media query of object because we need it here for the orientation. Orientation
hasn't changed
but as I mentioned, whenever something in a media query changes, everything that depends on media query
will rebuild.
So that's why build here runs when we open the soft keyboard and then of course as you learned it, build
runs this, code gets parsed, all these widgets are recreated, new instances are created and therefore,
we also create a new chart, all these new chart bars and the transaction list.
Now of course, this might sound very inefficient now. Just because media query changed, even though we're
not using a feature of media query here that did change,
we rebuild this entire tree, isn't that a problem? It's not a problem because for one as you learned, rebuilding
the widget tree is really not that bad,
it doesn't mean that Flutter has to rebuild the entire user interface and recalculate everything there.
So rebuilding the widget tree is way less expensive, way less problematic than rebuilding everything
and therefore rebuilding the widget tree is a core mechanism of Flutter and really not bad.
But of course what you can always do in your apps and what you should do especially in bigger apps is
that you try to split your codes into widgets, such that you have certain features which cause regular
rebuilds, like media query changes, only in some widgets and maybe not in your main widget tree like we
have it here that holds essentially your entire app. For tiny apps like this one, where you only have
one page so to say, only one real section right.
We only have that personal expenses tracker,
we have no user profile or anything like that.
So for apps that only happen on one screen, it's not that uncommon that your main widget tree changes
a lot
but if you have bigger apps, you might consider splitting your app efficiently so that the parts that
do change often are confined or contained in their own widgets, so that they don't spill over into other
widgets because for example if something would change only in the chart widget, only the build method
there would be called and therefore all these widgets would be recreated and the chart bar would be
recreated but rebuilds here in the chart would not spill over to our MyHomePage or MyHomePageState
class here. This build method here would not be called if a child widget of it, like the child
widget rebuilds.
Now that's just something important, so splitting your apps efficiently is a good idea but always keep in
mind that build calls, the widget tree being rebuilt is generally not problematic and a core functionality
of Flutter and Flutter manages this efficiently to not rebuild the element and the render tree all the
time.