So let's now do the same for iOS and
for that, I'll go to the iOS folder which you only have if you're on a Mac,
it's not possible to write
iOS code, to develop iOS apps on Windows or Linux.
In the iOS folder, in the runner folder,
go to the AppDelegate.m file and in here, you find some Objective C code.
Now just as before with Java and Android, you don't have to know Objective C, you might have found some
snippet which you want to use or you do know Objective C or you have some knowledge from a blog
post which you want to implement in your app,
so there are ways how you could have gotten some Objective C code to which you want to connect from inside
your Flutter app
and here you can of course simply follow along and write this code together with me.
So here in the AppDelegate.m file, we got to add some code above these lines of code that are already
in there. This here in the end is a function,
it's a function and application which will return a boolean, gets the application object and we'll set
up our MethodChannel listener in here.
To do that, you first of all need to add an import here at the top,
make sure to import flutter/flutter.h between angled brackets like this. So add this import at the
top of the file and with this added,
let's now go down there and create a FlutterViewController with a star after it, name it controller,
so that's essentially the type here in Objective C which we get with
self.window.rootViewController,
this basically gives us access to the application shell here in the iOS app.
We have to cast this to a FlutterViewController star by adding this type in brackets in front of our
self
window rootViewController call. Now with that controller fetched,
we can set up a Flutter method
channel, also with such a star here, named battery channel or whatever you want, this name is up to you
and then you use square brackets here.
This is in the end how you call a function there and you call FlutterMethodChannel, a method made available
by Flutter, by importing this of course
and then you simply add arguments by separating them with a whitespace or simply to make it more readable,
in a new line,
that's up to you,
it also adds a whitespace in the end and then we have methodChannelWithName:, so that it's a named
argument you could say where the value is @"" and then the identifier you're using in your
Flutter app,
so this MethodChannel identifier here,
copy that and
add it here between the double quotes
and then another argument we have to specify here is the binary messenger argument which we set to controller
so that the data is essentially passed with the help of that app shell you could say.
So with that line added here, let's add another line of code here.
There we now call again, between square brackets, Objective C simply has a quite different syntax than
Dart has, we call battery channel and pass the set method call handler argument which is a named argument
and there, you now use this symbol here and then a bit like in the Android example, you add an anonymous
function here so to say with brackets and curly braces, as an argument here, you get the Flutter method
call with a star, the call and a Flutter result and that's the same pair of arguments you got in the Android
example, so you get the incoming call and then a result object which you can use to send back data
and now here between the curly braces and we have to add a semicolon here, between the curly braces
we can now run our code to identify the incoming method and get our battery level in this case.
Let's now add a new function and we do that outside of this function here,
so outside of these curly braces
but before at end and you define a function in Objective C by adding a dash, then the return type in
brackets and then right after that, the function name, getBatteryLevel for example, again
that name is up to you, doesn't have to match the name you're sending in Flutter. Then you could accept
arguments
but here we don't get any, so we won't have a list of arguments and instead we continue right with the
function body. In there, we now get access to the device which is of type UIDevice star here, store it
in a device variable and we use UIDevice which is provided by iOS in the end, .currentDevice
to get access to the device the app is running on and then we can access device.batteryMonitoringEnabled
and set this to yes, so that we can tap into the device battery level and now add an if check and
check if device.batteryState is equal to UIDevice.batteryStateUnknown, that means we can't fetch
the battery level, then we'll return -1 here. Else if that is successful, we return a converted value,
convert it to an integer of device.batteryLevel * 100. So this returns the battery level
and now we can call that up there in this application method here in the end by first of all adding
a bit strange looking variable here with __weak typeOf self, weakSelf which is
equal to self.
This basically gives us a reference to the surrounding context here, so that we can use the weak self
here inside of this method to call this method and again that's just some object c specific, has nothing
to do with Flutter or Dart but now in here, we can check if in square brackets at and now you need that
identifier you're using in Flutter for this method name, getBatteryLevel, so if that getBatteryLevel
thing here is equal to a string and the string we want to compare it to is call.method.
So we are basically comparing the incoming call method to this string, just the other way around here
but this is just using some Objective C logic to compare these two strings and if this is equal, then
we know that we're getting a call to getBatteryLevel.
So in this case, we can derive our battery level and store it in the variable here by making a call with
the help of weak self to getBatteryLevel,
so to this method we defined down there,
this method, this function and then we're storing this in the battery level variable here and now we can
just check if battery level is equal to -1 which basically means it failed.
If that's the case, then we return a result where we call or where we create a new Flutter error and we
call error with code,
the code then could be unavailable, it's up to you
and another argument, maybe in a new line but that's totally up to you where the message could
be @, so that's how you create strings in Objective C basically, could be battery info not available
and third argument which you need to pass here, details nil, nil is like null,
so we're not passing any detailed data along with that error.
So we're using this result thing here to send back a result essentially with that configuration,
else if we do have a battery level, then we use result again
and here we simply pass at battery level to send this back here as a value through the result, so this
sends a success result.
Now on this outer if else check, we've sent back a result of Flutter method not implemented, in case some
other identifier was coming in for which we have no logic to run. With all of that,
we got the iOS code finished and we should be able to test this.
Now testing on an emulator won't work because the iOS simulator doesn't give you access to the battery,
so I'll actually connect my real device and test it on there. For that here in the terminal,
I'll run flutter build iOS to build my iOS code and then again open this in Xcode to then run it through
Xcode on my real device.
Now here, I'm getting an error regarding my sign in, so I'll first open this in Xcode, open the entire
iOS folder there
and there select runner and set up my team here, so Maximillian Schwarzmuller in my case as a signing
team.
Now if we look further though, we also got another error here,
so besides that team setup,
I also forgot a semicolon here which we should add, so make sure to add this and then rerun this Flutter build
iOS code here and now this was successful. Now back in Xcode,
make sure your connected device is selected there and click play now to launch the app on this connected
device and here, the app is launching and this battery level you're seeing here is correct, that's the
current battery level I have and therefore this also works on iOS.