So back in our project here, in the edit product screen, how can we now handle the user input there?
What's a good way of doing that? Instead of manually collecting all inputs with text editing controllers
which we have to assign, Flutter has a built-in widget that helps us with collecting user input and with
validation as well
and that's the form widget. The form widget itself is invisible,
it doesn't render something on the screen which you could see but inside of the form widget, you can
use special input widgets which are then grouped together and which can be submitted together and validated
together in very simple ways with the help of Flutter.
A form takes a simple child argument and now there, you build your normal widget tree but now wrapped
inside that form and where you can now use special form widgets that help you build more complex
forms.
So in here, I first of all want to build a scrollable list of input elements and for that of
course, we can use a column with a SingleChildScrollView around it for a ListView
but now not in the builder mode but in the normal mode like this, with children added to it
and this will ensure that we can have multiple items below each other which automatically are then scrollable
because we don't know whether we'll exceed the boundaries of our device
on the given device the app runs on, so it makes sense to make this scrollable.
Now once I thought about using a ListView here, you might want to consider using a column and
SingleChildScrollView instead of ListView because at least, you can actually get rid of some of the elements that are
scrolled out of the view and therefore data input could get lost there.
So if you have a longer form or you do allow landscape mode as we actually do it here and therefore
you might have less screen height available in your final app, then using column plus SingleChildScrollView
might be an option and in the lecture after this one, you'll find a bit more details on that,
so definitely don't skip that next lecture.
Now since I'll primarily use this, in portrait mode here however, I'll go with a ListView for now
but again, consider that next lecture to avoid data loss and now in that list, we can simply start adding
our different inputs.
And now here instead of a text field which we used before, we use a text form field and that's the special
input I was referring to which works together with this form. Text form fields are automatically connected
to that form behind the scenes so to say and can interact with it and you'll see how to interact with the
form in just a second.
So text form fields are based on normal text fields and hence you have rich configuration options there
as you saw it before in the course to set up auto correction and so on but you also do have some differences.
Whilst you can connect your own controller, you don't have an onChanged listener here for example. You might
remember that earlier in the course, on the normal text fields, we could use onChanged to listen to every
keystroke, to every input the user did and then save that manually somewhere. Here this doesn't work and
instead we can only act on this being submitted which is when we hit the special submit action in the
soft keyboard, onEditingComplete and onSave which is an important new method which we can trigger
with the help of the form and which I'll show you later.
So the way you get the value out of the text field differs a bit,
thankfully you also don't have to add a controller here to get the input because again, the form will
help you get that value and will manage it for you behind the scenes so to say. So let's start simple
and let's add one text form field for a new product,
so when we're adding a new product. There we could add a decoration which takes an input decoration
object which then in turn gives you a lot of configuration options to change the appearance but also
some text on that text input.
You can also enable or disable it and
here I want to set a label text which is basically like that hint text that's shown above the input
where I say title because this text input field here should be used for entering the title of the new
product.
Now always feel free to play around with the other options you have here,
there are simply too many to go through all of them here but you can configure a lot of things and besides the
popup here and the IDE completion and the hints you get here in the IDE, the official docs of course
are a great place to learn more about the options you do have here. For this text form field, besides
the decoration,
I also want to set a text input action.
This controls what the bottom right button in the soft keyboard will show, whether it's a checkmark or
a done text to confirm that you're done
or a next text or a next icon to go to the next input
and here indeed,
I want to use a text input action and text input action is an enum with the value of next and this will show
a soft keyboard with a button that indicates that pressing this action button in the bottom right corner
of the keyboard will move to the next input instead of submitting the entire form or submitting this
input or anything like that.
Now that's it already for this first simple element,
one thing I want to do is I want to wrap the form here with some padding of let's say 15 or 16 in all
directions, so that the form elements are not directly on the edges of the screen. But with that,
let's have a look at this before we then continue with it and add more elements which we can focus,
submit the data and also validate the data.
So let's first of all make sure we can see that edit product screen and I want to be able to see it when
in the user product screen,
for now we click on that add button in our appBar.
So here when I go to the edit product screen, again I want to use named routing here, so we can simply
add to the widget though, add our static const routeName field here where we say edit-product and
now we can use that routeName in our route table as we did it before in the course.
Let's import screens/edit_product_screen and with the import added here,
let's go down to the route table
and of course reach out to our edit product screen routeName as a key and then here in the builder
function, return a new instance of the edit product screen.
Now we can go there with pushNamed from inside user products
when we click that add button by using navigator
of context pushNamed, not push replacement but just pushNamed
because I want to push the new page on the stack of pages so that we also can go back to this
page from the new page and then the name here of course is fetched from our imported edit product screen,
here we refer to editedProductsScreen.routeName. Let's save that
and back here, if I click the plus button, I'm now taken here
and here we see the title,
we can tap in there,
I can type there and we also see on the bottom right corner of the soft keyboard,
this indicates that clicking here does go to the next input.
It doesn't do that automatically,
we have to control that an
I'll show you how to control that later
but it shows us the right button here. And that's all nice
and with that, let's add a second input.