Even though rebuilds of the widget tree aren't that bad,
of course it's never a bad idea to avoid unnecessary widget rebuilds because that simply means that
even though it's just a configuration tree that changes, even if we can avoid a change there,
we of course save some processing time and therefore, can overall improve our application performance.
In small apps like this one,
not really in a measurable way to be honest but especially in bigger apps,
every tiny bit of performance improvement can count and one relatively easy improvement is the usage
of so-called const constructors and const widgets and that's simply something we haven't learned yet,
so now is the time to do so.
You know final and const already.
As you learned earlier in the course, final variables or properties are variables or properties which
are created dynamically at runtime but which then never change. On the other hand, const properties or
variables are properties or variables that are holding a certain value which is already known when the
code compiles and which will never change after compilation.
Now you can also build so-called const constructors,
now what's a const constructor though?
Let's go to our chart bar here.
There, we have a constructor,
here it is and what you can do is you can add the const keyword in front of that constructor as well.
You can do this
if you bind all your arguments here in the constructor to final properties,
so for example if I turn that string into a non-final string here, so if that label is not final, we
get an error down there that we can't make this a constructor for non-final fields.
But if you only have final field which you're targeting,
so if you saying that whenever you're creating an instance of this ChartBar class, this instance will
be unchangeable because you won't be able to then access this instance with the dot notation and change
the label after this object has been created,
then you can mark this as const which means every instance of this object you create is immutable, you
can't change it.
So what I mean in detail here is that in the chart widget, in the chart class where we create the instance
of the chart bar, this here in the end is just the instance of a class,
it's an object, right?
Of course an object that's treated and used as a widget by Flutter
but most importantly, it's a normal Dart object,
just like if we built an object based on our transaction class. So therefore as on every object, we can
use the dot notation after it was created,
so after the closing parentheses of our constructor, to interact with that object and there for example,
we can access the properties of that object, the label, the spending amount, the spending percentage of total.
Now we don't typically do that on our widget objects because we don't use them like normal objects in
Flutter and Dart,
instead we simply use them to pass them onto the Flutter widget tree
but you could access the label here if you wanted to read the label for this concrete chart bar instance.
Now when the label is marked as final as it is here, what you would never be able to do is assign a new
value to label here with the equals sign,
that's simply not possible because it is final.
Now that's what I mean with immutable, an immutable object. This object, the chart bar object, the chart bar
class is immutable
as soon as it's instantiated because all its properties, so all the things you can access with the dot
notation are marked as final and then you can turn this or you can annotate this with const to make
it clear that your intention with this classes, that every new object that's created based on it is immutable.
So it can't be changed,
you can only change it by replacing it with a new instance.
And if you remember what I said earlier about the widget tree and the element tree and the render tree,
I said there that the widget tree is full of immutable objects, all the widgets are immutable.
When the build method runs, in the end it creates a bunch of new instances because it calls the constructors
again,
so then it replaces the old instances with the new ones,
it does not go ahead and take the old widget and only update its label by assigning a new value, instead
it creates a new widget with a new label passed into the constructor,
that's what's happening.
So that's why we can use const here.
Now when we have const here and we do indeed create an instance of this widget with compile time constant
data, then we can let Flutter know about it.
So here, we could then, when we use our immutable widget, we could add const in front of it.
Now in theory, in Flutter, every stateless widget you build is immutable and you can add const in front
of the constructor, of basically every stateless widget you build because in stateless widgets, you always
have final unchangeable properties because you can't use set state in here and update the user interface
if you would change a property anyways. So hence, basically all your stateless widgets are theoretically
immutable or are immutable but you can't create them here with const in front of the constructor because
the data I am passing here into this concrete object of chart bar is indeed dynamic, it's not known at
the point of time of compilation
and you see this here if I hover over this. Arguments of a constant creation must be constant expressions
and this is not constant because this value here changes dynamically.
Of course, this does not change the object dynamically but when a new object is created, at the point
of time we're writing this code, we don't know which data will end up there,
so we can't add const here.
Now why would we have wanted to add const here is of course the important question.
You can skip unnecessary widget rebuilds if you mark a widget as const here when using it in the
widget tree and a good example for this would be some text, like in a transaction list widget. There, we
have this text widget with the text of delete in it. At the point of time of writing this code, we know
exactly how this widget will look like, it will always be just some delete text, this will never change
at runtime. Now still, when the build method here gets called in our main.dart file, when this is called,
this will also be rebuilt and all these widgets are rebuilt and this includes text widgets like this
one which certainly will never change.
In such cases, you can add const in front of the widget,
so when you're creating it because text which is a built-in widget if you inspect this code also has
const in front of its constructor because it extends stateless widget
and as I explained, basically all stateless widgets are immutable because changing properties in there
doesn't really make sense.
So now what we're telling to Flutter is something important though
and by the way, this is a Dart feature which Flutter takes advantage of
you could say. We're saying this here, this object will never ever change.
We're not assigning any dynamic data here when we're creating it,
so when build gets called again and when Dart goes through this code and creates all these widgets anew,
it doesn't have to do it for this one because we certainly know that this will be the exact same element,
the exact same object as it was in the previous widget tree.
Other parts of this widget tree might change but this text certainly won't.
Now by default, Flutter doesn't know that and it would rebuild this text widget again.
Of course, it's not super costly to do so because it only happens in the widget tree and that is done
very efficiently but still, if we can skip one extra redundant object instantiation, we should do it.
So adding const here is a good idea because that tells Dart that the value after it will never change
and that tells Flutter that since this will never change, when it rebuilds the widget tree, for this specific
widget,
it can simply take the old widget which was in the same position,
it doesn't need to recreate the object. It's similar for the icon here
for example, icon also is in the end a class that has a const constructor and here, we're not deriving
the icon we want to use dynamically, instead it's already known at compilation time, so we can mark this
as const as well. It's the same, for example down there, for this icon.
It's different for this text here though,
this text here of course also uses the text widget but the data we output as text does change dynamically.
So when build gets called again, this could have a different value than when build was called the last
time.
So here, we can't use const
and indeed if we tried, we get an error that in the end, we're passing non-constant data to this constructor.
But there are a lot of cases where you can use const, for example also here for EdgeInsets.all,
EdgeInsets also is a class and there, it also has const in front of the constructor,
so we can add const here too because this value here, which we use to derive the padding we want to set,
is also known at compilation,
we never change that value. If you wanted to make this padding overall const though, this overall widget,
you would get an error because whilst of course the padding value here is constant, a child widget
of this padding and this is part of the constructor of the padding object is not constant.
This holds in the end some other dynamic child widget, this text here, which hold some dynamic const.
So the overall padding widget, the padding object here is not immutable but a part of it, the object
we assign for its padding argument,
this would be constant. Now you can certainly identify more opportunities where you could do this, for example
for this SizedBox widget which only has one argument with a compilation time constant value. Not
for this text here though because there, the theme, we could change that,
so here we can't do it but in other places in the code, you might still be able to add const.
Now obviously, you'll not double the speed of your application with tiny changes like this but still,
it's a good habit to get into and something you might consider in your app, maybe not whilst you're writing
it because there you typically want to implement new features and you might not think about optimizing
the code yet but when you go over your app, before you publish it, before you finish it up, you might look
for opportunities like this which certainly won't hurt and which might help the performance of your
app a little bit.