So that's it for this module. You learned how you can add your own native code in case you know the
native languages or you've got certain snippets you want to execute and how you can connect it to your
Flutter app to then send messages to your native code and use the result of that in your Flutter application.
Now in most applications, you won't have to do that
too often because there are so many plugins and with Flutter growing strongly and already being very popular,
we not only get a base of lots of plugins that are available but there are more and more high quality
plugins coming out all the time. So chances are that when you need a certain native device feature, there
is a plugin that helps you work with that
but in case there is some functionality you want to implement on your own or where there is no plugin
or whatever it is,
this is how you could run native code from inside your Flutter app.