If we inspect the post method, we don't just get more information about it and see which arguments we
can set
but we also see that in the end returns a future and I had a look at these future objects before in
this course already.
Future is a core class built into Dart which builds an object which generally is a normal object but
which gives us a method, the then method, that allows us to wait for a certain action to finish or actually,
it doesn't allow us to wait for that, it doesn't pause our entire app until this is done,
instead it allows us to define a function that should execute in the future,
hence the name, once this action is done.
So here for this post method, by default
the next line of code after HTTP post,
so here this is where we create the product, will execute immediately after Dart execute this without waiting
for the response to arrive here.
So Dart treats this as done as soon as it sent the request off,
it does not wait for the response, it immediately continues to the next line and that's good,
otherwise our application would be frozen until the response is there, which for Firebase doesn't take
long because it's super fast but other service might be slower
or imagine you have no internet connection or a slow internet connection, then it might take even longer
even if you have a fast server. So therefore here, we can add or call a method though on the result of
post which is this future object and that's the then method and then takes a function which it will
execute once,
in this case, here we have a response and that's different for every future, every future
you can build your own futures too, decides when it should treat itself as done
so to say, so when it should trigger this function.
The future returned by post treats itself as done and triggers the function once the response is there
and conveniently, it gives us the response,
that's what this indicates here, as an input to the function we pass to then.
So here inside of then, we actually have to pass in a function which receives the response.
So here we get the response and now inside of this function, we can work with that response.
So not in the next line after post because that will execute immediately but only inside of the function
we would pass to then because this function will not execute immediately,
instead it's registered by Dart and it's executed
when this is done. It's a bit like registering a function for onPressed where we also simply define
a function, either with a pointer at one of our functions or by adding an anonymous function which implicitly
also then just passes a pointer to onPressed which will be executed when the user presses something.
It's the same here,
we define a function and we could have a named function here too at which we then point, without parentheses
to not execute it immediately, which will only execute once the operation is done.
Here, I'm using an anonymous function and now if we execute this logic here inside of this function, now
this will only run once the response is there and not immediately and we can see that effect if we go
back and we add this again, should be long enough so that we don't get a validation error
and now let me add that image here again, save that
and now you see, it took a short while, fraction of a second, for this to appear, it wasn't instantly there.
If you would have stored it in memory and done this outside of this then block, then it would have been there
instantly because that line would've been executed right after the request was sent off.
It only took so long because we waited for the response, which is the case because we're executing this
inside of this then block.
Now the advantage of this is that we can now use data from the response and it turns out that Firebase
here actually sends us a response which contains this cryptic key,
this unique ID which this actually is which it automatically creates for us and that's awesome because
then we get a really unique ID out of the box generated by Firebase and often of course, you'll work
with back-ends, with servers that generate IDs for you because you can do that much better on a server.
To see what's inside of the response,
we can simply print it here. Let's print the response and see what we get here.
If we now save this and we add this one more time, we can later clear this on Firebase of course to get rid
of all our dummy data
but if we add this one more time, we see we get back an instance of response and to see what's in there,
let's use json.decode response.body because response is an object
and just like the request has a body,
so some data we attach to it, a response also has a body.
That is in JSON format and with json.decode, we can convert this from JSON into some data we can
work with in Dart
and typically, this will convert it into a map.
So now if we save this one more time with this little addition here, if we create one more, just to test,
and again I'll use my image here and save this, then we actually see this is what we get back,
that's the converted map already.
It's a map with a name key
and on that name key, we have that cryptic unique ID which Firebase automatically generates.
So since we wait for the creation and storage of our product until this is done, we can now take advantage
of this and not generate our dummy ID here but instead take the ID we're getting here, so we can
simply execute this code here to decode our response body,
then we know this is a map with a name key, so we can then access name like this to get that ID and the
advantage is that we now work with that ID which we also have on the server here in our front-end
and that's what you generally want to do because if you then ever need to send a delete request to the
back-end or something like that, you will need the ID on the server to identify this item,
right
because the server only knows its own IDs. So if you use the same ID in your app, you never have
the problem of having to match the back-end ID with your front-end ID, simply take the back-end ID
everywhere and you have no problems and that's what we do here.
If we create a new product,
now on the front-end,
so in our Flutter app, add it to our local list of products, use the database ID for that creation
and then on the front-end, we work with a perfect copy of what we have on the back-end,
that's the idea here.
And with that, we're sending requests and we're waiting for that response to return.
Now obviously, it's a bit of a strange user experience that when we add something here, that we then have
to wait for a short moment until this appears here in the list,
this is a bit strange.
It would be better if we would see some loading spinner here until we are done, so that we only go
back here
once this has been added and we have all the latest data again.