In this demonstration,
you'll learn how to create a repository for an existing solution.
Here I've opened a directory of the Git repository that
we have created in the previous clip.
You can see here the WiredBrainCoffee.ShopInfoTool solution.
Now let's delete this .git folder, which is our local Git repository.
Let's also remove the two files gitattributes and gitignore.
Now we have actually a solution that is not under source control.
Let's double-click the solution and let me show you how you can create
a Git repository for the solution in Visual Studio.
Let's go to the Solution Explorer, and all you need to do,
you just right-click on the solution and you can select
here Add Solution to Source Control.
This will create a local Git repository.
Instead of using the Solution Explorer,
you can also use Visual Studio's status bar to create a
local Git repository for this solution.
So, let's click here on Add to Source Control, and now you can see Git.
Let's click on Git to create a local Git repository for this solution.
Now Team Explorer shows the Synchronization page.
Here you can push the local Git repository to a remote repository.
Now let me just bring up the File Explorer again.
Here in File Explorer, you can see we have,
again, a new local Git repository,
and Visual Studio has also added the two files,
gitattributes and gitignore again.
Now let's go back to Visual Studio.
Let's go to the Home page of Team Explorer and let's click here on Changes.
As you can see, there are no changes,
so let's look at the history of the master branch.
Let's go to the Branches page, let's right-click on the master branch,
and let's select here View History.
As you can see,
Visual Studios has automatically made the two commits that
we did manually in the previous clip.
First, it added the files gitignore and gitattributes,
and then it added the project files.
You can actually look what is part of such a commit but
double-clicking it in this history view.
So you see, the other two files were added,
and in the other commit, the Program.cs file,
the cs project file, and the solution file were added.
Alright, so now we have a solution in a local Git repository. Let's push this repository now to Azure DevOps.