In this demonstration,
we will continue to work on the feature branch
coffeeShopCommands with the user Thomas.
Let's switch to Visual Studio.
As you can see, we work here as user Thomas.
In Team Explorer, let's click here on Branches to navigate to the Branches page.
Here you can see that we are on the feature coffeeShopCommands branch.
You can also see this down here in the status bar.
As you know, in the meantime, Julia has made commits to the master branch,
but as we are here with the user Thomas on this coffeeShopCommands branch,
we are not affected by these commits.
We can just continue to work on our feature.
As you can see, I have opened here already the Program.cs file.
You might remember we have implemented here this else block with the
user Thomas where we handled the coffee shop commands.
But the whole Program.cs file got a bit big, so let's refactor our code.
Then we select all the statements in this else block, and let's press Ctrl+X.
Let's create here a variable, and let's call it commandHandler.
Let's initialize it with a new CoffeeShopCommandHandler instance,
and that instance takes the coffeeShops list and also
the line that the user has entered.
Then we press Ctrl+dot to generate this
CoffeeShopCommandHandler class in a new file.
Now let's use this commandHandler instance,
and let's call the HandleCommand method.
Let's press Ctrl+dot again to generate this method in
the CoffeeShopCommandHandler class.
Now let's go to the Solution Explorer.
Here you can see this new CoffeeShopCommandHandler.cs file.
Let's double-click it.
Visual Studio has created this constructor for us that takes the coffee shops
and the line that the user has entered on the command line.
Both parameters are stored in private fields.
Then you can see here, the HandleCommand method.
Let's make it public.
Now in this method,
let's paste the logic that we have cut from the Program.cs
file to handle the coffee shop commands.
Let me put the cursor here on the Where method and let's press
Ctrl+dot to add a using for System.Linq.
Now when I scroll down, you can see we don't have any errors.
Let's go back to the Program.cs file.
This looks now much cleaner.
Now let's do the same to handle the head command.
Let's also cut this code here, and let's create a commandHandler variable.
And let's initialize it with a new HelpCommandHandler instance.
That constructor just takes the coffee shops.
Then we press Ctrl+dot to generate this class in a new file.
Now on this commandHandler,
let's call also a HandleCommand method and let's press Ctrl+dot to generate it.
Now let me right-click this class and let's Go To Definition.
Let's paste the code that we cut from the Program.cs
file into the HandleCommand method,
and let's also make this HandleCommand method public.
And here we don't need the dollar sign if we
concatenate the string by using the plus.
But let's keep the dollar sign and let's use an interpolated string here.
Now we have two command handlers, and both have a HandleCommand method.
We can optimize the code in the Program.cs file even further if we
have an interface for both command handlers.
So let me put the cursor on this HelpCommandHandler class,
and let's press Ctrl+dot to extract an interface.
Let's call the interface ICommandHandler,
and let's use that HandleCommand method.
Let's click OK.
Now you see the HelpCommandHandler class implements this interface.
The interface is now also part of our command line tool.
Let's go to the CoffeeShopCommandHandler and let's scroll up,
and let's also implement the interface here,
ICommandHandler.
As you know, this class has already here a HandleCommand method.
Now let's go back to the Program.cs file.
Here we can optimize our code now.
We can create here before this if statement an ICommandHandler variable,
let's call it commandHandler,
and then we just assign the command handlers to that variable.
This means we can call this HandleCommand method
just once after this whole block.
And of course here, I need a semicolon.
Now we can even optimize it further by using the conditional operator.
So let's do this.
Let's initialize the variable directly here,
and let's check if the string that was entered by the user equals help,
and if that's the case,
then we just use a new HelpCommandHandler and else we
use a new CoffeeShopCommandHandler.
Now when I hover this,
you can see there is no implicit conversion between
HelpCommandHandler and CoffeeShopCommandHandler.
Let's solve this by writing here explicitly as ICommandHandler.
And let's use here, instead of the interface, the var keyword.
Great!
Now I'm really happy with this code.
Let's run the application and let's see if it still works.
Let's type in help, and we can see the available coffee shop commands.
Let's type in, for example, Freiburg, and we can see in Freiburg,
we have 23 kg of coffee beans in stock.
Great!
Let's enter quit to exit the application.
Now the user Thomas has refactored his code and he is done with this feature.
Down here in the status bar, we can see that we have four changes.
Let's click on this to navigate to the Changes page of Team Explorer.
Now let's enter here a commit message.
Let's write here, Introduce command handlers,
and let's select from the drop-down Commit All and Push.
Now you see here the outgoing commit,
and now we successfully pushed to the remote branch feature/coffeeShopCommands.
Now we did a lot of changes with the user Thomas.
I think it would be good if Julia could review our feature
branch with the new coffee shop commands.
But for such a review,
we should have the latest commits of the master branch in our feature branch.
So let's check if there are changes on the master branch.
Let's go to the Branches page,
and let's double-click on master to check out the master branch.
Now let's go to the Synchronization page, and let's click here on Fetch.
The user Thomas can see now that Julia has made two
commits on the master branch.
She added the PaperCupsInStock property,
and then she merged her feature branch into the master branch.
Now let's click on Pull to pull these two commits from the
remote repository into our local master branch.
Now we have the two commits from Julia in our local master branch,
but we don't have them in the feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.
Let me show you in the next clip how you can bring these
two commits from Julia from the master branch to the feature/coffeeShopCommands branch.