Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this lecture.
This is going to be short one on.
What we're gonna do is look how to join up our code.
So at the moment,
if we wanted to apply,
the said these highlights toe are formula sells.
The first thing would want to do is clear all the formatting to make sure that all format
in his gum on Then apply the formatting code.
Now these are the two bits of code that we currently have.
This is the highlight me which we can see highlights on this is the unroll like me which
unhygienic it's now.
What we could do is make this all happen in the same subroutine.
So one of them do temporarily.
He's just put a few lines of code in there on between the end sub on the sub.
I'm just going to take this code,
copy it and paste it up here and that the formatting looks a little bit ugly at the moment
.
But they go basically so everything below this line is original code and everything above
this line is our new code.
So now if we had formatting frog was like,
let's just do call that in green and we wanted to underplay its men apply yellow toward the
formulas we could know Just hit this hit play on,
Boom!
All off that macro execute.
So that's our first macro which have copied and pasted in here on our second macro,
which is the warmly originally recorded to color in the highlights.
OK,
but there is,
um,
or elegant way of doing this or more practical way of doing this.
You remember from the Let me just under a few times you remember from the 15 golden rules
of coding that one of the things was to code simply on and in small chunks.
Now,
that particular demonstration,
we've still only got probably that doesn't lines of code.
So it's nice and easy,
and you can still edit that,
and you can still understand it when you look at it.
But there is another way to run one piece of code after another piece of code.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna code something completely from scratch.
So I'm gonna type sub because we're entering a new subroutine.
Andi,
I'm gonna cool it.
Join these two together on notice.
What happens when I hit Enter automatically.
I get opening closed brackets after the title.
Joining together on VB is automatically added an end sub for me.
So what I'm gonna do here is I am gonna call the other subroutines in this module.
So all they need to do to call the subroutine is one of two things I could type,
call and say clear.
Well,
I haven't finished yet on type clear format and in fact will type it in because you'll
notice that there subroutine clear formatting has a capitalized,
see capitalized F There was always good practice when you're typing something in
particularly names of subroutines or instructions such a cell's interior pattern and all
these kind of things type in lower case and notice what happens.
Former Tink.
Now,
at the moment this says call with a C in lower case clear formatting with C in lower case
in the F in lower case,
but notice what happens when they hit,
enter or click off the line.
It automatically capitalizes this letter,
but it didn't capitalize this.
If you look closely,
you can see why what I'm actually typed here.
It is clear formatting,
which is not the same as clear formatting,
which is the name of this subroutine.
So always hoping in lower case is really useful because it helps you to spot those obvious
mistakes that you make.
So if I put on our in their men click off,
boom may go,
you can see that we have clear the capital C and formatting with a capital F.
So now we're just going to step through that code and notice what happened.
So I'm in this line on their press f eight.
So I am running the joint these together.
I am going to call the subroutine clear formatting and then notice what happens to the
highlighted sell.
Well,
no press f eight,
it immediately looks for this subroutine and jumps to it.
So now I can just step through this subroutine,
his end sub,
and then my yellow highlighting joins back up to end sub on the subroutine.
We started in on F 81 more time finishes it.
So I said there were two ways of doing this.
One is to use the word call,
Andi.
The only reason that you can use word call is years ago you had to call a process or a
subroutine.
Now you can literally just type the name off the subroutine.
So clear formatting is our 1st 1 and highlights my cells was hello?
My formulas that highlight my form.
You last on when I click off,
you'll notice the capitalization they go.
So it no ties up with this subroutine eso Now,
when I run this code,
notice what happens.
I'm going to step through F eight F eight clear format in f eight.
Jump down to the clear formatting subroutine.
Execute that.
Come back up to the highlight formulas Line F eight going Select the highlight My formulas
subroutine Execute that all the way down n sub back up to n sub f eight Andi finish,
um,
a go.
That's how you join two pieces off code together.
Okay.
In the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at a way to prevent users from running thes subroutines
accidentally.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.