Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
This lecture is gonna be comparatively simple.
But what we can do now know we've done all this really complicated stuff.
Bold in certain sections of the text is weaken.
Delete the bulk of this because most of this code was all to do with find in this start
length,
finding out the length of the string and bold in it.
So almost all of this Congar.
Oh,
so most of this And I think it was at the very end of that recorded macro here where we got
to a one not select where we did the formatting here.
And we can see that what we have is range a one dot select with the selection dot fund.
Change the color change the Tintin shade.
We don't need to change the Tintin shade,
but what we do need to do is change the font size to bowl so we can see we already have
selection dot funds.
So all we need is the dot size inside that end with,
So I'm just gonna pace that in there.
So I'm gonna delete this.
I'm gonna delete everything after the end with did we say,
Oh,
we did say bald as well.
Didn't they said,
Let's have bowled in there too.
So also the dot bold Because we're doing three things with that selection.
That's it.
That's better.
So we have fun size 16.
We have bold.
True on we have Colin minus one moment for 89280 obviously s.
So what I'm gonna do is just copy that,
like those lines of code.
Oops.
Don't delete the ends of balance on.
Let's come up to a a one where we're working.
Andi,
here we go.
No,
it's entirely up to you.
But I prefer to keep everything grouped together.
So everything I'm doing on a one is going to sit in this little black of code on the night
group.
Everything I'm gonna be doing with a three into this little black occur and everything with
a foreign to this block a coat.
There is absolutely nothing stopping you,
creating all of your text and then a little later in the code doing all the formatting,
it's entirely your choice.
So this is the one we just ran.
So let's just hit.
Delete,
delete,
delete.
Let's choose here,
Andi,
Now we've deleted all the redundant code are moderately sure that that's going to work.
Famous last words.
So what women do is just select our run order hit play and let it run through.
And they go a perfectly formatted monthly reports a month report for Jerry 2016 in the
northern region.
All of the different things bold.
In fact,
let me make that a little bit bigger so you can see it.
We can no see that this charts is coming out a little too far,
Will correct that at the end on there we have all of this data on what we do want is a
lovely great pie chart in here to show us what the category split is.
OK,
And the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at adding a nice pie charts.
I know nothing will be just about done.
Okay,
I'll see you.
That