Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
what we're going to do is just finalize a few the details on this sharp by recording a
couple of quick macros.
So the first thing you want to do is change the tart chart title.
So I'm just going to call the new Macron.
There's only a few of them will be able to spot what they do,
the codes generating over here.
I'm just going to right click on,
say,
text,
I'm gonna say,
split by category whips.
No enter click off macro number one Macron number two is I want to see the values
associated with each of these elements.
So there we go.
Macro number six me.
Just scroll up a bit so you can see that.
So we have on data labels at data labels and there we go.
We can see them.
That's perfectly fine.
Hit.
Stop.
Bizarrely.
Normally you can right click thes and delete these category headings for some reason.
And I have no idea why it's not allowing me to do that.
But luckily I know the code to do that so we can do that then.
So macro number five.
Wow,
what a load of code has been generated here on what we actually interested in Is that
particular line there where we change the chart title,
Doc text.
So I am just copying that.
In fact,
let me bring that back into shot a little bit better there.
So I'm gonna its view on the Venus Project Explorer back to project number one,
which is where we're working.
So the active chant duck titled the text split by category that's going to change the name
.
Then we down to this ongoing We have loads of scrolling on.
What we actually want to do is apply data labels.
So copy over here on underneath there will say,
paste data labels on delete,
then tied it up.
Allied comments this a little bit later.
And the final thing we wanted to do so we wanted to remove those data labels.
Eso We're still gonna be working on the active charts property.
And remember,
this is the active chart.
But this time,
what we want to do is say,
show all field buttons equals false and they go on.
That should be So what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna delete that and I'm gonna run the thing from the absolute beginning from here,
Onda.
Let's just go up to hear him play am Boone,
See what happens.
Let me just zoom out a little bit so we can see all of that.
So you go.
That's how perfectly formatted month report we have split by category.
Those buttons of gun.
The numbers are on their Everything is being built dynamically at runtime.
So all we need to do now is poured this over to a separate spreadsheet on,
then test it on our four sets off data.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.