Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this action.
This action is completely dedicated to retrieving data in real time from the Internet.
Now there's masses and masses of data on the Internet.
It's very easy to pull the data from there.
You may need to do a little manipulation with what you get,
but basically,
if the information is on the Internet,
you contrary,
vit with VB a code.
Import it into excel for use.
However you want to do it on their there is a downloadable resource from this particular
lecture called Super Weird Web query that Excel s X.
And in there you will find this section here called Get Your code here.
And this is all the code that we're going to go through during the course of the upcoming
lectures.
Andi In she one,
you will see the sheet.
Now what we have is this beautiful chart,
and I'm just going to click that chance because that's how we run the macro and you can see
no down the bottom left inside.
We are just getting the weather forecast from Rome on.
This is gonna be completely live as own record in this lecture,
and you can see,
the messages just changed.
And we are now retrieve in the weather forecast for Cancun.
And any second now will be populating our final one,
which is London.
So it's going to go to the Web service.
There you go.
We're just getting the weather forecast from London on.
I'm going to show you exactly how you do that.
How you had these little messages on the bottom.
Left inside on they go the day tress fully retrieved.
I'll see you in the next lecture will start to deconstruct exactly how you achieve this
Also,
you in the next lecture.