Okay,
guys on Welcome back,
right.
Let's have a look at how we get this done.
Now,
you may be aware that you can pull data from a Web source using Excel on.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna get three.
Web queer is pulling data for each of the three countries in our charts.
They are Rome,
Cancun on London.
Obviously,
you can do whatever you want with this,
but this is just for the purposes of demonstration.
There wanna have Here is a friend sheet called sheet one.
The data sheet is where will be storing our data queries on renamed it the VB name as shirt
data.
So back to hear what we're going to do to begin with is we're gonna go to a website and the
website we're gonna look at is this one here,
which is time in date dot com and here you can see that I have when they're Italy,
Rome e X t.
And that is going to give us the data for room.
So I'm gonna do for now.
Copy the name of that website,
the address of that website,
starting new macro recording,
and I'm gonna call this Rome because that's what we're going to be querian And from here,
I'm gonna come up to the data tab and I'm gonna hit from web and this window is gonna open
up.
Now,
this is essentially a very,
very old Internet explorer that's just available for doing web queries,
and I've pasted the address in there.
I'm gonna git go now.
I'm gonna drag this out a little bit,
and you can see you right up the top here.
It says next to the tables you want to select?
Sorry it.
Click this little image next to the tables you want to select and then click import.
So I'm gonna roll down here and while actually wants to import is this particular table
just here?
So I'm just gonna hit the little arrow button,
which exactly what it says here,
I'm gonna select import,
and now it's gonna ask me where do or want to import it,
too.
I'm just going to click cell a one on our data shooting hit.
Okay,
now,
because this is retrieving data from a website which we can see down here,
it is gonna take about 15 or 20 seconds to pull all the data back.
But what we're going to do is,
once the date is pulled back,
we'll have a quick sneak a peek at the code.
Okay,
here's Aled,
the data,
and I'm scrolling,
and I probably shouldn't be.
CSI's gonna recall that.
So I'm just going to stop recording.
There we go on.
I'm just gonna size that in a little bit and we're gonna have a look at that data.
And essentially,
that is the table that we just saw on this website just here.
This particular table right here.
Okay,
so that's going to have a look at that code old NFL Levin modules.
DoubleClick Number one on that.
Here is the code.
Now just a four.
Warn you.
Occasionally,
when you get a script era,
you'll have a little message box pop up that says,
Do you want to continue running this script now?
If you say yes,
you'll be able to continue warning.
You may get asked this question thousands of times.
I know when I originally wrote this piece of code,
I was getting the script warning.
For some reason,
it didn't happen just now.
But the way to get around that when you play your code back in all of the code,
you'll see this line here.
Command type equals zero.
Just realm that out because that will stop the script areas.
And I'm just gonna add a little note in there to say that so you'll remember it.
So that stops the script.
Harris on The next thing that we need to change is this particular line here where it says
refresh style.
And currently,
by default,
it says excel,
insert delete cells on what we actually want.
That to say which I stole from the Microsoft website was Excel overwrite,
sells other ways,
just keeps dropping new data in front of the old data.
You end up with a spreadsheet filled with millions of bits of data.
Okay,
so that was my active window scroll and then delete that.
And in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at Butcher in this code to run for Cancun on London,
and we'll have a look at the little bits of code that we're going to need to modify to do
that.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture