Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
And so we can do our chart.
What we now going to do is have a look at the whole of color me where this feels like.
So this is a temperature,
and this is what the temperature feels like.
What I need to remove is this space on the degrees centigrade.
So I'm just gonna copy that there partly because I have absolutely no idea how to do that
degree symbol.
And I'm just gonna record a simple macro,
which we're gonna butcher in a second.
And I'm gonna slight all of column me.
I'm gonna hit,
find I'm going to pace the Degree centigrade thing in that I just copied from here number
to replace it with nothing.
And I am going to replace all okay and close on stop.
And that is the code that we're looking for.
So here,
that's obviously going to No,
here it is way down the bottom on the world Got such a great big gap there.
There we go.
So this is a code that we've got.
We have columns e dot Select on with that selection so we can get rid of that.
So what we want to say is columns e replace the degree centigrade with absolutely nothing
on that is gonna tidy up our code.
So after we finished doing the while wend loop,
that is the last thing I want to do.
That woman do is tidy up this code,
but will bump on and tab everything in.
And I'll fully round this for when you download it.
And it's gonna look very,
very pretty indeed.
But for now,
what I'm gonna do,
it's just pause for a second and I'm gonna check that that code works from the very
beginning.
Now I'm gonna hit,
play on,
I'm gonna pause,
and then I'll be back to you in just a second.
Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
So that code has run through from beginning to end.
We now have a perfectly tabulated table on.
We have now remove that annoying degree centigrade from column E,
which is no gun.
Allow our child to work.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture,
where we're gonna look at populating the formulas in the front sheet.
Okay,
I'll see you.
That