Okay,
guys.
And welcome back,
right?
I've had in another private subroutine called redo formulas on have added redo formulas
will add redo formulas unless to our room order up here on Ive Also added notes as to what
each of these calls does.
I'll do that for this one in just a second.
Now,
one of the first things that we need to do because we're going to write the formulas.
Or rather,
we're gonna call the macro from she warm here.
We need to specify in Rome the first data that we call.
We're gonna have to specify that we should be on this sheet here.
Now,
if I go Teoh View Projects Explorer,
you will see that the data sheet is called shirt data.
So long and do here is on a line of code.
Say,
select the right sheet and I'm gonna add shit.
Data don't select,
and they go on their woman do.
That's going to ensure that we're on the right day to sheet when we capture all the data on
a copy that come way down here to our new sub.
And I'm gonna pace that in here,
but it's not sure Data we want to select its the front sheet,
which is called shirt main.
So that sounds like a Michael Jackson song.
Charmaine.
So they d show Maine.
We are now on the right,
chief.
So let's actually go to the right sheet and you can see that everything in here has
reference on the chart is completely screw if because all of the data is wrong in here,
so I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna record a simple macro,
and I'm gonna reference each of the cells that we want and then leave it a macro three
diesel.
The one and do is still the co fruit from it.
So the first thing I want to do is say equals Flip back to here and say that I'm gonna hit
enter,
and here I'm gonna say whether equals no,
Remember among Rome,
which is the first day to set,
we call.
So everything from 18 down to this 18.
So the weather in Rome is morning clouds.
So that's that one done here.
I'm going to say equals and I am looking for the temperature and that's here.
Enter and here I'm going to say equals on it feels like,
and I'm still in this first black a code,
and it feels like 30 that's going to allow us to use our charts here.
I'm going to say equals now.
This time I'm into our second block of CO.
So I need to come pass this 1st 18 down to the next 18 because this is Cancun and I'm gonna
hit enter.
So no,
I'm looking at that Particular cell temperature equals and I'm gonna come down to hear
their until next 18.
That's the temperature for Cancun on the fails like equals.
And I'm going to come back to here on We're on our 2nd 18 and it feels like 36 lucky people
in Cancun.
And now we're into London.
So medically,
here,
I'm going to say equals.
I want to come down past that 18 to our very last 18 our third day to set.
And I'm going to say more someone clouds because that is the first data from London here
I'm going to say equals flip back on day 18.
That's the temperature.
Enter and finally I'm going to say equals and it feels like in London on the 18th feels
like 25 not bad day for London.
It'll so far so good.
Norman,
do come back,
select everything all the way across,
and I'm just gonna double click.
And that's all about data populated.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.