Okay,
guys.
So this is really starting to take shape?
No,
because we have re populated the data on ear automatically.
Weather chart has automatically updated so we can see that we have.
This is obviously gonna be London down the bottom on.
If I click on here on the line whips,
I can't select for some reason,
not intelectual.
What's going on here?
If I click on the line,
you can see which data sets being selected.
So clicking on here shows us that we're in London.
Clicking on the are in shows us that we're in Rome and clicking on the Golden one shows
that we are in Cancun so clearly Cancun is doing better on the weather.
Anyway,
outside,
let's go back and have a look at that code that we've just generated.
I'm still recording.
Let me stop recording.
Okay,
So the Kurd that we just generated most of that is gonna be me flicking around all over the
place,
which is going to be complete nonsense.
So I am just gonna delete everything all the way up to this bit.
Just here where I started screwing around.
Okay,
so this is what the code looks like we want to simplify this somewhat.
So I'm gonna copy.
It'll delete,
and I'm just going to paste it in here.
So,
paste,
this is our redo formulas.
I'm just gonna delete everything from below it.
OK?
No.
Here we can see that we have ranged a six top select with the active cell.
Formula one always see you want right,
the formula immediately.
We know we don't need to do the select in the active cell weaken Just hit,
delete and say that.
So I'm just gonna do that for all of these.
I'm just gonna bringing them up,
get rid of the select,
and that's gonna literally have the light,
the amount of code that we're gonna have to execute.
So this may be boring to watch,
but it's You're gonna have to do yourselves eventually.
Okay,
so on d J six almost there and then we'll do a quick sanity check on.
We'll say s so we have a B c d e f g h i and J.
That's absolutely correct.
OK,
so the next thing we need to have a look at is tied in up this thing over here.
What?
We actually want to say is range a six to J six and then do this auto sort thing over here
.
This auto fell.
So this was just one of selecting a six.
And this is where I went over to get to the end of the data range.
Now,
because we know the data range is from a six through J six weaken,
Just hard code that directly in here so rather saying selection What we can say his range
open quotes a 62 j six close quotes,
close brackets,
auto fill on that is going to fill that day to down perfectly.
I don't think I need to select it on what I'm probably gonna do.
Wait.
The end is select a warm to go back to the start and we are almost done.
So what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna pause for a second while I run that entire section of code on.
Let's just make sure it works,
so I'll be back with you in just a second.
Okay,
guys,
And welcome back.
And there is the brand new brand new populated data,
which it's just pulled all the data from the Web site.
It took about 40 seconds or something to run,
but they go.
That's how you retrieve data from the website on Format it up.
So it looks perfectly nice in the table with a beautiful charts underneath.
Now one of the really neat tricks,
particularly when you have code that's going to take a minute or two to run or really
anything.
Love in about five seconds to run is toe have that meet little notification in the bottom
left hand corner,
then explains to the user exactly what is going on,
because the amount of times I've seen people executed macro that's going take site.
If it's a colossal macro state takes about 40 seconds to run,
people will say that this has crashed when in actual fact,
just that little bit of information to give them feedback on what's currently going on in
the code can save them complaining.
Okay,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at exactly how you do that.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next life