Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
And then we're gonna have a look at how we add that useful little message for the users
just down here.
So I'm gonna give myself a few lines on when it's actually called is the display status bar
.
So what I'm gonna say is application If I can spell application application dot and then
we're gonna look for the display.
Stay to spawn,
which will be down here somewhere.
Display status bar.
They dismayed display status.
Bar equals true.
That's the first thing that we need to say.
We want to set the display status.
My property to true name again.
Say application.
Don't stay to spar on.
There we go.
Status bar equals.
And then whatever way we want it to say,
So we can say just getting the weather I can't spell.
Just get in the weather for cast for room exclamation point,
dot,
dot and close quotes.
And it it's simple as that.
So what we're gonna do just run through that code one line to time F eight F eight F eight
.
Notice what happens down here.
The display states part is true and notice what happens now.
Just get in the weather forecast for Rome.
Now,
At the end of that code,
what we need to do is set the value to off.
But the first thing we're going to do before we do that we're gonna copy this and we're
going to add another message on what we're gonna say here is application dot status bar and
this is probably gonna be so fast that they use is not even gonna see it.
What we're gonna say is,
got it.
That means this part of the code is finished.
Execute in this will excuse and be displayed before we move on to our next world.
Now,
the last thing we need to do is turn the application status,
part status back to falls.
And that way we'll just about normal displays down there.
So I'm just gonna copy this a copy.
Onda set that,
too.
And it's very important that you do that.
Otherwise you will have that message displayed forever.
So I'm just gonna hit f eight and run through all of this code until we get to.
I'll run until we get to them.
It was going to take a few seconds because it's obviously It's retrieving data in real time
from the Internet.
So you can see here.
We're just getting the weather forecast for Rome on here.
It's no gonna say.
Got it?
And then it's going to return The state aspire to excel,
Andi And know what I'm gonna do is similar messages into the subs for Cancun on London on.
I'll be back with you a second where we're going to tie it all together.
Okay,
I'll see you that.