Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to this final lecture in this section on Web data retrieval.
Okay,
now what we're gonna do is final few touches.
What we have is this chart here.
So I'm just going to right,
click on the charts and I'm gonna cheat.
Let me scroll up so you can actually see that men right?
Click on the chart and choose a sign macro on my amazing web Queary is where our macro lips
.
So I'm just gonna double click on that.
And then when I click here,
all of our code will execute.
But at the moment,
if we think about what our code does,
it flips back to this sheet.
Richie,
VSEL The date of them flips back to this sheet there.
We don't actually want the user to see that.
So what we're gonna do here immediately after my amazing Web query sub starts?
I'm gonna make that private.
By the way,
I am going to say application don't screen updating equals false on that is going to stop
the excel sheet itself.
The Excel window will not change at all.
Other than the messages up the bar,
the main window display will not change.
If they're looking at this now,
remain looking at this,
but absolutely critical.
When every and only ever do this at the end of your code,
would you know everything works is you must turn the screen updating back on.
Okay,
let's give it a final check to make sure it works.
I'm just gonna delete all the data in here,
which is going to completely mess up their table.
I'm gonna come down here on the hit Our charts.
Onder who flee they go were retrieving the forecast from room.
I'm just gonna pause while it executes on.
There you go.
That's our code Complete,
completely dynamic.
Retrieving data in real time from the Internet building a beautiful table on the lovely
charts.
Look at OK,
I'll see you in the next section.