Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
we're gonna have a look at a different workbook event.
This so we're gonna have a look at that before print Workbook event.
Now again,
I'm gonna have to come to hear Select workbook by default.
It's gonna put workbook open,
Will delete down the second they were going to come to the procedure drop down box and he
at in the scroll way up to the top here.
I'm gonna choose before print.
So now I can safely delete this workbook open on Dhere is the module that we are working
with.
So a code is going to go in here now.
I'm gonna set up a variable for the print response on the set it up interject.
Is there nice and efficient?
So dim print response as interject.
And then what we want to do is display a message box to the user to ask them if they are
completely sure that they're paid you set up before they go ahead and print.
So P r T e S P O N s e print response equals M s G b o X.
Because we're doing a message box here.
I'm going to say Quotes please.
Ah please And show your pain.
Jews set correctly before printing.
Who's quotes?
Come out?
I'm gonna hit.
It'll score on forces Stand on to a new line on Dhere I'm know going to say vb Savy be okay
Council the B Okay Council.
So that way,
if they click OK,
it will continue to print If they clicked council,
it won't print So comer IHS,
you'll page set question mark close groups close brackets on down.
So there's a message box which we're going to read the response into the variable print
response.
So now we need to say what we're going to do when that variable is being populated.
So we're gonna say if PRT arrests Pontes Absolute now,
that's right.
If if print response equals,
let's say vb council then and because we don't want anything to happen after that.
So let's flip back to excel on here.
I'm gonna hit control and Pete's bring your by a print dialog box.
I'm gonna hit the print button on,
then notice what happens.
This little dialogue box pops up here,
so our code is executed beautifully.
It says,
Is your paint set up,
please ensure your pages are set up correctly before printing.
If I click council,
then the end will trick Abacus of it.
BB council.
Andi,
If I hit OK,
then it will go ahead and print.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.