Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
here's another thing getting Use the workbook open.
Eventful.
You can use it to track how many times people have bean in and out of the worksheets.
Now,
one of the tabs on this particular workbook,
this workbook events is called the user log.
No,
If I hit F 11 get the visual.
Basic editor in a normal module.
I have written this code here on all this does is it adds the user name to the bottom of
the list.
So the list is here,
so the user names going to go here on the time and date that they accessed.
It goes there now,
if we just look at this,
what we have is the the order of hierarchy.
So we are stating it is sure.
Use a log and you can see that that has a V B name of S H user log here.
So we're calling this sheet bites BB name.
We are specifying the range five invalids say 50,000.
Just think,
actually get loads of people going into the sheet.
So we're gonna start outline a 50,000 old wait up set up,
then we're gonna offset one and then in the back of the value property we're gonna enter
the environment string user name that you'll remember that from way back in the my macro
book section.
If you want to capture the user name,
environment,
string,
open rackets,
user name in quotes,
close brackets that is going to get us the user name.
So we're gonna know who went into the spreadsheet and similarly to at the time of day were
just going to use the hierarchy again.
Shh.
User log range Be 55,000 All the way up.
Offset one on Do the value as now.
And if we want to hide that later if we want to hide it so the user can't Unhygienic from
excel,
we can use the property.
Excel very hidden on that way.
The only way you can unhygienic it is in here in the visual basic Elyssa in the properties
window.
Andi in your properties down here now at the moment just so I can see it,
I haven't done that.
So let's have a look at how we incorporate that Now,
at the moment,
you may be thinking on a second I thought we were looking at a workbook.
Open event.
So let's just have a look at the workbook.
Open event the workbook.
Open event Say's user form 0.1 show on that brings us this splash green that comes up now
from the user form.
If we come over to here,
we can get to the code window for the use of form itself.
Now,
by default,
we here have private sub user form Click.
We are not looking for the click event.
We are looking for the initialize events.
So that is the second The use of form initialize is that is it shows We want to execute
some code here.
Now here's the really cool thing.
We have now written this piece of code in a normal module and it is called update user log
.
I am just going to copy the name of that,
come back to the use of form and go to the code window for the use of form on inside the
user form initialize I'm gonna say run space quotes the name of the macro that we want to
run close quotes and then I'm gonna click off now I'm gonna hit save I'm gonna close the
visual basic editor noticed that there is absolutely nothing in here in the workbook events
.
User log.
I'm gonna close that.
I'm gonna open that file one more time on.
Here we go.
Welcome to my jazzy spreadsheets.
And when I close,
you can see that now the user log has Allen because that's my sign in Name was last
accessed a 28 16 At 13.
13 I'm gonna close it again.
I'm going to save and here I'm going to double click it again.
I notice what happens this time.
Welcome to my jazzy spreadsheet and I have no gone into it.
Alan again,
20 through the 8th 2016 at 13.
13 and 38 seconds.
Whereas previously it was 19 seconds there obviously cannot as much codas you want to this
He can have it save or send emails or whatever you want it to do all or literally select
the front sheet because some people,
if many people use the same spreadsheet,
someone may leave it on this sheet and you actually want them to come back all the way over
here,
right the way to the guide sheets.
So in fact,
let's just that.
That s O sheet guide is called S H Guide that has a V be named Suratman.
Do come back to my modules.
It's over.
Click module one.
And there I'm just four fun.
I'm gonna say ship guide don't select.
And there you go.
So now I'm gonna close that whip said Daisy,
I'm gonna close that.
I'm gonna save that.
I'm gonna close again.
We were actually on that sheet,
so that's not gonna make any difference whatsoever,
is it?
Okay,
let's say we're on this sheet.
No,
it's close it and save it and open it again.
Eso No,
we weren't on the guide sheet.
No opening the file and then go.
We're going straight back to the guy.
Cheeks are splash screen has appeared.
And if we was way over here to our use a log ago,
you can see every single time that I have opened this spreadsheet.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.