Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Now you'll remember.
And you may well have noticed that when we recorded Mac rose up to know we had the option
to enter a keyboard shortcut,
and I normally just skip over it on.
The reason for that is a lot of the keyboard shortcuts are already taken,
particularly if we just look at the control on letters.
So looking at the list here,
we can see the A B,
C D E f G h i k n o P r S,
Y and Zed are already keyboard shortcuts in Excel.
Now,
if you were for argument's sake,
to record a macro on,
assign a keyboard shortcut of control and P,
your control and P would always execute Your macro would never bring up the print dialog
box again.
So this is why normally avoid using keyboard shortcuts.
Plus is also a very good chance that even if you picked one that wasn't on there so we can
see that we have a gap between D and F,
which means control and e may well be free,
so we could easily assign the macro to control Andi e.
But in a year's time would really remember that this particular keyboard shortcut control
and e triggers this particular macro because within a few weeks you will have built dozens
of these things I can almost guarantee you are not going to remember them all.
So the best ways to run them are either from buttons from pictures or alternatively,
from workbook events.
And we're gonna have a look at all those in the upcoming lectures.
But for now,
this is the reason that I don't use keyboard shortcuts.
This less is a downloadable resource.
If you do intend to use keyboard shortcuts over,
suggest you print this out on,
then scribble on here the ones that you do a sign.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.