Okay,
guys.
And welcome back now,
you will have gathered by now so far in this section that there are lots and lots of
workbook events on.
We've looked at a few of them and we've worked out that you can put code in the workbook
event.
You can call code from a workbook event,
as we did with the user form in the splash screen on.
We then had that access in the macro that were written in a normal module.
So literally,
if you can imagine it,
you can probably code it now.
One particularly useful thing on the before close,
I used to manage a team,
not the people who are named here,
which are all friends of mine.
But I used to manage a team where one of the individuals always used to filter to their
name and then save the workbook and close it.
And that way,
when any other user went in,
they had to go in and unhurried his name.
Un apply the filter so they could see their own name.
No.
What?
This particular better code is really,
really simple.
What it's gonna do is go to this sheet on It is going to remove any auto fill for.
So for argument's sake,
let's just say I usually pick.
Let's click Ashley.
So OK,
so actually is in here.
This is his work.
Lissy has thing want to do thing too.
So thing one thing six and thinking.
11 on.
I'm gonna hit.
Save now.
Olsen F 11.
I'm gonna come into this workbook.
I am going to choose workbook.
I'm not been delete that just yet.
I'm gonna choose Be full clothes,
which now means I can delete this.
So all ominous do in here because this sheet the coming on but the sheet was called it was
called Random Data sets.
The random data set sheet has a VB name of shirt RND data.
So what I'm gonna do is say sure are nd data don't select,
and that is going to make sure I am on the right sheet.
And then I am going to say active sheets dot on What I want to do is choose show oh,
data.
And the next thing I want to do is say active workbook don't safe.
So before it closes,
it is going to select this sheet.
It is gonna un apply the filters and it is going to save.
So let's just go back to that sheet.
So here,
I'm gonna click.
Save.
Imagine.
Now I am.
Actually,
I'm gonna close the file.
I'm gonna come over on Rio from the file and notice what happens this time.
We are back on this sheet on It is no being applied.
So we can know.
See everyone.
So let's imagine Young Danielle does exactly the same thing.
So Danielle is beaning.
She saved it.
I'm just gonna double click on when it reopens.
There you go.
Everyone could be sitting again.
Okay.
I'm gonna see you in the next Like to ever gonna get onto work sheet events.
I'll see you in the next lecture.