Okay,
guys.
Um,
welcome back.
So now we're gonna have a look at a quick fun one.
This is gonna be a work sheet.
Event is supposed to work.
Book event on what we're gonna do over here,
you'll see all the green ones are the work book events that we've looked at so far.
Just copy and paste The code exactly is the red comments say,
up here on now,
We're going to go on to this one,
which is a worksheet event that says you can't pick this.
So what we're gonna do hit Olsen F 11.
We're going to go to the sheet that is named up here as you can't pick this.
Where are we ago?
You can't pick this.
I double clicked sheet 10 which is You can't pick this on.
We are now in a work sheet module,
so I'm just gonna choose worksheet,
and you can see that by default we get selection change.
We're going to come to actually,
But for now,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna pick the worksheet,
activate.
So when the worksheet is activated,
that is,
the user has clicked it.
We're going to execute the code that's in between the private sub on the end sub on all
we're going to say here is a sure guide not select,
which you'll remember from a few lectures ago is the name of the guide sheet.
So let's just hit Olsen F 11 and see what happens when we click this.
You can't pick this when we click it.
It immediately goes to the guide sheet.
And even if we scroll over,
no matter how many times we try it,
the code you'll execute and automatically take you back to the guide sheet.
Okay,
I'll see him in the next lecture where we'll have a look at another one.
That's just for fun.
I'll see you in the next lecture.