Okay,
guys,
from Welcome back Now,
in this section what?
We're gonna have a look at our the U D efs.
The user defined functions.
Now,
as we know,
there are loads and loads literally hundreds of functions already built into excel as a
standard and eventually something like the some function which we can see just here.
So when we type equals some,
some is a function on now.
Years ago,
Excel didn't have anywhere near the number of functions that it has currently s o There was
a need to create a function specifically for re users need no.
Since then,
most things have never been added as a standard.
But this still could be an instance where you need to perform a specific calculation that
is unique to your need.
Now,
just give you an example.
Years ago,
pie wasn't included as a standard function in Excel.
So you if you wanted to calculate pi,
you needed to create a UDF use of defined function.
So part is going to be one of the first things that we have a look at.
But firstly,
a couple of things to remember functions live in standard modules.
So here you can just say that I've added module one just a standard function,
just like we've done with the sub's up to this point.
So as a function is always coded in a standard module thing,
number one thing number two functions can be called by their name in the workbook in which
you created them.
So if you created a function called my clever function,
you could only call that from the workbook in which you created it on where it saved.
Or if you have that workbook open,
you can use it in another open workbook.
But you will have to change the way you call it.
But we'll come to that shortly.
Okay,
so they go.
They use defined functions,
live in a standard module on They differ slightly from the subroutines that we've looked at
up to this point,
inasmuch as they begin with the word function.
So instead of saying sub,
we will say function.
So we will say function pie.
And yes,
I know that's not how you spell pie.
Now,
what we're gonna do here,
we're going to specify which arguments are going to be required.
So I'm just going to say my value.
And I'm going to say that as a very and because I don't know whether it's going to be a
long number or a number with a load of decimal places after it.
So variant is going to capture all of those when they hit enter,
you can see that end function is already being had added,
just like when you type sub the end sub sortie added.
So here we go.
We've now got the shell of our function.
Now what we need to do is add some code into it.
No together return value.
What you need to say is the return value is going to be the same as the function name.
So here the function name is pie.
So I'm gonna type Pi equals and then I'm going to say this argument,
the my value multiplied by I think I can't remember what bias to that many decimal place.
I think it's 3.1415159 something like that.
So they go.
So now that is our function complete.
So we have function pie,
my value that is going to be the arguments.
That is what we're going to perform a calculation on and we're same pie because that's the
name of the function equals my value multiplied by 3.14159 So here,
when they come over to excel,
I can and type equals pie and you can see that that is now a function within Excel on when
I double click it or well,
he's open brackets we can know Put the arguments in now Number one drawback of custom
functions You do not get tool tips,
so you're gonna have to remember what the arguments are.
So now if I said pie 10 close brackets hit enter,
you can see that the calculation of pie for 10 is three point.
Where is it?
31.4159 I need new glasses.
Okay,
so that's a very simple demonstration of how you do it.
So let's have look at another function.
Let me just make that look a little bit pretty like that.
So Okay,
so an ex function show is going to be square me.
That almost is definitely a square function in excel.
But we're going to say square me.
So here's a new function.
So this time what we're going to say I haven't said what we're gonna use.
We're going to use my value as a variant again.
So here they go square me,
my value as variant So say square me because it has to have the same name as the function.
Thanks a equals and it's going to be my value multiplied by my value.
On day you go.
It's a simple Is that so?
Here,
if I said equals our on There you go.
We can sniff c square me.
If I said five and closed off the rockets hit,
Enter,
they go.
The square of five is 25 similarly I could actually reference that self.
So you could say square me Open rackets point to that cell closer rackets and hit ends.
That may go the square off 25 s,
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we can have a look at another simple use for the use
of defined function.
I'll see you there