Okay,
guys.
And welcome back there.
So far,
the couple of examples that we've had look at function pie spelt incorrectly on functions
square me both do calculations,
but you can easily using a UDF user defined function to use to pull some data about the
spreadsheet that you're working in.
Now what I'm gonna do here,
I'm gonna create another function on gonna say function.
Where is this file?
And I don't need to specify any parameters between the between the brackets here.
So what I'm gonna say is here I want to copy that because that's the return value.
I'm gonna say,
Where is this file equals?
And I'm gonna say this work book,
adult path,
and you can find a load of these different things.
In the macro book section,
there's there's loads of different things,
like finding the use of find in the name of the file,
all kinds things in there.
So now let me just a little of that.
If here I say,
equals where you can see where is this?
Fire has been added here as a user defined function.
Just gonna hit the tab closer brackets.
When I hit enter let me just drag that out so you can see they go.
This particular file lives in my f dropbox you to me excel level three v b A programming
slash Complete.
So there you go.
You don't have to use a calculation.
You can use a custom function user defined function to return information.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next one where we can have a look at doing something a little more
complicated.
I'll see you there.