Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
let's have a look at another function.
But this time,
one with a few more moving parts.
Now,
what we're gonna do for this one,
as we're gonna say function and we're gonna call it be day can't down Andi,
We're gonna say we'll stick with my value.
My value as very it rips very,
aren't there?
Where are we?
My value as variant bump bump.
Okay,
so this is going to give us a countdown timer to our birthday or any date in the future.
So let's just get was back to excel.
Say 25th of 12 2016 that is.
Let me make that so you can actually see the 25th of 12 2016.
Let's imagine,
that's our birthday.
Now here.
What we could say is now on,
we can see that currently it's the second of October 2016 at 8 38 in the morning on we can
also say equals whips equals that minus that looks notes the other way around.
Alan's equals that minus now so we can see that we're currently as I recall,
this 83 0.639 blah,
blah,
blah days away from Christmas.
Okay,
so what?
We have a few elements in there.
If we wanted to return,
he says that number,
we could literally just write this calculation here inside the dysfunction.
But what if we actually wanted it to say it's X amount of days and this many hours and this
many minutes and this many seconds?
Well,
that's what we're going to do in this lecture.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna add a few variables.
So here,
we're going to say,
Let's set up the very boss,
the very balls on,
Let's say dim,
let's call Count Day.
Let's capitalize that.
So it's easy to read Count Day,
and I'm gonna make them always variances variance because we're not actually execute as
variant.
We're not gonna We're not gonna be calculating or we're not gonna be writing a piece of
code that's gonna run over 20,000 loans of data.
We're actually gonna be writing a piece of code that works on one eso who?
So let's have can't anyone else do.
We have.
We have ours.
So let's have cames Allah.
Let's have count minutes.
Manute on counts Second Okay,
so there are four elements we want to return the day,
the number of days,
the number of hours,
the number of minutes and the number of seconds.
Ok,
fantastic.
Then we need to do a calculation to work out each of those four elements.
So what do you say?
Count day equals on.
What I want to do is I'm gonna build this in ST someone say it's my value.
Minus now open and close brackets on.
That's going to give us essentially this.
That's this formula just here,
written in plain old excels in written in VB a code.
Now what we do need to do is actually return the interview.
So if we become too if you want to come to the formula here,
what we would actually say here is int over brackets to come to the end,
close rackets on that would tell us interject valleys,
everything before the decimal place.
So we have 83 days.
So we're going to do is I'm gonna shrink that down is going to come in from to this here
and we're also going to say int on this will be a number.
So now we're going to return 83 just like we did in Excel.
Just there.
So so far,
so good,
we've managed to return the interject the number of days.
But what we were actually want this to do is be a string.
So what we're gonna do is we're going to concoct innate this and tag on the word day.
So I'm gonna add on.
I'm gonna adding quote a space because I want a gap between the number on the word days
that I'm probably gonna want a comma because we're going to come on to do hours,
minutes and seconds.
And then I'm gonna close the quotes.
So now that will return 83 at this particular moment in time,
Space days.
Fantastic.
Now we also have can tell us,
Can't on that is gonna equal.
And I know I haven't finished.
Yes,
let's just stick zero in there.
What I'm gonna do is just copy all of that from bottom up pace of their But instead of
saying into what I'm going to say is there were's It's our is Nick.
It's our Okay,
So our my value Andi,
it was on gonna copy that.
There we go.
And now I'm gonna be onto.
Let me just tidy that up a little bit.
There we go.
So they were going to be on camp Minute Newt.
And this time we're going to say instead of our mute or I can type a Z,
Everyone who's watched any of my goals is Will know Min Utes Eso we should say that no
minutes minute.
There we will say minutes here so minutes and finally we want the seconds so crappy pace
underneath.
And this is Kent second,
second on.
We want Second Onda and we can no tied to this end.
Bit appear and say seconds exclamation point Lego We have no built using my value.
The input we're gonna work out.
What?
The day is Another word Days on the comment.
Then we're gonna work out the animals.
Then we're gonna work at the minutes,
and we're gonna build this string into the value be day countdown.
So what we're going to say is,
let me just copy.
It's actually that was safe.
Tell him in the entire thing in so being day came down,
got be,
Stick that in here.
And that is gonna equal there.
We're gonna build it all together.
We're gonna say Count Day,
game day and groups,
not times.
Andi can't our Andi times again.
Eso We have missed the and offer there.
So we have count Day Can't our helps minutes can It's second And then when I click off,
if they all capitalize,
I've got it right,
OK,
so now let's get rid of all of that.
In fact,
let's put that back in 2015 12 2016 On here I'm going to say equals B day and you can see
Here we go be day countdown open brackets.
I'm gonna point to the date that we're looking for closer brackets Hiss.
And that may go 83 days,
15 hours,
14 minutes and 59 seconds to Christmas.
No,
here's the thing.
What we actually have there is a formula that if we If if we hit f two and come back into
it,
you can see that it changes.
But if we hit F nine hit in f nine that you can't see that it does not re calculate.
So there is something that we can add into this code that's gonna make it re calculate.
So here What I'm gonna say is application dot volatile.
And when you say application dot volatile,
particularly you spell application correctly application dot Volatile.
This forces a recount on F nine or Cal Canal.
They so No.
Every time they hit f nine,
it's going to re calculate because it is volatile.
Now,
obviously,
we've gone through a long and complicated process to actually build that string.
What we could do,
instead of doing all of these steps,
is actually put in something that looks just like this of his one of prepared earlier.
So here we have exactly the same thing.
But we have used these individual calculations and built them into a string in just one
line.
So if you want to do it that way,
that's perfectly fine.
And then you could either just delete here and you could ram out all of this Or you could
delete it and literally just have that as your function.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture,
where we're gonna have a look at a function where we have more than one argument.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture