Okay,
guys.
And welcome back up to this point,
we'll have a look at just using a single argument in our use of defined functions.
But here,
we're gonna have one way we're going to use to.
Obviously,
you can have as many as you like,
but you must remember the order in which they appear.
Because don't forget you don't get tool tips with user defined functions.
Eso here,
one of them do is in a sailor that that that I'm going to say Discount.
No.
Imagine the scenario we have a business on.
We give people a discount,
depending on how many of our goodies that they buy.
So here will have his custom function shelter.
It's called Discount Couch.
I have two arguments.
I have my quantity,
which I want to type in here I have my price,
which I'm gonna type in here on this function is going to be used to derive the discount.
So I have a couple of variables that have price break as interject.
Imagine that we only sell in hold units on.
I have discount as a single precision variable because I'm just gonna be dealing with
currency on a discount of a percent at a percentage.
OK,
so now what we need to do the first test we need to do,
you can see the parameters.
Here.
The price break is 1000 and if they breach $1000 they by 1000 and one,
then they're going to get a discount of 5%.
So now what we need to do is add a logical test so we can actually test to see if the
quantity entered is greater than 1000 or not.
So we're just going to use a simple,
logical testing and say,
if my quantity,
we're going to say if my quantity is less than or equal to.
But actually,
having type one thing has never taken just a price make price break,
then then what do we want to do?
If it's less than that,
we want to say,
Let me just add the end difficult.
I'm frequently forgetting to do those and they'll have the Elsa's.
Well,
we're in there so they go.
If the my quantity that is our first argument is less than the price break,
which is 1000 then discount couch and you'll remember that this has to be the same as this
,
so the discount Kulka is going to equal nothing.
OK,
so now let's.
So let's let's just test that.
So if we said 100 on their pound each,
then we just change the format in groups.
Let me just change the formatting on the east currency formatting currency.
Okay,
obviously whatever currency or in it's perfectly fine.
So now I'm going to say,
What's it called?
It's called this Can calculus A equals disk?
No,
but the one thing to remember whatever case you use here is exactly the same case that
appears.
He s so if this said discount go all in uppercase,
it would appear here all in uppercase of discount coke.
My first argument is quantity Comer.
My second argument is price there.
So when I hit that and hit enter zero,
they go because 100 is less than 1000.
Calculation is straight ful with discount calculation equals absolutely nothing at all.
So let's just copy that and let on in our else.
So discount talc equals is going to be my quantity multiplied by my price whips eso This is
what's gonna happen if they breached the 1000 set here and it's gonna be multiplied by
discount on the discount.
Here is 5%.
They've all capital I.
So I have no typing mistakes in there,
so let's try that.
So if we have 999 we still get no discount.
If we had 1000 we still have no discount book.
If we have 1000 and one they go,
we know get 5% discount on the discount.
Value is £50 on 50 p.
Okay,
so have fun with playing with you.
D efs on.
I'll see you in the next section.