Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now it does There.
We're not quite done with user defined functions just yet.
I've had a question from student named Ram who has asked in the What can I have for dinner
section of this course in level two?
You remember the one where we we type in the names of all the sheet names down here and
then we hyperlink to them.
Is there a formula that we can use?
It will actually read all of the sheet names this implants or is there isn't.
But we can write a really simple user defined function to do just that.
So I've tagged this onto the download and you'll never find this at the bottom of the
download code in your get your code here.
Now,
what we have is function called get sheet name,
and that should give you a clue as to where it's going to do on.
We're gonna,
uh we're gonna have a number as long near the number is going to be the index number off
the sheet,
so you'll recall that she won His is index one.
The second sheet along.
This is the order in which they appear.
Is she too?
So be sheets to on.
That's basically all the number is going to do.
So you'll recall from an early the earlier lectures that the name of the function must be
where we return the value,
too.
So get sheet name equals sheets,
number and name.
So let's just have a look at the an operation.
So this is the first sheet in our workbooks.
So if I typed,
get and you can see I get sheets.
Name there.
If I click on there,
click one.
That is the first sheet going left to right on.
Did that hit?
Enter?
I get.
She won.
If I change that to sheet,
too,
I get get your code here because that's the name,
their second sheet.
But the idea of this is that we have a formula that weaken dragged down.
Now,
obviously,
typing one in here and two in there is not going to do the trick.
But what we can do is incorporate the row.
So if I hit one cool on one and close the brackets and then hey,
center number one is sheet one and then I can drag this down and row will increase to two
on,
then three and then four and then five and so on and so on.
Selectively.
If you have 100 sheets across here,
you just write this formula.
Once using this UDF get sheet name drank 100 times on all of your sheet.
Names will be listed in the order in which they appear across here Now.
Obviously,
you cannot do never trap up the front here so we could say equals if a role open rackets,
What do we want to return?
If it's an error,
let's return nothing hit enter and then drag that down and then we'll just get blanks Where
we've run out of sheet Seems okay now.
I'll see you in the next section.