Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another lecture.
Now,
technically,
this is a student questions and selected,
but the solution lies in the UDF.
The questions from Chun Li Lu on what Charlie Lu asks is is it possible to use counts if
through on non contiguous data,
whether they're named or not really doesn't make any difference in the answer is no because
that functionality is just not built into excel out of the box.
But we can actually bypass that and create a user defined function.
Given us the solution that we're looking for So there's that there's a file that
accompanies this on.
Did you can find whips?
Let me foot the Excel for look first,
getting ahead of myself on the file is called Super Can't if and super some if because
there's very little difference in the CO between counting and something.
So here's the problem.
So let's say we had genic on and then let us use numbers.
12341 Onda.
We use that as a a date.
Eso we say data one.
I'm used,
uh,
account if equals ken's If open rackets and we say data one comma and we're looking for one
close brackets.
Centre Exeter one appears twice in our named range off data one.
That's this.
Even if we came over here and 12311 three on,
we made this unnamed range data to on.
We used data to hear and counted all the ones you can see that we get Fox.
We've got 1234 But this data data,
we're going on date two.
It's still contiguous.
Even though we have a gap in between actually specified the name data.
Two runs from a three to see seven with me so far.
OK,
but what happens if we say we want this?
So I'm just selecting that.
Hold them control.
Copy all of that and call this data three hit.
Enter their lives.
We try and use the candidate.
If on change that to data three,
you'll see that we get an era.
So here we go.
This is how you build a you dear function for it.
You'll find the code here,
so just copy all of this.
Come to the developer ribbon,
Go to visual Basic insert module and paste this code in here now,
normally,
when I'm writing you d efs.
The first thing I do is create a program and just test at my logic to make sure that I
could actually do what I'm trying to do.
And that's what this sub test does were dimension and arranges.
Arranged my name range.
I'm gonna call it data.
I call it something else.
When I wrote this code,
call the data three.
So Data three set my range.
The actual code is fully remedy for this is just me playing about eh?
So what we're gonna do is we're going to get the range.
It's called Day 23 and we're gonna set that to my range,
which creates an excel on object with all of the cells and all of the data for those cells
in it.
And then what we're gonna do is we're just gonna iterated through each of the cells and say
for each this cell that with cell,
we're looking at at that particular time in this range data three.
Then if this cell value equals one,
that is,
we're looking for the number one.
Their next equals X plus one so that on the first pass through the first cell,
we're looking at.
If X equals one that first X will be zero but will add zero plus one will become one.
And then the next time we find one again,
it will increase X by one.
And that's how that works.
So let me see if I can shrink that down a little bit.
Whips.
That's made it too big.
Let me see if I could move That ended the way a little bit on D show you how that works.
Hopefully,
that's still in shot.
What I want to do here is I'm just gonna have to stop.
This won't be in the code when you download it and I'm gonna add a watch.
Two x so x.
So let me just struck that down so you can see.
I guess I'm just gonna room that come back over here.
I'm just gonna run that to the stop debug Run to cursor boom.
So there you can see the code actually works.
So we've got the range day 23 We set it,
that is,
we've created an object with all the cells in that range to the variable my range on.
We've looped through each of the cells in that in my range until we find a one.
Then we return the number 41234 and that's how that works.
Now there's a say that would be in the thing that you download,
but that's how it works.
So top.
Let me just delete that and click stuff.
So here,
that's the simple code to work out how to do it.
And here I have butchered that and turned it into If I can make that full screen,
and I've turned that into this the super counted function.
So it's just like any of the function.
This is the name of the function.
Super can't if my name ranges variant because we have no idea what data we're gonna have
been there.
Look for that's what we're looking for a string on.
We're going to return.
The answer is a string as well,
so even if it's a number that we're looking for,
it'll actually come.
Backers a string so rather than the number four it will be the text for You can change that
if you need to.
So it's a you the African tive with non continuous data and be the named pain judge that
should say range.
I'll try and remember to change that in the download.
Must be in quotes in the formula.
So dim my Rangers range holds the named range dim the camp.
That's the iteration where we're going through and every time we find a match were
increasing by one.
So that's as long because I I honestly don't know how many bits of data there are so long.
Pretty much covers everything.
So now we're gonna go create the object to hold all the cells in the range.
There were only actually interested in the value.
There are loads of properties associated with leet selling Arrange.
All we're trying to get to is the value so set my range equals range,
my named range.
That's what we're gonna get typed in in the formula.
And then we're going to do that loop just like we did up here.
So we're gonna loop through eat selling specified range object which we just created here,
and they were going to perform a logical test to see to sell value.
We're currently on matches our criteria.
Now the criteria is going to be the criterium is going to be the look for if so,
increased the count by one.
So if this cell value each interational so we're looking at if it matches our look for
value than the cams equals the camera plus one.
So on the first pass through before we get here,
the count will be zero.
Once we find a match,
the zero will be zero plus one.
So the count will become one.
And every time we find a match that will increase by one and then finally to return the
value to excel we're going to say super can't if the name of our function equals the camps
which we've got from here,
so super can't If we're going to say the range on what we're looking for,
let's flip back to excel So if we said equals super and you can see that it's come up their
super can't if open brackets the named range must be in quotes.
My data three think it was called my data three comma we're going to be looking for Let's
say we're looking for the number one.
Hand it enter.
No,
Maybe I didn't call it my day to three.
What did I call it?
A day to three.
That's cool.
The Data three and then we're actually looking at the right thing.
So now we can We can see that in date of three noncontiguous.
1234 instances of one occur.
Let's just change that to a different number.
And there you can see the three occur All we could look at number five and see that that
occurs twice.
What?
We just talked five in there and here we could point to that itself.
The'keeper's thing is your data set that your named range must be in quotes.
So if we look to that that you said,
we still get the same answer now slightly differently.
Uh,
let's say Rita Onda se Rita,
that was with space.
Sue Bob,
Jack,
uh,
Bob,
they because we're looking at this south,
we can see that restore appears once.
But if we were to type it and we couldn't just say Rita because Rita doesn't particularly
mean anything,
so you get value.
So if you're actually gonna type in the value groups rather than look it another cell,
you must enclose the string.
That is the word that you are looking for in quotes a ***.
That's how it works now.
Very simply,
I've also just adapted this to say super some if which works pretty much saying like no,
no ranges where intercourse.
We don't know what date we're gonna have on what we are looking for.
And all I've done is I have modified this line of Cose earthy sell,
value equals Look for then the sum equals the song plus this cell value.
So let me just demonstrate that.
So if we said 1111 seven So the summer veil accidents for the one in there,
the sum of our ones should be 123456 So if we said equals super some if open rackets data,
lips,
data three comma one.
We should get the answer of far 6123456 That's right,
They go.
So that's how it works for a summit as well.
Okay,
and that's all there is to it.
Hopefully,
that's helpful.
If you have any questions yourself,
do let me know.
Have a great deck and I'll see you in the next,
like Jack