Okay,
guys.
And welcome back,
right?
The core piece of code to add a new folder.
Toe windows is just one single line of code on that is this line of cold code here It's M k
d I R make directory.
Then we have a space,
then enclosed in quotes at the beginning.
At the end,
we have the path to the folder,
which is this first part just hear a backslash and then the name of the folder that we want
to create It is simple as that.
So here is the folder my folders on my desktop.
And if I just run this code by hitting play,
you'll notice that I know get a folder called my new folder in that very path.
OK,
we're gonna take that single line of code and we're going to turn into something more
useful.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.