Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
in this one,
we're gonna have a look at the complete code again,
and we'll just go through it as it executes,
and I'll talk you through what it does.
But I want to draw your attention to this tab down here called sub folder.
Structure on what we have in here on the names of the four sub folders that we want to
create in the new folders that were creating for companies A through H.
So company A will have these four new folders inside its folder as well company B C all the
way through to H.
So this is the code.
We have four variables we have my path on.
I'm just specified my pathway at the top here.
So that way,
if we ever have to change the path,
we just lying change this line of code and we're golden.
So in this instance,
it see uses Alan,
desktop slash my folders backslash.
Remember,
for this code to run your computer,
unless your name is Alan,
you're gonna have to change that to your path.
Okay,
so that's our 1st 1 structure array struck array is an array that is going to hold the
names of all of our sub folders.
Okay,
We have fold account,
which coming back here is going to be the count of the number of folders which we need to
know so we can re dimension era ray toe hold exactly the right number of folders.
Notice way at the top.
By the way,
that this is option explicit,
which is sorry is option based one which forces air erase the beginner number one.
It's also option explicit,
so it forces valuable declaration.
So that's our folder count.
How many folders are we're going to need to create a sub folder loop?
Well,
that's just a loop toe loop through to create each onthe e sub folder.
So let's just have f eight through there.
So this sheet here as a VB name of S h f l D stroked dot select were already selected fold
account.
We're going to use that range range a 12 a one end excelled down.
Doc can't and we can see that that is full.
Now we know that we have four folders or four sub folders.
We're going to re dimension are array to match that number Fall account F eight Solar array
is now set up with four elements,
one each for each of these four things.
Now we're just gonna loop through the sub folders from one to fold account and we're gonna
lewd into on the first interational.
Some folder,
loop one,
the cells,
some folder loop,
one duck value,
which is 11 So it's going to be this cell.
And then when I looked through again,
it's gonna be to one,
cause it's road to now because of all the loop is now in its second iteration from Bom bom
bom bomp.
And there we have invoices in array Position one poet sorts into credit notes in three and
other stuff in four share Index,
Stop,
Select Back over to here,
B four,
Select.
This is all looking very familiar.
This code up to this point is identical to the code that we've just created other than the
fact that I now have my path on the active cell to the left.
So make directory my path.
I'll live through Alu three once,
and then we'll have locally in action.
So now we're going to go through the sub folder loop and this is an inner loop inside the
wider outer loop.
So we have a while when glued on the outside and inside.
Once you've created that folder,
we go through the same routine.
But we'll go through it four times because we have four folders.
So again,
we're going to use the same structure we're going to loop through when I hit F eight whips
when I hit F eight.
So some folder loop is going to be number one on the first pass through,
and that is gonna pull structure array Number one,
which holds the name of our first son folder,
said the path is exactly the same.
Still m k still the i r.
But it's no looking inside its parent folder,
which is company A on the second pass through that loop structure array will be worth two.
So it's going to return the second some folder 34 on,
then down to here and then loop through again on again.
Okay,
Now,
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna stop that.
I'm gonna expand this window.
I'm going to bring up that fold referred and find it for me.
Just one second.
My folders have deleted what we've already done.
And you still can't say it again the second year in a car seat.
So now I'm gonna delete these,
cause we're not particularly interested on these eye blinks again.
Delete shift cells left whichever.
Okay,
so now we have companies A B C D.
Through to h with a subject,
a sub folder structure of invoice,
poachers,
criminals and other stuff that we want to appear in.
Each of these.
This is the directory we are looking at and let's just hit the button.
So there go all of our hyperlinks.
Here are all of our folders and I clicked.
Company A.
You said we have a fold of credit notes.
Invoices of the suffering purchase orders.
Obviously,
these are alphabetical company.
Be exactly the same thing on on and on and on on day.
There you go.
You've just created a complete directory structure,
including sub folders.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next life