Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
from this lecture,
you'll find a downloadable resource.
And that is an excel file called email automation dot x l s X.
And in there you're going to find us file.
That looks pretty much like this.
A tab here that say's get your code here.
So what we're going to do in this section is look a automating outlook so you can send an
email campaign from the push of a button.
Now,
what we have in this particular demonstration is we have an amazing sunscreen product that
we want to sell to people with blond hair.
So here we have our data set,
which I know you've seen before.
We only have about 50 people in there,
but we have some people with blunt hat,
and they are the people that we want to send our email too.
So I'm just gonna flip to outlook so,
you know,
there's no trickery.
I'm just gonna close that bet so you can see that outlook has no e mails in it.
So won't do is press the button on the flip back to outlook on,
depending on how fast my Internet connection is any second.
Now,
all of our e mails from a email routine should start dropping into our in box now,
what will weight him?
Perhaps I'm not going to speak.
While that happens.
Chris is gonna keep making a noise.
But here we go.
Everyone with blunt hair in our list is now receiving an email.
Obviously all the email addresses of Just Excel essentials at gmail dot com.
So everything is going to come to me.
But you can see if we look here.
The 1st 1 is to Luca,
and we have our wonderfully tailored message here.
The next one is to Leo on the next one is tamale.
So it's actually extracting their first name so we can personalize our email and they go,
The routine is complete there,
Just in case You ever hear these terms?
There are two ways that you can automate.
Outlook from excel using B B A.
You can either use early binding or you can use late binding.
We're gonna use late binding and I only ever use late binding,
early binding.
There are some advantages in that it slightly easier to code.
The major disadvantages is that you have to set a reference to the outlook library in your
visual basic applications editor.
Now,
that is not a problem whatsoever providing that the code on the spreadsheet is always run
from your machine.
If you give it to your body when they press the button,
it will not work.
So need gonna have to go to their machine.
And you're gonna have to go into then visual basic editor and set the reference to the
outlook object library.
And if they pass it on to someone on the other side of the department and you're gonna have
to go to their machine and do the same so literally,
if your programs ever gonna have to be used by multiple people use late binding I always do
on it's a jolly good idea that you always do too.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at how that works.
I'll see you in the next life