Okay,
guys.
And welcome back now,
before we get into code in this project promptly.
One I want to do is talking through this code here.
And this is called Private sub Simple.
Send email original code.
And this is my e mailing routine.
And I have used this literally hundreds and hundreds of times.
Every time I create a project that requires emails to be sent,
this is the base code that I use.
So there are a couple of things that you need to know when you control in external
applications within the office suite searches at local word is you have to die.
Mention them as objects on the only do you after dimension the application.
You also have to dimension the objects within the application.
So the very first thing we have here is dim outlook as or outlook app.
And you can call that only thing you want ugly.
Say so dim outlook app as object that creates an object for the outlook application.
Now,
because we're gonna be sent in an email,
an email is an object within outlook.
So we also have to dim the outgoing email as an object to no my body text.
I normally take the data from the spreadsheet that I can build dynamically at runtime so I
can can Katyn eight different elements from different cells and that them all into a text
string here.
And you can see here this is where this is built up.
So okay,
we've got everything dimension.
There's objects.
The next thing we need to do is set them and that means create them within our code.
So set outlook app,
which is the object we don't mentioned above equals create objects,
open brackets outlook dot application That creates an instance of outlook.
And the next thing we need to do is to exactly the same thing for the outgoing email,
because that,
too,
is an object.
OK,
so we're going to set out,
look up and create the outlook application,
and then we're going to do exactly the same thing for the email.
Now here is the body text and we can add this dynamically at runtime or if you want to hard
code it,
we can literally just write words in here.
Obviously baby new line forces a new line and here we have high there on we could read the
person's name from the file.
Okay,
so obviously,
this is like one this line to this Line three.
This is lying for now.
Here we have turns off the error handling on.
If you don't do this,
what you're gonna happen when what's gonna happen when your code executes is you're going
to get a little poppet warning that says someone is trying to send an email from ever?
Look,
do you want to allow this yes or no?
Or words to that effect.
Now,
if we turn off the error handling here,
that won't happen.
So the emails were literally just be created.
Boom,
boom,
boom and sent.
Okay,
now,
here's the good stuff.
These are all the properties off the email,
and you will recognize and they are,
too,
which is who you're going to send it to.
If you are a hard code,
just one individual person just put the email address in here on,
That's who it will go to enclose it in quotes.
If you want to send it to two people separated with a semi colon just like out looked us on
.
Then again,
at the end,
closing quotes a riend out cc But obviously that's who you gonna carbon copy of Rammed ABC
say that.
So you're gonna blind carbon.
Copy.
The subject is obviously what's going to appear in the subject line.
And you can see the hard code that or you can build it dynamically at runtime.
Uh,
body is the text,
the actual message and you can see here.
We're just gonna populate that with my body text,
which we've done up here.
Now,
here we can solve the error trap that we did back up here.
So everything goes back to normal within the office suite.
Now,
the last thing you need to do is destroy the object variables in the reverse order in which
we declared them.
So the first thing we declared was the outlook app.
So that is the last thing we destroy.
And all we do is we say,
set the outlook.
App equals nothing on because we did the outgoing email the male itself as the 2nd 1 That
is the 1st 1 we do.
So we destroy them in the reverse order in which we created them.
Now there's a low debate on the Internet where you actually have to destroy objects after
you've created them,
some people suggests No,
because they're automatically destroyed at the end of the subroutine.
Andi,
some people suggest yes,
because you can get orphan objects.
I'm not entirely sure.
So up to be on the safe side.
I always destroy the objects.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture where we'll have a look at how we're going to capture our
data to use in our email routine.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.