Okay,
guys,
I'm welcome to this section where this section is so important it warrants an introduction
all of its own.
So this is probably the most important section off the entire course there.
At the moment,
we've looked at recording macros on We've seen that we can only go so far just by recording
macros and coding or programming.
Both.
Both words are interchangeable.
Coding or programming is so much more than just recording a macro because there are some
things that cannot be done by just recording a macro on.
To do those things you need to learn how to code now,
just like any other language.
VB,
a visual basic for applications,
is also a language.
And like all languages,
it has words.
Some of those words are reserved and have specific meaning In code on we've already seen
some of those We've seen the words sub We've seen the the phrase end sub we've seen with an
end with we've seen range we've seen private on the protected words.
The reserved words always capitalize on are always in blue.
Now a good coding practice which we've already looked at,
It's always type your code in lower case.
That way,
when you hit,
enter or you click off the line.
Any reserved words will automatically be capitalized on automatically turn blue.
So if for argument's sake,
you think you've typed end with correctly,
but you've typed end W I t T h.
When you click off the with with the T T H will not be capitalized on.
That's a clear indication that you've made an error.
So always type in lower case until we come to variables.
What will come to that in this section?
So don't worry about it,
but always type in lower case.
And that way,
anything that's a protected word.
A reserved word will automatically capitalize on turn blue for you Now,
while we're talking about V.
B.
A is the language.
It also has just like any other language,
a grammatical structure,
and it has syntax.
Noah's You work through your programming career as you.
As you develop,
you're gonna learn key phrases on the correct syntax to use now,
rather than learned them through repetition.
Learn them.
Once,
remarked them well,
that is.
Add an apostrophe on that green rice in just before the line of code,
and that way you will always know what it does,
and it also makes debugging your code and awful lot simpler.
You are also not only going to develop phrases,
you're also developed little snippets of code.
They're going to be completely adaptable for future programming projects.
Just as an example,
I have an emailing routine that I wrote.
I don't even know how many years ago,
and I never bothered to rewrite it again.
Every time I have ah program in project that requires e mails to be sent or e mails to be
read,
I just pull up my email in routine on wrapped the rest of the code around that.
Okay,
now what you're going to develop here in your macro book is going to be your bread and
butter.
So rather than develop a brilliant piece of code with loads of things that you've learned
as you develop and keep it in a specific workbook two years later,
you may not remember which workbook that particular piece of code is in.
So always stall these pieces of code in your macro workbook.
Don't re meant the wheel.
If you write a piece of code that works,
keep it on always keep it in your macro book.
Then we already saw a little earlier when we were recording a macro that there is a
personal macro workbook.
Now I know a few coders that actually use the personal macro workbook,
and that's perfectly fine if you're working at home on your computer.
But the thing to remember and the reason I never use one is that the personal macro
workbook is stored locally on your computer.
So if your computer is stolen or your hard drive fails,
you have lost everything.
So the thing I always do is I keep a macro book,
and this is an Excel file and XLs m file,
just like any other file so I can copy it in my hard drive.
I can copy it to a pen drive.
I can email it to myself if I'm working on a particular contract and I need access to all
of my code.
So I always keep it on a separate file.
And personally,
I do not use the personal macro workbook.
It's entirely up to you.
You make your decision,
but if you do decide to do that and you have thousands of lines of useful code on your hard
drive fails,
your work will be lost entirely.
Your decision.
Okay,
Now your macro book is going to become your phrasebook your dictionary,
and it will have all the essential pieces of code.
And by the time we finish this section,
we're gonna have more or less everything that you could ever need for any project that
you're ever going to create.
And you are limited only by your imagination.
If you can describe it,
there is every chance that you can automated with a bit of programming behind it.
Okay,
Without any further delay,
let's move on to the next lecture.