Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
before we get down to our email routine,
we're just going to run this code through so you can see what it does life.
Now,
what we're gonna do,
it's just hit f eight and step through the code one Linus sign.
So we've just loaded check out and those new sunscreens into our subject.
We've selected this sheet.
If it wasn't already selected,
we using the worksheet function can't if to find out how many people have blonde hair.
Andi,
there are 13 there.
We know there are 13 weaken resize,
weaken re dimension era ray tohave 13 by two elements.
So ago.
My array is 13 by two and you can see down here I've added a watch to my array And for each
of these individual elements one through 13 I have two elements.
One for first name,
one for the email address.
So no,
Minister elect column E.
And I'm gonna find first instance of blond and select that cell.
So far,
so good Initialized the counter.
So it is no worth zero.
Now we're into our active cell.
If the active sold up value doesn't equal blank,
then do this check value of my counter crony zero against the Bluhm camp,
which is 13 on when this equals this jump to the section e mail section.
Which is this label down here?
We're not there yet.
So what we're gonna do is come to biological test.
Is the actor cell equal blunt?
Well,
yes,
it does.
In which case,
my cancer equals my counter Zero equals zero plus one.
So my cantor is now worth one.
So my array warm my cancer one.
So this element here 11 is gonna equal the first name which were using by extracting the in
string to find out where the space is.
Subtracting one on extracting the left.
Most characters of column A.
So look what happens down here.
There we have Luca,
and then we're gonna have a look.
Two rows over or two columns over.
More to the point which want to capture the email address Excel essentials,
they go.
So now we're gonna move down a cell on,
we're going to keep moving down a cell,
and we're going to carry on all the way down.
In fact,
I'm gonna run all the way down until we get to hear.
So debug rule.
Ticker sack.
Whoops,
A daisy.
Now I'm going to run and get to do poke on down to here.
So now when I expound all of these watches all the way down to 13 you can see that we have
all of our data.
OK,
now we know exactly what the first section does.
Never gonna close that.
Okay,
so now we're down to the section the loop to send the emails.
So for my can zap,
we don't need to re initialize,
because at the moment it's where 13.
But we're now going to say it's going to be worth from warm to the blown counts.
As soon as we execute this code,
my cancer is gonna equal one again.
So let me just clicking here.
It hit F eight and they were into that email route email routine bump.
And here we go.
So here we have exactly the same code that we looked at earlier,
but I've just made a couple of modifications.
This part so far is exactly the same.
I have changed the body of the text.
So said hi there on and my array 11 which is the first name.
So it's gonna say hi there on whatever the first person's name is.
Kama Andi New line,
New line.
Insert two gaps.
We just want to let you know about our on done.
And here's our message.
This part changed and I'm gonna hit body text that's going to do that.
I'm gonna pick up that era.
I am sending it to my array one on the first pass through Element number two,
which is the e mail address.
Andi,
that's about it.
I don't think I made any other changes.
So let me just show you Outlook,
Bago,
our new e mails in outlook at all.
No dependent.
Oh,
fast.
My Internet connection is I'm just going to do that.
And hopefully if I come back to outlook any second now here we go with synchronize in the
in box,
there is our first message.
So there you go.
It's from Alan.
There's a second message and you can see over here in this window it says how they're Luca
because obviously the 1st 1 was Luca.
We just went to let you know about the new range of sunscreens.
This range is the best sunscreen there that.
And we'd love to send you a sample.
What?
Hope for this delivery in the next couple of days.
Those nice folks at Excel Essentials.
And they can see because we've actually used the same email address for everyone.
We have that one that went to Lily.
We have Sophie.
We have Isabelle.
We have mayor.
We have Abigail.
We have We have them all.
So we should have 13 e mails.
And if I can't want 23456789 10 11 12 13 e mails on.
That is how you run this email routine.
OK,
I hope you enjoy that.
And I'll see you in the next section.