Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
So let's have a look at this word routine,
and it's very,
very simple.
Maybe gonna butcher this a little later on only slightly after we captured all the data so
we can create our document.
Now,
you'll remember from the Outlook section in the last section that whenever you're calling
another Microsoft application,
you have to dimension it as a object.
So our first line of code dim word app as object sets up the word application all sets up
the variable toe hold word as an object.
Now,
obviously,
a document is an object with them word.
So the next thing we have to do is dimension object,
new dock as objects.
Obviously these Commie called whatever you want them to bay.
So our next line of code set word up,
which was declared above equals,
create object word dot application on that is going to create a new instance of word for us
to control.
Now our next thing to do is to create a new document within that word up.
I'm here.
We have set object equals word up,
which we've declared a puff.
Don't documents dot ad,
and that gives us our new documents.
Now,
here's where most people make a mistake.
With word you do not make it active as you do with workbooks,
you make it visible.
So our next instruction is word app dot visible equals true.
Okay.
And then finally,
almost finally,
we're gonna add some text.
No,
we're going to say is world amp dot selection,
doc type,
text,
colon equals.
And then whatever text we want in this simple example,
it just says hello world.
And you'll remember also from the outlook section that whenever you create object variables
,
it is better to destroy them,
and you must destroy them in the reverse order.
So the very first thing we declared was the word app itself.
So word up is the last thing we destroy.
And the second thing we created was the new dock object.
And that is going to be the 1st 1 we destroyed.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture,
where we're gonna have a look at that code where we gather all the data.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.