Okay,
guys,
from welcome back there.
One of done is I've taken this base code here that we looked at in the last lecture on.
I've created an almost exact copy of it here,
and I've renamed it to letter To whom?
Ever on.
We'll be calling that at the end of our subroutine in the gathers of data.
And the only of the change I've made is here for the text.
I'm using the variable body text which we're gonna build above live at run time Now,
going from the beginning,
we have option explicit because we want to force variable declaration near the body text
that we're gonna pass to the subroutine to actually open word,
create a new documents and write the text needs to be passed from the build the data
subroutine to the letter to whomever subroutine.
So that is declared up here at module level.
The other variables are built at local level within the subroutine.
Build the data.
OK,
so this is gonna be split over into a couple of lectures because we've got some really
interesting code in here,
and it's worth exploring it in detail to make sure that you understand how it actually
works.
So very straightforward.
To begin with,
we have shipped my date at night.
If I move this out the way raw days at this sheet,
just here,
with all of our data in its is called shirt.
My data so sure,
my data select.
Now,
this is the first really interest in peace of code here.
What we have is shit.
My data on what is going to do is read the range from B one to B one end,
excel down.
So ALS the data set in column B down to the last entry.
That is the range it is working on.
Then we're gonna use on advanced filter with an action filter copy copy to Range K one on.
We only wanted to paste unique values,
so I'm just going to step through that coat on.
Jackson put K one into view so you can actually see what that does.
So there's K one.
Let's come back to the code.
I'm just quips.
Let's try that again,
Ella.
Let's hit f eight and scroll them eighth all the way through and have a look.
What happens when this code executes all of the unique entries have Bean returned to K one
,
including the Heather sales person.
I'm not particularly worried about that because we're gonna have a clever way of dealing
with that when we actually write the formulas in.
Now,
here we have a slightly bush ad version of how to write a formula to a bunch of cells lap
once.
But there is a quirk when you use this function here,
this filter copy and pasting unique ranges.
So we're gonna have a look at that in the next lecture when they show you how I built this
code here.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.