Okay,
guys from Welcome back.
So we've most ability,
unique list using this code just here on there.
We want to be able to populate all the formulas a sum if formula to be able to calculate
the total profit against each of those individuals.
Now,
what we're trying to get to here is this particular code.
But there is a quirk.
So let me just show you I'm just gonna write a play in all summit,
which is by far the easiest way to get formulas written in code.
It's just write the formula record the macro hit F to hit ever hit.
Enter and you done so here.
We're going to say plain old some if I want to look in column B so column B comma.
I want to look in the cell immediately to the right combat,
and I want to some g close brackets and fantastic.
And then when I double click to film that down,
notice what happens?
Nothing.
Because when we build a unique list using the code we just used,
you'll know sis that it now say some some if BB extract and this is extract.
So when a copy it down it's still looking at extract.
So what we need to do is modify this code even though we would think we could just recalled
the formula.
And we need to specify it in good old Excel speak.
So we want to some BB our criteria lives in K u one on.
We are going to some g enter now.
Sales person has no sales,
but when they copy that down,
that works beautifully.
Great.
Now we need to record a macro.
So recorder macro,
it's OK.
Hit f to hit.
Enter.
Stop recording the macro.
Flip back to visual Basic editor Control.
And are,
which is keyboard shortcut to display the project Window Double click.
I'm not interested in range.
J one All I am interested in is this code right here.
That is the formula in the B A.
So I'm gonna close that,
and I'm gonna pasted under here when I line it up.
Megan,
you can see that this formula here matches this formula here.
Precisely.
So that is our formula.
That's how we built the formula part.
And then we have a really cool thing.
Let me just scroll over so I can get that interview that should do it.
Okay,
so here what we have is the range K one.
Let's ignore the off sex for a second.
So we have k one to k one,
Excel down.
So that is this entire cell.
But because we want to write the formulas to the left,
we have also added an offset open brackets zero no rose minus one to the left.
So we are selecting this range,
but working with the offset that is where we're going to write our formula.
So I'm just gonna delete ALS that because I know if you noticed,
but in the notes,
let me just click off in the notes.
Whenever you pacer value using this code here,
the range must be empty.
So I'm just going to step through that code up to that point on notice.
What happens now?
Perfect.
It works beautifully.
Okay,
so I'll see you in the next lecture.
Well,
we'll go through the rest of this code.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture.