Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
there is a slight modification to the recorded macro here because what we want to do is get
the highest value to appear at the top.
So what I'm gonna do is stop the code.
I'm gonna come over to here.
I'm gonna say bombing going on record a macro.
It's okay.
I'm gonna hit J one hit control in a to select everything.
I'm gonna come to filter and sort and say sort largest to smallest on.
That is why we put the value in front of the name just so we can use a very simple filter.
So here,
I'm going to stop the macro record and flip back to the visual Basic editor hit control and
are to bring up the projects,
Flora.
And now Meghan steal that code.
So that's the code that we just generated back to here.
I can close that now.
Andi.
Yeah.
Let's pace underneath.
Okay,
so here is the recorded macro code.
Now,
we don't need to say range.
J T j want k one dot select because it is already mentioned down here.
We are going to stick with J one.
However,
so I'm just gonna delete that code.
So now that's brought it down by one line.
Now what?
We also don't need to say,
because we literally just built this and we know we have no filters.
Applied is weaken.
Just clear the first line of code.
Okay,
so it's coming down now.
We can safely delete the Excel header because we're going to deal with this sales personal
it later,
so that can come out.
We don't care about match case because we're actually sorting by a number.
So we don't need match case.
We do need orientation.
We're not dealing in opinion.
This is just a salt method.
Eso Essentially these are the three lines of code that we need in our with end with the set
range orientation on the apply.
Everything else is the same.
Now here we have set range range J want to K seven on.
I have replaced that with range J one dot current region notice.
There is nothing after the current region.
It just simply say's range j one duck current region.
And that is going to be enough to make that code work.
So let's hit Delete on.
Let's have a look remember,
this has to be empty when the code runs.
So let's just run straight up to that point and I'm gonna come right the way down to here.
So I'm gonna hit debug,
Say,
run to cursor.
I am in this line,
so we're gonna get all the way through on.
There you go.
There's our unique list.
There are formulas written correctly on we now have Sarah Bond way at the top with
£1613.58 p.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Will finish this off by having a look at building the body text on.
Then we're done.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture.