Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this brand new section Now since the release,
of course.
A few weeks ago,
a couple of students of contacted me and said it would be really helpful if you could have
vb a create PowerPoint presentations automatically.
Well,
your wish is my command.
And that is exactly what this brand new section is entirely dedicated to.
Now.
PowerPoint has an awful lot of elements to it,
so it's slightly longer than the word section,
but it's well worth looking at.
Okay,
So what we have here is the northern sales report that we looked at back in the reporting
section on.
What we're going to do is use this report that we've created toe automatically create a
PowerPoint presentation.
Okay,
guys.
And this is what the finish report looks like.
All the data is taken from our report that we already created.
You can see that we have a very nice company logo of the top rate own side and all of their
charts,
all of their titles of automatically being created.
Okay,
so let's crack on and have a look at exactly how we do that.
So you can know create all of your PowerPoint presentations in seconds.
I'll see you in the next lecture.