Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this section.
Now we're going to use as a base for this particular project the report that we created
little earlier.
So this particular one is the monthly report for January 2016 in the northern region on
this report is what we're going to use to generate our power point presentation.
So let's have a look at the base code on this.
Is it just here.
Now,
with this,
you're gonna be able to do pretty much most things that you can imagine with a power point
presentation.
So just as we did with word and just did without,
look,
we're going to be used in the late binding.
That is,
that you'll be able to transfer the file to other computers and the code will still work
perfectly.
So what we're gonna have to do?
We set up three objects,
Dimension.
Three objects were gonna have PP app.
I've just used pp to represent power points,
but obviously you can call these whenever you want,
So I have PowerPoint app,
PP apples and objects,
pp presentation.
That is the presentation object within power.
Point on.
Be below that.
We have PP slide and they will be the slides within the presentation.
Okay,
Now we're going to create or open a power PowerPoint application used in the set peopie app
.
Create object.
PowerPoint application to add a new presentation will use the code set PEOPIE presentation
equals PP app.
Just here dot presentations dot ad and that will give us a new presentation within our new
instance off power points on.
Finally,
we're gonna make it visible.
So this codes broken it up into different sections and the different sections relate to the
different things and the different elements that can use within PowerPoint.
So,
too,
are they slide.
You will use this code set peopie slide equals pp presentation,
all of which have declared above adult slides dot ad And this is the only bit that will
vary.
The index number is the position off the slide within the slide show,
so index number one will be the first slide index Number two will be the second and so on.
And then the other thing is the layout.
No layout.
If you look down this list in the realms here is title only.
If you use lay at one,
you will have a title at the top on a subtitle at the bottom and so on and so forth.
Through all these leather,
11 pre defined layouts numbered one through 11 from enough anything beyond level beyond 11
.
So,
she said,
layout 12.
It will become a custom layout,
which essentially is a blank slowed,
to which you can add images or text,
and we'll look at that in just a second.
Okay,
so adding text,
we have a few different ways of doing this.
We can use the name off the text rain as we did in this example,
or as we would in this example just here.
So it's a PP slide dot shapes title,
which refers to the title text frame on.
We would use this particular line of code PP slide dark shapes up titled Doc Tex Rain.
Very complicated,
but basically at the end.
Whatever is in the quotes is what the text that will appear within that frame or
alternatively,
you can just reference.
Arrange on your spreadsheet.
Obviously,
if you have more than one sheet on,
do you are working on a different sheet?
Be sure to remember the hierarchy and specified that she just here now.
The other way we can do this is we can use the index number off the shape,
as you can see in these three lines of code just here on basically,
the index numbers refer to the numbers off the objects from left to right from top to
bottom.
So if you have a title frame at the top on a subtitle frame below,
title frame is Index one,
so that would be shapes one on the subtitle frame would be shapes to Okay,
we'll explore this as we go through the code on now.
Teoh a new bullet point to a text box.
We will use the VB new line,
so if you have a few lines of text,
but you want to be separated by bullets,
always add VB new line between the lines of text and that will force a new bullet point.
Okay,
formatting texts.
Basically,
it's very race simple.
This is the format,
PP slide dot shapes on the index number Text framed up Tex ranged outfront on name equals
times or don't fund duck.
Call recalls whatever color you want dot fund dot size whatever size you want,
Andi Italic or bold or whatever you want.
So very straightforward stuff.
So this is literally just plug and play.
Just copy this and paste in.
No,
Obviously,
if you want to change a few the different formats,
you can wrap that in a with end with as we have just here.
Now we have a couple of ways of aligning text.
We can use the MSO,
which is the Microsoft Office Align right which will align the text of the rightful enough
mso alain left which will firmly enough behind to left and M s align center or mso alone
center and that will send to your text if you want to on a text box.
This is how you do it,
you say PP app dot active presentation dot Slade's Whenever the index on review Osleidys,
don't shape start add text box one left,
100 top 100 or whatever value you want with 100 on height 50 and you can change these
values.
One thing to knows.
These values are expressed in points and you will notice here in the comments position of
sizes are in points so one inch equal 72 points.
One centimeter equals 28.346 points.
But I have a very clever way of coping with that.
So this is basically the text adding attacks box.
Now this number one here basically means that the text is going to be the right way up.
If you change this to a to the Texas rotated counterclockwise to change it to three,
the Texas rotated clockwise.
Now,
if you want to delete a shape,
just refer to it,
bites index number and use the code.
People slide dark shapes in next number.
Dr Lee.
OK,
there were them.
Two images.
Now we have a few different ways of adding images we can paste.
Arrange as a picture a bit map on what we'll do.
We'll specify what we want to copy from our Ex Felt Excel spreadsheets hit dot copy picture
appearance equals X l screen format Excel picture on,
then to pace will just specified slide PP slide duck shapes duck paste on that will paste
it in the dead center.
Now,
if we want to paste an object such as a pie chart,
we have a pie chart on our report.
We were used this terminology sheets sheet one dot chart objects the name of the objects
dot chart doctor.
Copy Picture on,
then to paste it,
use the PP slide that shape stop paste.
Okay,
now there is another way of doing this,
but it does retain some of the data from the spreadsheet.
So personally,
unless you want them to be able to access the data that the presentation came from,
I would avoid using this.
But should you need it?
This is the code to do it Now.
Finally,
we can add a saved image,
so they picked a J peg or a gift for something that we have on our own computer on.
This is the code we need to use for that now.
Obviously where?
Here I have my my use that Alan Pictures logo J fig.
You will put your own path in your own image in there and again.
These are expressed in points again,
re sizing images to change the size of an image.
What we'll do is we'll say PP abduct active window dot selection dot shape range Height
equals whenever it is in points.
But I have a clever way again.
Ran that or with now you don't have to do both because it will maintain the aspect ratio.
So you only need to change height or wits and everything is good from that.
Okay,
I've just realised couldn't spell position.
And Okay,
so position in images.
Note that there is a slight unusual way This is expressed position.
Image use pp apt,
Attractive window.
That selection Obviously this will be with the active shape,
shape Ranger line mso align left It's on.
There is an s at the end so we can align Left rights,
middles centers,
tops or bottoms Eso notice it's not left right middle.
It's left,
sir Within s at the end.
And all of these have left or all of these Haven't s at the end.
Okay,
Finally we have the align image using points and then this is position your image precisely
.
But don't worry,
I have a very clever way of doing that too.
Okay.
And then finally we have to destroy the object valuables in the reverse order in which we
created them.
So we created PP up first.
So that's the last one to be destroyed,
PP.
Presentations second.
So that's the last but one to be destroyed.
And the last thing we created and the first thing we destroy is the PP slide.
Okay?
I don't expect to remember all the lamp.
What we're gonna do is put this together like Lego and build our presentation.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thanks very much.