Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
from this lecture,
you're gonna find a few downloadable Resource is now the 1st 1 that you should be getting
Is this file just here?
It's called my macro book dot x l s x on.
What going to do?
Since you've downloaded that,
you've opened it.
So you're looking at exactly what I'm looking at.
Come to either file and save as or just hit f 12.
Choose a directory.
We're going to keep it on change the save as type two a macro enabled workbook on.
Then just click save.
So now this is a macro enabled workbook.
Next thing we're going to do from Excel is hit Olsen F 11.
That's gonna bring the side visual.
Basic editor on The next thing we're gonna do is come up to the insert menu and we're gonna
choose module.
And that is going to give us module one.
Now.
I know in the last in the last section,
we created modules by recording macros.
No,
created automatically.
But if you ever need to add one,
that's how you do it.
You go to insert and choose module.
So module one.
Now we're going to change the name of module one using the properties window down here.
If you don't see the properties window,
go to view and choose properties window here or you can see the keyboard shortcut is F four
.
So if this is invisible to you,
just her f four and it will pop up.
Now we're going to come to the name and we're going to call this whips deleted the day
we're gonna call this mod 01 underscore the basics.
Okay,
so they can see a module.
Name has changed that.
The next file that you need to download is the mud.
01 Underscore the basics text file on when you open that this is exactly what you're going
to see.
And this is what we're going to be going through in this section.
There's an awful lot of code,
but don't worry.
We'll go through it line by line and you'll understand it perfectly by the end.
So with this file,
open hit control in a hit control and see to copy it.
You can close it then on with mud.
01 The basic selected Clicking the colon window on hit control on V and that will paste all
of the code in my own personal my macro book into your personal my macro book.
Okay,
now we have a few more to go through,
so I'm just gonna come to here again.
I'm gonna hit module,
and again,
I'm gonna click.
Module 11 has just been added.
And here on the change,
the name of this one to copy on day trips.
No spaces.
Alan,
copy Andi Paste.
And now I'm going to double click that module.
So this is this window is associate ID.
With this module,
they're going to come to the mod copy and paste text file and he can see the code that's in
.
That's going to hit control and I control and see,
So I've copied it'll.
I'm gonna come back to this window.
I'm gonna paste in here.
Now I'm going to continue to do that for the other modules and I'll be back with you in
just a second.
Okay,
guys.
And welcome back now,
at the point of which I recorded this,
there are four downloadable text files.
They are called mud a one.
The basics mud copy and paste model looping on modern text and you can see that I've added
modules and rename them over here in the project Explorer on a side double click each one.
You can see the code associated with it,
and all of this code lives in those text files.
Now,
as the course develops,
they may well add MAWR text files here.
So if there's Mawr than the four text files that I've just mentioned,
don't worry about it.
Just download them and import them into a module that has the same name as the text file.
Okay,
now here's the thing.
Now we've imported all of that.
You should be looking exactly what I have.
You have a my second sheet that says she to she one that says sales nater she to that say's
looping in bracket sheet.
Three.
Let's hip say's scratch on this workbook and then these four modules with all the code in
that we've just described.
Now here's a thing.
If you are in V B.
A,
you can hit save,
and that will save your workbook.
If you're not in V B A.
And you just click save on Excel.
It will also save your workbook so you can save in either the V,
b E or Excel.
And it saves both of often seen people save him.
One immediately flipped to excel and press save again.
It does exactly the same thing.
Okay,
now what we're gonna do,
we're going to come to the scratch sheet just here.
We're gonna hit developer on.
So far,
we've looked at how to run code using the using the macro section up here or using the
whatever else they are.
But what we're going to do for a new,
awful lot of the section is we're going to run the code from a button.
So from the developer ribbon,
we're going to come to hear the insert on.
We're going to see form controls and Activex controls.
What we're gonna do is choose form controls.
Button on.
That's the 1st 1 at the top left.
So I'm just gonna left click on.
I'm just going to drag a button here.
It doesn't matter how big it is,
So there you go.
Now,
what we're going to be clicking here is the basics.
Testing this.
I should have made the rest of these private,
But what we're gonna do is double click basics testing this on.
I'm just gonna rename that by editing the text on the same Osho.
Say,
run my code groups on Don't hit.
Enter on,
then.
Just click off on.
Now when we come back to here,
Whenever we look at all these bits of code that we're about to look at in this section,
what we do is we're just going to copy of the elements.
So this particular bit here on we're gonna paste into here,
and that is the code that we're going to execute.
Okay,
I'm going to see you in the next lecture.
We're gonna have a look at customizing the visual basic register a little bit,
and then we'll crack on.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.