Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
before we get into actually creating the presentation normally on the front page of every
presentation than I've ever seen,
it will have a title on the name of the presenter.
Now,
as the name of the presenter doesn't actually live,
you know,
Bay State and what we're going to need to do is at an input box to get the user to end to
that.
So to do that,
what we're gonna do is create a new module level variable,
and we'll call it Prez.
Name a string on this will be where the variable where the presenters name is stored and
hear what we're going to say is president equals input box input box.
Oh,
from rackets a prompt on.
We're going to say something like,
Please and,
uh,
the present.
Same here,
Close brackets.
We're gonna have a prompt say's who is the presenter or something like that.
So who is the presenter?
I normally like to do these in upper case.
So who is for the promise anyway?
Who is the presenter presenter?
Close records on close quotes on that is going to allow the user to enter.
Obviously you can have been error trapped here.
So you can say actually feel equals blank and the code.
But we're going to assume that this is going to go in,
find so he out.
We're going to capture the name of the presenter,
So capture,
uh,
that name of the prison on.
There you go.
So that's the very pet first bit of code we need.
But if we have a look at our source data,
we can see that we have different sheets.
Now,
what we want to do is make sure that we are on the right sheet when we're copying and pull
in data from here.
So perhaps one of the other things that we should do his view The Project Explorer Get the
name of sheet one,
which turns out to be sheet to make sure we are on the right cheat.
So select the correct sheets,
Correct.
I can't for the life of me select the correct sheet and this is VB name sheets to I think
sheet too.
Cheat too dot Select.
Okay.
And then we're ready to add our first slide.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.