Okay,
guys,
welcome back there Rather than have this impl anal dull black tax let's change this Let's
make it blue and let's make it bold.
So I'm just gonna close that off on I'm gonna hit no safe.
So here we valued the logo here.
We've added the text so immediately underneath that between the title and subtitle.
What we're gonna do is come down to here to the text to the formatting text.
Because we're doing two things we're gonna do is use the with end with someone's gonna copy
that code,
come up to here,
and I'm just gonna pace that in here.
So let's just tidy that up.
So using the with end with,
we can delete their sweetened delete this weaken,
Delete this weaken.
Delete this.
I'm not gonna bother change in the typeface,
but we could also need Teoh delete the Rams in front within the end with So we're going to
say VB blue obviously can make this review once I want to rent in the file.
So the font size because I don't know what's gonna look like.
Andi.
I don't want it to be Talic.
I want it to be bold So let's run that and see how that works.
So up to the run order hit Play into my name Andi Mango Month report for January 2006.
Actually,
what we could say is presented by just in front of that Couldn't be so Let's just come down
to here and say I think the PP slide shaped to the subtitle is actually going to say
presented by colon space.
Close quotes Andi Prez name.
So let's have a rumor that and see how that looks.
So let's say on Jervis to be terribly formal on they go from three port for Jerry 2016 or
the region presented by Alan Jarvis.
Fantastic.
Right now what we're gonna do because we have the base code sorted is we're just going to
steal that,
modify it a little bit and create slide to I'll see you in the next lecture