Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Right now let's have a look.
What we want to do for the next light for side to or we're gonna do is copy all of this
code that we've just written because most of this is going to become going to be constant.
We're always gonna want to add a new slide when we add a new slide.
We're always gonna want our company logo to appear in precisely the right position.
We're always gonna want our title toe have the same format.
So basically,
almost all of this code will never change.
This is going to be the bit that we're gonna be working on in this particular lecture.
But here's the thing.
When we copy this code,
we're gonna have to change a few things.
We're probably gonna have to change the layout,
but we're also gonna have to change the index,
so we're gonna deal with that immediately.
What we're gonna do is comes the top on.
We're gonna add a new modular level variable,
and we can just call it dim X as into General on all X is going to do is allow us to set
the slide number he at the very beginning.
So set slide number.
And we're just going to say X equals one whips a X equals one.
They go.
So now,
instead of saying index one,
we can say index X and all we need to do is remember to change this lumber to match the
slide number mentioned here.
Now also,
we have it again in hair slides one.
So we want that to say slides X and there we should be good to go.
So we already have slide one slide to to the run order there.
So it's going to copy all of this code for slide one.
A copy pasted above.
I'm gonna call it slide to they would change the slide number two,
too.
So now that is going to appear.
It index to their layer one.
That's the title on the subtitle,
but we don't want layout one again.
What we want is the title of top on bullet points text at the bottom.
So that is layout number two.
So let's was back up to the top and just change the layers to number two.
Okay,
now let's just run that code to see what that looks like so far.
So when I hit play,
let's just say Allen hit.
Enter Andi,
boom!
A Go.
So we have our title Subtitle Second slide Multi Report for January 2016 Northern Region.
That's perfectly fine presented by Alan,
and you can see that that is listed as a bullet point.
Okay,
so let's close that what we actually want to do if I can just drank this over a little bit
,
I want to change the wording there.
I don't want that to say a range,
a wonder value.
I want that to say something like summary off performance on with the summary of
performance whips.
There again,
I wanted to actually highlight or right values in a three a four and a five this commentary
that were produced before.
So here I'm going to say text equals.
I'm just gonna happen under school and at the new line SE range A three is Nick's.
Arrange a three.
I don't value Andi vb new line because we want to separate.
That's not on BB new line because we want this to appear as a second bullet on bond space.
Underscore on now.
Just copy that on pace it a few times underneath.
So range a three and two range a three,
so we won't range a three range,
A full range a five.
And that will be the end.
So I can just sleeve the and delete that.
So,
no.
In our second box underneath our second shape,
we should get this common tree with separate bullet points.
So let's just run that code and have Look what it does.
Alan on bum bum,
bum,
bum bump.
And there we go.
Monthly report for January 2016 presented by Alan Summary performance.
And there is our common tree in bullet points.
Okay,
fantastic.
We're gonna copy,
slide to to create slide three,
and I'll see you in the next lecture.