Okay,
guys,
let's wrap this up.
There would have done.
I've realized that I was using this ad logo routine here,
this particular section of code in each of the slides.
Now,
obviously,
if you want to change the logo,
you've then got to go in and change the particular line of code in every one of these
subroutine slide ones like these,
like three.
So what I've done is I've just moved it to its own sobriety,
and I've placed a call to it in each of these.
So in slight for we have an ad logo calling slight three Slater and slide one.
So that way,
if we ever do need to modify our logo or we need to do is change this particular subroutine
.
OK,
so the last side we want a mad is the thank you and any questions,
which is how all good presentations and so we're gonna do is I'm just gonna choose slide
number one.
I'm copying the code from there.
I'm gonna wears way back up to it up to say it doesn't particularly matter where you have
these because the run order is determined above on.
We are now on slide five.
So slide in next.
Number five on We want to do way,
actually want to delete that?
Don't make eso sledge shapes to I think it was Was it just delete?
We'll find out when we run it because we don't want the subtitle on We don't It's a range A
one.
What we wanted to say is,
thank you in probably in capitals and from from pump and close coats on and vb New Line.
Andi,
Any questions?
There you go.
So hopefully that is going to give us our finished presentation.
So that's just hit.
Play president Taste with prison taters.
Name presents his name on Jarvis.
Andi There you go.
There is are fully automated Power point presentation slide one slight to slight three.
Slide for Andi.
Thank you.
And any questions?
OK,
guys,
that's it.
That's how you create a presentation automatically using VB A enjoy