Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
we're gonna have a look at a butchered version of that open all files in folder.
you'll remember that the code looked pretty much like this.
Originally,
we had a hard coded path to the folder which we're now going to use folder picker for to
get the folder name so we can do that dynamically.
But here on had added on my criteria before we just add Thea wildcard character and dot
Excel.
But there were actually going to build a string.
So theory Jinling code looked like this,
so that's gonna be option to if you want to load all of the Excel files.
But if we look at this here,
what we may want to say is we just want to pull any file or open and act on any file that
begins the 2016 12.
Or we may just want to do be completely oblivious to the year in the month and just do
anything from the south or the East or whatever combination it is that you want.
So what we have here just at the beginning is this option one Now again,
I have a publicly declared my criteria on variable right at the top of the screen on what
we have is my criterion equals input box and we've used in pop boxes before.
Please enter the unique string of the fouls you want to open.
So we could enter 2016 12.
Just get the 2016 12 files or Southern and just get all of the Southern files.
Or whenever we wanted to do Onda open the files containing the word that's gonna be our
title.
Then we're just gonna have a logical test that says,
if my criterion is blank,
that is nothing has been entered.
Just end the subroutine right there.
Now we come down onto this Now here we had this hard coded we said,
full name equals directory.
Fold the name Andi.
Wildcard dot Excel World card wildcard.
All we've done here is we've said file name equals directory.
Fold name?
Andi.
Ah,
wildcard Onda.
Whatever the criterion is,
we've just entered in our input books.
Onda Wild card again.
Now we have wild card at the beginning and the end because we don't know where the
particular string that we were gonna enter into my criteria is going to appear if its way
out front or way at the back we need or somewhere in the middle we need to cover all
eventualities.
So we have a world card of start.
We have a wild card at the end.
Andi,
we're only looking in Excel files.
So again,
enclosed in quotes dot Excel,
question mark Question marks that's going to capture any XLs ends in the Excel accesses any
version of an Excel file that will capture as long as it has my criteria on that,
we've just entered somewhere in the file name,
and then we get back onto the normal stuff.
Do while the file name doesn't equal blank.
Then we're gonna loop through,
do some clever code here.
Then we're going to close the file.
And here is where it moves through the next file that matches this criteria.
So what we're gonna do here,
we're gonna add a sub to another thing on.
We're gonna work on the data,
gather at where we're actually gonna open the file and then do something useful with it.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture