Okay,
guys on Welcome back.
Now,
this is a sober team.
We were just looking at This is the loot through all the files in the folder using the my
criteria and he at between the workbooks open on workbooks closed.
I've put a call to a subroutine called Grab The Date at which we're gonna have a look at in
this lecture.
Now,
I'm just gonna was way up.
So it's up here.
He can see all the publicly declared valuables folder,
name,
file,
name might try to which we've looked at in the last clue last couple of lectures.
And here we have a running order.
And this is a format that we've used in a lot of the projects you in this course.
So we have the get path to folder that gets us around.
That problem of having a hard coded path to a specific holder that we want to read files
from.
We have the loop through the files in a folder.
Now,
that is a subroutine we just looked at in which we have no placed a call to our new
subroutine.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to step through this and get us to a new subroutine
which I've already written.
So my fault,
my fault files live in the demo folder.
I'm gonna move through,
looked through files,
informed that this is what we just looked at.
So I'm gonna say 2016 12.
So any of the files that begin or have 2016 12 in them?
That is what I want to be looking at.
So OK,
now I'm gonna hit Enter and or F ace F eight.
No,
that will be our folder name.
So it skipped all the 2012 11 files because they don't match my criteria.
So is our 1st 1 Alfa numerically 2016 12 Eastern region on While the file name doesn't
equal zero or blank workbooks open on that group's somewhere behind all of that will be the
eastern region,
so you'll notice the eastern region only has one shop in it.
Now,
I mentioned that for a specific reason and you'll see why,
as we go through this particular subroutine,
so basically we have region east date,
the date item,
quantity,
price and then sales and all the data down the bottom there,
so That is the fall that the File 2016 Eastern region now back to our code.
Never gonna call.
Grab the date at F eight.
And here it is,
grabbed the data.
Now there is There are there are a couple of not particularly complicated things.
Very useful things that we can learn in this.
Most of it is all basic stuff.
You can see that I have to locally declared variables called Start road and Stop row.
And as we get through the code and I show you where we populate these,
you'll see exactly why we have thumb.
So let's move through the code.
So again,
F eight this workbook activate.
So we are now activating the workbook where the code lives.
The mass data get Iraq workbook so F eight shirt.
Which sheets select again?
I'm gonna move this out the way a little bit.
You can see we have a couple of tubs and given them VB name.
So our data sheet as a VB name of shirt data on our which sheets sheet has a VB name of
ship which sheets.
So that way,
people can change the names on these on our code is still solid.
So back over here F eight a one select shop,
one so nowhere into a loop,
a basic error trap.
So if we find an error,
we looped down.
He Acto error Handler,
which is called Next Shop,
will get to that shortly.
So here,
the next thing we want to do is we want to take workbooks file name and you'll know that
that's the file name that we've just entered Criterion for.
And it's the fault,
the file that we've just opened up work sheikhs,
active sound up Value Range a one current region which essentially it is they're on current
region being the equivalent of control and a so it's going to copy all of that day to that
.
Let me just come back here and come back here.
So what's going to do is copy that on.
We wanted to paste into this particular workbook Worksheets data range D one million
something or all the way down at the bottom of the column D go all the way up and moved
down one cell.
So what's going to do?
Essentially has come to column D.
It's going to start down here.
Technically,
it's going to start there with all the way back up and then move down one cell.
And that is where it's gonna pace its data from D Dem to wherever it goes now.
Because this says this workbook on We have worksheets data you'll notice of remnants out of
replace that with shirt date exits.
The VB name on that removes any chance of someone renaming the sheet on the code falling
over.
So we are on which sheets,
some coming back to which sheets I'm going to step through.
It is now looking at file name Eastern Region,
and this is going to a one off shop,
one active,
sold up value.
So that's the sheet name it's going.
Take the current region.
It's going to copy it to shirt data on whatever the first blank cell in column D's by going
to the but McCollum d going all the way back up to the top till it finds its first set of
data.
I'm moving down.
One someone hits have ain't bump.
And if I come back here,
there is all the data.
Now,
let's just have a quick look at this Start row,
Equal shirt data range a one million something or other all the way up and moved down one
on the stop.
Perot stop row is sure Data range D So where we just pace in our data all the way up.
Onda cross one.
So what we're gonna get here?
Is this cell row?
So we're going to get C or we're gonna get four because that's where we want to write our
shop name.
I'm in the wrong thing all the way down to here.
Because here from four that troops from four down to 31 is where we want to say the name of
our shop and from be for them to be 31 is where we want to say the name of our region on
the period in a four through a 31.
So here I am just going to get those start and stop Rose bump,
bump.
So the start road is for on the stop.
Pro is 31.
Now we can build a string specifies this range explicitly using the correct start row
number on the correct stop row number.
So here,
basically what we're doing is this We're building a string that says range que 22 are to
value dot,
dot value.
He equals hello.
And essentially,
what that would do is write hello in every cell between K two and are too.
But what we're doing is we're building that dynamically,
using the start wrote in the Stop Pro.
So should data dot range underscored,
just breaks it the code down onto multiple lines,
open brackets and close brackets because we have toe have that when we specifying a range
on our star one is shirt data range.
See,
because we're gonna be populating column C as we are here.
So see,
here is the equivalent to the first K Aunt start row dot Address Andi on his are cool,
um,
Andi shirt data dot range,
see again and stop route.
And that's going to get a stand to 31.
So essentially,
what we said is C four to C 31 don't value equals whatever the active sold up value is
there.
So in this instance is going to say shop one.
And when I do that,
you'll see that shop one has been populated exactly in line with the data that we've just
written now.
Similarly,
when we get down tear.
Better be on the right sheet when we get down.
T we're doing exactly the same thing,
but for column B.
But this time we're looking at the workbooks file name.
That's the one we just opened the eastern region.
Worksheets active,
sold up value.
So it's got the right tab Shop one tab,
Range B one.
And if we have a quick local mayor range,
be one value on here.
So we're all tab shop.
One be Wonder value equals east on just so we don't have to come back and have a look again
be to duck.
Value is the date.
So this is why it's looking on this sheet on shop one on B one and then be too so back to
here.
So we're doing the same thing from before to be whatever it was 31.
Write the name of the region on.
Then when we get there and here we're in column a four to a 31 right,
the value off the date.
So bump bump on error go to minus one now.
Previously,
we've always said go to zero.
There is It's a really technical difference between the go to minus one and go 20 on.
This guy at this link here explains it far better than I could.
So if you are interested in the technical differences,
go have a look at that because that's a marvelous explanation of it.
So,
f Let's just have a look at that day to know we've populated it.
So back to the data sheet.
So they go there.
We have the date,
the period in that the region,
the sharp and all the data that we want Shop one from that particular file.
So here we go.
Let's step through whips.
Make sure you're on the right sheet.
Allen,
They were gonna move down to shop to loop while the active cell doesn't equal blank.
So we do need to do that.
Here's our error trap.
Are next shop go through.
Here we go on,
we jump straight them toe ever trap because we're all looking for shop too.
But we only have shop one in the file.
So therefore it's arid,
so we're just gonna step through active cell and there were moving down to shop three loop
.
While it doesn't equal blank on their egos next,
now it's gonna be looking to shop three and it can't find that.
So that's going to air again.
It's gonna move down again.
No,
we're on a blank.
This will exit on and sub on.
What we want to do now is close a file with just opened f eight move to the next one.
So we're currently in Eastern when his F eight We're now going to be opening the northern
on when North opens.
Let me just show you the north ever go.
We have three shops.
We have shot one shop to on shop three in the north.
So then we can just call the grab data looped through all of this and you can pretty much
guess what's happening is Godel shot one has got all the shop to its looking for shop three
.
It will find shop three so it will build the data on.
Then go all the way through.
Andi,
close the book And now we're onto the next one.
Bomb,
bomb,
bomb bomb!
I'm just going to stop that there.
Close the sheet.
We've just opened because I think you get the picture on.
We can no see that our data is building So we have East shot one.
We know there's no other shops in the Easter.
Then we move on to the fold the north.
But we have shop one shop to shop three on.
We're down to here now.
All we really need to do after this is clean this up because we have this region date and
item in there every time we copy the data over.
So let's just stop there And you'll know,
since the last thing in my running order is the clean up and this is very,
very simple.
Clean up is just going to come down to the sub clean up.
It's going to select shoot data.
So we're on the right sheet is gonna go to range D four,
which is Let's go here de full.
That one just there.
So it's gonna ghost deformed.
It's gonna test if it saves region,
then delete the entire Oh,
if it's safe date,
delete the entire oh,
or if it says item,
delete the entire road.
So that will delete everything that we know interested in and just leave the same data and
then we have an offset.
So if I just blank all of this out for a second and of Roma code through,
you'll see exactly what it does.
So from the beginning to end,
what we have is this.
I'll leave the screen updating on.
We'll say,
Look at that.
Look,
a turd.
The fold of my demo On this time,
we're just gonna be interested in Southern such a safe place to say,
s o You hit the enter bum bum bum bum bump and they go,
it's going to the South and it's retrieved Shop one on two for the first of the 11th 2016
and those we moved down the first of the 12 16 or equally,
we could just say,
You know what?
We're just interested in December.
So I already have that.
That that particular subroutine import data tied to this So I could say my demo selects
fall that I'm just interest in 2016.
December It's OK.
Bom bom bom bom bom On they go.
We only have data from 2016.
Okay,
and that's a you do it.
As always.
Any questions just dropped me a note,
and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day