Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this brand new section student questions answered.
But I had this question in a few hours ago and says,
Hi,
Alan.
I've created an array like you've shown us in the lecture,
and I also have a dynamic name range in my excel sheet.
Listen,
all the I DS that I wish to exclude from the array e g Mireille equals on the I D to
exclude.
Is there a way to do this?
While there are three ways to do this,
the 1st 1 is horrendously complicating using preserve with the rays,
which I never use.
And the other two ways are either to check when you populate the array if the value to be
excluded is in the active cell,
in which case don't read it into the array.
But obviously we're going to be using Excel calculations there to do it.
And using a loop to loop through,
which is not as efficient is doing it in code.
So,
by far the simplest way of doing this in the most efficient way of doing this is to
actually capture the entire array in one shot on.
Then literally,
when you write the array.
Then do the checking to see if it's of value that you want to exclude or not.
Okay,
so here's the code.
I'm just going to run it through.
There's a Chiti.
You can already see how fast this work.
So basically what we have is 20,000 loans of days that they have a start time stop time,
the elapsed time.
So let me just run the code and you will see that that takes 1.1 seconds to run.
And that is across however many lines of day,
Trey said,
as 20,000 lines of data processed in one second,
doing it this way.
So let me just talk you through the code here.
I've set up the variable,
so I have my Raya's variants declaring the array.
The road count captures the row count in here now.
Obviously this is going to capture the maximum number,
so it's going to capture 20,000 lines of data on because we have exclusions that's going to
be bigger than we want it to be.
But we also know it's never going to be bigger than the number of entries in this column,
so that's gonna work perfectly fine.
That is to say,
it runs room one second anyway,
and then we have a right loop for where?
A loop that we're going to use to write the data.
Now,
here I have turned the application screen updating off.
Obviously,
I've tested the code before I did this aan den to make it even faster,
I have turned off excels built in automatic calculations.
It is critical you turn this back on at the very end of the code.
So at the beginning,
application screen updating equals false.
Turn that off application dot calculation,
Excel Calculation manual that stops Excel,
dune.
Any calculations?
Okay,
next part range de two e clear contents That's gonna wipe out what's in columns D and E,
which is where we're writing our data.
Then we're gonna add the start time just to clock the speed at range G one so arranged,
you want don't value equals time,
and then we're gonna Riedel the data in one bite.
What we're going to say is,
Mireille equals range a one current region dot select,
and it's just gonna gobble all of that up there.
There's also going to capture this,
but we're only interested in these two elements column A and B,
And just as we looked at earlier in the course,
I'm going to read the upper bound of the array.
That is how many rows off data are there into the valuable row.
Can't and then we get down to a simple loop to write the data.
So range D one select.
This is where we're going to begin writing our data on a rat resume.
Next.
That is gonna lay this code to execute because what we're gonna do is use the match
function the worksheet function dot match on.
We're gonna test my array,
right Loop one.
So on the first pass through this is gonna be testing my array 11 that is,
on the first situation the value in 11 comma range,
my named range.
And that is your dynamic named range there.
And obviously we're gonna hit combat zero Chris,
we want an exact match.
So what we've said is,
if this is an error,
therefore the value here is not found in your exclusion list.
Go ahead and populate the array so the active cell value equals my array.
Right.
Loop one on the first past three combat one,
an active cell offset 01 column B don't value equals my array.
Right loop,
too.
So it will be element one part two and then we're going to move down the cell.
So if we do not find a match if this function here the worksheet function match looking at
your named range returns an error,
then we want to right what is in the array.
Otherwise do nothing on,
then just go through.
So returning off the era,
trapping here on we turn it back on once this loop is completed.
Now,
with the end,
we're just gonna have to stop time to G two and we're gonna turn back on the calculations
on we're gonna turn back on the screen updating.
So let me just delete columns D and E or clear the contents more to the point.
And that's exactly what this is going to do.
So when I hit play boom,
they go,
it runs through in one second.
So I don't know how big your data set is.
Obviously,
if it's more than 32,000 odd lines,
you're gonna need to change these inter jizz two lungs.
But if it's less than 35,000 Your fine with vintages and obviously integers and more
efficient.
They only use two bytes of memory rather than four.
Okay,
I hope that's helped.
Clarify that for you.
You can find this file is the downloadable resource from this very lecture so you can have
a play around them.
Hopefully that helps any more questions.
Just let me know.
Thanks very much.