Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered on this one's from John.
Now,
John,
watch the folder creation gizmo and set him thinking.
Now what John has is a workbook with about 50 of different sheets in it.
On this,
this master workbook is used to used to control territory managers on their budgets and
their actions on different sites.
Never don't know what the data looks like.
So this is essential here,
plank spreadsheet.
But my understanding is that we have different tabs,
so this won t m 01 would refer to territory manager one on this would control the budget
and then we'll have similar tabs for terrorism.
NGO one for site,
one site to then we have the budget for territory Manager three or something like that on
what we want to do.
We want to actually,
every time we make amendment or changed,
any one of these tabs is automatically saved that single tab as an individual spreadsheet
on post it,
save it to the appropriate territory managers file so they can see it.
And we want to add a time stamp on there so they can see that that is the latest version
that they should be looking at so would have done is have also made in another tab in here
called safe paths.
Eso What I have is tm one tm to tm three,
which match the total managers along the bottom.
Here.
This is obviously a much cut down version from the version that John Jews and but here of
this is just a dynamic named range.
And I have the individual safe paths to each of the territory.
Manager So territory Manager one,
it's c uses our deaths up my temple That Rod Tim to Jane tm three Freddy Now these
obviously don't have to live in the same root directory.
They could be in totally different directories.
But long as you record them here,
we're going to be golden.
Okay,
so what we're going to do first is we're going to record a simple macro to give us our base
code.
Doesn't Mobile is going to be called someone's gonna hit record new macro.
They want to come down here,
right?
Click now,
because the resolution I'm using it slightly off screen.
But I'm just gonna choose the fourth option,
which is move or copy.
That's gonna bring this dialog box up.
Woman do is click create a copy on the come up to here and choose new book and click.
Ok,
so here's our new book book Seven On from Here.
What I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna hit f 12.
I am already here,
but navigate to the appropriate thing,
So we don t m 01 So that's Rod this conflict that for now,
I'm just can call this t m 01 space less space base,
which is exactly the same name as this tab.
Save that.
I'm gonna close the file.
Okay.
I know.
I'm gonna stop recording now.
Let's have a look at that code.
So here's the code for saving in any individual sheet as a separate workbook.
Now,
this is the base of the code.
Okay,
We're going to take that.
We're going to use that to build our code.
So we're going to say is sub lips saved me now.
Luckily,
his one I prepared earlier.
So we already have all of my my variables declared.
So just so you can see,
I have dim my t m.
That is where I'm in a capture.
Those 1st 4 coaches of the active sheet name,
which is going to give me my territory manager's name.
So btm a one or 02 or 03 at my save path,
which we're going to capture by using a V look up function,
using my tm and reading from that front sheet my file name,
which is what we're going to be building.
In fact,
we may not even use that my year.
My mom from my day just so we can have let me close this stuff now just so we can we can
build that time and date stamp.
So we've used this before,
so it's gonna pace that in there.
So we're going to say my year equals now yet now my month equals month now.
So for just step through that bump,
bump,
bump.
My years 2016 My month is 10.
My day is 26.
Fantastic.
Now the next thing we need to do is capture the safe path.
So again,
what I'm gonna do I'm gonna stop there will come back to excel where only there we go.
That's excel,
and you'll remember that this is a dynamic named range here and I can't recall Have called
it.
Call it tm safe path.
Okay.
Close Eso woman do is I'm just going to say a t m one that and then say equals V looking.
But be if I could type It's a little early in the morning for may be Look up that comma.
And it was a t m safe path There it iss comma two comma false and enter right Norman
recorder macro to capture that.
That that function there.
That formula.
So Okay,
hit.
Have to Hey,
center,
stop recording.
Now let's flip back to here on day.
Here it is.
This is the code.
So we have active cell dot formula one C one equals V.
Look at we're just going to take that copy,
and we're gonna butcher that over here.
Now,
one of the first things we need to do is we need to find out what the T M name is.
So we're going to say at my t m equals and we're going to say active sheet dot name.
Okay,
So before we get down to the formula,
I'm just gonna step through that and you can see that my name is safe paths.
That's a poor example.
We need to put another sheet here.
Let me just delete that.
So here we go.
So let's stop and step through that again.
So here I am on sheet tm one base.
So if I step through bum bum whips Bom bom bom bom bomp t m equals t m one space The space
based Now what I wanna wanna actually capture of the 1st 4 characters.
So I'm going to say left open brackets Wasel the waves The end.
I know.
I am finished Comma for Unclos Andi,
stop now!
When I stepped through Bom bom bom bom bump My t m is t m one.
And that will allow us to use this V.
Look up there.
We need to modify this a little bit.
So we're going to say my safe path.
He s a mine.
Safe path equals,
I mean to say,
application dot work sheet function adults,
they look up open brackets and then we're just gonna delete all of this here.
So,
RV,
look up.
Value.
This bitch is gonna be my t m,
which is what we just read now.
This part here because we using the named range we're going to say range open brackets,
open quotes.
That is our named range Close quotes close brackets come into com A false lips.
I've missed something yoke until it that bit off the end.
So now if I step through this code,
we can go bump,
bump,
bump.
My t m is t m 01 which is we're going to know you's in out be look up So my safe path will
be See users.
Alan,
desktop slash my team folder slash rod.
Okay.
So far,
so good.
No.
Well,
we need to do is add this bit of code here into a coat.
So let me come down the bottom bubble bubble bump.
Andi controlling V.
I'm not gonna delete that,
cause we don't need that anymore.
Andi,
I'm also gonna delete this bit down here because we don't need that anymore.
So we have sheets,
tomo one dot select No,
we don't actually have to select this.
Chris were already on the sheet,
and that's where we're going to call the code.
From now.
What we do need to do is copy,
but we were already on the active sheets.
Okun just delete all of this and say active sheets sheets dot copy.
So we have copied the sheet.
This is I was scrolling around with only that in there on this is the next important best,
the active workbook save as File main.
Now what we're gonna do is we're going to replace some of these elements with the variables
that have already captured from my tm my safe path,
my year,
my month and all that.
So we can see here the first part all the way up to there is the safe path.
So they say my safe path.
Andi,
Noah do need that bracket in there to make sure that all that slash in there So I'm gonna
add that in quotes.
Oh,
my safe that Andi backslash Andi.
Now,
this is where we're gonna pull our dates times We're going to say my year and my month.
Andi,
my day.
on here.
We're gonna have the name of the active sheet,
so we're going to say active groups I can't tape at every time the Wright active sheet dot
name and that will give us the name of the sheet.
Onda.
We just want that dot Excel s ex whips mr dot at the end on There we go.
So hopefully that will give us exactly what we won't see.
Okay,
before we run that I just realized that forgot to put the space stash space in there.
So we want my year,
my month,
my day.
Andi There we want space dash space and then theatric tive sheet.
Don't name So with any look,
let's certain Let's come back to excel We're on tm one base.
Let's run that code and hopefully they go Something's happened.
Let's have a look at the folder t m 01 they go 26 216 10 26 Tiempo one base.
So let's just test that out by going to another one s o That was t m 01 Let's pick tm to
Can't remember who Tomo to was,
but we'll let we'll run that code.
Probable bump room that we g o and let's have a look at the folder.
Tim 02 will be Rod Jane at a guess on they go to 2016 10 2060 m o to cite one.
Obviously,
if you want that to rumble blisteringly fast.
Just add your application.
Screen of dating application dot screen updating equals false Andi at the end.
On your screen,
a dating application dot screen of dating girls True,
Andi that should now be blisteringly fast.
So who have we not done?
We've not done number three eso.
Let's pick that.
It's come back here and let's run their code.
Obviously,
you can add a book known to each of these sheets.
So the second you made your your change just hit the button.
Then it should work.
So here we go.
Let's just hit play but on that should have happened.
So it's going to have a look in here.
Ron,
Jane and Freddie was the last one,
and they go and that's how you do that.
Okay,
as always,
any questions just let me know and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day.
Thanks a lot