Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Now this.
This was really a two part question from Alice Andrews in the complete course.
That's levels 12 and three on Alexandra's question related to making dynamic charts and
graphs,
now one of done in level two.
I answered that in the named on dynamic range section of the course,
but the third part was held to automate this and make it animated using V B A.
So that's why that sits in level three here.
So basically,
this is the This is the file that I created to show have to do dynamic charts on.
We have a little scroll bar here,
and you can see that the chart updates dynamically.
But what we want to do is effectively create an animation out of this.
So what we're gonna do here is we're going to create a thing.
I'll just call it cycle clips on Hit enter a few times.
No,
because we have let me just flipped back here.
Olsen F 11.
We essentially have 31 sets of data each in six month blocks because each of these graphs
will show six months worth of data.
So this will be block one.
This will be blocked too,
if that six so and so forth.
31 times.
So we get through to December 2016.
So what we want to do,
we're just going to say for X equals 1 to 30 whips.
31 Allen on We'll say here,
Next X.
So there is our loop?
No,
because the this is this is how we started in level two.
We just type a number in here.
What we need to do is programmatically increase this number by an increment of one each
time.
So back to the code,
what we're going to say is range open brackets,
a one dot value equals X because we're gonna increase by one for each passed through this
four.
Next loop on DNA.
Now,
if let me just make that little bits whips as full screen,
let's see if I can make this a little bit smaller so we can see both windows.
Let's have a look.
I squished this right the way down.
This isn't gonna work terribly well.
It'll let me close that on debt.
Me Come down here.
So of chopped off half of the the thing here,
but hopefully you'll be able to see that.
So when I step through this,
you can see that this will become one on our chart.
Looks like that on.
Then it would become two and three and four,
and it'll keep increment in.
So that way,
if we press stop,
just run the code.
You can see that we'll get an animated charts up here.
So let me just press play.
But unfortunately,
that animated that quickly that you couldn't actually see what it was doing.
So what we need to do is introduce a pause between each of the interational is of this four
next loop.
And to do that,
we're going to use the application dealt Wait,
and we're going to say now,
plus on time value open brackets,
and we're gonna put this in quotes so we can say zero.
It was zeros minutes on.
Let's say one second.
Close quote close brackets on.
Now look what happens.
In fact,
I'm just going to bring this off screen and just hit play,
and you can see what happens in the chart here.
So I'm just gonna play that macro January 14.
It's waiting for an increment of one second.
And then it's going through on performing the animation.
Now there's no smooth way to do this animation excel,
but essentially that becomes an animated chart.
Now,
obviously,
let me just sit,
escape a bit and stop that running.
There we go.
What we could do so we can change the interval here.
So we changes.
Say,
let's say every three seconds on that will obviously then change the chart dynamically
every three seconds.
But this bits just for fun.
Eso There's another thing you can I'm in here.
Um,
I've never really found a practical use for it,
but it's a bit of fun,
so show you had to do it and that is add application dot speech.
Don't speak on,
say,
open rackets And this is we wanted What?
This is what we won't say.
This chart begins at on.
Then we want to close that quotes.
Let me just make that look bigger so you can see here.
So we will say this chart begins that andi sheet warm dot range from records open quotes B
one.
I think it's in B one.
The B one is the date,
so this chart begins at sheet one range.
Be one close quotes cause closed.
Brackets stop value on close brackets.
Again.
Sorry,
I had a slight mishap with my keyboard there,
so I've just bought This is the code that we've just looked at.
I'm just gonna bring it off screen on.
I'm just gonna play it and you can see what that does.
Oops.
OK,
run.
This chart begins at the first of January 2000 and 14.
This chart begins at the first of February 2000 and 14 of just sitting escape to stop that
code executing.
Obviously,
if we wanted to have that play a little bit quicker I'm not sure how many seconds it takes
to actually play that through.
But let me just play that.
And here we go.
Charge begins the first of January,
2000 and 14.
This chart begins at the first of February,
You go eso if you ever wanna have your code talk to you.
That's exactly you do with the application dot speech not speak.
Okay.
Any other questions?
Just let me know and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day.
Thanks a lot