Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
And this one's from Neil.
Now,
Neil has a huge file that he downloads from A s,
a P sap database.
What he wants to do is literally go down a massive data set on search for particular values
in column A,
which is coming,
and obviously,
in the real date set,
there'll be lots more values and there's lots more columns,
but basically what he wants to do,
we scroll down all of this and create a specific file for each of the companies in here.
So if the company just appears once,
he wants to have that line of data extracted to another file and say that with an
appropriate name a similarly,
for two or three once those two or three lines on that.
So here's the code.
This imagine is the master data setting.
You can download this file from this lecture.
There are three tab sheet.
One sheet to encode code is where you're going to find the code on she two.
Now,
this is where it is gonna be executing the code from on this particular macro here.
This subroutines attached to this but Miss Run May.
So here we have a list.
So we have done a ski vamps,
Bob's burgers,
McDonald's,
Burger King a one,
burgers,
even on Ethel's Diner.
So what we're gonna do is go through this long to time.
We've got a few dump a few variable set up.
It's up.
My string is just going to capture the search string from sheet to remember it's being run
from Here s so we're gonna go application display.
Let's false because we're saving the file.
We don't want that little pop up coming up saying you sure you on the same eso We're
turning off the display alerts at the top right here.
We're going to turn them back on at the bottom down here,
so it's just step through this code sheets seat to select,
just to make sure we're on the right sheet.
There we will be if we're executing from here.
But I've left that in there for Just knows right in the code.
So let's go through.
So we've picked sheet to if we were in already on it,
we're gonna pick range a two,
which is where our first value that we're looking for lives,
then we're gonna step through.
But a sign Whatever value is in a two to the valuable my string.
So my string no Now holds the value Donner Dullness Keep tabs.
Very imaginative name.
Now,
the next thing we're going to do is use the application worksheet function count if we're
gonna look at sheet one in the whole of column May for the value my string because if the
value doesn't exist,
we don't need to do anything else.
We just need to loop down,
move onto the next one.
So dollars keep labs.
When we do that on,
we hover over X.
We can see that Donner ski Babs doesn't actually appear in that list.
So if X equals zero,
that is,
I have no match F eight moved down the cell on,
then moved down here to our next loop and come back up on.
We're just gonna keep looping until we get to the bottom of this.
Now blank souls reach So let's now override my shrink with the new cell value.
Bob's burgers.
So Bob's burgers on.
We can see by hovering over the X that Bob's burgers appears three times,
So we've bypassed this zero Because we do have an entry.
Then what we're gonna do is open the template file.
Obviously,
you'll need to change the path in the file name.
But here we go.
That's off screen a little bit.
So let me just drag that over.
So here is a new open file,
and we're trying to do this.
You can actually see everything you should about seeing it from that.
OK,
so now we've just opened this file.
We're gonna come back and activate this workbook.
Booms are no.
We're back over here.
And they were going to get a sheet one,
because this is our master data set,
and we're going to go to the very start of the range.
Notice we have titles in row one,
so A to select.
And we are looking for my string Bob's burgers.
So we have Bob's burgers.
Just that.
So again,
we're gonna loop through until we get to the bottom of this data set on.
We're going to say if the active cell top value doesn't equal my string move down one.
So we're looking for Bob's burgers and active cell value is Bob's burgers.
So we're gonna jump straight to our else.
Now,
what we're gonna do is say with the active cell,
entire row dot copy.
So here,
we're going to copy the whole of line to let me just showing that down a bit so you can see
what happens here,
and c Fuck.
Um,
make that a little bit wider.
They go.
So back to here.
So the active cell,
entire road up.
Copy,
which is over here.
This entire row on.
We're going to copy to the workbooks master template.
Which is this one?
Sheets One.
Just in case we had more than one sheets range a 10,000 which is way down at the bottom.
Then we're gonna go end,
excel up,
which is going to take us right up to sell a one,
and then we're gonna offset by one row.
So our first blank cell is Well,
we're going to copy that data to.
So when they hit F eight,
they go.
You can see Bob's burgers.
It's just copied the entire road from here.
Then we're going to move down the cell,
and then we're gonna loop.
So we still haven't reached the blank self.
So my strings Bob's Burgers.
Active Sellers.
McDonnell's That's not right.
Move down.
One you can see expletive down one here.
We're just gonna look through.
So we get to Bob's burgers again.
There we go.
So now we're back over to here.
So now Bob's burgers,
his 100 copy the entire row from the active cell.
And copy two sheets,
one range,
8 10,000 excel up and down.
One cell that is here,
our first blank cell.
So we're going to move down and then we'll go all the way through until we get to the end.
For more,
more,
more.
Mom on day.
I think we've probably got that almosts now.
Okay,
so now we're going to select the master template,
which is this sheet here.
We're gonna auto size range A B.
So we're gonna make these that the appropriate column.
It's bump.
We can create a say file name the safe,
Full name.
I stole this from your care code,
by the way,
Neil,
but I've put the day so up front.
So we're gonna have year,
year,
month,
date,
space,
dash space,
my string,
which is Bob's burgers.
So you know which violist that XLs.
So we've built that string and there were going to do the same house.
No,
I'm saving it.
Teoh,
See,
uses our invest in my folder Say,
false on my save file name which is now going to be called two of 17 05 25 Bob's burgers.
And then I'm gonna close the active workbook,
which is this one I'm going to go back in select sheet to I'm gonna move down the cell,
and then we're gonna go back to the top of our loop on.
That's going to go all the way through and let me just I'm just gonna play that out now.
So it's going to go through each of those values in sheet to bring us back there.
Now,
if I just open that folder,
if I can find it Damn me,
just one second.
You will see that in our say you've file.
Here we go.
In our saved file,
we now have today's date space,
that space and never felt a wound.
Burgers,
Bob's burgers,
Burger King,
Ethel's Diner on McDonald's.
If we open any of those up and put them in shot,
you can see that it's done just that.
Okay,
Hopefully that helps.
As always,
if you have any questions,
just let me know.
Thanks very much and have a good day.