Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered these questions from Katrina.
Katrina has I would imagine a huge data table that sorted something like this simple data
table that you can see here that you can download this file complete with all the code from
this particular lecture.
Now,
the challenge here is that Katrina has written some code that she wants toe act on day sad
that's being read into an array.
So the element of the all the flavor of the question is with a data set that looks like
this read Group One into the array and then go into the other clever stuff with it and then
loop down and read Group Two into the same array over right in the original data,
obviously.
So we're going to reuse the array for this particular block of dates and this particular
block of data,
this particular block of days of this particular block of data and so on and so forth.
Now we know we can simply loading array,
using a medico just like this.
My tester equals range 82 c three.
And if I had a watch to that on just step through that code we see bum bum bump.
And when we have a look down here,
we have two elements from a to two C three And when we expand because see that we have one
absolutely absolute to one absolutely absolute to absolute see absolute to In our first
element,
the 2nd 2nd elements,
we have the next line down.
So the trick is we want to be able to do that,
but build this string dynamically at runtime.
So what I'm gonna do is delete that watch on was up to here,
and here's from Kodo prepared earlier.
Now it's basically sin option based one survivor array will always begin a tele mint,
one rather elements hero.
And we have to variables.
We have my camped,
which we're gonna load the count of this particular cell value from column A using the
application worksheet function count if a my array which we're just gonna declares a very
and because we actually don't know what kind of data we're going to be holding.
So there are two variables.
First line of code pick the first cell.
So a two and that's that in here we have our loop,
so Let me just let me just add a watch to this so we can see what it does.
Okay,
Right.
So here we go.
Let's step through.
So range A to select do While the act itself doesn't equal blank.
We've used that many times throughout the course.
So basically,
it's right through the whole of this dates table.
However long it is until we get to the first blank on,
then stop.
So this is the code that we want it to look like.
So my array equals range A to C three dot about you that will read the hall of that data
block the whole of that range into our array.
Now,
what we're gonna do now is get the count of how many times the active cell value one
appears in Column A.
So we're going to use the application work sheep function.
When I step through,
we can see that it appears twice now the data assorted perfectly.
So that's perfectly fine.
And that will work here.
Next.
We're going to build this string dynamically.
So we're going to say range the active cell address,
which is absolutely absolute too.
Andi.
So we can Katyn eight in the separator colon.
See?
So absolute absolute to to see Andi the active cell dot ro.
So we're on row two plus my count,
which is two.
And then we're gonna subtract one to get us back to three.
So we're going to go a to two C three,
and then we're gonna read all that into my array.
And when I hit her fate,
I can have a look there,
and you can see that that's pulled this road on this road into our rate on this bit.
Here,
the ad Your own clever code here.
That's where Katrina is going to use this array to do some other clever things with,
and then we're going to move down to the next group by using.
The active cells are tough.
Set my counts.
Remember,
we've already captured my count here.
So any hits F eight were instantly gonna jump down to the next group and we're gonna go
through our loop again.
How many times just to appear in column a while this summit appears three times.
So now we want to load into my IRA range a four to C four plus three minus one and Now we
can see that all three have bean loaded.
So this only captured this line of data.
This line of data on this line of data again,
we're going to use the my count,
offset once more F eight.
And then we're down to block three.
So when we stepped through,
my can't equals one.
So this time it will be from a seven to see seven plus one minus one.
At this time,
I can't.
Eagle three.
And there We have one to on day three.
Okay.
And then when we get down to the bottom,
obviously that's going to end.
Okay,
so that's hey,
can use a simple loop to read blocks of data providing these organized in this way by using
the application worksheet function count if toe work out how big that range is.
Okay,
Hopefully that helped.
And as always,
if you have any questions,
do let me know and I'll be happy to help you.
Have a great day