Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now,
this one is piece of code that I've had for a long time.
I can remember,
and I wrote it to be honest with you,
but don't solve a very interesting problem.
Now.
You may have come across this somewhere in your Excel.
Korea.
You have a workbook.
It was perfectly well,
It's certain size.
It's very manageable.
And you have it for days and days and weeks,
weeks,
months and months,
maybe years and years.
And all of a sudden it explodes in size,
and you have absolutely no idea why that is.
Now,
if that she has multiple tabs,
that is,
the workbook has multiple sheets.
The problem usually resides in one of those sheets.
But finding which one it is is a question off,
either using HTML,
which I find a little bit complicated for the task,
or individually save enough each one of those sheets to its own folder on vet in the file
size of that.
And that's precisely what this piece of code does.
So as a downloadable resource on this,
like you're gonna find something called Sq may for two in Magic Sheikh Sizer enable macros
on.
It's gonna look something like this.
All I'm gonna do This is how you're gonna operate it.
I'm just going to select everything hit control and see and close it up.
And I do want to keep what's in the clipboard.
And here is something we used in level three,
but I've added a few extra tabs.
If we look on here,
we can see that this deliberately is now about 10 Meg,
which is quite big for an excel file.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna come back to excel.
We're gonna hit old N F 11 to bring up the visual.
Basic editor.
We're going to come to insert.
We're gonna get to module.
We're just gonna pace that code in this window.
Just here.
Now,
this violence 10 Meg.
But we don't actually know why you're here.
So what I'm gonna do is just hit the play button and then that is going to calculate which
of these sheets are causing us an issue.
So he's gonna leave that co two room for a few seconds on.
I'll talk you through.
Had the code works in just a minute okay,
We should be that.
So let's go back to the the file.
And here we go.
We know of new.
She called my jazzy sheet.
Details on this code is gonna work as long as you don't already have a sheet called my
Jazzy she detail.
So here we go.
My Jessie,
she details is 11 kilobytes hr table is 33 v lookups is 64.
Formatting is 39 here at 9.5 megabytes.
Is this couch sheet?
So now we know that this is the sheet that is bloated.
All the rest are fine Now,
the easiest way to solve this is to in my experience is you just copy everything you have
in this sheet copies into a new sheet,
but use paste specials,
just the values,
and then go back and color meta time Or wrote a time,
reintroduce your calculations,
and then hopefully everything will fix itself.
I have deliberately made this fall 10.
Meghan,
I'll show you have So we've got this one that's got all kinds of conditional formatting
attached,
which is reasonably small.
We have table,
which is reasonably small,
but this one is the problem.
What we have is the HR for use in level three.
It's got a couple of 100 entries on.
I've added a new calculation.
The end called age.
Now,
if I had 200 calculations,
one fridge,
they each record,
we would be good.
But when I deliberately did here was,
I also pasted the same calculation down to the bottom.
So I have almost or over one million calculations that they don't actually need.
So that's one thing to check for.
If your calculations go all the way down to the bottom of your sheet,
what,
you could do it just come down,
delete them.
Okay,
so let's have a look at that code in action now is very straightforward.
It's all simple stuff.
We're gonna have a temp file,
which is set up as a string on an X,
which is just a simple counter.
We can turn off the calculations to make the code on fast and turn off the screen of dating
so we can't see you took dating then.
This is basic recorded macro stuff,
which we just tied it up a little bit.
We're going to add a new sheet and rename sheets.
Add before worksheets One that weighed always appears at the beginning,
beginning to give the active sheet name values the sheet.
We've just added my jazzy sheet details.
Then we're gonna add in a heading through a one through D one she named sizing by size and
kilobytes sizing megabytes.
Then we have a simple loop for X equals 12 worksheets count.
So however many sheets we have in this workbook this situation is going to pass through
that many times.
So on the first pass through worksheets X on the first pass will be one on the second pass
will be to copy.
Now,
here,
I'm going to save it to attempt file on the temp file is going to be stored in C slash
users slash allen allen slash desktop Obviously changed this to the path of your desktop.
Andi the active she name Andi docked x l s x So that is gonna be the name on path of my
temp file.
Then I'm gonna take the active workbook.
That is the one we have just created a copy off and save it as my temp file.
And then I'm gonna close it.
And now I'm going to say in the sheets.
My jazzy sheet details range a one fares next cell and excel up.
That is basically take me right up to below that title.
I want to record the worksheets ex dot name and that's going to give me the name of that
workbook,
which is the name of the first worksheet.
And then similarly,
on the next line,
this one just here,
the one in blue.
We're gonna do exactly the same.
But this thing we're going to go in column B on,
we're going to go up and we're going to say Value file length.
My temp file,
Andi Bites and file win is going to give us the size off the file in bites on the assembly
.
We just doing maths for the next one.
So it's exactly the same thing.
But this time we're going to do it in kilobytes.
So we just rammed him by 1024 on,
then simply at the bottom.
We're just going to do exactly the same thing whips too far.
But we're gonna go around following my temp file by 104576 which is going to give us the
answer in megabytes.
Then we're going to come down and we're gonna use the kill instruction,
kill my temp file and that will delete the file that we have just created and save to the
desktop.
And then we're gonna loop through.
We're going to do the same thing for the second sheet and the third sheet for as many
sheets as we have.
Finally,
we're gonna auto size columns eight d Then we're gonna turn the calculations back on,
and we're gonna turn the screen updating back on.
And that is how this code works.
Hopefully,
that's helpful to you.
But there's always if you have any questions,
do let me know.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.