Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered on This is a question from shore.
Now,
what Sean has is to files are identical in structure.
this date is completely made up.
But what we have in Sean source file is sheet one,
she to sheet three and sheep four.
Sean assures me it doesn't matter what the day to say is on.
We have another file,
both of which you can download called Sean Destination file on the game.
We have sheet one sheet to sheet three and sheep.
For now,
the structure in each of the files is absolutely identical.
Now,
the object of the exercise is to loop through each of the sheets in the source file and
find anything that's new or changed.
And if it finds something that's new or changed,
it wants to take that entire row of data that entire line of data on write it to the
corresponding sheet in the destination file.
Now,
this is actually quite straightforward thing to do.
What we have are essentially two loops.
We have an outer loop that's gonna loop through each of the sheets in turn on and in the in
that outer loop.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna write a concomitant nation Formula two column E just
here and all the concatenation formula is going to say that on that on that on that and
right,
the value in there that's gonna build back in Katyn ation string.
Now we're going to do that in Leak source file,
and we're also going to do it in the destination file,
then back in the source file a column f here.
What we're going to do is look for a match of this.
Can Katyn ated value in this can Katyn ated value column just here.
So if it finds a match,
it's going to return the position off that can Katyn ated match in column E in the
destination for their file.
Now,
if it finds a match we wanted just move over it.
What we want to do is if you find something that is not a match,
that is either one of the current values that as that's had something added to it.
So I'm just going to add my name in there,
so that will be a mismatch.
What we're gonna do is at an error trapped.
That says,
actually,
if I can't find a match,
just write the text update.
Now,
let me just show you how we do that.
So I've already written the code and the code looks something like this,
and it's very,
very straightforward.
So what it says at the top is this code luxury multiple sheets checking for changes between
the source file in the destination file.
Any changes new or changed are written to the destination filers and new entry.
Both files were identical in structure.
Okay.
At the Temple of Four variables declared,
my source file holds the name of the source file.
My desk file holds the name of the destination file.
My sheet name holds the name of this sheet and should say name,
shouldn't it?
Does the name off the bar?
Actually,
just also the name of the sheet.
They go on the outer loop,
and that is the outer loot cycle through these sheets.
So let's step into this.
Here we go.
Load the names of the source and destination files.
So my source file is Sean source file.
My desk file is Sean destination file F eight F eight.
Now we've captured the name to the to file,
so we can easily flip between them.
Go to the source file F eight workbooks.
My source file doesn't activate nowhere into our outer loop.
So for outer loop equals 12 workbooks.
My source file sheets dot Kent.
Now,
because we have this sheet over here,
this Get your sheet.
Your code here.
We actually have one extra sheet that we don't have in the destination file.
So I've just added a minus one.
So what we're going to do is out loot from 1 to 4,
which is the five minus one.
So that cycle,
through sheets out of loop one dot select.
So we selected by the index number one,
which is sheet one just there.
Now,
we're going to capture the name of that sheet so we can use it in our formulas.
So here we have our first block of code.
Now,
this is the formula that is going to be written to cells e to to e my source file my sheet
name range 65,000.
Way down the bottom here dot end excel up dot ro.
So in this particular instance,
it's going to write from E two to e 17.
This is covered in the course,
but it's very straightforward.
And all this is is a formula that were recorded.
I wrote the formula,
recorded a macro hit F two,
stopped recording a macro.
I've just pasted the foreman there in there.
So watch what happens in this sheik here.
F eight.
No,
we have all of our can Katyn ations.
Now,
I'm gonna do exactly the same thing to the corresponding sheet because I'm no got the sheet
name in the destination file.
Now,
I am gonna look at it,
but we don't actually need to be looking at it for this to work.
Just look what happens over here.
F eight.
And there they go.
Now,
let me come back here because the next thing we're going to do is write that check.
And this is the formula that I have written in their I've actually got that down twice.
I think so,
Yeah.
I don't need that in that many times.
That's the formula that I use just there.
Scroll over.
They go.
So workbooks my source file sheets.
My sheet named range F two to F muscles formation named Range A 65,000 way down in the
bottom end,
excel up and get the row number.
So that's going to be rose 17 on right that formula.
And again,
I just wrote this formula here in in F two recorded the macro hit F two stocks recorder
macro.
And that's how I got this coat.
So now you can see that we have to.
So this particular line of date has been found at row to I have update because I know have
Alan written in there on That's the one I want to look at.
So now we're going to go to the inner loop.
We're gonna hit F two a face rather to select the first line of data Robert gun sales While
the active celled up value doesn't equal blank,
that is cycle all the way through until you get to the bottom.
So if the active cell value equals update,
then do something.
If it doesn't move down the cell loop through No,
the active seldom value does equal update on what I want to do is copy the active cell
entire row dot copy to worksheets.
My destination file my sheet name That way,
we always know where right into exactly the same sheet range a 65,000 dot end excel up
that's gonna take us to our first populated cell.
And then we're gonna say dot offset one road.
So that's going to take us to our first blank row F eight and I'm gonna move down,
and I'm just gonna cycle all the way through that until we get down to a blank on.
Then I am going to any second now.
There we go.
Now I'm gonna clear the formulas that I've just written on my source file on my destination
fall.
So my source file may sheet E to f clear contents.
Look what happens over here and here.
When I flipped back,
you can see that we know have that new row of data written at the bottom.
And again,
if I come back to here,
I can just hit f eight on that removes that next out of loop.
Now I need to be on the destination sheets back to the code on this is just gonna loop
through again.
So again,
I'm gonna write the blocks.
Now we have a different one to update loop all the way through right that update for me,
I you can see that that changed to 12 because there is now a match and again just loop all
the way through.
And I'm just gonna run that out.
Number one more month.
Now here we have the source file on day you go on.
Now,
if we look at the destination file will see that we have a couple of new entries.
Vast one Andi among the source file.
Sorry.
Here's the destination file.
So our new entries have been added to the bottom of sheet one to the bottom of sheet to on
.
There was nothing new in Sheikh three and nothing new in sheep for hopefully that makes
sense.
But the codes fully rammed and you can get it from from this tab just here.
Hopefully,
that's helpful Shown.
Obviously you'll need Teoh make the concatenation longer because I think you have columns A
B,
C d e f on on.
But in principle,
that should give you exactly what you need.
Okay.
As always,
if there are any questions,
just let me know and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day