Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now this is in response to a question from Claire,
who's working away through Level two on Had the idea that what would you do if you have
multiple date ranges for one item in gallant charge?
She's just completed began Child section Now,
actually,
Miss read this question originally,
and I thought the question related to this middle part just here that said,
What do I do for one different colors?
Which was part of the question.
If I have different reasons for the absence,
so answer that question.
Back in Level two,
that actually wasn't a full question.
And the four question,
though it could probably be done with formulas.
It's far simpler if you do it in V B A.
So the question is,
what do I do if I have the unique identify the same unique identify or look of value
multiple times.
So store number seven,
double 01 We don't particularly want to lower Gannon charts a list it five or six times.
We just wanna list it once and have it color in the Gant chart in different colors,
depending on the reason code.
So that's the question.
Now,
here's some data that are butchered together and you condemn low this as a downloadable
resource.
It's called Gantt charts with a little more sophistication.
Andi,
as always,
you can get your code here.
Just copy all of that and paste it into a regular module and I'm gonna show you what it
does.
This is our data.
We've got different store numbers down here We have from Nate's.
We have two dates on.
We have reason codes.
So we only have three in ages for the purposes of illustration.
And they are stock take or its and statutory holidays.
I'm just gonna hit the button.
The goal is going to go away,
and it's going to generate this gun charge just here.
So we can say that green is a you which isn't all it.
And we've got little au in each of those cells to tell us it's not.
It s t will be in red on.
It will be a stock.
Take an S H will be a statutory holiday.
And in yellow,
obviously canal.
It's much sophistication to this as you like,
but this is just for the purposes of demonstration.
So let's have a look at the code.
So the code looks something like this.
A couple of things to point out.
The data sheet has a VB name of share data.
The gallant sheet,
this one here that we're looking at has a VB name of shit Gant,
both of which were covered in the course.
Now here is the code.
Now what we're gonna do is I'm just going to ram out the application screen updating so we
can watch this code go through as we execute it.
So here we're going to say,
shirt guns because we calling by cheat name,
range A range seven rose seven to row,
10,000 clear contents than clear format.
So it's just step through that bump on bump and they go,
That's giving us a completely blank sheet.
No,
we're going to say copy from ship Data range a four to a and again,
I'm specifying shit data because it's the data range on the data sheet.
Range a 65,000 way at the bottom.
Use the end,
Excel up.
That's going to take us to the last populated cell and get the road number.
So whatever the road number is and we can see here it's 52.
So essentially was saying,
should date at range a four to a 52 copy and then paste it to ship gowns.
This one range a seven.
So let's just execute that ***.
That is an exact copy of everything that we have in there now it should.
Gallant selects were already on it.
Now remove duplicates.
Now we're going to do a similar sort of thing.
Here we go.
But this time we're going to go from a seven to a We're going to go range.
We don't have to specify which sheet now because we're on the right sheet.
Range a seven and Excel down Row,
which is a similar kind of thing.
But we've gone from here down instead of 65,000 on up.
Remove duplicates columns one headed Excel.
No,
that's just butchered from a simple recorded macro.
Me his f eight,
We get our unique list of things.
You could probably other sorts of this.
Oh,
yeah,
clear.
Any sort filled.
So let's go f ace And again,
this is just a butchered recorded macron.
Step through now.
There you go.
So we have a sort order.
So then now they're sequential.
Go back to the main data sheet.
Here we go.
Range a four and do while the active cell doesn't equal blank.
So literally we're going to just loop through all of the's.
So we're on our first line.
Just contract,
then in a little bit,
so you can see it better.
That's probably about right.
So we're gonna do this while the active cell doesn't equal blank step through,
We're going to capture my store.
My start may end on my reason.
So we have my store.
7020 my start.
10 January 10th 2018 12 genera 2018.
And my reason is stock take F eight and we're going to step through again and we're coming
back to this sheet.
Began chart McGuinness.
You choose a seven.
They were going to have another loop.
While this column doesn't equal blank on,
we're gonna test if the active cell value,
which is currently seven double 01 equals my store,
which is 70 to 0.
And if it doesn't,
we're gonna skip through and we're going to move down the cell and then loop back up and
we're going to continue that until we get to this part.
Just here,
that is.
We have found a match.
So I'm just going to hit the bug and run to cursor.
And they go seven to blow four active cell value seven to blow four.
Sorry.
Here's where it should go to bug rule to cursor Try again,
Alex.
Diego.
So now we have xsl.
Value equals 7020 which is my store 7021 So now what we're gonna do is we're gonna have
another loop that goes across,
so we're going to go eight and we're going to move over to our first date column,
which is here.
So we have gone active Cell zero rose one column across and there we have another loop
that's never gonna loop across and check the date above.
So I might need to close this place off so you can actually see the four code Nega,
and that's a little bit better.
They go.
So now we're going to say do while the active cell offset minus active cell ro minus six.
Because we have six rows of the top selectors ro minus six.
The value doesn't equal blank.
So while this row here doesn't equal blank,
it's going to continue to loop.
So now we're just gonna loop through that their fate and check if the date in rows six is
greater than my end.
And if so,
go to the next pass.
So we're just going to step through that on.
We're gonna go like this and we're going to keep looping until we find a date that does
match again.
And with this,
I think I'm gonna run to cursor here for a second.
Let's go there,
debug.
Run to cancer.
Bigger.
So now we've found date match the matches our start date.
Now,
if my reason equal stock take this is just three logical tests of my reason.
Equal stock take and it does.
What we're going to do is collect the internal collapse vb red and to the active self value
.
We're gonna add the value S t.
And there's a second test to safe in equals old it it doesn't.
There's 1/3 test that says,
if unequal statutory holiday,
it doesn't.
So it's going to skip that,
and then we're just going to keep looping through that until we've done all of these.
Now what we're gonna do,
I think somewhere we're gonna loop out of this,
right?
Let me just go back up to that so you can see what that did.
So we had a jump to next pass.
So what we said is,
if the date in rows six is greater than my end date,
that is,
we've already reached the end of the things that we need to call it in,
then go to next pass and next pass lives down here.
So now we're going to go back to our store coat,
sell a six,
and we're going to go to sheet data.
We're going to move down the cell,
and we're just going to repeat.
And again,
we're going to capture all the data,
jump back there,
loop back through until we find out particular store code,
and then we're going to go across and coal retain.
And I'm just gonna play that well while it works.
I'll tell you the other bit that we're going to do now.
Now what this does is it generates It runs this code when you hit this button,
but oops,
that's a kitten coming in from the outside.
What we also have is this here You remember this from the gun child lecture back in level
two.
But rather than having that in Tyco duplicated as a workbook event,
what I'm gonna do is I just have a simple workbook event,
a bit of code,
which I did take outs.
It will keep calling this otherwise,
and I'm just gonna put that back in into the v b e,
which is No,
not that I concludes that I think I don't safe eventually will close on.
I'm just gonna pesetas a workbook event in here.
So I'm going to go to view to Project Explorer,
and it's gonna live in shit,
Gant.
And I'm gonna pace that in there.
Literally.
This is copied straight out of the workbook change events section because the law is gonna
do you say,
Look at that sell.
Look at that cell.
And if either of them change display a message.
So if a type seven and then he tends that you'll see you just change the either the
incremental the start date,
please it generate gam button again.
Okay.
And then with the gam button,
he could have just looked at will execute,
obviously turn screen update enough.
And then then you won't see all this flickering happen on then any second now.
And there you go.
Now you have your gun chart,
which is completely scalable to use in this increment.
I hope that helps and has always any questions.
Do let me know.
Have a great day.