Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
in this lecture,
we're going to discuss objects,
methods on properties.
Now,
technically,
I guess we could describe visual basic for applications as an object oriented language and
O L.
And that's because Excel is made up of lots and lots of objects.
So if we have a look here,
we have range a one selected,
so range a one is an object.
Range B one is a different object.
Range.
D six is a different object again.
We now have a little run,
but none here on this button is an object.
We have the scratch sheet,
and this is an object on this sheet is an object on this sheet is an object,
so you can imagine the real Lux and lots of objects.
Now the important thing here is you don't particularly have to know all the names of the
objects and the methods and the properties,
but what you do have to do is understand what they do just to give you an example.
I think that Eric Clapton and Jimmy Hendrix,
who most people would consider to be fine guitarists,
couldn't read or write music so they couldn't describe it.
No one would question their mastery of their subject.
So the important thing is that you understand what they do.
Okay,
let's have a look at the little video here,
so let's imagine for a second we have the object banana now with the object banana.
To separate the object from either the method or the property,
we will use a dot There will never be a space.
We will specify the object and then we will specify specify a dot now a method is an action
or something to do with an object.
So if we had our object banana dot we may want to say our method would be eat so we would
say banana dot eat Now sometimes methods can come with extra settings that called
parameters.
No,
between the method on the parameter,
that was always a space on DSO.
If we imagine for a second we would have the parameter off eating style.
So we have the object banana.
Our method is going to be eat on.
One of the parameters of our method is going to be the eating style.
Now,
whenever you see a parameter,
it's always going to be followed by a colon and in equals on that is the surefire
indication that you are working with the method.
Colon and equals always means you are working with the method,
and there we would specify the value of that method.
So in the case of our banana,
it will may well be the eating style is peel and munch.
Okay,
so one is a property.
Well,
let's take our banana object a gate.
And remember that everything is going to be separated by adults.
Be method or property.
Will.
The property is a characteristic of an object.
So we could say without banana that one of the properties,
one of the characteristics of the object could be its color on a game.
We have dots that separate the object from the property.
They can always tell if you're working with the property because it is followed by on
equals.
So here we can see the banana object,
its color property equals yellow,
and they go that say,
you can tell whether you're working with the property or you're working with a method.
If you're working with the property,
it will say equals before the value.
If you're working with a method it will say Coolum and equals.
Let's have a look to re a life example.
So it's come to excel.
It's also an F 11 on.
I'm just gonna use this bit here,
So range a five copy is our object.
Notice what happens when we hit a dot We get this little window pop up and you'll see there
are two different kinds of entry in here.
There are flaying green books.
I'm not entirely sure if that's what they are,
but that's what I call them.
And these are the methods.
These are the actions.
These are the things you can do with that object on.
By default,
the visual basic editor will look at the object that you have,
and it will only display the methods and properties that are available to that object.
So if we use this example here,
this select method,
what they could do exactly the scroll down here to get to select,
or I could literally just type s and you can see that Select is already selected.
And it has this little flying green book.
No,
I could either double click on select to select it,
or I could just hit the tab key on they go.
So now we have our objects.
Range a five on our method dot select.
Okay,
so let's have a look at a different one.
So let's say let's look a property.
If I hit a dot,
you'll see that we also have these little index cards here on the property I'm looking for
here is the front swelling and achieves fund.
But notice what happens when they hit a dot Again,
you'll see that the property phones of the object range a five also has properties,
So these are sub properties of the main property.
So I could say bold and I'm just going to double click it.
Andi,
I have no more options.
So for hit dot nothing else comes up.
So I am now at the end of the properties for funds Samonas say equals and I'm going to say
true.
Now,
if you're unsure,
the best thing to do by far is just record a simple macro.
Have a look at the code that's generated and it's gonna tell you exactly what this
structure looks like.
Now if you don't get these little drop down boxes here,
where my if you don't get these little drop down boxes here.
When you here to dot make sure that you have your settings exactly the same as I do or toe
list members.
That is what brings up that little box when you hit the dot OK,
right now,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look.
The hierarchy don't be put off by the name.
It's very simple to understand.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.