Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now this question is from Marine or Rennie or N a r e and E.
I'm not entirely sure how you pronounce that on Green or Rennes.
Question is,
how do you use the application?
Worksheet functions specifically the V look up to write a bunch of look up formulas to a
range of cells all at once without actually using the range dot Formula are one C one
equals and then actually right in the formula.
So what we want to do is get the output from the formula,
but use the formula in code,
which is much faster than using a formula in excel.
So just to make sure that I have covered absolutely every aspect of this question,
I'm going to show you every possible permutation that there is release everyone that I
could think of.
Now you'll find us a downloadable resource from this lecture,
a file called V lookups.
In code,
they can access eat in the Excel window.
But this is it V lookups in code another three sheets through a sheet one,
which is where we're gonna do our look,
hoping there is sheet to where our data set lies.
This is what we're looking up from on.
There's also going to be a get your code here sheet and when I finish this later,
I'll post the code in there.
So all you need to do is download it.
Copy all of the code in the get your code here and paste it into a regular module.
So here we go.
Permutation one.
We're firstly gonna look at hard coded ranges using this sheet name that is the tub name
that's down here.
So this subs call hard coded V lookups single cell.
So what we're going to do is say range be $1 value here equals application work.
She function dot v Look up range a $1 value.
So we're looking here.
She eats she too,
which is the name of this sheet just here.
Let me just move back.
We're going to say dot range a B because I want to look at all of this range he Xidan
around many entries on may end up having,
and I'm gonna say common to come a false because I want to return the second value.
So I'm just going to hit old.
Actually,
I'm just going to run that and you'll see what happens.
So they go never get the value one in a So that's how to do a hard coded V look up on a
single cell.
So next up,
we have hard coded V lookups over a range.
Now what we're going to do here,
let me just delete that D Actually,
I'll leave the dean.
This is gonna be the same thing,
but over a range.
So what we have is range B one to B three,
which is here equals application dot worksheet function dot v.
Look up and we're going to say range a one toe a three,
which is here comma sheets sheet to again range A B.
So we're looking in all of columns A and B comma to come a false and I'm just going to run
that and see what happens.
They go.
So began out 123 Which is V looked up from sheet to just here.
So I say you do it over a range.
If it's hard coded now there are other permutations.
So what?
You may want to do issues and named range so here in sheet to have actually called this
unnamed range off my data and you can see there that that's the name range called my data.
So let's come back to here.
Let's clear those out.
Hit Delete.
So here we go.
So this is hard coded V lookups single cell with the named range.
So what we have is range B one they sell just here equals application dot worksheet
function dovey.
Look up.
Range a one dot value again.
Range my data.
No.
Notice that we have range open brackets,
open quotes the name of the named range close quotes closed brackets comma two come a false
name.
This is case insensitive.
So the actual named range is capital M Capital D.
But it will actually work out what this is,
so that should work perfectly.
So it's just run that and they go,
we get the answer of one in cell B one so similarly,
we can do exactly the same thing with the named range.
So this time we're gonna say range B one to b three dot value,
which is going to be the three cells.
Hair equals application dot worksheet function.
Don't be look up and again We're going to say range A Want a three So we're hard code in
this dot value combat range.
My data might named May named range comma to come falls.
So when over in this sub Diego yet 12 and three down there.
So that's how you do that with named Ranges.
And there is another permutation.
Let me just scroll up a bit eso again.
We're going to use a hard coded range and we'll start with a single cell.
But this time we're gonna use those sheets VB name.
Now if I just If I just go to view from go to Project Explorer,
you'll see that she too here is actually got vb name of shirt,
my sheet So we're going to be calling it bites VB name So again,
what we're gonna do say range B one doc value equals application that worksheet function
Davi,
look up range a one don't value again Shirt my sheet which is thievy be name of sheet to
dot range a be coming to come a false And when we hit play,
you know,
we get one returned in here.
So again let me just delete that and similarly conduce this over a range of cell.
So this time we're going to say hard coded B one to B three.
That's the cells Just here.
Come again,
say dot Value equals application.
Would she function dot v Look up.
Range a one to a $3 value shirt,
my sheet dot range A and B comma to come a false And then when we run that they go,
we get 12 on three down there now.
So far,
so good.
But we have hard coded where we are looking and where we are writing to.
But what if we want to make this dynamic?
Well,
here we go.
We've covered this in the course one just going to go have a quick run through it here.
Dynamic named ranges.
Now,
this sub is gonna this this always basically to recap on have you capture arrange
dynamically.
So this is what we actually want to select.
We want to say range a one to a force.
If I run that sub,
they go.
That's the range that's bean selected.
But what we want to do is capture that dynamically because if we had,
if we had say f at the end and then we run that sub.
You can see that we're gonna completely miss f out because it's hard coded and not dynamic
.
So what we need to do is build this string dynamically.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna say range open rackets,
open quotes,
a one we need to hard code start of the range to a and close quotes.
Now,
what we want to do is add something to it.
So we're going to say andi range a one groups a misfire,
quotes range,
a one close quotes close brackets dot end and open the brackets,
and we want to go excel down there.
We could start at lane 65,000 or a 1,000,000 go up,
but I'm just going to go down first on a range a one.
So I'm going to say,
excelled down double click close brackets and I want to get the row number there.
Close brackets dot select Now I want to use Sam.
I want to use the road number cause I've already said I want Teoh A So all I'm looking for
is the number of that last row.
So Now let me just realm that bitter code out.
Now,
when I run this,
we should get all of the cells highlighted,
all the ones with values.
And similarly,
if we if we just had three and there we could delete that and run the code and then we're
just going to get 123 So they go.
That's how you do that Dynamically.
Now what we need to do this is where we're gonna be.
This is where the look up value is gonna live in our dynamic name range.
But what we actually want to do is we want to write the first argument where we are writing
the result to in column B.
So what we're going to do here,
I'm just gonna inaction was just going to copy that for a second,
uh,
copy,
and then you can see it in action.
So what we're gonna do here before we go to select one do say dot offset.
And I don't want to move any rose,
but I do want to move one column over because that is where we're going to write the
results of our application worksheet function dot v.
Look up and again.
I'm just gonna do select so you can see what that off sent to the sun.
Just a step through this code.
So there's that range selected the A They were going to go to a but this time we're gonna
offset.
So when they hit F eight b is selected,
but it's selected on rose 12 and three.
And let me just run that through if we had d actually,
these don't need to be in any order in particular,
so I'm just gonna step through that again.
So they go on.
There you go.
So that's how you build the dynamic range.
So again,
I'm just gonna wish through those three permutations.
So this time we're going to use this sheik name,
which is the tub name,
which is sheet,
too.
So we're going to do what we did in the first instance,
Or rather in the second instance,
because we're writing our values to column be so we're gonna say range a one to a from a
one end,
moving down all the way down here till we get to our last cell and capture the row number.
So at the moment,
this is going to be a one to a five.
We're gonna offset one No rose one column which is going to give us this range here that's
currently selected and the game we're gonna say application,
which you function dot v.
Look up on this time we are going to read Column A So we're going to say range a one toe a
a one moved down and get me the road number.
So a one to a five comma sheets she to range a B comma to come a force close brackets.
So then when we run that code Boom,
there you go.
We get out results of half of the lookups.
Now,
I'm just gonna really through these last couple really quickly.
This is exactly the same.
Was true done before.
But this time it's using the named range.
So again,
we're going to use that same dynamic way of capturing where all of our V look up values
start and offset one to get US column B on.
We're going to use the application worksheet function dot v Look up.
But this time we're going to say range my data because it's a dynamic because it's unnamed
range just mixes up.
I'm gonna put a in there again.
They go just keep you excited on.
Now I'm going to run that.
So they go,
There's off re lookups in action on finally using the sheets will be name.
It's exactly the same,
but here we have sure,
my sheet dot range a b.
So let's just go backwards.
F G h A B.
That's s assistant.
Even in there is it lets a day and let's just run the last one on they go.
Obviously,
we didn't have an agent.
Now let's say C you will most certainly had to say So Let me just from that There you go.
And that is every permutation I could think of on how to use the application worksheet
functions in code.
I hope that helped,
and it's always any questions.
Just let me know.
Have a great day