Okay,
guys,
I'm welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Now this question is from Theresa.
It's regarding date date stamps.
When someone has made a change.
What Theresa asks is,
I wanna have a current date inserted in a cell within columns.
Ed.
Any time a date of the data in any cell is changed or added in columns,
beat a Y on column A.
On At the moment,
she's completely lost on how to do this.
Now this is,
well,
first of their two ways to do this.
You could do this through trip track changes,
which I can't recall for the life of me if I've already covered in this course.
But if not,
I will check an ad elect tactic over drag changes or,
alternatively,
we could use a worksheet event.
There's a whole section on worksheet events in level three.
Andi,
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna take the code from the very last lecture,
which is another student.
Questions answered.
Long adapted to show Teresa have to do this.
So here goes.
You'll find a downloadable resource from this like check.
Uh,
it's called level three sq.
A student Questions answered.
18 telling a date stamp.
If a change has being made now,
you'll find two sheets in this downloadable file.
You have sheet one which is completely blank.
And you have your get your code here on dwelling them Do.
So I'm just gonna scroll up to supper this select all control and see to copy.
I would come to developer open visual basic,
and I'm double gonna double click in sheet one because we're this is work sheet code now,
just like in the last lecture of the the section about workbook events.
This code was something I've butchered from Microsoft on.
The link to the original code is here at the very top of the code.
So I'm just gonna stroll down and here's the modified code.
Eso If it's rammed on the far left,
then it's the original Microsoft wording.
And if it's rammed here,
they're my remarks.
So basically,
what we have is a work sheet change event on.
What we're gonna be doing is we're looking at the key cells range B Y comma,
a notice that the quotes go before the B and after the last a day.
So we're looking for any changes that occur in columns.
Be to why or column A Now here's the villa code that's gonna look to see through has been a
change.
If not application does insect.
He sells range target dust Address is nothing.
Then,
if a change has been made,
execute this code.
If no changes being made,
this code isn't gonna run anyway,
or it's going to go straight to the ends up.
And so what I've done,
because Theresa wants to add a time stamped to range zed two columns said,
is the first thing we need to do is we need to find out which row has being changed.
And that way we can build our cell address for where we're going to write our time stamp.
So what we're going to do is say,
range zed because we know it's always going to be in columns set or see if you're in
America.
Andi Target.
That's the cell that is being changed dot ro,
and that's going to get us the row number.
So said,
Plus,
the road number will give us the act.
The actual cell address no we're going to do is we're gonna change the DOT value to,
and I've also added this environment used name just so we can have a use and Hayman there
as well with a space onda a time stamp.
So let's just flip back to that word but can have look here that works now granted,
because there's nothing in the sheet,
it doesn't look terribly impressive,
but then we just type something in a And where's over?
Two column column boy,
isn't it?
And you can see that nothing was.
COLUMN Why so Must have to write down that alphabet for me.
Diego COLUMN Why nothing at all has happened in column way.
But if I had something in column B and hit enter and then come over to column white Ah,
you can see that we now have a timestamp.
Jarvie.
That's May 23 11 2018.
At 706 I start work early on 13 seconds.
That has a change has been made.
So there,
if I was back over here and delete that on with Mike over here they go.
You can see that another changes being made.
Now let me just delete that and make a change in here.
No,
because this isn't in our specified range.
Nothing's gonna happen on because a B isn't in our specified range.
Nothing is gonna happen,
but a is you never specified range when they hit Enter.
I automatically get a time stamp on the use of stamp that says Jarvie.
23 11th 18 2007 07 And also I think it went through toe.
Why didn't it see if I change something?
W bump Lego We got an updated timestamp Jarvie 2011 2018 at 77 on 13 seconds.
Hopefully that helps Ondas always.
If you have any questions,
do just let me know and I'll be happy to answer them for you.
Have a great day and I'll see you in the next lecture.