Okay guys and welcome
back to another student.
Questions answered lecture.
Now this question is
from Danish, Ahmed.
I'm a Danish asks is,
Is it possible to create
a custom shortcuts such as
using Control shift in G,
where all the grid
lines should be hidden.
But if we hit
control shift in G,
again, they should
all be returned.
So basically it's
an Excel shortcut,
the toggle something on or off.
Now it's really
straightforward to do.
I'm going to walk you through
it here in this lecture.
Now, all we need to
do is record both of
the options for so we're
gonna go to developer,
we're going to hit Record Macro.
Then what I'm gonna do is
put control, hold down,
Shift and press G because
they're the shortcuts.
That's the shortcut
that we want to use.
I'm going to press Okay, now,
I just want to get the
bones of the code for now.
I'm just going to
select all the cells
by clicking this little,
this little box up
the corner here.
I want to come to view.
And I'm going to
click grid lines
now I'm just going to click off.
Then I'm going to click
the little box up
the corner to select
all the cells again.
And I'm going to
click grid lines
back on and then I'm
just going to click off.
And that's basically
all we need to
do to get the bones of the code.
So now I'm going to
press Stop recording.
And I'm going to go to
the Visual Basic and
have a look at the code
that we've just generated.
So here it is,
the keyboard, shortcut,
Control Shift and g,
and we have self-select active
window display grid lines
equals false.
Then self-select active
window display grid lines
equals true.
And then we've got a random
range, E Eight select.
So I'm just going to change
that back to A1, one Vega.
So all we need to do here is
just introduce a logical test.
So what we're going to do is
we're gonna say, here we go.
Let's say the chances are that
they're gonna be visible.
The grid lines will
be visible the
first time we open Excel anyway.
So I'm going to say if,
say active window ductus,
my grid lines equals true,
then and here's
our logical test.
So if it does share a true one,
I'm going to do is leave
that cell select and active
window grid lines false.
So if the grid
lines are visible,
make them not visible.
Else.
Select the cells.
And if they aren't visible,
that is the displayed with
lines true equals false.
Then select the
cells and make them
true and make them visible.
And then just end if,
and then just range
A1 at the end,
select nowhere will
run this code,
but let's just take a
look at that in action.
So here's Excel.
I'm going to hit
Control Shift and G.
There you go.
All the grid lines
of disappeared.
Now I'm going to hit
Control Shift and G again,
and now they're all
back. So there you go.
We have one macro with
the keyboard shortcut
assigned to it,
the toggles, a particular
feature on or off.
I'll run that code for
you and I'll make it
downloadable as a resource
from this lecture.
One more thing
before we go, guys,
I've just run the code and
I've dropped it in here.
But the one thing that
I had forgotten to
mention is if you copied
the code and paste it in,
it loses its shortcuts.
So I'm just going to quickly
talk you through that.
So I've come to the
Get your code here,
Control and C to copy it,
go to Developer and go to
Visual Basic, insert
regular module.
And I'm just going to
drop the code in there.
Just like we do with
all the other curves.
Now, if I just flip
back to Excel for a
second and try the control
shift in G. You can,
you can see that
that is what we get.
That is definitely not the
code we were looking for.
So what we're gonna do is go
to fund the developer ribbon.
We're gonna go to Macros.
We're going to click the macro,
which is macro one,
and we're going to say options.
Then we get this
little box back.
So I'm gonna hold down shift
and G and then click Okay.
And then cancel.
Now if I hold Control Shift
and g, it toggles off,
control shift in G,
toggles on, off, on, off.
And that's how you get your
shortcut keys back in.
Obviously, once
you've done that,
then save the workbook
as an XLS m macro,
Macro Enabled Workbook and
everything will be fine.
That's it.
Have a great day.
And if you have
any questions, do let me know.
I'll see you in
the next lecture.