Okay,
guys,
some welcome back.
And in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look at the hierarchy.
They just make this a little easier to see.
I'm just gonna close the project window,
and I'm going to zoom over here to excel.
If I can drag this,
they go,
OK,
so we should be good for now.
so let's have a look at the hierarchy now.
One of the most important things that you need to remember with your coding is golden Rule
number five Be explicit because vb a cannot guess.
So just to illustrate that point here,
what I'm gonna do is execute this code,
which I've just dragged from here.
So when I step through this by pressing F eight,
notice what happens over here in Excel they go.
So range a five.
We have applied the method dot Select on range.
A five has been selected.
Okay,
so far,
so good.
Now,
if I would come to this sheet,
come back to this code and run this code again,
just sit in the play button.
Noticed that range a five has been selected again on That's because whenever you run code
like this,
whatever she you are looking at is exactly where that code is going to be executed unless
you specify explicitly Golden Rule number five.
Unless you specify explicitly the hierarchy.
Okay,
so let's have a quick look.
A hierarchy.
Now the hierarchy looks something like this at the very top of the hierarchy.
We have the application itself.
Analyses excel,
No,
underneath excel in the hierarchy.
We have the work book on there,
the files that you say they're the XLs exes and the XLs ends on that is the next level of
the hierarchy.
And then underneath the workbook in the hierarchy,
we have the work sheets,
and they're all the different sheets and taps that you can see along the bottom of your
spreadsheet.
And then finally,
the last level of the hierarchy are the cells.
So let's have a look at a quick video so we can understand what that looks like.
Okay,
the first thing we have is the cell that is the very end of the hierarchy on that could be
represented by something like Range a five now,
immediately above that,
What we have If you want to know which sheet we are working in,
we need to specify the worksheet and in this example that could be sheets,
sheet one dots and then range a five.
So we have sheets one on that,
specifying which worksheet we're working with.
And then we have the bottom end of the hierarchy and we are saying Range a five.
Now,
if we have multiple workbooks on our coat,
can work across multiple workbooks.
We need to move one level of the hierarchy again.
And this time we will specify the workbook.
So for argument's sake,
if we're in my macro book,
But we wanted to write some code that acted on range A five in sheet one off workbook one.
We would specify workbooks.
Book one does Excel s ex dot Remember,
they're separated by dots sheet one dot range a five.
And now whatever we wanted to do with that after that.
Okay,
so that's the hierarchy were going to come.
Too many examples of this is we work through our code,
but for now,
I'm going to see you in the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at this first
blocker Coaches here,
we'll explore what it does.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture.