Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this lecture.
Now,
whenever I meet someone that uses Excel,
one of my first questions is,
Have you learned how to program?
Now,
most people,
the immediate response would be Why would I need to learn how to program or the second
response would be?
Isn't it difficult?
Okay,
let's address them one at a time.
Where would you learn how to program?
Now,
if you have 1000 jobs that you need to do with Excel and every single one of those 1000
jobs is unique,
has no common characteristics,
and you'll never have to do them again.
There is absolutely no point in learning how to program,
because coding cannot help you in those situations.
But if you have 1000 jobs and excel and some of them you do every day or some of them every
week or some of them every month reporting is an excellent example.
Then you absolutely must learn how to program for three reasons.
Speed,
speed,
the difference.
You can get by automating a process using program in staggering,
which is the point of this lecture,
which I'm going to demonstrate as we go through it.
Accuracy No matter how hard we try,
humans will always make mistakes or if they don't make mistakes,
they are working at such a slow pace to ensure accuracy.
Then it would just gobble up your entire day,
and the 3rd 1 is reliability or repeatability.
If the tasks that you have are repetitive or you have to repeat those tasks,
it is begging to be automated.
With a little bit of programming a little bit of code in behind it,
you can make things fast,
accurate and repeatable.
Now the other concern that I mentioned was people think that it's difficult to program now
.
People of a certain age may remember a show called Buffy the Vampire Slayer now in Buffy
the Vampire Slayer.
In this one particular episode,
Zander was having trouble getting a girlfriend.
Now Oz,
who was one of the gang played guitar in a band on Xander,
realized that chicks dig musicians,
as Xander said.
So Zander says to ours,
I need to learn to play an instrument.
Andi,
he says,
You play guitar,
he says.
Is it difficult to play guitar and all says not the way I play it,
which is a very poignant statement because I'm sure programming can be horrendously
complicated,
but not the way I do it.
So you're gonna learn to program the way Island program and you'll find that although it
may look complicated the first time you see it,
you will grasp this so easily.
You wish you had done it years ago.
Okay,
let's crack on.
Now here's a file that you'll be able to download,
and we're going to look at code in this a bit later.
But for the moment,
this is just to demonstrate that speed difference on the accuracy differences between doing
something manually on doing something in code.
Now what we have is an employee list in a particular format on what we have is employee
number,
name,
national insurance number and Dunnellon Elland until we get back down to employee number.
So we have employee number down to car Reg on.
There's our first record.
We have MNC triple 01 and then as we move down,
we have MNC triple 02 down to here and MNC triple 03 down to here on.
We have a total off 200 records.
Now imagine that you get this file from your head,
office or whoever and unique ticket.
And you need to convert it into a table so you can do V lookups from it.
Now,
I've already programmed this just to give you a demonstration of the speed difference.
But let's imagine for a second that we're going to be doing this manually,
so I'm moderately okay.
It excel,
and I reasonably know what I'm doing.
So I'm just going to start the timer on my phone and see how long this takes to do manually
.
So let's go.
Okay,
First thing I need to copy the titles,
so I'm gonna copy that number.
Could move to D one and I'm gonna hit transpose boom.
Okay,
there's my first record.
I'm gonna copy.
In fact,
only use keyboard shortcuts from now on.
And I'm going to transpose that come down to hear record to down to record three control
and see back up to hear it,
right?
Click transfers,
Dan here,
record three dance record for control and say,
back of hair and paste at mistake Their control and said I meant to transpose right click
transpose.
Okay.
Down.
Teoh Andan emerges.
Click sundown to record four dance record five.
Copy.
Scroll.
Back up.
Right.
Click,
transposed and stop.
Okay,
42.78 seconds.
I'm not gonna do the entire 200 records,
so don't worry.
But here we go.
We can see that we now have our titles across the top on.
We have each of our records in sequence.
So we have record one record 234 now,
at the moments let's assume we already have the titles in on.
We have four records in,
say,
took 2.72 point 87 seconds to do the titles.
And then we took 10 seconds a record.
Now you because I'm working at the top of the data.
Obviously,
it's quick to get from here.
Back up to here.
But imagine by the time we go,
I'm only down to lying.
Let's go back.
Uh,
let's get to the thousands,
at least.
Okay,
so now I'm down to line one Sam's and on record.
I can't even see where the record is There again.
Goodness,
we're only up to M N.
C.
76 on we go down to 200 wasn't So we go down to 200.
So then we gotta keep scrolling down and copy and then coming back up to the top here,
right?
Clicking and transposing.
I think it will probably take longer than 10 seconds per record as we get further down the
list.
But for argument's sake,
let's call it 10 seconds per record.
So we have 200 records to do.
So let's because I'm useless at Mass unless I use Excel.
Let's say we took 10 seconds a record on we have 200 records to do.
Lips equals that times 200 boom.
33 minutes on 20 seconds.
So just so I can remember that I'm just going to put that in.
Yeah,
let me just copy them and pay special values.
I need to format it same way down a so format painter.
But don't dump,
say again if we were to do that manually on dure,
realize that we made a mistake.
So there is every chance that you could make errors while you transpose in 200 sets of data
.
But at 10 seconds per record,
it's going to take you 33 minutes on 20 seconds.
Okay.
Lets still eat this slop.
Now imagine that we had a piece of code that would do a similar thing.
Now,
I don't need No,
no,
I don't need to use my stopwatch on this particular one because I already have programmed
in the start and stop time.
And then we can quickly work out what the difference is.
So how long the toe code takes to run?
Okay,
let's have a look at the scope of this.
So we have 2800 lines of data.
We have 14 individual interests and we have 200 records,
each with 14 interest.
Andi,
it takes us 33 minutes and 20 seconds generously to do it manually.
So let's have a look how long that's going to take if we did it in code.
Now,
I don't need to use the stopwatch because I've already programmed in the start and stop
times for this.
And we can just do the calculation at the end to see how long it takes.
So let's go.
Okay,
we're done.
So now we have the table built.
So have employees name,
which is the employee name.
Sorry.
The employee number two number.
We have name to name national shows from massive insurance number andan London and all the
different things over here and we can see that we have this record.
MNC won hundreds kind of Phillips coming Phillips J T.
59 blab about Andi all the way down.
Let's just go down to the button to do quicksand.
Check.
So number 200 is Isla Collins and backups there Date they go.
Employee number 200 is indeed Isla Collins.
So manually that would have taken us 33 minutes and 20 seconds.
And here are my start and stop times.
I'm just gonna format these three cells to show us.
Chris,
we are that interested.
We're going to go to Allah's minutes,
seconds and milliseconds.
Some reason.
My screens having trouble update in Sligo.
I kicked off the code at 11 04 29.4 to 9 seconds on it.
Finished a little while later.
So let's have look equals that minus that one second on dpoint one millisecond.
So let's be generous and knock off the 10.1 milliseconds.
So that took one second to run compared to 33 minutes on 20 seconds.
If we were to do that manually,
OK,
so what's the difference?
So We've got 33 minutes.
Onda,
there were 60 sections it.
So we have 1980 seconds in 33 minutes,
plus the 20 seconds.
So we're talking 2000 seconds to do that job manually versus one second to do it
automatically using code.
So there you go.
How fast is it?
It's 2000 times faster on 100% accurate if you use it in code on.
That is the reason that you should learn to code.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.