Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
this time we're gonna have a look at the active sell property because up to now,
what we've done is reviews the range object within the range object reviews like a one B
six or whatever it was all specified a range to select the cell that we want to get to.
We've also looked at cells to look to the cell.
We want to get it so because they sells over brackets five comma two to get to a fire,
for example.
But what if the cell that's currently selected is the one that you want to perform an
action on?
Well,
that's exactly what the active cell does whenever cell is selected.
So currently,
here,
if I click here,
the active cell is D five.
Whereas if I come over to hear the active cell is B three.
Now,
I haven't changed.
Anything in the code is literally just looking at the active South.
So I'm just going to click a one here.
Let's have a look about the coders Active cell.
Technically active cell is a property that returns the value off the object.
So the active cell in code when it executes will work out what the active cell is,
and it will retrieve the object name.
So in this particular instance,
the active sell property is going to receive the object range A one.
Okay,
So what's going to do with the active cell?
It's gonna act on the fund property.
It is gonna act on the bold property off the front of property and set it to true.
Now,
because certainly one line of code,
I am not gonna f eight and step through it.
I am literally just going to click here.
Notice I am on a G five.
So if a hit play,
nothing of parents has happened.
But you can see the Bold has been selected up here because G five is the active cell.
While I actually want to work on is a one.
So if I select a one and hit from my code Boom,
they go.
It's no bold because a one was the active cell.
Okay,
I'm gonna see you in the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at the offset property
.
And I guarantee you you are going to be using that a lot.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.