Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
And here we're gonna have a look at the offset property.
Now,
if you look at the remarks here that are included in the code,
it will give you an idea of how these work.
Now what we have just to talk through this is we have an object which is going to be range
a five.
We have a property,
Andi.
Then we have a method.
So we combine in all three.
We have object property method.
So what this does is it is going to go to sell a five virtually is not were actually going
to select it,
because we have this offset command between the object and the method.
And it is gonna upset one road down and zero columns across a men's select.
So I'm just going to hit their fate and step through that.
Now,
remember,
a five is where we are beginning virtually.
And then we're gonna offset one row on zero column.
So when I hit f eight notice what happens over here?
So they go,
you can see that range a six is being selected because we've virtually went to a five,
and from there we moved down.
One column Andi Sorry,
one row and no columns,
so negative numbers move up.
So if we said minus one,
let me just hit stop on hit F Ace will virtually go to a a five.
Then we will move up one room so we would get to a four.
And similarly if we we can't put a minus number in here because we're already in column A
and we can't go left from column A.
But if we were in column,
B minus one would take us to column A or a postive number would move us over to the right.
Now,
you don't have to specify when you use the offset,
a specific range to begin with.
What you can do is use the active cell.
So here we used the active cell,
which currently selected is a four.
When they hit F eight,
you can see that we've moved no rose and one column across because the one is a positive
number.
We have moved over to the right.
Now we're going to use that.
We're going to incorporate it to something else we're going to see in just a short while.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture