Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
in the last lecture,
we looked at how to select a row of data or a column of data using the end incorporated
within a range.
But what if we want to actually select the entire range without going through the two steps
from here To hear them from here to here?
Luckily,
VB as a built in function for exactly that built in property called the current region.
Now the current region is from anywhere near the object where you begin,
so objects is gonna be range a five.
So from range A five,
the current region is going to be anything that is bordered with spaces.
So here we have the border off spaces.
So range a five dark current region dot select is going to select the whole of this region
.
So I'm just gonna hit her fate and step over that Nager.
You can see that all of that range is being selected.
Just gonna hit Stop.
It's also gonna work if we sick select anywhere within that range.
So even if I'm in C nine and I just step through that exactly the same thing is gonna
happen.
It's going to expand out and capture your entire data set.
I guarantee you're gonna be using that one quite a while now.
You also condemn exactly the same thing with cells.
Sophie,
just click off here and hits F eight cells.
51 which is essentially a five does precisely the same thing on Also,
finally,
let me just click on here.
So if I click the bottom corner one,
the active cell,
which is now 12 also works exactly the same way.
Now,
you may have noticed if you've been playing with code that if you froggy mistake type and
objects that should range a five,
arrange a one and you hit the dot.
The very first thing that you see is activate the activate method.
And you may be wondering,
what on earth is a difference between activate on a select.
We'll have a look at that in the next lecture.
So I'll see you.
That