Okay,
guys on Welcome back.
Now you know how to do just about everything with Selznick,
you'll know how to navigate around them,
selecting individual cells.
Ranges of cells go to the ends of ranges,
select entire ranges.
Cells is pretty much covered.
Now we're into work sheets,
and they are these little tabs at the bottom of your workbook.
As you well know.
Now I've copied some code from down below,
pace it into the basics,
testing this.
And here we're working with the active sheet on.
Remember that the active sheet is this sheet that we are looking at just as with active
cell,
active sheet is exactly the same thing.
But applying to the sheet,
we are going to go to next,
and we're going to apply the method dot select.
So I'm guessing without even having seen this code before,
you know exactly what that's going to do.
So I'm just gonna hit f eight on notice.
What happens in excel?
Boom.
We go to the next sheet.
So sales NATO was the active sheet we chose the next property on.
We so chose the select method.
Now,
similarly,
we are back to sheet previous select So the active sheet?
No,
she two previous go to the left and apply the select method.
So when they execute that,
there you go.
We can move left and right use in the next on the previous Now,
you also could call a sheet directly by its sheet name Or,
more specifically,
it's tab name,
So you can see here the next sheet that we have the next sheet,
in order after sales data,
has a tub name of sheet,
too.
So this code,
say sheets,
specifies the tub name on uses the select methods,
so sheets sheet to dot select.
There you go.
Fantastic.
That works beautifully until a user comes into here and says,
I don't want to be called sheet to anymore.
I want to be that to be called Let's call it my sheets,
you go fantastic.
And that's great for the use.
That theme user knows what's happening.
Andi,
I'm just going to a little of that code.
The user knows what's happening.
It means something to them until your code executes on.
Then this happens subscript out of range.
Runtime era nine.
I am looking for an object that no longer exists so there is an inherent floor with calling
sheikhs by their tab name.
Now,
luckily,
we have a way around that which we're gonna come to in the next.
Like,
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.