Okay,
guys from Welcome back,
right.
We already know there is a fundamental floor in Try and select a sheet using these sheets.
Open brackets open,
quotes their tab.
Name close quote.
Close brackets.
Dots,
elects.
That doesn't work if someone re names the tab.
But luckily,
visual basic or visual basic for applications has a way of dealing with that.
No,
to do it.
What we're going to need to do is go to the View menu and choose our Project Explorer.
So that is visible.
We're going to go to our view memory you,
and we're going to choose out properties window.
I'm just going to resize those so you can see it now,
This file when you downloaded it.
If you look here,
you may have noticed something a little unusual.
We have all of our worksheet elements of here,
and these are all the objects.
This is the work book object,
and you'll notice that we have sheet one,
which is sales data she to which is looping sheet three,
which is scratch.
So you you'll Nobel toe workout that whatever appears in brackets here is what appears in
the tub name here.
But this one say something else.
It doesn't say she 12345 or anything else It says Tab,
my sheet,
which we now have in here because we changed in the last lecture.
But well,
front,
it say's my second sheet.
Now that is the visual basic name for this particular object on the way to change that in
your properties,
select the sheet.
You want to change the name off and in the name in brackets section just here,
just clicking here and call it whatever you want.
Now this is just an example.
So I've called it my second sheet just to make it easy to remember.
But generally my convention would be S h and then whenever I want to call it so technically
,
in a normal programming project for me,
this would be called shirt my second sheet or something like that.
So once you've renamed it,
just hit.
Enter on,
then that sheet permanently because has visual basic name of whatever you just called it.
So here,
let's test this code.
I need to be on a different cheek doing that.
Let's just test this code.
If I f ace through,
we no longer have a sheet with a tab name sheet to,
So that code is gonna era.
And so I'm just gonna delete that Now,
notice what happens now?
I'm gonna call it by its visual basic name.
It works.
So if I come back in here on rename and call it sheet to again and hit it whips or shot to
a site type there on I come back over here and I re execute that groups.
Not that code.
Alan in here and now execute that code.
It still works because the visual basic name is now hard coded to the object.
And by far that is the best way to reference your objects.
Okay,
Elsa,
you in the next lecture.