Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
And here they are,
the 15 golden rules of coding.
This is a downloadable resource from this lecture.
I highly suggest you download it printed out and keep a copy with you,
particularly as you'll start in your code in Korea.
Sit to these 15 golden rules and you are not going to go far wrong.
Right?
Number one work on a backup.
There is no undue.
I know that when you work in Excel,
if you make a mistake,
you have that comfort feature of hit in the undo button.
Not so when you make a change using code,
there is no undo.
All you can do is close your file without saving and then reopen it.
The drawback is that any work that you did do is lost.
So always wear coming back up.
There is no undue okay number to think through the process.
The guy who got me into programming originally all those years ago told me If you can
describe how to cross a road precisely without getting killed,
you can lend to program.
So as long as you think through the process and adopt that philosophy when your programming
you are not going to go far wrong.
All of these rules are built in to this course natively.
So we're gonna explore them as we go through the course.
So number to think through the process.
Number three,
test test and test again.
If you write a particularly exquisite piece of code that works beautifully on one data set
,
test it on a few more data sets just to make sure that there are no little bugs in there.
So test test and test again.
Number four,
keep a macro book.
Now,
Macro book is just next cell filed that you're going to save is a macro en abled workbook.
And your macro book is gonna hold all the really useful bits of code that you're ever going
to need on.
We're gonna build a macro book as part of this course.
Okay,
so number four keep a macro book number five be explicit.
VB a Can't guess No.
By default,
unless you code it differently.
Whenever your code executes,
its gonna execute on the sheet that you're looking at on on the work book that you are
looking at.
And that may not be what you want.
It to do.
We're going to cover this fully in the course that don't worry,
Teoh too much at the moment.
But just remember,
be explicit.
Okay?
Number six code simply Andi in small chunks,
although is going to be tempting to write 10,000 lines of code.
If something goes wrong,
it's gonna be a nightmare to try and debug it and find out where the error is.
So I highly suggest you could simply alley in small chunks.
Just write a little bit of code.
Make sure that works and then progress.
Okay,
Number seven Realm extensively.
Now Ren is short for remark,
and all that means is it is a comment in your code when you work out what something does.
If you add an apostrophe and you're going to see this throughout the course,
you can add a little note that describes exactly what that little bit of code does,
and that's going to make it so much easier if you come to look at the same code a year
later and you think I don't know what that does So realm extensively.
We'll cover that in the course took Okay,
Number eight re usual code.
This comes back to the macro book.
If you write a brilliant piece of code or a brilliant routine that does something,
keep it in your macro book.
There's no point in writing it again a year later.
Just go back and re use the code that you've already written.
Okay,
Number nine Code iterated Lee,
though,
is going to be really tempting view to solve every problem all in one huge piece of code.
I strongly suggest that you break your larger problem into smaller problems and solve each
one individually.
So number nine code,
it's relatively numbers 10 and 11.
Shorter code runs faster,
but ugly code still works Now have put that in here because everyone I've talked to program
whenever they write a program at the start of their program in Korea will look at it again
year later and say,
I could do that in half the mantle lines.
Probably true.
Shorter code does run faster,
but if you're ugly,
code still works.
It still works.
Okay,
that's 10 on Day 11.
Number 12.
Use the built in translator,
and that is the macro recorder.
The macro recorder,
Although it'll often generate many lines of code a lot of which you don't need.
It's very useful for telling you the structure of what it is that you're trying to do,
and we're going to cover that throughout the course.
So Number 12 use the built in translator number 13.
Is there a function for that?
Most of the functions that are built into Excel are already built into VB A,
but not all of them.
But if there is a function that you can do in excel,
then we have a really neat way of making that function available to V.
B.
A.
And we'll cover that in the course to.
So number 13.
Is there a function for that number?
There is always more than one way if you can write a piece of code.
The works perfectly is solid on repeatable,
but it looks different to someone else's solution.
Don't worry about it.
There is always more than one way and number 15 have fun,
and I guarantee when you start to automate your routine tasks,
you're gonna have a lot more time to have fun.
Okay,
their number 16 off 15 is used Google.
Years ago,
when I started to learn to program.
Google wasn't even invented.
I'm not even sure the Internet was invented.
But I can guarantee you if you have a particular problem.
Someone else has already had the same problem on there will be a least half a dozen
solutions on Google.
So if you come across a particularly sticky situation,
your first move should be go to Google,
type in VB a excel,
and then what it is you're looking for guarantee you're going to find some solutions.
They may be very complex solutions,
but by the time you finish this course,
you will be able to break them down and simplify them and make them more elegant.
Okay,
so there they are,
all 16 off the 15 golden rules of programming.
Stick to these and you're not going to go far wrong.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.