Okay,
guys.
And welcome back now,
occasionally,
when you look at other people's code on DPI,
perhaps even throughout this course I can't remember exactly how I remember thing that
you're going to see two different ways of reference in sheets.
You will see this way that the sheets objects.
So here we have sheets,
sales data dot select or sometimes you'll see written this way as worksheets sales data dot
select.
Now there is a fundamental difference.
It's not by accident that we have two different things in here.
Sheets will recognize any sheet within excel,
whereas worksheets will only recognize regular excel sheets.
They are the sheets that you can see down here.
But if I wanted to add a new charge,
she just by hitting after 11 you can see that we know have Chart One.
Now,
if I If I come over to here and just go to the view on due to the Project Explorer,
you can know,
see that the charge sheet looks different to the other worksheets.
Okay,
now,
that's gonna be particularly critical here,
So let's execute through this code.
So when I hit F eight sheets,
sales data will select this sheet Perfect sheets chart.
One will select this sheet because sheet will recognize all elements.
Worksheets.
Sales data will work perfectly,
but worksheets only works with regular excel sheets.
So when I try worksheets chart one dot select,
we get a runtime error because the specified specified dimension is not valid for the
current chart type.
And basically,
worksheets will not work with anything other than a regular excel sheet.
Okay,
so there's a difference between sheets and worksheets.
I'll see you in the next lecture.