Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
in your coding career,
mostly you're gonna be doing one off two things.
You are either going to be reading data or you're going to be writing data.
And that's what we're gonna have a look at in the next couple of lectures.
Okay,
up to now,
we've used the methods,
select and then we're gonna have a play with at the Value property.
So I've got a bunch of code in here.
I've just pasted it into our sub basics test.
Testing this on what we're going to do is work with the range A one object.
Now,
just a note on the hierarchy here.
I haven't specified which sheet or which workbook.
So we are working with whatever we are looking at.
That is the active sheet.
So that's this one just here.
So what we're gonna do is say,
with range a warm we are going to set its value to hello world on notice that because this
is text,
we have enclosed it in quotes before and after.
Okay,
so let's just hit f eight and step through this coat.
Notice what happens over here in excel they go range a $1 value.
Property has been set to Hallow World.
How cool is that?
Now?
We can also write the same text to multiple cells all at once by using the range and
specifying the range here,
separated by Coghlan's.
So the game,
when they hit their fate,
notice what happens over here in Excel.
Boom!
They go.
We get that same text populated to all the cells we specified in that range.
Now,
equally,
we don't have to use the range object we can use.
The cells object,
so it's exactly the same.
Structure sells 30 most down one column across a 13 by any other name.
The daughter value property is now going to say this is a 30.
You know,
when I hit f eight,
they go on pointing.
You can't see that.
There you go.
So in cell A 13 we now have this text.
Now here's the thing to note.
If you're entering Texas,
I said just a second ago,
you have to enclose in quotes if you're entering a number.
Not so.
If you're entering a number,
you can literally just write the number,
So range a $1 value.
1234 When they hit that,
you can see the A one has changed toe.
1234 as a number.
Okay,
Now observing the hierarchy You'll remember a couple of lectures ago that we renamed the
visual basic name off sheet to hear to my second sheet.
So what we're gonna do here is specify my second sheet range.
A $1 value.
Will say I did this from Sheet one actually did it from scratch.
So let's come over here,
Hitter Fate.
Nothing's happened here because we've said it's in my second sheet.
When I come back,
Here they go.
I did this from sheet one.
Now,
Not only that,
we're gonna observe the hierarchy again.
Just a quick note on this.
This code here,
you can see that I have dot space underscore,
and then the text goes onto another line.
If you have a really long line of code,
you can literally just hit space.
Underscore Hit.
Enter your code will still execute as a single line of code.
It just makes it a little bit easier to read.
So here we are,
specifying workbooks one which is this one here groups,
which is this one here sheet,
too.
And I'm gonna come back to sheet one.
So there's nothing in cheat to.
I am picking sheet one and coming back to my macro book.
So here,
I'm gonna say workbooks Book one,
which is the other workbook sheets to which isn't the one that we could see because we just
flip back to sheet one ranger You want to stop,
Value equals.
I did this from another workbook.
When I hear that right,
Boom,
Let's go back here.
She want his workbook?
One She too.
I give this from another workbook.
How clever is that?
Now you'll remember.
I mentioned a couple of lectures ago that if you want to select another workbook,
you must activate it first.
That is not true.
If you just want to read or write data or make changes in another workbook only if you want
to select it,
that is.
You want to see the thing.
So if you're reading and writing data,
this structure here works perfectly.
OK,
Now what we're gonna do is have a look.
It's a variable now.
All of variable is is a little units of memory that we can allocate a value to now in the
next section recover variables in debt.
But for now,
all you need to know is a variable is a little unit of memory that we're going to store
something in on what we're going to store in my first variable.
That's its name is the text Wonder.
Lovely day.
So when I hit enter this tax.
There's no been loaded into this variable here.
My first variable no holds this text.
And now what I could do with it is right that to a cell.
So notice here.
This is like this from sheet one.
But when I hit f 81 a lovely name.
Okay,
so now you know how to write data to cells.
To ranges of cells,
two cells on a different worksheet and even to cells in a different workbook without even
having to activate and select them first.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.