Okay,
guys are welcome back now in the last select Should we looked at how to populate values
into cells Now it could be that we want to take a value that's currently mon cel
unpopulated to another cell.
And that's what these little blocks of code here do.
So here,
if we look at this line of code,
we're working with the object range B one on the object range.
A one on what we're going to say is the value in B one is equal to the range in a one.
So here,
if we said hello or he low,
I can't type,
found talk at the same time and then and then ran this line.
Mako.
So I'm just gonna hit f eight.
Notice what happens in B one So the value of B one is equal to the value in a one there for
clicking there,
you can see it doesn't say is equal a one.
It literally is just the value because it's the value property we're working with.
So let's say I can't remember how many,
uh,
whips.
Hello.
How are you today?
1234512345 That will.
Day s O here we say working with the range objects again.
But this time the range B one to B five.
Now,
the important thing when you're copying a range of data or when you're saying a range of
data equals another range of data,
you have to have the same size range.
So B one to B two wouldn't work.
If we're copying a one to a fight,
you'd only get the first to value.
So b one b five a one a five and this will do exactly the same thing.
So when he hit at eight,
there you go.
Everything that was in a one through a five has been written out to be one to be five.
Now,
what we could also date is captured the value of the active cell on reading into a variable
.
So if I said this is the active cell,
so have written lips.
I can't type told Wickham type tonight.
So this is the active cell.
Andi,
make sure that it is the active cell.
I could read the active cell value into the variable.
My first variable hit f eight.
And if I hover over that,
you can see that we've no captured the data.
The value data from the active cell into this variable on.
Then I come right that variable to range g 16.
And if I hit F eight rips the G 18 and there it is in G 18.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.