Okay,
guys,
some welcome back.
OK,
we've had a look at some of the most commonly used methods.
Now,
let's have a quick look at some of the commonly used properties.
So here,
we're going to be playing with the front property.
Now,
I've already got the text.
Hello?
Written into a one.
And here we're going to be working with the object range.
I want this one just here.
We're gonna hit dot font dot bold and say true.
So you can probably guess what this is going to do.
I'm just gonna hit f eight and go through,
and you can see the text in a one has gone bold near the opposites or the reverse function
to that is font dot bold equals false.
So if that if so,
if I hit f eight again,
they go,
It's no been emboldened.
Now there are two ways that you can set a front,
a bold or not bold or regular by any other name on that it's used in that is to use the
funds property on the fund style property.
Now that has a specific use,
which we're going to get to in just a second.
So here.
Let's just do exactly the same thing.
Make the text bond to use in the font style property of funds.
So they go.
Text has gone bold,
and now I can set it back to regular notice that I have regular in quotes,
just as I had bowled in quotes a few seconds ago.
On they go,
it's back to regular now.
The beauty with fun style issue can change mawr than one format or more than one phone
style at the same time.
So here you can see in quotes I have bold italic.
So this is one line of code to do two separate things.
So when I hit F eight,
they go,
we get it in bold italics.
Now,
I strongly encourage you just set up a new worksheet,
open a new workbook,
type something to sell a one type range a one dot and have a play around with all the
different properties and see what they do.
So here we're gonna look at the range a one interior dark color property and set it to V B
red.
Now all of the colors in Excel and there are tens of thousands,
maybe millions of Kalis have a different number.
So if you record a macro,
you may find that a particular yellow is 6 5527 Whatever.
But you can also use if you literally if you type in low case such as we be read baby green
vb blue.
If it capitalizes the way this is,
it is still a recognized name and visual basic.
So now if I hit F eight there you go.
We can see that the interior property of range A one the color of the interior property has
turned to read.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at a fume or of the commonly
use properties.
I'll see that.