Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Never gonna have a look at another property that I guarantee you're gonna be using Quite a
lot.
That is the address property.
So what we've got set up here is a bunch of code that's gonna demonstrate loads of uses for
the address property.
Now,
when you write in projects in V B A,
there were going to be times where you use something to find a particular piece of data,
and you need to know specifically where that data resides.
So you can either copy it or you can reference that sell a little later on.
So here we have a few lines of really useful code.
So the 1st 1 this is a variable done.
We're going to come to valuables in the next section.
So we're going to read into a little block of memory.
Called my cell address,
the active cell address,
or when I hit F eight,
you can see that I'm currently in 11.
And if I hover over here,
I get the cell address A 11.
Now,
what I may want to do is find out where the bottom of a particular range lives.
And here we're going to incorporate that end that we looked at a little earlier on Excel
Down.
So I'm going to say my last row address.
This is a different valuable started range A five go down to the last active cell or the
last cell with the value and tell me what that addresses.
So here,
I'm just going to press f eight noticed that this hasn't moved because we haven't used the
select.
But when they hover over last row address,
we can see that we have a 10.
And that is the last populated cell in this range of data.
No.
Similarly,
if we had before,
I execute that line of code,
but let me just copy all of that over.
Similarly,
we could use the last column address.
So again we start arrange a five.
We're doing the end again.
But this time we go in Excel to write,
So notice I have these selected,
and that's not gonna affect this because the range A five is virtual so when they hit f
eight,
you can see that the last column address from range A five going excel to right is absolute
.
Be absolute five,
which is exactly what it is now,
one thing that you're most definitely going to be using,
particularly when your tagging new data onto the end of old data sets is you want to find
out where the bottom of your range is.
So the game we're going to incorporate this end and excel up,
but this time we're going to start way had the bottom of excel in line Is that
1,000,048,546?
If you're using an older version of Excel,
you're only gonna have 65,000 536 lines.
So you may need to change this.
But again were virtually going from here.
When we're not actually going to go and select it,
we go virtually from line.
A 1,000,048,500 76 were using the end and going excel up and capture in the address.
So when they hit their fate,
you can see that the my very last row address is absolute A 10 which is exactly correct.
Now,
when you are capturing new data to stick onto the end of all data,
what you actually want it gonna want to know is one is the first blank cell because that's
where you're going to write your new data.
So here we have almost exactly a line of code.
But we've done the excel end up,
and then we have tanked on their the dot offset one which is one road down.
So what this is going to capture is this cell address,
which is our first blank cell after this data region.
And that's where we may want to paste on new data.
So when I hit F eight,
I can just hover over here they go.
Absolute.
A absolute 11 guarantee you're gonna be used in those quite a bit.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at rows and columns.
Okay,
I'll see you.
That