Okay,
guys,
I'm welcome back.
Now,
this is again from the sub,
the basics code.
And we've already looked at this particular line in the last lecture.
I just included it in the same group.
So if you happen to look there,
you'll find exactly what you're looking for.
So those two particular blocks of code appear twice in sub the basics.
Okay.
Never gonna have a look at two other properties.
They are the Rowe property on the column property.
And all this is going to do using the dot Rowe property is returned the row number of the
active cells.
If I click on D seven and hit F eight on read into the variable,
my row number equals the active cell dot ro on the hitter face and hover over here.
You can see that my row number is row seven.
Then that's gonna be particularly useful if we need to work out which row of data we are
working in on.
Similarly,
we have a corresponding function called dot column on.
I bet you can guess what that does say.
If I hit f eight on hover over here,
you can see that my column number is column number four.
So I know.
Know that the active cell is in Row seven,
Column for on That's going to be fantastic if we use in cells.
But what happens if we want to actually get it in plain old a one?
Speak and find out that we have he seven selected,
and that's gonna be the subject of the next lecture.
Okay,
I'll see you that.