Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this lecture.
Now,
what we're gonna have a look at in this later is the visual basic editor on recording a
simple macro on you'll remember from the 15 Golden Rules of cold coding.
Rule number 12 is to use excels built in translator because trying to work out VB a coding
from scratch is tremendously difficult and not always obvious.
But using the clunky built in translator Sorry,
Microsoft,
you can get a good idea of the syntax and the structure that you need to use.
Okay,
Now,
this file you can download from this lecture as a resource so you can play along on.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna look at the different ways of accessing the visual basic
editor on also different ways of recording a macro.
So,
firstly,
to get into the visual basic editor on my preferred method on the preferred method of
everyone I've ever taught from Excel on your keyboard hit Olt and F 11 and your visual
basic and it's out will open.
I'm just going to scroll that down.
So it's full screen.
They go on.
This is the visual basic editor.
Now it's made up of three primary areas.
There is the project VB a project which is this area just here There is the properties area
,
which is this area just here on the main coding window.
Now,
at the moment,
we have no code written,
so we have nothing to edit.
But these are the three key areas.
Okay,
I'm just gonna close that for a minute.
We're gonna have looking and mill the way to get into it.
If you don't have the developer tab in excel,
just right.
Click on any of the terms that you do have choose customized ribbon,
and this window will appear on what you want to do is come down to develop at and just tick
the developer button and click.
OK,
and then you'll have developer.
So from develop a menu or from the developer Riman,
you can click visual basic on Boom.
You're straight back into the visual basic editor.
Okay,
now turn to put some code.
And so what we're gonna do is we're gonna record a simple macro,
so I'm just gonna close that for a second.
Then we have three different ways of recording a macro from the developer ribbon.
We can go to this button.
Just he had that says record macro.
Now all macro is going to do is record a set of keystrokes that you perform while it is
recording.
So you don't have to whisper while it's recording because it doesn't record audio.
I'm thinking a friend that I used to work with for that one who is always silent.
Williams recording macros.
You know who you are.
You could also use the view menu on.
Do you have a Mac Rose option over here with a little down arrow where you could hit record
macro or my preferred method is to use the little button down here.
Now,
if you don't see a button down here next to ready,
just right click come up to the macro recording and you'll notice Well,
not record in and just ticket.
So when you click off,
you have this little button.
So when the but looks like this,
you are not recording.
But as soon as you click it,
boom,
you get this window on.
That means you are now recording a macro,
or you will be when you click.
OK,
now,
a few things to consider here Macro names.
You can call them pretty much anything you want.
By default,
Excel will call the macro one micro to macro three and on and on and on.
But it's generally a good idea to call your macro,
give it a name that actually describes what it does.
So what we're actually going to do with this particular macro is we're gonna highlights all
of our formulas.
Now,
there are three rules that you must dear to your names cannot be longer than 255 characters
.
They cannot have spaces,
and they cannot begin with the number.
Pretty much anything else is allowed.
So I'm gonna call this highlights on.
I tend to use Camel case.
That is,
I capitalize.
The first letter of each word some people prefer underscores.
I'm just a camel case.
So highlight my form.
You,
Laz,
I'm not going to assign a keyboard shortcut.
Um,
now store macro in this workbook,
but we have different choices.
We could have new workbook,
which is pretty obvious one that us on a personal macro workbook.
Well,
we'll discuss this a little later on,
but for now,
we're just gonna choose this workbook on description.
What we're going to say is this will cool,
uh,
in yellow.
Oh,
my phone.
Um,
I can't look on type.
This will color in yellow,
all my formulas.
Okay,
we are no recording a macro.
As you can see,
that this little symbol has changed to a square.
Okay,
let's do something.
So what we want to do is come to the home ribbon we're gonna come to find on and select.
We're going to go to go to special on.
What we're gonna do is choose formulas on.
We want formulas that result in numbers.
Okay,
so you can see automatically that all of the's cells,
which contain formulas that result in numbers,
have been highlighted.
And then what we're gonna do is color them in yellow.
So from the home tab,
I'm just gonna hit yellow,
and then I'm gonna click off.
That's just click that.
So there you go.
That is everything that we wanted to do.
So now we're gonna happily stop that recording and then begin again.
Have a look at the code that's being generated.
So we have three ways to stop a macro recording.
We can hit the little stop button down here,
which is normally the way I do it.
We could go to the view tab to Mac Rose on press the stop recording button.
Or we could go to the developer tab over to hear impressed.
Stop recording.
I prefer to use this one,
so I'm just gonna hit.
Stop.
Okay,
so let me just hit Cult and 11.
And you can now see that we have a new thing.
Appeared in R V B.
A project.
We have a little folder called Modules with a plus button side of it.
So I'm just gonna hit plus,
and you can see that we have module one.
I'm just gonna double click on module one.
And there is our first macro.
You'll see that it is called a sub,
which is short for subroutine.
And it begins with the word sub and ends with the word end sub.
Wherever you have a sub,
you must have an end sub.
And when you record a macro,
that automatically happens.
The name of the foot.
The name of the macro is the one I typed in.
And you can see that that's repeated here on our description.
This will color it in yellow.
All my formulas has also been added here.
Now,
a couple of things to notice is that some of the words it's very difficult to see,
but some of the words are in blue on they are reserved words such as Sub Andi,
I think with Andi and with and with our controlled words,
reserved words.
Some of the coat,
some of it is in green,
which is a remark.
Remember the 15 golden Rules of coding number seven realm extensively,
because remarks are always in green and you can always tell because there's a little
apostrophe at the front of the line,
so this technically is non execute herbal code.
You can write absolutely anything you want in here,
and it won't make a slightest bit of difference to the code because there is an apostrophe
at the front.
These are literally just for remarks on the rest of the lines.
The black lines is the execute herbal code.
Now you can come anywhere in this,
and you can insert spaces or insert blank lines by just hitting enter to make the code a
little bit easier to read on.
That won't affect the code in any way because this is the execute herbal code.
This is the excusable code on this is the excusable code.
So now we have our macro recorded.
Let's have a look at how we can use that now.
We didn't assign a keyboard shortcut.
So we're gonna have a look at the various different ways that we can use to execute or play
that code from Excel that we just Then we just remove that highlighting to know felt There
we go.
So we're back to where we were.
So to play or execute that macro,
we could come to developer,
we could hit Mac Rose and we could double quick highlight my formulas.
So just double clicking that will automatically play or execute that code.
Let me just put that back.
So there's Method number one.
No fell from view.
We could come to Mac Rose,
choose view microbes.
We could highlight that on we could press run.
That would also cause the same thing to happen that would execute the code languages
Berland back.
Um,
we can also do it directly from the visual basic editor.
So I'm just gonna bring that back up.
And here we have two options.
We can either come to run and press run,
or we could press at five.
Or we could just literally be somewhere any of accursed anywhere in the code and hit the
play button.
And then when we go back,
we can see that that code is executed.
So okay,
so that's all well and good.
So let's straight on her neck sheet.
So let's go to develop on a Mac Rose DoubleClick and they go that codes executed
beautifully.
We could go to this one.
Let's do the view one this time down to here.
Few micro's on run I go.
There's all of ourselves highlighted that have formulas we consume.
It will do the same on that and weaken.
Do assume it will do the same on that.
So they go.
There's our very first macro recorded.
There is the visual basic editor on That is your first glimpse at visual basic for
applications code.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture