again guys on Welcome back.
And then we're gonna have a look at some more even useful properties that from time to time
you're gonna need to know how to use.
So the 1st 1 is particularly important if you ever want to create a user log.
We look at how to do that a little later on.
So the 1st 1 is going to say my user name,
just a randomly made up variable name.
Don't forget recovering variables in the next section is environment String open brackets
quote user name,
close quote,
close brackets.
So when I hit F eight through this on hover over,
you can see that my user name is Allen.
And that's how you retrieved the user name of the person who's access in the book.
Then the next one we have up is my active book name,
which is the active book dot name.
That is not the workbook that the code resides in,
but whichever workbook is currently active.
So here Book one is active.
So when they hit their fate,
you can see that book one dot Excel S X is the active workbook name.
Now,
similarly,
this is going to the same fall.
This workbook,
this workbook being the coat that the workbook where the code resides.
So in this particular instance,
it's my macro book dot XLs m.
Now let me just scroll these up a bit so you can see them get the past to the active
workbook.
That's the active workbook.
Not necessarily the workbook where the codus remember the Distinction f eight and you can
see that this particular file the active workbook installed on C users Alan Desktop
Fantastic.
Now the next ones is exactly the same thing for the this workbook where the code resides
and I think that path is going to be too long to even see it.
But they go if you need to retrieve the path of the work but that you're in,
that's how you do it.
Okay,
get the full path,
Onda the name at the end of it.
So that's going to give us the full name on the path.
So here,
when I hit F eight on hover over it,
you can see that the full string is going to be C users.
Alan Desktop Book one Docks XLs X because that is the active workbook Now,
that's a particularly useful thing if you ever need to capture the location of a fall that
you're looking at,
but you're gonna be using that one.
Now,
of course,
this my full name again.
So we call this my full name too.
Okay.
So my full name to does precisely the same thing.
But with this workbook by the code resigns.
And if I have Rover it well,
it was too long to see the path when it was just the path.
But I assure you,
at the end of that is the name of my macro book.
My sheet name is the active sheet Don't name.
So when I hover over that,
I can find out that I am currently looking at sheet one on my cell equals active cell.
That address.
We've looked at that before,
and we know precisely what that does.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we're just gonna have a look.
Some more obscure things that you never know may come in use one day.
I'll see you in the next lecture.