Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
these are some things that don't come up very often,
but when they do come up,
they can be an absolute nightmare to find out how to capture them.
So I just have the same valuable name in all of these,
and it's all called all they are all called my various attributes.
And here we have the active workbooks.
That's the word,
but that we're looking at now,
in this instance,
it's my macro book with the DOT built in document properties.
You'd never guess that one open brackets and we have the application name,
the author,
the company,
the creation date,
The last order on the last save time.
So I'm just going to hit f eight.
We can see here that the application name is Microsoft Excel.
We could probably have guessed that one.
And if they are faint through it again,
I have captured the author as Alan.
If I f eight again,
I have no company set to my file creation date must have a look that was the 13 for the 7
2016 That's a while ago.
Last author.
That's probably going to be me again.
they go.
And the last save time Waas on the 23rd of the 8th 2016 13 46 and 19 seconds.
Okay,
so from time to time,
you may need to use those,
as you can see by the layout,
their nightmare to try and work out.
Luckily,
you have them all in your macro book.
Okay,
Here's another useful thing.
If you're using the sheets dot next or sheets stop previous if you try to go next form or
sheets than you actually have.
So if you say I want to go next five times,
we only have four sheets.
Your code is going to fail,
so it may be useful to know how many sheets you have,
so both of these lines do precisely the same thing.
It's the active workbook dot sheets dot count on.
If I hit F eight rips me like if I it hits FAA,
they go.
So we have four sheets in the active workbook.
Alternatively,
we could just omit the active workbook,
and by default it becomes the active workbook,
and that does exactly the same thing now.
We spoke a little bit earlier about index on before sheets on this piece of code here,
the active sheet dot index property will return the index.
So I'm currently on a sheet scratching.
When I hit F eight,
we can see that it is the fourth indexed sheet on Dhere.
We have open workbook counts on What we're doing is counting the number of open workbooks
using application dot workbooks Don't count from his F eight to because I have my macro
book and I have a book one.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we can have a look at right in some vb a code to
open workbooks.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.