Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this section the programmers Toolbox.
Now,
in the last section,
we looked at lots and lots of intimate individual lines of code and snippets of code.
They're going to teach you the structure of how to program.
But to really make your programs dynamic and powerful,
you're gonna need to master a few of the key programmer's tools.
And they are variables.
Looping logical test in math,
how to write formulas using code input boxes,
Andi message boxes.
And finally,
we're gonna have a look at a raise.
Now,
by the end of this section,
you're gonna be able to program anything that you can imagine.
Okay,
without telling further delay it.
Let's crack on and I'll see you in the next lecture.