Okay,
guys.
And welcome to the learning how to program properly section off this course now.
Recording macros is going to get you so far,
but it's really useful.
If you have a bunch of programming techniques in your toolbox that will allow you to be
able to program anything that you can think of them.
We're going to cover all of those in this section.
Okay,
Now,
this is gonna be a downloadable resource.
It's in a file called variables dot XLs X now,
because I can't upload files with Mac Rose in them.
What I'm gonna do is add a tab to this sheet with all the code that we're about to go
through,
just create modules in the V B A,
which we've done before on pace all the code in there.
And then you'll be able to see it working exactly as you are in these lectures.
Okay,
so one is a variable.
Well,
you can think of a variable as a box that contains a certain value or certain values,
but there is a lot of technical detail behind variables on.
Hopefully,
we're gonna have a look at that now,
and it's all gonna be very simple to you.
Don't worry if you're not fully grasping it as you work through the first few lectures
because they'll be a summary electorate.
The end of them.
Okay,
variables.
Here's our first bit of code and we can see this is demo number one,
a simple local variable.
Now,
look,
this is a local week declared variable.
Locally declared variables are declared inside a sub,
and you can see here,
this is our variable declaration.
So it sits between sub and n sub.
So that means it is locally declared.
It is declared using the dim statement which you can see just here and dim is short for
dimension.
So dim is dimension,
and it's just one of the declaration statements that we can use.
There are all this will come to them scope near the scope.
This is only available in the subroutine in which it is declared so as it is declared in
sub one.
Here,
we can only use it in sub one here.
Now you'll notice here we have a call to sub,
to which we've also done before on we're going to attempt to use this variable down here
too.
Okay,
so the scope is is only available in the sub in which it is declared,
and the other key characteristic of a variable is its lifetime palace.
How long does it stay in your computer's memory?
Well,
this particular type,
a locally declared sub,
is destroyed at N sub.
Now,
one of the things that you may want to use that's included in the visual basic and it's on
a really powerful tool is called the Watches Window.
Now we're going to do just click on the name of your variable right click and come down to
here and choose and watch.
Then this little window will pop up.
Just click OK and notice what happens at the bottom of the screen.
We get a new window on.
This is called the Watches window and you can see str My string is listed there.
It is currently out of context.
Don't worry too much about that at the moment.
That just means we are not using it and there is nothing stored in it.
Type is empty.
On the context is the module in which it lives.
This is the area you want to be watching the value.
Okay,
so let me just drag this back And here's a sheet I carefully prepared earlier.
So then we go.
Okay,
let's execute this code and have a look at what it does.
So I'm just going to click in here and hit F eight on step through the code.
There you go.
Are variable is no declared.
And you can see that it has a value off double quotes.
Now,
that is because it is a string type variable,
which means it is designed to hold text on.
There's currently nothing in it.
So good code in practice,
I am going to sheet select by visual.
Basic name.
The sheet that I want to work in,
which is this sheet here,
which is called local level on its Phoebe code name is shit one local.
Okay,
so step in three.
The right sheet has been selected.
Range a one select.
I am picking the range that I want to grab my data from.
I'm going to clear the contents of column C because we,
as we work through this code,
is going to get populated.
So before I execute the code,
I want to make sure it's clear now what I'm gonna do here is read the value from the
specified range A one into my variable str my strings so hovering over it or looking down
here,
you can see it's currently empty until I hit F eight and now you'll notice it has a value.
This is my data which is just read from a one.
So far,
so good.
Let's just screw all of Tibet,
right?
The value in the variable to specified range.
So now I want to say range C $1 value,
which is currently empty,
will have a value off my string.
So when I press f eight fantastic,
bigger.
This is my date with just successfully written str my string variables data into cell C one
Now look what happens.
I'm gonna call to sub two on.
We've done this before.
When we did the run in order a little earlier answer is gonna press f eight.
We're going to jump strength down sub to,
but I'm gonna hover over str my string here and you'll notice that it's completely empty.
And that's because this str my string is a different variable to this one because it's
local,
It can only be used within that sub,
so we'll carry on well hit f eight on,
I'm know,
going to attempt to write the value of that.
To see three union See,
from that's from sub to No,
absolutely nothing happens.
Because although this is still in the memory as it is a locally declared,
we can actually use it in any other sub.
Now,
I'm just gonna press f eight.
I'm gonna come toe end sub and notice what happens here now,
out of context,
because the lifetime of a locally declared variable is only good until you reach end sub or
you finish it and council it with an end.
Statement on 11 statements is literally just end.
And that will cause your crew to end.
OK,
but there is an exception.
And that's what we're gonna have a look at in the next lecture.
Okay,
I'll see you.
That