Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Now,
in the last lecture,
we have a look at local variables now going to move to this module,
which is called modern underscore.
20 underscored local level,
and I've just done that.
So they run in order of the demonstrations.
Double click on we can see that we have all the general code written up here.
All the aled,
the remarks to help you understand it when you download the file.
But for now,
what I'm gonna do,
it's copy all of someone cupping.
I'm gonna paste it all into sub to So they go.
That's almost well,
that is exactly bar the comments at the top.
Exactly what we have in the first sub.
No,
you'll remember that the variable lost its value as soon as we reach the end subsection of
the the procedure the subroutine in which it was declared Well,
there is something that you conduce with a locally declared sub that enables it to retain
its value on what that is is utilizing something that we've seen 100 times already.
But we've not yet discussed.
And that is this little area here thes open and close brackets that appear after the sub's
main.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna change sub two on Add the words s t r my string and just
click off now because I've never added this to this subs name calling sub twos.
Not gonna work.
So what I'm gonna do is copy that name and paste that in here.
So I am now calling sub to open brackets str my string and you'll remember that is the name
of our variable.
So now look what happens over here and notice.
In fact,
I'm gonna delete that watch if you need to.
Dili to watch.
Just literally right.
Click it in the watches window hit,
delete watch.
And I'm gonna other watch to this version of str my string.
Okay,
so we can watch it.
What's happening down here?
So let's f eight through that.
So the sheet select a one.
Clear the old contents.
Fantastic.
Read the value of str my string from range A $1 value hovering over.
This is my data we can see down here.
This is my data organ so far.
Call sub to on may go We're calling sub to my string and you can see already If we hover
over that,
the value has bean retained because of the way we've worded this sub on because we added
the name of our variable in here.
So f eight now this time C three should be populated with the current value of str my
string So eight Fantastic that's worked beautifully up to end sub f ace and no,
we go out of context.
So if you declare a sub locally,
but you want to pass the value of a variable declared in that sub to another subroutine on
the name of the variable after the subroutine aim of the one you want to call just as we
did here.
When you call it,
make sure you include that sometimes you'll see code where you have multiple things,
so you'll have str my sub comma my value.
I'm just making this up now,
but you can have multiple names after all of the so you can pass the variable values to any
other subroutine as long as you name the variable in here