Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
this is kind of a bonus like chap.
No,
it's not actually about variables,
but we've done a lot of calling toward the subroutines to demonstrate the variables in the
last few lectures.
Now,
what this bonus Lakes was actually about is how do you call code that you've written in a
completely different workbook that is calling code that lives in a workbook aside from the
one that you want to use it in.
So what I've done is I've added another tab.
He had the bonus subs from another workbook because the conflict ended in longer than that
in there.
And you'll find this code in the variables download.
Now,
what I've done is I also have a cleverly created where rich gone.
Another workbook that I've opened.
There's nothing in this.
It's just literally another workbook called my other workbook.
So what we're gonna do,
you're just gonna write a bitter code very quickly.
So I'm coming over to the visual basic editor which is here and in the subroutine in the
project area for the my off the workbook I'm gonna insert and modules are going to come up
to insert Go to module and they go.
It's just a regular module and I'm going to say Ah,
sub Rome me lips.
I've got my caps.
Look on.
Let me try that again.
So So,
actually put that right.
Sobe run me and I'm going to say something simple.
Range A Actually,
we don't wanna write it.
They say range a 12.
Just making this up as you go along.
Range a 12.
Don't Value equals.
I ran.
I can't type until this from elsewhere.
Okey dokey.
So there's our code,
and it is in a sub called Run Me In the Workbook.
My other word books.
Now let me just flip back Teoh to the variables workbook so we can steal that code.
And this is the only bit we're actually looking for this bit just here.
So I'm just going to copy that and come back up to here and I'm gonna insert amount module
in the variables workbook in a set.
Now,
I can't upload a file with modules in it,
so you're gonna have to add this in yourself,
but here we go.
So sub on and my test will call this.
So my test bump and paste that code in there.
So what we have is application dot Run.
Now notice The use of the apostrophe is here because we have spaces in the name of our
workbook.
We need to have an apostrophe at the front of the name on apostrophe at the end of the name
after the file extension,
but before the module.
So what we're doing is we're pointing to application dot Run open brackets,
quotes apostrophe because we have the space is mild.
The workbook on that's oops,
Sorry.
That's this one over here.
I keep getting the windows.
Things slide in driving me mad.
Eso were pointing to mile the workbook dot XLs m.
It's actually excellent sex.
This I think it is Excellent sex,
Andi.
I am pointing to module one so my other workbook docked x l s x apostrophe module one
because that's where that code lives dot Run me because that was the name of our subroutine
.
So let me just,
uh,
just click on here and let us run that coz I'm just gonna hit old an F eight to step
through the code and then it's gonna immediately jump to the other workbook module one that
subroutine his F eight and they go Ram,
This which turns that really goes well.
I run this from elsewhere.
Then we're gonna hit every it f eight.
And there you go.
That's how you call a subroutine in a module that lives in a completely different workbook
.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.