Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
you've just seen everything you could ever need to know about variables.
But here's a quick,
summary variables.
There is a naming convention with variables,
and it follows the same naming convention as subroutines.
That is,
they must be less than 255 characters in length.
They can only use letters or numbers or underscores eso question marks and hashtags and not
allowed.
You are not allowed spaces,
so the use camel case or underscores on they cannot begin with a number.
You can have a number somewhere else in them,
but the first digit cannot be a number or the first character cannot be a number.
Now there is a notation,
albeit unofficial,
called the Lisinski notation,
or sometimes known as Hungarian notation on that suggests prefix in names of variables and
objects with an abbreviation of what they are.
So as an example,
if we had accounted,
that was an inter jet.
We may call that variable I NT in lower case because that short for interject my counter
camel cased if you like as integer or if it's a form we may call it FRM my form or if it's
a module M o d.
The May 6 We've already used that one.
If you want some more information on it,
you'll find in the downloadable document that can get with this lecture this link to
Wikipedia and it gives you a load.
More information.
I've gotten away without using most of it my entire program in life.
But some of the things have actually used automatically,
like mold the basics.
Okay,
we also have a look at the scope of a variable on the scope of a variable,
basically means where you can see from,
so the scope of a variable is detect determined by when you declare it so.
If you declare it a procedure level,
it can only be used in the sub that it's being declared in as we saw our little area.
I mean,
it's declared with the dim statement,
and then we also have module level variables on bacon views anywhere within the module in
which they're declared on a game,
we declare with a dim statement on the very top.
We have the project level variables which can be used anywhere within the current project,
and we declare those with the public statement.
Now you'll remember that we also have a slight modification to the procedure level.
Variable,
inasmuch is that we can pass values to another subroutine if we name the variable in the
called subroutines name in the brackets after the subroutines name.
Okay,
now the lifetime of a valuable another.
One of the key things.
A locally declared variable,
a dim valuable is destroyed at N sub of the subroutine in which it was declared,
or if you have end in your code,
it will be destroyed.
At that point,
that means your computer's memory is freed again.
And now a module level variable declared with dim is only destroyed.
A workbook close hitting stuff in the visual basic editor.
A new sub is added to the module or the end statement is reached on.
Finally,
the procedure level public variable is destroyed at the end sub in the module in which it
was declared.
So that's just a fault in my notes there.
So we're just going to change that or it reaches the end statement.
Okay,
assigning of value to a variable unless we assign a value to a very built then not much use
to us now There are two types of way to assign a value to a variable.
There is either dynamically coded or hard coded hard code.
It would be if we said str my string equals Hello world.
We've written that in the visual basic and it it lives in code and it doesn't matter what's
going on in excel str my string will always equal Hello whale world because we've hard
coded it and what we've looked at in the last few elections is dynamically code.
In analysis,
we have populated a value into the variable str my string by looking at excel and picking
up the value from the range A one Okay,
let's have look at the data types up until now.
Other than the last lecture,
we didn't actually declare our variables.
So when we used my first variable,
we didn't actually declare it and say what kind of data it would hold.
And that's all this.
Does you tell vb a.
What kind of data is going to be stored So we have a few different options.
But if you do not declare them by default,
visual basic assumes it to be a variant.
Now is it sets it up to bearable to hold any kind of data that's passed to it.
Now they that has uses.
But it also has one major drawback.
If you look at the memory allocated,
it uses 16 bytes of data.
Not a problem if you only have one variable in your entire projects.
But if you have multiple variables,
it could easily become an issue.
So looking at the top,
if we if we consider interject,
introduce any hole them,
but between minus 7 32,068 and positive for 2767.
If you're variable was to hold an integer and you didn't declare it as an integer,
then it would allocate 16 bytes of memory in your computer rather than too,
so it would be eight times more inefficient.
Okay,
lets with through these Boolean can only answer or can only hold true or false.
Very small,
very memory efficient only takes two bytes of memory.
Now you can either read a value off.
True or value are false.
Inter 1,000,000,000.
I must admit I have been programming for 20 years and I've never used it.
But if one thing to note is,
if you try to rent,
read a text string.
If there is text in the cell,
Boolean would return.
True,
that is,
it isn't blank.
So,
therefore is true.
But if the cell was empty,
it would return falls.
Very quirky as a say,
I've never used it.
Interject.
I use this all the time.
Very useful in loops,
which will become into shortly very efficient only uses two bytes then we have long on.
That is for numbers longer than 32,000 or smaller than minus 32,000.
The parameters there so you can download this imprint often.
Memorize it if you want,
but long no takes four bytes of memory.
So if you're definitely dealing with numbers or whole numbers that a smaller than 32,000 in
the range here in inches,
don't bother resigning along because she can use twice a such memory.
Only assign it as long.
If it is a long number.
Now the next do single and double are short for single prison single precision variable
interval precision.
Variable on.
Basically,
that'll hangs around.
How many numbers do you have after a decimal points?
I have no idea what for 028535 e plus 38 means,
but it's less than the double one s O single precision valuables hold a certain number of
decimal places on the double holds holds even more.
Okay,
I do.
You single very rarely used double.
And I would imagine unless you're dealing with scientific calculations,
you're probably never going to use them either.
Currency,
These air the ranges for this nowhere into the eight byte section.
I have never used currency in my entire life,
but they're the parameters.
Should you need to date again?
Here are the ranges for the dates came taking a bites again.
I have absolutely never used them.
String.
This is what we've used in the last few lectures.
You use string all the time either to just ripper string a text value from a cell or to
build foul names and path names,
which we're gonna come to later in the course.
Andi,
you can explicitly declare something as a variant,
which means I have no idea what's going to be passed to it.
But you will be able to store anything.
The drawback bean,
the amount of bites it takes now We've looked at this in tax for declaring variables nice
and simple.
Dim.
If you are declaring it locally or marginal level on public,
if you are declaring it's a project level.
Okay,
No,
you can't declare multiple variables on the same line.
I tend not to do it,
but you can do that so sometimes you'll see it written as dim X as in Georgia Comma.
Why as long or public X as Inter jet?
Why,
as long there's a link here which will also see on the downloadable document that gives you
a link to the Microsoft article.
If you want to geek out on everything to do with variables,
okay,
well done for keeping up,
and I will see you in the next lecture.