Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
And then we're gonna have a look at the four.
Next loop.
Now.
Ah,
four.
Next loop is going to use a variable.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to write the code,
and then we're going to declare the valuable so no se equals equals sub loop will begin the
more with loop for next.
His answer A few times I'm going to steal the code from here because we want still select
the start of the range.
Boom,
Andi,
Right of the tough Because I want this variable name to be usable in any subroutine within
this module.
I'm just going to declare the variables at the very top.
So you remember anything is declared here becomes available to all the subs in this
subroutine on.
I'm going to use the dim statement and I'm going to say dim my counter as interject because
we just moved using it to move through lines.
There is no cell.
A 1.5.
There's a one is a two.
There's a three on that all inter.
Just so an integer only two bites of memory is the most efficient thing to use on.
That is the name of our variable My cancer.
Okay,
so,
back to our sub.
Let's come in here and we're gonna say full my cancer equals 1 to 10.
Well,
I'm gonna hit Enter and I'm gonna close this loop by saying next because for every four
that will be in next and now I have that.
I'm just going to use this thing occurred in here again.
I'm a pace that in the middle.
Let's have a look at what that does.
I'm going to step through.
A one has been selected for my cancer equals 1 to 10.
So if I hover of my counter,
you can see on our first situation It's worth one on were going from 1 to 10.
So active soldiers offset all the way through key clicking it my counters.
Net worth 57 89 Andi down Andi end because I came to reach 10.
So we offset 10 times the code in between the four and the next was executed 10 times on.
That's how you use a four next loop.
There is a slight variation on that which is a stepped for next loop,
which we're gonna have a look at next.
Ok,
I'll see you in the next lecture.