Okay,
guys,
welcome back in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look.
It's a simple single.
If test,
that is,
we're just going to write the entire test on one single line of code.
Now,
if you only test him for one value,
then this is a really fast and efficient way to do.
It will come to the more complex versions of that later on.
But for now,
we'll begin with a simple stuff.
Okay,
so here I have the shell of the code.
Andi,
this sheet here that you can't see See it because I've hidden the Project Explorer is
actually called S H Logical testing.
Now,
I will paste this into your macro book.
So it's there when you download it on.
All of the code for the module is available as a download.
Reese Downloadable resource,
which you'll find in here.
Okay,
Right.
So let's have a look at the data.
So what this does is it calls?
I'm just going to step through this.
It calls this sheet to make sure we are on the right sheet because there is no undue when
you do something in code.
If you make a change in excel in code.
There is no coming back unless you quit without saving.
So remember Golden Rule Number one work on a backup.
There is no undue.
Let's look would have it.
You can download this as many times as you like,
so you perfectly fine,
okay?
And that we are going to be writing days into column G,
which is just out of view at the moment.
Don't worry too much about whether you can see what the actual values in the cells are at
the moment.
The key thing,
it's we'll zoom in the middle,
have a look at it as we working through the code.
So everything is gonna be written in here.
So the first thing I want to do is clear the content so we know the range.
Objects range open rackets open quotes G two G,
which is all of column g dot clear contents.
It's fairly obvious what clear contents does F eight range be to select in this test,
we're going toe.
Look for the sex of the person in that particular lines.
Arrange me to select on Ben.
We get to our first loop,
and this is a wile wound loop,
which you saw a few lectures ago.
Okay,
so now we're gonna add some more code in here,
notice that I'm in denting here.
And that way there is a natural flow to the coast.
So I'm just going to say the logical test because that's exactly what this is.
Now I'm gonna remnants before you download it,
but at the moment,
I'm just going to write the code.
So what this is going to say is if because it is a logical test and if the act is seldom
value now is whatever value,
whatever cell were in its value.
So here it's be,
too.
So the actor sell value will be male,
and that's what we want to test for.
If it equals male whips in quotes because it's text that we're testing,
then what do we want to do?
If it's male,
then we're going to say,
Well,
we will rise a value.
Two column G so at its cell because we're currently in column b don't forget offset.
However many columns across that is so it's zero rose.
We want to stay on the same road comma on If we have a look,
it's 12345 So active cell dot offset,
zero comma five dot value equals.
And what would we like?
It's the same.
We can say it's a man.
Close quotes on Ben.
We hit.
Enter.
Okay,
so that's a little long to see.
Uh,
yeah,
but if you scroll over or if I drag it over,
you should be able to say so There you go.
If the active cell value here equals male and it does,
then the active cell value offset zeros.
Five columns,
which is column G set that value to say its a man on.
When I dragged down back about me just one second,
I almost got that right first time there.
So let me come down here.
But before we execute over this line of code,
the next thing we want to do in our while wend loop is continue to test the rest of the
data.
So we need to add another line of curd in here that says active cell adults upsets because
we want to move down 11 row zero Collins dot select.
So now look what happens in column G to just here.
Let me just click off.
That helps if I could smell select f eight and there were over to this part.
So this logical test has evaluated.
True.
So I'm gonna say active cell offset.
No rose.
Five columns equals It's a man F eight c.
It's a man has just appeared in their active cell offset moved down a cell when repeat our
loop on Dunland and and and and then I can just hit play and set that running on.
Boom!
There you go.
That is all 50 lines of our data executed,
and you can see if I apply filter to female.
No one has any comments,
and you can see if I apply a filter to mail.
Everyone has a comment,
so that works perfectly on.
That is a logical test in its simplest form.
Okay,
now telling fuel program in projects.
Let me just make this a little bit bigger,
and I will explain to you what your program in project is.
If you have a look at this code,
you'll see that certain elements of it is starting to make sense.
We know what the selecting a sheet bites Phoebe named does weaken very easily into it.
What clear contents means we know this one,
because on the first things we have looked at But if we actually look at this statement
here,
if the active self dot value that is the cell you sell,
we are in equals male,
then axis l offset zero comma,
five column G The value there will say it's a man.
So your programming project here is to copy this code paste underneath Onda there.
I want you to modify the code to say something different.
If it isn't a man on just to give you a hint,
Don't just change male to female on.
When you look at the operators in this on,
just copy this code paste it,
modify the code slightly and change the message to make it do something different.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.