Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Now,
You'll recall when we executed this macro,
the one we were recorded a couple of lectures ago.
What the macro did was it selected all the cells that contained formulas that resulted in a
number and letting just hit control.
It highlighted all of the cells that match those criteria on.
We then added a yellow color to it.
But you'll recall that every time we had to rerun the macro,
I did something manually to removal.
The highlight in on what I did was clicked up here,
selected all the cells,
came to here and chose no fell.
So what we're gonna do now is record another macro.
That does exactly that.
And then we'll take a look at the code.
So I'm going to come down to the button button just here.
I'm in the left.
Click on default list will leave it a macro one at the moment there because we've closed
and opened this workbook.
We are now back at Macro one again.
I'm gonna skip the control of the shortcut keys.
I'm gonna store it in this macro.
Andi,
I'm just going to say clears formatting.
So clears formatting.
Okay,
right now I'm gonna click.
OK,
now I'm gonna click up the corner,
which is going to select the entire shades.
I'm gonna come up to the Phil and I'm gonna choose no color.
And I'm just going to click a one Andi hit.
Stop.
Okay,
so alternate 11.
Let's go and have a look at our code.
Now you'll notice something has changed.
This was our original code toe.
Highlight my formulas,
which converted them all to yellow on that lived in module one.
But you'll never see because we've closed the workbook and reopened when we saved it as a
macro enabled workbook.
We now have a second module which is called module to.
So every time you close a macro enabled workbook,
when you reopen it,
if you record a macro automatically,
a new module will be added and you can probably spot the pattern.
The original one was called Module One and the 2nd 1 was called Module to,
and I'll bet you can guess what the next one would be called.
So let's have a look at the co generated in module to,
so I'm just gonna double click.
And here it is,
Macro one clears formatting.
And here is the code for that.
Now,
what we're gonna do,
because we actually want tohave it in the same module,
is this.
We're just gonna double click module to come up to here.
Copy it.
Delete it on.
Come over here on underneath.
End sub.
I'm just gonna pace that in.
So now we have to subroutines in the first module.
Now,
just so you know,
if you have a blank module and you don't intend to use it,
you can just delete it.
So I'm gonna come to module to I'm going to right Click on.
I'm gonna choose on.
That's not in view.
Terribly.
Well,
I'm gonna choose.
Remove module to and you'll get this little warning pop up.
Do you want to export module to before removing it?
If you say yes,
it will give the option to save a bass file dot be A s file,
which is basically a macro module code file.
But what we're gonna do is just say no because we read.
We're really not worried,
so OK,
now we have two sets of code.
We have the one that highlights the formulas and we have the one that highlights the
formulas.
So now I'm just going to come into macro one,
and I'm gonna change the name of that.
So I'm just gonna hit backspace.
I need to live.
Leave the sub in there banging the coolest clear formatting on your most It's of use.
Come.
Okay,
so c is capitalized and f is capitalized.
So let me just click on there on Let me flip back to here.
And they were going to run our to Mac Rose one after the other.
So we're going to go to developer.
We're going to go to Mac Rose,
and we're gonna double click Highline my formulas and you can see that I have formulas have
been highlighted.
I know.
I'm going to go back to Mac Rose and click clear my formatting,
and you can see that that clears the highlighting.
OK,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at stepping through the code so we can watch and execute one line
at a time.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.