Okay,
guys,
welcome back now.
Have Rendall the code there,
So that will be available to you when you download the file.
And now I'm introducing a new theme.
A logical test using the if then else so rather than you watch me write the code.
I've already pasted the code in here and we're just going to go through it line by line.
So we already know what?
The first few things too.
So we can it f a through all of these.
And I'm using a while.
Wend loop here on.
You can see that the loop is lined up perfectly here.
So do while the actor self doesn't equal this when we're back to the range object objects
arranged be to select.
Okay,
but no,
you can see that we have other elements before we have it all in one line.
So said if the active,
sold up value equals male,
then do this.
But what this introduces this isn't If then else test on what this does is if the value
equals true.
Do something.
If the value equals false,
then do something different.
So you can if we look at the structure of the If l.
If then else test.
It says If the active seldom value equals male,
then do this after cell offset zero columns.
Sorry Zeros.
Five columns that value say's It's a man,
and if it doesn't it says else,
then the anti cell offset zero comma,
$5 Value says she's a woman.
W O M A n end of logical tests.
And then because we have this encapsulated in a loop,
it would just keep going round until the active cell doesn't equal blank.
So let's just execute that.
So if the active cell equals mail,
it most certainly doesn't.
You can see by hovering over the active cell Don't value.
It tells a sad that the value is indeed male,
So this will evaluate to true.
So we want to do this line of code F eight active cell offset.
Zero comma five equals It's a man on.
There you go.
That is the end of the logical test.
So now we want to step out.
We want to move down a cell loop and come back up to the Sorry,
it's a do loop.
No,
While Wen,
please,
we want to come up to the next do while the active cell doesn't equal blank.
So again,
I'm just gonna step through this a few times until we get down to the female.
Here we are so active.
Celled up value equals male.
Well,
that's false.
So it will skip this line of code else.
Move over to this line of code on,
right?
She's a woman.
W o N a m on.
There you go.
And that's just going to keep looping around until the active self doesn't equal value.
So I'm sorry till the active cell isn't blanket.
I'm just gonna hit play on.
There you go.
That is our data completely populated.
So if it's a man,
it says it's a man.
And if it's a woman,
it says she's a woman.
W O M A n on that is Harry using,
if then else test much useful.
If you want to do one thing,
if the answer is true but a different thing,
if it's not okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture