Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
that's another program in project here for you.
If you're up for the challenge on I've pasted the code directly into here and this is gonna
be called logical to be.
What I want you to do is copy.
Logical to a That's the code we just looked at in the last lecture.
So couple the current into here,
but converse it change some of the code to test if a person or a precedent as I've typed
there,
if a person is over a certain age and then put a message in appropriately so that your
program in project okay,
own theological test to see simple,
logical testing using the if then else on the cells objects of this exactly the same code
we just looked at.
But I've modified it to you cells instead of ranges.
So that way we don't have to move down the cell.
So what we do,
you'll also notice,
have incorporated this from our macro book.
And what this does is he gets the last row number.
Before,
when we used to four next loop,
we knew there were 50 values.
So we said for X equals 1 to 50.
But data can be dynamic,
and the may not always be 50 lines.
So what happens if something gets deleted or something gets added?
The coach just not gonna work anymore.
So now we're introducing an element of being able to be dynamic with echoed.
So what this is going to do is gonna have a variable which I have declared up here,
my last root as interject.
And I've just got to find that again.
They're here again.
Eso my last row equals range be one million,
I think,
Or 1001 every $100,000 and excel up to the row,
which is going to get us to the bottom of this range here.
So we're starting down the line,
a 1,000,000 or something moving up on.
Then we're going to subtract one because we have 50 lines of data because we have a title
at the top.
On that way,
Alyssa will be 50.
So let's just execute all way through that by pressing F 84 X equals one to my less road,
and you can see that my last row already has 50 because it's dynamically calculated that
out just there.
So Frank's equals one to my last row,
which is 50 cells.
X plus one x on the first pass through is once a one plus one is two so cells to 212 rows
down 12 columns across Selby to in any other language.
It's that equals male F eight cells X +11 plus +12 so it sells to +712123456 7/2 column G
right?
It's alone F eight.
We don't need to move down and sell because that's going to be taken Care off because we
use in X as a reference in the cells.
Object,
eh?
Phase next.
Exes.
No worth two.
That's a male again.
So again,
it's a man.
It's a man.
I'm just stepping through by hitting F.
A cheese woman hit play and they go.
We didn't even have this screen a scroll then,
because the cursor actually never moved away from B to.
But still every line occurred was executed,
and we have a value against everyone.
So that's the efficiency of use in the cells.
Object.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we are looking at.
What are we looking at?
Testing.
If there is more than one criteria.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.