OK,
guys,
Now,
so far,
so good.
But what happens if we want to test form or than one criteria?
Well,
this piece of code here is going to do just that.
Now,
most of it we already understand.
So I'm just going to step through.
So we're gonna select she clear the contents like B two.
Do what?
This is a do loop again.
So here's the do you Here's the loop.
Do while the act itself doesn't equal blank right?
If the active cell don't now e equals mail.
Andi Lego.
That's how you test for more than one criteria.
Andi.
The active cell offset zero comma three.
No role rows three columns,
which is gonna put us into column e equals brown soups.
If column B saves mail and column e say's brown,
then do this.
Okay,
so we're just gonna hit their fate that didn't evaluate to True.
So obviously active,
sold up value equals male and the active cell dot offset zero comer three equals brown.
So we know going to execute our true statements so that to sell up to offset zero comma
five,
which is over here,
is going to say it's a brown haired man.
So there you go.
Now we're going to move down because we're using the range method.
We're gonna have to move down.
So that's the end of the logical test loop.
And again,
so active,
sold up value consume Harvin over it and it say's male active cell offset Say's black.
So this particular person has black hair.
So when I hit F eight,
it's going to skip over all these these lines of code,
and it's going to go to its else.
And what's going to say is just moved down yourself.
Okay,
on down Onda again and again and I'm happy that that's gonna work.
So I'm just gonna hit play.
So there you go.
It's no gone down and said,
If the person is male on and they have brown hair,
then right,
it's a brown head man in here so you can see that that that's worked perfectly.
Okay,
now,
if you're on the ball,
you will have noticed that there is some inefficiency in this code.
What I've done is I said,
if the values equate to true,
do this on,
then moved down the cell.
I'm gonna leave this in here so you can modify and you'll understand what it does that if
these evaluated true.
Do this on,
then move down a cell.
If it doesn't just move down the cell,
the more efficient way of doing Max I have this line of code in here twice,
or a different way of doing it is to put it just before the loop.
These will only execute once,
whether it's true or false.
And it will only execute once here.
But it just saves having more code written.
Okay,
so in the next lecture,
we are going to open a challenge.
Sub logical.
Three B,
this is one for you to write.
Ah,
yeah.
Copy this code here.
Paste it in here on converted to cells because we've used the range objects here on want
you to change these two cells.
Okay,
That should keep you going for a few minutes.
And in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at test in.
Receive one criteria.
Is troop or wrong?
One criterion.
It is true on one is false.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.