Okay,
guys.
And welcome back in the next four lessons,
we're gonna have a look at doing maths in code on that comes basically in four flavors.
We're gonna do simple mathematical calculations in code.
We're gonna have a look at writing formulas into spreadsheet on.
We're also gonna have a look it calling on excels built in functionality and all the work
shape functions that are available in excel and heavy can utilize those in our code.
Okay,
So quickly.
Here's the 1st 1 This is just doing simple massing code now,
because we've got quite a large data set.
State largely got 51 things,
but all we're going to be acting on in these next few lectures is this the age.
So I am just gonna hide.
I threw sing Andi these to hear your recognizes status,
what we will be using before.
So I'm just gonna step through this code until we get here.
We're gonna work out what the last row is fantastic,
and you'll notice that this time I've done at four x equals two to last row.
And that's because our first data set appears at row to on.
We're going to be using the cells arguments here at the cells method.
So I'm gonna tab in a little bit.
Then we'll say Cells open brackets X.
Remember,
don't have toe.
Add one here because I've already started X counting at two so immediately.
We're at Row two,
Comma seven because seven is column g A B C D E f g.
I'm counting on my fingers there,
although you can't see it so cells open brackets X comma seven equals cells strips open
brackets X comma four Because A B C.
D is where our age currently lives,
so they go cells x seven Equal cells x four plus one Simple mathematics.
Take whatever the current age is in column d Add one to it and stick it into column G.
So let's just f eight and step through that on they go.
So 20 becomes 2122 becomes 23 24 becomes 25 on on and on and on.
I'm just gonna hit play So they go.
That's a you simple mathematics in vb a coding.
It literally is a simpler specifying your arguments on then adding your mathematical
operators Simple.
Is that OK?
In the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at writing formulas into cells.
I'll see you in the next lecture