Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
in this leg's,
we're gonna have a look at writing formulas to a range off cells.
Now,
you may think we could do this with a loop.
Obviously on you'll remember the drawback that we had when we tried to write it.
In plain old,
I can understand that sort of language,
This one here,
that if we did it in this cell,
it works beautifully.
But if we did it in any of the cell,
it was still looking here ugly.
If you write in exactly the same format to a bunch of cells all together.
So we were saying here range H two to H 20 right?
The formula in plain old English 65 minus G two.
So let's have a look.
What happens when we execute that code?
They go.
All of our code has been written automatically,
all in one shot with the executed one line of code.
But if we actually look at what's being written 65 minus G to quite right,
65 minus g three.
And then we come down here 65 minus g 12.
So it seems if you write a range so you're writing to a range of cells all at once.
Using the doctor formula,
you can actually write them in a language that you can understand.
And it works perfectly.
OK,
so you may be wondering one is the difference.
And what is the point of having two different types of formula?
While the don't formula generally is sent to be less efficient than the formula R one C one
style.
We just did 20 calculations just there,
So it makes absolutely no odds whatsoever.
But here's a quick demonstration for you.
Now,
I'm just gonna pause while I unhygienic all the days that survey me one second.
Okay,
welcome back.
Now have a look at these two bits of code terribly ugly,
but this does the job perfectly.
What this is going to do is copy all of this data and paste it immediately below itself.
Just ordinary huge data sets,
and it's going to run 1999 times.
Now that's going to take a few seconds while it's executing that.
We're not even sure that I did that Then,
um,
I on it.
Yes,
I am.
Okay,
Go.
So they go.
It's happily populating were down to 10,000 lines of data.
Now,
in theory,
if we use the R one C one style on,
we re using it on 100,000 records and you can see that we're already up to 45 4 to 6000
records.
Then you should see a noticeable difference between the R one c one style on the just plain
old vanilla formula style.
So one of programmed here very crudely is a speed test.
And what that's going to do,
it's populate that cell that we just looked at.
That 65 minus g two,
which we know changes depending on which cell it gets written,
too.
So we're going to write all that 101,000 times down this data set,
which is essentially the same data set.
So we're going to write this 101,000 times,
and then we're going to write the start time whether to put it out well,
right,
this start time in here.
Well,
right.
The stop time in here.
So have this code work says I am going to record the value of now in l one execute the code
on,
then recalled the value of now,
which will be a little bit later in l two.
And then we can subtract one from the other and see how fast it ran.
So are you ready?
Speed test underway.
Let's just scroll over a little bit so you can see What are we on?
Aging?
Experts think I remember.
Were working at years from retirement.
That was it,
wasn't it?
Uh,
Okay,
Andi,
go.
Okay.
There you go.
We can stop.
So we just wrote 101,000 calculations and you can see up here.
We're looking at 65 miles streets and wailing on the bottom.
It's 65 minus 100,000 on one now.
There was no trickery used in this in this demonstration whatsoever,
but just looking at the numbers,
we don't even t.
We don't even need to do maths on this.
We can see that we started that code were basically essentially looking at these these last
three decimals after it.
So we started the code at 11.
48 45 and we finish the code at 11.
48 45.
So we could not even measure how fast that Waas using merely seconds.
And that's on 101,000 lines of data.
So it may well be faster to use the formula.
I want to see one format.
But generally,
if you're happy with something that's that fast,
you can't measure it.
Milliseconds.
I would suggest you stick to the dock formula on right in a formula format that you can
actually understand.
Okay.
I'll see you in the next lecture when we're gonna have a look at port in some of those
really powerful excel built in functions and using them in our visual basic for
applications.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.