Okay,
guys,
welcome back now.
We already have two pieces of code inside this XLs M workbook called Sales Data on.
What we're going to do now is execute the code a single line at a time so we can see
exactly what it's doing.
Now what I'm gonna do to do this,
I'm just gonna hit F 11 to open the V b e the visual basic editor.
Andi,
what I'm gonna do temporarily is just close the V b a project,
and I'm gonna close the properties on.
That way you can see the code in the whole window.
Now,
don't worry.
If your view is like Max,
it's easy to get the Mac.
You just go to view and you choose projects Explorer on boom your projects.
Explorer comes back on view properties window on your properties window comes back,
although you may have to resize it a little bit.
So I'm just going to close those two just so we can see the code here.
And then what I'm gonna do is strength this over here.
That should be perfectly fine on.
I'm gonna drag this over to here so hopefully you can see both windows side by side.
Okay?
No,
What we're gonna do is we're going to step into the code now.
At the moment,
we can see that this isn't highlighted.
So the appropriate code to execute is this one,
which is the highlight.
My formulas.
I'm just gonna delete these remarks here just to bring the code up a little bit.
Okay,
so now what we're gonna do is step through this and you can see at the top you have a debug
option.
And if you left click on debug,
you can see that you get the option to step into,
which is F eight.
So woman do is click into the code,
and I'm gonna press F eight on the keyboard and you can see because I was in this
subroutine.
It knows this is a subroutine we want to step into.
So highlighted Number one is sub highlight my formulas when I pressed F eight again,
I want to come down to this line of code now because it's highlighted.
That means that is going to be the next section of code that will be executed.
So when they say fate,
it's gonna move from here.
This line is going to be highlighted,
and that line will have executed.
So just have a look at what happens in the worksheet.
As we press f eight,
they go.
You can see that this particular line here has managed to highlight all of those formulas
that resulted in a number.
Now,
if you remember the 15 golden rules of coding,
it says number 72 realm extensively on.
Now we have learned what this particular line of code does want to do is his end.
Tabin.
I'm gonna hit an apostrophe on.
I'm just gonna make a little note of what that does.
So this code,
uh,
select oh,
form you laugh cells resulting in,
I value.
So there you go.
Whenever I come back to this code,
if it's a year or two from now,
I'm not gonna look at this particular line and say,
Wow,
I wonder what that does because I know have a little ram,
a comment,
a note that tells me exactly what that line of code does.
So this code selects all formula cells,
resulting in a value,
and that is what matters.
Okay,
so,
no,
let's pay attention to what's going on over here.
in the Excel file.
So we have with selection dot interior.
I'm just going to hit F eight.
Nothing.
A parent has happened there.
I'm gonna hit F eight again,
which is gonna execute dot pattern that equals X l solid.
Okay,
so that looked like it made a slight change.
I'm gonna hit pattern color index equals X l automatic by pressing f eight.
That doesn't look like it.
Did anything color?
No.
My guess is this is going to make a difference.
So color equals 65535 which will be the code number for that particular shade of yellow.
So when I hit F eight Boom,
everything has gone to yellow.
Tinton Shady call zero.
I'm just gonna here to f eight.
That didn't make any difference on dot pattern Tinton Shady Call zero.
And guess,
And that's the default value.
I'm just gonna hit at night.
Step through it,
Andi,
end with Andi.
That finishes all of those,
Okay?
And then the final instruction is range.
Open brackets quote.
0 16 Close quote.
Close rackets dot Select.
So let's have a look.
What that does on that moves a stand to sell.
0 16 so I'm gonna insert a new line next.
We've just learned something else.
Select.
Ah.
So named in quote.
So they go next time I look at this code,
I'm not gonna have to wonder what that particular line does because I now have a comment
that tells me exactly that.
Okay,
now,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look.
At what?
This with and end with process Tres.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.