Okay,
guys on Welcome back.
Never can have a look at manipulating the text that the uses entered in response one on
response to I'm just going to leave that from there by using some casing statements in V B
A.
So this is exactly the same coaches before of no fully remarked it.
So you'll be able to understand what it does and what I'm gonna do before I build my string
.
It's going to give myself a few spaces.
So what I want to do is step through this code and get a so far through,
so into your first name.
And I'm going to say,
Alan,
but I'm going to state in lower case and hit.
OK,
so now,
in response one,
I have Alan in lower case,
so before a execute line to because once I do,
it's gonna move straight down to here on.
I want something to happen in between times.
I'm going to say response one equals you case,
which stands for upper case response one.
So whatever value is in response one,
replace it with the upper case version of response one on.
Now I'm gonna hit F eight so I can get response to on this summer.
I'm gonna type it all in uppercase.
So I'm gonna say Jarvis on hit.
Okay.
Now,
before we get past this line,
I know Want to say something very similar.
I want to say response to equals.
L case,
which is lower case response to.
So no notice what happens when we execute over this?
Currently response one says Alan in lower case,
but we're about to change Response one to you.
Case response one.
So when they hit F eight response one becomes Allen in upper case because we've just
changed it here.
And similarly currently response to saves Jarvis in capital letters.
But we're going to change it to l case.
Jarvis in capital letters.
So when I press f eight were no gonna have Jarvis all in lower case,
and I'm just gonna play the rest of that code out on notice.
What it says.
Pleased to meet you.
Capital letters,
Alan.
Lower case letters,
Jarvis.
Now,
it could be that we want a proper case.
Everything.
No upper case is you case.
Lower case is l case.
But to use a proper case,
that is,
have the first letter of each word capitalized.
We're gonna have to call on one of excels built in workbook functions because there is no
vb a equivalent,
so we're never going to build the string that does that.
But what we're gonna do is do it to my string.
That is the combined string here.
So what we're going to say is my string equals applicator whips can't type application,
don't worksheet function.
I could just click that now that would be quicker.
Application dot worksheet function dot proper open brackets.
And there you can see it's asking for argument.
Wanna string?
So what we're just going to say is my string and close brackets So they go,
my string is gonna equal application worksheet function dot proper my string.
So,
no,
I'm just gonna run through that code loan to Same and to your first name,
Alan.
Enter F eight into your second name,
Jarvis.
Okay,
that's going to convert it to all uppercase That's gonna vote it converted to a lower case
that is going to build their string,
which saves.
Pleased to meet you,
Alan.
In all capitals.
Jarvis,
low case.
And then we're gonna complete that string and converted all to proper case F eight and
naked.
See that my string has the first letter of each word capitalized because we used the
application worksheet function dot proper and no one I write it to that cell,
you can see that that's come out in proper case.
OK,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at the input box method,
which is slowly difference the input box function,
and you'll see the use for it.
When we get that,
I'll see you in the next life.