Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look at using the input box method which differ slightly from the input
box function,
which is what we've just looked at now.
One particularly use for this is to allow the user to click on a cell in Excel.
And so you can read that cell address.
So you may want to mask the user in which road your titles like and have them click it and
then you'll be able to use that in your code further on.
Or you could say,
Where does your data range begin?
Have them click that cell and then you would know the beginning cell address for your data
range manipulation.
But to do it,
we need to use an input box method,
which is slightly different.
So we're still gonna use valuable response one.
But rather than Dimmitt as a string,
we gonna dimension it as an object.
And that object is range.
Don't worry too much about the technicalities of this,
but we're going to say response one is going to hold a range object.
So we have dimension response one as range because this is an object Arrange.
What we have to do is set Use the word set before the response one equals input box.
So we will say set response one equals.
So this part of it's the same response one equals,
But we've used the word set up front and there because we're using the input box method.
What we have to say his application dot input box and it should start to auto complete.
Just double click there.
So I know I've spelt it correctly.
So application does input box This parts the same prompt to string.
So click a cell chips sound that I can't talk Click,
click a sound Close quotes Comma title is the same.
So select cell,
right?
Whatever you want in here.
Obviously,
Andi,
just so we can read this,
Okay,
I'm just gonna hit space.
Underscore and enter.
So now hopefully will be out.
See,
all in one line.
I'm gonna need to tidy that up.
And here is the final bit.
This is where the magic happens when you use an input box method.
There are different types which we access by typing type colon equals and to get a cell
address into that range response one as range.
We need to use a type eight close brackets on end the lips of miss something there.
Obviously at the Kama.
In fact,
let me just delete that.
Bring it all opponents of one line on make it so we can proceed along one line.
So I'm just gonna hit an underscore and bom bom Lego.
Now we can see all of online so we have dimension response wonders arrange,
which means we have to use the set command.
Then we have response one equals application input box clicker cell.
That's going to be the prompt Select cell is gonna be the title and this is type eight.
Okay,
so it's just step through that.
Let's see what happened.
Sweeps.
Well,
we input,
but I think this is a escape.
I think this is number three.
Now.
I've already got number two above eso 123 Here we go.
Response A And there we get this select cell clicker cell.
I'm gonna click over here and you can see I've clicked Selby four.
And now I'm pointing at the screen again.
On now.
In the input box,
you can see we have absolute B absolute for Okay,
but if I hover over this response one you can't actually see that it says be for in there.
So what I'm gonna do is at a watch,
and we're gonna have a look at what that's actually captured down here in the watches
window on prepare to be staggered.
It has captured absolutely every tiny detail of that cell.
Literally.
There are hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of properties that that has captured.
But actually,
all we want to get is the cell address.
I'm just gonna hit Stop on.
What I want to do is say my address.
So I'm gonna need another variable.
Appear so dim my dress as string because that is what we actually want to get my address.
So my address equals response one dot deter.
So now,
out of all of those values that have been returned,
all of those different properties from the range response one that we just saw in here.
I just want to extract the address because that's the thing I'm interested in.
So I'm just gonna f eight through this clicker cell look like that one this time.
Absolute.
A four again.
You can see we've captured millions and millions and millions of bits of data about this.
But what we actually want to know is the address someone I press f eight.
My address equals absolute.
A absolute four on that is really useful if you ever want the use.
If you ever want to ask the user,
where does your data begin or in which row are your titles?
That is a little bit of code that will help you do that.
There's a very useful Microsoft article on all the different types of input box methods on
gun.
Oppose that in this lecture just here.
I'll also put it at the bottom of the code as a remnant statement.
So as usual,
you can download this file,
which is called input boxes.
Start Excel s.
All of your code will be in a sheet called Get Your Code Here,
just paste it into a module and you'll be able to follow along.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture