Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now we can have a look a simple,
one dimensional dynamic array.
Now,
I've already written the code in here,
most of which you're gonna understand,
but we'll go through it line by line.
So notice the first thing that's changed.
Here is how I have set up the variable.
I have said dim my arabi,
which I cleverly added a watch to already for you Open brackets,
close brackets as string.
Now the reason I put open brackets close brackets is although I am setting up the array,
I don't yet know how big it should be.
So I'm just going to say dim Mireille,
be open brackets,
close brackets.
Now here's another important thing when you're when you're setting up your arrays.
If you know that all of your days out will be strings,
it's quite safe to set it up as a string.
As this is just a one dimensional array on all of these values,
here are strings.
I am quite safe to do that.
If you have a variety of different data,
particularly when we get to multi dimensional race which will do short,
like then expected to set them up as variant.
I know they arm or memory inefficient,
but that will stop you having any read iris.
So it will say we trying to read a long decimal number into a string.
It's just not gonna be happy.
So set them up as variants.
Okay,
so that's how we set up a dynamic array.
We say dim my array be or whatever you want to call your right open brackets,
close brackets.
So let's step through this code.
Most of it you'll understand.
Anyway,
we are selecting by VB named the correct sheet,
which is this one over here.
We are clearing the contents,
indeed,
because that's where we're going to be right in data.
Okay.
And this is where we get dynamic.
We're gonna say my row can't equals range A 1,048,576 way down at the bottom of Excel End
Excel Up Row.
So that is going to get us the row number off this cell here.
So now we know how many elements are array should have on.
Then when we do that,
let me just click in their F eight.
Now.
Our row count is eight which we can see.
12345678 is exactly correct.
And here's the part where we re dimension our ray This is to make it dynamic.
Now we know how many elements we should have because we've just read it from my row Can't
weaken se ri dim my array open brackets And there we know the number that we can add that
in here.
So what we're going to say is re Dimension Arabi to my row can't.
So now we know we're gonna hold eight elements.
So our array is going to be set up to hold eight elements.
OK,
and here's our four next loop toe load the race on the first pass through my cancer is
gonna be worth one.
So my array be one is going to read from cells 11 which is a one that I'm just going to
expand that there.
So when I f eight through it,
you can see that we now have read just going to step through yellow,
pink,
green,
orange,
purple blue,
Andi Indigo Let me just stop that And I'm just gonna add ah satar Toysmart know how to
spell it s so let's just think of another cooler.
A future that's a spell fusion.
So now I'm just going to run straight down to this right part here.
So I'm just going to click on this line I'm gonna come up to debug on will say,
run to curse.
And that's gonna immediately get us through all of the code down to this point.
Now I'm gonna expand that and you can see that future has been included because my rail
count has now changed to nine because it's dynamic and we have re dimension there array to
say go to nine.
So there this is just a straightforward loop to write the data.
So we're just going to write all the way through.
So again we're looping,
saying my counter equals one to my row count,
which is nine f eight and notice what happens here at the bottom erases array.
Be on notice what happens here when we execute that all of our memory as no being freed and
that's one of the beauties or one of the other good points of a dynamic array is it
releases your memory when you a raise or destroy the array So the first benefit is it is
dynamic.
It will expand and contract depending on the data set that you're working with a big plus.
And secondly,
it will free your memory once you raise it.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.