Okay,
guys on welcome back and never can have a look at the absolute,
most efficient way toe load your array.
Now,
again,
we're gonna be dealing with a multi dimensional rates.
Gonna have two dimensions,
just like x elder.
So we're gonna have lots of Ros and lots of columns.
And he I have a data set that I prepared earlier.
I mean,
how's that sub?
Look?
It has 461 lines of data,
including the titles on We have seven columns of data.
Now,
you'll remember before in the last lecture and we when we populated the arrayed statically
,
we had an outer loop to iterated the first dimension on an inner loop to iterated through
the second I mentioned.
And if that did your head in,
then this is going to be music to your ears because what we're gonna do is just use one
single line of code that will populate the array in its entire ITI in one go.
So we don't actually have toe have the sheet selected to read the array.
So this is the sheet that we're reading from and you'll remember 261 lines of data.
Seven columns of data Woman do is click here to the right here because this is where we're
going to write the data.
So I've added a watch to my arrayed de I'm gonna debug and I'm just gonna run to cursor and
you'll notice that Maya Radi has been initialized because we've set the array there.
And when I press f eight look what happens here.
One line of code plus my r a d one plus I have all of the titles in their my array to I
have all of the first.
This is Robi that so let's just flip back here.
So have all the titles in a row.
One,
I have the first record set.
Let me get back up,
Sit up.
Have the first record set in array to so to one is the first of the 1st 2016 Sarah bomb
north bangle clothing on all of these numbers Over here on all the way down in fell images
drug casus citizens take forever 461 lines of data completely populated with seven columns
of data in one line of code.
Now,
the thing that we don't know at the moment because it's easy to read a whole bunch of data
into a two dimensional array using that one line of code.
But when you write the code back,
you need to say to excel.
I am specifying a range of exactly the same dimensions.
So we can't read all the code into my radi,
then select cell a one on right,
because all we're going to get is the first element off the first element.
So what we have to do if we had a three by three dimension Deray.
So three rows and three columns we would have to say to excel right in a one through C
three.
So we have to know how big that array is now.
Luckily,
you you'll recall that we had an upper bound before and there is a command called you bound
that we can use to find out the road can't.
Now here I have specified the first element.
So I'm gonna hit F eight on the row.
Count is going to count how many elements,
How many rows of data what the upper bound it.
So what is the highest number that that array is reaching its 461 Because you'll remember
we have 461 lines of data.
Now,
Cole count is again a you bound.
It's the upper band,
the highest number.
But this time we're looking at the second element.
Hence we have Comma two.
We're now looking at the second element.
So when I press f eight,
you can see that we have 461 lines of data that is rows of data on.
We have seven columns of data.
Know what I'm gonna do is select the sheet to write to calling bites.
Phoebe,
Name on here.
I just have a range statement.
So sells 11 We want to begin at a one cells row count.
So 461 rose down to seven columns across on.
All I want to do is say that equals my array D,
which is everything that we have just copied in that one line of code above.
So I'm just going to hit F eight and look what happens over here.
So it's all been read in one line of code with works out how many rows we have worked out.
How many columns we have on.
We've written the entire data set back in one line of code.
Just here.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.