Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
In the last lecture we have look,
it read in an entire data set into an array,
used a single line of code and then with another single line of code,
we wrote that complete a race somewhere else.
But it could be that we don't want to read the array with the explicit intention to write
the array somewhere else.
What we may want to do is hold that Iranian memory on get some input from the user to
display a result.
So what we're gonna do in this lecture is combined some of the things that we've looked at
a little earlier,
the input box and the message box to do just that.
So this the shell of this code is exactly the same as the one we had in the last lecture.
But I've just added a few more variables in here.
We have a simple counter on my category,
which we're going to use to get the input from a user,
my some which we're going to use to some my response,
which is going to be the response to an input box of that later on.
So this line of code reads the data array.
We get the upper bound of the first element on the column count of the second elements.
And then we get down to this body,
this part where we're gonna have an input box where we're going to get an input from the
user.
So I'm just gonna hit t bug click over him just gonna hit the bug and I'm gonna come
straight down,
run to cursor to get here Air Fate.
And then this category box will pop up this input box.
So what would I like to look at?
I would like to look at clothing now to get around any case sensitivities.
What I've done is so said that my category,
which is the variable that this entry is going to be read into,
is going to be lower cased on.
I've met the same adjustment here when I am checking column E,
which is five.
So that so I'm just going click.
OK,
so my category have no title in lower case.
If I hadn't,
it would be lower cased No,
I have a loop check for a match.
So if the lower case of Mireille e number one my cancer column.
Five.
So 12345 If that equals clothing and we just come up to the top so we can see what it what
it is.
They go said the first line is actually gonna say category because this is our first line
of data.
So I'm just going to step through this.
The 1st 1 doesn't because it saves category.
The next one does.
So we're now going to come down to here,
so my son equals mice.
Um,
plus Mireille e cancer on.
We're on cancer number two line,
too.
Column seven,
Which is where the prophet lives is going to be my some plus mice.
Um,
whatever the current value is,
plus that.
So when they s f eight,
my son is now worth £6.30 or 6.3 because of that there.
So I'm gonna reiterate again we get another match.
So my son's Currently,
we're £6.30 from here,
but we're now looking at this line,
so it's not gonna add that to that.
So there we have £45.30 and I'm just going to run that through.
So it looked through all 460 odd lines of data.
And then we come down to this line here,
check to see if a value was found.
Now,
this is very important because if the usual type something incorrectly,
then a value wouldn't be found because there would be nothing in column e matching what
they typed in.
So all we get here is a VB critical message box That's a snow value found.
But we did have a value.
So we skip straight over that right?
My response equals the total profit four space,
my category which is while I typed in little earlier Waas or space waas vb New line Andi
format my some as currency so you can see there currently.
My son is where 4955.6.
But we'd like it picked to be displayed in the format of current sick,
hence format over rackets.
My some comma currency on DVI Be new line.
Would you like to look for another category?
VBS No result found.
So let's hit F eight CEO.
The total profit for clothing was £4155.
60 Nicely formatted.
Would you like to look for another category and I'm gonna say yes on what that's going to
do is now reset the sum to zero because we want to look for another category.
What we want to do is actually start that over.
So I'm just gonna hit Stop there.
And here's a line of code that I wrote earlier.
If my response equals V b yes,
on you'll remember from a nearly elect we used I think six was no and seven was yes or vice
versa will be be yes is also a valid response to a yes,
no box.
So if my response equals V B,
yes,
that is the use of pressed.
Yes.
Then go to start over.
Now start over is a label in a code.
In the olden day,
she usedto have lines.
5 10 15 2025 30 And you could say go to 30 on your code would go back to 30.
We can do the same thing.
No,
but this time we're going to use the label now.
We already have the arrange red,
so there's no need to re read it.
But what we can do is come in here on.
We're gonna type are label is going to be called start over called Anything you Want and
notice that start over will not in dent,
even if I indented it when I come over because I have the colon after it that's identified
as a label.
It will always go right over to the left,
so they're very easy to spot in your code.
So let's let's run through that security bug run to cursor.
In fact,
let's try.
Let's just talk something completely nonsense and hit OK And they go,
No,
we get this area of code that's executed because of some equals nothing because there is no
value found.
Okay,
and then we're gonna end.
So let's run that again.
But actually type something useful in there that lets room.
It's a curse of their rooms.
Clothing on they go.
The total profit for clothing was £4955.
Would you like to look for another category?
Yes,
I would.
So my response to this was six.
Which is equivalent to VB.
Yes,
F eight.
Then go to start over.
And now look what happens when I hit F right straight up to here and executes the next line
of code.
So when I press it again this time I would like to look for groceries.
Enter and then I can loop all the way through on Get back down to here.
Run to cursor The total profit for groceries for £774.
Would you like to look for another category?
Yes,
I would.
In fact,
I'm just going to stop that and run it out now.
So I'm just gonna press play,
so I would like to look for household enter.
The total profit for household was £2116.
Would you like to look for another category?
Yes,
I would.
Let's have a look at clothing.
The total profit close them was £4955.60.
Would you like for a friend of the category if you click?
No,
you're just come straight down to end sub.
So there's one use incorporating the message box and the input box that we can use to check
the data that we've just read into an array and do something useful with it.
OK,
I will see you in the next lecture