Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
this is kind of a bonus lecture.
In response to a student question Muhammed is asked,
is it possible to use a data table that you captured to an array with the look up?
So it's the data source for the V.
Look up.
So I've updated the file that you can download now and you'll know,
find an additional table in their additional.
She called H R table.
So what I'm gonna do,
let me just come back to visual.
Basic.
There we go.
I have repurposed sub a raise five and called it sub arrays six.
And I've also imported the HR table,
which have given a VB name of S H H R table.
Now,
here's the repurposed code.
We don't need quite so many variables this time.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna have at my array f instead of e.
On.
I am keeping my category provided a new variable called my name,
and I'm gonna keep the my response now.
It's very straightforward.
This code,
what we're gonna do is have that single line of code reading.
All of share a chart table dot range a six current region.
All of this over here,
into my array f that's captured our array.
We're gonna leave the start over labelling just like we looked at in the last lecture.
I'm going to keep my category.
But I've just changed the wording on this and I've also eliminated the lower case.
So we're just going to say please enter the employee number on.
We've changed the title to employees hashtag we're going to use a V Look up.
We don't need the Lupin anymore.
Consistency is straightforward.
V look up.
So we're gonna say my name,
have a new variable equals application dot worksheet function dot v Look up on the syntax
for this is exactly the same as it is in Excel.
So I'm gonna say my category which have just captured from the user my array f which is all
of this data that we've just captured into our array called my r a f comma to because we
want to return the whole name Common fall.
So we're looking for an exact match.
And again,
I've just slightly modified the my response to say this employee's name is and then vb new
line my name.
What we've returned from the V.
Look up,
and then Do you want to have a look for another one?
So it's just hit play and see what that does.
Enter an employee number M in C dash,
go eight and enter.
They go.
This employee's name at no apostrophe.
This'd employees name is Annabelle Read.
Would you like to look for another employee?
No.
So they go.
That's how you can use on the application worksheet function V Look up with an array that
you've captured.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.