Okay,
guys.
And welcome to this section.
And now in this section,
what we're going to look at is automating all of your monthly reporting or weekly reporting
.
Whatever reporting it is that you need to do now,
mostly computer generated reports very,
very rarely change.
So therefore,
if you write a piece of code providing that you code dynamically,
you can write the code ones and you can automate your reporting forever.
Now there are five downloadable files.
Faith Downloadable Resource is from this particular lecture.
They are called 2016 01 north,
south,
east and West.
And these are the four data sets that we're going to be working on.
You will also find a file called month reporting dot XLs x on.
That's the sheet that we're looking at just here.
So when you download the sheet,
if you want to get to the finish code,
just select sheet one hit control and A and control and see to copy its alternate 11 come
to insert him on John and paste the code in there.
On there,
you'll find all of the code that we're going to go through in this section,
completely rammed and completely dynamic.
Now,
just to give you quick demo what this is going to do?
What I'm gonna do is just move this out of the way.
Temporarily.
I'm gonna open up one of the files East.
Ondo,
let me just right there into shot.
Here is a monthly report data,
and I am just going to play the macro on create the report.
So there,
when I close that you'll see Let me just assume it's a little bit on the front data set
completely dynamically.
We have created this month report that scale perfectly in a landscape orientation.
It captures the eastern region name dynamically at runtime.
It adds the commentary,
including all the specific areas,
like which monthly?
In which year,
which region we're looking at.
The total profit who the top salesperson was,
creates although charts and lays it all out perfectly for every one of the files.
Now,
I know that your data may be slightly different,
but we cover absolutely everything you're gonna need for month reporting automation in this
section.
So do this section and then adapt it to your own data sets and you'll be good to go.
Okay,
let's crack on and learn how we do this.
I'll see you in the next lecture