Okay,
guys on Welcome back.
All of the things that you're gonna learn in this section going to be completely adaptable
to whatever data set it is that you look at.
But just as an illustration,
we're gonna work through this point by point.
And what we're gonna do initially in this lecture is we're going to record a few simple Mac
Rose.
They're going to give us the bones of what we're looking for.
So the first thing I'm going to do because we need a new sheet to add our report onto its
own record a macro and we'll call it on new sheet hit.
Enter.
I'm gonna hit.
Plus,
now,
I want this to be import rate orientation.
And I wanted to fit one page by one page,
so it just it controlled.
And Peter,
bring up the print dialog box on.
We change the orientation to landscape on the scaling slightly off screen there.
But I'm choosing fit sheet on one page on when I'm happy on that click back.
No,
I'm gonna hit.
Stop recording Macron number one.
I'm coming back to here and there were going to do macro number two.
What?
This is going to do is give us a chart that's going to show us the profit by day.
So again,
I'm gonna start record.
I'm going to call this profits by day.
Hey,
center,
I'm gonna choose here,
which is sell d six.
I'm gonna hold down,
shift control and down that gets us all the way down to the bottom of the state.
Arrange hold control again.
Choose profits,
shift control and down.
And then I'm gonna come to insert and I'm gonna choose recommended charts on I'm gonna
choose this one here That gives us the value down the left hand side,
across the bottom,
the dates.
So that's the Clustered column.
I'm gonna click,
OK?
And you can see that that's been added to this sheet.
And that's not where we want it.
So,
men,
right,
click and cut.
Come sheet one.
I'm just gonna choose Sell a five right click and paste.
Andi,
I'm gonna scale detail it a little bit today.
Go.
OK,
so stop recording.
That is our first chart on next one is going to use all of this data sets because we want
to return how much profit to the sales person makes So and then a recorder macron Cool it.
Profit by sales bond on its.
OK,
now I'm gonna select a six hit control and a to select all of that region.
I'm gonna come to insert recommended pivot tables and you can see that this one gives us
Exactly what we want is a sum of profit by sales person,
which is exactly what we're after,
so OK,
but we can see that that's been added to sheet to.
We'll correct that a little bit later.
Hit.
Stop.
I'm gonna come back to here.
I already have this selective but won a record again.
So I'm gonna hit record and I'm gonna call this profit by category.
Hey,
center,
select this self hit control in a That's going to select all of the current region board by
spaces on the come up to insert owner Choose recommended pivot tables on this time This is
the chart that I want.
I want the sum of profit by CASS agree on hit O'Kane You can see that's been generated in a
different chart.
So far,
so good hit.
Stop on now What I want to do is I want to add some commentary to this sheet.
Okay,
Now we're just gonna record a macro toe at some commentary and hear someone called this at
Com and Terry.
Okay,
so they go.
That's what we wanted to say.
The month report for months.
And it's in upper case because this is going to be dynamic.
Remember,
year on the North ERN region North will be dynamic.
Luckily earned will take on through the end of north,
south,
east all west and still be the right word on.
We're going to say that total profit for the dynamic months dynamic here in the northern
region waas on whatever the Prophet Waas and you'll notice that those particular sections
that we want to draw the eye to have done in bold OK,
in the next section.
We're gonna have a look at deconstructing that code that just stop that recording on.
We'll see how we can make it dynamic.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture