Okay,
guys.
And welcome back,
That would have done temporarily.
I've saved this file is a macro enabled workbook that where can happily play with the code
and not lose it if I accidentally save it without changing it to macro enabled workbook.
So this is a sheet we just created.
So it's just hit all 10 F 11 and have a look at the code that's being generated and you can
see that it is considerable.
So that really is quite a staggering piece of code there.
We already know that most of this is going to be redundant.
So what we're going to do,
though,
is hit control and a and control and see and copy all of this code.
And I'm gonna come up to incest and I'm gonna choose module toe,
add a new module.
I'm in a paste,
all of that code in here.
I'm just gonna comment right up top That says original recorded code.
And I'm also going to change the name of module to to marred a rich groups.
And now code said that way it doesn't matter if you make a complete hash of module one
where the code lives.
We automatically have a copy.
It isn't gonna cost us anything.
We're not gonna be using it.
We're just having in there.
So we have a backup.
Okay,
so let's have a look at this code that we've generated.
Now,
throughout this piece of coding,
we're gonna have multiple variables on.
What I want to do is ensure that all the variables are declared.
So when does come right up to the very top of the code on a type in option,
explicit on what option explicit does is it forces you to declare the valuables,
so forces variable.
Declaration.
Fantastic.
Okay.
Sub on new sheet.
Now,
this is a staggering piece of code for essentially.
What we did was we added a new sheets.
We made it landscape orientation,
and we wanted it to print in one by 11 page tall,
one page white.
So let's deconstruct this code.
I'm just gonna remove these here for a second,
and we can see the first line the sheets on after active sheet,
which adds the new sheets.
So that is definitely one.
The piece of code that we want adds a new sheet after the active sheet.
Fantastic.
That is one of the hundreds of lines of code that we need.
Eso Let's give ourselves a bit of breathing room application,
print communication titles Rose.
We didn't do anything without that.
Can all go applications?
Print communication,
true Prince area Nothing in their print communication.
False.
We don't need any of that.
Now we get into this big with end with thing and somewhere in here there it is.
It will say orientation,
Excel One escape on.
That is the only change we made when we did the first change.
The other one will be wrapped up in this second with end with.
So I'm just gonna delete everything from there on because we only have one action we don't
actually do with end with.
So we can just take this dot orientation and move it immediately after the page set up so I
can delete the with.
I can delete the end with on here is a next line of code.
Let's just bring that up.
Tablet in on that sets Page two,
lend skate.
Okay,
so it's coming down already.
Here we have this print communication True thing entitles Rose,
which you didn't do anything with on all of that.
So we don't need any of that.
And here we get to our next with end with and again,
we're on the active sheet,
Dr Page set up,
lose and lose different things on what we actually changed was this Now because we're doing
two things,
I am going to leave that within a with end with Bronwyn.
Delete all the things that we didn't change,
which is all of this stuff down here.
And I'm just going to delete that in tidied up.
So we have a with and with There you go And that Let me just add a comment in there that
scales to print on a single pinch Fantasticks us Bring that up application,
print communications.
True,
we don't need that.
So that is nearly all of the code that we need.
But we do need one more thing.
What we need to know is what the name off the sheet is,
because in this particular instance it was she won,
but we ran it again,
be she two or three or four or whatever.
The next sheet in sequence would bay.
So here's our first module level variable declaration dim because we want it to be used in
all of the subroutines.
My new sheet as string I'm gonna say I'll tidy this up a little bit.
So they all line up eso this holds their name off the nearly created sheet.
Okay,
so this holds named the newly created sheet.
And here it is.
So my new sheet,
we can say my new sheet and I'm typing in lower case because we have already declared it up
here.
It's automatically going to capitalize equals active sheet dot name.
Now we know it's gonna be that to sheik us.
It will have just added it just here.
So that's the new sheet routine sorted.
Now,
I'm just gonna comment that I'm gonna make it private and I'm gonna comment,
comment?
It's a code complete,
and then I'll add a note to say exactly what it does.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Will have a look at deconstructing this profit by day or profit by days of gold in their
profit.
By day they go.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture