Okay,
guys.
And welcome back in the last lecture,
looking at this subroutine the profit.
By day on,
we established that this part just here is where we were clicking on excel and literally
selecting the Rangers that we wanted to build our table from on.
We also worked out that this range that we marked off here was replicated exactly down here
.
Save some punctuation,
zin that on what we want to do is build a string dynamically at runtime.
So we always get the right sheet and we always get the correct data ranges.
So to do that,
we're gonna have to set up a few more variable.
So I'm just gonna delete these now.
Ultimately,
what we're gonna do is move all of the data capture into its own subroutine and have that
run first.
So while the usual is actually looking at the source data as soon as the macro executes
capture all the data ranges that we're gonna need for the rest of the subroutines all in
one go before we even add the second sheet.
But for now,
let's just set up the variables so we could look at moving them shortly,
so I'm gonna say my source sheet Azaz,
And they're all gonna be strings.
So my sell sheet is gonna hold the name off the data sheet that we're working out.
And the next thing we had was this a six and a six down which captured the date Rangers.
So gonna call this my date a string.
And then the next thing we had was this G 62 G six down,
which was the profit.
So I'm gonna call that Tim.
My whips can't type my profits a string,
and they go on finally.
What we need to do is we need to put all that together into one build string that's going
to represent this text right here.
So I'm going to call that I'm going to copy the new ambassador routine.
I'm gonna call it dim.
The name vassal routine data a string.
Fantastic.
So they're all are variable set up.
So now let's have a look at capturing the 1st 1 so we can say my source sheet equals active
sheet dot name,
because what we want to do is make sure that we are looking at this sheet the data sheets
when we execute code,
so that will be the active sheet name.
I'll reminisce out shortly and then we'll know what we're doing.
So the next thing we're looking at is my date.
So my debt whips no spaces,
Island,
my date equals Now we already have the bones of the code right here.
So for a second,
I'm just gonna put zero to stop me getting an error on this is the bit of code that we're
looking at.
Now we can see that when we selected in Excel,
we selected range a six and then with that selection,
selection,
Excel,
end down or and excel down dot select.
So that's almost the code we want.
So rather than selecting,
there will begin.
Do is replace a selection with the range selection with the range on.
We don't actually want to select it.
What we want to do is guess the address off that range.
So now I can copy all of that code copy,
remove the zero and paste that in there.
Now that's almost identical to what we want to do for my profit.
Except it's looking at column G.
So I'm just going to do that and copy and paste it underneath instead saying my date on the
same my profit clips my profit on.
Instead of looking at a I'm going to be looking at G and I need to change both references.
So,
Jean,
I'm just going to step through that.
Seo tips.
I condemn these out because we don't actually need those anymore.
Indeed,
we don't need that'll that'll that anymore.
Eso Let's just step through that and see what we get.
So my source sheet equals 2016.
01 North.
Fantastic.
My date equals range.
8th 6 to a 466 which you can see,
is quite right here.
My profit equals g 62 g 466 which we can see is exactly right just here.
So now we can hit stop and now we can delete all of that.
All we need to do now is build a concurrent innate ID string to replicate this.
Now we said we recall this profit by day data copy that their pace it in Tabin a bit on.
Here's where we need to pay very close attention because we cannot get the syntax of this
wrong at all.
So we're going to say quotes apostrophe because it's an apostrophe is the very first thing
in this data source here.
So apostrophe close quotes Onda.
And there we have the name of the source sheet,
which we now have in the variable my source sheet.
Andi.
Then after that,
want to be have we have another apostrophe and an exclamation point?
So quotes,
apostrophe,
exclamation point,
close quotes Onda And then we have this range here this a six way for 66 which we read into
the valuable my date on and no been hitting on the score and enter and tab in.
So that's the first half of our string built just there on the second half of our Shing
says Comma,
apostrophe,
quotes comma,
apostrophe.
Is that right?
Come on,
Apostrophe?
Yep.
Absolutely so close Quotes Andi.
Then we have my source sheet again.
My source sheet.
Andi.
Then we have after my source sheet on apostrophe on an exclamation point.
So apostrophe exclamation point and close quotes.
And then finally,
we have this G 60 g 466 which we read into my profit.
So my profits.
Andi,
There you go.
So now we have that built completely dynamically at runtime.
So let's just step through and make sure that this say's what they say is for now,
I'm just gonna add a watch.
How to watch.
Okay.
Millet,
step through code F eight F eight F eight on Dhere we go.
This is the code that we want to replicate.
And if we have a look here,
we can see that that is replicated this string precisely which now means we can just copy
this and paste it over all of that because we have no built that dynamically at runtime.
So let's just hit.
Stop.
Let me close these for a few seconds and let's just drag this in.
If I can pick it up,
There we go.
Let's have a new sheet so we can have a play with it.
So sheet fall is where we're going to be going.
I think somewhere down here we had a different sheets.
I'm gonna call that sheep for for now.
Now let's step through this and see if that works.
Fate a fate if fate If fate a fate.
Andi,
there's our chart there.
We couldn't it we're going to shoot for on were paste in its on there you go all the way
through.
And that chart is being built perfectly with the data captured dynamically at runtime again
.
The next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at creating a new module way.
We're going to put all of our data capture.
So I shall remark this code on.
I'll see you in the next lecture.