Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Now,
I strongly recommend whenever you're doing any recording or any code in that involves pivot
charts or pivot tables that you just did the basic outline first in one recorded macro
because they can generate enormous amounts of code.
Which is why we're doing this.
Changing the title in here as a separate recorded macro,
because essentially or we're gonna be looking for is one or two lines of code.
But if you do everything you do that the chart exactly as you want it in one recorded macro
,
you will be generating pages and pages of pages of code on That makes it a little more
tricky to decipher.
So do the outline.
First we said exactly what we've done and then just do your little modifications.
A separate recorded macros.
It will be easy to pick out the bits to code that you want and then just drop him into your
macro.
Okay,
so let's have a look at this.
What we're gonna do,
you gonna start recording Macro,
macro on.
Don't care what's called.
I'm just going to steal the code from it.
I'm gonna right click on the chart and hit edit text.
So I'm just going to call this profit by day.
And I'm just going to click off anywhere in Excel.
And that set that title where it stop recording alternate 11 Because I've saved and closed
this.
I'm now on a different module and you can see for just changing the title.
This is the amount of code that's been generated s so we can see we have inactivate.
We have a select That is the thing that we are looking for.
So I'm just going to copy that.
Come to our module one.
I'm gonna come to our profit by day underneath here after we've sized it,
and I'm just gonna pace that code in there on We know that it's the active sharp because
profit by day is where we add the charts.
So its active all the way through this on that is the only line of code that we need.
So changes the title,
so I'm just gonna come up to enclose that now I'm just gonna come up to our run order off
here.
Here we go.
So I'm just gonna drag out across Britain,
will test that out.
So she 15 I'm gonna delete.
I know.
Olsen F 11 back to our code.
Hit the data capture.
Make sure we're on the right.
Cheat on hit that on hit play.
And they go There's our brand new sheet unsheathed for with profit by day in it.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture where we're going to get down to looking at the profit by
sales body,
which is a pivot table rather than perfect chart.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.