Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
And now what we're gonna do is we're gonna make three changes and we'll look and modifying
that code,
incorporating it into our exist in subroutine.
Normally,
we only do one thing per lecture,
but these are fairly straightforward.
So we're going to do all three all in one.
Go.
So what we're gonna do first is we're gonna record three.
Individual macro is the 1st 1 to change the road label on a hit record.
New macro.
I'm just gonna call it,
label it enter.
I'm gonna choose this cell,
but in the formula.
Bar it up.
I'm gonna type sales person and hit.
Enter.
That's our first macro that changes the road ahead a second,
macro,
I'm going to call it money on.
We're going to convert this to currency.
So woman do Here,
it's select this cell control shift and down that's going to select all of them.
I'm just gonna hit the currency button.
My default currencies pounds,
whatever yours is is perfectly fine.
I'm just going to click off and I'm gonna hit stop and then record our third macro and this
one is going to going to be called sought me.
What we're gonna do is select the very first value here.
Right click.
We're going to choose,
sort and sort largest to smallest now,
although it's not apparent at the moment that is really gonna help us a little later on
when we come to do the common tree,
you know,
I'm just gonna hit Stop,
Let's go and have a look at the code that's been generated all the module to.
So here's our label.
We have range A 23 select.
But we can see here that the anti she pivot tables is already selected and it already knows
where the compact row header is.
So that is the only line of code that we need to change the header.
So I was gonna pace that in that I'm gonna say changes the header.
Okay,
so far,
so good.
Let's hit space a few times.
So we got some more room.
Eso that's this one.
Dealt with them,
just can delete,
actually don't want it anymore.
They were onto money range B 24 rain selection selection and their own currency style with
the selection.
See,
26 Astra's where I clicked off.
So this is our money.
So copy into here,
paste it into this one on Dhere changes to currency here we can see that we have B 24
selects.
Then I did the control shift and down,
which then said with that selection,
do the Excel down thing.
So that way it's completely dynamic.
But we already know that we can eliminate this line of code by specifying that as the
selection.
So I'm just gonna replace the word selection with both of those.
So we can never really be 24 because it's incorporated in this line of code.
And here we have a select and then with the selection dot style,
so we don't need to have selected selection.
We can immediately just say dot style equals currency on.
That's our current seat line of code.
So that's done the head on,
lest on the current say,
what was the final one?
The sort Gillete Next.
We don't want it anymore,
right?
Here's a sort.
And again we have this b 24 but because it specified in the active sheep pivot tables,
it already knows where to look.
So what we're gonna do is just copy that and quick in here and paste it in here.
And this performs a sort,
so performs a swart Right now.
There's a peculiarity with this.
Inasmuch as we don't need anything after some of profits.
Now that's one of those things that you either know or you won't know.
All you need to do is just delete that and delete some of the comments,
the comma afterwards and that will sort this perfectly.
So now what we can do.
Yes,
we can delete that.
I know.
Select the source data sheet was way back ups that up here to fire in order longer run to
profit by sales.
But wrote cursor,
There's our first chart and we'll come back here.
It's f eight.
Andi,
Here's where we started making changes soon in development.
That's where we were on never gonna change the road.
Header two Sales person.
They were going to change this dynamically to currency on.
There you go.
And now we're going to do the auto sort.
So Justin G looks like our most profitable guys.
Someone needs their fate.
Justin.
Jesus.
The top on that.
Is that piece of code completely finished?
OK,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at butcher in that and using for the profit by category.
I'll see you in the next lecture.