[Autogenerated] Alrighty.
Let's dive into Amazon Kinesis.
Now, the first clip we're going to look at is for data streams.
Now, we just had an overview on what data streams are,
but let's go ahead and start looking at how we can create a kinesis data stream.
And then how we can create a producer and a consumer so
we can visualize the flow of data.
Something to click on.
Get started.
Here on the cane is is dashboard.
And you see, we get our four options here on the left.
Now, for this clip,
we're just gonna focus on the first option ingest and
process streaming data with Chinese streams.
These other three over here, we'll talk about in some upcoming clips.
Now,
I'm gonna go ahead and click on Create Data Stream and
it brings me to my create scream.
I had to give it a name.
We'll call it Pluralsight Stream, and then we go down to our shards.
So if you recall a shard is how we scale Arkin is is stream and
a very important factor here is that in each shard can ingest
up to one megabyte per second or up to 1000 records per second
there's a buffer limit, and as soon as it hits that buffer limit,
it's going to cut off that shard and then start
generating new records into the shard itself.
And you can see here that they actually read at two megabytes per
second so we can pull data at two Meg per second.
Now, an important thing to keep in mind is that if you want to scale up,
you have to increase the number of shards.
And we specify that here in this box right below this
diagram and what's nice is in the console.
A W s provides you a shard calculator so you can estimate what you need.
So we just guess our average record size,
Let's just say 2 56 were going to Max, right?
25 records per second number of consumer applications will have one.
So with this, they're estimating we need seven shards,
and that's based off this ingest limit at the top.
Now, I'm not going to come close to this,
so I'm gonna go and exit this and I'm just gonna put one
because that could get pretty expensive,
and that brings us to our total stream capacity so using
our shards that we just specified.
You see,
we have a one megabyte per second in the 1000 records
per second as our right limits.
So if I change this to two, you can see it doubles,
which is expected, so I'll keep it back.
At one I'll click on Create and that's it.
You have now created a can.
Is is data stream within a W s now or done with the
can is is part is far as creating.
But what I want to do is going to here and I want
to run through this little menu.
So in the details page we see our S3 Marne our status.
And then when we look in the middle, we see our number of open shards.
But there's also a close shards count.
So what's cool about Ken is is if you tie this back to the
retention period that they talk about, what happens is for us.
Since we're specifying a data retention period of 24 hours,
what you can see here anytime we close a shard,
the data in that shard will be available for consumers
for that entire retention period.
So that shard does not go away completely until the data
retention period you specified is over.
Now, the next thing we can do is we can enable services IT encryption.
So if we wanted to,
for compliance purposes we can encrypt all data coming into Ken is is using kms.
So I can go ahead and use the default key.
If I wanted to, in all of the traffic would be encrypted.
I'm not going to enable that because that encourage some extra cost.
And then we just covered data retention.
So let's look at shard level metrics.
So here we can actually look at shard level metrics that get measured by a W s.
So we can go ahead and identify all of these and then
go ahead and collect that data.
Now you'll notice it's an additional cost because it's picking up
massive amounts of data in a one minute period.
So I don't want to enable that.
But if you wanted to view your metrics,
that's how you could do it at a shard level.
So I'll cancel out.
And what I want to do here is I want to create a producer
and I did that already here in Lambda.
You'll see that I have my producer function and I
wrote some code in Python here,
let me go and close this and all it's doing is it's creating
a kinesis client with the bow to three.
It's pulling in a stream name from our environment variables,
which is right here at the bottom of the screen.
I'm creating a random string with a function here
with the default length of tin.
And then it's just returning that random string.
Now the lamb to handler itself, which is what actually executes the code.
This is just doing a few different things.
I set an IT aerator.
And then,
while that IT aerator is less than 21 I'm basically generating a random string,
printing out that string into the logs and then putting that data
that string as a record into arcane is is stream and you can see
we're passing in the stream name, which is what we read in our string,
which is set right at the top of this wild loop.
And then we have to set a partition key.
So this is how you can partition data for optimizing reads.
Now, for our use case, I'm gonna put Pluralsight.
So we should see Pluralsight in our partition keys when we start looking at
records and then I just finish it off with plus equals one.
So I'm just adding one as I iterate through this wild loop.
Now that's one side of the equation.
So we have our producer.
We have our stream, but we also need a consumer.
So if I look at my consumer here, you can see I created another function,
and this is just doing a similar thing except for its consuming.
So I have my lamb to handler.
It's pulling in the event and we'll see what that is here
in a minute and then a context object.
Now I'm reading that event, and I'm setting a record variable here,
and I'm pulling in the data from those records.
I'm printing the event.
I'm printing the record, and then I'm printing the partition key.
Just so we can verify that it's actually working in all of these
data values should be output to CloudWatch.
So before we actually do this, I need to configure this,
as a consumer for Ken is is so I'll do this from the Lambda console.
I'll add a trigger I'll select can is is we choose our stream.
An optional consumer are batch size which all set to 20 our batch window.
So how long it's gonna wait to collect records and
then we set our starting position.
So latest is the latest record in the stream.
You can specify at a certain time stamp,
or you can trim horizon,
which is the last record that was trimmed from the last read.
So I'll do trim horizon and you can see we have some
additional setting so on any failures we can alert via a
topic we can set our retry attempts.
Let me just limit this to 100.
We set a max age we can split on error and we can
set concurrent batches per shard.
So I'll enable this trigger and there we go.
We're now pulling in.
Data from that can is is stream once it gets put into the stream itself.
So if I go up to my producer now and I go ahead and test,
this is just invoking it with a hello world function,
we get a success and you see that I'm putting all of
these data strings into the records.
So there's 20 of them in there and they're all random strings.
And if I go to consumer,
I go to monitoring and I'm just gonna shortcut to
CloudWatch here and after I refreshed you.
See, we have our latest stream here, So if I go in here we can see Hey,
I'm printing that record that I received.
So there's 20 records within this batch file within
this batch event that was received.
So these error the random strings that were produced by our function,
our producer function and put into the stream itself.
I'm printing the data itself that was pulled in for the first record.
And then I print Pluralsight, which is our partition key.
And you can see the partition key here in the JSON record.
And then for each record, it gets invoked again.
So there was another record placed on there,
and we can see the data right here and then it's got the same partition key.
So that's how you can use Ken.
Is is to stream data from both producers to consumers.
Now, one thing to keep in mind here is with your shards.
If you're having lambda on the back end,
you're essentially configuring it for Lambda to scale
automatically to the number of shards.
So you'll basically have one concurrent execution per
open shard that you're consuming from.
So be sure to keep that in mind.
That's how that works.
Alright, so that's going to do it for this clip.
Hopefully, you're a little bit more comfortable with poking around.
Can is, is data streams and how they work.
We can figured a producer, the stream itself that ingested records.
And then we configured a Lambda Consumer on the back end that
printed out those records that were received.
And we visualized that here.
Now,
I'll be sure to include this code if you want to play around with
it in the downloadable files for this course.
But with that, let's go ahead and wrap up and then we're gonna move on To Ken. Is is data firehose