[Autogenerated] Okay, let's dive in to Sqs now.
Amazon Simple Cue Service allows us to use a hosted
platform for queueing messages, which allows for a D coupled architecture.
Er.
So let me click on Get Started now,
and we'll walk through this and this brings us to our create a new Q screen,
so we'll give it a name.
Let me call it Pluralsight.
And that brings us to what type of Q do we need now?
A standard que allows for unlimited throughput,
the transactions per second with an API action.
Now, the difference between these two types of queues are pretty significant,
so it's very important that you understand them for the exam.
Now a standard Q on the left has unlimited throughput,
which is important to know,
But the two big pieces are that the messages are only guaranteed at least once.
But that does not prevent duplication in the system,
so messages can be processed more than once off of the queue.
And that's a very important point to keep in mind when designing
an architecture for sqs and then just as important is that is we
have best effort ordering now.
What this means is that Sqs is going to do its best to deliver
messages in order from which they were sent.
But there's no guarantee that they will be received in order.
And you can see the graphic here at the bottom.
You can see we have message one and then we have message three on the right.
So Message three is getting delivered twice and before
one and two and then we have a FIFA Q.
Now a 50 que has a very specific purpose,
and you'll see when we choose it,
you have to have .NET Python at the end of your cue name as well.
I'm not going to create a fight.
Folk UI just want to read through this,
but you can see that it has high throughput but not unlimited.
So you can only go up to 300 messages per second.
And what that means is that you can only have a
total of 300 API calls per second, so that includes descends,
the receives and the deletes.
Now A W S suggests a best practice here,
and they really preach about batch ing messages together into groups of 10.
If that's possible,
what this does is it allows our consumers are workers that error polling the
queues for the messages to pull up to 3000 per second?
Because there's many messages in one single API call and batch ING messages,
either in Standard or Fife.
Oh, allow for a cost optimization.
Since you're making less API calls to sqs.
Now, the two biggest parts of a 50 que is its first in first out.
That's what FIFA stands for.
So whichever order messages error sent their received in the exact same order.
So you can see in the graph that it's 12345 And that differs
from our standard Q on the left and then another major benefit
is the exactly once processing,
so a messages only going to be delivered once until it's consumed and deleted.
There's no duplicates that error introduced into the queue.
So with a standard Q,
you have to build in some type of D duplication process that can
handle duplicate messages coming in as opposed to FIFA,
where you know your only going to get one message and the order
is going to be preserved so I'll go into a standard queue here
for this demo will configure our Q and let's walk through these
attributes and settings now.
The first is the default visibility time out,
and what this is specifying is the amount of seconds or hours or
minutes that we want a message to be hidden on the Q.
Once it's received,
it's important to note the difference between receiving and deleting a message.
Receiving a message simply hides it based on this visibility time out.
So when a worker pulls a message down, it doesn't delete it from the queue.
You have to make a separate call for deleting that message.
Otherwise it'll get populated back onto the Q.
And you can see we could go between zero seconds.
So don't hide any of them, and 12 hours.
It's just dependent on your use case.
The next thing we have is our message retention period.
So how long do we want to store this message on our cue for resiliency?
So these messages currently with these settings can live for
four days on the queue before they're deleted,
so this allows for some downtime in between,
so you don't lose your messages and you can see the maximum is 14 days,
and that builds into maximum message size.
Now, messages in sqs can only be up to 256 kilobytes,
and a common exam scenario is having to send larger
messages than that on to Sqs.
And then they ask you what kind of architecture you could use?
Well, a very common architecture er.
To solve that problem is to store the large objects and S3 and then
passing metadata as the messages in sqs pointing at those objects
similar to the graphic you see on the screen here.
So this is sort of a bypass in a way to get around
that size limit that Sqs holds, and this is a hard limit,
so keep that in mind.
The next thing we have is a delivery delay.
So how long do we want to wait to deliver a message?
So how long do we want to wait to deliver the message?
Once it's on the Q on we can, hold it from 0 to 15 minutes.
So if we wanted to we can go ahead and hold on to that message and wait to
deliver it and building off of that we have our received message.
Wait time now this is where we talk about short polling and long polling.
So zero seconds is considered short polling.
And that means you have to constantly check the queue for new messages,
since there's no wait time messages, error not gonna build up.
But if we wanted to we can specify up to 20 seconds,
and that's now in the long polling range.
Anything more than zero is considered long polling in sqs,
and this allows for two things.
It allows sqs to gather all of the messages so we can almost guarantee
that we're gonna have at least one message in there,
which, if we didn't, would be a waste of an API call which you pay for.
So this allows messages to build up so we have a better
chance of pulling them off the queue.
Now.
This provides a few main benefits,
the first being it allows us to wait for messages to be cute onto a rescue
sq in order for processing and building off of that,
it allows for less API calls to the Q.
Because now we're waiting 20 seconds in between calls,
as opposed to having to check the Q constantly with a set of zero,
so we'll go ahead and leave this at zero.
But this is an important architecture question that comes up
quite frequently on the professional level.
Exams understand that zero is short polling,
and then anything from 1 to 20 seconds is considered long polling.
And then we have our dead letter Q settings.
Now, this is where we can specify a re Docker policy,
and what this does is it allows us to store messages that fail
processing onto a separate queue for longer retention.
Now,
this is a best practice to use dead letter cues because it will
allow you to go ahead and view the message that was failing and
then do some type of diagnosis to solve.
Why it error it out.
Now you'll see we have to have an existing Q.
I don't have one, so I'm gonna diesel ect this.
But this is a very critical component of SQs,
a dead letter Q, which is also known as D E.
L.
Q.
And finally, we have our server site encryption.
So if we wanted to we can use server site encryption and this is going to
encrypt our messages when they go into the Q And what's neat about this
is that we can specify how long we can allow sqs to reuse a data key that
it generates from our kms key.
So we can say, hey, every five minutes,
I want you to generate a new data key and start
encrypting and decrypting with that.
And then it continually cycles based on our re use period.
So I'm not going to encrypt.
I'm gonna go ahead and click on Create Que and there we go.
We now have our Q.
So what can we do with this?
Well, some architectural examples would be similar to this graphic.
Here we have a decoupled architecture er,
as you can see,
where we have our workers which are pushing
messages or sending messages to our Q.
We have the Q itself, which allows for the decoupling and data retention.
And then we have the polar or the worker on the back end
that's pulling the messages off the queue.
So what this does is it allows us to separate our application components and
allows us to break away from a traditional monolithic approach.
We can have separate components that error
independently operating and being updated.
All right, this is a pretty good breaking point,
the clips getting a little long, so let's go ahead. We'll break here and then we'll pick back up where we left off in the next clip.