[Autogenerated] Okay, so we just wrapped up data firehose.
And let's talk about Ken is is data analytics.
Data Analytics is another can is is stream that's
available to us and it allows us to do real time
processing and analysis of streams using SQL.
So a structured query language.
Now, since we're able to perform SQL code against these streams,
this allows us to create time series analytics,
real time dashboards and real time metrics so it allows
for some very powerful processing.
Is far as applications go due to its use of SQL to perform
analytic actions on the streams data now,
Data analytics also output to fire hose lambda and other data streams.
So these error destinations similar to how data firehose had
destinations that it could output data to.
And the nice thing about this is if you output your data to a data firehose,
let's say you can go ahead and dump that data through fire hose into
maybe Splunk-ES any type of analytic processing you need,
and it's all done in basically real time,
which is pretty awesome.
So with the general overview of Data Analytics understood,
let's move into the console and start looking at these data analytic streams for SQL applications