[Autogenerated] and now we can make our way to Amazon.
Elastic search service now Amazon Elastic Search services,
a fully managed service for running elastic search within the AWS Cloud.
Now elastic search itself is an open source search and analytics engine
that's used for real time analytics and visualizations.
It's a very handy tool for quickly identifying patterns within a dataset.
Some solid use cases for elastic search include Log analytics or even real
time application monitoring with click stream analysis.
These error all solid choices for elastic search service as the back end.
And since it's a manage service, this means that A.
W s provisions all resource is that we need for our cluster.
We just set a few different configuration options, depending on what we need.
And that could be anything from instantiation to
maybe the storage size that we need.
And we'll take a look at that here in the upcoming clip.
Now next.
It allows for detection and recovery of failed notes.
And what's nice about this is that this is an automatic action,
so it automatically detects and recovers if we have any
failed nodes within our elasticsearch cluster,
and then finally,
it allows us to scale extremely easily with a single API call to the service.
So using either an STK or the A W s CLI we can easily
scale to our needs via one call to a W s.
So that really makes for an efficient service all around.
It's managed.
It's open source.
It handles detection and recovery of failures,
and it can scale easily within API call.
It's a very solid offering.
So with that wrapped up, well,
cut this clip here and then we'll pick back up in the elastic search
service console within a W s and start spinning apps, um, instances and clusters and then preview how that works.