[Autogenerated] All right, So now that were experts and sqs and s and s.
This allows us to talk about pubs, apps, architectures.
Now pub sub, which is short for publish and subscribe,
is an asynchronous service to service communication that's used
within services in microsurgery is architectures.
So any message published to an SNS topic is received by
multiple subscriptions to that topic.
And then each of those back ends,
those subscribers are able to perform whatever needs
to be done with the same message.
So it allows for parallel processing of the same data.
So in this example, here we have our producer,
and it's pushing a message to our SNS topic here on the left side.
Now message A, which is what's being pushed,
gets published out to all three of our subscriptions.
So these three sqs cues are considered subscriptions to the topic on the left.
And what's cool about this is you can put IFilter policies
into place so you can only pick up certain messages
depending on the back end subscription.
So this is handy if you're sharing an SNS topic with other cues
that might not be related to the same work,
or if you want to filter out unnecessary messages and only act
uncertain ones that contain a specific JSON field.
Now,
once this message a hits all three of our subscription cues
we can configure different types of compute on the back end of
those cues and those back in resource is our what performed the
actions on the same message.
But you'll see each level is doing its own thing,
so we hav e c two out, putting some type of message result to S3.
We have a container service running that pulls the message from Sqs and
then places some data and dynamodb and then at the bottom.
We have a lambda that pulls the message off the queue
and then pops it into elasticsearch, which we looked at in the last module.
So let's go ahead.
I want to dive into the AWS console, so we can see how you can set this up in an efficient manner.