[Autogenerated] awesome.
You've made it through the second module of this Pluralsight
course before we move on to the next module.
Let's just have a quick wrap up and review on what we
learned Now we started off by using E M R elastic map
reduce to perform Big Data Analytics.
So we looked at spinning up a cluster and then passing
in data using the Apache frameworks.
We then moved on to exploring red shift for data warehouse needs.
So we mentioned how whenever an exam question comes up on the
solutions architect exam relating to data warehouses,
Amazon redshift is more than likely going to be within
that architecture for the solution.
So be sure to keep that in mind.
We then moved on to standing up in elastic search
service cluster for real time analysis.
So we stood up a cluster and then we passed in some data,
so we can see how it works.
And while we did that,
we talked about how elastic search plays well with log
analytics in real time application monitoring.
And then we just finished up discussing how quick site can
be used to visualized data and reports.
So using quicksight allows us to gain business insights for our companies.
So we can visual eyes, What's going on within our applications?
So let's go ahead.
We'll wrap up this module and then we'll pick up in the next module,
where it will start looking at using application integration services within A.
W. S.