[Autogenerated] all right, way to go.
You have now made it through the third module of this course
before we move on to the final module.
Let's have a quick wrap up and review.
Now,
we looked at using sqs as a queuing service for distributed systems and we
looked at the different types of cues that we can create,
including Standard and Fife OAuth.
We looked at how we can publish notifications through s and S.
And we demo that by sending an email to a subscribed
address which was my quick to cloud address and then
building off of the sqs and SNS lessons.
We looked at integrating both together for a pub sub architecture er.
So if you recall that diagram we looked at,
it allowed us to send the same message to several different subscriptions
and perform parallel processing with different compute.
It allowed us to efficiently fan out and perform multiple actions.
And then we just finished up utilizing step functions for
stepping through application work flows.
So we looked at the visual builder and console that comes with step
functions and how we can use it for both the bugging and creating different
work flows that will do it for this third module.
Let's go ahead and wrap up and we'll pick up in the final module where it will start talking about implementing a W S I O T.