[Autogenerated] Okay, let's dive into a W s I o t Now I o t If I scroll down,
which stands for Internet of things you could see
there's several services that make it up.
Now all of these services that you see essentially play hand in
hand and work with each other to solve your i o t.
Needs now for this clip.
It's going to be high level, and I just want to dive in to I o t core.
Now this is the main page in service that you use to monitor
and set up most of your I o T infrastructure.
You can see we can monitor our connections and messages that
error published you can onboard new devices,
which we'll talk about here in a minute.
You can manage existing i o T.
Devices.
You can manage your green grass deployments and green
grass is a service that a W s created,
which allows us to process our data that's generated locally.
But the cool thing is, we can still use several A.
W s services to complete that processing.
So, for example, we might have a lambda running locally on our raspberry pi,
which is taking advantage of sage maker for some machine
learning computation that we normally couldn't do locally on
the machine due to resource constraints.
Green grass is a very cool technology,
and I really recommend that you check it out.
Now.
Moving on,
you can see we have secure so we can go ahead and look at
certificates that are created to establish a connection.
And these Certs work hand in hand with a protocol called M Q T T.
Now M Q.
T T is an industry standard for Internet of Things communications,
so it allows our devices to communicate with R A W s I.
O T services.
We have our defend, which allows us to audit and monitor activities.
We can act so these error where we define what are called
rules and we'll talk about these in a minute,
and then we have test so we can test on our gateways by publishing
and subscribing to topics as you can see here.
Now,
I'm not gonna walk through any of this because I have a course that dives in
at an extremely detailed level on setting this all up.
And it's also available in Pluralsight.
And I'll show you that here at the end of this clip.
Now,
I do want to talk about really quickly the primary
components that make up an I o t architecture er,
And to do that, I'm going to use this graph here.
Now, in this graph, we have several I ot things.
Now I ot things are all of these here and these error i o t devices.
So things error any thing,
any physical item or resource that sends data to the cloud.
So this could be things like an i o t button.
What you see here and these error even available on the Amazon
store to allow you to place one click ordering by pressing a
physical button that you have in your house,
it might be a car censor.
It could be an Amazon echo running some type of request that you ask it to.
It could be a raspberry pi that we're running a lambda locally on and then
leveraging sage maker like we were talking about in a W s.
It could be a factory sensor where you're monitoring
inventory or status of machinery.
It could even be a smart thermostat like a nest or Aneka to be.
Now, all of these devices communicate with a W S I O T.
Primarily through what are known as topics.
Now,
a topic is similar to an SNS topic in that it allows
devices or things to publish to the topic.
And then the topic has rules.
That error subscribe to it on the back end.
And these rules, which are in this act section over here on the left,
allow us to take actions based on the messages that come in from R I ot
things so an example might be our factory sending in some type of
sensor data for inventory that triggers an I.
O.
T.
Rule that updates inventory in a dynamo DB table.
Now the cool thing about this is that we can actually bypass topics
and invoke I o t rules directly from R I ot things.
So what this allows us to do is two primary things.
It allows us to bypass a hop through that topic and
just directly invoke our rule.
And it also helps us avoid any unnecessary API actions and
calls that may occur if we send to that topic.
And that's because you have several rules subscribed to a topic So if
you're avoiding all of those other rules that don't necessarily match
up to the request your device is making,
you could invoke that,
ruled directly and then maybe invoke a lambda function like we see here.
So an example from this graph might be this smart thermostat that
is maybe reporting a extremely high temperature.
And we want to take an action.
So that device sends a message using M Q T T Protocol.
It hits this rule and activates an action which may be hits a lambda.
And when that Lambda is invoked,
it sends a message back to our device that tells it to
turn it down to a few less degrees.
And that's just one example.
Now all of these devices use what are called device shadows.
Now, device shadows are what manage our connections and the state of our devices.
So these device shadows are extremely important to the
functioning of R I O t architectures.
Now that's gonna go ahead.
Let's wrap up here.
I just wanted to give you a high level overview of how a W s I o t works.
Now, if you're interested in diving in a little bit deeper.
I would suggest you go ahead and take my connecting I O T devices and A W
s with Amazon Greengrass course here at Pluralsight.
And you can see that here now with that,
let's go ahead and in this clip here and we'll pick up with a module review in the next one.