[Autogenerated] Alright.
Congratulations.
You've made it through the final module of this Pluralsight course
before we move on to our course review and next steps.
Let's have a quick module review here.
Now we reviewed the offerings of a W S I O.
T.
And one of the services that we looked at was I o t green grass.
So we looked at how we can use green grass both in
a W s and on personal devices.
And with this, we discussed i o t device Shadows.
So we looked at how we can securely communicate with our devices
and configure them via these device shadows.
Now let's go ahead and move on to a course wrap up so we can have a final
review of everything that we learn from a high level.
Within this course we explore,
the different Ken is is stream offerings that AWS has,
which included Kenneth's data streams, video streams,
Data analytics And then we looked at data firehose.
We saw how we can Leverage Analytics services within a W s.
So things like e m r red shift elastic search in quicksight and we talked
about how you can tie all of them together We then looked at integrating s and
S and sqs for pub sub architectures within a W s.
So we looked at configuring different topics and topic policies as
well as different sqs cues like Standard and Fife.
Oh,
that subscribed to SNS topics and then have different
consumers on the back end like a lambda,
for example.
And then we just finished up by gaining a general
understanding of the A W S i o t offerings.
So we looked at all of the different I o t offerings the A W S
has and talked about him at a high level.
So that's going to do it for this course on implementing
analytics in real time data in a W S.
I want to sincerely thank you for taking the time
to take this Pluralsight course,
and I recommend you start looking at the other courses
that make up this solutions architect, professional path.
There are eight solid courses that make up this entire path,
and this is just the seventh out of eight.
So once again, thank you very much for taking this course, and I hope to teach you again soon.