All right welcome back my students.
It's time for us to start having some really cool fun or hey we have been having a lot of fun with commenting
having a lot of fun with this course but it's about time to hour some really cool features.
I'm thinking right now that we should be adding features to the posts section.
All right.
So I already show you something like this in the demo video of discours song going to actually do it
with you.
We are going to be installing 3-D you or else.
Well we're going to be creating free to you or else in our application we want your application.
You are able to look to have the name of the you are L instead of the ID.
All right.
And that's why the pretty you are l feature is right.
So that's what we're going to be doing.
Alright cool.
Right now I just created these polls a couple of minutes ago.
So if you don't have no data in your application make sure that you have some data going to come here
and then to create a category here by awry.
Let's go to pose for a quick.
We don't have to do this.
I'm just doing this because I want to get an update this.
All right cool.
All right.
So let's go to our one of my best friends here called Google and we are going to be looking for a package
.
All right.
And I'm sorry about my internet connection but I mean a hotspot.
And it's super slow.
All right.
That's because I move to a new place.
And right now I don't not have my crazy Fahs 200 megabytes 200 down connection megabytes down connection
or high.
So I have a really really slow connection as you can see here but bear with me OK.
So the package is going to be called Slogger bought by this gentleman right here as you can see him
there.
And let's go down and just follow the installation requirements so the first thing that we're going
to be doing is we're going to be requiring a package price on his go to our terminal real quick and
we're going to place that in there.
We got a click enter.
I'm going to post the video because it's going to take a while and my side Bush should take one second
.
When you finished it when you see this finished for you.
All right.
For me it took a whole bunch of time.
Hopefully for you it can take that much.
Right.
So once the package is downloaded.
All right you can verify this very simply by going to the post Jason.
So you come here and should be wearing here is making me look bad because I think I have to synchronize
.
All right.
Well the package should be here somewhere.
Do you have it has not synchronizing my side.
But but anyway should be required here in the second line.
There you go.
As you can see.
All right.
So cool.
So once we have that we have to go to config.
So the config folder.
It's come here actually and go to the app and we have to add that provider right here.
So we go back to the page as you can see the providers right here.
Now copy this.
Come back here.
For a dislike this page.
There you go.
And if you see that this is read somehow.
And as luggable key word or anything here it's because it has not been installed in the composer that
Jason should be all looking like this.
That's if you're using of course BHB storm.
Now we'll let you know.
You know we'll let you know if it's installed or not.
So this is a good sign because the you know it's not telling us that he's not installed he's telling
us that something dire everything everything's good.
All right cool.
So what's the next step after this.
Well we have to go to our polls and we are postmodern and we have to actually use this.
All right.
So let's go to our polls tomorrow.
Let's minimize this.
Let's go to our polls right here.
Let's go all the way to the top and we have to use those classes so I'm going to paste them here.
All right then we are going to be implementing this luggable interface.
So we're going to implement that here.
And
basically copying what's on the page.
All right guys like this.
There we go.
All right so we're using that tree right here.
Basically that's class.
All right.
And then we have this property here with this array.
And one thing that he's doing here basically saying I want you to grab the title every time you save
it right and save it to the Slate column.
All right.
Now we're going to add another property here and this property if you will back here.
This should be somewhere here right here so we can return some configuration and we are going to be
returning an update.
All right.
Because right now if we do leave it the way it is every time we save a post.
Yes.
We're going to say this log.
All right to the title to this blog column and we high fence.
But the problem is that when you're doing update it won't do it.
So if we got this update and we changed this to true.
Now every time you update it.
You also do the same thing as you're doing here when you're saving it.
All right.
That can trip people off a lot there.
Let's see what else we've got to do here.
All right.
So.
It doesn't say here wage actually does say here but we haven't done it.
So we are going to be creating this slug column on migration.
So let's go to database migrations.
Let's go to our posts and here right below the title we can actually insert or we can actually create
a new migration.
So if you go back here and see if you already have data why you want to do is you want to use this command
right here.
Luggable semi-colon.
Or call them table pulls the name of this SLOC column which is going to call a slog.
All right.
So let's go to a Ph.D. artisan artisan this use of Beechfield is in command instead of sort of that
we're going to say is slog all right and then we're going to come here and we're going to do this to
commence.
Composer Don Portillo mph Fioricet and migrate.
So that and then THP artists and I agree.
I just wanted to show you.
There we go.
So we added that column there to our migration.
So if you go to your BHB admin you should be able to see that.
So let's go ahead and visit my ph be my admin and check it out.
Right.
So let's go.
Called hacking our polls.
And as you can see slugger's right here.
All right.
So once we have that configuration we should be ready to start creating pretty you or else.
So we're going to do that in the next lecture because these elections getting kind of along.
All right.
So let's have some more fun in the next lecture.
Take care guys.