All right.
Welcome back.
This story is so sad for us to start creating some categories just to start getting things going right
.
All right.
Well actually we being having things going but we got to make them better now with categories.
All right cool.
Let's I actually create a category
controller so BHB Ortiz and make
controller we give it a resource and we're going to say admen category
controller.
That's a long name right.
Ok cool.
Let's go to route real quick and see with Guy anything there.
We don't.
All right let's just copy one of these guys.
Actually we don't have to call let's just write it down guys.
Stop being lazy.
Right.
So we're going to say when the user goes to admin categories they find all their stuff re admin Catholic
horis controller.
OK.
Now let's go to the controller itself Ray.
I mean synchronize my side here.
There we go.
And let's go to him that real quick return view
.
Remember guys if you don't know the wrong name you can always look it up by doing BHB Ortiz en route
list.
All right let's go to the resources
main categories.
We already have an index there.
Why don't we get something started here extends
and section
let's just see categories here.
All right.
Let's also
fix this here.
This is do admin this make it dynamic
route
men
and it's
in here would be they create one
night on the right all that again.
You right.
All right cool.
All right.
I think we're set up here.
All right on the next lecture we're going to start working on the controller.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.