Welcome back my students in this section we're going to be learning how to send e-mail with Meribel
now sending email with Meribel is super easy.
Now the problem is that if we use the native BHB function to do it we're going to have a problem our
e-mails are going to be sent to the spam folder on that recipient right.
So what we wanted to write is use an API to make sure that our emails get sent to the bots instead.
All right.
So we're going to be using a company called Melgar.
So we're going to use Mail gone right to their API to send e-mails.
Now Melgen is free up to like I think is like 10000 e-mails or something a month.
So don't worry about it you're not going to have to spend any money out of your pocket.
But we're going to make sure that our e-mails get sent to the right place.
All right.
I remember that I know the course courses we use BHB malfunction that caused a lot of problems and we
don't want that we don't want that.
So you're going to enjoy the sexual one last saw.
Pay very close attention you're going to learn something that you're going to be able to use with a
lot of new applications.
Right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lectures below.
They care