Write welcome back my students on this lecture we're going to learn about made awareness and awareness
is like a filtering mechanism for H.E. or our HTP requies are coming in in the application.
So if you have a request to go to the let's say they create a functionality or create view then we can
have a middleware saying OK listen do not allow anybody that's not authenticated to go to that create
.
All right.
So that's what we can do we're made a wish is super super cool is next layer of protection for application
and it's very useful and you're going to use them throughout your whole application process.
I'm pretty sure.
All right so if you're not going to use middleware you're not building a really cool application midways
or one of the keys in protecting certain aspects of your application.
So for that we're going to build a new We're going to create a new installation of Clarabell.
Yes that's right.
All right.
You're going to create one and I'm not going to even do it in this lecture and I'm not going to do it
on the next lecture or I already created one.
So I want you to go to the next lecture with that installation of Laro create it.
And it needs to be called made aware right.
So go ahead and create your database.
Go go ahead and create your migrations.
Go ahead and create even your logon system.
And on the next lecture I expect you to have all that ready.
This is an assignment for you.
So how old are ready.
And then we're going to go and learn about middleware.
All right.
So I see you in the next lecture.
And if you have any questions please post them in the discussion.
But I expect you to do that remember.
You build a whole application from scratch.
Meaning that you're going to have what you're logging system you're going to have your database connection
your migrations.
Now just want the deadly migration doesn't have to be any other migration just the full migrations with
the logging system.
Right.
And the application needs to be named made aware.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
I hope you're ready.