All right welcome back I'm a student so it's tough for us to go to the update met Let's do that.
Let's go to our post comments controller and let's check the update and update here.
It's pretty simple.
We're going to find for fail.
All right.
And we're going to update super simple guys.
Super simple you guys know how to do this already.
I don't how to tell you but just in case you forgot.
There we are.
And we're going to right redirect back to admin.
Or we can redirect back to the same place.
We can just put the comment and mantra here I read back.
Right.
We can change that function.
But I'm just gonna leave it like that.
That's OK.
Let's go and take a look at that to see how that works or no proof.
Whoops.
That's going to the wrong place.
All right.
Let's make sure that he goes to the right place.
The men comment
routes for a quick
comment controller goes to UPS and can't.
So let's go back here.
See what in the world happened.
Oh is that my redirection.
It's not 100 percent.
So those comments and comments.
There we go.
It is working.
You see that.
All right.
In the future we king at a judge to this.
All right that way we don't have requests we don't make a request of the page but right now you get
the idea.
All right.
So let's go to the straw here and we can just find the comment.
Just something with a here
and the lead.
Of course we need the I.D. and we redirect this one.
We're going to redirect back
just to show you that it does work.
So we got this come in that I don't like they're just going to delete it.
Oops.
Why in the world just happened.
There we go.
You got.
We need to put the return here.
All right.
That should work.
There we go.
No comments there.
Pretty cool stuff right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture