All right welcome back my students so we are making good progress here with the comments.
I'm going to go to to our what you might call it to our posts here.
And as a matter of fact I'm going to add a little feature here that I was going to take as to that specific
post.
All right.
So we had this but we don't have it and it would be nice to do.
So let's go to the post page adman's.
I'm going to minimize all this.
There we go and I'm going to add this right after body that's going to be a link and very similar to
what we did in the in the other.
We're going to say I want you to take me to the home post and please take this idea with you.
All right.
Cool.
If you post
and it's super cool.
We're going to open your tie and that's going to take me to the post.
Cool.
It will be nice to also have a tag here for comments right now if you put a lot of stuff here guys.
You know you won't be able to see your body here.
So you know I'm not going to go into details on how to create a page to see the comment because you
guys should know that right.
We I mean we do that with the post we have.
We do that with everything here and this publication is about doing the crowd Ryrie create read up day
in the lead.
So you know that should be very easy for you.
So I'm not going to go into details about that.
All right so let's actually be on now functionality where we can see the comment.
So I'm going to have a link here.
This link is going to take me to the comments page.
I will leave his admin comments and that's it.
I don't know.
You see I took an answer that's nothing wrong with that guys.
Nothing wrong with that.
So admen
comments that ended I think I'm right.
I am.
There we go again.
All right.
So a few comments.
Let's see if that allows us to do that.
We could do that we can view the comments but it would be nice to view just disposed comments so we
could do that as well.
All right.
So right now we are linking to this.
But if we go and do a show and pass the idea of the polls we can go to a specific page where we only
see the comments for this post.
So
let's go and create that real quick.
I wasn't planning on creating that.
But now that you insist.
Let's do that.
All right.
So
this is a table here for.
For that I'm going to face a year and see if we can modify this and make it
make it better
.
We don't need to do anything
As a matter of fact we only need a table here guys
and for each of us
actually we need it.
And the
this one here.
And if and then there was let's see what we get.
All right there we go
your comments you also comment want but we don't have anything there.
So he goes to that specific comment there.
We could however create a page where we only show the comments for The View.
All right.
So that's what we're going to do in the next lecture.
We're going to play around with that a little bit because I want to show you how to do that.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you in the next lecture