All right welcome back my student in this lecture here we are going to be learning how to create polymorphic
relations.
Now that sounds super complicated and it's even spelled complicated.
All right.
It is.
It's even programmed.
Complicated.
All right.
But I'm going to show it to you in a very easy format and I'm hoping that you're writing as you go with
as you go along in this lecture.
OK.
I want you to write the code.
I want you to do it.
I don't want you to just watch me if you want you can just watch me the first time and they start writing
the second time you watch the video.
OK.
Now once you know this is going to be a breeze and you are going to enjoy making this party more free
relations are right.
So why are they.
Well polymorphic relations allow a model to be loaned to more than one other maade on a single association
meaning that for example we could have a users table.
Right.
And we have opposed table and they both can be related to one other table called photos.
So in the photos table will have some columns that we say that would specify the model in which they
belong to in the idea of our record so they could we have a photo table that would say something like
hey listen this belongs to the poles model with the ID of one and this belongs to the user model with
the ID of two.
You see what I mean in that same table where we just have to create this relationship.
And of course create in-migration.
But anyway even if you did not understand what in the word I just said I am going to do it now in code
and you are going to be able to understand it or right.
So I'm going to come in this hour and remember one thing guys were going to be building an application
where I'm going to show you how to create some of these relationships there how to date them how to
you know delete them and do all kinds of great stuff in there.
All right.
I just want you to understand how to build relationships later on you're going to be able to update
them in and they lead them as you want arise is going to be pretty easy.
So anyway the first thing is creating a migration right.
This is clear he was just experimenting there.
Sometimes you have to keep writing this over and over again to get it to through your head.
Right.
Not perfect.
Write it.
I use a lot of frameworks out there and I build a lot of applications so sometimes I forget methods
.
But anyway so here let's do BHB already sent and let's do this make a model and this color photo which
is going to create a table called photos all lowercase with a plural right list.
Tag a would m to be a migration at the same time.
Burford going to synchronize mine.
You don't have to do that some of you are going to see it right away under your app.
You're going to see your photo model there.
Now before we mess around we're building the relationship here.
Let's go ahead and go to migrations for a stable and let's build some columns here.
All right.
Table and the first column that we need here is the string and one the path of the picture right at
least there so we can display it right.
Let's call it path.
The second here.
Let's make this an integer
integer and remember correctly we get to follow this convention here image able ID.
So this would be the ID of that Recker right if his a user would be the user ID in there.
And this is a table and this would be a string.
This is where the type would be.
So this could be the user id and here would be the app the name namespace app user because that would
be the type so it would be something like app in the in the database.
I mean OK.
And you're going to see in a minute a user like that anyway.
So we've got a string here it's going to be called Image able type.
All right.
Just follow this convention and you should be good.
All right once we have that all we got to do is migrate.
So BHP areason I agree.
All right so I'm going to leave it like this up to here and on this lecture and on the next lecture
we'll continue.
All right guys.
I want you to digest the information while on this video rewind that if you want up to this point a
couple of times until you understand exactly what we're doing.
If not no worries continue.
And I'll see you in the next lecture Okay.
Thank you so much.
And bye bye.