All right welcome back.
My students saw the last lecture we have migrated there and created a forest table where along with
the model now we still need a little bit we're a little bit more work to our migrations because impose
We have the user id which we don't want anymore.
All right.
We don't need a user ID here in polls because we are going to be using polymorphic relations so I'm
going to comment this out I'm going to roll back on my migration or do migration refresh.
OK I'm going to be putting some data there you won't see me because I'm going to post the video.
I want you to see me writing all that data.
All right.
But just to give an idea I'm going to be putting And I want you to do the same thing.
Let's go to Claribel CMOS.
I'm going to be putting a forward path.
This one Ali for last because I want you to see me doing it but I'm going to insert one or two pulls
.
I'm going to do some roles.
I'm going to do a roll user and the user and one or two users.
All right so if you want to go ahead and answer that data you can and I'll see you in one second.
So I just finished inputting some information I put a country's D.R. in PR and I also placed to posts
some roles I did.
I related this user id. one we wrote like the one which is the administrator and that to the user number
two with the role ID number two which is a subscriber as you can see we've got tools users here.
OK.
So I just put some information on your photos.
I wanted to do it with you.
So I'm going to put the first photo that I'm going to relay is going to be my picture right.
G g.
G.
The image ID is going to be the user ID for that specific photo rife with our table users.
So is number one we know that and the image type is the address the name space the model right there
.
All right.
For this one it's going to be a poll so I'm going to say something like a match or I don't know the
Laro.
Bill GBG and the image IDS is going to be number two.
I mean the actually could be number one in NBA in a totally different area and image type is going to
be app post Reiser's going to be polls with ID of one.
Right.
Cool.
All right.
So now we have some data here.
And one thing that we need to do is that we need to double check that the user doesn't have a user ID
field here.
The polls no user ID.
All right cool.
All right so now that we have this we need to set the relationship right the polymorphic relationships
.
Let's look at the model real quick and I'm pretty sure we haven't done that yet.
So for there we go.
All right.
So public function.
And this is going to be called Image able I'm following combines conventions from the documentation
in the allowable dot com Web site which I will always give you some type of the link at the end of each
section of lecture's so that where you can refer back to the documentation and find some more information
about them all right.
All right cool.
So this one here we're going to do this return this morph too.
All right.
So that's the first one now we've got to set the other tables because this is the main table now for
this if we want photos out of you we need to create a method called photos right public function forwarders
and you can name this whatever you want.
So when I pull out the photo from here so I'm going to say return this more if
I'm trying to remember more many.
This is fine.
And then here we are to morph what the photo and then
image
a match table there we go.
OK cool.
All right.
And now we could do the same thing to the press.
So they use a stable model right there to the user model.
Beautiful.
All right.
I actually already had it there.
Sorry about that guys right here.
All right.
I was doing a lecture and I had some issues with my computer and I had to redo the lecture so that's
why I was there.
OK.
But anyway so that's there what else we need.
That's about it.
Now we can start pulling out information from this model so let's go back to the routes and let's create
a little comment here and we're going to say let's see if we can spell it correctly polymorphic relations
.
There we go I think we spell it correct it was spelled correctly.
Let's pulao a photo and let's see let's pull our users for the array.
So let's first grab the user.
So user find user number one.
OK.
And now we're going to going create a for each loop and we're going to pull that out real quick.
Let's indent our cold a little bit.
All right.
So now we do this user very similar to what we did before with other relationships.
The only thing that changes in most of these relationship is the way we were going to model and link
them and create them all right this thing.
This is what changes here.
This meant that depending on the method.
OK.
We we have a different relationship but here most of the time we're going to always point them out like
this with dynamic properties.
Right.
This would be the Med this name so user photos as forward on.
OK.
Now here you can just see this return photo array.
And let's go and create a row for this.
All right.
Because we don't even have a route for it.
So let's just make sure we have a route for you guys.
And I told you a couple of years ago that I was going to get to go and get a rest.
I did not just in case some of you are wondering.
So user photos function beautiful.
There we go.
Let's just take that out and pasted in here.
That's why my code was in Denton before because the HP story is really smart when it comes to indenting
.
So if it doesn't find the right code it won't indent it correctly.
OK.
So beautiful.
Let's go and do this now in the browser.
So see a mess and let me just bring that here user
forums.
There we go.
Beautiful right.
So we found the user's photo there.
And when J.P. G and phone dies you can pull out the path of the image.
All right so you know how to do that right.
I mean I don't have to tell you that's super simple to do.
You have to do is do this Ray.
And we can follow the path that they look at that and there is where you would display the image of
that of the user.
Now the user has had multiple images you will display multiple images here.
OK.
That's what's cool about it.
Not only that but you can also all right now pulao users the pose images as well.
So we can say polls photos and we find the first polls.
And let's just call these polls here.
We're going to change this whole thing.
We'll find the force first polls.
And there we go.
So now we go back here and we just changed this piece for a you know safe post.
Now we got the post photos.
You see that.
That's beautiful isn't it.
Now let's go back and add another picture to polls for example.
So I'm going to insert a different photo for the post dodgy Biji image ID
for the post number one.
And they have the names.
They would be that would be the model right there post.
All right.
Antar.
Remember that we are making an image for this post right here.
All right.
So now if I refresh this well
where is the photo right here.
OK.
Now if I come back instead of returning we do the echo because remember that return only returns one
value.
So we have to echo it and make sure that you would abrade tagging here so that way you can have a second
line and see this in a very nice way.
Enter And as you can see this post has two pictures.
And of course you can customize this and do it like we did before like this and
that and instead of the ridges.
OK.
So
now we can just say oops for pulls one on one other of the photos and for post to.
I want the photos for us to have no photo so we don't get any photos there and we could put a condition
there a photo a post number two those doesn't have any photos just say.
This post has no photos.
You see what I mean.
And we can do that very easily with eloquent as well.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture guys and it's been a pleasure showing you how
to know how to make this happen.
And I'll see you in the next lectures which you are going to enjoy as much as I enjoyed teaching them
.
See you.
Bye bye.