All right welcome back male student.
This is going to be a very short lecture because I want to show you how to pool the owner the owner
of the image.
All right.
So let's go let's get to it.
Let's create a raúl real quick and it's come in this out.
This created a really cool round here or root.
Some people call it root I call it round but it's up to you to call it whatever you want.
All right.
As long as it makes sense.
All right so for it all and let's just say the IDs there will we'll put an ID on the browser.
That's fine let's just do this and.
OK.
And that's a matter of fact this photo.
And let's just call this user actually post has to.
So we can pull all of that.
All right.
So here what we need to do is we need to loop well not loop but we need to go ahead and Querrey the
the photo and we need to say find and it's better that you use this fine or fail.
OK.
That way you can kind of throw a four or four or there.
So file fail ID and I haven't been using that much but when we started building our application we are
going to be using this all the time.
All right.
So fine or fail ID.
So we're going to find that.
And as a matter of fact I'm going to play a variable to it.
So that's going to be the photo.
OK.
As a matter of fact we need to import as well so I'm going to put this on top import the class.
And for those of you that are happy it is to make sure that you have this on top.
All right.
In the name space they're beautiful so once we find the photo we will pulao the owner.
So we will say Forteo Orner or something like that.
OK.
Mitch you can write it however you want.
You can write for all you can write photo owner 4:2 ideal owner or whatever you want but I mean not
here but when you find this you can do it in your column Serai.
I'm just following conventions what they have in the documentation and that's it.
As a matter of fact I don't even need this.
I'm just going to return.
Return Ramsey returned with the ID which is going to return like this.
We need the name of that method.
All right let me see if I got this correctly.
Ok return photo image image table.
All right.
Each piece Tony is telling me has a new version.
But anyway let's go and try to see if this works.
If not we'll debug it.
That's OK.
So we'll
come here and say photo ID number one for user oops was a user.
Now I suppose I believe all right there we go.
All right so we found the owner of the photo I.D. number one.
Cool.
What about the owner for ID number two.
Who is that.
Ha.
We've fallen for number two here.
She says he has that.
And there we go.
See that beautiful.
All right.
So anyway Guys thank you so much for watching this lecture I tell you is going to be short and sweet
.
So as you can see we were able to find the photo.
All right.
Number one for a number two owner.
So we can see that number two is the owner is a post and the full four are number one the owner is a
user.
We just got this confusing you are all here.
But don't worry about that.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching guys and ladies and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Keep it up.
You're doing a great job if you're following me.
Very good.