All right welcome back my story.
So we got to work on this page here for our replies right.
Well we don't have any replies right now.
We do have a reply's table but we don't have any replies.
All right.
So let's actually work on the Create for functionality.
Let's do that.
Why don't we do that.
It's very simple to do.
It's going to take a little bit of time since we're gonna have to modify a couple of things but you
should be really easy.
All right.
OK.
Let's go here to.
Well first you got to do is figure out how where does nested device.
So as you can see right there let's just take it from there and take this file and paste it right here
.
Right below this guy right here.
So let's see how that looks real quick
as you can see it looks good.
That's the way it is.
All right.
Now we got to figure out where we got to put that reply form.
We have to build this reply form and we have to find a way to put it in here somewhere.
So
I think right below these media media body right here should be a form.
Let's just see how that looks in there OK let's form and let's open one form here and this is going
to the store method and to to to to to do common replies
controller
right.
Whilst this should be a têtes area and it's Shumi body we're going to fix the security later.
We might have to create a maybe a custom method so that way this form can not send any more requests
or anything else.
If you remember this is inside our admin middleware.
If you wan we could create a group just for users there are not.
Then instead create a custom method just to send down request there instead of giving access to all
this in the admin section.
All right.
So as a matter of fact let's just do a real quick
and this will give access to the user that's logged in and
we can just create a get.
This is actually not a get or post post
and it could be a comment reply like this.
And he goes to the comment
replies controller
and he goes to the mat.
I don't know create We're going to create them meant to now create a reply or something.
All right.
And now if we go to the comments replies controller
that's do it all the way.
Actually that's too close to store we could take store out of there if we want to but I'm going to do
it right below here so you see that is different create.
I believe that's the name reply.
And this mentor is going to have their requests just as they were on top and return to functionality
right here.
It works OK.
So
create a reply
then send the body there
to its area.
Let's create another row here.
Well I'm not sure you Rose maybe one.
I don't know how that looks.
But let's try it.
And fine now.
And that's how it looks.
Let's submit this and we go to that method.
All right cool.
So we're going to finish this in the next lecture.
Are we're going to try to go that way.
Some comments.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture actually submits replies.
Take care.
See you in the next lecture