All right welcome back my excellent student we are ready to rumble again.
All right so now we are ready to find the relationships on tomorrow.
All right.
So the polls in the video model should have that taxing method in there OK.
That's the one that caused him more of too many men on the eloquent class and now I'm going to show
you what I just said.
OK.
So let's go to the app and then let's go let's say for example let's go to the polls model here.
And this is what's going to have the tags here method because we want to be able to tag at the polls
.
We want to be able to say I want to get all the tax from the polls.
Right.
So this is where we get to half the Tagamet and now we're going to return here.
Like I just said are more Too many method so let's returned
this more if not more of many like we did before.
Well we I think we'll use that one.
We can also use more of my money.
I mean there are many other ones that we can use but we're going to use more too many.
Because that's what we're doing here.
All right we're Morfin this too many.
All right.
So where are we going to be doing.
Here is app and we need to refer to the tag estée model here.
And then Taggett will.
OK.
Beautiful.
So I think I'm spending incorrectly taxable.
All right.
So now that we have this here we have to go back to the the tag model right here and we've got to let
him know a listen.
All right.
The Post wants you.
So let's go public function and we're going to say polls.
All right.
So now on this and this is what we are not find the med for each of its related models.
So for this example we're going to define Polsce method and that will define the videos as well.
But we're going to use polls.
All right.
So let's do return
this and this one is where we're going to be doing more by many.
OK.
Not on the last one.
Like I said before I just you know what I meant was that we can use more of by many methods as well
we have many different mentors that we can use not to use it on the other side.
All right so this tag is going to be more.
It's going to be used shared by many That's what we're saying here.
OK.
So who's it going to be share from.
It's going to be share from post.
So that's what we've got to really put a human first parameter.
And of course we got to say staggerer.
All right.
Taggett Well as you can see this is taking the the singular name of the table because if you go to the
migration right here let's go base and then right here is taking the singular name of that table.
All right.
So anyway let's go back.
All right so we're we're good with tags right.
Let's go back here.
We can do the Wii.
Let's just do the videos were let's just copy this real quick.
All right.
And I was like All right my voice has left my body in a bad way there let's just do video here see that
way you know what we're doing video.
OK.
Now we're going to do just pull out the information from Paul so that way you can see how it works and
then you can do the rest if you want.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture where we are going to
be retrieving some of the relationships so that way you can see how it works.
But I want you to try it on your own.
This is super simple guys.
We have been retrieving related models and you know all the models before when we got to well when the
same way.
OK.
So then we find it ok we find one and we returned with the method as a dynamic property.
So just try to figure it out and try to do it on the next lecture we're going to have a lot more fun
.
OK.
So keep it up be doing a great job if you follow me on to here.
And if you are coming back here with all the knowledge of all the relationships that we have done you're
doing awesome so keep doing it.
We are learning a lot.
We're going to learn some more.
Take your.
See you in the next lecture