All right.
Welcome back.
Why these students hope you're having a really good day today.
We are going to be starting the forum to create users.
All right cool.
Now before we start this I want to actually use the package I don't know if you remember but we are
actually in one of the sections we were using in the form class the age the amount from the collective
.
And let's do a check to see if our application has I doubt that he has it because we have actually not
included that right.
So let's double check just in case so let's go to config and then app that BHP.
Let's see if we have that service provider here.
We don't have it.
All right.
So we need to actually require.
All right cool.
So we required a couple of different ways or I'm going to show you and I'm just going to give you a
little reminder of how we require this stuff.
All right.
So Claribel collective estimate.
There we go.
Even there an auto company.
And I'm just going to show this one 5.0.
And as you can see we could if we wanted to go to that computer.
Our Jason File put that in there then to compose or update and include is any clue this but just because
I want to do it in terminal.
All right I'm going to do a composer require.
And then we're going to spell it Claribel collective enter.
All right
there we go.
That's going to take a little bit to do.
Mine already finished.
And if you go to computer there Jason we have the let's actually do synchronize here real quick.
Make sure that it is working there.
There we go.
So it is there.
All right so now all I have to do is go back and add that service provider class.
All right.
So let's go back to La Belle collective.
Let me see if I can find it in my alarm bell.
I had it here somewhere.
Let me see if I have it.
Let's go back here real quick guys.
A collective actually a male right here.
And all we have to do is grab this.
OK.
Go back to our app where the service providers are right here and just based that in there.
And then the alias's.
All right so we have to copy the aliases that way we can use that with these keys.
Let's go back to where it says alias's in a space setting here like this.
All right.
Now if we go back to create we can actually start using that.
So let's go back create.
And we also have a shortcut that we created on our collection to go cold form open.
Actually I think it was open form.
Now we don't have that at all.
We already did.
But if we go to BHB storage preferences we check on the live Templi section for a form.
We just type for Main and we do everything for us.
OK so let's let's do that.
There we go.
Now let's go back to our create and let's see if if he's working all right now the fine that's OK.
We're going to just define it real quick.
Whoops.
We're going to call this admin users.
And now let's go back and see if it's working.
There we go.
So our form is working.
If for some reason it was not able to installed to be installed that you were going to get an error
here OK.
So now this is a sign that it is working you can inspect it and see that your form is there ready.
All right cool.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture guys.
I hope it was pretty exciting for you and you are really motivated to keep going.
If not I want you to think about your goals and I want you to think about the stuff that you are going
to be creating after you finish a course that's going to motivate you to keep going guys.
Right.
So in the beginning just a learning process later on.
It's just more fun.
All right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture