All right welcome back my student.
It's time for us to start pulling out do Orner all of our polymorphically relation.
So what is the owner of this.
Whatever tag we want.
Well the owner of that could be a POSSO could be a video in this case right.
So let's come in this hour real quick and let's find out how we do that.
All right.
Let's create a roll real quick and you can create Israel however you want right.
Right now we're not putting much importance on it because we're not building an application right.
Well let's say we want the tag for polls for the polls.
Usually I will have tag and maybe a the name of the post or something here.
OK.
But anyway we're now building an application.
Yes are we not going to bother with that.
So let's go here.
And for us we're going to find the tag.
So let's find tag number one.
I believe that was P-H being Ark. in my case.
Whoops.
Let's put it a little.
Let's go do it for each so we can loop through the method.
Or in this case that namak property remember that Laro is doing that for us.
OK.
So we will say tag pose as post and all we got to do here is say let's pull out.
Let's see the title without pause.
That's pretty cool right.
Let's make sure we import this tag on top.
I remember that that's going to add the namespace all the way on top of this file.
All right.
And then you show you he's even highlighted because we are using those and the ones that are great ours
because BHP star knows that we now use in those so he graze it out for us.
All right cool.
So let's go back here and this time we just say tag puls answer.
And we're not getting any response from here that's because
let's check it out real quick please
.
That is the tag.
Let's go to the tag motto that we forget to put the pools in gear no there.
And
here
we are forgetting something here guys
let's go back to route and let's inspect it a little bit.
OK.
All right so here this is trying to find the tag number one which is BHB we know that.
And here we are trying to pool that tag the Poles for each call and Echo would do the senting as returning
.
Or I mean almost ascending with one value so it's not that it's just not doing anything there.
Let's return let's see if we get some type of object here.
All you know why we work where it can be that pulls those and half.
Let's just return the object to see if we at least get that.
Let's get the poles returned and see what we get.
OK.
We don't we're not even getting that so we're not getting anything.
Tag.
That's we're.
Let's find out.
We get these return we'll get this object here.
All right.
All right we always get the tag.
OK.
Taghavi we get that but for some reason it's not giving us the pose that answer we're not getting that
.
Some reason so let's go back to the tag model.
Let's inspect a little bit.
So this is more of by many more by many we're good here is for the Poles tag of all for the video tag
of war.
All right.
I don't see anything wrong here.
They are both returning data.
So we are good on that.
And
we should be getting something.
Let's go and check those taxes see that leaves the tax have the same ID ID number one and the number
two.
So we are guys this is the type of stuff that you are going to encounter when you're doing this stuff
.
So we Taggert Y.D. or you know what.
It's now one is too.
That's why we can't find it.
There we go.
Mangalam that I left his video guys.
All right.
Because we're never going to find it like that with the wrong ID.
And there we go.
OK.
That's why we couldn't find it.
He had a differing I.D..
Now this was the tag ID number one.
We will be able to find out polls.
All right.
I mean that tag would go awry.
ID number one but was number one was number two.
OK.
So that's why we couldn't find it.
I was just so weird for a minute there but you see one little mistake it cost you not to not to get
the stuff working so make sure that you have all that data in the right place.
So post title as well post title real quick and then we get to see this.
Now as you can see it's javascript pools one.
All right.
Beautiful.
So we got it to work.
No biggie.
So thank you so much for watching guys and keep active kid motivated you doing something really good
for your career and your life.
And you know eating a few frustrated keep practicing you've got to get it.
Don't worry.
This is going to happen but you need to practice practice and practice OK.
Remember that we also going to have a Facebook for this cause we sure already have a Facebook.
So make sure that you sign up if you have any issues.
It's sometimes faster to do to go to Facebook because there are a lot more people sometimes that can
help you.
And they are always checking their phone.
So but if you don't like facebook don't worry we've got that discussion on the course and we can help
each other out.
OK.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lectures