All right welcome back I'm a student so we had our application here taking a lot more form than what
it was in the beginning.
We have our comments here.
We can view the polls where we can actually view their replies here.
So let's put a link right here so that we can see the replies of this comment.
Here we still have to complete.
All right.
Our replies shil page.
I don't think he's 100 percent yet.
We'll find out.
But right now
he has to end it here for their replies.
But I think it's better that we would do it in the show.
All right.
Actually the in the test not in there is just a show.
OK.
All right do we have the end it's all right.
Cool.
So let's go to comment and it's in here let's put it and make sure link here to see.
And that's what we're going to put out after you pause to see the replies and then we take it from there
.
OK.
So this is going to be after the view polls and this is it right here.
Let's just say link route.
And
if I remember correctly.
Add in that
let's go back and just verify that
men come and replies.
All right.
So
let's go back here again to our show to end it ng comments.
OK.
Let's put this guy right here we lose him.
The guy is the reason why not doing shortcuts with BHP storm here because I can do this and look for
the class because I know some of you have not said set that up yet so I don't want to leave you behind
.
OK.
But that would be nice for you to set that up that way you can look for the files instead of you know
search for the files instead of going all over the place.
And I do this when iMac was shift.
OK.
A tab on the sheet.
Click it twice so I know for Windows I think I had a Windows machine.
I tried it doesn't work.
You have to look for that short keyboard shortcut.
All right admen comments replies that show.
I think yes
it's one.
And then we have to take in the comment ID.
Because we have to find the comment and then from there we find the replies.
All right let's close this a little bit.
Actually let's look at this one more time.
He has one of those who have a Nesse.
All right.
So right here and let's call that few replies.
Look at it real quick.
All right.
And let's go and work on it
and let's return something just to make sure that it is working.
And let's put this boy right here.
Return it works.
OK.
Let's see.
All right.
It's working.
All right so how are we going to do this.
Well we first have to find the comment right.
So we find the comment that's all we get and we get in the coming ID or fail
and then we find its relationship.
So for that we're going to call replies and when I say comment replies and we're going to return the
view
men that comment that replies that show us a long compact
and replies do do do.
All righty.
All right.
Less tested less debug it.
Cool.
All right class controller common not found and come in replies.
Eighty nine
men sure enough found.
All right.
Let's check those routes again.
Men come in replies.
Men come and replies.
Let's check our BHP route
.
This was even my editors taking notes freezing me one too.
There we go
.
I don't know about you but it's playing games with me
or I'm misspelling
.
The show admin come in reply show and called me replies Oh and that's I'm doing and it's what am I doing
All right let's check in again.
Let's do this
all ties these guys
.
That's OK.
You are either we're looking for.
Remember that with an s.
And then on the fine very well and that's OK.
We'll fix that in the show.
So
I was actually copying the wrong thing guys.
I was called Beyond name route instead of copying the from here.
So recopying they you or I.
All right.
So we have in the show let's go to the show area
.
There we go.
We have a common day is not defined.
And he's on line eighty nine.
So
could it be this little guy right here.
Maybe they would miss him.
Yeah we missed him.
All right cool.
There we go.
We got it working.
And of course that's not working yet but you get my point.
All right.
So we're are seeing the replies on the next lecture we're going to work on the update and the lead and
all that and Apple and all everything we got to work on here.
OK guys.
Ali's that's working.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.