All right welcome back my student.
So in this lecture we are going to be taking a look at views.
All right.
I'm going to be leaving the last one which is you know for these main subjects these main things which
is NBC right model view and controller I want to leave the last one the best one for last which is the
model I think is one of the best things to talk about.
We're going to be dealing with models a lot when we're building applications.
But anyway I hope you're really excited because we to learn about views right.
Yay.
Anyway let's go ahead and learned about views so we our viewers located views are located in resources
right here in the same level as app resources views.
And this is where our views are right now.
Let's use this resource that we got here.
It's controller post controller tool displacement views.
So let's go to HDTV controllers both controllers click on it and if you are using BHB storm you can
double click on your shift key and you can search files like this.
Just type in the name of your class and you are their boss controller and you're like that.
All right.
And if you have Windows you can go ahead and look for a shortcut key which I don't remember at this
point I think is the same thing but sometimes it doesn't work on my Windows computer so make sure that
you look for that.
If not you can set it up with the HP store and whatever key you want things to happen.
All right.
Just go to your settings or preferences and you can play around with it.
Anyway so another thing that we got to do is let's say for example we're going to be showing something
so let's me see is that the best one.
As a matter of fact let's create a custom one.
How about that.
You want to do that.
Let's do that.
Super easy to create a custom controller method for a controller.
So public and I want to show you as much as I can on this lecture.
So you're going to see me doing things that are not uniform with other things.
Just I don't know where I come up and I'll show you how to do something custom All right.
So function function and show you look at my convention right show flashes from this show my view.
All right.
Like this.
You can do that as well.
You can follow this one as well.
Sure my view even though I like this one show you.
All right.
So now we're going to be returning you so we're going to use a view meant for that view function while
you do.
Are we going to we're going to return.
Well we're going to make one right.
So let's actually create a view something that makes sense right guys.
Contact page.
All right.
And then we're going to return a contact view that makes sense or I was just making things up there
it didn't look very nice.
So let's go to our resources and their views.
For that I'm going to right click on it and then go into create a BHB file.
I'm going to call this contact dot blade dot THP am going to show you in a minute why we're doing this
.
But they just follow me right now and they will explain that later OK.
Enter All right.
Now this that blaze because we are using as you can see the welcome that Bley that BHB here this is
the full file for our work on Page.
A lot of fine welcome page.
The reason why we using these dot blades because HP uses a templating engine a feature a special programming
psi Lauber uses that too.
Now BHB Larabee uses that to to do things easier with BHB and you'll see in a minute how we can use
blade to instead of writing for example BHB ekal like dis equil there's no way we can eliminate all
this and and do this for the curly brackets like this and write whatever we want in there to echo for
example a variable like this.
All right.
So that eliminates a lot of PH BE CALLED IN OUR templates in our HD.
Anyway so we've got the contact page creator created there and we can use this sample the mail and welcome
and just going to copy this to contact entery there.
All right.
Take all this time Laurie.
You don't need that.
I don't have no styles.
Now a my applicant with your application yet because we have installed will strike and assure you in
a minute how to do that but right now I think we could put it from the Internet.
We wanted to but I'm not going to do that.
Let's see something real quick.
This is all right.
So I'm just going to put H-1 here.
Hello contact page actually contact page.
There we go.
So let's go to our controller right here and we should be seen this.
Let's make sure our route is good.
We don't have a route for that so let's create a route.
So we're going to say route get in parentheses.
That's a static method remember when we type in contact.
I want you to go to the pulse controller
to the Met the contact.
All right.
So that's all he's saying.
So make sure you have your routes good your method defined.
All right.
And of course your view and the views for her.
Now this function impulse control of view will look for a file name contact inside the views folder
.
But if you had if you had another folder let's say for example and for the call names let's just create
Just say BHB file.
And I said for names of all pages and I have a contact page in there click enter.
You can see that I just create a directory or for the call pages and inside there I have contact.
All right.
I could do that as well but I would have to change it here.
So I would have to say something like pages contact contact ok or pages that contact just to make it
easier.
You can do that as well.
But in this case we're using this here and I'm going to delete this directory and then right click in
the lead all right.
So now we should see something then when we type in contact Let's go ahead and type in contact.
There we go.
See they're beautiful.
So now we're able to show a view using the controller which is pretty cool.
Now you are you're welcome to do more things if you want and play around with it.
All right on the next lecture we are going to be passing data to views.
So you really know how to pass data to that returned key word that we use right.
Bass strings with variables in there.
Now do it with a view and see if you can do that on the next lecture.
We will do that.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Keep it up