All right welcome back to the students.
So it's tough for us to start getting acquainted with dead date functionality in Clarabelle or I or
have some fun with dates that's what we got to do list.
Let's have some fun with dates right.
So I got to tell you how it works really simple let's create around real quick and let's call it dates
.
Right.
And I am now going to go over every date minted out they are all functionality since there is a ton
of date dates information and I'm going to give you a link at the end of the section so you can you
know learn more about dates.
But I'm going to give you the general overview on how we create dates with Clarabell.
You see Largo comes with this class called carbon.
All right.
And Carlings including every Larabee installation.
As of this version I don't know if maybe in the future they'll take it off.
But right now it is included and it's really great for playing around with dates for you know creating
a lot of data functionality and we're going to do that in a mass when we get to it.
Not in the same as I mean the application where we get to it.
But right now I'm going to show you how he's done.
So let's say you know him in regular Ph.D. we create at the time right object we have a day telling
you that we can at any time write so we will do this and we've got these daytime object writers on this
subject that we can use and we can use it.
Let's say for example we can say plus one week and we can echo this out when we can say let's grab the
object and we can format the object and we can say I want to display the Monda day and the year.
OK so now we go to our application
right here.
You can see that we have the month the day in the year right.
Cool.
All right.
So we know we can do that.
But now let me show you about Harben real quick.
All right let's create a B or tag right here.
So separate some other stuff.
All right.
So carbon is included in the allowable installation.
All you have to do is go all the way to the top and import it.
OK.
So we're going to use carbon.
There we go.
That's it.
So now now if for those of you that want to include carbon in your proj all you have to do is go to
composer.
All right.
And let me see if I can composer Serge CARVIN Right.
There we go.
And this is the package you have to require composer require your nest but carbon you can include during
any project you have.
OK.
But anyway Clarabelle already has it included.
Cool.
Let's go all the way to the bottom and let's play around with carving a little bit.
All right.
Let me show you some of the things that we can do.
Let's go out carbon the best way here to for you to know is that we have the date the current day and
carbon and enter as you can see that's the current date and time.
OK.
Cool stuff right.
But look what we can do with this.
We can come here and we can say something like.
And you see where my ph be stormed does automatically adds the med that we can use against me suggestions
.
So let's say I want to use this guy right here Antar and now is going to tell me the cooking time in
a readable and human readable way.
One second ago one second ago.
OK.
Now what we can do is actually see this a little better is that we could add another method here and
say we can add let's add some days to a list of four days.
There's 10 days to it.
And now let's go back and.
And as you can see it says one week from now.
All right.
Really cool stuff.
Let's do a couple more.
Let's
do some more taxes here and let's do one more here.
So let's say eco carbon.
Now let's play around with this and let's say some months four months.
And we want to see it in a human readable way right.
So that way we can see this five months from now look at that beautiful guys.
Right.
And there are so many other methods.
I'm going to give you a link.
Anyway at the end of this section.
Boy they are so many guys get it now.
All right.
I'm going to go down a little bit.
And as you can see there are so many different mentors that we can use.
All right.
Watch this
yesterday.
Let's do it in the human readable way.
One day.
Go.
Cool stuff right.
If we do it like this we just get it and in a time stamp way.
Right.
All right.
I mean I'm going to leave it up to you to actually you know play around with dates.
But as you can see super easy to do.
And if you want to do this in a preview that you already have already show you.
All you have to do is do a composer with this package right here.
Composer require this carbon is going to include that packaging your project and then all you have to
do is do they require.
OK.
And then you include your order function and you can look it up in your composer in the composer website
and in the.
That's how you require
you require composer projects.
OK.
All right.
I think it's we will go with this.
And if you again if you want to learn more go to the link at the end of the section and then I'll give
it to you.
And always look for links at the end of the sections OK.
Or in the lectures.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.