All right welcome back my students so the first thing that we got to do here is install.
Good.
All right.
For Windows user We already did that before because we installed the shell so that way you guys can
write command lines just like we do a Mac for Mac users.
You can also install good in the good Web site.
All right so if you type in get you go to this Web site get hyphen NCM dot com and you can install it
or let me just make this very small here so that we can see it.
All right.
When you can download it right here once you download the then you can open your terminal and verify
that you have it.
So I'm going to say get high foot high fence version and you can see that I have an older version I
have to obey my version that's OK.
Or I have.
This is a very stable version and I've been doing.
It's been very good for me but I will update my version.
But anyway you can go ahead installed.
Good.
And once you have it installed check your version and you are up and running OK.
All right cool.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture