Write welcome back my students in this lecture here I'm going to show you how to download it I'm going
to give you all the project files in this lecture as well.
So I want you to know that now.
All right.
So go somewhere here on the left side believe for the top of the Raiola bottom go somewhere and download
your files right now for the project.
Now I want you to use these files just for reference.
All right.
Even though I'm going to show you how to install them.
But I want you to use and useful reference because I want you to learn how to do this stuff if you don't
really jump into the cold with me.
You're not going to learn this if you look at it from the beginning and you install it from the beginning
by just looking at the files you're not going to learn it.
The only way that you are going to learn this is by making mistakes right and doing it yourself.
So jumping through the code and doing with me.
But anyway once you download the files that I got for this course and I'll show you right now very simple
.
We can use composer to regenerate some of this stuff.
So for example I'm going to give you.
I'm going to give you this files.
All of them except this vendor folder I'm going to show you right now.
Really quick.
I'm going to move this to trash.
I know I know it's crazy because if I move that's a trash.
No my project will work.
So another vendor for this.
Now here I'm going to synchronizes are refreshing and it's not here.
All right so when you download your file if you want to have the vendue folder back or you have to do
is do a composer update.
Right.
And this is going to bring that vendor folder back.
So you don't see a here but you're going to see that in a little minute.
All right.
But anyway so there you go.
You see it is just appear there.
So that's that's perfect.
Now it's going to take a little bit for some of you to get that file and the reason why they're giving
you that vendor for this just because it takes more space is a lot of folders in here in a lot of files
and it's just not necessary for you to go down there you know for me to give you all those files all
you have to wait more time to download all this to your computer.
Some of you are already using a laptop for somewhere or a very weak internet connection.
And if I give you more files it's going to take you more time.
All right.
So here you have all your files they all all the things that were going to be doing in this project
are right.
So I'm going to try to keep this updated you know as when I update the chords I try to put some files
back in here so that way you always have a fresh copy.
But anyway to here you probably your files if you need to look at them look at them for reference only
.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching guys and I'll see you in the next lectures