All right welcome back my student so one thing that I want to do here before we go on I want to ask
some links re years so that we don't have to be typing it in you are out.
But in this lecture what we're going to be doing is we're going to start doing the file configuration
in our controller.
We need to overload photos and we need to set that up.
But right now we need to have some links here so it just makes it a little easier for us to do that
.
So let's go to our layouts in views and then admin in here somewhere which says All users here.
All right.
We've got to go and use that route.
And the reason why we what I like to use routes are I would I use a route name here would function call
route and we've done that before.
All right so the reason why I like to use route route names in staes because just in case in the future
I change the route of my of this section here for users is always going to be sinked with the route
name instead of being hard quartering here.
If you then I understand it.
Let me explain.
So let's say for example in the future.
I come here and I change this to whatever right.
Then we have to go to each part of my application and update it if I have a hard core.
But if I'm using a router name all I have to do right is nothing.
All right so let's say for example I have a wrong name here of Agyeman users right.
Yeah I already show you how to change the name of your routes.
All right.
So if you have a default route you could always pass a parameter here and change it.
Let's say use your ass if you remember that you can go to the documentation and look it up but you give
it your your.
You get requests around name and the will reflect in your application is a lot more dynamic guys right
a lot more.
So that's why I like to use routes.
All right let's do routes.
And we're going to take me and that users we go.
All right.
So that's where we're going.
And this one here are out and men users create.
All right.
So let's come back here.
Whoops.
All right so.
OK.
We are actually typing in that as well.
All right there we go.
So now if I go to all users if I go to create we've got that working OK.
So now we are actually uploading files so let's go ahead and receive that file in our controller.
OK
let's go to our controller right here and we can take all that off.
We will leave this there.
All right so the first thing that we are going to be doing is we are going to put everything inside
a requests a input variable.
So that way I can modify this and we're going to check if their requests file.
And I think we are naming this file.
Let's go back.
Actually his photo ID for I.D. Let me check on that right now because that something just occurred to
me.
All right this is in the users that's fine.
Let's check.
Yeah OK.
We add a column here called
photos.
No that's not it.
This song is all right.
All right.
So let's go back here.
So if this exists.
I want you to do something with it.
So I'm going to return for Lloyd's List.
Let's check it out real quick.
Guys I let's just real quick make sure that this is working.
Let's fill this up real quick.
A regular 90 is that as
well up 18 put it out data.
I think weirding refresh.
We need to make sure that we refresh that array.
And now let's try to do that again.
OK let's come back and see what in the world happened.
I'm going to take that feature of my operating system.
I don't like it.
All right.
So we are putting data here even though
we don't have a photo ID for it.
All right.
We're supposed to return this.
Oh this is redirecting That's why we have a second return here that's why he's doing that.
So let's go back here and try these again
Ray.
OK.
All right it's not returning anything.
So he's not finding this here.
Let's take this out and let's go back to our creator for him real quick.
I think I already know what the problem is
resources man users create.
All right.
This is named file we shouldn't name this file in a database but this is photo I.D..
Right.
And I really wanted to name it.
Named is file.
But we're following a convention.
All right.
So let's go back here and let's do this again.
Let's refresh actually.
The guys and I leave all these lectures here when I make mistakes so I will you guys can learn some
debugging skills OK.
And I always do that in all my courses I don't think is natural for me to raise these lectures and redo
them again.
You guys won't learn much.
OK for you this as you can see there.
OK you guys won't learn much if I live on mistakes here you learn from my mistakes you learn from your
mistakes and you just become better.
And I want you guys to be better than me a lot better than me.
OK.
If you guys are better than me I was successful teaching you something right.
So that's what makes my day guys when you guys you know e-mail me and thank me for showing you something
that you know or helping you find a job out there because of the skill you got from the Course does
.
Those are the things that wake me up in the morning.
OK.
And don't let me sleep at night sometimes.
All right.
So now we know that we are getting some data here and uses controller we're getting the fire we get
in the photo.
Now the next lecture we're going to see if we can complete it complete the whole process of storing
the user.
And at the same time storing is storing a photo of the user with all the required fields.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you in the next lecture