All right.
Welcome back my student.
All right so it's time for us to start actually persistence some data in the database not only just
persistence but persisting everything right.
So let's set this up real quick.
I'm going to comment this all right now that we know that following this that we are able to submit
file information we're going to assign a variable right here in this if statement right away.
We can do that.
All right.
So that way we don't have to do it down here we can save a little line of code.
So we're going to create a variable here and I'm going to spend a time native function from BHB.
I'm going to get the name of the photo.
All right.
So we're going to have the time appended to it.
We could do this at the end of the file as well.
I'm going to do it at the beginning just like Clarabelle does right here you can see that has happened
in the time right here.
All right even though he's opening it in a different format you can if you want to.
I'm going to do it this way.
This takes a little bit more modification to do that.
OK.
You can do that with carbon's pretty easy.
But anyway it just takes a little bit more time.
So File.
We're going to move the file to an images folder and we don't have one is going to create and create
that in the public directory and we get to give it a second parameter.
We got to give it a name as a second parameter.
OK so once we have that we're going to check for the file if he has one.
We're going to pull out the name appended with the time moving to the images.
If not create the images for then this is going to create it.
But most of the time we're going to be moving stuff right.
And now here what we need to do is we could do it in many different ways and you get to choose this
way.
And guys remember that sometimes and most of the time that I do this lectures I do this the long way
.
I want you guys to look at it and think how you can make it better all the time.
All right.
Just think about it how you can make each of these lines shorter and work better.
I'm showing you the long route.
Maybe later in the future we create a section where we going to be refactoring some of this stuff a
little more a lot more.
But right now I'm going to show you the basics I'm going to show you how to create these awesome application
.
Then we make some tweaks later.
OK.
All right.
So we're going to use a photo.
We're going to create a photo and I believe we named this file instead of pass.
That's where the confusion was in the beginning there for me.
Usually I usually name this path but I decided to go against my beliefs in name and file.
OK.
So horrible.
And it's true that I did try to be a little bit more spontaneous there but it backfired on me.
All right so file and we get to give you the file name.
All right.
So make sure that you include this namespace on top.
Import that right here on top and less assigned.
Since we have all that in here and a photo ID because once we create this photo we going to have an
I.D. available to us right away.
Make sure this is not array actually guys right here.
So once we create it we have this very well we have a photo I.D. available to it right away we don't
have to do the you know like we used to doing in adp HPN pulao the last sort or ID or anything like
that it does it Automattic for us.
So we can just say photo ID like this.
Pretty cool stuff right.
All right.
So let's just double check this to see if everything's good.
OK.
I think we did a lot on this lecture.
I'm going to leave this short and we're going to finish it up on the next one OK.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.