All right.
Welcome back.
I'm a student in this lecture.
We are going to be taking a look on how to create and not Slessor in Lara bell.
All right.
They are accessories a mutator is that sensors are do the functionality that pulls data out of the database
without doing and then being able to manipulate it before we get it out.
Now the the mutator is I the is the functionality where we can actually set a value before we go to
the database and manipulate the value and set it in the database.
All right so let me show you how we we could do that.
So let's go ahead and create.
Let's see what we got here.
We've got a route of dates right there.
We are still inside that group so let's go and do something real quick clicks access.
Use an access or let's define what.
OK.
So let's create a route.
Real quick.
Let's just the roads and we will say we're going to call this
get name.
OK.
So that's what we're going to do we've got to get the name Ryan notchy view from the or call column
from the user model.
We've got to get that out.
And we're going to manipulate it before we get it out.
So that's what we're going to do.
Ok cool.
So I'm going to say user We're going to use a user model here I'm going to find the first user and bring
him out.
OK.
Of course we can't say user name and we're going to see that name.
So let's let's go ahead and open up a
new browser here.
And if we go to get name
I can get maybe we don't have a user.
Let's see.
Let's check our BHB admin first.
Let's see we have a user there.
Let's go and see Pidge be my man.
And that's what I love else.
Mass and users.
All right looks like we don't have a user I don't know maybe you do.
So I'm going to put all lowercase and India's e-mail.
That's all I'm going to do for the user.
OK.
And the password.
Ok cool enter.
And now we can see that we pulao that user.
Cool.
So now we are not sir we can't access de-value manipulated before we get there before we we equate.
So let's go to the user model and do that.
Let's go to the user model and is fine the successor now right.
And if you go to the command table which you're going to have a link to.
All right are you going to see exactly how it's done.
What I'm going to show it to you is do public function in the way we do this is we say we use a key
the first key when you always have to use this is get.
And then what is it that you want to get.
So now get name.
All right.
And remember this is all going in camel case.
First it starts with a lowercase all right and then everything is Kemel case everywhere.
It's in Kemel case.
Uppercase OK.
So good name.
And then these were has to go there as well.
Ouch review.
OK.
So look at the convention we use the word get.
Then the name of that column that we want to pulao for get the name of the column we want to get.
And the key word acha you all the time and then whoops you're going to pass a value here.
Could be any very what you want.
I'm using value right here because that's what it is.
Right.
And then we're going to say return.
Now you can this is what you mean you played out data.
All right.
So I got to say you see uppercase first and we get to Oprah.
Oprah case that all right.
So if we go back there we see that is all lowercase here right now if I refresh.
You can see that the first letter was converted to uppercase.
All right.
I mean you can try whatever you want here.
You can try many different string functions.
String to upper.
Watch this and it's yours to operate.
Enter everything was capitalized.
So you can see it but nothing has been done here though.
All right.
And this is where I'm going to get to now.
All right we're going to use a mutator and you can see that we can manipulate the data.
But the mutator works when you actually save the data definitely you convert this to something else
.
So as a matter of fact I'm going to do that in the next lecture so that we can take our time and see
how it works.
OK.
Thank you so much and see you in the next lecture.