All right.
Welcome back.
STUDENT So we don't have any polls right now.
All right.
We just created the migration.
If we go back to our project here and our editor lets actually come back here real quick and let's play
around with thinker a little bit.
This go to thinker which Fiore's and thinker and let's just create some quick data.
All right.
Nothing too fancy here.
And let's just say post and make sure this new new post and let's create something here real quick.
All right.
So while we can do is we can say
we don't have to actually create it if we do use is meant that we don't create a guys so you could just
persisted to the database and inspect it if you want.
All right.
But you've got to take this method out of there.
But anyway
let's create.
Let's just make a title out of it and I'd say something like my first post and Lescure a body
of I love Clarabelle with 20 years Antar Whoops.
Don't expect to how a syntax error somewhere.
Let's find out where it is.
Oh one thing guys.
And that's why you can't miss the lecture.
Let's actually put.
I just remember here to put my line in the editor.
Show line numbers.
All right.
Really cool.
I don't use I use them but because I am so used to writing this I don't even look at it anymore.
But it's good to have in mind especially if you're bugging.
All right let's
see where the problem is
.
We don't need the word Neil here.
And he says mass assignment.
OK.
So we need to actually go and make sure there are mass assignment.
We didn't need the word new because we're not creating a new object we already actually are creating
the data directly.
All right.
When you want to persist that's when you create a new object.
So let's actually go to a post and let's do some math assignment here real quick.
All right.
Protectin fillable
print is downloadable.
And we're going to make available the category ID.
I think that's OK.
Gorie I mean and what else.
Photo IDs fine
that title in the body.
All right.
So let's go and try these again
.
Master Simon title We misspelled.
Probably
no we did not.
OK we have to come out a think actually.
So let's go back page artist and thinker.
All right you have to go back and that's why I love making mistakes guys because if I don't know if
I don't if I don't tell you that it would take you a while for you to figure out that you have to log
back in.
OK.
So let's do it again and let's try this.
There we go.
So now we persist that information to the database and the whole reasoning is to.
So that way we can show some information here but let's just check it real quick.
There we go.
Right now we still have time to go and display some data right here right.
Let's go into that real quick.
You guys know how to do that if you want you can pause a video and try yourself.
Let's go to the controller impulse controller.
This is the end that's when I said polls post here.
Let's make sure that we import this on top
compact.
All right.
Cool.
So now we go to the aspecific view and we just play that information.
I'm going to use a table.
There we go.
We already have that.
And there we go.
So we're going to say something like if the polls very woods just we're going to display the information
here and if and let's do it for each let's take that object add in there
.
And for we try here remember to do that and start displaying information here let's just play the post
ID right here.
Let's just play the user ID.
We've got to play the user id for now but we wanted to obviously display the owner
and this display the category ID for now until we create a relationship.
Let's just play the photo for now
array and we get it we got to fix this a little bit guys.
Let's see if we.
There we go.
What else Geez a lot to remember.
Right.
Post body.
What is the other one was
.
All right.
All right I think we're done.
What do you think.
All right so I'm going to actually do this.
So you guys don't see me and that plays a very real quick.
All right I just feel this in real quick guys.
All right.
Let's see where we get
answer.
As you can see we have some fields here.
All right.
Obviously we're going to want to display the user here that category in the photo and we want to do
the carbon here as well.
We can do that right now as a matter of fact here we just do diff for humans like this and we can use
copy the same thing for this one back as you can see that changed.
Great.
All right.
Beautiful.
So on the next lecture we're going to set up the relationship and we're going to finish it up.
Thank you so much.
Bye bye.