All right welcome back.
My students always start for us to start using get.
Now now that we have installed it we can use get it anywhere in your computer.
All right.
So let's just create a for them here.
Just for demonstration purposes I'm going to name this and I want you to do the same thing also.
All right.
Name it.
Learning.
Good.
All right cool.
And once you get to your terminal open it up.
Go to your desktop and go to that fire.
So all travel to the file and staying inside for folder.
All right.
Now in order for us to initialize good for good to work you have to initialize it you have to say get
in it.
Enter now you can use get.
Now if you do there's good.
You can see that it's going to give you some suggested commands commonly use commands that you can use
right away.
And remember that you first have to use the word good and then whatever command after you read you can
see that we can add stuff we can do branches check our clone difference.
And it tells you the description of each file each command which is really cool right.
All right.
Your Don't go crazy thinking don't you know don't worry too much thinking that you have to learn all
this commands.
You don't have to.
All right.
You got to learn a couple of commands like and check out klong or they're for it.
You know some of these basic commands and once you learn like four or five commands you are ready to
go and then the rest is history.
Is practice right on the next lecture.
We're going to continue with this.
And we are little by little we're going to be learning how to use is more and more and next thing you
know this is just going to do this is it going to be done automatically you're not going to even think
to write these commands is going to be so easy and you won't be able to live without using good for
your projects.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.