All right.
Welcome back.
The student so the last lecture we learned how installed this form package.
All right.
And we even learned some of the fields that it creates automatically right when we did inspect element
.
Now we're going to learn how to pass a couple of parameters and not just use the ones in the fold but
actually override those default parameters.
Now let's go to our browser.
Let's check this out first.
Let's see if it works right.
We've got to make sure that this stuff works.
So
let's going canso this and if we try to use this it says method not allowed.
Right.
Well if you look at it you inspect element again right.
If we do that and we see what's going on is going to send those to our create method.
That's not what we want.
All right we want to go to the update method now of the I'm sorry to the store method.
OK.
So let's go ahead and do this real quick.
It's I'm going to go ahead and pass a couple of Ramadan's I'm going to pass an array actually.
And with a couple of keys the first key that I'm going to put in here is demented.
What method do we want to use.
Well this is going to be storing information.
We are going to be using a post.
All right now I'm going to separate it and we're going to put another parameter here.
Where is the action where is it going to.
All right well we want this to go to a specific you are now.
But at the same time we want this to go to a specific method.
Right.
So why don't we use that why don't we use use a controller and the method to where he's going.
So let's do that is going to the polls controller at what At story method.
All right remember that.
So this is the way we do it here.
We put the controller first and that's the controller we have for
pulls post controller and then demand that work is going right.
All right cool.
So now let's try to see if it works.
OK so I'm going to take that I'll refresh it.
And now let's create another
enter as you can see it just created that.
So let's go back and create another one.
All right what else.
Clarabell of course we're missing Loubert right.
Submit and as you can see it's working perfectly.
All right.
So now that we pass him down let's actually create the closing form tag.
So let's take that out of here.
The curly bracket exclamation if you do that one curly bracket one inflammation BHB strong will finish
it for you.
So we do the form and then close static method call.
All right.
So now we go back and we check it to see if it still works right.
It looks like it's working.
Cool.
All right so now let's create this input right here the title input.
So how we do this.
Well if you use ambil strap which later on we will be using bootstrap of course you have to have some
type of def here.
Would a form of group actually right here.
All right and say this we will have a name put a label and on the input so that we go.
And now let's create a label.
Remember that all this information would be the last lecture of the sectional guys.
I know to give you the resources so you can find out how to do this.
All right.
Remember to go to the Lauber collect the Web site as a matter of fact I think I have a window here that
I can show you.
And you can see all the possibilities for this.
All right all the methods all the extra stuff you can do is going to be pretty cool if for some reason
I forget to give you the resources.
Go check out the documentation.
All right.
The version number of the Larabee you're using and the H mail.
All right cool.
So now let's learn how to create this label.
All right so of course we're going to have a label function and we're going to pass a couple of parameters
so the label function and the farmers are going to be as follows.
I'm going to say that title right.
And then whatever title we won in this case we want to use title like this or the Post name or whatever
you want to use.
OK.
That's going to be this is going to be.
All right.
What he's for and this is going to be the actual têtes.
The people can see.
All right.
So now we got the label.
Let's go ahead and create the tets input form.
Then tets function.
Now first parameter is the name attribute value.
OK this is where the name equals whatever.
In this case is going to be title The second parameter is going to be the default.
And we're going to use no for that.
And the third parameter can be anything you want.
In this case we're going to pass an array.
And we're going to use a class because later on we will need a class for bootstrap write form control
would be the bootstrap class.
And of course I forgot my single quotes we
control.
All right.
Cool.
Now this has to Courtland's there.
All right.
So they say the tests were there and he will go back and you can see that we have.
And that's the first one that we created.
Actually that's just the Laro one that we created.
And this is the old one.
OK.
So now we can remove this old one from here.
All right cool.
So now let's go and try it out to see if it works.
Example cement Y LA it's working.
Ok cool.
All right so now we could if we wanted to create a bun as well.
So let's do that actually.
There we go.
And we don't we don't need a label for form for the bar and so we're going to say form submit
and that's if all form meant if you want to leave it like that.
That's up to you if you want to modify it or you can modify it and you can say create post and then
we can pass an array here for the class so you can say class and of course you can give a B and later
on you're not going to see this resource here for the class because we don't have bootstrap linked yet
but we will in the future.
All right.
And now you can take this off course right.
Now of course you want what you want if you want to create a group for it.
You can
write up to you.
Now let's go back and see how that looks.
Answer.
There we go.
Here we go.
Now it's working.
Now we got a form totally made with bootstrap function odds.
I mean with the reform package functionality which is pretty cool.
All right later on you're going to see why so useful and how we can use it to make our application a
little bit more dynamic in some of you already know this how we can make a little bit more dynamic and
easier.
OK.
So anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.