All right welcome back with your students.
So now that we know how to insert information into our database trying to learn how to pull it out.
All right.
So I want you to come in this hour real quick.
I'm going to write this from scratch every single time I want you to get very used to writing this.
So ingrained in your brain.
Right.
So we're going to make a comment here when I call this database raw askew Aquarius and think this is
appropriate.
There we go.
All right.
So let's write let's create a RAWI if you want to positively do unto yourself first do it and then you
can compare it with my code.
See how it relates.
So we got to create the first parameter as a.
You are that you are of course of this get method.
Second problem is going to be what the function right.
Parentheses one pair of parentheses one pair of curly brackets bring you down.
Use a DB class Array.
And we're going to say select first parameter is going to be what we select.
And you can use a single Tessie's the single quotes.
That's how we have it and there's the command Tayshaun.
So we get to select everything from where from polls our table right where Id equals.
OK.
Second parameter we're going to bind this question mark with this value right here.
That's all we're doing.
Remember this is a type of a real way right now.
So we're selecting this.
And now we can actually save those rissoles here in a variable.
Now this is going to return an array of results.
All right.
This results come in.
A s t d.
All right class object meaning that whatever is coming from there whatever resource we get from there
it comes in a generic empty class.
So that mean we can add them like properties of an object like dynamic properties.
All right so all we can access them like is results whatever.
This results like this.
OK.
But because it is an array we need to look the way right.
Right.
So I want you to post a video and try to do that yourself.
Look to these results and come out with that title and return it.
Do that and I'll do that in a in one second.
I hope you're able to do it right.
So I just paused a really like for I don't know how many seconds were in your psi and probably like
less than a second.
But anyway so let's use the for each.
And let's look through it and we like this results as result.
All right.
Or we can make it better we can say we saw US post or this make it more semantic and we can return
post title.
There we go.
Now let's go to the browser and let's check it out real quick.
For the last read enter.
There you go.
They will get the title out of it and you can do that with the other column name content or whatever
other column you have in your record.
OK.
So as you can see this returns.
And now if I come in this hour in I returned.
This guy here.
You see what we're getting the browser.
We get this array of object an object right.
You see the square brackets at the end.
And then the curly brackets indicate it is an object is in an empty class that we king Xs properties
just like we do in an object right.
Look at that.
Is separated by the call and that's when you find out that this is related to an object.
OK.
Now you can also do var dumb.
All right so you're going to ward them and do all results.
OK answer and you can see clearly what it is.
All right you see array 1 and then each key 0 he has an object and then it is on to the class even with
a number 1 16 and now it starts having the ID and that title is a string 16 characters and so on and
so on and so on.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much.
Ladies and gentlemen and I'll see you in at the lecture