All right welcome back my students on the last lecture you learned how to create a controller in different
ways.
You will learn how to create a controller manually.
And we also learn it by using the BHB command line tool BHB artisan.
Now before we go anywhere else let me show you how to find some more commands and BHB artisan right
BHB areason enter an issue as you can see here.
There's a bunch of other commands that we can do with Beechfield addition.
All right.
Even though most of most of them you don't know them now but you will know them later.
And if you look at some of this you could tell what they do.
All right.
This deal with databases.
This is the route.
All right this would give me controllers models you name it we can make it with BHP Orison.
All right.
I don't know how it is.
I sure am going to bring it down a little bit.
I like to always have my terminal of the table close to me.
All right.
So I just told you that we are going to be learning how to use a controller.
So we're going to use a pulse controller here.
All right.
To give you an example.
So let's go to route's because that's where we start to build everything in our application.
All right.
And let's actually comment on this
when I come in everything now and I'm going to leave
this one here.
That's fine.
OK.
And then bring down a little bit.
I'm going to create another
GET request right here and this one is going to be name post.
All right.
Remember what I told you about that.
And then the second parameter instead of being of a closure function is going to be a controller.
So here we just type in the name of the controller.
So polls this is the same name we got right here.
OK has to be the same controller.
All right.
So let's say for that.
So now every time we try to make a request to post it's going to have this controller right here.
But guess while we also have to tell it what type of method is going to hit.
Right.
I want to access the end it's so I'm going to say post controllers at symbol and then the index method
.
Right.
So once I do that then every time I click on post it is going to go to the post controller is going
to look for that's met it beautiful.
So now if I do like this the way it is right now what you think is going to happen let's go see a mass
that the flash polls enter.
Nothing's going to happen is going to be blank but at least we didn't get any arrows right.
So we know that it is working.
So let's go back here.
Let's go to the controller.
This double clicking and typing something here and it's good this is what he's hitting right now.
All right.
This is the root directory.
That's what we tell he were telling it to hit right in it.
So we're going to return some data used to find out if it's working.
So we're going to say it's working well some string actually.
So let's go and enter here.
And as you can see we are returning data so we know the control is working.
Beautiful.
All right.
Let's go back to it now.
Remember that we can passing data Ashwell to the controller.
OK.
So without me doing anything I want you to guess.
So I wanted to go around and guess how we can pass data to this controller right here.
And in this method.
Right.
So I want you to guess and try to do it yourself even if you have to spend 20 minutes doing it you learn
a bunch in the next lecture I'm going to show you how to pass data to the controller.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture