All right.
Welcome back my dear student in this lecture here I'm going to explain to you a couple of things about
the course before we go one.
All right.
So at the end though every section of the course the last lecture where we'll have a resource is a link
to our page in Larabee that come where you can reference what you just learned.
All right.
Again at the end of every section the last lecture.
All right at the end of every section we're have a link that is going to take you to that documentation
page on Largo dot com where you are going to find out about that specific section.
Whatever you learn if you learn about routes you're going to have a link to routing the documentation
on the end of every section.
So make sure that you look for those links if you want more information after we after you learn everything
on that section.
OK.
Another thing that I wanted to tell you is that on this course we're not going to have many exercise
files or we're not going to have many reference files.
Right.
And if we have any for this course they will be right here in the lecture that you are watching right
now.
Just look for the link right here in this lecture.
Download it and then that would be your reference for.
But I want you to write the code with me all the way and don't move from that lectern to you have it
in your brain trying to learn a really good.
I'm always going to keep you know giving you guys references to everything I do everything that we do
in the course.
So I well you can go back to the recommendation and find out about that specific subject.
All right.
If you have any questions I'm here for you.
You know we have a lot of people that are willing to help out in the in the in the discussion.
We're always going to have Facebook groups for you for the courses so if you have any questions and
you have a form and you're on Facebook you can join the group.
All right.
And that information will be in the announcement tab.
In the meantime you can find the link for Facebook groups or anything like that where you can ask me
or as any other students out there.
Thank you so much for watching.
And if you have any questions I'm here for you.
Take care.