All right.
Welcome back my stood and so it's time for us to start actually ended in this category.
All right cool.
Let's get to it.
Let's go to the end it is a matter of fact we already have a let's go back to this and get this guy
right here.
I like this the way this is laid out for now.
So I'm going to get this guy right here this actually copy everything then we can edit it face to there
.
All right.
My God I take this guy out of here and leave.
I'm going to modify this one here.
This one is going to say update.
Right.
And to give it
another array remember that we have to get rid of the
category idea here.
This is going to be patched and category here.
Don't try this.
Now am I now work.
All right.
And update here
is are we missing something.
Here we go.
So I think this is done right here.
Pretty cool stuff.
And the next one here should be a form to delete it.
Oops.
Why did I do.
We go.
OK.
Just double checking because I did something with my editor.
Oh guys make sure that you make your comments OK.
You get stuff working like this.
Make sure that it is working actually.
That's just right some of stuff there it's working.
Make sure that you write your comments OK.
As a matter of fact let's just do a real quick get and get comment and able to create categories.
All right.
Let's go back to it.
And this is looking good.
Let's go to the controller real quick in I mean categories controller we don't need the screen mentally
here
at it right here.
All right.
The gory fine or fail
.
Then we're going to return.
There was a stray
.
You see how easy this starts getting guys.
OK.
Now let's actually put a link somewhere here so we can go to that page when we click on this.
So let's go to in it's and ride on the I guess it title is fine.
What or link
to use our favor function route
men
categories.
We get the idea.
All right
.
Why did I do here.
I mean
we've misspelled it right here.
All right cool.
There we go.
Pretty cool.
Even It even looks good because we have the same thing on that page the same title and the form and
it looks like it doesn't even go so anywhere else.
All right.
Good stuff.
Let's do that right away.
All right.
So let's go back to it
right here.
We're going to the form
and delete.
Let's do this drawing
not post Category 2 that all danger
and that's about it.
Let's check it out real quick.
Let's see we have an arrow here somewhere
else.
It's just we're
let's see something here quick.
Take that off.
Come back here.
Yeah that's the one creating the problem.
And let's just see.
Oh ok I see.
We know change this
categories controller.
Here we go
again.
I mean categories control destroy
method delete.
What am I doing here.
Can see
gosh
problem right here.
Couldn't see things like this can actually mess everything up for you.
All right cool.
So it works.
Now we got this little thing here.
We could make it however part of this or that of a form here so
we could let's do this real quick and see if we can just play see here
and there we go.
Then all we could do in this case is do the same thing with it on the other one.
Call us cits and let's do that here
.
It's of course we had to being say here.
All right.
Let's check it out real quick.
There we go.
It looks a little better right.
But instead of create pull Swisher's say delete those.
All right.
And now pulls.
Category.
All right.
So let's take this functionality to that means controller and right here is going to grab the category
and delete it
or fail.
And this time we can do this and we don't have to worry about pictures right.
All right.
Crea wrecked.
Guys you can do your flashing if you like.
All right.
It just makes sense but I'm going to do that like an extra lectures.
All right so let's see the categories here.
I wanted to lead this guy.
Well this this one here done.
All right so now we got an update.
We got to create the update functionality.
All right cool.
So let's go back to our means controller admin category's controller and right here we are going to
be creating that functionality.
So we're going to say category.
As a matter of fact we can just do it like this category find or fail.
OK.
Super simple stuff right.
And we can just go ahead and write it do it from here.
Fine.
Fail this I.D..
And this just of data right here.
Why waste any time right.
Let me see we can.
I don't like to have it in the same line like this.
Let's do it right here.
So that way.
OK.
All right.
All right cool.
Redirect.
Let's actually make sure that we return it.
All right.
And we're going to go to admin categories right.
I think that would work.
Well let's check it out real quick.
All right let's go to all categories here.
Let's update this one.
And as you can see is working Java.
We add an s and it's working.
Beautiful guys.
If you were able to do that.
Great job.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.