All right.
Welcome back my dear student.
So when this lecture here we're going to create some security for admin all right or admin users should
have a security for this page.
Or I only add me users are logged in only users are logged in.
And would a roll of admin and active should be allowed in here.
All right.
So we have an admin that is not active is not going to be allowed either.
So if it's not if is that the reason I mean is Shrader not going in.
All right.
So the first part of this is one thing that I want you to actually notice here is that every time we
of day our records you can see that these changes and different from here you see that 30 seconds ago
three hours ago.
So it's pretty cool stuff right.
Carbon makes this really nice.
There's a whole bunch of the documentation with carbon So that's the cloud that deals with data.
By the way.
All right.
So let's go and play around with this a little bit and let's create a middleware.
Let's register it and let's create a route group.
All right.
A lot of stuff right.
Geez how are we going to have a lot of fun right guys.
Really good fun.
So it's Fiore's and make what does it matter where you go.
Sometimes I ask myself a question and answer me.
I don't think that's crazy.
Some people think is a little weird.
I don't worry about it.
It's OK.
So this areason make middleware and we're going to call this guy admin.
Really good stuff.
All right.
I hope you're awake and not falling asleep.
I don't like that in my class so if you are falling asleep go either get arrests or get some coffee
.
All right.
So middleware admin.
There we go.
All right.
Before we do these guys this is a really good time to do some version control.
So let's actually do it right now before we do anything else.
Let's do get ADD.
We're going to add every day when I say get to it.
So let's make a comment real quick and we're going to say what do we have done here.
Well we got the users working 100 percent right with everything except security.
So
users section working 100 percent minus of security.
OK.
Let's say that we go
now we know that if anything happens after this we can roll back to where this was working 100 percent
.
But the only thing that was missing was security.
OK.
All right good stuff.
So now that we have a middle where Let's play around with it a little bit.
Let's register first and let's go to our colonel
and let's name it admin and we know that it is an app HTB controllers and he's on middleware actually
.
See Actually no it's not on controllers.
Whoops isn't middleware.
And then the name is admin.
No it doesn't have that class.
Ok cool.
Whoops.
What am I doing.
What did I do wrong here.
I don't see it or are missing the arrow arrow here.
All right cool.
Now once we have this we can go and create a raúl group here.
So let's say around group actually is not groud is group like this.
We go create an array for the middleware.
OK we tell it which made to where we want and we want which one the admin middleware of course create
a second parameter here would be a function.
And
there we go
starting to look better now.
Right guys really good.
All right.
So we're got to leave it like this.
Now we did our quite a bit in this lecture and on the next lecture we're going to continue with this
and we're going to have a lot more fun.
Right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture.