All right welcome back my students so now that we have initialized.
Good.
It's time for us to start using.
All right.
So let's get to it.
Let's go to our terminal and make sure that you are inside that folder OK.
All right cool.
So the first thing that you could learn though I want you to Larry's guest status.
This is going to tell us everything we're going to use this command a lot.
It's just going to let us know what's going on.
All right.
So let's say for example we let's drop this in brackets.
I think I have brackets somewhere here.
Let me see brackets we go.
Let's drop this in there.
All right.
As you can see there is nothing here but he fired a file.
I'm going to use touch in this case the mail.
You can see that he did follow there.
All right.
If I had that and I say status it says that we have an on track file.
That's what he's telling us.
Let's go ahead and add something to this file that's double click it.
And this is the reason why I'm using brackets here is because this is a very simple lecture a couple
of simple lectures.
I don't want to you know open BHB storm and have it have all their files there because when you open
PSAP store and when you try to do something like this is going to ask them all their files in there
.
I don't wonder I want everything to be very clear for you.
So we are using a very simple editor like brackets or we can use no bad or any other type of editor
out there.
It doesn't have to be BHB storm OK.
All right.
So we're going to add something here we're going to add the key word.
Hello I'm going to save the file and if we go back to guess status is not going to let us know anything
else.
He's just let Keep letting us us and letting us know that he's on track he's not being tracked.
Remember that the job of good is actually to keep track of your files.
So if you at a lecture like let's imagine for a second this is an application and we added let's say
let's just do it right here at it first let's add a feature 1 one 2 application.
All right.
Let's say we do this and we add this feature to our application.
But we want it to track because we're going to keep adding features.
And maybe one day we're going to have something that's going to fail and we want to come back to that
specific time where application was working.
We can do where we store.
All right.
We can do a rollback.
Right.
So let's see.
This is called good as and let's just clear this away.
Well you can see it clearly.
We're going to do good add in the name of the file.
Or if you want to add everything in that Arek three you put it up.
All right so I'm going to do a job because I don't have any other files.
Most of the time you went out all your files.
So you do that die anyway.
So now if you say good status you can see that it says new file in green.
Right.
In that age the e-mail.
All right.
So now we're keeping track of that.
So if I if I do anything here if I even put a space and put a dot in save it and I do just that.
Now it says that I modified that file and now we got two versions of when our first insert of the file
.
All right.
And now when I mortify does that's how he keeps track.
So now if I would get comment
and get comment is a command that he's going to record that specific time.
All right.
Specific time when I added the first when I first saved a file which is this one here.
I know this can be very confusing.
First played is going to be become very clear.
The more you do it.
All right of course.
So we're going to say good commed with a little flack here with I am and flag to same message.
Right.
And we're going to say it feature or feature one.
Enter.
All right.
As you can see one file change first this has being a first comment.
Now if you do a good log you can see all your comments there.
A new age committee is going to have a identifier.
This is how we go back in time and say listen I want to go back to this where my kamay was this number
and we're going to see that later on but this is just a little crass lecture here OK.
All right.
So now if I do get started is I still see that all the time where I added this dot when I say my file
remember that because I got it first does and you can go back in time in the video you can rewind it
.
I first added this added feature one up to application and I saved it and then later I added a dot.
So now this comment here will be for the DOT So if I go like this get Let's at it first.
All right good ad there we go.
And now let's do a comment on it.
Dot to sentence in feature one or something like that.
All right.
Enter now with two guests that is not in there right.
We get we do get Glaude.
And as you can see we have two recordings now.
All right.
Now remember this is that crash little lecture.
We're going to keep doing this a couple of times over and over with different commands so that where
you can get a better idea you can get very good audio OK.
You don't need to be a on a yet later on you will become one.
All.
All right.
So cool let's say for example I want to go back to where this dad was in there.
How can I do that.
Well we go back to the first one.
Because right now this is the latest one this is with a dot and if we go by that we need to go back
to this one this is the one that did not have the dot.
So to go back we do get reset Haar and I will explain to you what we said does.
This is a soft reset without the flag this with the heart.
It's the hard reset.
This means that we're going to race everything we're going to raise the command.
We've got to make sure we're going to risk everything to that point in time.
So now if I do this this command will not be available anymore.
But if I do the self reset the commit when I'll be there.
But that changes would still be available or I don't know if I may explain it later on.
We're going to we're going to do this a couple of times you're going to see.
All right.
So anyway let's do this thing actually restudy.
Let's just base it again because I think instead of there enter and now you see you saw that actually
that first command did not have anything on a just how they were hello and nice.
Actually I put it put in the wrong information.
I should have put the word hello so good log.
Whoops there we go.
So instead of this it should have been done when they had the key word Hello.
All right.
So now as you can see there we went back in time to where we were how this file with the word Hello
.
All right.
So anyway I hope we get a really good idea of what it is and we're going to keep doing this a couple
of more times and then we're going to take it to get up and show you how to push this to a place on
line where you can share it with other people.
And let's say you have a really good project and you want to share it.
You will be able to do it.
All right.
So it's going to be pretty cool actually.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lectures.