All right.
So in the last lecture I challenge you to find out how we pass data right how we pass parameters to
our controller and hit this in this in this method and it's all right remember that we already did some
of this in route's So we say that if we put.
I show you how to put a force last year and type in the curly brackets and some type of variable here
right.
So you might be asking Sosa how in the world do I take you there.
Right.
And then you go then you probably went to here and you say ID.
So he's working the number.
Is
that right.
And then you came here and you did this and blah.
And he's working right.
I hope he did that.
If not don't worry about it.
I just showed you how to do it right.
You did a good job if you did it that way.
Now don't worry about it.
All right this is super simple stuff for me because I've been doing it for you know for a long time
.
But if you're new to Lara Bell is very very very understandable if you weren't able to do that.
All right.
That's not something I expect you to do.
I just wanted to challenge you.
But if you did it you got to learn this really well and you're going to do fantastic if you deny not
you're still going to do fantastic because I'm going to help you out right.
So don't worry about that.
Let's go to route again.
And as you can see here you might be wondering how in the world does it know that he has to pass this
.
Don't we need to function.
Don't we need a function.
Well we already have a function.
If you go to post controller we have the in that function this is going to take everything that comes
from the you are l right here.
All right.
So we could keep taking IDs here if we wanted to keep taking variables.
So that's how we pass information.
All right.
That's one of the ways that we can pass information.
We can also pass information remember that we can go back to routes and do that that closure function
and returned the ID from here in that closed closure function from routes as a metaphor.
We did it right here right.
All right.
So now on the next lecture I'm going to show you how to make a special type of controller.
A controller with a resource a router with a resource is going to be pretty fun so stay tuned for that
.
Take care