All right welcome back Amanda stood and so in this lecture here we're going to be playing her a little
bit with route's right.
So we've got admin you're working with.
That's fine it's working is giving us the.
But I got a feeling that I know what it is.
But let's try to start from the beginning with the routes.
All right we have a group here middleware group.
So let's let's actually do that.
Let's create that group.
Let's copy this.
Why don't we just copy it.
All right let's just copy this group here and let's call back here.
And OK we got two oddments you a deadly one.
All right.
So let's try that.
Let's see what happens.
All right.
And I'm going arrow by Arrow because I want you guys to understand this.
You know what the problem is so that you can double your application better when you're doing these
upgrades.
All right.
So we get that and we know that fits in a minute but we go to outman it redirects us back so it looks
like our middleware is working.
All right and we get back there but what we need to do here is return the view for welcome right.
So let's say welcome.
All right.
It looks like his work welcome here.
So one reason we always left like that but let's go back here.
All right cool.
Logan page does not exist.
OK.
That's fine.
We'll fix that.
So what else.
One thing that I wanted to show you here is let's go to BHB routes to the routes.
So let's go to Beechfield is send
out a list.
Let's do this.
And OK we have a problem here.
We can see the route less because we need to take care of this guy right here and this guy that trade
is founding.
Let's see if I remember who
HTP controllers in the controller.
BHB.
There we go.
All right.
Let's take that out.
This is one thing that we have to take our I think fire.
I saw this somewhere in the documentation.
Let's do this again.
BHB artisan I mean route list.
And there we go.
All right.
So this is going to shaughs our routes.
I immediately see something that I don't like and I just going to cause a little bit of trouble with
us is that our admin routes usually.
They were supposed to be I mean categories that store in categories that create suppose to have the
admin in front of a dozen.
So he's omitting the first value here of this string right here is omitting all of this in your eye
.
So now what we need to do is we need to fix this because if not this is not going to work right.
So how do we fix this was.
Well we we've got to go and create.
Now the good thing about Florida before I get into that is that you see now we have a problem with our
routes right.
We have a big problem because the routes are not going to work now.
The routes are different.
So remember back when resources arrive we go to views and layouts I mean Bley Let's go down another
layer.
This is a good one.
If we go here you can see that we are using a function here called route and this function is actually
routing.
This links this link to widening the users that index to the router name.
So when we can we did it this way because if we had a problem with routes in the future we wanted to
be able to change it there and make it available throughout the whole application just like this.
If we would if have created some type of route like this here we would have been a lot of trouble because
we would have to go to each of these files and change this individually.
So this is why the is so great about doing this dynamically like this.
Right.
Anyway so let's go back to the web that BHB page and here are the resources we need to start changing
takes.
All right.
We need to start making sure that these routes they take us where we want to go.
But let's go first and
all I mean you get three direct that we need to work on the slogan.
OK.
So we're going to do this.
We're going to work on this logging on the net lecture.
It's going to be pretty fun.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Bye bye.