All right welcome back my students another we are back.
It's time for us to go and try something else right.
We have instead of records into the database we have read records and now it's time for us to update
that information and then delete it so you can see how this works.
All right.
So let's actually comment this out.
Let's create a nother get requests for us or a route I get.
So we are we are going to be updating now right of date when I pass a second parameter as a closure
function.
There we go.
All right.
So now what I have to tell you is that these returns they update method of the method returns an effect
that Roe.
All right.
So if for some reason we delete a row or two rows we returned the number so we could say something like
affected or updated.
All right.
The an update.
So now we can say something like of date set of date polls set.
Title excuse me equal to updated title.
OK.
Make sure there where ID equals.
Let's put that question Marchal we combined it with the ID this array there.
And now I'm going to return
the updater variable there so that what you can see how this works right.
So now let's go to update.
I mean let's go up here.
Right.
Update and enter and you can see that we have a number there.
So that's a value right.
Let's refresh pools of data title right here.
Beautiful right.
You see how simple that is.
All right.
Lauber makes a very simple even with raw SU Oake whereis.
So even keep our information protected with his binding right here like we do MPD All right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and the next lecture I expect you to try to do it on your own
right now.
Before you jump into the next lecture which is me try to do it and then compare with my Michael to see
if you were able to do it.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture