I welcome back my students so it's time for us to add a little bit more security to our application
just a little bit more.
If you remember we have created this active status here and this is for a reason because we don't just
want to make sure that these user is logged in and he's an administrator.
We want to also make sure that he's active What if for some reason these user does something in our
application.
He's an administrator.
We can we can delete him if we wanted to but we could leave the ministry in her role and make an active
.
All right.
Not taking my will not take him out of the application right away and not take him out of the role right
away but just make sure that he's on active to do certain things with him.
We could all day that he's profiled do something and he's not able to log in while we finish updating
his stuff or do something like that right.
It's just more security a lot more control.
So the way we do that is we go back to a user and the hearing where he says is admin We also want to
make sure that it is he's active as well.
So we could say and the ampersand here this
is active
he calls to one worker and that's all.
So it shouldn't do anything here because we are administrator.
So let's go and try Maria.
She's an administrator too but Rico is not an administrator or he is an administrator Let's make and
not active and is giving a password just in case if we don't we haven't given it to him.
Let's go.
Let's try to in with Rico and let's see what's going on.
Whoops.
Recall this again and let's try to go to admen.
As you can see we get redirect back again and you can tell right here that Rico is an administrator
.
You can see the role he's just now active.
OK.
Now one thing that I want to do here is I want to redirect every time we log in I want to go ahead and
read right back to add me now to the home page.
So if you remember back in the lectures in the beginning lectures we talked about that and it is in
this off controller you see the redirect property here goes to the root.
So that's why you can't miss the lectures.
You see I just showed you or reminded you of something new.
Right or different.
All right.
So now this should be good now.
Listen again with Edwin
and now we are logging into Outman.
All right now we are we will of course attack this dashboard later in the future where we have a lot
more information and a lot more features in our application that way we can either display them here
or do some type of settings here.
OK.
Well now we don't have much features that we need to you know incorporate any dash dashboard right now
.
So cool Riego now active let's make them active.
Ok cool.
All right.
So that's one way of implementing a little bit more security to our application.
Take care and see you in the next lecture