All right.
Welcome back my dear student.
So on this lecture you we're going to start up the form to create porks.
All right we've got to learn a lot in this lecture guys or this couple lectures because it's going to
really take a couple of lectures since we have a lot of feels right for a forum so let's go ahead and
start this.
Let's go to our create right here and let's just create the form and we go of course we're going to
go to the store and we already have it almost complete it.
I mean post controller that's it.
So what is the first thing that we have here.
All right we've got to look at our migration real quick and
we go now we can look at this.
All right.
So we got the user id we get to get that when we submit a post from my logged in user so we're going
to get this with a relationship.
We don't need to worry about that category we don't need to worry about it now.
We're going to have a relationship for that as well.
But all this feels need to be they all need to be imports or this category needs to be an input for
all and has to be an input title embody.
All right.
So let me actually put this away somewhere so he can guide me right.
That way I don't forget one of those fields so let's go to that create is actually take all these A
here that we don't need for now.
All right cool.
So we got title that's going to be the first thing for post.
What else category should be that second one or should be the input.
All right.
Let's say it's field and
let's just make this category here let's do a little different than the users category Heidi.
OK.
And this is going to be a select.
All right.
Of course we're going to have an array there.
For now we're just going to do options.
All right.
Geez I don't like this indentation That's field.
Let's do this a little bit there and let's
we've got to fix this in our live template so that way comes out straight.
Let's go to a live template form.
This just fits that there
.
Whoops
that's OK one more for that
.
This should be all the way in the wall
and this should be a little bit more than let's say there was too much.
All right I think that's better though.
OK.
All right.
So category 80.
This one needs to be there file
and for file we don't have any.
Whoops.
Any of that what else is there.
It's field here.
All right.
Still coming up a little bit.
Not 100 percent but Wolf I think I have to restart my editor have to check on that.
All right so we have a file now the next step is the search area.
Actually I think we have a method for that area
and that would be body right here.
Scription and we're going to pass in another review.
I don't know if I show you how to do this right here.
This third parameter is four attributes and it's going to be rose and we're going to pass it three rows
.
I think there's a good size.
All right.
So this only is tied or this should be what we have in the database actually or ID is for the photo
for the radio.
It's taking form.
All right let's double check.
We've got a title category photo embody.
All right let's now check our application
.
It looks like this one is of classes being applied that doesn't need
to know.
Here let's see.
Now
let's take a class out
one second guys.
For some reason this is this is not working here that's weird.
I'm missing something here.
Let's make sure that this has the files shrewed here and I'm pretty sure he's not there.
All right.
But it's there other classes now working there.
I'm almost certain that this is.
This is correct here.
If we take a look at the create for users maybe I've been coding too much and I don't see it.
You can see that that's almost the same thing here.
Should it matter that.
No they're
going to pay Saray here almost exactly the same on less.
It doesn't have that.
No there.
That's weird.
I'll leave it like that if it doesn't work.
Yes we are we getting this.
I remember it now like this color but that's I guess that's the way it's working right now.
That's weird.
I don't like it.
Let's go and check it out.
It is not the class is now being applied.
You see that
is not being applied to the import
.
Anyway we'll figure that out later and I will let you know how to fix that.
But right now for some reason this is not working here.
If we go to users create users.
Oh it's now working on users either.
So we never got that working.
I was working I think Bush has a better functionality for this.
I got to figure it out and I will always come back and let you guys know.
But right now we have come very far with the Create paused and actually I think we should make this
bigger this tetes area.
So let's take these roles out of you out of there and it's come back to it.
And there we go.
OK.
Pretty cool stuff.
All right so we got to have categories so you can have a photo and a title for it.
Beautiful.
So the next lecture are going to continue with as it is.
When I come up with a solution for this little class thing I will let you know.
Thank you so much.
See you then.
Bye bye.