All right welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to start inserting data into the database using eloquent which is pretty cool sold
or stands for object relational mapper.
I might say something different sometimes I quote a manager or mapping or something like that.
Yes.
You know if you guys want the real definition just Google.
OK.
But anyway so we are retrieving data.
All right well one which is pretty cool using the word mad.
Their first fail just to make sure that we find the first one if not we throw an exception right.
It's time for us to start using eloquent to insert data.
Let me show you how easy this is.
And the fighting make a comment make sure that you do OK.
I think I made a comment right here but you should make a comment for every functionality so if you're
going to read data find data make a comment for OK.
All right so let's create a route.
Real quick.
And this rally is going to be for inserting right.
So let's just give it a different name basic insert just a basic insert.
OK.
All right.
And let's get up into the closure function here.
Beautiful.
So for a basic insert all we have to do is call the the actually instantiate this cell we're going to
see a post and we can say something like this new post.
That's it.
Right now we access each property or each column in our table like this.
So if I want an update or now all day I want to insert something for the title.
All I do is get the property out and assign a value to the new or am title or something like that.
OK.
Well you could you say eloquent eloquent title insert and then for the content we just do content and
we'll say wow eloquent is really cool.
Look at this content to get there.
And then if I wouldn't just save it all I have to do is this safe or inserted right this save me the
will insert the wrecker.
All right.
And we'll also update it if you need to update it.
So you see it live with the way it is.
Let's go to the browser real quick
and right here which is a basic It's basic insert enter.
All right cool.
Let's go to the Peachtree my admin refresh.
And we have actually inserted a record.
All right.
So this this this is going to insert it.
Now if you notice that
this also what it did was that it also created it created at an all day they add stems.
Now if you want to use a Save method as to update what you need to do is first you need to find find
the record you want right.
You find the record you want and then you can use the same method to update it.
All right
if you want we can do this right now and that's all.
Let's actually do a real quick so that where you can see I'm just going to copy OK so that way we do
this Fahs and we're going to find a record actually let's leave it like that's fine.
We don't need a new we don't need to instantiate it.
This is a static method the Rykes will find.
We find that and I think we have you've got to look at your your your database table to see what views
you have.
So we got this wrong too.
Let's update this one since this all has a small title right.
So we're going to find number two and I'm going to change this to say new eloquent title.
Insert number two.
And the Konting number two.
OK.
So now if I go to basic answer I'm going to put a number two here that way different come here and then
I see the basic answer Number Two answer
leads to two to go refresh.
And as you can see number two has been updated.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff.
Now we can also use the update method.
We'll do that and then the next lecture.
OK.
Is going to be a pretty fast lecture.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture guys.
Very good job if you're following me.
Take care