All right so when the last lecture I mentioned something about resource right around resource controller
resource.
What the heck is that.
Well right what is that right.
Well is this a special static function like get.
All right.
That will give us access to automatically two different types of routes.
That we can use in our controller and I'll show you right now how that works.
So I'm going to come in this hour real quick and I'm going to call this special method called resource
.
All right.
So
resource will help us very simply by creating special routes for us that we can use in the controller
sort of.
Let me give you an example.
So let's say I want to create everything polls.
I'm going to write it down.
Fluoro and I'm going to say pose controller
troller.
I don't have to type in the method anymore because I'm not just sending requests for the method and
it's sending a request for Create of they delete destroy all that stuff right here.
All right re update creating delete or destroy are already here.
So let me show you right now.
So if I go to my little terminal right here and I type in THP artists and you can do this in the regular
terminal remember guys and I say route Kallen list enter logo is
with that route that I gave in the first parameter of the method pose he created for me some name routes
already polls that in this that store.
So it created all this resources for me.
These names automatically.
What that does for me is that not only does it create the names but it also creates the methods in which
there are sent.
So we can see that this post created a send as I get requests.
Right.
Because we don't have any information we send in data for this wonderful post that is strongly.
All right.
We are sending some type of ID these get Same with a method that the leading method that special in
Claribel right is very secure.
Another one is tools for Slash post update for updating.
We send that as a put or patch.
We talk a little bit about that later in the course how we use this patch.
This one is saying as I get to show and this only sends does it get to edit.
All right.
So let me show you real quick.
So now if let's say I want to see something right I want to be able to see I'm going to use polls in
my in my view or L polls for us last idea or something might show you that.
So let's go to the controller and let's go to the I meant the show right here.
So you can go into a return.
This is this show meant that Yay yea now I'm always exaggerating with my words right.
All right.
So we can see that it is showing an I.D. there.
And if we go to that show right here we see that it does have an I.D. right.
So we have to type it in like that right here.
So enter it doesn't find it.
OK.
That's because
that's fine though.
Real quick.
That's because we're now using that I.D. right here.
So let's use that.
There we go.
PPOs actually is because I wasn't in spudding right.
Enter.
All right.
And not only that but we are also passing the I.D. I wasn't putting it correctly before.
So I hope you see that.
Now if we want to access let's say another method let's call it the method create.
All right.
We can go to the Met to create and just giving giving you an example and we get every turn.
I am the method that creates stuff.
All right.
So now if I go in there you are able and I say pose for Slash create enter.
You can see that that the I guess return.
So what we did was with the resource is that we were able to create all this you are well.
All right parameters for us automatically with our methods that the data gets sent with not only that
but we also have name routes so we could use his name routes in whatever we want our application we
can use it in a link to say in listening user.
If you go to polls that in it's one you are going to go to this part of my application.
Hey user if you go to post that create I want to send you to this part of my web site or application
which is going to allow you to create a user or a post in the form.
All right.
So we without resource we get all this action our name routes I you or I in our methods that the data
that data gets sent.
So this right here this post astore we get post data right here.
All right.
So if a user types in goes to post all right automatically we can create some type of page there that
will send a post request to our database to ask for information or to even input information in our
database.
A super secure.
All right we're going to see that in the application that we will be building later on.
I just want to you do have some really good information on what you know we can do we're resource in
how we communicate it to our polls to our control methods here.
OK I hope you have a really good idea on why they are.
You can go ahead and try the edit.
Will they all the same as long as you follow this convention.
If you don't follow the convention that is here.
It's not going to work for you.
Make sure that you follow this you or I hear all of this.
Here you are else here have an idea after the after the four slash.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.