All right welcome back my students on the last lecture we didn't get done.
A lot of a lot.
Because I want to make these lectures short shorts or short.
OK.
I said it correctly guys my English is getting worse by the minute anyway.
So what we're going to be doing in this lecture is going to be doing a lot more than what we did in
the last one.
But just to give you some information we can actually make the logging views.
All right.
We're going to do that little make Auth. BHB Ortiz in command and we're going to create that because
I like to see something already right.
I know you would like to see something created.
And so we're going to take care of that so let's do that right now.
BHB Ortiz and make off.
All right.
Let's see if we get our application working already because we just want to see something going right
.
All right.
We can see that our application is already taking form.
We can register users right out the gate right now.
All right cool.
All right.
So now let's talk about what we're going to be doing for for this application a little bit more in depth
.
So let's actually open up our resources views we're going to have a couple of folders.
Right.
And it's actually synchronizes.
There we go.
We've got we're going to have a couple of four days besides this four days that we already have.
I think we should put Adam in a separate folder all the admin stuff in one separate folder.
We don't have to.
We can actually use middleware to actually prevent users from going into those folders so we don't have
to really create an admin folder and block everybody from there we don't have to do that with Clarabell
.
Gay is a simple as actually creating a middleware and preventing the user from going to different sections
of our application.
So creating an admin folder Users folder or inside the admin ampoules for their entire admin maybe creating
a subscriber for there and a alter for them.
How about that.
All right why don't we just do that right now.
Real quick.
All right let's just create a couple of folders just to get things going.
And as a matter of fact and going I'm going to start with admin.
That's for that that we're going to be starting with.
So I mean is going to have an end it's of course Gladman.
We're going to have users folder and users for that is going to have an index.
All right.
So we're going to take a little bit further and we can have a pulse and we can also have categories
.
All right so we can say categories and it's all right.
So now we're going to think about this a little bit around users.
Let's start with categories and categories.
What are we going to do.
What I showed you in the demo is that in that we had we were able to create categories and we were able
to see them we can kill two birds in one shot here.
So all we really need is a netted page for this one here.
All right.
And you can make this however you want.
I just I'm just showing you a way of doing it guys.
If you can come up with a better way.
Once you finish this course you can do whatever you want right.
This is just my way for showing you for demonstrating some of the features that we have learned already
.
Some of the techniques are right.
Some polls here.
We're going to create what we're going to create to create.
And we are also going to do the edits here.
All right I told you we were going to get a little bit more done in this lecture on the last one and
users we're going to have a create page for users of course in the edit page.
We're going to start with the admin user guys then we're going to jump into altar's and then we're going
to jump into subscribers.
I want to create at least three roles so that what you guys know exactly how to do this.
All right.
And and that's why he's at it.
Beautiful.
I think we should we have enough to start.
All right.
We got to work really hard on admin right now because on admin We need to attack the users.
How do we attack him but I mean we need to attack the U.S. we need to do this section really good.
We need to make sure that users can be created for madmen.
We can we've got to make sure that they can be edited.
We've got to be able to view them right and give them access to different parts of our application.
So we've got to do a lot of work here first on users before we can move on to the rest of the application
.
All right.
All right cool.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture