All right welcome back muddiest student I hope you're really excited on this lecture here.
We're going to be learning how to add columns to our tables are already created.
So for example you already have a migration right.
And you know you don't want to really go back and say you know I'm going to drop the whole table in
day and edit it and read you know re migrated again because you have some data already that you don't
want to delete.
Right you don't want to delete the polls.
You have 20 30 40 50 pausa rating you application and you don't want to go ahead and do that.
Delete it right.
Well you can add a column without interrupting your data that you already have which is pretty cool
.
So I'm going to clear my terminal here and I'm going to run the command.
Right to create a new migration to add a table.
Pretty cool.
So BHB artisan.
All right migrate actually make migration.
And then all right we write that what we wanted to add let's say what we want and we want to add a is
adamantium or something and is adding in column or something like that.
All right.
You want to write something like this or something descriptive or write is adding call in to tables
to post table something like that.
All right.
And then here you get it create a flag that's called Table because you want to reference the table that
you're using.
I'm going to put a little symbol some quotes around it if you want.
And now I'm working with a post table.
All right.
Now you click enter.
Now you created that migration.
And of course it's going to take a couple of seconds of mine.
Now you're also able to do it I believe without the quotes like this.
I think I've tested this before and it works.
So you're welcome to try with other quotes if you want.
Right.
You can try whatever you want as long as it works for you.
So I've got to figure out why mine Id taken a long time to produce this.
All right.
Let me see an event log and if we can refresh this if this is happening to you.
This has to be a way to refresh to synchronize the table
synchronize migrations.
There we go.
Synchronize would do it right away.
All right.
Cool.
So let's double click this.
And now we can see that we have that this schema here that instead of actually creating that table is
actually is referencing the table pools.
All right.
So we have to do here is use the objects write table and we've got to add that that column.
So we're not are adding a column to our table.
Right.
And we're going to say is admen.
All right.
And as a matter of fact this admin could be an integer so we can use Integer.
And we can make this on signed on signed means that it does.
It cannot be a negative number.
All right.
And if we want to drop it of course here what you need to do is you reference the referenced object
use.
This meant drop column.
There we go.
And you write the name of the column is admiring is the name of the column Antar.
Right.
So once you have this you're good to go.
Now all you have to do is migrate BHB artists and make no migrate enter.
Now this has migrated.
Now we have to go to PH be my admin and check it out.
If you're using some type of using another source
for your database that's fine or you don't have to use it to my admin you could use anything else that
you are able to see your database like I use Zeke equal Prawle as well from my Mac to look up my database
information which is pretty cool.
So anyway so let's go to Lara Bell database U-Mass and you can see right here we go to polls structure
.
You can see that there is admin Karlo has being added as an integer of 10 by default.
It's going to give you a limit on how big it is how big this is.
Right.
So if I wanted to let's go back and let's use run a command here and the going BHB artist and migrate
Roback I'm going to roll that back answer.
This has been rolled back so he's not longer there.
So what I'm going to do is I want this to be a default of two values.
All right.
So now if I press my key and you can see that I'm doing things down here.
All right I'm going to migrate again.
Antar
see.
Let's see something.
Let's see if it migrated again.
All right.
It does not migrate.
I think I misspelled this.
Let's just clear it real quick.
Let's see what I did wrong here huh.
OK.
All we can do this.
Default and we can put let's say a zero here.
All right.
Or we can make this a tiny
tiny tiny.
If you forget this values here I'm going to show you a way to find that to find it in your Clarabell
.
All right so we're going to go to Claribel dot com and we're going to find this migration stuff.
All right documentation migration.
Delicious food values.
Let's see if we can find the like this really quick
creating or editing.
I think it says is the right thing.
Right here you see that and it's supposed to have a list.
There we go.
So if you go to tiny integer tiny quickly see that.
So this is a tiny integer.
This is what we want.
And this is all in numbers here.
So we can go back call these guy tiny and like this.
All right now where you can go and say My great artist and and refresh it.
And now you can see that tiny int with a value of four.
So that's a tiny value for a tiny integer.
There is another one called Tiny int.
But anyway you can see that you can go to Larabee all that come and find all that information which
is really good.
All right.
So you had to do that already.
Everything is in the documentation guys remember that.
Anyway thank you so much for watching.
OK.
On the next lecture I'm going to show you some extra stuff with migrations but we're almost done.
We've got to learn a lot.
A whole bunch.
And when we're building our application so keep tuned for that.
Keep enjoying Claribel is really cool.
And I'll see you next lectures