All right.
Welcome back.
My students so we learn how to do a basic insert.
All right.
Now it's time for us to learn how to create data and features the function idea that I'm going to show
you right now works very good with forms and with forms.
When you're doing forms you want to use a create method.
OK.
So I going to copy and paste and just going to select this and comment it out and I'll show you right
now how easy it is.
So and I want to show you this way because when you are creating data there is something called a mass
assignment operation that goes on and allowable prevents multiple records from being all dated.
I mean create it at the same time unless you specify it in the model and I'm going to show you in a
minute how we let Clarabell know that it's OK to assign values to create new values for multiple columns
.
OK.
Out of the body would not let you do that.
So unless you do what I'm about to show you in a couple of seconds it won't allow you or any application
to create data in your application in multiple columns or tables.
All right.
So let's do this get.
And I'm going to call this create function and it's a post.
And now the matter is create like this.
Now they create method is going to take an array array of associative an associate of array.
So if we want to have the the title we go like this title and we updated BHB and create method or something
like that.
Now the content
content.
Wow I'm learning.
Whoops you had escaped this.
I sure do.
You can skip it like this.
I'm just going to like this.
I'm learning a lot with BHP with Edwin.
OK.
Let's just keep it real quick.
This is the Coomer right there.
And this was whoops gosh we go this you scape it right there.
All right.
Wow.
I'm learning a lot with Edwin.
Yes.
There we go.
So now let's go to that create your echo and we should see something going on there.
Now I'll show you right now let's just call.
Come here.
Let's just take all these out and do create enter mass assignment at ception.
You see that it doesn't allow you to put data in there.
Period.
Unless you let it know that it's safe to do so.
So how do we do it.
Well let's go and let me show you those thing even if it's a q it doesn't go here and do anything refresh
we still have the same right title and I have a different title because I play around with my courses
and they're like lectures before I publish it sometimes and I might do different things.
So if you see that my title and content are not the same as yours don't worry about it.
Sometimes I I'll make a lecture I make a mistake and I read do it again.
All right so anyway so the important thing here is that we're going to learn how to do the math assignment
.
So let's go to a post model right here which is the one that controls the database.
You know call is a mad thing all that really cool stuff that we get from the model right.
This is every time you write something here he's going to override what we have in the parent.
So let's come here and write unprotected fillable property.
Right now these fillable property is available in the model somewhere right.
But right now we're going to assign it assign a value to it.
So right now what we're going to be doing is actually this is an array like this.
OK.
We bring it down and now we write each key so it's safe for the title.
And we safe for content to be updated.
OK.
Now if we go in and try to do this now you know
by there we go answer why law.
Now we are able to create something.
So let's just go back to Peachi my admin refresh.
And now you can see that we have a new record here.
They create method.
Wow I'm learning a lot with Edwin Diaz and we escaped that single core so that what we have here as
well as our as well as our Stamm time stamps.
OK.
Beautiful.
All right.
So remember we come here sometimes to allow certain data to be inserted into our application to create
men that solve it later on we're going to talk a little bit about that and I got to get into it right
now.
But I almost did.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll talk to you and see you in the next one
.
Take care