All right welcome back my students on this lecture here we're going to learn how to delete using polymorphic
relation.
All right cool.
All right.
Why do I keep writing this instead of copy and pasting guys.
Come on I told you that because we want to get used to writing it so that way is in our heads and when
we go to sleep we dream about this stuff and when we wake up we have new ideas on what programs we can
create.
All right.
Like I have a really good idea and I to tell you because you know you might take my idea and become
a billionaire but you know we can talk about it.
So anyway we're going to find this to have the first staff member right.
And you know if we find him we've got to say and right here let's just say if we find them.
All right we're going to allow these photos and use the method here for this and they need it.
That's what we've got to do right now.
We find this guy because he hasn't paid the bills.
And if we find all his forces we're going to lead it.
All right.
Now you can also remember that you can also do something like this.
You can find his photos where we're name something equals bad food or something.
All right.
GBG you can do this stuff like this if you want of course is more is more.
Come into the where ID.
OK.
So let's check to check it out real quick.
All right.
Polymorphic the.
We need more data.
Enter refresh.
That is the only picture we had that's why we need data.
Right right right.
So we're done with this one here and let's see if on the next lecture's I can show you some more tricks
.
Thank you so much and I'll see you then.
Bye bye.