All right welcome back my students.
So we have finish setting up zap we have finished setting up an editor composer good.
We even create a new project and set up some virtual holds.
We're doing very good.
Now it's time for us to wopping our project.
See how it looks inside right now.
We're going to finish this section here because this is the section of doing this with Windows I'm going
about to jump in a section where we can do it with a Macintosh.
All right.
So I just want to see I want you to see how we can do this how we can open this project using BHB storm
or any other order to Ed..
It's super easy right.
So let's click on whatever editor you're using.
Right.
And then I don't want to import anything.
So I'm going to click OK and I'm going to evaluate this for 30 days and go into a set.
All right this is for PHP storm right after we create this app I create this video and I'll show you
how this is done.
Then if you using a Macintosh or whatever other computer everything would be the same.
All right.
I just want the Windows users to you know set everything up so that when I jump into a Macintosh there
is no problem everything will be the same.
All right.
So I'm going to click OK and then I'm going to click open and then I'm going to look for that project
or write in whatever that directory I put it on.
So isn't zap HD docs and see a mess.
I am going to click OK super easy right.
All right.
That's it.
The projects here and we can start our we can jump into any operating system any computer as long as
we have this and everything will be the same.
All right.
What I mean with everything being the same is that now if I switch to a Macintosh and I open Pietsch
be still in there and I open the project we can start working on our application and everything else
that I do here will be where we apply to Windows computer as well.
All right so now that you know how to do this how to install this in a Windows computer.
I'm going to go and help our Macintosh users in the next section and started doing this in Mac.
All right.
But if anything happens if anything is a little different in a Macintosh I would let Windows users know
immediately.
All right.
So don't worry about that.
We are doing very good.
You can.
You're welcome to explore the documents here.
But in the lectures after this in the section where we start inspecting our files I will start explaining
it.
All right.
So for those Windows users you can jump the whole section of Macintosh if you like and you can start
the project on the next section with me.
All right.
Well you're also welcome to watch how he's done in a Macintosh so that way you can still have that knowledge
just in case in the future you have a Macintosh.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture