All right welcome back my sister.
And so sad for us to find out how to read tree authenticate a user's information or identikit it you
know applications right.
All right so cool.
Let's go to our home view here.
I want you to see something here.
This view here would not be available unless you are logged in.
How.
If you go back to your home controller OK we have this thing called middleware in the constructor meaning
that this is going to be activated.
All right throughout this home controller that means that every method is inside this home controller
would be protected by the middleware or unless you are authenticating it would not allow you to proceed
.
All right.
So I'm logged into my application right now I can easily go to Forest last home.
Whoops right here.
You can see that right.
But if I'm locked now and I try to go back in there.
I get redirected to Logan.
OK.
So I know that stuff.
Now let's log in real quick.
I'm logged in.
All right.
I want you to understand that we're going to go over this matter where later on but I just want you
to be aware of that.
So how do we pulao the users information.
And guys remember these routes here all right there are the fine right here.
OK that route for home.
You see the control of the route before flight home goes to one controller.
So that's where we are right here.
OK.
But anyway let's retrieve some of the users information and what I'm going to do is I'm going to access
a class called off and the method for user.
All right this is where how we ox's out indication identikit a user with its class.
So let's click on there and let's import it on top.
Make sure you importing this and make sure that you have this compact user already had it there.
But that's because I have my dog bark.
You know I had to remake the lectures so.
But anyway so compact user used to do it from scratch review.
Beautiful So we now that we're passing the user.
If we go to the home controller real quick we can use Bley right here to display the user's name so
we can say a user name ok.
Dennings should say the name of that person right.
There we go.
You are logged in.
Yes.
All right.
So that's how we retrieve the user's information.
Let's go back to Rousey here.
I'm going to come in this out and show you another way to check.
I'm going to show you a way to check the users logged in.
All right cool.
So we can say if we use is meant to check.
All right.
That's it.
Make sure that you import this on top.
All right.
So we're going to return.
The user is logged in.
All right.
Let's go to our route.
Real quick.
There we go the users logged in.
But if we log now you can see that we didn't see anything right.
Nothing.
So let's go and go to home log in again.
All right.
Whoops.
Oh and one thing about this.
Well this logging system does is that if you keep trying here over and over again is going to lock you
out for a couple of minutes.
I don't know if it was 15 minutes or five minutes the first time.
You can go to Larabee and check it out.
But they would actually count how many times you tried.
And he would lock you out.
All right.
So that's one of the cool things about this is Logan.
All right cool.
So what else let's actually try to log in a user.
All right so let's say you have a form and you are getting some values from the form.
Like maybe they username and password and you want to create this you went out A.K. that user.
All right.
So you would do something like this once you and you would put this in a model or something.
OK guys in a user might or.
OK.
All right.
So let's do this.
And this time it is the method and we can pass an array here real quick and we can say something like
if the username in the database equal to the user name you give him the form and password.
All right.
Is.
Cool.
So the past where you give it me then you're good to go.
I want you to read.
I want to redirect you.
OK.
Back to where you try to log in.
All right.
That's what we do in this piece of code here.
So we not only just the we are the user but we're giving it the same you or I.
They try to log in.
So if they were trying to go to admin for some reason before and they got redirected back of course
we don't have that route.
But if they got redirected back to log in because of that and they try to logging now they are going
to get redirected to outman the next time because that's what it's meant to doing.
And we can put a default here just in case.
All right cool.
And the reason why this is underlined like this with it has red lines because I haven't put values forward
for that yet.
So my ids letting me know hey listen these variables are empty.
See that.
So now it's for the other one we can leave user name by itself you know.
All right cool.
So that's one way of doing this.
Now you can also log at my real quick guys at the end of this section check for resources check for
links I gave you this link so you can go to the documentation.
Look at this method you can do that yourself.
So Breezer stuff and just giving you an overview of some of the methods.
But this is piece of cake.
OK.
In the project that we're going to be creating We are going to be really really really practicing the
practices stuff really we're going to really jump into the project and we're going to create something
amazing that you're going to love and that you're going to get a lot of knowledge from OK.
This is basically going over a couple of things and things that you can go into the station and do yourself
.
But this gives you an idea how he's done so when you look at the documentation is going to be easier
for you to digest.
OK.
Anyway thank you so much for watching guys.
It's been a pleasure.
And I'll see you in the next lecture