All right welcome back to the students on this lecture I'm going to show you how to create an advance
validation and I'm also going to show you how to put all this cool the hear in little snippets so that
we don't have to keep writing in writing and writing over and over and over again.
All right.
All right cool.
So right now as you know we are you know just using this value the function function idea right here
just doing it manually but we could if we wanted to create a whole class and they inject that class
right here.
The requests show you right now.
So let's see BHB areason that's when you want to know what type of commands you one type have available
.
So right now it's going to tell me that I can make all of this right here.
You see that in one of these is says requests and that's what we want.
We want to make our requests.
Pretty cool stuff right.
So we're going to say BHB areason make requests and we've got to give it a name create pose requests
.
Whoops there we go.
Enter.
OK the request has been successfully created.
Oh it doesn't say that but it says requests create a successful.
All right cool.
So where is this class now.
Well we have our requests folder.
OK.
And as you can see it's why not here because I haven't synchronized my folder so I'm just going to synchronize
it.
And while there we go.
All right cool.
So now we have this class here where we can authorize or not authorize this functionality for certain
pieces of our application.
OK right now I'm not going to worry about the rising or now rising because we've got to make this open
says we are not really creating something really advance here so I'm going to authorize to everybody
to be able to use this.
All right.
So just in case if you wanted to use this function for.
I don't know for just post then you were right there logic right here.
But we are using this for everybody.
So that's where we're going to be putting that as true.
And now this is where we type in the rules so we already have rules that we can use right.
We have a tie on and we have the content if you want to but I say that's all you got to do here and
now instead of using this requests we can use force requests.
We can say this.
Let's go and it's happening here.
Create post requests.
All right.
So you can put the whole namespace like that but if you want to pull your mouse over the HP song help
you import this all the way to the top.
OK.
So this is how you were imported all the way to the top.
You first put it where it is.
This is a namespace app HTP requests.
And then the name of that requests right here and the name of that class.
So that way you can use it here and we use it as requests.
Now if you go back to that let's see if I can find a window that we can use if we go back to see a mess
create and we try to do this again.
We still have the same functionality but there are differences that are actually as a matter of fact
let's just take this off so that way you can see it working it's commented at our actually.
Here we go.
OK.
And we go and try to do it actually went through.
Let's go back here and see where in the world just happen
.
All right let's go back to our fourth request here to our class actually.
Oh we forgot the require here.
OK we need to do this required.
OK.
Now I'm going to go and do each job.
All right.
Enter And as you can see now it works OK I'm glad that I actually went now and change that here and
took that off so that where you can see that we still needed to complete the key and values here.
All right cool.
All right.
So there you have it.
Advanced valuation guys.
Oh and I forgot to show you the.
And I was going to do then the next lecture because it's going to take me a couple of minutes to show
you how we can create some snippets and that way you don't have to keep writing over and over again
especially the form code which is a little complicated in the beginning even though you should practice
.
I'm going to show you a way to to have a shortcut.
In writing this stuff over and over again.
OK.
Anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.