All right.
Welcome back.
My student so we have our validations in place but we need to actually hook it up to our top posts or
create requests and we also need to display the errors below here somewhere.
OK.
So that's going to be our next challenge if you want to go ahead and positivity on and try to do that
yourself.
You are welcome to doing OK.
So let's go ahead and do that real quick.
We're going to say close create requests we can use it like this but we could if we wanted to employ
this on top.
All right.
And now what we got to do is we've got to go to the Form eight and include our form errors.
So let's go to our
form here.
Actually let's do this let's divide this create a rule for it.
A quick
array and create another rule here.
And we're going to see include.
And we're going to include the
Cluj dot for mirror.
OK.
Let's go now to our create refresh to submit it and we can see all the errors right here.
You can modify this and get a different name if you want to.
That's the way we have it we have our category ID on top for two ID.
We should actually make this so that way it will be or for some type of category like that if you want
you reorganize and you can live with the same way.
Actually let's go and reorganize.
Guys let's stop being lazy right.
If I don't do it you will not do it either.
All right.
So let's go to our here.
So what we want first is this title
and the second would be category then for all and the body that's it.
Now I tell you I'm going to take that feature off I swear.
There we go.
Title category photo and body.
All right so we got our validations in place.
Here we go.
All right beautiful.
So on the next thing that we got to work on.
All right.
It's updating this information in the data.
They start actually doing this right now.
So impulse control are
right in the way we're going to do this is a little bit different than what we have been doing in other
lectures because this post has an owner.
We could actually pulao the owner the use or that's love then and then update the relationship.
All right.
So we could do that because they are
actually user user that there go and come here and now we can go ahead and say user posts and update
it this way.
All right on the next lecture I want to show you how to do this.
What I want you to also think outside the box and try to do it yourself.
I want you to try to of they all these fields are right here with relationships right.
Of course we don't have a relationship or category yet.
So don't worry about down to worry about photo but try to actually update this pose and make sure that
he belongs to the user.
Try to do that and see what can you do.
All right.
You were never known to you try.
I will see you in the next lecture will we.
We are where we will compare our code and see.
They are a match.
Take care