All right welcome back my sister.
So it's time for us to learn how to lead with the many to many relationship.
Now we already know how to do this right.
It's super easy we just create a route right or route like some people call it and we just name it.
And why should we not naming it we are setting it up right here.
We're setting up get requests.
So we find the user in this case because we want to find out its relationship should do fine or fail
here.
Once we have the user we can look through it.
It's relationship roles and we can go ahead and say delete but this method right here will delete all
the relationships in the database.
So let's let's actually do it so you can see it but I'm pretty sure you already know that.
I was just playing around here returning some data.
Let's just say delete.
OK.
So I just executed that.
And let's just open another window here and open BHB my admin many to many relationship.
And we have no rules.
OK let's create one.
I'm going to go to the create method that we created or functionality I believe right now is doing subscriber
.
And if you don't have the same values don't worry about it guys.
I'm constantly changing my data.
Just worry about what you're learning right here that is more important than my data in the database
.
Enter refresh.
OK we've got two of them.
All right.
I think we executed a couple of times.
Let's just actually let's just edit this one here.
I'm going to call this author.
All right.
Cool.
So one of the leads.
Number five.
Let's go ahead and do that because the limit is not very exciting if you're deleting everything as you
can.
As you saw there we were able to delete everything from the database.
It was not in there but we don't want to do that right most of the time.
We don't want to do that.
We want to delete it where statements of what we're going to do is we're going to set up we're going
to look through it.
Whoops.
Way down there.
We're going to look through it through its rules.
We're going to set it up for a role and then once we have that let's just do or die dumb Brooke quick
can see what we get.
Oh OK.
That would be interesting right guys.
Always do like Dom's Ambar Dobson and try to find out what you have so you can do things with it.
OK so we have this object now with is of Julie King ouches its methods.
Remember that this comes from the model so we have some stuff available to us so we can do is we can
say roll where Id eat cause I believe is five.
So where ID equals five we go now the elite Watch this.
I think that's more exciting right guys.
All right girls.
All right.
Every time I say guys and girls guys I mean girls to enter with fresh and while Law is gone.
You guys scare there for a minute.
You do that I delete everything.
No we deleted them when we won it.
All right.
So remember every time you looping through this collections or raise whatever it is that has objects
inside right we can access its methods.
We have the where methods they're really mad.
This is saving all that.
And then you can do things with it.
All right.
All right cool.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lectures.