All right welcome back my students another we have our migrations right we need to migrate this.
And let's just say BHB autism I agree.
Let's just do that with migration.
In my case I have migrated everything I've been playing around with my migrations so I have no data
guys.
Oops.
Make sure you have some data.
All right.
And here we go.
Let me just create my user real quick guys.
All right you can forward the video if you want if you don't want to see me or hear me.
And Elisha's do coring faculty.
I'm going to do a really quick guys probably doesn't even get to be my e-mail or all just going to do
a really quickly does that say.
All right now let's create.
Let's pull some data for our roles so let's just create two rules and I create a rule called administrator
.
OK.
And no date stamp.
I don't we don't need that right now.
Oops I forgot we need to insert another one so insert and the other one would be subscriber.
OK there we go.
Now the user this another user right.
So we can let's call this guy what do you want to call this guy Peter.
That's a good name.
Peter and he works according faculty for him which is my web site guys remember that.
All right.
And his password is the same as mine which is a really bad idea.
It doesn't matter because it's hashed is not I'm just joking around guys.
All right.
Beautiful.
So now we got to go to we have the rules and we have the users right.
Now let's go to roll user which is a pivot table and we're going to insert some data here.
We for the user one we've got to make this guy a administrator.
OK.
And for the user to use or two we're going to meet these guys will scriber simple look there.
All right.
Because remember the rules here the subscribers know as I has identity or two.
So that's why we went to the pivot table and plays the number two in there.
All right.
Don't worry about this.
This is just the ID for the wrecker in the pivot table.
But this is why it counts right here.
OK.
Beautiful.
So now let's go back to the application.
Well is not an application yet but it's getting there right.
All right.
Now we need to define the relationship in the model right here in the role model actually in the user
.
Oops.
OK.
It was a public function and roles.
Me and we'll get no return.
This belongs to many.
We go app backslash.
Full rule.
OK.
That's beautiful isn't it.
Now everything is set up.
All right.
Now we are able to pull this information from there.
As a matter of fact I should leave it to you to actually pull it.
Super simple we have been doing it all this time.
All right.
This is super simple stuff.
So if you want to pool information you are welcome to do it.
I just paused the video and try to do it yourself.
All right.
I'm going to do it in this video.
But just pause it and try to do it.
All right so let's go to Roger real quick.
I hope you a video and try it because it's super cool and you know in a lot if you're trying to figure
that out.
So many to many relationship will create a route.
Real quick and we're going to do.
We're going to say.
All right.
When I try to pull out the user number would ID or whatever I want to pull out the roll of that out
of that user.
All right.
Beautiful.
So now here we're going to grab it.
We're going to find the user finder user number one ngi the user's roles.
You like that.
Or we can do this
right here.
Let's this tool for each.
Actually better do it this way it makes more sense user roles as role.
And now here we can say we turn.
We're just going to return one value array
actually wrong name
and there we go.
So a user wants to have an administrator role.
Let's find out how we made our application really cool right now.
Well our little function I do because we have the request in the on top and the you are l the ID requests
right.
So we could say something like user 1 all answer as you can see we get administrator but if we change
this to to enter user number 2.
Oh the reason why we are now getting that is because we are returning one value here.
And actually I'm sorry it does not it is because we didn't make our application dynamic like I thought
it was.
And we go and here now we are in business.
Answer as you can see user number two is a subscriber and the user number one is an administrator.
So we pull in the roll out of their user which is really really cool.
Now let me show you something else you can pool out there all ideas but you can also do this we can
find it.
All right.
And watch this.
We can find the rules right and we can use a method instead.
All right.
The model and you do this order by.
And you can order by name or like say whatever you want to order by id descending or something like
that whatever.
And then you can come here and do this get.
OK.
Whoops I should have left and right there for you.
And we can return the user
array or the roll right but you get my point re
look at that.
All right.
So we're returning the all completely in there and just doing that by Lidice order descend by id descending
.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff.
Anyway I want to thank you for watching this lecture I hope you learn a lot and I hope you like Larabee
like I do.
Larabee is going to help us actually make a lot of really cool Vance applications out there right.
Remember that we can also do the deed chaining or right in constraints like does with most with all
the relationships we can do the Order By OK we can always do this constraint out there with these relationships
so I don't think just because I do a we one relationship you can do it with the other keep trying different
the methods that you see me try and in one side try to with the other side see how you can make your
own things your own queries and relationships and just try just experiment a little bit.
OK.
Get out of the.
Don't.
Don't worry.
Don't wait for me to do things right.
Try doing yourself a swell.
All right thank you so much for watching this lecture and.
See you in the next one.
Take care.