All right welcome back my students so we have we have accomplished a couple of things right.
We are setting in certain data.
We are updating data and we are forgetting about reading data.
All right.
But that's super simple right guys.
Super simple so we're going to be reading the data before we delete it.
All right so let's do that.
Let's do that now and let's create a rule for that.
OK.
And let's just read it before we delete it because I don't want to enter it again.
All right so that was we are laughter right.
Well don't laugh at me OK.
All right so cool.
They are super easy to pulao just fine or fail.
Come on guys.
Do I have to really show you this.
I have to do it because I just put it in the in the course.
I already did this user.
Yes.
All right.
And the name.
That's it.
We can do echo if we want to.
All right.
So let's go and check this out
read.
And guess what.
Let's actually delete it as well here.
And I'm going to name this lecture like delete and read.
Ooh that rhymes.
All right cool.
So now that we know we find the data there's actually let's try it from scratch guys get used to it
please let's delete it.
There we go.
And here is to function.
And let's just find the user again.
All we're doing here is always finding the user find or fail one.
And then right here we can just say delete it right.
But remember we're not just finding the user we're finding the address of the user.
All right.
So we find or fail and then we pull out the address.
So we say yes and now you have to use the method here if you want to use some method for this method
.
Just like the safe we just use delete here.
Ok cool.
So we're going to find the user's address is indeed it.
That's what we're going to be doing here is going to be a pretty fun and why law and if you want to
know if this went through just to this.
Always done.
Remember that we can also do this and we already or whatever we're doing here is sending in PSP artisan
.
Anyway there you go.
Refresh address is gone.
Beautiful.
All right.
So that's it for the one to one relationship that is not the more that we got to do here unless we do
it in an application.
Remember if you didn't get this if for some reason you do not get to go back into it this is not working
100 percent.
Go back and start from scratch.
Don't get lazy because that way you will never learn.
All right you will only stretch your mind when you are tired frustrated and you having issues for hours
days weeks months that's when you really grow emotionally intellectually and even sometimes even physically
.
Right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching guys.
And I'll see you in the nads lectures