All right welcome back my students so are you ready to learn some more eloquent really cool right.
I'm ready to teach you.
So let's get it on.
All right.
Cool.
So now that we know how to create data and we even know how to muscle science right.
It's time for us to learn how to update it.
So let's create a role for that.
And this to date and now we did this before with a statement to write a statement that was able to create
new data.
We don't have it right here.
And if we did have it and we just find the wreck and working on data so this is a really cool matter
that uses most of that time.
But we also have an update mentor that I want to show you that's pretty useful and I'm going to show
you a little trick right now.
So I'm always trying to show you something new in every lecture besides what I'm the main subject is
so let's do something like OK let's just change some where statements on different conditions are better
.
You really know how to do that so I show you.
So where Id cause to
and where is at and men equals zero.
We're going to update some information.
OK.
And now we can say we have the title waves so we put an array here OK because this this can take multiple
parameters.
So Title 2 new BHB title or something like that and the content too.
I love my instructor.
There we go.
I know some of you guys love me.
So.
So we were right to a statement here right where Id go to and where is Admin the zero.
So we're going to be updating this little guy right here.
So let's refresh him make sure he's still there.
So he's still there is zero.
So those those conditions are SRU.
So that is going to update if there were not you of course is not going to pass and he would not update
.
So let's try update enter.
Whoops that's not it.
Is this one.
Beautiful.
So now let's go and check out these Outman.
Nice admin.
But BHB my admin we go.
And you'll be a spitfire.
I know my instructor.
When we get the time stamps beautiful low when the larva does this with either time stops automatically
.
I'm going to show you some pretty cool ways to deal with time stamps later in the course.
All right.
So I hope you are really excited and we are going to be learning a lot more in this course.
I want you to keep up your energy and remember that you are learning something that is going to change
your career.
If you already have one if not it's going to allow you to get a better job out there or even a new job
.
So be motivated wake up every day like you want to do this stuff because this is your.
This could mean a life changing experience for you.
OK.
So anyway thank you so much for watching my courses all the time in you know supporting me and I'll
see you in the next lecture.
Take your guys