All right welcome back my students on this lecture we're going to learn how to lead in eloquent using
eloquent Clarabell in different ways.
All right.
So let's just come in this hour real quick.
Let's create a delete.
Let's just say this.
Let's get one then we go and we're going to say delete function.
All right.
So the first thing the first way that we are going to learn how to delete.
And let's just say post and let's just do it like this which is actually we already have the model there
.
So let's just find Paul's number one and Malesherbes deleted this by calling them the lead method.
OK.
Super simple.
So let's come here real quick.
And we are ready.
We have this in PH BE MY outmatch you can see there we have that in our table.
All right we are the number two.
So if you want to delete something that's how you do it.
Answer.
Oops.
Actually I always make the mistake of putting ID number one.
I don't know why is.
Go now into it enter.
There we go.
Refresh and that is gone.
OK that's one way of deleting stuff.
Let me show you another way.
So I know some of you don't like to be writing but I am forcing you to write because I'm the instructor
I want you to learn this stuff.
OK I want you to be very clear how to do this just from the by instinct.
So the leading number two sort of going to say that lead to here and.
Ok cool.
So now if you're one of the lead and it's 16 maade or you know the key.
All right.
We can't use the destroy method like this.
We can destroy it and we can we can if we're going to destroy one we can.
And let me just show you right now.
I'm going to destroy number three.
All right.
March is number three they're in.
Let's see how simple this is.
I mean if I have the browser behind me there we go.
So I lean over to enter Let's go and see.
And you see how easy that was right.
Beautiful refresh.
And he's gone.
But let me show you how to delete multiple records.
So now we are four and five here and we're going to have to get some data source are going to show you
how to answer a lot of data too which is pretty cool with something called Cedar's and
factories.
So anyway let's go back here and let's do a couple of them.
So I'm going to put an array here and all we got to do is put the idea of we know in.
So four and five that say.
Now this is going to lead it.
Remember that you can also really by Querrey.
OK.
You can also lead something like you can make your query like this post way using the word statement
.
Right.
These were a method and you could really were whatever Where is admin is equal to zero or whatever.
OK and you can call this like this.
All right.
Remember that you can do this well but I'm going to come in that hour I'm just going to make sure you
have that.
So let's go and try to see if we can leave everything Antar come back to you my admin.
Now refresh and why law is Garren right.
Super easy.
So if you know the model you are deleting or if you know the condition you could use destroy or destroy
we fine.
If you know the key.
So pretty cool stuff right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture I hope you enjoy it and I'll see you in the next
one.
Take care.