All right welcome back my students.
Before we start pushing projects into the hub and in doing more things we get less actually set up our
good settings.
All right.
Let's set that up so that way when we are sharing stuff with people somewhere else they can know who
the comments belong to.
All right.
So let's do it like this.
If you notice when I do get a comment oh good lord.
Well we don't have anything here.
Let's go to the learning.
Good.
And if I do get a log we have a couple of committee but he says the name.
My name is Gordon faculty and this is my e-mail.
All right.
As you can see right here according to faculty other works.
Boy that's what he's saying that my e-mail is.
So I want to set that up.
So he says something else.
Right.
So I got to say good.
Actually called config global.
And you can do this from any file as long as you have good initialized All right.
And I got to say that my username is doing.
But I've got to put quotes around here.
So I'm going to see it when I just go live like this one.
Enter now.
I also want to change my email address to say something like and when at courting faculty.
All right.
Now for the good log.
Well I still have that there because I made those comments with that.
But if I make a new comment and I say new when you file that age the amount and I do get ad good command
file if I do get blog.
You can see that I knew comment was created by Edwin That's the author and he has my new e-mail address
.
All right.
So I want you to do the settings before we start pushing projects into get help or I push and file.
So that way when you are sharing there people know who you are.
Anyway thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you in the next lecture OK.
Take care.
Bye bye.