All right welcome back I'm a student so it's tough for us to start exploring the pool speech.
All right what do we have here.
Well first of all we have a role here.
Looks like we have some custom route.
All right.
It's been a while since I checked the routes so let's check the routes he or.
OK look we have a custom route here.
Let's put that back here to web that BHP and we have a group here.
This is supposed to be the ad men group and it is can we put this year's software which is close to
polls.
Let's check this out right here.
All right let's come back here and refresh.
All right now it says Listen you've got something with comments right right.
That's fits the comments.
Good.
All right.
Meant that comments that show that should fit in law.
All right so we got polls working and we even got pagination.
I think we need to make some adjustments.
Pagination has a lot more.
It's a lot more manageable in this version of.
But we can actually even change it in the first version the 5.2 version actually we are not able to
do much with pagination But now we are able to to actually modify this more.
All right.
For those of you that you know we're asking how can we modify that well with this new version we can
.
Right.
But that would be probably some extra lectures for you know like cosmetic stuff.
But right now we need to make this work all right when we make this work on your percent then you guys
make your requests and then we start playing around with it a little bit more.
But you guys should be masters of radio this.
But anyway.
So let's go to polls and of course yes we have the same problem.
Let's go back to oddment posts and then we need to pluck a couple of things here and we've got to end
it.
We need to block and believe create it.
All right let's come back here and be fresh.
We'll we'll we'll.
Everything lose good here.
Can we update the polls.
No we cannot.
All right.
Let's create a new polls.
New polls.
And OK we have a problem with this now
too.
We don't have any less here any more I believe and we have a problem with storing stuff here.
But we don't how any of this matters here.
All right let's do a
what I'm going to do is I'm going to do a dump right here of this little guy here users push.
See what I get.
If this works he's our Creator meant to mess up.
All right we fresh air.
All right so that works we're getting a collection of nothing but that's working.
So that create is messed up.
I think I have an idea what it is.
All right let's go to composer Jason real quick.
And let's look at what we have here.
OK.
I see a problem.
First of all this is now being updated to 5.3.
We're going to do a composer all day on that.
This little guy here could be a problem right.
If Let's go to the polls
and actually not polls.
Let's go to the model.
And ooh
we need to eliminate this guy.
We're going out to work on this.
Our Aslaug.
There are more than a pretty you are.
Later on but I think this is a problem.
I don't think they have upgraded their version
so we can go and do a little search for a quick log of all
this just for Larralde real quick.
I know I'm misspelling it.
I know that.
All right this is the guy right here.
Let's just look at what's going on.
Right.
It's over five doesn't say that version.
Let's just put test that I usually find things when it's just tested.
Oh there you go.
We found it.
OK.
So a test against larger 5.1 5.2 right disguising causing really updated is not good.
Good not good.
I think this is this might be a problem.
Let's actually comment all this out and let's just take how
this implement from here.
And I think we are.
All right let's just do that and see what happens.
Right.
Because we want to.
All right.
New posts and I think it worked.
Yeah I worked for a second too.
Let's create another one.
Wow this is working.
All right let's put a picture here.
Why not.
Right.
What do we get to page 3 haha.
Yeah.
So yeah that is a problem.
Let's try to upgrade to the computer that Jason because we have this Lauber collective feel.
Lauber collective actually is has all graded allowable collective
collective
right.
And a male here.
Yeah.
And they have let's do a little dot here and a multiplication symbol or believe you call this star.
So they forgot the name of it guys I'm sorry my language is not English.
All right.
Composer update I think that's quite an asterix.
Dante Astras I forgot the name.
All right we got involved version number five point three.
Oh OK.
Let's take this out.
Let's make it happen again.
Let's see.
All right.
Doing something now hopefully.
Let's cross our fingers.
We don't get another area that we spend 20 minutes trying to fix.
All right guys.
Please don't fall asleep all right.
If you're falling asleep I want you to post his video and I want you to get a really really good energy
drink natural energy drink OK.
All right Buzzer.
Because he kind of it took like 30 seconds or more.
All right.
But anyway let's make sure that our application did not break and we don't have to come back here and
go crazy about it.
All right.
A lot of our collective is pretty cool anyway.
Let's just say Wow another pose is gone this is for this description.
Let's do this
and let's pull some javascript guys.
If you have not brushed up on Javascript you need to do a javascript is booming right now.
All right.
And I have a couple of courses there that can help you with it.
Now there are many other courses you don't have to take my courses but I'm just letting you know right
now if you want to be a complete developer you need to take jobs courses.
All right.
So anyway let's just do this let's go back.
There we go another place.
So he's working.
All right cool.
So we got this working.
Thank you so much.
We all jumped into the categories and see how that goes.
See you in the next lecture