All right welcome back my students.
So it's tough for us to start creating some routes just to make our application a little bit just to
have something more right to it.
All right.
But anyway let's go to our HTP routes.
And here we have some default routes already with home controller and all this.
You probably have one or two there but that's OK.
All right.
We don't have a group.
We can't create a route group to actually group our controllers here are our routes and we're going
to do that as a matter of fact.
But I want you to actually get an idea of what we're going to be doing so we're going to create instead
of doing a GET requests and then doing a poultry ques you know and it's just a waste of time.
Let's do a resource that creates all of our routes for us.
All right.
So we got to think about it about a little bit.
How can we or what kind of routes do we want for admin.
All right.
Do we want to have something like admin users.
Does that look good to you.
We could if we wanted to create a role for admin like this users.
All right.
And then for others we could actually do this author so that we know these are not there right.
And then we can say users or other polls because the author is now going to have users.
All right so I think this looks good.
Right so that was the script there from where that user is at that time.
All right let's do it like that we could.
I really like this approach.
Right.
Because we really don't need to add meaning here and let people know that it is an admin but just for
demonstration purposes only We're going to do very.
We're going to do a very simple simply like this or I admin and we're going to create the users for
us.
All right.
And this is going to a controller which we don't have and we're going to create right now.
So this is going to users controller
and we could actually make it more that it makes more sense and then admin users controllers.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create this control let's take thinker out of here.
All right let's just do it like this.
All right.
So BHB areason and we're going to do this make controller
we're going to say let's make sure that he has a resource that means the crowd read.
They read all the methods and it's called the admin user's controller.
All right.
That is good.
Let's check it out real quick to see if.
All right.
So we have everything here that we need.
Beautiful guys right.
He beat it.
This actually doing a lot of the guys he really beats doing procedure right or doing the stuff manually
right.
This thing is awesome.
All right.
Anyway let's actually.
So I think we're good now.
We have created our route here.
All right later on we're going to create a group just to make sure that all of the admins are in there
and have a middleware for admins and their routes for the alters have middleware for others and so on
and so on.
Right.
But anyway I think we're done with this here and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.