All right.
Welcome back my students so let's go back to get help.
And we have a project right here called good course.
Now I created a new project.
I also want to show you a new repository I also want to show you how to delete them from here.
So let's say I created this I created this Claribel proj repository and I wanted to lead.
I go to settings and I just delete it right here.
All right.
And I type in the name Clarabelle and when I type in the name you can see that this gets that you can
click on it if you don't type it in and you can click on it.
All right.
THE LEAD.
Beautiful.
Delete it now.
All right so we have this good course that we created like to lecture two lectures ago.
All right.
So that's the repository we're going to grab the you are L. And we're going to go to learning good right
here.
Let's go to let's go to Ed in the browser in the terminal.
So the CD learning good.
All right.
So reading say here we're going to clone this.
We're going to use a command called clone get clone based out yourself that way is cloning if you do
ls you can see that new get cores directory there so we can switch to that directory get seated Get
course.
Now if you check this out rectories empty right now if we do clear and you do get status
the first thing that you're going to notice is that gear is already initialized.
So if I do.
LS hyphen a lathe we can see that I get file was actually imported from or export it out from the repository
on line and get help.
All right.
So now look at this.
So now if I want to I'm going to create a file here touch and that's actually a mail by the way.
That's what I got in this good course directory.
But now look at this good.
And we add everything.
Good comment.
We commend it.
And we're just going to say created new age the e-mail indicates that the M-L file committed now we're
ready to push this to their own line to this repository right here.
All right.
Right now it does not show anything.
It shows you this quick set up screen because it doesn't have any any files.
Maybe they'll change in the future.
Right now has not changed it.
So if I wanted to push that to get up I could just do this.
Good
origin Matt.
Actually Hookham sorry get push.
Origin is the remould is gay hop.
That's the remote repository and you want to get push it to Master and it's going to ask you for the
user name.
Mine for this account is a password is this.
And as you can see writing objects 3 done.
Now if I come here and I refresh this you can see that that new in the mail is there and that new compared
with the message that we created is here.
So you click on this and there is nothing there.
There's no contributors.
Contributors to that far yet but people can come here they can find this link that you give them.
All right you give them the link and they're going to find this project or you given the name of the
project they can search here.
All right.
And we can type in here good course and they're going to find your project and they're going to contribute
to your project.
All right.
So beautiful.
So the next lecture we're going to let a couple of more things here just in case somebody else has a
project there and you want a country view.
And so I'm going to show you how to do that how to go and find a project.
Clone it in your own space.
Right.
And then you can contribute to it.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.