All right welcome back to the students on the last lecture with a little bit of everything right.
We've created some functionality where we see the individual post as you can see right here.
All right.
We also created the functionality where we find the post and we send it to the edit form.
So that way gets populated right and I'll show you that in this lecture how we do that.
So right now this is going to this form right here.
Actually it's not going there yet.
Let me see.
All right it should.
Let's go to our terminal look the HP router list.
So we supposed to go to polls an ID in between.
And then the edit.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And the reason why I did not do is because I forgot this for Slash.
Enter now you can see that it will form there but it's not getting populated.
So that's the whole reason why we're sending we're finding the post and we sending it there.
So that way we can take those values and populate the form.
So let's go into that.
Let's go to the edit and right here.
I'm going to create a value and use Billy to put the pools title in there and it's as simple as that
.
Guys very simple enter as you can see the title is there.
Now look at that beautiful right now in order for us to submit this.
We need to do a couple of things.
All right.
First of all we need to have the ID of the post sent somewhere so it's going to be going to let's open
our BHB route less real quick.
Is going to this update right so he needs to go in this in this format the post and the ID soling action
you put forward slash and the ID.
Now also make sure that your method this post may be on the last lecture I didn't do that.
Or maybe you don't have it.
Just make sure that your form says method post there.
OK.
Now Laro bill does not understand this post when you see the one you you're using this you or I understand
understands put or patch.
So we need to make it so that way Larabee understands it.
OK.
So in order for that to happen we need to create an imp hitting input all right and there are packages
and we will learn about them but they are packages where would all this is done for us automatically
once we define a couple of previous functions.
Right now we're doing it the hard way because I want you to understand how everything works.
OK.
So let's create this input is going to be type hidden arrived.
And let's give it a name.
This is going to be a super global.
Whoops we have a comma here.
So this super global is going to be sent as underscore method.
All right.
And the next thing is the value the value of this loops is going to be put.
All right we're going to be putting that information in there in that database and once you do that
you're good to go with this.
OK.
Also make sure that this is in belayed not jaws dropped in there you probably saw that.
OK what else are we missing here.
I'm trying to see.
All right.
Oh another thing here is that each of these four needs to have a talking.
So Larabee has this if you don't know what the talking is you should go back and take my you know BHB
log in of course which I show you how to create a really cool talking using a couple of functions from
BHP.
But anyways a big string of integers that I'll show you right now what it is so we're going to create
the blade format here and it's going to be a function called C R S is a series C S are actually sirra
is our field.
Now let's go back to our application let's refresh here.
Let's reichlich inspect it.
And let's look at it real quick.
And as you can see has it talking right here.
You see that.
So we have this name talking there.
Lara is going to detect that.
And that's the C or S or C S R F All right function.
All right.
Anyway let's go back here.
We have a problem here and that's where I was looking at in my input.
OK.
Let's go and fix this real quick.
So type
hitting Can you believe I don't see the problem here.
I don't see it.
I got two cords here and the name and then two cords right here
and then value and I don't understand it when you are so tired you don't understand what's going on
.
Recreate this stuff.
All right.
There we go.
Just recreate it.
If you don't see it just like it's happening to me and this is where you are calling for many hours
name method.
OK.
I still don't see a guy says unbelievable how the problem could be right in front of us and we won't
see it.
All right.
But anyway I'm not spending much time developing this as a matter of fact is not here a problem is here
.
Now I saw it.
OK.
There we go.
So I was right here I was I didn't see it because the mistake was over here and this function was not
even telling me nothing.
I was not telling me that something was misspelled here.
But anyway.
All right so we have this now and now we can edit this.
All right.
So we're sending the I.D. to the update method.
OK.
And now we catch a here we catch him with a request of the form as well.
Right.
So we're going to have a lot of fun in the next lecture of dating this data in the database.
Anyway thank you so much guys for watching.
And I see you in the next lecture