All right welcome back my students.
So in the last lecture we learned how to delete data using eloquent on this lecture here.
We are also going to learn how to delete data but in a different way.
Right so I'm going to ask you Have you ever use a feature in some of the CMAs programs out there like
Wordpress Drupal where you actually delete the item any put in the same as puts it in the trash page
.
Right.
And then you go to that trash page and then you can delete the item from there permanently.
That's exactly what we are going to be learning here on this lecture today.
We're going to now only the lead item we're going to put it on the trash Aspasia our application right
.
Well not in this case is not going to be our application yet but we're going to put it.
We've got to Larrabee know that it's not the leader 100 percent.
But it is a softer lead.
So he's going to put a time stamp on a new column that we are going to be creating called the need to
act.
So with that time stamp we let Larabee know listen is not deleted.
Do I tell you to force it to delete.
So anyway without explaining too much because sometimes we don't understand good explanations as much
as we understand we code.
Let me show you.
So the first thing that we are going to do that we have to do is we've got to import the database.
The class of the leads.
OK.
So let's actually import in this use you use it from here.
You illuminate then database Boob's database then after database is eloquent because we're going to
be using that and then it's called soft deletes.
There we go.
And then we want to use it.
So we just say use of delete here.
OK.
Beautiful.
After this what we also need is to set up protected property
called dates.
And the reason why we do this is because we let our vote know to treat this column as a date time stamp
column column.
So it's going to be called the lead it.
We haven't created it yet but it's going to be called the it at.
OK.
And make sure that you put it here.
All right remember this property is already set we Clarabelle internally.
So we already have these properties available from the model when we send extend all these classes or
if you go here you should see all of this
or these properties here.
Can you see dates right here.
OK and I did that by pressing control control click or command click on iMac.
Ok cool.
So now let's create a migration and let's just clear this out and let's just say BHP areason
and make migration add the lead it column actually delete it at column 2 pulls through.
OK.
And and that's it.
Oh actually we do a flag here table and we save pools.
I do it without all the cords this time.
All right.
Whoops.
I misspelled that oops sorry.
It's now be Orge P H O P I'm creating a new web programming language here.
Antar.
There we go.
So that's complete I'm going to do.
Right click and I and I synchronize this I don't have that problem that I used to have before with this
not appearing here.
All right there we go.
Double click on it.
That's where we are.
If so now I'm going to show you a new trick here which allows us to create this in a faster way.
They will solve the leads I'm going to use this function to create a column with a tag stamping everything
in there.
All right.
So I'm going to also use the object table to drop it just in case we need to roll it back delete it
.
There we go.
All right.
So this is just when we run that migrate rollback or reset or whatever he allows it let's Lauber know
that that it could he can drop it if we want to.
So anyway let's go back and let's learn how to do this let's go two routes.
And if you click imag shift twice you can navigate.
I believe Windows you can also do the same thing.
I'm not 100 percent sure.
All right.
So let's create a roll real quick around and let's call this soft delete.
Now I also have to create some data because I deleted my data before and you guys probably don't know
.
But what happens is that I got to tell you right now sometimes when you are creating migrations like
this and if you come here and you try to be.
And you just try to delete one of these files manually like right clicking or whatever.
Or from termino you got to have a problem because you does migrations are going to be recorded in the
migrations table inside your database.
Right.
This is how it keeps track of the migrations.
So when you delete it here is going to have it in the in the in the table and he's going to create a
problem is going to have it in the database.
So what you need to do is do my PH BE Adisa migrate reset.
So that way you reset the migrations table and then you can go ahead and delete this item from here
and then do BHB artist and migrate again.
OK.
So if you have any issues migrate we said could we solve it.
All right.
So we can solve the lead this item so what we're going to do is let's put some data first.
I'm going to come here and look for this create functionality right here and see if we can create some
data.
Real quick.
There we go.
Whoops.
Oh you know what I need to do.
Peachtree migration migrate actually BHB artisan migrate we go.
Now let's do it.
And that's because I did a migraine reset.
So that's why you probably don't have to do that guys.
All right so now you see this this is the table where records are the migration.
So if you delete it in the Claribel application it doesn't get the data here.
So make sure that you do the reset.
So let's go to the polls and we how we see that we have a new post here.
And let's say I want to delete it you see the column here.
It's said to know automatically.
So now when we we call the method on this let's say we will look for it find and I think he has I.D.
one find is and the leading
thinker.
See how easy that is right.
And we're just going to do of the lead Real quick up here Antar.
All right now we go back here and we refresh a look at this column watch.
You see that we get a date there.
All right.
So that's how he knows.
But in the next lecture I'm going to show you how to pour this information out because we can actually
run a query through this and pull it out like we normally do when we have a record.
Now we have to force it to actually give us the lead items.
All right.
Because we won't by default we will not show this when you try to read it.
By default will not show you the record because he has just deleted this time stamp here.
If it was no then he will come out.
They will come like a regular polls like a regular Recker not on the leader record.
All right so every time he has his stamp is deleted.
So we won't show you when you do a fine or OK or or when you try to just pull the information out.
But anyway on to the next election going to show you how to do that in a couple more really cool things
from our.
Laura Bell thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture