Hello everyone and welcome back.
Welcome to the bootstrap section of the course.
Bootstrap is a very common framework to use for front and web development and it's actually going to
help us save a lot of time from dealing with CSSA manually.
But first we need to ask ourselves what is a framework what makes it different than just a library or
some sort of package.
Well a framework has a couple of key qualities.
Some of those qualities are inversion of control meaning you're giving up control to the framework and
the framework is going to have some sort of default behavior.
And it's a non modifiable framework code.
And basically what this means is the framework is going to be defining the rules for you to follow not
the other way around.
Usually we've been seeing ourselves write some code defining the rules and then executing the code.
Here the framework is going to tell you what the rules are as far as how you can manipulate the code.
So there's an inversion of control there between what we're used to and we'll get more use of this idea
of what a framework is when we reach Django because Django itself is a web framework for Python now
a large part of bootstrap is not memorization but really understanding how to reference the documentation
for your own use cases and this section will focus on some of the more common use cases of bootstrap.
But the main thing to get across here is your ability to reference the documentation understand what
you need to get out of it and then apply it to your own web site before we begin though let's talk about
bootstrap version 3 versus version 4.
So bootstrap 4 is currently still in development at the time of this filming and will be released soon.
Right now it's an alpha so likely beta will come out after that and then after that we'll get some sort
of first initial release.
Now it may already be released by the time you're viewing this video but if it hasn't yet bootstrap
actually makes it really easy for me to use the alpha version or the beta version that that's out by
the time you're watching this right now so you can actually quickly and easily use whatever the current
version of bootstrap for is.
While bootstrap theory is still the main release for our level of use the differences between version
3 and version 4 won't really be apparent to us.
We're not going to dive so deep into bootstrap that these differences are even going to be on our radar
while version 4 is a major rewrite from Version 3.
We are really not going to dive deep enough to notice any of the differences.
A few of the differences are things such as panels are now being replaced by something called cards
larger default font sizes.
There's a new grids here.
The use of flex box throughout the version for framework and a move from less to SAS.
Now a lot of these terms if you're new to bootstrap and to see assess probably don't mean anything to
you.
And you have no idea what I'm referencing here.
If that's the case really don't worry about it.
We're not going to dive into bootstrap so deep in this course nor will we need to that we need to understand
all these differences between version 3 and version 4.
So again the most important thing to get out of this section of the course is the ability to reference
the bootstrap documentation.
So let's explore the documentation and see some examples of what bootstrap actually looks like.
The documentation is amazing it's full of examples that makes it really easy to copy and paste and modify
in your own code.
Let's go to get bootstrap dot com.
OK so here Eric get bootstrapped dot com you'll see a little banner here that says Ayyash bootstrap
4 is coming.
You can click on that if you want more information on Version 4 but you'll notice that there's actually
links on quickly getting started with a version for right now.
It's in alpha.
So who knows.
By the time you're viewing this video it may already be in beta or it may already be on its first release.
But let's go back and work of the current release which is right now version 3 and again for our use
cases.
Either one will work fine for you.
So if you click on dialup bootstrap it takes you to this getting started link and there's essentially
two ways to use bootstrap.
As far as in conjunction with pure web application you can either download the source code itself which
is going to be the font files the source less some javascript etc. or you can actually just use what's
known as a Cdn a C The n is a content delivery network and you can think of it as essential to working
in a really similar manner to how we use google fonts.
So Google fonts API or the font library that or essentially Ladas to copy and paste a CDN link into
free html file and then it just got the files over the Internet and that's basically what we can do
here.
We can see the links here.
That allow us to copy and paste into our HMO file to actually leak to boot strap which is great.
You can see here there's a stylesheet as well as some compile them in a fight Javascript.
And we'll be talking about this when we actually open up the editor and start dealing with bootstrap.
But essentially we're going to be copying these links.
You can also manually download the links and then save them onto your computer and link to the local
reference on your computer.
But that just is a bunch of downloaded files that we don't really need.
If you're trying to make your application self-hosted without any internet maybe you're going on a train
ride or something you want to play around a bootstrap then you will have to download it manually that
way.
But if you have access to the internet then you can just use CDN.
And if you're watching video then it's most likely they do have access to the Internet.
OK.
So coming back up here I want to explore the documentation a little more if you need to click on getting
started.
You'll take it to this link and you'll notice that beyond the download there's just basic information
like what's included.
Which is right here is what pre-compiled nuestra looks like.
It's really just a bunch of the SS files bunch font files and then two javascript files here.
There's the bootstrap source code and then if you keep going down there is just basic information basic
template information etc..
And then there's some examples so here are some examples of what the framework looks like.
Click on these to open up in New tabs.
Hopefully you can begin to see an idea of what bootstrap actually does.
So here are some very simple templates of what bootstrap looks like.
So you can see there's a nav bar here.
There is some sort of theme example and then there are some buttons here.
There's also the grid template which we'll be talking about later on.
There's a Jumbotron template there is a narrow template again if a jumbo tron here.
And then there's a nut bar template and we're going to be walking through a lot of these things throughout
the section of the course.
Jumbotron snack bars grids.
Those are all really common things that we are going to cover with bootstrap.
But for specific things if you scroll back up here and click on components this will take you through
basically all the components at CSA or excuse me bootstrap has to offer.
So if you want more details on for instance a nav bar you just click here on the side the nav bar and
has really great documentation I'll tell you what the default nav bar it looks like and that it has
tons of example code.
So this is an example of what this nav bar looks like.
So you can see has a dropdown menu and will be discussing what this looks like later on.
And that also has a code for it so you can always reference the code as well as what the code is going
to look like.
So if you want a brand image in your now bar it shows an example what that looks like and shows the
example what that code looks like.
You want forms input forms you know.
Or maybe a search button shows you what that looks like as well.
So you keep going down here maybe you want to check out how progress bars work with bootstrap.
Well you just click on bootstrap here on progress bars and you can see the basic example of what a progress
bar looks like.
And it shows you the code for as well.
Then if you want to label it also shows you that you can see that bootstrap is basically just a bunch
of predefined CSSA styles that are really going to help you.
And they each have their own class and we're going to discuss how to actually use these and a lot more
detail in future lectures.
What I want to do is get out this lecture is the fact that you can reference basically anything you
want about this strap and C example code for as well as what it looks like.
All on the documentation page.
OK.
So the very first thing we're going to be discussing we talk about bootstrap is how to use these buttons
these really simple buttons and you'll see that they actually already have classes defined to them so
very basic examples look like this lift left middle right but they'll also have their own colored classes
which are going to be exploring later on.
All right.
So go ahead.
I encourage you to just jump around the documentation and check it out.
But coming up next we're going to talk a lot more about bootstrap and buttons.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture.