Hello everyone and welcome to the CSSA level one section of the course.
We've now completed h T.M. both sections and it's time to move on to learning about CSSA and the SS
will have two sections to it Level 1 and level 2.
CSA stands for cascading style sheets and CSSA really describes how Timah elements are displayed on
the page and we're going to take this lecture to describe what's the SS is and show you some examples
of its true power so styling can affect many things such as color font size borders and many more properties
of h m l.
So far I've been able to create basic h tim l documents while they may have some content and a little
bit of functionality.
They basically all look the same and when you're actually on the web you want things to look nice and
usually the fine styling outside of the html file you create a separate CSSA file and then link that
to the HTML file.
We're going to show later on some examples that you can actually find styling within the HTML document
itself.
But it's a much more common and better practice to separate your styling into a CSSA file and then link
it to the html file in the head of that a small file document.
And that's where we're going to be discussing that meta data OK.
Let's show a quick example of just how powerful CSSA can be.
Exploring the same HMO code but with different CSSA linked to it.
Let me go to this link right here if you can find that just by googling W3 schools see SS and there's
actually lots of Web sites that show similar examples of this.
So you can just google search CSSA demos and you'll find lots of Web sites like this one.
To open my browser and jump to this link.
Ok here I am at my browser and I've come to the W3 schools dot com Web site that has CSSA introduction
and you'll notice here on the left hand panel is actually a really nice reference to a bunch of CSSA
topics such as outlines text fonts etc..
We're going to be covering a lot of these but throughout the course if you feel like you need more reference
you can just visit W3 school ZCom on CSSA.
Another Web site I want to mention that I like probably a little better than W3 schools is the Mozilla
developer network.
They also have a ton of information about cascading style sheets or CSSA they have tutorials introduction
reference and as you become more of a developer.
As you already learned the tools you'll probably be using the reference more than the tutorials and
introduction sections.
So just keep that in mind these are two really great links for you to check out.
In case you want to dive deeper into some of the stuff we talk about during this course but I just want
to show you the s.c.s introduction page which actually has a kind of a fun demo so you can see what
a simple page with multiple styles.
Notice if you scroll down here it says Welcome to my home page and this is HVM L that's linked to SS
and you'll notice we see that we have the screen header bar.
You have some different fonts etc..
A little sidebar but we also have these links to different stylesheets and if I click on one of these
links to style sheet number 2 for instance you'll notice the website completely changes.
But the fun fact to know here is that this is actually the exact same h HTML code.
The only thing that's changing is the CSSA file that it's linked to.
So all the changes you see here when you hit on the stylesheets is just sheer CSSA none of the Himself
is changing the content changing just the CSSA changing itself.
And they can really see me cook Ancel shoot for here just how powerful CSSA is it can make your website
look completely different.
Using the same content and if we click on No stylesheet.
This is what we've been working with just pure H Tim L So the same page just different stylesheets.
There's no stylesheet you can see as you play around with these.
You can get a vastly different looking website with all the style sheets.
And after these two CSSA level 1 and level 2 sections are going to be learning about Bootstrap which
helps streamline a lot of this process and take care.
A lot of the work for you.
But before we hit bootstrap we really should understand CSSA itself that way if we ever need to customize
anything we can do that before we just jump straight into bootstrap.
OK so let's continue on and start learning about the basics of SS.
Thanks everyone and I'll see in the next lecture.