Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
We're going to be getting started with Django.
We finally reached the moment we've been waiting for throughout the whole course using our Python skills
and all our front end skills along with the jayega web framework before we actually dive into the technical
details of Django.
Let's learn a little more about it than it's really interesting background Django is a free and open
source web framework.
And being a web framework it really allows us to solve two major problems.
It allows us to map a requested your from a user to the code that's actually meant to handle it and
then it also allows us to create that requested HVM dynamically.
So using templates which we'll learn about later on we can actually inject calculated values or information
from the database into an aged female page to show to the user.
So we're going to be really connecting all the front end stuff to the backend stuff through this web
framework.
And Django is extremely popular it's used by many sites including things such as Pinterest PBS Instagram
bit bucket Washington Times Mozilla and much more.
You can check out the official Gengel Web site for a whole list of example web sites that operate using
jingoes web framework Django was created in 2003 when the Web developers at the Lawrence Journal World
newspaper started using Python for their development and the fact that it originated at a newspaper
is actually really important to the culture that surrounds Django because the original developers were
surrounded by those newspaper writers good written documentation is a key part of Django.
And we're going to be exploring documentation as we go along through this part of the course and that
also means that you have excellent references to check out on the official Django documentation pages
jingo has its own excellent basic tutorial where you're basically walk through creating a basic pulling
web application.
And I would definitely suggest that you check out that polling tutorial later on throughout this course
and also the reason it's a pull is because that also extends back to newspaper routes.
If you're on a newspaper Web site you may want to pull your readers to see whether or not they agree
with the topic of a story.
So when encountering Django tutorials you're going to often read that you should use what's called a
virtual environment or you'll sometimes also see it as V and V.
Let's talk about what a virtual environment is.
How do you use it and why it's so important to use one whenever you're working with Django for a large
project.
The virtual environment allows you to have a virtual installation of python and packages on your computer.
So why would you ever actually want or need this.
You've already installed Python.
Why bother with a virtual environment.
Python packages change and get updated often and there are changes that sometimes break backwards compatibility
that your web application or web project made depend on.
So what do you do if you want to test out the new features of a package update but you also don't want
to break your current web application.
After all you can't just take down your web site every time a package gets updated.
Well that's where the virtual environment comes in.
You can create a virtual environment that contains the newer version of the package or the virtual environment
for your older version of the package.
And luckily Anaconda makes this really easy for us.
A virtual environment handler is already included.
So to use this virtual environment with Conder you're going to use the following commands.
Now we'll walk through this and just a little bit but the Kada create command initiated the virtual
environment.
So we say Konda create space dash dash name and then another space and you type in the name of your
So in this case I've called my environment my E and V there and then the last word there.
Django is going to say well what package do I want to initiate this environment with an Konda requires
that.
So you'll say create dash dash.
Name the name of your virtual environment and then the package that you want to start that environment
with and later on you can specify a specific version for that package.
So you can say Django something like equals equals 1.9 or 1.8 1.10 etc and then you could activate that
environment with activate space.
The name of the environment and this all happens at the command line.
Now anything installed with Pitt or Khanda when this environment is activated will only really be installed
for that environment.
So that allows you to create separate versions of packages and pythons all on one computer with the
use of these virtual environments.
And then you can deactivate the environment with deactivate my envie or the name of the environment
and it's highly encouraged to use virtual environments for your projects to keep them self-contained
and not run into issues and packages are updated.
All right.
So let's jump to our command line and show you an example of actually creating a virtual environment.
OK here I am at the Adam text editor and before we get started by walking through a virtual environment
using Konda what I wanted to point out is that Konda itself has really good documentation on creating
virtual environments or managing environments and it's linked to in the resource notes.
But let me jump to that Web site real quick over here and show you what it looks like.
Just go to the IO slash thok slash using slash and VS for Environment study CML or just google search
Konda environments should take you to this page or just use the resource link.
But this has a lot more details on what we're going to be showing here.
Shows you how to create an environment change an environment clone an environment remove etc..
So if you ever have any questions further than what we discuss here you have this documentation that
will walk you through all of these steps.
So we're going to be doing is creating an environment and there's an example here Conda create dash
dash name.
They're calling their environment snowflake's and it uses bio Python.
So let's create a virtual environment that will create a virtual environment for Django for us.
So I will come back to Adam klick plus here to open up my terminal.
And then what I will do is say this Konda create a dash dash name and let's call this my Django E and
the.
And then I will type Django because that's the package I want to initiate my Django envy or environment
with.
I will hit enter and what it's going to do is download that Gengel package if I don't have it already
and then apply it to that virtual environment and Conda is actually pretty smart and it will know that
if you have already a similar version of Django somewhere install on your computer it may not need to
copy it you just referenced it that way you don't need to download anything it'll just reference previous
installations.
I don't have Jeng on this computer yet so it will do is fetch that meta data and let me expand this
shew what happens.
And it will ask you hey these new packages are going to be installed.
Is that OK with you.
And I will say no right now because I actually don't want Python 2.7.
I want Python 3.
So what I'm going to do is say no on proceed and instead I will say this Conda creates name and let's
say my Jingo and B and instead of starting with J go I'm going to start it with Python 3.
And the reason I'm doing this is to show you an example of specifying a specific version of Python or
a package.
So it's a very similar process you say Konda create dash dash.
Name the name of your actual environment.
And in this case instead of a package I will say Python and then you say equals and then you type in
the version number you want.
So for instance I want Python 3.5.
I'm going to enter it will fetch that packet's meta data again.
It will show me the new packages that will be installed here I can see that I have the correct version
of Python I want 3.5.
You can also do a 3.6 depending on when you're actually viewing this course if that's been added to
Khanda.
But let's stick with something 3.4 or above.
So 3.4 3.5 3.6.
Those should all work fine for what we're going to be doing.
I'm going to proceed on that select Y.
And then I will jump forward in time for this to all being downloaded and installed.
I'll see you there.
All right so that has finished installing and now we actually get the instructions so to activate this
environment we can use activate and then the name of the environment and then deactivate it once we're
done using it we can say deactivate and that will deactivate the environment.
And if we ever want to use it again we can easily just activate it with the activate command.
And if you're on a Mac or Linux computer and you're using bash you probably have to use source.
So keep that in mind.
All right.
Now that we've set up our actual environment it's time to activate it.
A quick note.
In case you forget what environments you have on your computer you can easily list them through this
command Konda info dash dash E and V S and this will list all the environments you have here I just
have my default Anaconda the root environment and then this environment I created my Django Ian V and
depending on what Anaconda version you initially installed this may say Anaconda 3 instead of Anaconda's
2 but lets actually activate this environment.
If you're on Linux or Mac OS and you're using bash you will probably have to say Source activate and
then the name of the environment.
Django E and VI.
Since I'm on a Windows computer right now I don't need to specify source.
So let's bring that back down to just activate my Django E.A..
I hit enter and it will activate the environment.
And the way I can tell that the environment is activated is she should see here parentheses might Django
envy and that means that everything I do right now in regards to Python is going to only take effect
on this environment which means if I decide to install a Django in this environment it's only going
to be installed.
That specific version of Django for this virtual environment.
In fact let's do that now.
I will say Konda install Django enter and this will install the latest version of Django.
And for this course basically any version of Django that's higher than 1.8 should work just fine.
So 1.8 1.9 or at the time of this course 1.10 should be fine let's say proceed y.
But I do encourage you to at least use 1.10 that way everything we do in this course matches up exactly
with what's on your computer.
OK.
We're going to hop forward in time for this to finish installing and downloading.
All right.
So that finished installing Django to this virtual environment.
And if I want to confirm this virtual environment is actually working correctly I can just type in Python
into this command line.
And I notice that the version of Python here matches the version of the environment.
If I were to say quit and then deactivate this environment suffice just say de-activate notice I'm no
longer in the virtual environment.
So if I say Python now I'm back to my original installation of Python which happens to be this 2.70
version.
So that's a nice little confirmation that you're in the virtual environment and you're actually doing
effects on that environment.
Let's say quit and we're ready to go.
OK.
So we did a lot of housekeeping stuff in this lecture haven't actually dived into Django but a lot of
this stuff is really important and it's going to clear you of headaches later on if you don't learn
how to actually use virtual environments correctly.
So by this lecture you should have a full understanding of virtual environment at least how to create
them activate them and deactivate them.
You can always reference that link in the resources if you want more information about the environments
and you should have installed Django to your virtual environment.
Coming up next we're actually going to get started with using Django.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture.