Hello everyone and welcome to this advanced topic section.
Well we're going to be discussing customizing the jingo adamant interface now often the default admin
page is great and it's all we need for our projects but sometimes we may also want to expand with the
Admin Page can do and we also have a lot of tools and Django to customize it to our own needs and we're
going to now learn how to customize it.
Adam page as well as features of the atom in page.
So we're going to learn how to do the following.
We'll discuss a quick review of the atom in page how it's used.
Then we'll change the out in page template so you can actually overwrite templates on the Admin Page
and that will show you things like changing the order of fields that show up and adding search and filters
to the Admin site.
We're going to start by quickly creating a new project an application you won't really do anything on
the front end since we really only are going to focus on the Adamant backend.
So essentially it's just going to be an empty front and we have two models connected and registered
to the admin.
Let's shift to our editor and get started.
OK.
Here I am at the Adam text editor and one I'm going to do is just create a new project.
I've gone ahead and created a new folder on my desktop called test to do this and really it doesn't
matter too much for the size to do this.
And we're going to call this my underscore video rental.
We're going to kind of make it as if it's a rental video store web site.
So go ahead and create that project and then I'm going to see the into my video rental here and then
offer this I'll say jingo admen star app and we'll just call this app videos.
And this is where we're going to have a model PI file and an admin file that we can later kind of play
around with.
So to expand this make sure that's all worked out.
So you see my video rental I see videos I see models.
So what I'm going to do is in my settings start by going to make sure I register this video here somewhere
scroll down and and there are installed apps.
Just go ahead and add that app name that we just created called videos.
Save that.
Always make sure you save so you can have those changes.
There we're going to come over here to models and we're going to quickly create two models.
Nothing too major here.
The models we're going to create essentially just going to mimic having a movie and having a customer.
So we'll say.
Class movie.
And then we'll say models the model and then let's give it some fields will say tidal is models.
And we'll have it be a character field.
Let's go ahead and give it a max length of 256 characters.
And then let's say the movie has a length of minutes.
And this is since it's lengthened minutes we know it has to be a positive integer.
So we'll have that be that type of field.
And then there's also a release year.
And technically that should also be a positive integer so we'll do that as well.
Just keeping things simple the main ideas not working with the models is working at the admin page.
We're essentially just creating these because we need something to play around with later on.
So I'm also going to create another model here called customer model and we'll say in her models not
model it let's say customers have a first name let's say models.
And that's also a character field if max length equal to 256.
You can always copy and paste this from the notes as well.
You don't want to type this all out.
Now let's say last name is models.
Basically the same thing here has a max length of 256 and then finally let's say you have some sort
of phone number or some sort of digital code.
Doesn't matter too much but we'll have that would also be some positive interest field.
OK.
So command or control s to say that and then I'm going to make sure that I register these into the item
and file.
So we'll come over here.
To adamant that pie in our videos let's these We're going to say from the import models and then I'll
see adman that PSI thought register is register and I'm going to register my models that way I can see
them in the actual admin page.
So I'm also a customer.
And then Adam and that site the register models movie then it goes into control as to save that.
And let's go ahead and make sure we do our migrations.
So over here them of the terminal I can zoom in a little bit for you guys.
I'm going to do the following.
We'll say make sure say Python managed up high and then say make migrations.
And it went ahead and created model and movie or excuse me create a model customer created a model movie
that we're going to say Python managed up high and I'm going to migrate any changes that we have under
videos.
It may say running migrations.
There we go.
And then I always like to say make migrations one more time to make sure there's nothing left so no
changes that are perfect.
And since we're actually going to be using the admin interface we need to actually create a super user.
So let's make sure we do that as well.
We'll see Python managed up high and this line is create super user which you've done before and if
you get this error.
No such table off the user.
It's actually an easy fix.
It just means that you need to run Python managed that PI migrate.
So come over here back to the terminal and say Python managed up-I migrate.
Hit enter and let it migrate everything.
Now try it again.
Python managed up-I create super user and you should see it ask for your username.
I'll say Jose.
Email address doesn't really matter we'll see.
Blank gmail dot com password.
I always use test password and type it in again.
Your password is hidden for security so there is no super user created successfully.
Let's make sure it all works out so we'll see say now Python managed up-I run server.
Enter there and then let's copy and paste the URL and bring it into our browser which I need to bring
over now.
So bringing in my browser it says it worked.
Congratulations your first single power to pay.
That's exactly what we want.
As I mentioned before really not going to be doing anything on this front end.
So let's go ahead and say slash admin and come over to her admin page my username and password are already
filled out for me.
Jose and his password.
You may have to fill it in the Pentagon.
How many times you've done this before.
Go ahead and log in.
And here we go.
Let me make this full screen.
I could see my groups and my users.
That's often dictation authorization which we've actually discussed before you click here and users
can see Jose blank as email.
I have staff status etc. and you'll notice that I have a filter option here and we're going to discuss
later on how to create these sort of filters on our own models.
Bullets go ahead and go back home and check out our models.
See here I have customers.
And then if we come back to videos I can see here I have movies etc..
So let's go ahead and create some customers willing to add a new customer here.
Let's just how the customer be me as well.
And then some sort of phone number.
It doesn't really matter.
So we're going to save and add another and then we'll make a couple more kind of generic names random
phone numbers doesn't really matter save and add another and last one.
Say.
Let's say it's also Smith because I'm not very creative here.
And then we're going to say safe.
OK so we have three customer objects.
Those really good.
We'll come back to videos.
Well same movies.
And then we'll add some movies here.
So let's go ahead and add in some Muzi movies traffic park let's say it's 120 minutes.
Really.
You're right.
1993 I'm guessing.
Save another one will say Star Wars like this one let's say it's 90 minutes I don't know if that's true
or not.
And I'll say 1973.
I also don't know if that's right.
And final is still one more movie here let's say Indiana Jones
let's say it was in 1984.
That's actually the length.
So let's also say it's once 134 minutes and 94 again Polish making that up.
OK.
So now we have three movie objects and we're ready to go.
So let's go ahead and go back to our page where we had the models and make the string representation
not just say movie object to have it actually say the name.
So we're going to go back over here and under models that PI notice at my class movie in class customer.
Let's go ahead and give it a string representation that we've done before.
We'll go ahead and here will say the F underscore underscore as TR underscore underscore it takes and
self and it's going to return.
Self-taught title will have that be the model and then also down here for the customer.
We're going to add a method here.
This will be self.
And then let's have it return which is how it returns self first name and then we're going to concatenate
it with self-taught last name and basically just concatenating the string and then a little space there
and then the last name.
So now that we've done all that let's go ahead and make sure that we migrate any changes that may have
occurred.
Will say Python managed of Pi migrate.
They'll say running migrations no migration is to apply.
So let's make sure that all works well say Python managed up high run server enter our servers running
again.
Let me come back to the browser and bring it over and I'm going to come straight to the Adamant page.
OK so is the admin page and if we took out customers now we see Cindy Smith Mike Smith Jose Portsea
and have it come back to movies.
We can see Indiana Jones star wars Rasik park.
So now that we have these kind of string representations here the string method we can see that it's
printing out that string as its name cyclic in Indiana Jones gets a tidal length and release year etc..
OK so that's the very basics of the Django adamant interface and everything that basically already comes
for free.
Nodine by free is that no work was involved.
Which is kind of crazy when you think about it because this is a lot of kind of power features and already
stuff that you can edit without having to code anything out.
All you have to do is basically read straight to the oddments site.
But we're going to learn how to add even more stuff to this.
So the first thing to learn is how you can edit this template.
Maybe you want things like a different color or instead of singing saying jingle admen or jingle administration
you wanted to say like Blockbuster's admin page or something like that.
Not every user is going to know what jingle Adam means etc..
So in the next lecture we're going to learn how to actually edit these templates.
Thanks and I'll see Ilir.