Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to the backhand So welcome to the back half of the course
and before we begin we're going to get a brief overview of what to expect for this entire second half
of the course.
But I also want you to congratulate yourself because you've already learned so much about the entire
front and stack.
And we're going to continue on learning about the back and stack and get that full stack web developer
knowledge again congratulate yourself.
You've learned a ton already.
OK.
So to use Django and Python effectively a basic level of understanding the command line is necessary
and these commands are sometimes slightly different.
For Windows users versus Mac OS and Linux users so refer to the notes for full examples and reference
commands since we're only going to need to know a few of them to get started.
So the next lecture is going to have a quick overview and a basic introduction to command lines and
using that command prompt or terminal.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux and there's also a full note different explanations in case you want
to reference those that's just going to be a quick overview lecture.
And that's actually all that's in this particular section of the course.
Then in the next section in order to use Django we need to have a pretty good understanding of Python.
So we have Python level 1 and Python level 2 and we need to learn Python up to the point of object oriented
programming.
If you already have previous experience of Python feel free to skip certain lectures look around in
the curriculum and see if it's a good starting point for you.
And I'll remind you do that again when we actually reached us Python lectures.
Once we've learned Python we can begin to use a jangle web framework to create Web sites.
And let's go over a very high level overview of how Django actually works and don't worry if you don't
fully understand this.
This is just kind of to plant a seed in your mind that way once you actually reach Django you can remind
yourself oh that's what we were talking about in the introduction lecture.
OK.
So it's a very high level overview of Django basically a user will request a URL on your Web site something
like there'll be that hello dot com then that's going to go to a PI file which is then going to call
the views that py file in Django and the elves are just connected to views through a simple call and
then that will call your model Pi which contains all the information of your database.
And then that will query your database for the information feed it back to views that pi which creates
the view of your Web site what it actually looks like.
And then we use templates to fill out that view with a TMLC SS and Javascript and then we send that
back to the user so far.
We now know the front end technologies and that mainly falls right there under the template sets h TMLC
SS and Javascript.
We're going to be doing next.
Is learning enough python to then we can use Django to actually understand this essential workflow.
OK so now it's time to learn Python enough to successfully use the jingle framework that we just described.
That's a very high level overview.
And as we go through the back end make sure to visit the documentation for Django.
It's actually really well written and we'll get into why it's so well-written.
Later on when we talk about Django.
OK.
Now quick caveat and quick no many Jingles tutorials dive straight into a clone project where you're
guided through a clone of a popular Web site.
Maybe they guide you through a clone of Twitter of Reddit etc..
This course is going to take a slightly different split approach where we create a very simple web site
first and then we move on to clone's So we first develop a very simple web site and the Web site is
just going to be a simple registry of user provided links with some basic user interactivity.
The reason we don't do a clone at first is because this doesn't really provide the best learning experience
for fundamental concepts with a simpler web site approach.
We can give really clear explanations on the actual fundamental concepts and how Gengel works.
Usually if you just start off straight into a clone you have a good idea of how to create that specific
clone Web site but you don't really have a good understanding of the fundamentals in order to create
your own specific Web sites.
And this approach also allows us to add an exercises that you can try out independently so that we can
test your knowledge on the core concepts instead of just guiding you through a code along where you
don't really get a chance to test your knowledge once you've gotten the main concepts down the simple
website.
Then we can tackle clone projects the later sections of the course will then utilize those clone projects
introduce more of anti-cop concepts things like social logons authorisations security the placement
IX cetera.
So we do have clone's and there are a great way to introduce those topics in a fun and interesting way.
All right.
Get ready to learn a lot this half of the course is where you really get to build all the cool stuff
and eventually you'll find yourself just staring at your computer thinking whoa that I just build a
freakin Web site and it's really exciting stuff.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.