Hello everyone and welcome to part nine of the social club project.
Now we're going to jump over to the Post's application and set up our views that PI filed there a lot
of the views will require extra methods to ensure that certain privileges are connected correctly to
the logged in user and selected group.
But we're also going to need to do is install a library called Django that braces and you can do that
at your command line with Pippin's Telecinco dash braces and this allows us to access some convenient
mixdowns to use with class based views.
All right let's up over to the editor because the Post's fuse up high file get started already here
and at my posts views that PI file is going to collapse the directory tree to give us a little more
room.
I'm going to start off by doing a couple of imports.
We're first going to say from jingo talk contrib off the Nixons in poor loggin required Nixon.
That way we know someone has to be logged in to actually do a lot of these post actions such as creating
a new post.
Then we're also going to save from Jingo the core the Yoro resolvers import reverse lazy so that in
case some wants to delete a post we have that reversely is a call which you can use later.
And then we also are going to be using some generic class based views.
I will say from Jingo the views import generic and there we're also going to be using HTP 404.
That way we can return for a four page later on so will say from jingo HTP import HTP 404.
Save that and then finally we'll save from Brace's views in poor select related mixin.
Now remember that you have to install braces as we just discussed in the slides and you can do that
just by going to your command line.
And that your command line instead of your virtual environment just say Pipp install Shingo dash braces
enter and then let them install.
Now my requirements are already satisfied because I've already installed it before this lecture.
OK so now we have Brace's ready to go.
And then I'm also going to say from the import models so that smacks role models for the post and then
later on we're actually going to create a form for the post.
So we'll say from the import forms although we haven't actually created the forms up high file yet although
we'll do that later on.
And then I will say from Jingo that contrib a th import get user model and that's going to be a function
that allows me to set a user object equal to get user model and then I call it user model.
Basically what that means is when some is logged into a session I'm going to be able to use this user
object as the current user and then call things off of that.
So let's start off with probably the simplest view here and that's going to be the post list view.
So when you select a person you can see a list of all their posts or once you select a group you can
see a list of all the posts for that group.
So we'll start off with the post list class.
And that's going to be lists of posts belonging to a group so we're going to say pass and the selected
related mixin as well as call this a generic list view and then let's give a couple more lines here
all the way back up and inside of this post list.
All we're going to do is connect it to a model the Olby models that post to our post model that we created
earlier and then I'm also going to have this method or attribute selected underscore related which is
just the mixin that allows us to provide a tuple of related models so basically the foreign keys for
this post.
Now that's going to be the user that the post belongs to and the group that the post belongs to.
I'm saving that and up next we're going to create another class for user posts and that's just going
to be a generic list view and let's give ourselves some more room here.
Don't forget that colon and then this is going to be the generic view for the user posts so we'll connect
this with model models.
Post and then we'll give it the template name so the template name is going to be called to post slash
user underscore post underscore list.
HTL OK.
Now we're going to have to add a few more methods in here to make sure that all works correctly when
a user is logged in.
So we're going to have a method called Get underscore queries set past and self and we're going to do
inside this method.
We're going to first try to say self post the user so check if self-oust self-taught post-flight user
is equal to x.
This is really a check.
This is an assignment so assign user to objects and then we're going to call prefetch underscore related
posts.
Remember we can say these different methods or attributes can call off objects as is another one.
There's a giant list of them in the documentation and then off of this we're going to say get.
And we will say get the username underscore exact underscore or excuse me equals self-taught keyword
args that gets in print C's user name and that's it.
So we're going to first try to do this whole giant life.
So let's explain what's going on here.
Here we're going to try to get the queries set.
So basically when you call user post that list view what does it actually going to attempt to do here
is going to try to set postop user.
That is the user that belongs to this particular post equal to user that users objects are going to
prefetch related posts.
And then this user name should be a double underscore as I described before in previous lectures we
can call these double underscores and you can see how the syntax highlighting changes.
And then we're going to get the user name is exactly equal to the user name of whatever is user logged
in or whatever user you happen to click on.
So we're going to try to do that and then we're going to match this try call with an accept call tool
say except and we'll say except this the user does not exists for some reason the user got deleted.
So say either it does not exist and this is just an attribute I will raise HTP four or four and we don't
have to actually call that you just raise it and then else I'm going to return self post underscore
user posts.
The law Okay and we'll save that.
Now this is basically just to make sure that when you call the query for the user post that these are
actually exists and then you're able to fetch the posts that are related to that user using this check
right here.
I exact continuing on what we're going to do one more method here.
The ref also underscore context data that's going to be self.
And then some keyword arguments
and then we'll say context is equal to super underscore context data and then passing keyword arguments
and then we'll say context post underscore user is equal to self-taught poster's core user.
And then I'm finally going to return that context that way I'm just returning the context data object
essentially connected to whoever actually posted that that specific user OK.
Moving along we have a couple of more classes these are much simpler than this one is probably the most
complicated class that we had to deal with just connecting this post.
The users actually want to do it just to post the tail.
So I'll say post detail and that's going to take in that select related mixin as well as a generic detailed
view essentially this is the detail view and you click on a singular post and what happens is we just
connect this model's up post and then we'll say select related and we're going to connect it with some
foreign keys.
And this is just going to be the user and the group that this post belongs to.
And then after this we're going to say E-F get the queries set self and then I'll say queery set is
equal to super get super thoughts gets queery set and we'll explain all this in just a second.
And then we will say return the queery set and we're going to filter it.
So what are we going to filter this.
We want to check that the user's user name is exactly equal to where self keyword arguments get that
user name.
Kind of similar to what we were doing before with this get queery set.
So again all we're doing here is we're saying OK get the query set for the actual post and then I want
you to filter where the user name.
We're going to passen as you go to the user name and have to be exactly the user's username.
Centrally just that username off that model's object.
And I know the sort of syntax can be really strange.
First those double underscores and the sort of object model that object relation model that Django has.
But definitely check out the documentation that can help a lot essentially just go through those examples
of really well-written documentation there go through it and this will become clear and clear as you
see more and more examples of this.
It's definitely really weird at first the sort of customized get query calls OK.
Moving on we have two more classes we want to create for those views and that is a create Post and a
delete post.
So for the create class or create post we're going to say create a post and this will have a log in
required of mixin a select required mixin or select related Mixner I should say and then generic create
view then it gives some extra lines here inside of this we'll start off by saying fields.
So the fields to want someone to be able to edit is just the message of the actual post and then the
group that the post belongs to and then the model can be models the post and we just want to check that
the form is valid.
So we'll say DPF form underscore valid as a method and it has taken self and the form and then this
will be self object as equal to form that's safe and we're going to set commit equal to false
and then say self object user and set that equal to the request user.
So the actual user that's at the request.
And then we will say self object save.
And essentially what this is just to connect the actual post to the user itself and then once for those
that will say return super form the form score valid Pessin form save.
And then finally we have to delete post which will be the other class called Delete post and that's
going to be logged and acquired a mixin a select related mixin and another generic view.
In this case the delete view get some more lines and here come back up and we'll connect this to a model
so they'll be models that post then we will also say select related and set equal to the user and group
as we've just been doing before and he's to be in a string.
And then we're going to say success you're ill and that's going to be reversed lazy and that's going
to go to post.
All so you can use that your template tagging.
So basically what that means is once you delete a post well what's the success you or else if you hit
Yes I confirmed delete.
It should take you back somewhere.
Reverse lazy and we'll just go back to all the posts.
Then we're going to say the F A.
Get queries set self.
And then we'll say the queries set of this is equal to super get queries set and then I'm going to return
queries set that I just made that variable then going to filter out the user ID is equal to self request
user ID.
OK so that's the parameter and for the filter and then finally I'm going to have a delete method on
this self arx keyword arguments and that's going to be the messages success and will say self-taught
request and will send and post deleted and then we're going to return super delete and you can look
up a lot of these kind of convention calls in the documentation for a delete view.
A lot of these things are really just chosen by the convention that delete views to delete you.
Kind of expects if you want to mess around with what happens after you click delete.
It has a delete method for it or get queries set.
So a lot of these things were not actually making up the terms or methods or variables.
To use a lot of them just come with the class based views.
We've already seen a couple of them.
Things like model are success you are all methods like Duleep are just on top of that kind of thing.
OK.
So that should be everything we need for actual views not pie and what we need to do next is linked
up to our Urals in our postop pi.
So let's come over to the posts folder.
Open up your Olsdorf pie here and then fill out the Euros we need we'll say from jingo CNF for configuration
you Elle's import euro and then I'm also going to save from the import views and let's give this app
a name of posts that we can use that in our template tags.
Then we will say you are all patterns is equal to and essentially now it's just time to make all the
list of your old patterns and I'm going to collapse the directory tree to get a little more room here
and also offer further expression.
So for the actual If you just go to your domain name dot com slash posts will say dollar sign.
And this would just give views post list as underscore view and I will just give this the name all so
simple view they're the next Euro.
We can do for a new post if someone wants to make any post.
Those just go to post slash new dollar sign and then this will be the Create post so views dot create
post as a view and the name is equal to.
Then after that we're going to do is for the user post.
So when you click on a user you can see a list of all their posts and then we all need to do the post
detail and delete posts.
So start with that user post so say your all in here again regular expression and this will be by or
honestly whatever you want to call that and then we'll use some regular expressions here which is just
going to look similar to what we just used in the past.
Question Mark P and then open tag username clothes tag and then we'll use another regular expression
minus backslash w plus sensuousness matches up the user name.
So when you go to your domain name that compote slash by Slash who's every user name then we can actually
have buse dot user posts as you and we'll give this the name for user.
So I believe that's what we've been using and the templates will say for underscore user.
And then we want just one more or two more actually the post detail.
So it's actually going to look really similar to this as far as regular expressions are going to copy
this entire string.
And this shows all the user posts.
So then we're going to do one more slash and we're going to copy and paste this actually let's just
write it out so we can see more detail here.
We'll see princes.
Question mark p. open tag.
P.K. close to backslash.
The plus forward slash dollar sign.
Views post the tail as a view and will give this the name single
and the last one is just if you want delete something it will be delete and then we want it to connect
to the actual primary key here because we already know it's going to be that user itself that is going
to be able to delete them so I'll say delete the primary key and then dollar sign and then use that
delete post as a view but the name is equal to delete perfect So those are the URLs we need so we definitely
did a lot here and has a lot of new stuff that we haven't actually seen yet.
Whoops let me make sure that says From there we go.
So let's quickly review everything we just did.
We'll start off with the views so imposed views not pi.
We ended up doing is essentially a bunch of imports that were going to use later and we start off a
very simple one.
Just the post list but remember before that we wanted user equal to get user model so we could play
around and pass that in if needed.
So Clast post list.
So this shows a list of the posts related to either the user or the group or both of them really since
post model has that.
Then we have the user post so that's the list view for a specific users post and then we have this get
queries sent method which essentially just checks where the username is exactly equal to the get user
name of who's ever logged in right now so you can see here that user object that we set up.
They get user model.
This is where we could use it.
So let's see.
Or am that Gengel provides that object relational model or mapper then we have the context data which
allows us to grab that post-Easter and then return the contex dictionary for that.
Then we have the post details when you select a particular post.
There is a detail view on it.
Again just connected to the post model and select related that should be in a string.
So good catch there.
Save that and then we have the Create post and again that's just when you want to create a post the
message in the group and then we check to the form is valid and then we had delete posts.
Very simple thing except we added a little more on this delete method to actually return something saying
the post was deleted.
OK so finally after that we said you Elle's that pi and just matched up all the Euro patterns that we
just created.
Definitely check out the documentation for a lot of these class based views.
If you are having trouble with some of these methods such as the get context data or get query set the
documentation really explains those thoroughly.
Those are methods you're going to use as you get more advanced in Jingo.
A lot of the class based views you can use them without these additional methods.
In fact we've seen that already in the past.
So with that group's application it's only when you start getting more advanced or want certain functionality
that you'll end up adding on with extra methods.
A lot of the functionality you'll be using for a lot of your own projects probably at the start are
going to work just fine with class based views.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.