Hello everyone and welcome back to part six objects exercise.
So for this exercise check out the file Part 6 underscore objects underscore exercise that Jap's which
is under the javascript level 2 folder it contains three objects.
Along with tasks that involve you adding methods to each of these objects.
Let's take a quick look at this file and what you have to do.
OK so this is what the file looks like.
It has three problems which have three basic objects.
You get an object that looks like this for the first one and then we want you to add a method called
name length that prints out the length of an employee's name to the consul.
And then for problem to you're given the same object this employee object with the name job and age.
And we want you to write a program that will create an alert in the browser of each of the objects values
for the key value pairs.
So for example it should ILIR name is John Smith job as programmer age is 31.
So remember the use of this keyword in order to solve this and then back to Problem 3 the very last
one.
We just want you to add a method called last name that prints out the employee's last name to the council.
And for this you got to do a little bit of research because notice the name comes as just a single string
with a space in between and you're going to need to figure out how to split a string to an array.
And there's a hint here linked to W3 schools where they show you how to do that.
Right.
Those are the three problems.
Pretty simple.
I'll see at the next lecture where we actually cut through the solutions.