Well everyone welcome back to Part 6 ogic exercise solutions.
We're going to be cutting through the solutions for the previous exercises.
Let's hop over and get started.
OK.
For the first problem we had to do was actually console log the length of this name so how can we do
that.
Well first we need to create a method called the method name lines and then when I'm going to do is
call the function and then have the set of curly brackets here and I will console log.
And then I'm going to say this guy name that link and we didn't see an exact example of this of calling
another property off the initial key value pair property the Hopefully are able to figure this out.
So again this refers back to employee or current object.
Do we have a name which is this property right here.
And then I want to grab the link to that name which I say with that length and that's how you grab the
length off of this name.
Let's go down to Problem number two and Problem number two we wanted to write a program that will create
an alert in the browser of each of the object values and the key value pairs.
So for example it should alert.
My name is John Smith job as programmer age is 31.
So I'll call this method report we call the function won't have a name and then I say alerts and I'm
going to say name is in loans concatenate everything we need we want this done name.
And then I also want to concatenate Khama job is and then I want to say this job and then I'm going
to concatenate with comma ages and then concatenate that with this dot age and that's all you had to
do for this one.
It's basically a bunch of this calls.
So again this employee and then grabbed the actual properties name job and age and concatenate that
all into a single alert call.
All right.
Finally the last problem.
Problem number three which was add a method called last name that prints out the employee's last name
the con..
This is a little bit trickier because you had to figure out how to split a string to an array in order
to just grab this right here.
Let's show you how we can do that.
You were able to figure it out or create a method called last name type in function and then going to
do is say cancel the log and I will grab this name and we had to do was you had to figure out you can
call that split on a string and then as a parameter to that split method you can passen whatever you
want to split on.
And I want to split on a blank space here between the first and last name and then after that that returns
an array.
So index for the second item in the array which is the last name.
Index 1 and that's how you can create a method that prints out the employee's last name.
So again just to quickly review this one.
This becomes the actual object we're in right now called the Data named property and that's the string
John Smith.
I'm going to take John Smith and then call split and I pass in an empty string here.
Well it's not empty space there because I want to split on the space and that returns an array of two
items.
The first name and the last name John and Smith and I want to grab the second item index one which is
Smith and that's the last name.
OK hopefully you enjoyed those.
And you were able to figure them all out if you had a little bit of trouble with them.
Don't worry about it too much.
We'll get more practice later on the course.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next section.