Welcome everyone to Part 11 of the social club project before we can begin debugging we have to add
in views for leaving and joining groups.
We kind of left those views untouched and now we're going to add them in it's going to be too class
based views and then we're going to connect them to the Urals not py file inside of the group's application.
Once we've done that we should be ready to go for debugging and testing.
The reason we have to do this before we actually jump straight into debugging is that we'll get a lot
of errors because instead of a lot of our templates we're actually calling groups join in groups leave
for those actual buttons and we need some sort of view to at least connect them.
Let's hop over to the editor and finish that up.
All right here we have the views the PI file for groups application and we help create group single
group and list groups and I'm going to create two more class based views.
And that's going to be a joint group I'll pass there for now.
And a Leib group and they're gonna look really similar.
Just one is going to be for leaving a group and another one's going to be for joining a group.
Let's start with join group.
First off to join a group should be logged in so will have log in required Mixon and we're going to
use another generic class based view.
And that one's going to be a redirect for you.
So once someone clicks on join we should do some stuff on the back and for models to join the actual
user to be a member of that group and then we're going to redirect to another page so that we can do
here is say if there's a method we can define called Get redirect you are el.
And that will allow us to grab whatever we wanted direct them to.
Once they join it group will say self arcsin keyword arguments and we're going to return a reverse call.
So in order to use reverse make sure you scroll up here and actually import it it's right here under
your own resolver so we're good to go.
The only collapse that directory tree get a little more room here and there we're going to redirect
to groups single.
So that will be the detail view of that particular group.
Now in order to know what groups we're talking about we're going to add in a keyword arguments dictionary
and it's just going to define slug as self keyword arguments lips self cured arguments get slug.
Essentially you just get whatever slug of the page or clicking button that you're on the group of.
And that's all you need to do forget redirect you are all and know what we can do is add in some more
checks in case this person is already a member of the group so you can say the F gets and they will
be self request and that takes an args and keyword arguments and a well-defined group as object.
In fact we're going to need to import this was a good object or for or for which either means try to
get the group that this person is currently looking at or return a four or four page.
So in order to use this command we're going to scroll back up and then we'll say from jingo shortcuts
import objects or four or four.
And you also notice there's a get list option but we're just looking for a single object so just say
group and then we will say group is what we want.
So then we're going to add in a couple more things we will say group slug and slug is going to be able
to self keyword arguments get slug
and then we're going to try we will say group member objects creates user is equal to self request user
work group is equal to a group.
All right so what does that actually mean.
I'm going to try to get the group member objects and create one where the user is equal to the current
user and group to group.
So creating a number and then I will have an accept accept and I can actually accept a specific error.
So the specific error we're looking for is an integrity error.
Well you don't have to technically you can just say except you don't have that right in the air here.
So it can say integrity air.
And then we will say messages warning and in order to use messages you're actually going to need to
import it so let's scroll back to the top and say from Jingo that contrib import messages these are
basically things we can send back to the user.
So say from lips from Jingo that contrib import messages so we can send the message hey you're already
a member of that group.
If you're trying to join it again and then say itself the request and then we actually pass and what
we want to warn here so we can say warning already a member so that will be if they're already a member
we'll get some sort of error there.
Else we're going to say is messages success Noll's say self-taught requests and then say is a second
crap.
This is not supposed to be an equal sign neither is this supposed to pass in the self.
And then here we're going to say as a second argument you are now a member.
We actually don't need these princes here.
It's just the second argument.
OK.
So that should be it for that.
And then at the end of all this get we're going to return calls super gets request arcs and then he
word arguments and then save that.
So we're doing here is if you're joining a group we have this redirect you are ill from this a view
that just says OK once you join the group go back to that group's single detail page and then for this
we want to make sure that a person is going to receive some sort of error or warning message if they're
already inside the group and a good way to do that is by using jingoes built in messages from contrib.
So using that you can just try to do what we would do which is grab a group member object and create
it with the user equal to the current user and group equal to group which we just said Get object or
create.
So that's where groups coming from.
So this group right here is linked to this group right here on line 29 and then we can say except integrity
air.
And you can just actually say except So if there's any sort of air you could just say for instance this.
That's totally fine as well say that they were going to send some warning message says hey you're already
a member.
Otherwise if it works we'll say you're now a member and then we're just going to return super get requests
and then Arkes and keyword arguments then we're going to fix this for LIBOR and actually be pretty similar.
So for lebe group we're going to again say you should be log in to leave a group and we'll also have
a generic redirector view.
So once you leave a group you should be directed somewhere.
So I'll say in fact this will just make it the exact same thing.
Once you leave a group you get redirected to that group's page.
You can also make it redirect to the home page if you want it to or the grouplets page but we'll keep
things simple and experiment and Titian's right there is.
So again pretty much the exact same thing when you leave a group you'll be redirected to that group's
detail page.
And then finally we'll have a get method very similar to the one we just made.
So it's going to be self request arx keyword arguments to make sure that they can't accidentally leave
a group that are not really in it.
So we're going to do is first try we will try to get a object we'll call it membership and set that
equal to models group member and they'll be objects and I'm going to filter those objects.
And we will filter only start this new line user is equal to self request user and then group underscore
underscore underscore underscore slug Ziegel to self-taught keyword arguments get slug and then off
all that we're going to just call get method.
So we're going to attempt to try to get a membership and that's all that group member assuming that
the user is already in that group.
So grab the group slug grab the user off that group member object and that's going to be my little membership
that are going to be playing around with and then I'm going to be except now I can say models group
member does not exist.
That's an actual thing I can call off that group member object.
So if that thing does happen to actually exist it means that group member was never actually a member
of that group.
So you excellently click delete button on a group you were never a member of to say messages warning
self-taught request.
Basically same thing we're doing last time and says Sorry you are in this group and let's say you are
not so don't have to worry about syntax for single quotes.
OK so sorry you are in the group.
Else we're going to do is if everything's working we'll say membership and we can call a delete method
off of this and then we're going to say messages and call a success message and then pasand the request
request and says you have left the group then I'm going to return super gets passen request person or
X and then person keyword arguments.
OK so that should be looking good.
I'm going to save this and the next thing I want to do is make sure I actually connect these views to
my your stop PI file.
So let's open that up.
Else that pie inside of groups we have a couple of more views to do so we'll come over and we'll add
in the leave and join view to the left profile we'll say you're all
join forward slash and we will say we're actually going to just grab and copy and paste the same thing
here.
Join and then we will say views.
Join a group and call that as a view and give that the name join since that's what we did in the templates.
And then the other thing we're going to do is add in the leave.
So let me just copy and paste this into the same thing.
Copy paste instead of join.
It's going to say leave and sort of join group.
It will be great.
And then set the name join it will be leave so we're going to save that and that's it for the join and
leave views that we had to create.
So again over and views.
He's definitely more complicated views so we kind of waited till now for joining a group and leaving
group.
They're really really similar.
They're both read direct views.
Meaning you just kind of define OK what's this person's perform this action.
Where should they go to.
And that's the redirect view and I can actually pass keyword arguments and grab things off that current
requests such as the slug that they're looking at to go to that detail page and then we have to get
methods both in leave and join group and basically what these do is check to see if the user can actually
perform the given action.
If he didn't have these try except.
Else calls here.
You may just get broken pages if the person wasn't in the group and then try to join it and then try
to join it again etc. instead of doing all that they can just have these messages show up and that will
help fix any issues.
OK so that's it.
We should now be ready to take care of a few more things in settings that pi connect everything and
start the bugginess.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.