Hello everyone.
Welcome to Part 7.
Name and main and often confusing part of Python especially as you begin to learn about modules is this
mysterious line of code that looks something like this.
If name is equal to mean and then some code underneath it will sometimes importing from a module you
would like to know whether modules function is being used as an import or if you're using the original
dot py file of that module.
Let's explore this some more.
But make sure to check out the full explanatory text file that's in this parts folder.
Let's get started.
OK here I am at the editor and to get started I'm going to make two files.
I will make a one up my file that's O and e that pi and I'm going to make another file that's called
to that PI T w o p y.
And then I can say a split left or split right.
And then I can see them side by side.
OK.
So again as I mentioned sometimes when you're importing from a module you would like to know whether
a module's function is being used as an import or if you're using the actual original DUP PI file.
So as we saw before if I'm importing something from two into one and I run the one that up PI script
I want to know did that function directly come from one or was it imported from two.
And you can determine this by using the if name is equal to main statement.
And when your script is run by passing it as a command to the Python interpreter such as we've done
with Python notes that pi all of the code that is at the indentation level 0 gets executed in functions
and classes that are defined are well-defined.
But none of their code gets.
Unlike other languages.
There's no main function that gets run automatically.
The main function is implicitly all the code at the top level.
And in this case that top level code is that of an IF block and that's the if name is equal to main.
So let's actually show this one going.
In my one PI file say d f func.
And here I will say Prince phunk in one pie and we can collapse that tree.
And then I'm going to print top level one up high.
What's
And here I will say if and note that actually get this code automatically for me.
So if I underscore underscore name underscore underscore is equal to and in string there main and then
it says Execute main.
But we're going to delete that for now and say print one up high is being run directly and then I can
actually have an L statement with this as well.
Else.
Print 1.
Pi is or has been imported.
So I will save this and then into that pie and willing to write the following.
I will say import one and then say Prince top level
to that pi and then from one I will say call one that phunk and then I'll say if Again name is equal
to mean Prince
to that pi being run directly and then else and you don't often see an else but it can definitely work
fine else we'll say 2 is being imported.
In other well I'll just say is being imported.
Now if we invoke the interpreter here with Python one PI and I hit enter no to say get back out top
level 1 that PI one PI is being run directly.
And if I run Python to that pi I get top level 1 that PI one that pi has been imported top level to
the pi function one PI to that Pye's being run directly in all of this works because of this name.
So this underscore underscore name underscore underscore is a built in variable which evaluates to the
name of the current module.
However like I mentioned if a module is being run directly as in the one PI or my script that PI kind
of deal the name instead is being set to the string main.
So whenever I run to that PI correctly then this variable name is set to equal mean when I run it directly
here.
And thus you can test whether or not your scripts being run directly or being imported by something
else.
OK.
That's really all we wanted to get across here that if you ever see if name is equal to main It's basically
a way of initiating the code in your main file but also checking to see if you're importing functions
from another file or calling them directly from the file you're currently in.
So if you ever see this phrase or this line of code don't be confused.
A lot of times you'll see at the very bottom of that pie file and then all the main logic of the code
will come here so often you'll see a bunch of functions in a file that says that pi.
You get this line of code.
Now you see a bunch of code logic that uses the functions and classes defined above it.
So hopefully I'm not intimidated if you see it again.
Definitely read the notes for this.
But as far as this course concern that's really all you need to know the basics of how you can set this
up to determine whether you're using something directly or importing it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.