Hello everyone and welcome back to Part 9 javascript level 1 project.
So we've completed all the normal lectures for dropped script level 1 and now it's time to actually
do a project for this project.
You'll be creating a simple web site that asks the visitor questions using javascript and the prompt
function that we worked with earlier.
However through all of these questions you're going to be secretly checking to see if there is a spy
present and the spy is going to answer the questions in a very particular way.
Behind the scenes are going to be using javascript to check for certain correct answers to questions.
And if you find the spy do the correct answers you're going to leave them a secret message in the console
for them to check.
OK.
You're going to be needing to check the part 9 underscore J s underscore project but a team file has
the full instructions and the full correct answers.
An example solution of the job secrets file is located under Part 9.
Yes.
So remember to link to your own dot script before getting started.
So again you're only going to be editing a javascript file.
You won't actually be touching any Timo.
All right let's briefly explore the instruction page and see an example of what it should look like.
After you're done with it and what hop over to the editor room browser now.
OK here you have the actual HTML document open in my editor and also it links to the javascript filed
a contains the solutions and this is what it looks like over here in the browser.
So again just quickly to point out if you scroll all the way down on the part 9 javascript project body
smell page right here under the script connection.
It will connect to the solution script so it'll actually connect to part 9.
But yes that's what you can connect it to if you want to see what an example solution looks like in
your browser.
But I recommend that once you're done dealing with that you change the source to your own javascript
file so you can play around with working through the solution again everything you're doing is just
in a javascript file.
You won't actually be editing and he watched him for this.
So let me show you what he actually asked him ilks like I've linked to here in my browser and going
to zoom in a little bit so we can read it together.
But here we have the welcome to part 9 your javascript level 1 project.
And like I mentioned for this project you're going to be building a generic web site that just seems
to ask some mundane questions that normal users but secretly you are looking for a spy and anyone visiting
your web site is going to be asked a series of questions but only the spy is going to give you specific
answers that you expect.
And if all the questions are answered correctly you're going to post a secret message in the Council
for the spy to read.
So it's up to you what ever the secret messages be going to use cancel that log.
If the answer the questions correctly.
So here are the four conditions you're going to be checking for the spy.
So the spy has the same first letter of her first name and her last name.
So for example someone could be named Jose Johnson and J and J match.
So that's the first letter and last letter.
So that's a correct condition for the spy.
The spy is also between the age of 20 and 30 exclusive of 20 at 30.
So for example a 26 year old spy works.
Then the spy is also at least 170 centimeters tall.
Here we have 175 centimeters.
And the spy has a pet name that ends with the letter Y.
And in this case a pet name of Sammy would work.
So you're going to ask the spy for their first name last name.
What is their age.
What is what is their height in centimeters and what is their pet name.
And if the answer we think correctly according to these conditions so you're going to check these conditions
using everything you learned about control flow.
You will log a secret message to the consul and then they can inspect the page look at the consul and
see if you left them anything.
All right.
So again we're just using javascript here and you can prompt for the information in any order you want
and you can even do things like separate the first name prompt from the last name prompt.
They'll probably make your life a little easier but all we're doing is just checking to see if these
four conditions are true.
This one this one this one and this one.
So let's actually refresh this page and see what happens.
Well this actually looks like we're going to refresh and it says Hello and welcome please and to your
first name we'll say Jose.
And your last name will see Johnson.
How old are you.
We'll say 26.
We'll say we're 175 centimeters in the net.
The name of our pet is Sammy.
Oh OK.
Thank you so much for the information.
OK.
And that's it it looks like nothing happened.
But if I inspect and go to my counsel it says Welcome comrade you've passed us by test and exam and
we are going to be doing.
Let's refresh page and make sure that if I just put garbage.
So let's say my name is Andy will I am 42 and 10 centimeters tall.
My name or my pet is I don't know said OK.
And it says sorry nothing to see here.
OK.
Hopefully you get an idea of what this project's actually getting at in the next lecture.
I'll be coding out some solutions in the script file.
Thanks everyone.
Hope you enjoy the project.
I'll see you at the next lecture.