Hello everyone and welcome back.
Hopefully already attempted the javascript level and project because in this lecture we'll be coding
through an example solution for it.
OK I'm excited so let's get started by hopping over to the editor.
OK.
So here we have my editor open.
I've linked the html file to my own script.
My script is right now empty.
So nothing's going on.
When I refresh the page.
So let's expand or editor at everything we need and then we'll test it out with the actual web site
page.
So I'm going to zoom in just a little more so we can see everything clearly.
OK.
The first thing I need to do is have the four conditions that I'm going to be checking.
Remember those four conditions are this.
It's the name condition so I'm going to make variables for these.
And the name condition will have that be NULL to start off with the name condition.
Is this their first name.
First letter of the first name matched the first letter of their last name and you can actually not
have them be null they can be anything because we're going to be reassigning these later on but I'm
going to make them null to be clear that they're nothing right now.
And if you want we can put some icons there the conditions so they have to be between 20 and 30 exclusive.
We also have the high condition that's going to be No.
And then we also finally have the same condition.
So I will say var that condition is nil.
OK so those are the four conditions that I'm checking for.
But remember I'm actually going to need to at least ask some questions.
So let's put those questions at the top and going to grab the first name.
It's going to be a prompt whoops.
Now what I wanted it prompts and I will ask first name please.
And you can basically write as much or as little as you want and then ask for the last name and I'm
going to.
Sorry about that.
There it is prompt.
OK.
I'm going to ask for the last name please.
And then the next variable i want is age.
So I'm going to ask how old are you.
Questionmark
also on height.
So that's another promt.
So just a bunch of prompts so we ask the user when they reached a page.
What is your Height's question mark.
And then finally that name will ask for a prompt.
What is your name questionmark.
So we have everything after all of that.
I'm just going to say it.
Thank you so much for the information.
And it doesn't matter a whole lot whether we define these four condition variables before or after this.
But I like the idea of grabbing all the variables that we need from the user first and then having all
our logic follow it.
So we had those four conditions.
Let's start using control flow to actually check that these conditions are true or false.
So the first we need to check is the name condition remember the name.
Condition asks is the first letter of their first name and the first letter of their last name.
The same thing.
So I'm going to say if first name index at zero is equal to last name index at zero set the name condition
to be equal to true else the name condition is going to be equal to false.
That's a quick and easy way we can check if their first letter of their first name matches the first
letter of their last name.
Now we want to check the age condition.
So how do we do that.
Well we want to say if age is greater than 20s or are we doing exclusive.
So I don't put that equal sign and ages less than 30 so we make sure not to over shoot this.
I will say that the age condition Zuko is a true else.
I know they didn't pass the age test.
Age condition is equal to false.
And hopefully now you can see why we could have assigned something else for the age condition we could
have assigned them all to be true or all to be false to begin with.
Moving along we have our age we have the first name check.
And now I want to check the height condition
so I will say if
it's is greater than or equal to 1 7 Remember it was at least 170 that I want my height condition.
I can see helping us out here to be true and just like the last time I'll say else I condition is equal
to false.
Pretty simple and pretty straightforward so far.
And then last but not least I want to make sure that the pet name is ending with Y.
This was a little tricky because we haven't shown anything quite like this but hopefully you're able
to figure it out.
I'll see if the pet name and then somehow I want to grab the last letter of the pet names.
How do we actually do that.
Well we know how to grab the first letter which is just 0.
But if I want to grab the last letter I'm going to have to take into account that pet names can be of
different lengths and one way it can do that is by calling that name length.
So we might think that this gives us the very last letter but remember indexing starts at zero which
means I need to subtract one from this in order to make it work.
So you can imagine that if I had the pet name just be the letter A.
And I want to check the last letter of the string of a single letter.
I'd have to check 0 right.
So even if it has length of one I'd have to say one minus one to actually grab that last letter.
So that's just a quick explanation of why I have to do the minus one here.
That's because indexing starts at zero and if you don't believe me you can kind of check it out.
Play it yourself and I want to make sure this is equal to why and if that's the case then I know the
condition will be reassigned to true else.
I'll say that condition is equal to false great so have the pet name there and now I just want to check
if all four conditions are true.
So check all conditions
and what I'm going to do here say if the name condition is true.
Hans the age condition is true and the condition is true and the condition is true.
I'm going to log something like welcome's by else we can either not do anything or just say nothing
to see here.
And sometimes what confuses beginners is the fact that I'm just writing here the actual condition and
not saying something like name condition equals true and A's condition equals true etc..
Remember these are already booleans themselves so these conditions should already be booleans by the
time they get to this stage.
They're either all true or all false or some combination of true and false meaning I don't need actually
check.
Is Equal equal.
True because they're actually all conditional tricks.
So basically is going to be something like True and False and True and False or false false and false
are true or untrue etc..
Ok so you can always review the actual part 9 javascript if you want.
The written code for everything not just that here let's say this and actually test it out to make sure
it worked going to expand this.
We are going to refresh
and here we see first name please.
All input Jose last name will say John how old mine will say we are 27.
What is my height.
I'll say 180 centimeters.
Pet name.
I'll say Franki for y.
Thanks so much for the information we Right-Click inspect.
Check the console and it says welcome by.
Let's make sure the inverse is true.
So I refresh this page first name.
Just going insert some garbage.
Last name some other garbage held in my amp.
12 years old will say were 120 centimeters and pet name is Alph.
Now it says nothing to see here Merfolk So it looks like our solution worked correctly.
OK if you have any questions feel free to post them to the Kewney forums.
But you are now complete with javascript.
Level 1.
It's time to move on to javascript level 2.
Thanks and I'll see it the next section of the course.