Hello everyone and welcome to the course overview lecture.
As a quick note I have a favor to ask of you please watch this entire video lecture.
Regardless if you've already taken multiple courses on you to me or even multiple courses by me or if
you're brand new to you to mean or brand new to online learning in general please watch this entire
lecture video will really help your course experience be a lot smoother.
Thank you OK.
Continue on.
We're going to talk about three main things in this lecture.
We'll talk about general of course information how to get the course notes and files and how to get
help.
During the course first off a huge thank you for enrolling.
It really means the world to me.
To get messages from students every day telling them I help them in the careers.
Help them solve a problem at work or that they just really enjoyed the course.
So thank you again for enrolling.
I'm really going to try my best to make sure you have a good experience.
First off let's discuss some general tips for getting the best experience with this course.
You probably noticed that I speak at a pretty steady and deliberate pace so feel free to speed up the
videos.
You can check for a speed icon on the bottom tab.
In fact you can see that this video right now I would personally probably be watching these videos at
about 1.5 or 2 x speed.
But that's my style.
If English is not your first language you can probably also slow down the videos.
So do whatever speed feels right to you.
If a video ever appears blurry.
Make sure to check that you're viewing the video in high definition if you want to download the videos
for offline viewing.
You can do that with the utility app any technical platform issues you may encounter.
Please contact support you to me dot com.
Technical platform issues can be things like having trouble posting to the Q&amp;A forums having trouble
logging into your account or having trouble viewing the actual videos.
Those are technical platform issues.
I can't help you too much there.
So please contact support me dot com.
If you experience those type problems again the course is self-paced and you get lifetime access to
the materials and that includes any updates.
Also upon completion of the course you can unlock a certificate for your linked in profile and you can
check out the fake Q lecture which is the very next lecture.
For more information on how to unlock that certificate.
Now let's talk about how to get the course materials.
You can download all the files as a zip from this lecture.
The fake Q lecture or the installation lecture.
That's this lecture the next lecture in a lecture.
After that it's the same zip file so any one of those lectures is fine.
It's saved as a resource so you should see a little blue resource tab open up while you're watching
the actual video.
Just click on that and then download that zip file future missions to this course will get their own
ZIP file in the relevant section and I will also upload an updated that zip to these 3 lectures.
So what I mean by that is if later on in the future I add a new clone to this course.
Maybe we make a clone of Facebook dot com then I will create 2 zip files.
I will re upload an updated version of the whole zip file but I will also make a separate zip file just
for that section.
That way to have the read download all the notes.
Every time new material is added to this course.
Also as a quick note sometimes the built in unzipping program on your computer may not work for unzipping
a file.
Please try another program before posting to the Kewney forums.
If you're having trouble unzipping files.
Thanks All right.
Now let's talk about how to approach the course this course is divided into sections that lead into
each other.
Each section can be visited independent of the others but they also assume knowledge of all the concepts
covered in previous lectures has a very high level overview general curriculum or what this course has.
We first talk about HCM l CSSA and Javascript and then we continue talking about the document object
model and J.A.G. that's really the front end half of the course.
Then the second half the course discusses the Python programming language how to work with Django and
sequel.
And then after that we have Web site clone projects.
Also keep in mind that we do not assume any previous knowledge.
So you can take this course even if you have zero program experience.
We won't ever assume that you've encountered any other technology before.
However that means if you already have experience you may want to read through the code notes first.
Otherwise you may be viewing video lectures that just go over things you already know.
Again this is trying to be a careful balance for people who have never programmed before and experienced
programmers so beginners should follow through the course in order more experienced developers should
probably visit the curriculum page and decide what the best starting point is for them and be honest
of yourself.
If you start to have trouble if a certain section you may want to go back a section and review that
material OK.
Now let's talk about how to get help during the course.
OK so let's discuss the steps you should take whenever you need help.
During the course the first thing you should do especially if you run into a programming error is use
Google and stack overflow as tools to help you solve that issue.
A big part of being a developer is learning how to answer your own questions by using Google and using
stack overflow stack overflow or just a Web site where you can post questions and other programmers
will help you out.
But a lot of times almost 90 percent of the time your question has been asked by someone else and you'll
already find an answer through Google and stack overflow.
If you still can't find that there you may want to check out the fake Q lecture where I will be posting
commonly ask questions that pertain to the course.
If you still can't find that there and your question is more specific to something in the course search
the Kewaunee forums for previous posts.
It's likely that someone's already asked a similar question to yours while you're viewing a lecture.
You can also look at the bottom tab and you should see a Q and A button you can click that and that
will take it to queue in a post that actually pertains to the specific lecture that you are watching.
If you still can't find the help.
Not to worry.
Post a new question on the Kewaunee forms please include what you've tried your code and as much information
as possible.
That way the students and I can quickly help you out.
Here are some useful ways you can share your code online with us.
You can use code append the IO codependents SEO a just and get hub or even just a plain screenshot or
you can actually copy and paste with formatting your code onto that the to meet Q and 8 forums.
Choose whatever you prefer.
As far as some general information for the question and answer forums for this course you can usually
respect the reply within 24 hours.
In other students reply often so often a reply comes a lot faster in 24 hours that I checked the Kunin
forums at least once a day usually more than that.
You may also just get a quick link reply.
So if I see a questions very similar to yours answered on stack overflow I may just reply with the link.
If you're still confused by that or haven't given you enough information feel free to just continue
the thread asking follow up questions.
I'm always happy to help you out.
Also remember to say thank you especially if another student has helped you out in reply to your question.
It really helps build a great community of students answering these questions.
Also it's a great idea for you to go to the Q&amp;A forums and see if you can help out other students in
the course.
It's a really great skill to have and it really helps your own understanding to answer other people's
questions.
As a final know there are many ways to program and that includes the choice of your development environment.
The styling of the code your programming choices etc..
I don't want you to ever feel locked into the choices we make in this course.
Feel free to explore other options and also feel free to share them as well if you prefer another.
Ideally you prefer another library.
You have different programming styling from your experience.
That's totally ok.
Don't ever feel that you have to do exactly what we do in this course and again just a huge thank you
for enrolling in this course.
I'm so happy you have enrolled and I get to help you on your journey of becoming a web developer.
I'll see you inside the course.
Thanks everyone.