Hello everyone.
Welcome to part one of CSSA level 2 in this lecture we're going to be learning about Funt properties
of CSA such as size weight text alignment etc..
And then we're also going to learn how to download and change fonts when dealing with fonts.
We have to keep in mind that not every OS has every font and if you use both a Windows computer and
a Mac computer or a Linux computer often you'll notice that when you're actually trying to use a file
that was created on Windows on a Mac or vice versa sometimes the fonts have to change in what we're
going to be doing is exploring that relationship because sometimes we need to actually provide the font
for our Web site because the default font isn't available on a certain OS.
Because if this were going to be exploring a few links the first sort of link is about OS support for
certain fonts with its operating system support so what fonts does Windows support what fonts do Mac
support etc..
And then the second set of links is actually going to cover how to download fonts.
We'll be exploring two Web sites.
Google font's site then another site to show you how you can download your own fonts from the internet
or connect them using what's known as a CDN.
Let's go ahead and start off just by showing some basic font properties see SS in the editor and then
we'll hop over to the browser and check out how we can actually download fonts and check OS support
person funds.
I'm going to hop to the editor now.
OK so here and my editor and I have two files open a part one Fahnestock CSSA file and a part 1 Fahnestock
h tim L5.
And if you're looking for the completed version of these files we can always check them out under the
CSSA level 2 folder.
Right now I have them blank and we'll be coding through for this lecture.
Let me collapse that directory.
Lotus I also have my browser open and it's linked to my team l file.
When I first want to do is make some basic T.M..
Hopefully by now you can actually do this quite quickly using Adams built in help.
What I will do is add in a heading one here H-1 and I'll say something like heading 1 and then I'm going
to add two paragraphs to this first paragraph.
You're just going to be lordship summer.
That's that essentially filler Latin text.
And luckily I can just begin to type L O enter in it out of Madingley fills that in for me and I'll
add in one more paragraph but this paragraph is going to have an ID so I can individually target it
in the CSSA file.
We'll say it is equal to two and then warm up some will save that and let's refresh over here to make
sure that's working great we have heading 1 lordship some larm some.
And then what I want to make sure I do is link my CSSA file to make it himself.
Or that always happens in the head.
So I will say link that can begin to type in link enter here.
There really ship is a stylesheet and the H reference is going to be whatever I call that style sheet.
So my case is called Part 1 underscore fonts and as I mentioned previously in another lecture it's a
little unusual to have this sort of naming convention especially if a digit inside the SS file.
But this is just so it matches up with the lecture notes.
OK.
So everything looks good here.
Let's explore some of the basics of fonts with C.
So let's imagine that I actually want to change the fonts.
Right now it looks like it's in Times New Roman.
That's essentially the default if I want to change it to another font.
Maybe something like Arial I can start typing font family and that's going to allow me to then pasan
a property of a different font so we can see that there are some defaults here.
These are very basic.
So let's show you one of the faults there if I just say cursive save this and then refresh over here.
I can see now I have some default cursive it looks pretty ugly but it can also passen as a string.
And that means that I'm wrapping it in either double quotes or single quotes a font name that I'm familiar
with.
Maybe I've worked with a text editor before you're familiar with some font called Aeriel Salome's save
that refresh over here.
Now I can see now it's in aerial versus Times New Roman.
All right.
So that's the basics of a font family but something we're going to have to keep in mind is not every
font family is going to be defaulted on every OS so certain spots are really common between both Owasso
such as Ariel.
It's in like 99 percent of Macs a 99 percent of Windows.
The other font families such as he'll that sukkah is really only existent on Macs and maybe like less
than 10 percent of Windows computers have that font.
And we'll be discussing some Web sites that can help you choose fonts that will be available on both
OSes and later on we'll show you how to just download your own font so you can provide the font file
yourself.
OK let's talk a little bit more about font family so as I mentioned there are those basically default
styles if I want something like monospace I can do that as well for that paragraph.
So let me refresh this here and I can see this is all done in monospace.
Let's say I want to change the actual font size.
Well I can change the font size for everything in the body and the way I do that it's just a font size.
And here I can passen pixels.
So for instance I can say I want it to be 10 pixels in size refresh over here and I can see now it's
in 10 pixels and size 100 pixels and size make it much larger.
Now it's humongous.
OK let's change it back to 10 pixels nexilis do 20 pixels and something to remember is I'm zoomed in
here in my browser.
So it may not look as large to you.
So keep that in mind.
Now something you're probably wondering at this point in time is well what if I don't know the pixels
I want for the font size.
What if I actually want stuff to have a relationship between each other.
So maybe I want the second paragraph to be twice as large as the basic font size on the page.
How do we actually define that and using pixels as I've shown here is actually not very common.
What's more common is to use what is known as E-M values and values is a dynamic way of sizing things.
So when you define the font size property in E-M is equal to the size of the font that applies to the
parent of the element in question.
And that basically means that if you haven't set the font size anywhere on the page.
So let's say I delete this and I haven't set the font size anywhere so we can refresh here.
That's the basic font size then the browser default is often 16 pixels.
So by default then one E-M which would look like this one E-M would be equal to 16 pixels.
This is the default right here.
Which means if I tell another tag to be E-M then it'll be equal to 32 pixels.
Double that.
And then you can get a relationship or a ratio for various tags in your H T.M. what you'll usually do
however is set a font size in the body element.
So he go back here let's comment these out.
Usually what you will end up doing is for the body element you will select a font size and you will
have it be some sort of default font size that you choose.
You can do the 16 pixels which is the same as as the browser default where nothing is fine but let's
say font size is 20 pixels and then from there on the other elements that you want to assign you'll
use E-M which is going to like to do a ratio of this which is basically a ratio of the desired element
pixel value divided by that parent element which in this case is the body.
So let's see just a quick example of this.
I'm going to grab the number to remember that was the second paragraph the state ID and state its font
size is equal to 2.0.
E-M Let's save that will refresh over here.
Now you can see that we have heading on the first paragraph and now the second paragraph is twice as
large in font size as the first one.
So what you're doing here is you're stating some default body font size and then from there you can
actually call the ID font size as a ratio of it what you should avoid doing is trying to actually call
something like H-1 and make it mimic the font size of a paragraph or vice versa.
Trying to make a paragraph as large and as bold enough so that it looks like an H-1 a heading one that's
really not the point of this.
The point of this is that on your page if you have two elements of the same type but you want one to
be a little larger a little smaller than the other one then you start calling them what you don't want
to do is call E-M to the point where you should have just called heading one or heading to the very
beginning.
So keep that in mind and then what I want to show you now is font styles and font weights as well as
text alignment.
So if I call a paragraph here and say font style of paragraph and let me change just font size again
to 1.0 that way everything's the same.
OK looks good I'll say font style here.
Is a tablet so I can save this and now when I refresh my page I can see that everything is italicize.
So you can call font styles her basic things in that manner and you can also call things such as font
weight and that can be things such as bold Lider normal 100 200 etc..
Not every font is going to have every possible font weight.
It really depends on what font you are and what font you use.
And we'll be talking about that in a future lecture.
But we have font weight is bold.
So let's say that I make this both italic and bold in here I can see when I refresh.
Now they're in bolds great.
And finally I want to talk about text properties.
So if we see one one of the properties you're going to be using all all the time is the text alignment
property.
And you can begin to write text dash and you'll see Adam trying to help you out with various text properties.
We've already actually seen text decoration member that has stuff like underline over line line through
what we want to do is talk about text align and text line basically allows you to send her something
just the fight to the left to the right etc..
So if I want to center heading 1 I just say text the line center on that added element.
So I will save that refresh my page over here and I can see now heading 1 is aligned to be Center.
Great OK we're talking a lot more about alignments and how alignments work with mobile devices when
we talk about bootstrap.
But for right now what I want you to get out of this lecture is the following that you can call font
families have some awareness of that.
Some fonts don't work on every OS.
Now we'll be talking about that in the very next lecture as a continuation of the series.
Then you can call font families for very basic things such as monospace or some of the other options
if we take a look or things such as cursive or Sarah first answer if we can save that as well then for
font size what I want you to make sure you get out of the picture is that you can call a pixel.
But what you should probably do is call an E M based off the default for the body.
Then you can call font styles and font weights as well as do text alignment.
All right.
Thanks everyone.
In the next lecture we're going to be continuing this one discussion of fonts and talking about what
fonts work with which OS how you can figure that out and how you can download your own font from the
internet to use it for your web site.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.