Hello everyone and welcome to part one Dom interaction and this lecture will use javascript to actually
interact with DOM elements so as I mentioned we're going to begin to see examples of how we can actually
grab h T.M. elements from the document object model and these HTL elements are the properties of that
javascript object which is the document.
So we're going to be covering how to grab large groups of elements like the entire body of the HTML
or just the head of the T.M. and then we'll focus on grabbing specific HTML items.
Maybe your instrument just grabbing a certain class or a certain ID and in feature lectures will show
you how you can interact with those objects.
So right now we're just focusing on grabbing those elements themselves in future lectures We'll show
you how to change the colors or affect their properties somehow.
OK.
Here are some important document attributes so you can call document and say Dot your L body that head
that links so that your L that's actually going to return the actual You l of the website that body
that's everything inside the body is going to return each time of the entire body document.
The head is going to return everything that's in the head of the page.
And then that links those are all the links that are on the page and there are many methods for grabbing
specific elements from the document object model.
And these methods are usually pretty self-explanatory except for those last two.
But first off let's start off with element by ID so element by the.
That returns an element with whatever ID you pass in.
So imagine that your T.M. has a specific ID that you clarified earlier when creating the HCM L. S. document
that element by ID will actually grab those elements.
Well usually ID is a single element by the ID you.
Then you can get element by class name so pass in a class and Ill return a list of all items belonging
to that class then document that element by tag name returns a list of all elements of a certain tag.
So if you want everything that has an anchor tag you can do that as well.
Then we have queery selector and query selector all there.
A little more new than the previous three but they're still pretty well used.
Now the painting when you actually are viewing this.
But the query selector returns the first object matching the CSSA style selector and then query selector
all returns all objects matching the CSA style selector.
And we're going to show examples of query selector and query selector all since we're going to be using
those a lot.
So again the first three there are pretty self-explanatory but the query selector can accept any CSSA
style selectors so you can use things like the hash tag to clarify it's an ID or the DOT if you want
a class.
So basically anything for CSSA that you use as a style selector.
You can just pass directly into query selector and if that's unclear to you now don't worry I'll show
it plenty of examples as we move along.
But again the difference between group selector in the query selector all is that query selector all
returns a list of all matches group selector it just returns the first match.
OK the relevant files for this particular lecture are part 1 main page for each symbol and part one
color changer that Jap's we're going start off by this connecting the aged female file from color change
about javascript and exploring it a bit manually then we're going to cut out a complex example which
is actually going to be color change.
Yes.
All right let's explore these various methods and get started by opening up those two files in the editor
and linking them to our browser.
OK so here we have part one main page T.M. open in my editor and I also have open in my browser on the
right hand side and something you notice that's probably pretty interesting to you.
Is that the heading one is randomly changing color.
And you're probably wondering how the heck is that happening.
Well in this lecture we're going to actually cut out the example that creates that effect in order to
begin explaining how we can grab elements from the document object model and then effect them using
javascript.
But what we're going to do start off is in part one underscore main underscore page scroll all the way
down.
Now you should see the connection to the part 1 color changer that Jack script what I want you to do
is comment this out to begin with.
Save it and then refreshed the connection page.
And you should see it just turn to black.
We're going to be focusing on right now is grabbing those common document attributes and then showing
the various methods we have to grab.
Ace HTML elements.
So let's get started on that.
I'm going to expand my browser and start off by exploring these points right here.
The tree also covered in the slide so it's nice but the html file is.
It's basically notes for what we're going to be doing going to Right-Click inspects and then open up
the council and your council is probably not going be as zoomed in as mine because this is just for
readability.
Let's show you how to grab important document attributes if you want to grab the actual Yoro the Web
site you past document and then all caps you are ill.
And this turns to you are all the Web site.
In my case stuff is being hosted locally.
So I just get the file location.
If you want to grep everything inside the body you can say document that body enter and then you can
see here we actually have HTL code which is the entire body and if we want to grab everything in the
head we just say documents that head and notice these are attributes not methods so I'm not putting
any clothes princes after them.
We can expand this and check out the head of the document.
And finally if there are links on that page in our case there are no links.
But if you wanted to get a list of all the links you would use document that links here again and them
to the list because there are no links on that page.
Now let's move on to some of these more important methods.
Well not more important but probably more useful.
The element by the.
And then the query selector family elements.
Let's clear this consul if we want to actually grab elements by ID we can use the get element by id
method.
But first off let's go back to him.
And actually given I.D. to one of these extreme elements so let's give this list item the very first
list sign on says document that you are ill.
I'm going to give it an ID of pick me we'll save it and then let's also add a Classen here somewhere.
Let's give both unordered lists a class of my UL and also give this one a class equal to my will.
So my.
Well my.
Well there's a two classes and then we have one instance of the Pick me Id I'm going to save this and
then I'll actually refresh my page to make sure those changes are loaded up here and then let's show
you how we can grab these elements.
The document object model using the methods we just described.
So I expand this again.
And then what I'm going to be doing here is off the document.
I will say Get element by id and then I pasand the idea I want remember my ID.
If I look back at the actual ASML is just pick me.
Let's take that in.
Pick me.
We hit enter and we see here the T.M..
It's a list item has ID pick me.
And then it says document your URL to see actually URL the Web site.
So if we come back up here it's actually highlighted I want to hover over it which is kind of nice to
Chromes kind of helping you out here and pointing out what you actually grab.
So let's say you can grab an element by id and then if we want to grab by a class name we say documents
dot get elements by class name we can see kind of autocomplete there.
I remember the class thing we created was my UL and then we get back what is essentially kind of acting
like a list or an array.
It's not quite the javascript the.
So keep that in mind but it acts very similar to it.
If we expand this we see we have sensu this T.M. collection of these two unordered lists and those have
a bunch of properties themselves and later on we're going to see how we can actually grab those properties
and affect them.
But I'm going to collapse this right now.
So we were able to grab elements by the elements by class name.
And if you want to grab elements by the tag name you probably guessed that already.
You just say document dot elements by tag name and then put a tag on.
So if I want all the list elements I just pass it by and then those are all the list elements in.
You're also given awareness that one of these has an idea attached to it.
Now is talk about queery selector inquere selector.
Which are not quite as obvious as the ID class name and tag name methods Curie's selector is really
similar as far as grabbing a schema elements but what differentiates it from the by the by class name
or by tag name is it actually uses the c SS style selector.
So it saves you a bunch of time.
And let me show you what I actually mean by CSL style selector.
If I clear this ongoing going to grab my document say queery selector and then what I'm going to actually
do here is pasan a query selector for a CSSA selector so I will say hash tag pick me a hit enter and
I get the ID pick me.
So just like you would if you had a CSSA file attached to him l and you wanted to effect an ID you would
call the CSA style selector hash tag for the ID and then the ID name the query selector actually allows
you to grab things by that seeis a style selector so that makes your life a lot easier.
And now you don't actually need to even use by the by class name by tag name you can do everything queery
selector and selector all.
So let's imagine I want to grab all the tags will I could just say document queery selector.
Well let's say queery selector all I passen Eli enter and I get the exact same thing as if I had done
it by class name or excuse me if I had done it by tag name.
So I wanted to do it by class name where I would say document and then query selector all snuck clear
command wearie selector all and then pasand the class Berean over for CSSA style selectors.
A class has a dot.
So we say got.
And then the class name which was my UL enter and we get back the exact same thing we previously got
when we said get elements by class name and hopefully now you get the idea that all you have to do is
query selector and query selector.
All is passen.
The actual CSA selector tag.
And that saves you a lot of time for typing and it just makes the whole process a little more clear.
And as I previously mentioned the difference between queries selector inquiry selector all is a query
selector all returns all the objects matching the CSA style selector query selector just returns the
very first object.
So for instance here I see a document query selector all my UL returns two instances of that class.
Let's say I just wanted to grab the first one.
Well then I could say document query selector.
Well and that will just return the very first instance of this class on the team out page.
So that's the main difference between queries selector all and query selector.
OK so we've covered had actually grabbed the objects.
Let's show a very simple example of how to interact with those objects and changed her properties.
Let's imagine I want to change the color of the header.
Well the first thing I need to do is actually grab the letter so I will create a variable we'll call
it my header and it won't set equal to document dot query selector and then passen the CSSA selector.
In this case it's just the very first instance of heading 1 I hit enter and if I check out my header
I get back H-1 it has some sort of style call saying it's color black.
Most likely yours just says this is the header.
I've already manipulated it for.
But here we have the letter reached him L..
Now let's change the actual color.
So in this case I need to say my header dots.
Now you notice we have a ton of attributes available for this header object are heading object.
First of all we're going to mess around with it style.
So then I will say style and as you scroll down you're going to see a lot of the things we learned about
during the CSSA section.
Of course things like the border with things like the color other things such as font properties height
etc. margin but let's keep it simple let's just grab the color and if I want to change it all I have
to do is set this equal to some other value.
So for instance let's change it to red and hit enter here and now up here on the website page.
I can see this is the header has been turned red and that's the basic fundamental idea of actually grabbing
things from the document object model and then affecting them in some manner changing their properties.
And that's really how the front end stack works.
You have H.M.S. assess and then Javascript can use the DOM to go in and grab things.
And later on we'll show you much more advanced methods such as performing those actions or interactions
on clicks or when you hover over text.
But the fundamental idea behind everything is that you're grabbing things from the document object model
and then interacting with them or changing their properties in some way.
Now let's actually show you how we can create that random color generator in the javascript file.
Hi We'll come back here to this.
Tim L. page right here and all the way down.
I'm going to connect it back to part 1 color change your script save it and if you come over to the
Javascript.
So let's expand this a little more so we can get a good look at it.
We have some examples of what we just did grabbing that header change in that style color.
But let's show you how we could actually create the random color changing and I was going to walk through
this code because it's essentially a little too complex for us at this moment in time.
But later on you can always come back to this and you probably will understand it completely.
In fact right now you should know enough javascript they're able to read this.
But let's say I wanted to get a random color function.
So every second I change something to a random color.
Well the first thing I need to do is figure out how do I get a random color using javascript and for
that you will probably use stack overflow and actually linked the stack overflow.
That answers that question.
So for me personally I'm not dealing with javascript as often as I would like.
I'm usually dealing with Python more so if I'm forgetful of how to actually grab the random color I
would start Google searching.
And if you google search this you'll eventually come up to this stack overflow link which is right here
for you and someone has been nice enough to place the actual answer of a random color generator in javascript
so we can just copy and paste this code and put it in our script.
And basically what this is doing we can see we have letters.
We have some hex code and it's saying for eyes equal to zero all the way.
I less than six.
It's going to somehow grab a series of random letters and then put them in front of the hash tag and
that's making hex codes for us and it's returning that hex codes.
All this is doing is it's making random hex codes for us.
So then we create this simple function for clarity we say function change header color.
We say the color input is get random color.
So again that's just returning a random hex code and then I'm saying Hetter that style that color is
equal to the color input that random hex code that we just created and then I'm going to perform that
action over a set of intervals and this is some javascript code for actually performing some javascript
function over a set of certain intervals.
In our case milliseconds.
So all I'm saying here is every 500 milliseconds call this function right here.
Change header color.
So now if I save this then I come back to my actual page over here my main page and I refresh.
I see now that I'm changing the color randomly every half a second.
And that's the main fundamental idea behind the document object model and the interaction.
Now we're going to cover is many more methods and many more details about this process and how to go
through it in future lectures.
And this section of the course and then later on we'll show you a query which kind of also simplifies
this entire process for you.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.