Hello everyone and welcome back to the Part 1 h t m l basics lecture.
Let's start off by exploring the very basics of what an H Tim L file looks like and how he can open
it in a browser.
Plus learn about some Adam text editor.
Convenience features to quickly create him files.
I'm going to jump to the Adam text editor now.
All right.
Here I am at the Adam text editor as a quick note.
You can either just code along and create new files in the project folders that are provided for you
as a download to the course or you can add your new project folders or new files as you go along.
It's really up to you.
You can always just right click and click a new file new folder or just add a whole new project folder
so you can see a new folder over here.
It's really up to you.
I've already created a project folder called the Tim underscore level underscore one in another quick
note.
Try to avoid using just spaces in your folder names and in your file names you should always try to
replace them with something like an underscore to make sure that you can read the whole file path with
your computer.
Sometimes spaces will mess the computer up in reading the actual file path.
So just a quick note on that.
OK let's start off by creating a new file and we will call it basic stop h Timo and we can do uppercase
or lowercase here.
I'll just keep it simple lowercase because that's usually what they look like.
All right.
So here's a basic slide each T.M. And one thing I want to show you is I can begin to type H T.M..
And you'll notice that Adam text editor has this little pop up that says H him l.
If I hit enter when I see that pop up I will get the basically boilerplate code as it's called or the
skeleton code of and HVM file.
Now let's walk through this and explain what's actually going on in this very first line we see something
that says doc type H Tim L and that's something you are going to find in pretty much all the stem cell
files.
And that basically just tells the browser hey you're looking at an age HTML file.
Then we have the team l tags.
You'll notice we have an opening tag here at the line number two and a closing tag over in line number
10 and difference between the opening and closing tag.
Is it just lets you know when that starts and when it stops and the closing will notice has a little
forward slash in it.
And what's nice about Adam text editor is you'll see these little arrows pop up which just allow you
to collapse or open things between their opening and closing tags so that's just for organization.
Then we have two major sections.
The head of the team M-file and the body of the team are File.
Let's start off by just explaining what the head is the head of the HMO which is this first section
is going to contain the meta data and for this first section of the course the H team at level 1 we
won't be doing a whole lot with the actual head of the L that will come into play a lot more than we
actually UCSF in javascript but it's going to mainly serve as how to link your HMO document to other
types of files such as your CSSA file or your database javascript's file but another tag that we noticed
it's NHT male head.
Is this title tag.
And that's basically what's going to show up as the title when you open this up in a browser and the
title is just what's shown in the tab.
So I'm going to type in in-between this title tag something like this is the title exclamation mark.
And notice I don't need any quotes here.
It's just pure text in between these tags.
And h tim l will recognize it and then this other meta data is just telling you what character set you
would expect and that's UTF 8 encoding.
Don't worry about that too much right now.
Then finally we have the body and the body is going to contain the actual content.
We're going to be discussing actual content such as paragraphs and lists etc. throughout this section
of the course.
Right now we'll leave the body blank.
Last thing I want to show you before we actually view the safe's female file in our browser is how to
comment code.
So and ASTM l comments look like this.
You do a opening tag.
Exclamation mark dash dash.
And that says that's the start of the comment and then the end of the comment is dash dash.
The other closing sign and then anything here is a comment.
The other quick way to do this is if you have some text or a line of code you can just do a control
or command depending on your OS.
A forward slash in Adam and sublime text editor will actually just auto comment everything there.
Or if you wanted to you can actually highlight many lines and then do control forward slash to comment
or control forward slash to uncomment.
All right.
So anything in between those two types of tags is a comment and it's just control or command forward
slash to quickly make a line or multiple lines in actual comments and when you do control s here to
save this then let's open this up in a browser.
So the way we open this up in our browser is by just passing in the entire file path into the browser.
For now we're going to be just running things locally.
So that's how it will work.
I'm going to right click on MH T.M. file and then say copy full path.
So it will copy the full path to that and then let me bring in a browser window.
And here is a browser window and what I can do is right where my browser usually goes.
I'm going to just copy and paste that file path.
So this is just the whole file path to that actual HTL file.
I hit enter and I noticed something that's just basically a blank page and that makes sense we haven't
provided any content or each content in the body of each team I'll file but what we do notice is this
our little this is the title in the title actually showed up.
Perfect.
So that's really all there is for the very basics of an AFEs Himmel file.
What NH him I'll file mostly will be as we work with it or the actual body tags.
So let's go ahead and continue on by editing this file with body tags in part 2 in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.