Hello everyone and welcome to part one functions.
Functions are going to be our main building block when we're ever dealing with javascript code.
And honestly any code they're going to allow us to easily reuse code more than once and not constantly
repeat our cells.
If you've already programmed in another programming language you may just want to check out the notes
to quickly grab the syntax for functions in Javascript.
But if this is your first time programming Lets take a little bit of time to describe what a function
is and what it's going to look like in javascript and then we'll hop over to the editor and code out
a bunch of examples so the general syntax for a javascript function looks like this.
You have the keyword function and that's going to indicate that you have a function.
Then you have the actual name of your function and you're going to decide whether you want the name
to be.
And then you also have the option of passing parameters and you could also not have any promotors So
here I just showed two parameters parameter one parameter to and someone using the function could pass
in parameters required for the function to do something with Zuid passing those parameters and then
inside that code to be executed inside those curly brackets you would do something with those parameters.
So let's go straight to the other and our consul to really show how to create and use functions in javascript
and get a better understanding of what's actually going on here.
Going to jump to my editor now or so I have my editor open I have an html file that linked to my script
that Jesus and here I have a blank.
My script that Jesus and that is email file is open and linked teare in the browser.
And if you want you can also put everything that we're type being straight into the console but it's
going to look a little better if you put it into Atam.
Let's start off with the most simple function we can think of which is just a hello function.
So I'm going to put it in the special keyword function called my function hello so I give it a name.
Close parentheses so it won't have any parameters.
Then the curly brackets and inside this function and put some code in I'm going to input log.
And will just say hello world.
And this is the most basic function we can have.
So what's actually going on here.
A keyword function than the name of my function imprint sees a pass and any parameters.
In this case we won't pass anything yet.
And then whenever this function is called I will log.
Hello world.
So let's save this if we refresh our page.
Well notice that we can actually call hello enter and we get.
Hello world.
So in our browser after running this java script connected to say Tim L. I can now call this function
here and what I want you to know is sometimes what happens is students get confused on how to call a
function.
They'll just type in hello over here with no parentheses enter and they actually get back the function
itself.
So the difference here is that one of these is calling the function and the other one is just returning
it.
So going to zoom in a little more here just so you can see what I'm talking about.
In this case I called the function to execute with the parentheses there in the second case.
I'm actually just calling the function but I'm not executing the function.
And in that case javascript's says like oh you wanted the function.
Well here it is.
This is what the function actually is with the prince.
Though you're telling javascript OK actually execute that function.
All right let's expand this example by calling the function.
Hello you and we will pasan passen a name.
So that's my parameter name.
In this case I will say console log.
Hello
plus name.
So I will save that.
It's FREE.
Let's clear a console and then a refresher page
and now we're going to do is call.
Hello you boops clear.
Hello you and know what happens if I just typed help you if no parentheses.
It returns back the actual function but I want to call the function.
So I will say hello you if I just have princes with no name parameter I'll get hello.
Undefined.
So that's important to note here because I expected something to be the name a parameter to be passed.
In this case since I didn't pass anything it just said hello.
Undefined parameter.
Well I really should do something like this.
Hello.
You then pass in that name parameter which in my case I expect a string there.
So I will say hello you Jose.
And it says Hello Jose.
In the actual con..
So that's the very basics of a function that accepts some sort of parameter input and then uses it within
the function code itself and later on also talk about scope of the function which is pretty important
as well.
But right now the basics here that I want you to get is that you can put in a parameter and then use
it within your actual function code.
The main idea of a function overall is that I don't have to keep typing cancel that log every time that
I want to do something.
All I have to do is call.
Hello you and this is going to be really useful for more complicated functions.
Let's expand this to a simple function but a function that takes in two parameters and only to delete
this.
And if you can start typing fun enter and you get something like this function name.
Note that it's camel case meaning that we don't use underscores and instead we separate words by lowercase
and then uppercase letters.
In this case no pun intended.
I'm going to say add numb as my actual function name and then I will take number one and number two
to be the function parameters.
And then I will log number 1 plus 2.
So let me save this and I will clear the council Well I actually should refresh the page to make sure
Adam is loaded up.
So here I refresh the page let's call ad nauseam and let's passen two and three.
We hit enter and we get five.
All right.
So it's actually happening here.
While Adam is taking in two parameters and I called the printer's number one and them two.
And then inside the actual function code that block it's going to add them together and then lock that.
Let's see what happens if I say add
Hello comma
we hit Enter we notice that we get hello world back.
Something to remember here is that we can concatenate strings with this addition sign.
So later on we'll be talking about making sure that you have the correct data type you expect whenever
you're creating a function because right now this functions a little too loose in what it expects as
a parameter.
You'll end up working with either strings or numbers which isn't very good for us because that means
if we call this function later on in our code and we actually do something like this add and we pass
an maybe a two a string to as a number you'll end up getting something like 22.
But that's not really what you were probably expecting you may have been expecting for.
So it's kind of a dangerous situation to be in because of javascript's type coersion.
So usually you want to check types or make sure the operations will only work on certain data types.
So that's just a little warning but we'll talk a lot more about that later on in the course.
For right now what I really want you to understand is that I have two parameters and I'm using them
inside of my function call.
OK.
Now let's talk about default values.
So so far we've had to define every single argument or parameter in the function when using it.
But we can also have default values by using an equal sign.
And let me show you an example of that.
And again I will create a function here.
The function name will be hello someone
it takes in a name and it will console log Hello plus that name but instead of having a name be undefined
if no one passes in a name I'm going to have a default name.
Now let's make that the fault name Frankie.
So let's see what happens now.
When I refresh this page and I call hello someone if I call hello someone with Jose as the parameter
then I hit enter.
I get Hello Jose but if I call hello someone with nothing inside of it then I hit enter.
Hello Frankie.
So we can use an equal sign in this manner to actually assign default parameters in case a parameter
is not supplied by the user OK.
So that's the fault parameters.
Now let's talk about returning values.
So far we've actually just been printing or logging results.
But what if we actually want to return results so we could assign them to a variable and then we can
use the return keyword for this task.
In this falling manner let me show you what I mean by all this will create another other function and
let's call it formal and formal takes in a name will give a default name of Sam.
And it also takes in a title argument and will also give a default title of Sir.
So we have two default parameters are two default arguments there and the terms parameters and arguments
are used entertain interchangeably a lot.
So keep that in mind.
Now I'm going to say console log title plus a space plus name.
So let me save this going to refresh the page and call formal
hit enter and it says Sursum great.
So what if I do this I say welcome.
Plus formal will then it says welcome.
Undefined which is probably not what you expected.
You expected it to say.
Welcome sir Sam.
We can see here that it only outputted sir Sam when the formal was called.
But when I wanted to actually print this whole thing that said welcome in the find.
So if I would actually put that all within a console log call.
So I say welcome plus formal hit enter.
I get again a welcome on the find.
So you might be wondering what's actually going on here and what's going on.
Is this function right here.
Is it actually returning anything.
It was just printing something one time.
If we want to actually return something so we can use it in a variable we need to use the return keyword
and let me show you how we can do that.
We will just say return.
We could see there's already a return keyword and then say whatever you want to return.
In our case will return the exact same thing title plus space plus name.
And now I can save this.
Refresh my page and if I call formal I still get the output.
Sir Sam.
Now I can actually assign that value so I can say variable output is equal to formal Banafsheh call
output.
I get Sir Sam means I can also do what I wanted to do before which was welcome plus formal.
Now I get it.
Welcome Sursum instead of just welcoming the find OK so that might seem a little confusing at first
especially with these examples of showing the console log versus the return.
But all you really need to understand for now is that if you want to save the result of a function you
want to use the return keyword so that it actually spits out something to return.
So whenever I call formal whatever it does it's going to return what is on this line.
So usually you'll have a bunch of code over here doing something code some more code etc. and at the
very end you will return some sort of variable that you find using all of this code up here.
Let's break down a more complicated example by doing something like multiplication so I will call a
new function function name and I will call this function times 5 and I will say no input so takes in
this parameter and the input inside of my function.
I create a variable called result and set equal to numb input times 5 and then I return that result.
So far so good.
And then if I refresh this page I can call times 5 pasan a number 4 and I see I get 20 back.
OK so that also means that I'm using the return keyboard.
I can see variable let's say variable answer is equal to times 5 and will pass and another number 10
here.
And now if I call answer I get 50.
I wouldn't be able to do this sort of variable assignment if I was just doing a console log of the result.
Instead of this return key word I can now assign the result to some sort of variable.
In my case the variables called the answer great.
So you've talked so far about using the return key word using parameters and also using default parameters.
Let's take a moment to talk about a really important concept that's called scope and scope is the term
we use to describe how objects and variables get defined offend javascript's when discussing scope with
functions as a general rule we can say that if a variable is defined only inside a function then its
scope is limited to that function.
So let's consider the example we just showed here times five input we created a variable called Rozell
equals to input times 5.
Now we return a result if I call answer I get 50.
But if I try calling result here I get result is not defined at anonymous and the main idea here is
that the scope of results is limited to this function that actual variable doesn't exist outside of
this function.
Unless I define it outside of the function.
So again as a general rule we can say that if a variable is defined only inside of a function then the
scope of that variable is limited to the function.
So it's only going to be recognized when it's called inciters function and the same goes for these parameters.
So if I come up here next to the console and try to say something like num input and hit enter I will
also get a not defined error.
So that means that this has a bit of a Pip's local scope to the function.
Now let's try to make something more of the global scope.
So the global scope is going to be different than that local scope.
And basically what happens is if we have a variable that we define outside of the function that's going
to be a global variable and the function will have access to them due to their scope.
Let's show an example or create a variable.
It's outside of any function and we'll call it the and this is going to just be a string that kind of
really obviously is going to be a global variable so say global V.
So that stands for Global variables so we can see variable be just a big string out there.
Also make a variable called Stuff.
Now we'll say have it be a string global stuff you know and create a new function.
It's going to be called just fun.
It's going to take and stuff
and it's going to log the it's going to reassign stuff inside.
So I will reassign it literally to a string claiming it's re-assignment so reassigned stuff inside func
and then I will log stuff and let's delete this top function here since we won't be using it.
OK.
Before we actually run this let's break down what's happening here.
I have two variables defined outside of any function that I'm calling function fun have stuff as a parameter.
But no I never actually I'm going to call stuff.
I'm just going to do this fun and then I'm going to say console log the I never find the inside the
function it's only to find that peer.
I will reassign stuff only inside the function and then I will say console log stuff.
Let's save this and run it in our browser.
So refresh and I get this global V re-assign stuff inside function.
Now let's add one more line of code after this function call to execute the function.
And then when say this cancel the log.
And I was going to log stuff.
Let's see what happens when we actually run this code.
So let me save that and refresh and run.
So it says global V re-assign stuff inside func and then global stuff.
OK let's break down all the lines of code here and actually explain what's going on.
So we get a really clear idea of scope.
So this whole idea that we're talking about right now is known as scope.
So the folly happens console log the is going to check for the global variable v the outer scope if
it can't find anything there that is going to check for the local scope inside of the function.
And if it can't find anything there then it's going to throw an error that it was never defined.
Console log stuff over there at the bottom.
We'll also check for the global variable stuff.
And then the call fun stuff is accepting or even stuff that it's printing out V and it's re-assigning
stuff only inside the scope of the function.
And then it's going to print us stuff.
So notice two things here.
The re-assignment of stuff only affects the scope of the stuff variable inside the function.
And the fun function first checks to see if these the fine at the functions go.
And if not which is our case it will then search the global scope for the variable names V leading it
to print out these global V as a string.
OK.
So really take your time with these few lines of code and understand what's happening here.
Really Make sure you understand why global is printed out why we get this re-assign stuff inside function.
And then even with the re-assignment inside of this function.
So that's only happening at a low level.
Even after I call the function of line 11 when I print out stuff online.
Well I still get back the original global stuff.
Thanks everyone.