Hello everyone and welcome to relative your Elswyth templates and this lecture will discuss how to use
template tagging to create relative your calls and we'll also have a quick side discussion on future
releases of Django.
Let's get started.
As we mentioned so far we had to use an anchor tab and Atra we've usually pass any hard coded path to
the file meaning we either pasand the entire file path to actually get to the HTL file or we write a
file path to the actual view.
In general this is poor practice.
If we want a jingle project to work on any system and be scalable we want to really focus on relative
file paths not hard coded ones.
In this lecture in the next one we will show you how to use various methods to pass relative your Elswyth
template tags and at the end we're going to show you the preferred method that will be the main method
used when future versions of Jinggoy are released.
Let's talk about for a second.
A quick side note on Django and future releases.
Since we are going to be focusing on the end of this lecture Django in general has a really good roadmap
for future releases an every two years they release what is known as an Ltd's or long term support version
of Django which support guaranteed of at least three years now for a lot of people who work at enterprise
companies long term support usually means something like 10 years not just three years but please keep
in mind that jingoes an open source project.
It's really just a bunch of volunteers donating their time.
So three years is a pretty long term support for such an open source project but definitely check out
the release notes and documentation on roadmaps for Django to get a better idea and better understanding
of what the future of Gengel really looks like.
And as a quick note usually new releases involve better features and easier methods.
There are not huge paradigm shifts in the way you actually work with Django and the views the models
the templates etc..
So think of it more as improvements in regards to what you can expect in future releases of Django.
Don't be nervous or worried that all the knowledge you're learning right now is only going to vanish
if the next release.
It really usually doesn't work that way.
OK so back to the topic at hand.
How can we replace a hard coded path in an A-Trak with a your old template instead.
Let's see a few examples.
All right so we can easily fix that problem with ds of your Alzner templates.
So for example usually you may have something that looks like that first darker example you have a trick
basic app.
Thank you.
And then.
Thanks.
That's just an anchor exults if you want to use template tags you can change that to look like this.
You have the template tagged with the percent signs you have the keyword your all inside of that and
then and usually single quotes.
You have the actual name or you have name is equal to thank you in the Urals that high file of re-application.
That's one way to do this you could also just directly reference the view itself.
So for example the previous method we were referencing the name in the Urals PI file but you could also
do this if you have an eighth ref in an acre like basic apps Lesch thank you.
You could just change that to be in your old template tagged in single quotes that says basic app views.
Thank you and that will go.
The basic app find a view for thank you and then return that link so that when you click on things or
whatever that text and they grotesque happens to be on your web page it will take use that view however
this method is actually eventually going to go away with Django 2.0 in the future.
At this point in time at the recording of this lecture right now the latest release Django 1.1 0.
The next one it's going to be 1 point 1 1 and after that we should see Django 2.0 further along.
That's about one and a half to two years away from being released at this point in time.
But let's focus on how we can actually feature proof our method since that method is going to work right
now.
And in fact I believe it's a better and simpler method to understand so the suggested a must feature
proof method is to do all of this with the or else that py file.
So inside the euro's up PI file you add in the variable app underscore name.
You'd then set this variable equal to a string that is the same name as your application name.
And so this is currently the best way to use your old templates.
This most future proof example and I believe the simplest example of the way to use this looks like
this you're going to be changing something that looks like a ref equal to basic app slash thank you
to change to look like this year your old template tagging and then quotes the name of your application
colon and then the name of that view.
And remember that this method requires the app named variable to be created inside of you or else the
PI file.
Now one quick note.
So far we've really only been working with a single application Django project and so you might be thinking
What's the whole point of all this your template tagging since it's quite obvious to me.
What view matches what application.
I only have one application should be simple enough and I don't have to worry about the relative You
are all about py files.
Well later on especially if the clone projects were going to be building out multiplication Gengel projects
so a single project with multiple applications and have things separated as applications.
And with this sort of methodology the usual template tagging becomes really important and really helps
you have a clear understanding and clear pathways to your relative links.
So keep in mind everything we're talking about here is kind of overkill for a single application project.
But in the real world we're going to have multi application projects so that's where this really comes
in handy.
All right.
So again using templates for relative URLs big help multiplications.
Let's work through a basic example in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.