Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the Bitstrips section we're going to be discussing forms.
A quick note before we actually begin to dive straight into forms of bootstrap.
I want to talk about bootstrap in general for just a little bit.
Many students get intimidated by bootstrap when they first approach it.
They think they need to memorize all the classics that we cover in the section of the course.
Now that's actually certainly not the case.
You want to think of this section more as a guide to the documentation and what's really possible bootstrap
not as an overview of things that you need it memorize.
Even the people who work bootstrap often or everyday are going to you're referencing the documentation
a lot.
Well we really want a master here is the skill of gathering and applying information not just memorizing
information.
Now it's continue on talking about forms.
So bootstrap comes with many default classes for forms.
There's two really important ones that are going to be covering here.
And one of the first ones are going to cover is a class called form group.
So let's explore the various form components that we can use of bootstrap and we're going to be referencing
the course notes quite a bit.
So what I would suggest you do is to open up the part to underscore forms that each T.M. file that's
under the bootstrap folder.
OK let's jump straight to our browser and to her editor to get started.
All right so here you have my editor open as well as my browser and if I refresh major T.M. here right
now I have it linked to my browser this extra Mells linked in it also already has the link to the CD
version of bootstrap.
There is an empty body to get started.
I just want to point out where we can find a lot of this information.
If you go to get bootstrapped dot com click on the CSX tab and then click down here where it says forms.
They'll take you down to a basic example of forms and we can see here that we need to wrap labels or
controls in a dot form group for optimum spacing.
And what it says there it's just trying to tell you that it's a class.
Remember we're dealing of CSSA we reference classes with that period or Dopp.
So when you actually type in the class it will just be formed up that group you want to actually have
that dot there.
So let's see this example explore a little bit and see what happens when you wrap everything with a
form group class so I will copy this.
And it's actually a really nice copy to clipboard button there.
You can just use and I'm going to paste this into my system file save it and then check it out here
in my browser.
And we can see right now it stretches from end to end on everything.
So what I can do to organize this.
So it looks a little nicer.
Put it all in a container class and that's something we to be doing.
Often when we use bootstrap as put everything in different container divs.
So let's paste that there.
The closing tab.
And then grab this entire form and just put it a little more or indented a little more.
All right.
Now that everything is in a container class.
When I refresh you can see it's a little nicely centered.
So so far it's looking pretty good.
We have our e-mail input our password input and we could see some more advanced inputs things such as
a Choose file inputs.
If I click on Choose file we can see that it pops up something for me to choose File.
Now right now we actually can't do anything of this because we haven't learned the backend technologies
such as jingo to actually accept that file and do something with it.
Here we can see just a checkbox and then the submit button.
Now the class I want to talk about with forms is this class form croupe and what the class form group
does is it puts spacing in between components of forms so that they look nicer and they just read a
little better.
So to show you what I mean by this I'm going to just delete these divs for the first two refresh and
pay attention to the spacing here.
For email address and password you can see here that they begin to get a little closer.
And when we were dealing with our own input forms for some of the previous projects we saw that we were
using tricks such as adding in a break or adding in an empty paragraph to get that margin spacing nice.
But all that's taken care of for you and bootstrap student controls here.
When you use the class form group and then let me refresh here.
Now we can see the spacing is a little readable more readable now and especially between the actual
blocks of the email address versus the password is just minor things that bootstrap is helping you out
with a lot by having those classes ready for you.
In the next class I want to point out is this form control class that's in the input tags.
So we have these imput tags and we give them this class form control.
Let's explore what they do by actually just taking them out.
So there's my foreign control I've taken them out and I refresh over here and we can see that by taking
out the form control on the Impe attacks basically we have what looks like almost normal ASTM L or normal
CSSA styling I should say.
Let's show one of them on this password and put just to see that difference.
So with the form control tag I can see that it's rounding the corners it's making it stretch the container
size it's actually highlighting a little differently.
You can see that the highlighting has a bit of a almost like an alpha or a blur around the password
box.
Email is highlighting there but it's not as subtle.
And those are really the two classes that are making the forms look nice for bootstrap.
It's the form group and form control tags are classes excuse me they are going to be using all the tags
the DIV tag for each form that's the label an input it should have the form group and then each input
should have the form control.
Now let's explore just a few examples of various different inputs to you're going to be using on a form.
So I'm going to delete this entire form and then add in things from the notes so I'm copying and pasting
from part to underscore forms.
So let me copy and paste the email submission example.
So here we have a label and put and we've actually already kind of explore this.
But let's refresh.
And this is a typical email address so we have the email address the email input's is where you would
enter your e-mail and then you also notice that it says will never share e-mail to anyone else.
This is really common to have a little explanatory text underneath any input.
A lot of times in an email address to give some sort of a note like this what we use for that is this
small tag and we give it the class form text text muted and it says whatever text you want to say behind
that so that small tag basically just says OK a small piece of text.
So it's not same size as a paragraph.
That's another useful tip when you're dealing with forms.
If you ever want to give a little note there for a particular aspect of the input form so that's the
email submission going to delete that.
And then I want to put in the password submission not too much to see here let's save it and refresh
and here we can see a password submission again.
We've already seen this with bootstrap going to copy and paste the next component that I have in the
notes which is a dropdown select.
So here we can see we have Supe's the select form and let's copy all this in then a little more just
so it's more readable.
Save it and refresh and here we can see what a dropdown form looks like with bootstrap.
So if this trip you get this nice interface now we can see that it actually expands the entire width
of the container.
Again there are ways to control that with SS or just by adding the container itself but what a drop
down menu looks like with bootstrap.
If we want multiple select Options Let me show you what that looks like.
There has also the class form control here.
So I can copy and paste this save it refresh.
Now we can see here we can have multiple selections.
So if I want to select multiple copies I can do a shift and click and that's basically another example
of something very similar to a dropdown except now I can select multiple options.
And the way you do that is you say select just like we did last time but now you say multiple.
So just to reiterate from the last drop down option which I'm going to copy and paste here for you to
see the first one I save this and refresh it just a single selection if I want a dropdown that where
I can select multiple things using shift or using control or command or you end up doing is in the select
tag you add multiple And that's just a keyword.
OK so moving along the couple more is that I want to show you are the text area with bootstrap.
You can delete these and put it in text area it's also taking the form control.
I refresh this and we can see a nice text area houses rounded corners.
It has the ability for me to grab this and expand it.
There's the file upload input.
We actually saw that a little bit already.
Well let's paste that in from the notes.
We can see that it's also taking the class if we look here form control dash file.
So that's another important thing to know when you're dealing with type file input.
You want to make sure has the class form dash control dash file and the example here also comes at that
small type that we've seen earlier which is some placeholder block level for help.
So this would say something like oh please input your resume or something like that.
Then you click on Choose file and automatically pops this thing up.
Great.
And like I mentioned before we don't know yet how to actually deal with something when we upload it.
We still need to learn the actual backend technologies for that now there's two more I want to show
you two more examples and that is radio and examples with bootstrap.
So I'm going to copy this and we're going to see a couple new tags that we haven't seen yet.
And those are the field set tags.
So if we come up here we can see we have a field set tag and takes a class form group and the loss of
a legend.
So let's actually refreshes and see what that looks like.
So here we can see radio buttons and that's the legend tag that's making it look like this.
And you can see hopefully it's visible on your screen but I have an underline here because it's a Legin
and so easy option is this and that.
Be sure to include it's great option too.
Option 3 is disabled so if you want something to be the table again that's Option three over here.
You just put in a disabled call right here.
Disabled.
All right.
So nothing too fancy going on here.
You can just check that there's classes for each of these.
So if you want it to be disabled you can say form check disabled as the class here instead of just form
check.
So here we have the class form check which is really commonly used for radio buttons.
And as you may have guessed check buttons.
So we're going to put in a check button example here.
Copy and paste that from the notes
paste it helps get rid of that field set and that division
paste it in here.
So here we have classes form check label is form check label.
Let's refresh see what this looks like.
And here it says check me out.
You can click and click.
Not much going on here.
But if you want it you can put in class form check.
And that's really all there is to forms of bootstrap.
So let's copy this entire form from the notes and paste it in so we can see what's something or a bunch
of options would look like I'm going to copy and paste this
and copied everything including the form tags so I will save that refresh and here I can see a really
large form example so I have my email.
I can see the spacing is nice between the various inputs and the password.
There's my example select Here's an example of multiple selects.
Here's my example text area.
Here's the Choose file and put radio buttons.
Check me out.
And then the submit button.
Now we can always callers submit button.
We have different classes.
So before we end this lecture something I really want to stress here is that you do not have to memorize
everything that I just went over and if it seemed like I was just quickly going over many examples but
not diving deep into them that's exactly what we're doing for the section of the course.
Bootstrap is just being able to see what's possible and being able to reference the documentation.
So you have these notes available to you in your class notes if you ever want to make a form with any
of these you can basically just copy and paste to your own needs.
Or you can always just check out the documentation that has many examples.
So here we see a basic example of a form that we can do things like a focus stay disabled stay etc..
Validation States in line forms is a lot of examples in the documentation.
It can be intimidating at first but really it's all here to help you.
Just normal people referencing this and writing it.
So don't ever be intimidated and if you have any questions posted to the Q&amp;A forums I'm always happy
to help you out.
OK.
Hopefully you now have an idea of what's possible with the forms and bootstrap and that you're going
to be using class formed that group a lot whenever you're actually dictating that you have a forum there.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.