Hello everyone and welcome to part two function exercises.
Let's get some practice of functions.
But I want you to do is open up the file part to underscore functions underscore exercises that jazz
which is located under the javascript level 2 folder the problems will gradually get harder as you go
along.
Let's take a quick look at this file and look at the problems.
OK so this is what the exercise thought Jap's file looks like.
And a lot of these problem statements are sourced from coding that dot com which is a great Web site
for practice problems.
You want to get more than what's here in this file but basically you're going to have a problem.
The name of the problem and it's going to ask you to write a function to take in particular parameters
and then give an output.
And after the problem statement you'll see an example of what it should look like.
So here we can see the sleep and function when it takes an false and false.
It should output true.
And if we keep going down we see something like monkey trouble if monkey trouble function takes and
true and true it should output true center.
We go down to string times and it says given a string and some integer do something with it.
So string times we see it takes in a string a number and then outputs that string multiplied as many
times as the number shows here.
Then we see lucky some Which is another problem takes in three numbers a certain number of the penny
and what's going on.
And then finally we have problem five which is a speed ticket problem.
You get a number and a boolean value and you either get 0 or 1 or 2.
So if we go all the way down we get this bonus problem which is make bricks.
This is a pretty tricky problem.
So if you can't figure this one out don't worry that's why it's a bonus.
Go ahead and read the problem see if you can figure it out.
But this has to do not so much with javascript but more of just computer science and trying to think
like a programmer.
OK.
So leave that one is a bonus for you.
Go ahead and tackle the other five and I will see you in the next lecture.
We're going to be programming through the solutions.
Thanks everyone.