Hello everyone and welcome to part one.
Numbers numbers and Python have two main forms that we're going to be working with for this course.
That's integers and floating point numbers.
Integers are whole numbers and floating point numbers have it thus in them.
So for example an integer something like 23 a floating point number something like twenty three point
five or twenty three point zero etc..
All right.
Let's quickly walk through examples of some very basic arithmetic for Python.
And we're also going to be covering variable assignment in Python.
And what makes a dynamic programming language.
Let's hop over to the Adam text editor to get started.
OK here I am at the Adam text editor.
Before we get started talking about numbers integers variables and floating points what I want to quickly
discuss is the various ways you can run Python and play with Python.
One way is to directly in your command prompt or terminal.
Just type python.
And if you've downloaded Anaconda it should be set to the path.
See immediately see Python here and you can directly type python now into your command prompt or terminal.
Which means I could do something like this.
I can say print parentheses and in quotes.
Hello world.
Hit enter.
And I get the output Hello world.
So that's just the basic hello world with Python.
Or I can type 2 plus 1 and since this is in the terminal or command prompt if I enter it directly gives
me an output in a script it would not give me the output I would have to say print 2 plus 1.
If I was running a dot PI script.
So let's show you how you can run a PI script to exit out of this.
You can just type quits open and close parentheses in you've quit and if you want to clear the screen
you can do CLX or clear depending on your operating system.
Right.
So to actually run a script what you need to know is the current file path you're in.
So you can type TWD.
If you're on a Mac or Linux or for a Windows computer you should be able to just see it directly to
your left the entire file path.
If you're unsure you can always type CD enter and it outputs the file path right here.
You'll notice that it might command prompt.
I have something here in parentheses saying my Django NVI that's a virtual environment.
I've set up.
We'll discuss that when we talk about Django in a future lecture.
You don't need to worry about that right now.
All you need to know is being able to access whatever your current directory is which is just CD and
then it should output directory or P.W. the if on a Mac or Linux.
So what you need to do is create a folder here or add this folder to your project folders and Adam you
can see here have already added it.
But if you needed to added it you could just right click here and then select Add project folder and
then find this folder.
What I'm going to do is under that project folder I will Right-Click say new file and create a file
and I'm going to call it numbers and I will make sure to give the extension up pie so that Adam knows
it's a python file.
And so that Python also knows it's a python file.
Now let's discuss some very basic arithmetic her basic arithmetic addition is just two plus one and
I can zoom in here a little bit so you can see it clearly.
Two plus one is addition subtraction is just the minus sign.
Multiplication is just an Asterix and the vision is just a forward slash.
Again I'm not running these commands because they're so basic.
And we covered a lot of this when we were talking about javascript for actual powers.
That is something like two to the power of five.
You just have two sets of Asterix.
So this right here is two to the power of five.
And if you wanted to you could also do roots this way.
So maybe I want the square root of something I can do for.
So the power of 0.5.
That's the same as the square root.
But later on we'll show you how you can import the math module to do some more complicated math and
then take the square root that way.
Couple more notes.
Order of operations is followed in Python.
So things like multiplication happening before addition or subtraction that's all followed.
So if I were to say something like two plus ten times ten plus three let's print this whole thing out
and see what we get.
So I'm going to print this.
I will save it and then if I want to actually run this file all I have to do is add a command prompt
type python space and then the either the entire file path to the actual file or if I'm in the same
location as the adult Pi file just the name itself.
So numbers that pi and you can always do tab to help auto complete this enter.
And we see it's 105 for order of operation.
So if I wanted to affect this I can always use parentheses.
So let's say I want the actual additions happen first.
So I want to plus tend to happen first before 10 and 10 get multiplied.
Then I could just add sets a print Cesaire to make sure that happens so if I run this again up on my
arrow key now I get 156.
So a little bit different.
And you can just use parentheses to specify the order of operations.
OK.
Now let's talk about variable assignment with Python.
Python is a dynamic programming language meaning you don't need to declare what a variable type is going
to be before you actually just do the assignment.
So Python variable assignment is very simple.
All you have to do is choose the name of your variable for instance a set is equal to whatever you want
it to be.
For instance the number 5 and all those tabs that were popping up dashes Adam auto help there that we
downloaded one of the plug ins.
Don't worry about that.
You can just continue on without it later on when we work with functions and object oriented programming.
It's going to be really useful.
But right now you can just ignore it.
If I want to see the output of this I can just say print a let's save that run our script which has
Python numbers that pi and here we see the output five I can then also add objects together.
So for instance a plus say save it run this and I get 10 out Python also supports re-assignment meaning
I could do something like a is equal to a times five.
And then I could say print a.
And now we would expect it to give out not just 10 but also 25.
And if I ever want to make a comments in Python I just need to do a hash tag and then type whatever
comments I want.
And as a quick note by convention usually type comments above the code it references or right next to
it.
OK.
So that's the very basics of variable assignment and comments.
There are a couple of rules you need to follow.
When creating variable names with Python one thing Python variable names cannot start a number so you
can't say something like two dogs is equal to two or something.
What you would need to do is say two dogs is equal to whatever you want.
Now keep in mind usually when you're typing in Python and you have multiple words and variables you
want to separate them using an underscore.
This is known as snake casing.
So you'll usually see something like this instead of camel casing which is common with javascript which
would do something like that.
And we'll discuss these rules later on when we talk about object oriented programming.
But right now just keep in mind variable names cannot start for a number.
They also can't start with certain symbols and these symbols are in notes that it's usually pretty obvious
stuff.
Anything that's a shift on a number.
So you can't start it with basically any of these symbols right here otherwise you'll mess up the variable
name.
OK.
Now let's walk through a very quick example of using object names for table assignment want to do a
very simple example with my income equal to 100 will say my tax rate is equal to 0.1 my taxes is equal
to my income.
And we can see here and being helped out multiplied by tax rate and then I'm going to print my taxes.
We'll save that.
So what we get when we run the script I get ten point zero.
So notice I'm getting a floating point number.
The first number wasn't integer.
Second number was a floating point number.
When I multiply them together Python automatically makes the result a floating point number.
OK.
That's really all we need to know about numbers and variable assignments for now.
Hopefully it is pretty straightforward.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.