Hello everyone and welcome to the template views lecture for the class based views section of course.
It's that time to learn how to use the template view object that comes with Django.
Previously we just called in the basic view object from those generic views.
Now we're going to learn how to use the template view and it's really going to make calling templates
a breeze very easy.
Now let's see a comparison between using a function call a template as we have in the past versus using
the template view object.
So previously for a function based view that called some sort of template you had to say the ADF name
of that view function passing the request and then somewhere along the line you return the Render of
that request plus the actual template you want it to return for a class based template view.
It's also really easy and I would argue even easier than that function.
You just create the class call it whatever you want in this case which is called index view and you
inherit the template view object after importing it and then you just set the class object attribute
template underscore name equal to whatever the temple you want to return.
In this case index that each TNL OK let's show the basics of this and also show you how you can use
a template class based view along of a context dictionary.
I'll hop over to the editor and get started.
OK.
Back at her editor.
Let's start by opening up.
Use that pie in our application.
So far we showed that very basic class based view of a simple HTP response but usually you're going
to want to return the templates themselves so we can really all that and we can also delete the H.T.
response we'll be using it instead of just importing view what we're going to import is template.
We can do that from Django that use that generic.
So is it still known as a generic view.
Now we'll start off with creating the class and we'll call it index view and we will inherit the template
view instead of just the normal view from before and then all we have to do to match something up is
you say the template underscore name class object attribute and then you just pass in the actual template
you want.
So for instance right now under my templates folder I have indexed HVM L but maybe if you had it under
a template and then your application so it would look something like basic underscore app slash index
that page HTML etc..
Right now since I just have it under index or excuse me under templates I don't actually have a subdirectory
there.
We'll just call index like Steimle and I'm going to save this and that's it.
That's all we have to do and the views that PI file then coming back to our You are Elle's up by file
you know scroll down here instead of saying See view.
I will call that index.
I remember we always have to call it as a view so let's save that as well.
And just to make sure this is working.
We'll call index Steimle and say something like.
Testing template view save that now it's actually run the server going to CD into advance S. CD into
a TV CBB.
They now call Python managed up high and run my server.
Enter And let's actually make sure it's running OK.
Looks like it's operating will copy and paste this into our browser and bring over our browser OK.
Bringing in the browser.
Perfect.
We get testing template view and it's all working correctly.
So now you probably want to know is how to actually use a context dictionary.
A big part of using templates is injecting content into the actual template.
So let's walk through how to do that.
Later on we're also going to be discussing things like detail views list views which actually help you
a lot.
But this is the most basic way to do it.
If a template view or do Control-C to stop running that server and in here let's say H-2 will put in
injected content in here I'll have something like inject me which will be the key for our contex dictionary
that we're going to be working with in just a little bit.
So my plan is inject something into this index page html page so I'll come back to views that pie in
the way to do this is pretty particular but it's actually not so bad.
You create a method called Get underscore context underscore data.
And since this is a method in O.P. you Passons self.
And then you passen quarks.
So the passen Asterix Asterix a W A R G S.
And let me take a brief moment to actually explain this sort of syntax that we haven't seen before to
Asterix signs and then quarks.
And you may have also seen something that's just one Asterix sign and.
So in Python basically what's going on here is the actual syntax is just one asterisk or two asterisks
whatever you pass after that doesn't really matter can be your choice but by convention you always see
to Asterix with quarks for keyword arguments or one Asterix of just arguments.
So let's talk about what this actually means.
Keyword arguments and I got to do that by kind of opening up a stack overflow link.
Let's hop to that now.
Right.
So I'm at the stack overflow link where Sullum basically answer the question what do this single asterisks
and asterisks mean.
Well let's start off with the single asterisks even though we won't be using it right now.
But basically what this does is it gives you all the function parameters as a giant tuple.
So if you have one star one Asterix with arcs inside of the function call.
So here you see a very basic function foo and it accepts args.
Basically what happens is for an Arkes you can do something.
So it passes this all in as a tuple and you might be thinking well why do you need that.
Well sometimes for a function you don't want to have a set number of inputs.
You want to be able to take as many inputs as necessary and in that case you can use args.
So here we pass in one.
It just prints out one we pass in one to three.
Food doesn't care since you said Ark's will just say print out one print to print three.
It's basically a way that you can prepare the function to accept more than one argument and it passes
that all in as a tuple and then the keyword argument.
Or using double asterisked sign gives you corresponding dictionaries.
So it's just kind of an advanced method are not necessarily advanced but kind of building on top of
that concept.
So we have keyword arguments and that's denoted by two Asterix sign.
And here we can see a very simple function it's just called Bar and the input it accepts is to actress
to stars to asterisked signs and keyword args.
Kate they'll be args and then it says for a in the keyword arguments.
Print a and then like a dictionary call print the actual value for that key.
And basically what this allows you to do is have the user define a parameters as they go along.
So here they can say OK names is going to be equal to one agency called 2007.
Now when you were creating that function you never said there's going to be a name parameter or an H
parameter.
What this keyword argument allows us to do is actually have the user defined those.
And then essentially we get back we use keyword arguments is a dictionary where you can pronounce a
the key they gave just case age and keyword argument which is 27.
Now remember that dictionaries don't retain any order which is why you see it printed out in some random
order in 8:27 and named one.
OK.
You can check out a stack.
Another stack overflow page.
Google search what is quarks or what is ARGs in case it doesn't make sense to you.
But essentially what it's aligned to do is take keyword arguments and treat them as a dictionary.
So I'm going to bring this aside now and let's continue back with using quarks and what we'll do here
is call context equal to.
And we're going to use the super function that's built into Python and also say get context data and
then passen the word arguments.
And you're kind of having trouble with just understanding what's actually going on here.
You don't actually need to know it on a deeper level you essentially just need to copy and paste this
line because the work you're going to be doing happens on this next line which is the typical contex
dictionary that we've seen before you pass in the key injects me which matches what we wrote on the
index bloodies HTML page and then whatever we want to inject.
So either a list or an item later on we'll see how to grab stuff from our model but we'll just call
this basic injection and then we return that contex dictionary and that's how you can use a context
dictionary with a template view.
And like I mentioned with list of use and detail views that we'll learn about in the next lecture you
will have to worry about this even less.
I'm just showing you the very basic way of doing it with a template view.
So don't worry too much if this particular line a or he word arguments doesn't make a whole lot of sense
to you later I'll see much easier ways of dealing with this to save views that pi.
And notice here I called contex inject me and if I go over the index page T.M. I have this inject Mielke.
So I should see when I actually run the server again this injected content and I'll say basic injection
in all caps.
So let's call I managed up-I run the server and then bring in our browser again.
And here it is.
We see testing template you inject the content and then basic injection.
All caps great.
And those are the very basics of returning a template with a context dictionary.
That's really all you need to know.
Usually however you're going to be dealing with a combination of models and forms and you'll want to
either list out every object in that model or list out a particular object with all its details.
And we're going to be learning about in the next lecture is another generic view probably the two most
common ones which is a list of view and a detailed view and they're going to be building off this idea
of the template you essentially setting some sort of convenient class object attribute.
And then just being able to call convenient methods off of that to create very easy views and detail
view and list of you're going to make your life a lot easier.
But to see them where we have to do is create models which we'll talk about in the next lecture and
then link them up to those views.
OK.
Hopefully by now you have a very basic understanding of the power of class based views and then the
next lecture will show you more of their convenience features.
Thanks I'll see at the next lecture.