Hello everyone and welcome to the set up in instillation lecture before we get started.
I wanted to note that there are many options for choosing your development environment and your browser.
In this course we're going to be using the Adam text editor and Google Chrome if you're very experienced.
Another idea that's an integrated development environment.
Feel free to go ahead and use it.
Maybe you already have a lot of experience with the subline text editor or high charm.
That's totally ok.
Feel free to use whatever feels comfortable for you.
If you already have a lot of experience of a certain ID although I still highly recommend you try out
Adam I've learned to really enjoy it and it works really well.
It's all the material in this course as far as the browser choice goes.
We do ask that you please use Chrome.
It is by far the most popular choice for web developers and I also want to make sure that the sites
that I run in this course will also run on your computer.
Again in this lecture we're going to show you where you can install Adam text editor from and give you
a quick tour of it.
Let's get started.
Go to Google in your browser.
OK so in your browser if you don't have google chrome.
What you should do is go to Google dot com slash chrome or just google search for the term Google Chrome
and eventually you'll find this page right here which is Gool about com slash Chrome.
There may be a bunch of information about their Chrome books which are their physical products.
What we really want is just Google Chrome itself so you can click here on download click for personal
computers and then click on the download link for the web browser.
OK.
So that's making it Google Chrome.
It's just a web browser.
I'm sure many of you are or most of you are already familiar with it then to actually get the text editor
for this course go to atom.
Io that's 80 m dot.
Oh and this is the Adam text editor that we're using for the course.
And the reason we use Adam text editor is because it can support across platforms that OS X Windows
Linux.
It has a built in package manager so you can search for and install new packages.
You can even create your own packages and plug ins all from within atom.
It has smart auto completion that will be using a lot during the course file system browser multiple
panes find replace features has a lot of stuff that we're going to be using often throughout the course.
Now other text editors also have these exact same features so Adam is not unique in these aspects.
But it works really well for what we're going to be doing for the course.
The main reason I really like Adam though is if you scroll all the way down there's two really interesting
things about it.
The first thing that I really like is that it's totally open source so it's totally free it's open source
and if you really want to make a change to the Adam text editor you can make a contribution and help
improve.
Adam text editor and then the second thing which is kind of more of a curiosity slash really interesting
aspect of it is that atom itself is actually built with a lot of the front end technologies are we in
this course it runs with h tim l javascript CSSA and a javascript library called node.
Yes.
And then it runs all that on a framework called electron which allows you to use web technologies actually
build desktop applications.
So that's just a little side fact we won't be dealing with electron at all in this course but maybe
after you've done taking this course you're interested in developing desktop applications will you'll
be able to use a lot of the skills in this course to build something like atom.
So that's just a quick side note to actually install Adam.
It's quite simple.
Just click here on the installation button.
If you're on Windows this will download an executable file.
You just double click it.
Run through the installation process.
If you're on a Mac OS this will be something like a dmg file again.
Double click it.
Run through the installation process and then if you're on Ubuntu I believe it's a tar file that you
can just then unpack.
OK so let me hop over to the Adam text editor and show you what it looks like.
OK so once you've opened Adam for the first time you should see a welcome guide and this is just a really
useful guide for you.
It has a bunch of information about the various features of ADOM such as how to open a project install
a package choose a theme.
If you don't like the default color theme you can just click here on choose a theme and then open the
theme picker and then check the other themes out.
You can even customize the styling and you can do anything with SS that we learned later on in this
course.
That's pretty cool as well.
And then you can actually add snippets.
Learn keyboard shortcuts.
I would recommend you check out these keyboard shortcuts.
I'll be telling you the most useful ones as we continue throughout the course but the main thing I want
to show you is how to open a project.
So if you click on open a project will open a file open her see just click open a project here and then
you can select any folder you want.
So hopefully by now you've downloaded the files that go of this course and then you can just add that
select that folder and add it to the actual file path.
So let me show you what that looks like.
I'll just select this folder right here.
And here it can see.
I've selected a folder Django lecture's has some files in it.
If you want to open a file you just click on it and then it opens up the file itself.
And here you can see I have some H-2 him all code and that's basically we're going to be doing throughout
the rest of the course.
We're just going to be running through your project folders and then adding files here.
And if you ever want to collapse this directory all you have to do is do command or control backslash
and then you can open and close that.
All right so that's the very basics of Adam.
That's really all you need to know throughout the rest of the course.
We're going to be showing you more and more features of Adam and then playing around a lot more.
OK thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.