Hello everyone and welcome back to part two of the Level 2 this lecture we're going to be discussing
and learning about the CSSA box model the box model allows us to precisely dictate how we want HVM l
elements to look on a page.
So the basic box model looks something like this.
You have your e-mail content that might be something like a paragraph of text within each T.M. then
in-between the paragraph or whatever HVM content you have and the border you have padding and remember
the border is something that actually played with performance C Ss that was things like a two pixel
dotted orange border around your content.
So if you want more space between actual content and the border you have padding there.
And then if you want some space between your border and other HTL content within their own box model
there's a margin you can specify beyond that order.
So each of these padding border and margin elements have a space that you can define.
That way you can space out your elements exactly how you want them to look and you just specify each
side to just beyond padding border and margin.
You can actually specify left the right bottom etc. to have even more flexibility and control over the
box model and your T.M. elements.
Let's explore some examples of this by jumping to our editor in our browser OK.
So here my editor I have an HMO file open called Part Two box models.
It's linked here in my browser and then I also have it linked to a style sheet here that's blank right
now.
Let's add a little bit of content to this.
Tim L5 to get started.
I'll add a Heading 1 elements and it will just be saying something like top and we'll give it the ID
top and then we'll add another Heading 1 and we'll call it bottom with the same ID.
So let's refresh this and see we have a top and bottom and now let's explore what happens when we adjust
the box model around these.
Remember the box small consists of the margin the border the padding and then the actual content.
So to make it clear what's actually going on.
Let's come back to the SS and then create a CSSA call for each of them for each of their IDs.
So that's top and bottom and we'll give each of them a border.
So the border for the first one let's have it be a four pixel solid blue border.
And for the bottom one we'll give it a border of four pixel solid red so save that refresh over here.
Now we can see now we have the actual borders around them.
So something that we can actually specify is the width of the border itself which we've experimented
a little bit by actually color pixels but we can do is the find with as a percentage so we can see right
now that this blue border here goes from essentially one end of the browser to the other.
And if I stretch this browser out as well you'll see that the Border continues to stretch along with
me stress in the browser which is good but sometimes you don't want it to go from ends and you want
to fine it based on some sort of percentage and you can do just that.
So if I want to find the with based off some percentage I can say 25 percent.
Now if I refresh this I can see we're going to tick up 25 percent of the width of the browser.
So as I expand this we can see we're expanding the blue browser as long as it takes up 25 percent of
the width of the actual page itself.
Now let's show you another thing we can do.
We've already seen text align bullets go ahead and show that if I say text the line center and refresh
this page I can see now my text is aligned to the center relative to the actual order.
Now let's imagine that I actually want to move this entire blue block around.
Well what do I have to change then we go back to our box model image which opened up here in a new tab.
We see that it's really the margin that's going to define the space between the border and everything
else so right now if we come back here I have the contents some order and then the margin and in between
the content and the border is padding.
But what we really want to change here is this margin right here.
I want to center this entire blue border.
And one thing we can do is actually specify specifically margin.
And then what I can say is the top right bottom and left pixels.
So we'll start off by showing you the pixels.
What happens if we say something like this 10 pixels on the top.
Let me actually put this as a comment so you can remember the order it goes.
Top right bottom left.
The other way we could do this is by actually specifying something like margined dash left.
So we saw earlier an image that I was pacifically specify left right top bottom but you can just do
it all in one single margin call just by the spacing and there's actually no comma that goes in between.
So we'll have the top 10 pixels margin right.
The 20 pixels and let's say bottom is a lot.
We'll make it 100 pixels and left will make it 400 pixel or something just so we can get an idea of
the differences here and refresh this.
We can see here now we're actually defined in the margin based off of pixels where the width is still
defined to be 25 percent of the actual width of the page.
Now if I call auto here to the margin
save this and refresh notice that it will be auto centered.
So if you want something to be centered not just the textbook the actual block itself that box model
we can see that we can call auto here and right now I'm calling a with of 25 percent of the browser
page and the margin is auto that it's even on both sides.
Great.
Now let's mess around a little bit with this bottom call.
Let's specify that with to be 50 percent of the page and let's give it some padding and remember padding
is going to make space between the actual content and the border itself.
So keep in mind what you think is going to happen if I say something like padding 200 pixels here what
do you expect the shape to look like as far as the relationship between bottom and this red border.
Well let's find out.
Going to refresh.
And this is basically exactly what we hopefully expected.
Remember padding is the difference between the content itself and the border.
So if we come back here we see that we have the content the padding and then the border.
So what do I do if I want to maybe align this to the center while I just come back here and call text
align center refresh.
I can see now my text alignment has been centered.
OK so that is the basics of learning the box model first.
SS Really we just want to focus on those four things the actual content itself the padding the border
and then the margin.
Or remember the spacing that happens between all of them and the fact they can call top left right or
bottom for each of those things OK.
Coming up next is going to be an explanation of a project that will really help hone in on these ideas.
I know we just really briefly covered it in the lecture but the next project is really designed for
you to kind of discover these things on your own.
And then the next section will be discussing Bootstrap which is going to help automate a lot of these
things so you don't have to worry every time by adding a new element what the border is what the with
is what the margin is etc..
A lot of that stuff is going to be taken care of when we begin to use bootstrap.
But for now we want to make sure that you understand if you had to go in and manually edit the assess
that you're able to do that with the box model.
So again box model maintains to get out that if you need to adjust your content you have the padding
border and margin all to play around with to get stuff to look exactly like you want it to.
And you can define things in percent or in pixel and then you can align things to be auto as well.
All right thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture we're going to explain that project to you and how it's really going
to help you understand the box model and it's also a font aspect to it as well.
Thanks.
I'll see you at the next lecture.