Hello everyone and welcome to part three of a small level one where we discuss how to create a list
an HMO.
A lot of times you want to get your information on your e-mail page organized.
And one way to do this is with a list an e-mail has two main types of lists.
That's an ordered list and an unordered list and we can actually then add list elements to each of these
types.
Let's get started by jumping to the Adam text editor and our browser.
All right here I am with my Adam text editor open and I have right now just the simple basics that DML
documents we've been working with and I've deleted everything beleft one heading one that says lists
on it.
Let me first show you how to create an ordered list.
Now an ordered list is numbered so you can see number one the first item number to the second item etc..
So to start off with an ordered list you just type o l and then you can click enter here.
And Adam text editor will automatically create the opening tag and closing tag for you and then inside
of this ordered list you're going to have list elements.
If I save this and then refresh my page you notice nothing's actually changed.
So I do have an ordered list there but with no elements in it to create a list item or list element
it's just as I said be your tag and then whatever you want in there.
So in this case we'll just say first item going to save that and refreshed this.
And I see now I have my one first item and let me zoom in here a little bit.
We're going to do control plus to zoom in on the safest Tim else we can see it a little better here.
So here's my first item.
And as I continue to add list elements into this order list such as my second item save this and refresh
the page you can see here that they are numbered and this will continue on as long as I just keep Eida
adding items into this actual list so third item there refresh and here we can see the numbering.
Now later on of CSSA you can actually change the numbers if you want to use something like roman numerals.
But this is a very basic default of an HMO ordered list.
Now a lot of times you actually don't want to number things you just want some sort of bullet point.
And if you want that then what you're looking for isn't an ordered list and to create an unordered list.
You use the tag UL for an ordered list.
So you all enter there.
It creates the opening and closing tags for me.
And now as the add list items all say bulat one here.
Add another item here will say second item.
You can really add whatever text you want here.
Well do ally enter here and then we'll say third item going to save this and refresh and I you see I
have an unordered list where there is no number but everything is just a bullet point.
And that's the main difference between an ordered list o l and an unordered list.
UL and the last thing I want to cover quickly here is a nested list.
So you can actually nest lists inside of each other and you can test an ordered list inside of an unordered
list or vice versa.
Let me show you an example of this and I'll show you kind of an extreme example of nesting lists.
So you usually won't see that many list and into each other but I just want to show you this.
You can get an idea of what's possible.
So here's an ordered list and I'm going to have two items in it.
First item one and then item 2 and I'm just using the autocomplete there enter to make that a little
quicker.
So here's item one here's item too.
And they're numbered because they're inside an ordered list.
And now I'm going to put in an ordered list inside of these ordered list tags I put in that an ordered
list which means if I add some new list elements will be inside so I'm going to say something like I'm
nested inside for that list item.
And you know make another list item that says also nested exclamation mark will save that refresh this
and we can see here that was that nesting.
We also get an extra in the notation.
So a symbol can show that this is nested inside of this list so if we wanted to get say Item one item
two and then we could say these are like sub items of item 2.
That is an unordered list.
Now we can actually keep going if this if you wanted something further nested then we could put an ordered
list in there and then say something like whoa I'm really nice that exclamation mark and let's emphasize
this by putting some of this in bold.
So remember we have these strong tags to put something in bold.
And I'm going to go in there.
We go.
Now let's save that.
Refresh this and we can see here.
Item one.
Item 2 we have this nested unordered list and then whoa I'm really nested there.
So it's just a very quick example of nesting lists.
We're not going to do it too often in the course but I just want you to be aware of the ability to do
that.
All right.
So that's really all there is for lists themselves.
It's a pretty basic topic remember you essentially have this oh well for ordered list and you fell for
an ordered list and then inside of either these every item in that list is going to have an L.A. tag
Corri list elements.
OK thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.