Hello everyone and welcome to the solutions lecture the function exercises from Part 2.
We're going to hop over to the editor and get started.
OK here I am at the javascript file.
And let's start off with Problem number one which is actually quite simple but it may be a little tricky.
First you can do all in one line.
So let's see how we can do this.
The basic question here is we want to write a function called sleep then that takes into boolean parameters
weekday and vacation.
And if the parameter week is true it means it's a weekday and if the parameter vacation is true it means
we're on vacation and we want to sleep in if we're on vacation or it's on a weekday.
So let's see how we can do that.
It's actually quite easy if you remember your comparison operators and logical operators where we can
do is just check that it's not a weekday.
With an exclamation mark so we say it's not a weekday or vacation is true because remember these are
just boolean values and that's actually all you had to do for this particular function.
So that's the solution for sleep in check that it's not a weekday or using the two pipe operators that
were truly on vacation.
That vacation is true.
Next up is a similar problem called monkey trouble.
And here we have two monkeys A and B in the parameters a smile and B smile indicate if each is smiling
and we're in trouble.
If they are both smiling or if neither of them is smiling and return true if we are in trouble.
So here is an example.
If a smiling and be smiling then we are in trouble.
If neither of them are smiling then we are in trouble.
If it's one of the other true false then we're not in trouble.
False.
OK so how can we do this.
Again this is actually an other one liner will say return.
I want to check for the case where they're both smiling.
So since these are both booleans I can just say a smile and be smile.
So if that's true and true then I am in trouble.
So that's one case.
Or we have to remember the other case so I can also put the second case in parentheses where neither
of them are smiling which is going to look almost the same except in this case.
I have these operators here
and that's the solution and one line right there.
So we check the case where they're both smiling or the case where neither of them are smiling.
Anything else will just return false.
Let's continue on to Problem number three.
And if you are having trouble with these and that I'm in multiple lines don't worry I'm showing these
solutions on purpose because once you've done a lot of programming and you're more of an experienced
programmer These are the type of solutions are going to be naturally doing.
If you still got the question right but did it in multiple lines.
Don't worry if you're just a beginner.
That's totally fine as well.
As long as it actually works.
Don't sweat it.
Moving along to Problem 3 string times.
So we are given a string and a non-negative integer n and we want to return a larger string that has
any copies of the original string.
We see here some input output examples.
So how can we do this.
Well it's type of code and show you are going to make a variable called Return.
S t r.
And that's going to be the string that I return and start off with.
It's just an empty string and then I'm going to say variable I's equal to zero.
And only a while loop loops a while loop that says While I is less than an
the return String that I made is going to add SDR which is the actual input string and then I'm going
to increment.
I once that while loop is done then I jus return the return String and that's all there is to it.
So let's review what's actually happening here.
I make an empty string.
I initialize I to be equal to zero and then will I is less than n.
I'm going to keep concatenating the SDR the input string to the return String and then increment by
one until I reach an and after that the while loop is over and I just return string itself.
So hopefully you remember here how to use a while loop and the fact that you can concatenate strings
together Louis long to Problem number four is a little more mathematical.
In this case even three numerical values A B and C returned their sum.
However there's a little special rule to it if one of the values is 13 then it does not count towards
the sum and values to its right.
Also do not count.
So for example if B is 13 both B and C do not count.
So it was 13 then none of the values would count.
So here we have a function lucky sum.
And let's see how we can do this.
It's actually just they essentially a bunch of if statements to check for the various cases.
So the first statement if I'm going to say if a is equal to 13.
Remember that was the case where if A's tickled the 13 then it doesn't count.
And nothing to the right counts right off the bat.
Physical 13.
I'm going to return 0
and then I'm going to check for the next case and that next case can be another if statement if the
is 13.
Return a.
And then we can say if C is equal to 13 in that case return a plus b and if none of those returns get
executed we could return a B plus C.
So that's all you can do this with just a bunch of if statements.
But let's rewrite this now to use if.
Else if and else statements.
So I'm going to delete this composite screen if you want to see this code.
Also the in solution.
Well let's show you now with if and else if statement.
So if a is equal to 13 and I was using double equal sign there just because we assume that we're actually
going to get integers not strings but if it's triple equal science 13 I return 0 then we have LCF.
So physical 13 then I'm going to return a which makes sense because I still only wants the left of B
when we say LCF see is equal to 13 and I'm going to return a plus b.
And else.
So if a is not equal to 13 and B's not equal to 13 and sees that equaled 13 that I just return the sum
of all of them a plus b c and that's how you can do this problem using if LCF and L statements.
It's up to you when you want to use the same gender one makes more sense to you is fine.
And then finally problem 5 the bonus problem if you're driving a little too fast the police officer
stops you.
And basically what happens here is we have to compute the ticket and we have some encoded integer values
where 0 is no ticket.
One is a small ticket and two is a big ticket and a first beat.
Well we were driving a 60 mph or kilometers per hour or less.
The result is zero.
If the speed is between 61 and 80 inclusive the result is one we get a small ticket.
And if the speed is 81 or more the result is two we get a big ticket unless it's your birthday.
And on that day your speed can be five higher in all cases.
So the second input this false true that indicates whether or not it is your birthday OK let's actually
write some code here I'm going to start off by with an if statement and I'm going to say if it's your
birthday.
So if is birthday speed I'm just right off the bat going to subtract 5 from it.
And then I can say if speed is less than or equal to 60 I return 0 and then I can say well show it with
the IF statements for now.
If the speed
is greater than 60 but less than or equal to 80 then I will say return 1.
And if none of those gets triggered then I just return to going too fast overall.
So that's say you can do just a few If statements and if you wanted to you could rewrite these to be
in if LCF and then an ELSE to return to.
So this would be the if statement this would be the Elspeth.
And then this would be the else it's really up to you again however you want to write them whether it
makes more sense to you.
The trick I used for this was basically this very first if statement which is outside of these last
three because it says essentially just saying OK if it is your birthday then the speed is minus five.
And that way I can just check against everything except subtract 5 from it.
To me personally that's what made the most sense logically.
But there's tons of solutions for this so your logic may be totally different than what's here depending
on how you dealt with it is birthday Bulleen so feel free to share the Q&amp;A forums your solutions.
Finally we have the bonus make bricks and for this bonus problem we wanted to make a row of bricks.
That is some sort of goal inches long and we have a number of small bricks that are one in sheet and
a number of big bricks that are 5 inches each.
We want to return true if it is possible to make the goal by choosing from the given bricks.
And this is a little harder than it looks but it can actually be done without any loops and in a single
line.
And like I said before if you can't figure this one out don't worry it's a bonus.
But let me show you how you could do this all in one line I'm going to say return and first I will say
take our goal.
Inches same model five greater than or equal to zero has to be true.
And the goal inches model five minus the amount of small Brick's has to be less than or equal to zero.
And if we come back here we want small plus five times as big to be greater than or equal to the goal.
And that's how you can do this launch.
This is problem all in one line.
So let's actually break down what's happening here.
So you remember we want to make bricks.
We have a certain number of small bricks that are 1 inch each and a certain number of big bricks that
are 5 inches each.
And we want to make the road that is gole inches long.
And what we really want to know is return true if it's even possible to make the goal by choosing from
the given bricks.
So for example if we have one small brick and one big brick we can make 1 inch five inch and six inch
goals but we wouldn't be able to make four inch goals because we don't have enough small bricks and
we have just one big brick so we can't actually make that incircle if you will.
So that's kind of the logic behind the solution.
So the very first one just checks if the goal maade of five is greater than or equal to zero.
Then that checks for the large bricks and then we do this.
The goal modifies minus the amount of small bricks needs to be less than or equal to zero here.
And basically what that means is I need to know that I have enough filler bricks between the counts
of five.
So between the multiples of 5.
This checks for the actual filler bricks and then here this last case where I say small plus five times
big checks I have the right combination of small bricks and big bricks in order to at least meet or
exceed that goal.
OK.
So take your time.
This one's really tricky to think about.
And like I said it's not so much about general javascript's syntax it's more about programming in general.
I would recommend that you check out coding that dot com.
So if you scroll all the way up here I mentioned the actual Web site called coding that dot com.
They actually have a full video explanation on how you can get to this one line of code for this make
bricks problem.
It's kind of the famous problem on the Web site because it's so tricky and this solution on a one line
can seem so unintuitive at first so take your time with it.
Visit coding that com search for make bricks and you'll find that question along with a full video explanation
of the specific solution for it.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
Hope you enjoyed the exercises.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
If you get stuck on anything I'll see you at the next lecture.