Hello everyone and welcome to part three the front end project for this project we're going to be coding
through the creation of a Kinect for game and we're going to be heavily using j crew for this project.
And just a quick no we probably are using J.Crew more than we actually should.
So I really want to focus your knowledge of J.A.G. for this project.
We will be using j creates actually built the Kinect for game when in reality it would probably be a
smart idea just to use Badillo javascript arrays for a lot of the work here.
We're going to be interacting with the Dom really heavily.
So keep that in mind.
We're going to be really focusing on Jay queery for this project.
There are many many ways you could have build a connect for game using the front end stack that we know
so far this is just one way that heavily features Jake queery and Dom.
So this project is also completely optional.
Feel free to only watch to skip a completely ordinary sackless straight on your own.
This project will conclude our formal coverage of the front end stack.
So really if you've reached this point Pat yourself on the back you've learned a ton already and you've
basically completed the entire front end stack.
And after this we'll be talking about the back end with Python and Django.
All right let's take a look at what this project actually looks like when completed.
And then you can decide how you want to approach the project after that in the next few lectures we're
going to be coding through the solution.
Let's hop over to my browser and show you what the project looks like.
OK.
This is what the project looks like.
Upon starting the project you get an alert that says Player 1 enter your name you'll be blue.
So I will just input player 1 and then player to enter your name.
You will be red.
So he can give this some other name just give it the name be you hit enter and then we see the screen
so says welcome to Connect.
For the object of this game's connect for your chips in a row and player one player to alternate.
But the thing is you only get to pick a column and that is the column where you're going to drop either
your blue or red chip and it has to go all the way down.
So for player 1 to turn so we can pick this column.
Now we can see our chip dropped all the way down.
So as Player B if I also pick that column it drops on top of that one.
Now we can continue this process until someone has won the game.
Hopefully you're already familiar.
Connect Four If not you can always just read the rules.
It's a very simple game.
So here let's have blue win.
By correcting for and once we've connected four it says Player 1 has one refresh your browser replay
again.
And if I refresh my browser I get the alerts again.
So I will give player one a player to be in here that javascript's has loaded and I'm ready to play
again.
And that's really all there is this game.
So feel free to either completely skip this project tackle it completely on your own or just have a
code along section with me.
Coming up in the next few lectures.
Thanks everyone.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.