Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on template inheritance.
Let's learn how we can use Django template inheritance to practice dry coding principles dry standing
for it.
Don't repeat yourself template inheritance allows us to create a base template we can inherit from.
Earlier we saw that we created a base that H team l file but left it blank in this lecture.
We're going to explain what we're going to be using it for.
And in the next lecture we'll actually code out through the example template inheritance saves us a
lot of repetitive work and it makes it much easier to maintain the same base look and feel across our
entire web site for example if we wanted a nav bar at the top of our page it wouldn't make sense to
have to continually have the same nav bar ASTM Elco in each individual the HTL file.
Before this lecture we used to have to have the same nav bar as HTML code over and over again if we
wanted to extend it to every page in our Gengel project.
Granted we haven't actually done that at all yet but we would have had to do that given what we know
so far.
So instead of doing that we can actually set it to the base h team l file and inherits it using template
inheritance this idea is also sometimes known as template extending as an extending the base the HTL
file to other aged him files.
The inheritance doesn't need to just be limited to one base to each team file.
You can extend multiple templates.
Before you begin any Gengel project.
It's always a good idea to sketch up the main idea organization by hand.
This will help you realize what can be used for template inheritance and what applications you should
create planning out your project in this manner will really give you a good idea of what code is going
to be constantly reuse.
So you can put that into your base.
Each team El-Fadl.
OK so what are the main steps for inheritance.
Actually pretty simple.
First you find the repetitive parts of your project.
Things like now bar or a picture or a brand that you're going to see on most of the pages.
Then you create a base template of those repetitive parts such as the nav bar.
Then you set particular tags in the base template and also those tags and just the second.
Once you've done that you extend and call those tags anywhere else in those other H.T. mail files that
are not the base the HTML file.
So what does it actually look like.
Well on the left hand side we have that base to him file.
This is the file it's going to have things like links to your javascript your assess your bootstrap
a bunch of each team all things like nav bars etc. stuff that you want to inherit on to the other pages.
Then inside the body stuff that you don't want on every single page you have these two main tags and
that's the block tag with the name of the Block.
In this case is the body block and then you have the end the block tag.
Then you can have some more footer HTML.
Outside of that and in that left hand side baste the HTML file.
Basically what this is saying is everything outside of that is going to be inherited in the other file.
So we can see here we have some other HTL file and we want to make sure that the first line is always
doctype h T.M. after that you can call the extends and then actually call the path to your base studies
to metafile and then after that you call block body underscore or block that matches the name of your
baseless email file and then you have your HTL that's specific to this other that each team file stuff
that wasn't in the base then each team l.
Then once you're done with that you call and block so you can see it's kind of the reverse or opposite
on the left hand side you see everything outside of that is going to be passed in when we extend that
to the right hand side and on the right hand side everything in sight close by the box is going to be
put into the base sites female or extended with the base that it's Steimle.
OK.
So let's actually walk through a basic example of this temple inheritance.
It's actually a really easy and smooth process and once you start using temple inheritance is actually
going to make it much easier to read HTL files across your web page because you're going to get rid
of all this junk repetitive code.
And after that we'll all go to your base sites HTML file.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.