Welcome back everyone to this lecture on adding filters so we can also add filters for Adam in view
of our models and filters will automatically show up on the right hand side of the view and they will
also auto filter the printing on the data type.
And I'll explain more about that later on.
Keep in mind not every field will be useful as a filter.
Let's explore how to easily create filters for admin views and hop over back to the editor.
OK here I am at my admen PI file and if you notice what we have right now for bring in over my browser
is if I'm selecting videos then check out the movies.
I see a list of movies and I can search them and then I can also add movies here when I want to do is
if we come back to home.
Notice how the built in users has a filter filter by staffs that is super Beezer status active etc.
so I can filter based off these different fields.
I'm going to show you how to add in those kind of filters for your own models.
On the admin page so to do that it's actually really simple.
All you need to do is in this class that we created and you can do this for any model that you may just
create another class such as customer admin.
The attribute you need to add in is called Whoops list underscore filter and then you just added the
list of things you want to filter by so different attributes of your model that you can filter by.
So for movies what might make sense is filtering by for instance a release year or filtering by the
genre.
Or maybe even the length etc..
Well probably does not make sense of filter by is the title.
So I get to add all of these as filters that you can get an idea of how this actually works and why
some of these choices are probably not good choices for filters.
So I bring back my movies over here and I'm going to refresh.
Now I can see over here on the right hand side let me kind of expand this.
You can see it on the right hand side over here.
We zoom in a bit.
I can see by filter so filtering by really cear that may make sense because you know there's different
or multiple movies per release year by length that could also make sense depending if things are standard
length or not by title.
Doesn't really make sense because titles probably a unique ID in this model so you don't want just kind
of hundreds of titles here.
So usually I want to filter by some sort of categorical attribute of your model where many movies or
many objects are going to fit to that category.
OK so that's how you can easily add in a filter and that's really all there is to it.
As a quick review it's just an attribute of lists underscore filter.
And then the actual attributes you want to filter by.
OK thanks everyone and I'll say at the next lecture.