Hello everyone and welcome to part four forms.
Basics creating forms and each Malle really revolves around the idea of the in that tag.
And throughout this lecture and the subsequent lectures we're going to be looking at various types of
inputs for forms and how we can use them to accept user input.
So if you've ever visited a Web site where you had to input your email password into the form online
and then click submit that's an HMO form forms are actually going to be a key component of Django later
on.
But in order to really understand how to use them with Django you need to fully understand them with
just pure HCM.
Let's get started by looking at some basic examples.
Go jump to the text editor now.
All right so I'm a text editor open and I have my browser open.
And before we get started I just wanted to show you the two reference links you can actually find inside
the part for forms basics HTML file that correspond with this lecture.
One of them goes to the W3 schools where it just talks about input types.
So here you can see html input types and the basic form of an input tag is the input tag.
And then we specify the type and noticed you can have text types.
You can have password types submit types so has a little submit button.
And later on we're going to really be exploring a bunch of other types such as radio buttons dropdown
checkboxes etc..
So that's the idea behind this.
And if you want a more technical reference you can always check out the muzzle Developer Network web
site which is also linked in that aist him l file.
So let's get started by just kind of walking through this.
So basically what we do is somewhere in the body you start your form.
So before we actually get started I'm going to make two headings I'll say something like.
Log in and then we'll say heading to please input your we'll say e-mail and password.
Save that refresh over here and then we see log in please and put your email and password.
Let me just zoom in a little bit on that.
So it's a little clear.
And here we have our two headings later on we're actually going to learn how to do civically label inputs
but right now just keeping it basic let's simulate a loggin site.
First we have to do then is call a form and if you want we can actually call form like this.
And then we have our form or opening tag and our closing tag and we see we have a class which will make
a lot more sense when we talk about C Ss so you can just ignore that for now.
We have an action which is going to be later on use to actually call an action the Peniel kind of for
me using.
And then we have a method which is post right now we actually don't need to worry about any of these
things.
We're going to talk a lot more about them.
But basically the action is later on we're going to be sending the data and then the method of has to
do a get post a DTP method.
Right now we don't know enough to really use any of these so we're just going to delete all that and
just have form save that.
Now let's stick our two headings inside of this form tag.
And as I mentioned the main part of creating a form really revolves around those input tags.
So we're going to do is call an input tag and then we notice that as we call input and then enter Adam
text editor will automatically say type equals name equals and value equals and so let's break this
down type is where you actually clarify what type of input you want and by default it's type text.
And that's something we're going to be exploring a lot through this lecture in the next couple of lectures.
Different types of inputs.
Then you have the name of the input and the name of the input is just the name of scientists input so
you can call it on later in some other files.
And then we have the value and the value is the actual default value that's placed inside there.
So let's explore this right now.
Let's start off with one of the most common types of inputs which is an e-mail type and an email type
basically just checks to make sure you have an email in there will give this a name and we'll call it
user e-mail.
So let's save this and refresh.
And now we noticed that we have an actual text box here.
And what's different between a normal type equals text and a type equals e-mail.
Is that the e-mail type is going to make sure later on when we actually click submit that we have an
at gmail dot com or at yahoo dot com.
Or an actual e-mail in there.
So for a normal text type input you could just put in user and it would work.
But for a type e-mail it's going to make sure that you actually have X and then a dot com or a dot in
there.
So maybe you've been using a web site you actually mistype your e-mail and a little pop up will say
Please enter a valid email address.
This is the type of input they're using to automatically do that.
And basically all this work is being handled behind the scenes by your browser just specifying the type
will basically take care of that for you.
And that's really the big part of the beauty of H-2A mail.
It works across browsers that way at least for the most common types and it does create an other input
or our password.
So we'll say this type is password we'll save it refresh.
And I noticed that we had two boxes.
This was the email and this was the password.
Well look what happens when I start typing in my password here.
It's actually hidden from me and that sort of default behavior is happening because I specified this
type to be password instead of just the default text or an email type.
And these are the kind of types right now that you don't need to worry about memorizing them too much.
You always have those reference links for the different input types that are in the four forms basic's
that each team metafile those two links I explained earlier.
But eventually you're going to be using these inputs so often that you're going to just remember off
the top of your head.
Oh I need an e-mail type in a password type etc..
Right now don't worry too much about memorizing all of these.
And let's go ahead and get this input and Main.
So we will call this just a very simple name something like password and that name can later be used
to actually reference this.
So again you don't see anything changed here on the form.
And finally let's discuss this value.
So the value is if you want a value to be pre-filled there.
So let's say email here and we'll say password please save that refresh and notice her the value.
It basically has a corresponding default here.
So e-mail here password please.
But notice that right now this password please just shows up as a blank password.
So it does make a whole lot of sense to put a value here into that.
And later on we'll show you some better ways of actually showing some default text there.
But that's what you can use if you want it to be pre-filled.
And then finally one of the most important input types is the submitters and we don't need to give that
a name or value but we just refresh and here we have a little submit button.
And this is a little submit.
But look what happens here.
It says Please include an ad in the e-mail address e-mail here is missing.
So let's actually give this type submit a value I will type and submit their refresh and notice.
Now the submit button actually has a submit their in-call this whatever you want like please click me
save that refresh Quick me.
All right.
So let's explain what's going on here.
There's only three lines but there's actually a lot of moving parts.
So if we look at this code.
Everything here is wrapped in form tags.
And that's actually really important.
That allows them to know that we were talking about a complete form here and we have three input types.
The first one is e-mail.
The second one is password and the third one is submit and the key idea I want you to just take in right
now is not how everything is linked and working together but really the fact that you can call an input
tag specify type give it a name to reference it later on.
Right now that doesn't make a whole lot of sense because they haven't really used the name yet.
And then de-value which has some default value for its Ehab.
Sometimes that default value doesn't make two cents such as wifi password type.
Otherwise you just see a bunch of dots there or Asterix and then you sometimes really do need a value
such as with the submit button where it just looks like an ugly button if you don't have the value there.
All right.
So this right now the submit button is linked to these two inputs because if I click click me it will
actually work so I'll say something like please include it at the e-mail address.
E-mail here is missing at.
And that's why we want to specify something like type e-mail.
So now if I say hello at yahoo dot com and then put in a password click me.
Looks like it's ok.
Nothing's actually happening here it's just clearing it.
Every time we click Submit We'll get into that sort of functionality later.
I do actually grab information from those input cells.
But right now the very basics is you coliform tag.
You call these input tags you specify type.
You can give it a name which we'll use later on and you can give it a default value.
Sometimes you're not going to really want a default value such as the password.
Sometimes you really will submit button.
All right let's just walk through just a couple more examples some maybe a little sillier examples of
different types of inputs and a really fun one is the choose color input and it's just a color input
so let me show you what that looks like.
I'll say something like.
Choose color as heading 1 and heading 2 is going to be click on button and then I'm going specifying
input or enter there and the type is going to be a color.
So let's say that refreshed this page and notice it says choose a color.
Click on button and this is a default color picker.
So if I click on this button right here I get this little pop up that allows me to actually pick a color.
So for instance I can pick this purple color.
OK.
Now we can see a change to purple or we pick up bright red.
It OK.
And I can see it changed to bright red.
So all of that functionality is built straight into T.M. just by specifying the type is equal to color
and that's sort of a fun example.
Now let's show one more which is essentially the default.
So I'm going to say heading to will say enter some text.
And then we'll have some input.
And we're just going to leave it as the type the text which is the default and I say something like
X goes here we'll save it.
Refresh Elsy text goes here which means I can type just random text here.
And it works just fine.
Let's zoom in a little bit and you can see that there's really no limit on how much text that can right.
Later on we learn about things like a text area type which allows us to have a larger section or like
paragraphs of text but those are just a few of the input types that you can use as you begin to create
form.
So just the very basics here that we've covered really all I want you to be aware of is that there is
a foreign tag there are input tags and you can specify the type of input and certain types of input
will have restrictions such as the email type will have the restriction that you need an at symbol when
you actually click that submit.
But that's really all I want you to get out of this lecture for right now in the next lecture we're
going to be talking about two more things we'll talk about labels and how they work when you can actually
label one of these inputs.
And then secondly we're going to go back and talk about that form with the action and method arguments.
Remember that when I first typed in form and it had autocomplete it had these calls right here an action
and a method and the next you're going to be discussing those and seeing what happens when we combine
that with some sort of Submit button.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.