Hello everyone and welcome to part 4 divs and spans.
So in this lecture we're going to be showing you some examples of how to use a div and Hispan tag.
However keep in mind that we actually won't really be able to utilize them until we learn about CSSA.
Basically we're going to be using DIVX and spand tax to actually group together blocks of H Tim L.
And the reason we want to group them together usually is to apply CSSA to them.
So keep that in mind as we learn about them in this lecture.
They probably won't seem to take any effect into account but later on we will see how they are useful
when adding in style of success.
Let's jump to the Adam text editor just to show you how they work.
OK so here I am at the Adam text editor and I also have my browser open and a little zoomed in here
so you can see the text clearly.
Right now I just have a heading one here.
Let me go in and show you what it would look like if you were to use a DIV tag and this basically stands
for division and then allows you to tag together groups of elements into basically generic containers.
So for instance let's say I have another heading 1 and this is something that says we'll call it group
1 and then I have a paragraph here that says I want to be together in group 1.
So let me say that refreshed this.
And we see we have different span's group 1 and then the paragraph says I want to be together in group
1.
Later on when we learn about CSSA what we want to do is add styles to particular elements in our T.M.
and what we can do that is actually saying okay apply style number one.
So for instance the color red to all heading 1 tags.
So that would just go along and say Hayes is heading 110.
OK this font colors now red.
It's is heading 110.
OK this font color is now red.
But sometimes you actually don't want to do it by the actual element type.
You want to do it by specific division or a group of elements that you define.
And the way you can do that as we'll see later on the CSSA section is actually calling a DIV tag.
And so the way with the work is you can see here I have div..
Now if I hit enter.
Notice that we automatically get this class to pop out here and that's going to allow us to essentially
name this division after a class and then we can apply styles to that class and we can put whatever
you want in that class.
So for instance I cannot put this all here give this class a name such as something like group 1.
Save this.
And if I refresh us we won't notice anything different.
Here in D.H. Tim L..
Later on when we learn about C Ss we'll learn how to actually add style to a division with a class name
instead of just actual element tags.
And that's basically what we're going to be using a division for.
So right now there's still time by itself and each T.M. doesn't mean a whole lot it's going to mean
a lot more we learn about C Ss So if this was a little unclear to you especially if that class keyword
don't worry about it too much it's going to make a lot more sense in the future.
I just want to introduce it now because it really is just a Tamil.
It's not C Ss it's used in combination of C Ss OK and then the last thing I want to mention here is
the span tag and basically the spand tag is almost the exact same thing as a division except it's inline
instead of grabbing an entire container.
So let's say we have this class or this div division of group 1.
If I wanted to make essentially a little inline container to only apply effects to an inline section
so only apply effects for instance to these three letters or three words here be together in what I
could do is wrap them in a span tag and then put whatever I want there to be in that span.
And again I want to say this and refresh this here we don't notice any difference because we haven't
actually applied any style to it.
But just keep these two words in mind for tagging when we later learned about C Ss.
OK so again not a whole lot to actually show here.
Basics of this lecture's just to be aware that there is a DIV tag and a span tag.
If their usefulness doesn't make a whole lot of sense to you right now don't worry about it.
It will make a lot more sense when we actually read or reach the CSA section of the course.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.