Hello everyone.
Welcome back to where we left off last time and this lecture will be discussing two topics inheritance
and special methods.
Inheritance is a way to form new classes using older classes that have already been defined that way.
The newly formed classes are called derived classes and the classes that we derive from are called the
base classes.
So you derive from the base class important benefits of inheritance our code reuse and reduction in
the complexity of a program that we don't have to constantly be creating duplicate classes.
You can just inherit from another class and use some of the methods that are available there.
So let's see an example of this.
I'm going to create a base class and this base class is going to be called Animal class in the Animal
class it needs its initialization method.
That's a special method in it.
And here we'll just have self and then we'll say Prince animal created so we're doing very very simple
class just to show kind of the idea behind inheritance.
Usually you won't have a print statement inside of the initialization method.
You'll just have self-taught and then all your attribute assignments then I'm going to create another
method called Who am I will call itself.
And then this is going to print animal.
And then here and going say eat.
This will also take in self and then this will just prints eating that needs to be a string.
All right.
So a very simple class it just prints things when you call these two methods on it.
It prints something else.
So it's actually kind of play around with this and explore a little bit.
I'll make an animal we'll call it say my A is equal to animal instantiate that and then let's have it
say something like my a dot.
Who am I.
And then my A thought it.
And no I don't have to wrap this in print because the prince is already inside of these two methods.
So it's called Python those pie.
And I see here animal and eating perfect.
All right.
Now let's say I want to create a new class of dog.
Now all dogs are animals so I want to inherit from the base class of animal.
So I'm going to do here is instead of just passing nothing in these princes I will pass in the other
class which was animal and I don't have clothes princess here.
I'm just passing the whole class in there and then I'm going to say the F in it's essence self.
And then one actually creates the initialization.
I'm going to call animal dot in its And then pasand self here and then I'm going to Prince dog created
so will save this and then notice when I ran this first time it said animal created animal eating.
So that was for when I created an animal that animal created when I said who it's that animal.
When I said eating it said or when I said eat it said eating.
So what I'm going to do now is save this and then I'm not going to create an animal.
Instead I'm going to create a dog and have this be say it's my dog my dog who is my and then my dog
here.
Now when I save this and run it by fun it's that pie expand this so we can see the output here.
It says animal created dog created animal eating.
So that makes sense because when I created the dog I said animal here in it self.
So it means initialize an animal and then we say print them created.
Now I don't actually have to have this initialization line so I'm going to comment that out.
And now let's actually see what happens when I run this.
It says that created animal eating.
So know that even though the class dog does not have who him-I or eat methods inside of it it was able
to inherit those methods or derive those methods from the base class of animal.
And that's basically the entire idea behind inheritance is the fact that you can inherit from another
class or derive another class and then you can see here I can call who am I.
And eat even though they're not strictly defined inside of this dog class.
Now I can also create new methods here so I can say something like Barch it takes in self and then it
says print's.
So now I can go all the way down here and say My dog bark close parentheses.
And when I run this I should be able to see my new class Wolf.
Now I can also overwrite classes so I'm not strictly limited to everything that was an animal.
If I want eat to say dog eating I can do that as well.
All I have to do is just say F and then call eat pasand self.
And then basically right over it.
So here I'll say now dog eating save that.
So when I run this again Python oats I see that dogs created animal dog eating Wolf.
So I was able to successfully overwrite the previous method.
You can check out the nose for more examples of this.
But the basic idea I want you to get is that if you've already created the class and you want to use
some of those methods in a new class all you have to do is inherit it like this and you can then derive
from the base class.
All right.
So special methods are basically going to allow you to perform special operations and these methods
are not actually called directly but they're called by specific Python language syntax.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
Imagine that I create a list I will say my list is equal to 1 to 3 and then I say Prince my list and
if I run this by fun notes that pi I see 1 2 3 I printed my list.
Zoom a little bit out.
Now what happens if I create my own class and try to print it.
So I will create a class called book and this is going to be a very simple thing so far.
Say d f will pass an R in its special method will say self and this will also have a title and author
and pages and then what we will do here is say colon and assign those attributes.
So a self-taught title is equal to the title self the author is equal to the author provided and then
say self-taught pages is equal to the pages provided lips pages great and now what I will do is say
B is equal to book clothes print CS and then add in the title.
So the python is the title Wilson and the author Jose and we'll say it's 200 pages long and I always
say Prince B.
Print my book.
So is kind of the exact same thing we did here.
It's it.
Notice what happens when I run this I say Python what's up high.
I enter when I print out my book object it says main book object at its location in memory.
So the question arises What is the print function actually doing and how can I get it to pronounce something
that looks nicer.
Something that says like title Python author Jose pages 200.
Well what happens when you call the print function on an object is it looks for its string representation.
And right now we haven't actually specifically defined the books string representation.
We need to use what's known as a special method to do that and all special methods inside of a class
are annotated with two underscores the name of the special method and then two extra underscores and
we can see here the syntax highlighting also notes that there are special method and they all need to
take in the self argument so this special method as TR is the string representation of my object.
So whenever a function asks for the string representation of my object and the print function does that
it will return whatever I put here to return.
So I will just say return.
Hello.
We save that and when we run this we get back.
Hello when I print out my book and let's delete this my list is for an old beat using it anymore.
So realistically you're not going to want to say return hello but instead you're going to want to return
a string representation that actually makes sense.
And for our case the string represents representation that might make sense as something like title
and will use some formatting here.
Author and then let's say pages and then we will say that format and we Passons self-taught title comma
sulpha author comma self-taught pages and we will save this unless checked to see if we made any errors
and if everything runs correctly.
OK here we go.
When I actually called to print B or print that book prints the actual function.
Looked for a string representation and that was returned by the special method in which case we got
back.
Title Python author Jose pages 200.
And this is how you are going to going to typically see the special method SDR for a string representation
used.
Now will show you a couple of more useful special methods.
So another special method is the Eliane or length method.
So imagine I call Eliane on a list 1 1 to 3.
I know I will get back the number 3 indicating three elements inside of that list.
But what happens if I call length on B while I can return or save this and run it and lets actually
print out LNB But notice what happens.
I should get an error and it says object of type book has no link which means I need to add in a special
method.
The E-F underscore underscore Elyon underscore underscore.
And this is the length method so underscore underscore let me make sure I have balanced underscores.
OK two on each side.
I type in self and then what I end up doing is returning whatever I want.
The length representation to be of my book and a good representation here of the length of the book
would probably be the pages so I call self-taught pages.
Note that including self-taught pages and not just pages by itself.
So now see if we can print the link for the book without any errors.
When we get back 200 which makes sense because that's what I find here as the length of the book.
So what this link function that's built into Python does is it goes inside the object checks if it has
a special method Eliane and then returns whatever that method tells it to return and then finally one
other special method that you may find yourself encountering.
And there are a lot of special methods as you can see here.
All of these are special methods so anything that is wrapped in two sets of underscores is a special
method and there's a whole bunch of them that I'm just showing you the most common ones.
We'll explore more as we continue on with Gengel later on but delete is another special method you might
find yourself running into.
And that's just when you call deletes.
So I will say Prince book is destroyed.
And the way you can delete an object from memory space is with DL and then whatever the object name
was.
So now if I run this code I get back.
I created a book but a book has been destroyed.
All right.
That's all you need to know for special methods.
The most common one will probably be using throughout the rest of the Course.
Is this one the SDR the string representation.
Because if we ever want to print something it's important that we have the method to do that and not
get any errors.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture where we're going to be walking through a
project for you to do to practice object oriented programming.