Hello everyone and welcome to part three we're going to be discussing python lists lists our pythons
form of arrays and they behave very similarly to a javascript array.
Well we're going to do is begin to understand the important features of Python by jumping to the editor
and getting started OK so let's begin by showing you how to create a list creating a list in Python's
really simple you just type in whatever you want the variable to be equals and then you use square brackets
and separate every item in the list by a comma.
So for instance here is a list of the numbers 1 2 and 3.
Now we just created a list of integers but we can also create a list of many different ogic types.
So for example I could say my list and have it hold some string stuff maybe some more numbers integers
some floating point numbers and then later I will see how it can hold a booleans and more.
So again we can have mixed data types inside of a list and we can even have a list nested inside of
a list.
So this is totally good code and it will work.
So let's actually run this to verify that I'm going to call Python and then I call this script list
that PI enter.
We don't get anything out because we didn't print the list so we can do this print my list and let's
comment this one out.
Again this just command forward slash entry and we see that the list has no problems being printed out.
And just like a string we can call the Eliane function on it.
So length of my list.
And let's not use the more normal list 1 2 3 and actually print out that length and we see we have three
items in the list one two and three.
OK.
Indexing is slicing works basically the same as that in a list or excuse me in a string.
So I'm going to read the fine list to be a b and then whip's comma.
See if I want the very first item in the list I just have to use my list 0.
So let's print that out and confirm this should return a.
So if I run this to enter I get back I wanted see I could just say negative 1 and that would give me
back the last item in the list and to add a couple more terms in here so we can see how slicing works
not just indexing by hand.
ABC if I want to grab everything starting at index 1 all the way to the end again is just one colon
and that will give me b all the way to the end.
Or if I want everything from the beginning up to but not including index 3.
So this should be ABC.
I get a list ABC.
All right.
Now let's talk about actually adding items to a list of like a string.
Lists are immutable meaning I can say my list grabbed the item at index 0 and set it equal to something
totally different.
So let's say new item here and let me print out my list and let's print it out before.
So we'll say before reassignments and then prints my list.
Not as a string as the variable itself.
And then we will prints after reassignments save this run the code and here you can see before re-assignment
I have ABC and then with line code number five with this re-assignment I have new item B C D E and that
just puts the point forward that we can actually do reassignments with index calls on a list defining
it as a mutable item.
OK.
Now let's talk about some basic list methods that you may find useful if you want to add new item and
have it be appended to the very end of a list.
All you have to do is use the append call so I can say my list and you can see the very first one here
is a pen.
So we can select that and then you can append any item to the list so I can say something like.
New item
and this will not affect any current item in the list.
It will just append it to the very end of the list.
So now let's print my list after we appended.
So I'm going to save run this again and here I can see my list was now a b c d e and then new item was
appended to the very end of it.
If I end up appending a list to this.
So let's say I have a list that says X Y and Z just to make this clear.
Note my brackets here.
Actually appending a new list to the end of this.
What's going to happen is that now this very last item completely is a list.
If you actually want this list to be a part of the original will you have to do is NOT use a pen but
use the extend method.
And then we can let's just actually put this to a new variable.
So we'll say list two is equal to that list.
And I'm going to instead of appending something I will extend that save this note the difference here.
This was with a pen.
That means the very last item is the list so the list nested inside of another list.
If I use extend instead and then print out the list then I actually extend the list to include these
all these items right here.
So note the bracket difference between append and extend and you only use X10 when you want to extend
another list with the original list.
So we've talked about adding things to a list but what if you actually want to remove something from
a list.
Well the most common method for removing something from a list is the pop method.
So I can say my list does pop.
And basically what this does is it grabs the very last item from a list and returns it.
So we'll call this item and then say print my list and print item.
So it's going to happen here when I run this is my originalists was AB ABC then I popped off the very
last item in the list save that to the variable item and then when I print out my list e is now gone
an item is now that letter e.
If you do not want to grab from the very end of a list you can actually specify an index position in
pop so this can be any integer index position as long as it's in the list.
So if I put 0 here now it's going to pop off index 0 which is a.
So let me run this again.
And now I see B C D E and I have a as my item and that's the pop method.
And keep in mind pop method returns an item to more useful methods that you may find yourself using
our reverse and sort.
So if I say my list reverse close parentheses and then actually print out my list
that I will get a reversed version to the list ECB A and something that's interesting to note here is
that this occurs in place and what I mean by in place is I didn't have to save this to another item
to see the change effect.
All I had to say was my list that reverse and my list was changed in place permanently.
So then when I reprinted my list it ended up being in reverse down here.
So that's reverse.
And then let's create a list here with a bunch of numbers in it some random numbers and is that a reverse.
What I'm going to do is ask for sort in if I save that and run this it will actually end up sorting
that list.
So Python has its own rules for sorting things especially if you have multiple data types and they're
like strings and numbers.
It has a specific hierarchy and you can check out the Python documentation.
If you find yourself needing to know that hierarchy but for the rest of this course we won't be dealing
with sorting mixed data type lists and it's actually bad practice to do that because it's unusual to
have to do that operation should try to have only one sort of data type for a single list.
OK finally I want to mention two more topics which is a nested list index and then a list comprehension
and will cover a list comprehensions in much more detail later on.
But I want you to be aware of them now since they may be confusing to beginners.
But if I have a nested list so will say my list is 1 2 and then the third item in the list is going
to be x y z.
If I call Prince my list and I'm looking for the third item.
So an index to what's going to happen when I print this is I get this entire list back.
So if I run this right now I get X Y and Z.
Imagine that I'm only looking for the letter Y.
All I have to do here is add another set of brackets to actually index this list that was returned to
me.
And why is index 1.
So I just put the number one here save it run this again.
And now I get the letter Y return to me and that's how you can index a nested list and you can do this
with a nest within an S within a nest.
That's not too common.
Usually elect to do two levels at most.
But keep in mind this could keep going over and over again depending how many lists you had nested inside
of another list.
So that's nested list indexing.
And finally I want to show you a list comprehensions so to do this I'm going to create a list called
Matrix which is going to be a nested list.
So this will be one to three as the first item or 5 6 as the second item and then 7 8 9.
So right now I have three lists inside of a single list.
There's only three items in Matrix but each item is three more items in the list which means I can do
something like Matrix
0 0 and that counts as one.
So the very first item here and the very first item of the item.
Now for a list comprehension.
It's basically going to be like a for loop but flattened out into a list.
So if I want the very first column what I could do is say Roseboro for row in Matrix and we'll be covering
list comprehensions and for loops and a lot more detail later on.
But I just want to show what's possible with Python and how you can make really clean looking Python
code.
So then I'm going to Prince first call save this run this python list.
And now I see I have one for 7.
So what is actually going on here.
Well I'm saying for row in matrix in row counts as each item elicits saying.
For this one this one and this one grab the very first element so rad with Bracq index location element
0.
So then it returns 1 4 and 7.
So this is a for loop basically flattened out into a list and it's inside brackets.
So ends up returning illest itself.
And this is known as list comprehension.
Now we're going to be covering this a lot more but this is definitely something you're going to see
all the time with Python.
It's a great tool.
And as you begin to get more advance of Python you yourself will be using it a lot.
All right.
That's all we need to know about Python lists for now.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture.