Welcome back everyone to the part of the social clone project.
We're going to finish up the accounts application.
That means our log in log out and sign up capabilities by setting up the log in and log out your calls
and or setting up py file creating two more templates for that and then we'll also set up the migration.
So we're going to continue with the accounts application right where we left off from the previous lecture.
OK.
Here I am Adam text editor.
Remember in the previous lecture we finished off creating are based studies team M-file.
What we need to do is set up the log in to redirect your URL and log out redirect you RL that the log
in and log out views are going to call and we're going to need to do that within our settings that PI
file.
So go to simple social settings not pi.
And then these usually go all the way at the bottom so scroll all the way down and we're going to set
up two variables.
So you're going to say log in underscore redirects underscore you are l.
So this is the log in redirect and we'll have this redirect to a test page and then we will have our
log out underscore read redirect underscore you Earl and I'm going to have that be equal to A thinks
page.
So we'll save that.
And now that we've said test and thinks let's actually create those templates so we didn't create those
templates inside of our top level templates in the same directory we're based on index trees.
Tim L-R so we'll a new file and I'm going to call this file test.
H.A. and I'll create one more file under templates.
New file and I will say thanks to HTL and let's set those up so the test.
I was going to test this.
Basically we're going to say extends from base but each T.M. we're going to say block the content block
and put this inside of a can actually going into a container.
We just need to say H-1 you are now logged in exclamation point and then we'll just actually just have
that be it.
So I'll save that that's essentially going to be a test page to see if logging in worked.
Once you log in it should take us this page you are now logged in.
And then in our thinks each team pile this is going to be the log out.
So we'll say extends based HCM HTL I will call the content block here and then we'll say H-1.
Thanks for visiting comeback soon.
That's kind of the typical log out thing you usually see in a web site.
So if you log out of Facebook usually see oh thank you for visiting.
Come back soon.
Cetera.
So that's our log in and log out so log in view from jingo point eleven essentially going to look for
those variables which are then going to connect to these HCM files.
So now that we created those HMO files what we need to do is actually set them up with the views that
pi and euros that PI over a simple social app.
So in the simple social project come over to views that pie right now we just have our home page view.
I'm going to add in the test page and the things page I will say class test page and I'm going to again
use template view here and then just set my template name equal to test page T.M. and I'll add one more
for the actual thinks page.
So will say thanks page.
And this is going to be a template view and this will say template name is equal to think study.
Female perfect.
Now I'm going to say that since we have these interviews we're going to connect these two or you're
all stopped by.
So let's do that come over to your All-Starr pie.
This is our project your PI file and we will say you are el and WIPs you are ill.
And then we're going to use regular expressions here.
We will say something like carrots.
Let's actually make sure we have that in our accounts as well.
That should always be there.
So our curate counts carried accounts and then curate this will be for the test page support slash.
And then I can put a dollar sign in there just to continue in case we want to build off test.
I will say views that test page dot as View so call as a view and then let's give it the name test.
And then we'll say you are all using regular expressions again carrots and then I'm going to say thanks
and let's connect that to use the the thinks page as a view and we'll get the name.
Thanks ok save that.
So now are your patterns are done.
Let's move on to the next step which is to migrate all the changes we did to accounts.
So I will say Python managed PI make migrations accounts and turn let that run great.
We created the model user Nangle and say Python managed up-I migrate enter and we should see it should
have apply those migrations.
Let's check and see if this actually works.
We may have to do some debugging.
We will say Python is up high and then run our server.
Enter.
OK so we got no bugs there.
So we may have to do a little debugging but right now looking good.
I'm going to hop over to the browser in here and the browser let's refresh and see what we get.
OK.
So it says template syntax error.
Invalid block line 17 static that you forget to register or load the tag.
I probably did.
So let's make sure it's actually registered and we can see or hear that's happening at base that T.M.
error at line 17.
So let's fix that.
So I will go back to my base that each team l file.
So let me come back here and here in my base study C.M. file.
I can see him using static but in order to actually use that static call you need to load static files
scroll all the way back up here and right underneath this dock type.
I'm going to call load as a template tag and then say static files save that and balustrades again.
Welcome back to the browser.
Let's refresh and it says Welcome to our social.
OK looking pretty good right now we can see we have the basic navigation bar.
We have our social groups log in and sign up.
So right now groups shouldn't really do anything but log in and sign up should Let's practice signing
up will click sign up and you can see here it actually looks really nicely formatted.
Here you can see there's extra stuff about the password and then required 150 characters or fewer.
That's what bootstrap 3 library is doing for us.
It's making this really nice display.
So let's sign up.
I'm going to say my display name is test user.
My email address is going to be test at gmail dot com password is going to be password and then we will
confirm our password with test password.
Let's click sign up.
OK so it's signed up and redirected us the log in page as we expected.
And it kind of auto filled for me because I'm using Chrome right now which is kind of memorizing the
username password.
So let's make sure this is working and the log in and it says please correct username so it's wrong
username it should be.
Test User and then make sure that password is also correct.
Test password.
Ok now I'm going to log in and then boom it says now you're a log then perfect.
And I can see here the actual navigation bars change.
Now I have post in create group.
I also have log out.
So let's test with log out make sure that's working.
And it says thinks or isn't it come back soon.
Fantastic.
Looks like everything is working for us so we're going to do it in the next lecture we'll continue on
by moving to posts and groups and we kind of have to work with those simultaneously.
So we're not going to work on a single application like we just did here.
But since they're so connected it should be relatively straightforward as far as working with them in
sync.
OK I'm going to end it here and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.