Hello everyone and welcome to part five of the blog clone project.
So we finished the blog post views and you or else that is the class based views that work of the actual
blog post.
But we still need to actually create the templates for the blog post class based views.
That is the actual h team l files that link up to those views and after that we can create the function
trees that are going to handle the comments.
So let's get started.
Hop over to the editor right here I am at the.
Editor and what we're going to do is first create all the templates that will match up with the views
that we created here in our classes and we'll create one extra template for the actual comments we already
have are about page template that was actually quite easy.
Remember those the very first thing we did and it's just linking to the actual base studies timeo which
doesn't have much of anything right now.
Let's create a couple of more templates going to right click on blog and create a new file and we're
going to have this one be the post underscore detail.
H T.M. and I do recommend that you follow along and named these html files.
Exactly the same name that I'm doing here.
Otherwise when you actually run the server you may see some errors that we saw and discussed where we
talked about class based views that there's actually different names that jingle looks for.
So there's a detail.
Let's also create our post underscore form that each T.M. page and create another one and this one is
going to be or post underscore list.
That is Tim L..
It's going to be our home page with all the lists of all the posts and create a draft list so same post
underscore draft underscore list that each team will and then finally I want the delete for the post.
So say new file and this one goes.
Post underscore confirm underscore deletes.
So usually when you click on the buttons you need some sort of confirmation page.
So there it is.
And what we're also going to add in here is a comment form that age HTML.
So we haven't done any comment views but we will in just a second.
Let's create a new file and say this is the comments underscore form that H T.M..
OK so we have the about the base the comment form post confirmed delete post detail post-draft list
post form and post list and then under registration.
I'm going to do is create a new file called log in H T.M..
And note that this is going underneath the registration subdirectory under templates and will discuss
registration authorization all that later on we're going to do it a little differently because basically
we're kind of piggy backing off the super users who can create at the command line since those super
users are going to be people that are actually able to log in.
OK I'm going to close all these HTL files and templates that I just made later on we're going to be
working off those a lot more.
But here you are Elle's.
This is the sites your URLs will come back to that later.
That's my about that a HTML page and here are my views.
So since we're going to do what we did in the previous lecture.
A bunch of views and then only a bunch of your ELSE to them.
But in this case we'll do it for the comments to you already that everything that's due at the blog
post.
Let's continue on with the comments so scroll all the way down.
And if you want to match up kind of the notes.
I did some sort of comment or some hash tags here so there's a bunch of hash tags just so we can kind
of get an idea of what's going on and separate everything else out.
OK so first thing you need to do is have some sort of publication for the comment itself so we'll call
this the IF and let's have this be something like add a comment to post add underscore comments underscore
to underscore post.
So this will allow us to add a comment to a post and I'm going to have this big request and take in
a primary key.
And what we do is actually import a couple of more things in order to make this all work.
So what I want to do is get the object or four or four and then redirect and render.
So coming all the way back up I will collapse a tree right now so we get a little more room is up here
where it says Jingo that shortcuts not only will import render but it will also import object or 4 0
4 and we'll talk about that later on.
And then I also want the read direct and then I also want to make sure I have logging required since
we'll be using that later on and then something else I probably want is time zone so will say from jingo
da tills in poor time zone and that it looks kind of crazy if all these from import statements the very
top so feel free to separate these comments or kind of chunks.
However makes most sense to you.
But let's continue on.
Scroll all the way back down here and come back to add comment to post.
So we're going to do is have the post object instead of this function equal to get object or four or
four and it will take in a post model logic and have Piquet's will to the primary key provided with
the request call and I want this to require being logged in.
We don't have to have it require a log in just have anyone make a comment but we want to have the log
in required just kind of get some practice with that decorator.
So say if the request pop method is equal to equals equals to post then hopefully it's kind of jogging
your memory.
Will say form is equal to comment form and then we'll take request post and we'll see if that form is
valid.
Well we're going to end up doing is grabbing the comment saying form that save and I don't want to commit
this quite yet so I'll say it is equal to false.
What I want to do is connect that particular comment post to the post object and then I want to save
it.
And then once that's all done we're going to just return a read direct.
So say redirect to the post detail page with primary key being equal to that post primary key and else.
So let's say the request method it wasn't a post.
Meaning someone hasn't actually filled out the comment form will say form physical to comment form and
after all that will return loops.
We need to render the actual pace we'll a request and I'm going to have a blog slash comments underscore
form the H to him l and if I expand my the rectory I can confirm here it was called comment form that
each team L.
So that's what I'm putting in here.
And then we're going to say Pessin a context dictionary for the form is for him.
Hopefully this is more or less a little familiar to you given what we covered back we're talking about
forms.
OK so in case you're feeling a little fuzzy on this let's quickly go over the thing.
We have this dick reader which is a convenience decorator to make this interview require being logged
then.
So in order to add a comment to a post we take in a request and the primary key that links the actual
comment to the post.
So if you're in a post the tail page and click OK I want to comment on this.
There's a primary key that goes along with that post.
And they were going to say all right either get that object the post object or the four or four page
meaning you can find it in passen the post model and then Piquet's to Piquet.
So if the request the method is to post meaning someone's actually filled in the form and enter something
the form is equal to the comment form passing that request if the form is valid.
Meaning they didn't miss anything up.
We have the save of the form.
However we said it false that we would have at least some sort of form in memory and we say comment
that post is equal to the post object.
And basically what this does is if we take a look back at our models remember that the actual comment
has an attribute called Post which is connected by a foreign key which is the actual post over here
and that's basically what's happening here we're saying OK that comment that post make it equal to the
post itself and then save it once you're all done with that redirect to the post e-tail page with the
primary key being equal to the post-up peaky which again is just the peak or primary key for that actual
blog post otherwise.
So if this whole thing has to happen else where the form is a sequel to the comment form and we'll just
return the comment form that it's T.M. passing in the form for the context dictionary.
So I want to actually come to this comment underscore form that HVM out page over here.
This is where I'm going to inject that form contact's dictionary.
All right.
So that's it.
Hopefully it feels pretty OK to you.
But we still need to add that to our Urals that pi file.
So let's do that now.
Overhearing your calls that pi is going to have everything kind of has a bunch of long lines but that's
OK for us.
We'll say your L and I just created the add comment to post so we're going to do here is a regular expression
I'm going to say the following carot post slash and then copy and paste this primary key regular expression
and then when I'm going to do is say slash comments slash dollar sign for you.
There it is.
And then we'll say fuse dot add comments.
Post and let's give it a name that just says give the same name at comment to post as a function.
There it is.
And then what I'm also going to do is add a comma there the very variant.
So saving that let's come back to views that pi and we have one of them but not too many more.
We just need to add any approval of the comment a removal of the common view and then we'll also use
function based to be used to the actual publication.
So let's finish off the comments and it's up to you whether you want to do a below or above this but
we're going to do it below CTF and we're going to make one about comment approval.
So you should have to be log in to approve a comment.
So we'll just put that in now.
Decorator log in.
So we'll say log in required and we'll see comments.
Approve and again it takes or question a P K primary key and then we'll say comments is equal to get
object or four or four.
And we're actually going to be grabbing the comma in this case
and then we'll just say comment the proof.
So if you come back to the models I should probably just open this.
We're going to be referencing it.
So if we come back to the models we have this approved comment method and if you have the comment you
have this approved comment method here.
So what happens is if you call that method you just say it's an approved comment.
So you set this field equal to true when it's default was false.
So we just called the approved method on that actual model object and that's all you have to do for
the common approval.
Which makes sense we'll see a return redirect and send it back to the post detail page with the primary
key being the comment that post-up piqué.
So what's actually happening here.
Again come back to your model and it's all explained.
The comment is connected to a particular post.
And if I want to after approving that comment go to the post of that comment then I need the post.
OK.
So it's actually coming back up here and asking OK what's the primary key of the post that this comment
was linked to.
Well that's all there is there.
So we'll save that.
And let's add it to you or else again kind of a tedious process but it's not so bad considering that
you're really building a website if not that much code.
All right.
So we have to do here is we just created the comment approval I'll say curat comments slash and copy
this so that it links and they will say slash approve slash dollar sign we'll call views.
And I think it's called common approve.
Yeah.
And let's give it the same name name as equal to comments.
Approve the recall and note that I'm passing it in as a string.
So kind of taking advantage of Adam's autocomplete for functions and then just using it for a string
there.
So we have to use our comment to post the come Proview will come to use that page again.
And then what we're gonna do is create another function view and we'll have this one also be log in
required.
So I will say log in required and let me make a few more lines here just so you have more space to see
this.
Will say this is for removing a comment or say comments.
Remove this takes in request and the piquet it's going to feel really similar to what we just did and
we'll say the comments lips.
The comment is equal to the object to four or four of that particular comments where the Piquet's the
piquet and then we're gonna say is the post underscore Piquet is equal to comment.
Post-up OK so linking that up.
Basically what we did over here is setting a new variable and the reason for that is because I want
to say comment that delete so I'm deleting that comment from my database and then I want to return redirect
and go back to the post the tail
and then say Piquet's equal to post-peak K..
So you might be wondering well why didn't you just do the same thing you did here where he said common
thought post-up.
Well remember if I said delete by the time you get to return it's not going to remember what that post-up
Piquet was.
Which is why I need to save it as an extra variable before I delete this.
So this approval and this remove are almost the exact same thing except I have to actually save that
post primary key as a separate variable.
So about the time I delete it I still remember over here.
OK.
So pretty simple logic as far as or doing.
And as you get more experience these things will kind of come naturally to you.
So as we move onto this purely class based views or for comments using some sort of outside library
like discus But now we're kind of just grinding out the hard way to get review on everything we've ever
covered in this course at least most of what we covered in this course and then what we're going to
do here is wups set up that your link to it.
So we'll have this be comment as well and I'm going to copy and paste this.
It's almost going to be the exact same URL except instead of approving it we are going to remove it
slash dollar sign and then we'll say comma views the comments remove and then we'll say name is equal
to comments underscore remove.
OK so coming back to views we have three functional views are related to the comments.
I need one more function view in order to publish things.
And that is the published post.
So I'll make this also log in required and this will be our last view.
I know you're probably tired of writing these views by now so we'll see.
Post Polish request takes in a primary key and this one can look pretty similar to the ones you just
made except now it's related to the post.
So we say the post is equal to object or 4 or four of the post teacake with a K and then we're going
to say postop publish and after that I'm going to return a redirect to the post detail page.
So when you actually hit publish you go straight to the post detail page where the primary key is the
primary key of the post you just made and once we finished this functional view we need to just come
over to your Olsdorf pie and add it in.
So again we'll say your L and we'll do regular expressions here.
And we'll say this is post and we're kind of going to add this to whatever this is so essentially is.
Same thing here.
Except instead of remove let's copy this and just paste it and say results in typing.
But we're not removing something for a post.
We are going to be publishing that post so we'll say that publish or slash publish.
Excuse me views and this should be called Post underscore.
Publish in the name of this will just give it the same name post underscore publish save that and now
all your real patterns are ready to go.
So how about 10 year old patterns they believe 5 through 15 and we have our views ready to go.
So you did a lot of work here.
Eighty five lines of code if you count the white blank spaces or blank lines.
Not bad.
So we have a lot of use or euros ready to go and if we look at our templates we have all the blank templates
that are ready to be filled out.
Next thing you have to do is just fill out these templates to make sure everything works together.
Set up the actual bootstrap and see SS and Javascript for everything.
For those kind of special features and we should be pretty darn close to getting a full functional websites.
Now just the simple templates.
OK we'll set that up all in the next couple of ideas.
Thanks and I'll see you there.