Hello everyone and welcome to this final lecture we're going to be discussing credit.
Now you may have heard of this term credit before in web development but what does it actually mean
contrary to what you might think it means.
It really stands for create retrieve update and delete and this process of creating retrieving updating
and leading is inherent to almost every Web site.
Pretty much any web site with users has the ability for a user or an administrator to create content
retrieve prior content update that content or delete that content.
Now we pretty much already know how to retrieve things by using the connection between the Urals the
models and the views the PI file.
But we're going to be learning about here is more on creating updating and deleting information from
our web application.
Whenever you work of models and databases you'll need to perform those four basic actions and luckily
Django has class based views to simplify this entire process for you.
We'll start off by exploring how to use the Create view class.
Now a quick note while we are using this create view class in the programming section of this lecture
we will purposefully induce a few errors to clarify where certain variable names are coming from.
So I'm not making mistakes as I'm coding along.
I will actually be inducing those errors on purpose and I'll remind you of that as we continue programming
once we've worked through the create a view class working with the update view and delete the classes
will be very straightforward.
In other quick note there's going to be a lot of interaction between your Urals not pi.
The used up high end models not pi file as well as all your template files.
If you ever get stuck on an error I want you to triple check that your code has matching the notes exactly.
Or is matching what I've shown you here in the video lecture.
The nature of the interaction between all the files is going to make it almost impossible for me to
give you good help on this topic.
In the Q&amp;A forums.
So if you ever get stuck on anything and you're really stuck.
Make sure that you're actually following along with the video Exactly.
Or just go ahead and download the associated files for this lecture.
All right let's get started.
Hop over to the Adam text editor.
OK here I am at the Adam text editor and over on the right I also have a browser open to the page so
you've been working with throughout this entire section of the course.
I have the home page and we learned how to connect templates and also inject content into this home
page.
I can click on schools see a list of all the schools select first school and then come to the school
detail page and then I can always click on admin to go to the admin page as well.
Let's go back to schools and we'll see a list of schools here.
The first thing I want to do is show you how we could possibly create a new school using create you
in order to do that.
Let's hop over to our views that py file under basic app and I'm going to create a new class that as
you may have guessed is going to be called School create view.
So I will collapse this directory for a second.
And before we actually get started with this let's import the views we're going to be using.
Right now we're importing a view template view list view.
Now what I can do is put these in multiple lines is have some parentheses here.
And anything wrapped inside is print seis and then go on multiple lines.
So when importing view template view list view detail view we're already familiar those.
And then I'm also going to be importing create view update view and then delete view.
And basically what these views are going to do and help us out with is create you will help us create
new additions to our models update is going to take an existing entry in your model and a light update
it and then delete view will take something that exists there and delete it.
So let's start off with create a view which is going to allow us to essentially create a new school
easily.
I will scroll down over here and underneath school detail to you.
I will say something like class school create view and then we'll just pass and create view will inherit
from that.
And then what I'm going to do under the Create view is I will say model is equal to models dot school
and then I will save that and whenever we creative you want to make sure that it's linked to some sort
of your l.
So I'll bring back my directory tree and come over to the Urals PI file of my actual application and
I'm going to add another line there for you.
So let's actually edit this a little bit.
Right now I have this sort of regular expression and I going to simplify this instead of having this
in brackets here.
Let's just make the say digit plus.
And basically what this is doing is taking the primary key of the school as the display.
And what I want to do is create a new york Airlink here
and this will take in as a regular expression just create forward slash dollar sign.
So what this says is if someone goes to the domain page slash basic app slash create it's going to allow
us to create a new school and here we'll save views dot school create view dot as View member we have
to do that for class based views and we'll go ahead and give it a name and the name we're going to give
it is just create so we can reference it later.
And since they added a new item to this list I want to make sure that they're separated by commas.
OK.
So just to expand this a little bit so he can see this in a tiny bit more detail here.
I've just added your L create views at school create as View name as create.
We're going to save that and then what we're going to do is check it out over here and we will get some
errors but I'm going to walk you through them so we can get a better understanding of why we're getting
these errors.
So I will come back to schools refresh and then I'll click on first school.
It's the walk of the school detail page.
All right.
So far so good.
I'll come back up here to where it says basic app and I'm going to try to go to create enter and note
what happens here.
It says improperly configured at basic app create using model for mixin based classes school create
view without the fields attribute is prohibited.
So that's the error I want you to learn how to read.
In case you ever encounter it.
So basically what this is saying is hey you want to create a view but you didn't specify what fields
are prohibited and what fields are allowed.
Well that's easy enough to fix.
We'll come back to the used up high and over here under create just like we did back when we're working
with models.
We're going to find the fields that will allow a user to create.
So the school had three main fields the name the principal and location.
And this almost acts like a security measure.
Maybe you don't want someone to edit the location of a school or the name of the school etc. we'll just
pass in all the fields for now.
Principal and then location and I'm going to save this and as I refreshed this page I should see probably
another error.
And there it is so template does not exist.
Well that makes sense I never actually created a template for the school creation page.
But what's interesting here is it tells you that it's looking for basic app school form.
And basically what that means is that Django that create view is automatically creating a default HVM
l template that it's expecting and it's expecting it to be in the format of all lowercase.
The model name.
In our case at school underscore and then form so let's that in.
And I would always suggest that you use the defaults there.
So underneath templates basic app I will create a new file and I will call it what it was looking for
school underscore form that each TNL and it makes sense that we need some sort of form for the editor
or user to come in and create a new school and let's show you how we can create the school form page.
First things first though I want to say extends from the basic app slash and then the basic app base
which was basic app underscore based but each T.M..
OK so that's going to allow me to extend that template and then let's have in our body block tool called
block body underscore block.
And since I have a block I will say and block as well.
All right.
Now it's actually put some thing here and this is what the user is going to see when they actually try
to create a new school.
And I'm going to essentially think ahead and know that I am also going to add an update view later on.
So keep that in mind as I'm working here.
Usually you wouldn't just know this off the top of your head.
And then this header or heading one on point to use some logic.
Have an if statement and my template tagging and I will say if Knot's form the instance dot piqué and
we'll explain what that means in a little bit.
I will say create school
and then since I know I'm also going to add an update view later on meaning update a school that already
exists.
I will say else
update school and then since I haven't if I always need to and if so do these lines actually mean.
Well basically what I'm saying is the following I am going to extend from basic app have the body block
and the heading of this form page that create page is going to check if the instance of the primary
key exists or not.
If it does not exist that means this is a new school.
Now we're going to create the school.
Otherwise we're updating a school that currently exists.
And this will make more sense as we actually developed the update view.
Hopefully you get the basic idea that I'm checking first.
There's a primary that's here that school exists.
Well in that case if it doesn't exist I'm creating a school.
Else if it already does exist then I'm updating the school.
And then finally to actually update school we need to take in a form some information and we actually
just need to specify the method is post.
We don't need to have a class or action here.
You could have a class with this bootstraps stuff we've been learning about but we'll keep it simple
for now.
As always of any form we need to have our C S R F tokin C S or of Tokin and this should be underscore
tokin
and then we're going to inject our form as we've seen earlier as P and then finally we'll say input.
The type is going to be a submit button and let's give it a class.
So it looks a little nicer since we are working a bootstrap.
We'll say it's a BT and B 10 cash primary.
Always nice to flex those bootstrap muscles and let's give it a value of Samit we'll save that and hopefully
that worked out this error.
Remember that was the school for that age T.M. and it's really important that you have the ability to
read these sort of errors throughout the course we've been kind of avoiding errors to begin with but
now I really want you to get familiar and be able to read oh template does not exist.
Well that means I need to check out with templates expecting.
All right let's refresh this and perfec we see create a school.
Now let's try to actually create a school.
We'll give it the name of the school my brand new school the principal will be I don't know someone
named Larry and the location will say it's in.
I don't know Panama will say submit and boom we have another problem.
It says improperly configured at basic at underscore app create and it says has no your L to read direct
to either provided your l or.
And what we're going to be doing the define a get underscore absolute underscore your L method on the
model.
So let's follow those directions and actually do it.
OK so I'm going to come over to the models and I'm going to look for school and it told me that I should
define a get absolute Your L method for this model so as follows instructions.
I'll say if I get absolute's underscore you are l or pasand self.
And then we're going to do is basically reverse and tell it what primary key we want this school to
be created with.
So here it is actually import reverse from your resolvers which we have seen before.
Say from Jingo that Corda you are l resolvers.
Import loops reverse and that means I can use it down here where I will just return reverse and what
I am going to do here is called Basic underscore app the detail view not the detail viewers and the
importing but the actual detail and the views that py file.
And then we need to add some keyword arguments as a parameter and the keyword argument in past here
is Piquet for primary key and the value for that is just self-taught P.K..
So let's save that.
And again learning how to kind of read and roll the punches on some of these error codes so it does
get absolutely oral method.
We did that already.
Let's refresh this.
It may ask us to continue.
That's fine.
Says Walk to School detail page school details my brand new school.
Larry in Panama.
So what was actually going on here.
Basically what happened is after we created that view we never told Django where it should go to.
We never said oh go do something after you created the view which is why Gyngell was requesting for
a get absolute Your L.
And basically what we said is OK go back and reverse and figure out that you should go to the detail
page or whatever the primary key is of the school you just made.
In our case this is basic app for your number maybe different however and that's the very basics of
having a create view.
So if I go back to the list of schools I can see I have my brand new school in my brand new school.
So the reason it's inserted twice here is because we basically did it twice while we were kind of fixing
some of those errors.
But don't worry we'll fix that when we learn how to delete views.
But first let's learn how to work with up few.
And a lot of the work is actually have already been done for us since we did a lot of stuff we were
doing the Create view.
So school of the view should actually be quite simple as well.
Let's come over to views that pi and I will create a new class called school up view.
And I would recommend that you name your classes.
Basically the way I'm doing it with the model name and then create your view or detail view etc. and
then I'm going to inherit from up the view.
And this one's quite simple.
Again we're going to specify what fields we want to be updated.
Now this is where maybe you can think about OK who's going to be updating this.
What kind of user permissions will they have and also what makes sense for updating a school.
Does it make sense to up the school's principal.
Well yeah that makes sense.
Principals can change because it makes sense to update the school's name.
Maybe.
What about the location of school.
Well probably not schools usually don't move around that much so let's just say you can only update
the name and the principal of a school.
Obviously your own situations are going to be unique and you'll have to make that call.
And what we're going to do here is once we have this we'll just connected to the model will say models
equal to models thought and in our case it's the school model.
We'll save this and then we're going to do is come back to your Allsopp pie and actually set up a your
L for our updating inside this your PI file for application 1 I'm going to do is copy this detail view
paste that again and this is basically the same view I want except I want to clarify some sort of update
extension.
So basically if I go to basic underscore app slash up they slash and then the number of the primary
key of the school.
It will let me update that school so I need to change this from detail view to update view as View.
And then it will change the name to detail.
To update and then let me save that and the next thing we have to do is actually edit the HTML file
or the template file that relates the school detail page.
So let's hop over to that and right now this is our detail page and it just says for the information
of school to students etc. and what we will do.
Is outside of this fact let's put it outside this div but before the end block I'll create a new div
inside its own container.
It'll just be a paragraph with an anchor tag inside of it and this will be your template and this will
be a template that takes you to the basic underscore app was the name of the and will pass in an argument.
P.K. school underscore detail that Piquet and let's actually give this a class so it looks a little
nicer.
Will say this is class of her bootstrap we can say between will give it warning you give it success
whatever you want but maybe awarning makes sense to update something.
It's kind of a yellow hue by original nature and then we actually want to have some sort of texture
that tells you what you're going to update this.
All right let's save this and will refresh this page and see what happens.
So now if I scroll down a little bit I see this update button and we can always zoom out so it's a little
more clear.
So now on the detail page I can see the update button.
You may have to scroll down depending on how zoomed in you are.
If I click on it I get the form and the option to update the school and only the fields that I specify
the name and principal.
So let's try to change the name of the school.
Actually this is change the principal to something really obvious like Mr. obvious I should be really
obvious change will submit it and it takes back to that school's detail page.
That's what we were working with when we said here on the ref your L basic app update and then Piquet's
school detail.
OK.
That allows us to link whatever school we're actually updating with.
So what the school page I can see now for school has principal Mr Obvious.
And if I come back to schools click on for school I can see that that change has been permanently done
great.
So now you learn how to create views and how to update views.
The last thing they need to do is figure out how we can delete views.
So let's go back to our actual editor our bringing back my directory tree and what I'm going to do is
come over here to the views up high and we'll create our last and final view which is the school Dilley
view we'll have delete view here and this is going to be slightly different from everything we've done
so far.
As far as updating and creating views that it's actually not so bad.
First we have to do is say model is equal to models.
School connect the models that makes sense as far as what we're going to delete.
And then the next thing I have to add in is a success your L variable or attribute I should say because
this is a class so will create an attribute called success.
Underscore your L and what we're going to do is use the reverse underscore lazy function.
So I need to go up and import that and I'll explain what it is.
Right after I import it we'll say from jingo dot core dot.
You are all resolvers and it's actually from the same place we imported reverse from so we can import
reverse or reverse underscore lazy.
And if you're familiar of programming you may have heard of the term lazily evaluated and what we're
going to do is all the way down here and it's actually telling us we need to still finish that off where
it says success you IRL we will call reverse underscore lazy and passen that we want to go to the basic
app and the list view.
So what does success means is all right.
Once you successfully deleted a school I want you to go back to the list page of the basic app and show
all the schools and theoretically once you're done deleting that school should no longer be on that
list.
The reason we use reverse lazy is that we don't want this evaluated completely when running our PI file.
We only wanted to wait until it's actually called as a success.
And as with all the other views we've been working with we need to go ahead and add a Oreilles that
PI that actually matches with this particular view.
So we'll come back here to your Elle's that pie and let me collapses to see a little more room.
And again this is going to look really similar to update.
Instead of updating something though we're going to be deleting it so we'll hit enter and I'm going
to change this name from Update to delete.
I'll change this update to daily as well.
And then here it says update will change that to delete.
So I should be able to go to basic app slash delete and then any primary key and start getting some
options for deleting stuff.
But in order to do that I should have some sort of HTL file.
So will go ahead and go with the default H-2 him Al file that's expected.
We'll add it in right now.
We don't see those errors anymore.
Now all we do is we say school underscore confirm underscore delete that H Tim L and this is going to
be the page that's actually shown.
When someone tries to manually delete something from the database
we'll say extends and we're going to go from the basic slash basic app underscore based studies Tim
Ehle file that I have here
and the start our block
will have our body block.
Now if any block we need to and the block
and where we're going to have here is basically just says H-1 and we'll say delete and it will automatically
pass in a context object called school or whatever the lowercase version of your model is.
Remember we previously covered how to create your own context object names.
You come back here to views and scroll up a little bit.
We talked about it here context object name.
The basic one for detail that I encouraged each use default is the lowercase version of your model.
So we use that we expect school to be here and we're going to call off of it is the name and say questionmark.
So this is going to show is a heading that says hey delete that school's name Question Mark and then
we'll just have a simple form.
The simple form is just going to say method is post with any form we always need a C SRF token
and it's going to have an input.
The input would just be submit and now it can kind of play the classes of bootstrap.
And I've been waiting to use this a long time but we can finally use the danger button.
We don't actually give this a name but we should give it a value that way it says something we'll just
have it say delete and below this.
If you don't want to delete.
We should have some sort of link that goes back to cancel or at least some sort of text.
You can have this be a button in other form whatever you want are you going to have it be an anchor
tag with the word cancel inside of it.
And for the ref will have it take us back to that school's detail page.
So I have a template here that goes to basic app whatever the name of your application is detail that
your URL.
And then we'll say P.K. is equal to school dot primary key.
So again we're grabbing the primary key off that school context object that's returned just the same
way we grabbed that name because remember that detail your L if we go back to your Elle's that pie over
here under the term detail we're expecting some sort of primary key to be inserted which is why we then
having to pass it in as an argument in these HTL template files.
Ok so let's save this and we'll refresh our schools page and let's go ahead and try to delete school
number four because I have a duplicate there.
So up here in the your L I will say basic app deletes forward slash for enter and it says delete my
brand new school.
And I can see here we can click Cancel which is going to take us back to that detail page of that particular
school or I can hit delete so.
We'll hit delete.
And there you go.
That school has now been deleted.
Let's try one more time make sure it's actually working.
Try and that other brand new school and we actually need to enter this manually later on you can add
links if you want.
Obviously you should be very careful adding delete links all over the place the here and delete slash
3 delete my brain new school and we'll hit delete.
OK.
Perfect.
That's all working.
Later on we'll also learn how to use slugs instead of just primary keys where slugs are essentially
the name of objects lower lowercase with dashes in between any spaces.
And if you're familiar for development at all you've probably heard that term before.
OK.
I hope you enjoyed learning about updating creating and deleting views and I hope that this makes your
life a lot easier as you find yourself programming of larger projects and Django.
You're going to be using those views all the time.
And that's basically the whole point of Django to make your life a little easier as you try to focus
on what's really important developing your own web site.
Thanks and I'll see it the next lecture.