Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture we're going to be coding out the solutions for the game
project that tic tac toe project when the previous lecture Hopefully you had a chance to attempt it
on your own.
But if not feel free to code along with me.
Right now I'm going to hop over to my editor and browser to get started.
OK here I am at my editor and here's the browser and I have three files open and empty HVM file in MTC
SS file and an empty javascript files are ready to really tackle the front end and see its capabilities.
With this little project of ours.
Let's start off by creating the HTML file and filling out the actual content that will style it and
then will actually add the interactivity with javascript going to type HTL there just to set it up.
We have tic tac toe and let's actually link our CSSA file.
So I'm going to link right now to my CSSA file which I've just called.
Game C Ss.
And then I'm also going to link to bootstrap.
That way I can use the jumbo translator.
All you have to do to do that comes to get bootstrap But come in then I can just scroll down here and
grab the latest comp. The minute vide see SS.
Copy and paste that line into my file.
Now let's check the we're ready to go by just putting a heading in here saying connected.
Make sure that font looks good refresh or page.
And here we have connected in Bootstrap So we know we're good to go.
OK so far my links are OK and I also want to link to my script.
Let's just do that over here at the bottom so all the way at the bottom going to call script.
And we're going to make the source equal to my script which is called My script G-S will save that and
to verify that's connected I'm going to do a console log that says connected save.
That will refresh this page and then let's inspect B at the console.
Expand this just so we can see it and it's connected.
So we're good to go there.
Fantastic.
Now we need to create some HTL content to actually create the board.
Let's comment this out and then coming back to main.
Let's expand this.
First thing you wanted to do is since we're dealing with bootstrap create a DIV tag that contains the
class container so this will have the container class and then inside of this I'm going to create the
jumbo from
now we'll have a heading and say this jumbo tron says welcome to tic tac toe tic tac toe and we can
put a paragraph in here if we want says get ready to play.
Let's save this and refresh make sure it actually looks good.
OK.
Welcome to Gary to play.
And then finally let's add a button.
Remember we had that restart button so I will call a button tagged and then it will have the type button
the name button is fine but let's give it a class and the class for you are going to just reference
bootstrap for this.
So I would expect you to have this memorized I would expect you to reference the documentation but the
class I chose was between.
And then I also added the beats in primary to it and then I wanted to make the button large so I added
between LG.
So basically what's happening here is this class tells it it's a bootstrap button.
This tells it's a primary bootstrap button so that takes care of the coloring and this takes care of
the sizing be at large.
Let me save this.
And let's also add what we want the button say.
So let's have it say something like restart.
Now we could put this on multiple lines if we wanted to keep it all on line.
I'm pretty zoomed in right now but let's refresh and here we have restart.
I can click on it.
Nothing is happening but it's all working the way we want it to.
So for now let's continue on.
Something to think about at this stage is I will probably want to reference this button later on in
my javascript since the only button on the page.
Let's just give it an ID.
We could also call it by its tag but I like calling things by their ID.
So let's give it the ID B so I can call it later and we're going to do is add in the table that's going
to represent our board.
We're going to add in the table and then we'll have to style it to actually make it look like a board.
So let's continue on that we're going to put this inside of the container.
But outside of the Jumbotron.
So let's expand that.
So here we are now inside the container but outside the Jumbotron.
I'm going to call a table and I'm going to say my table has a line equal to center and an inside of
this.
I have three table rows so say TR an inside it be true.
There's going to be three cells so tiddy and we'll leave them blank for now.
See the leave that one blank and then he leave that one blank.
And now let's do this two more times.
You can just copy and paste
and if we save this we should have our table right here.
You'll notice there's actually nothing showing up and that's because we have no styling attached to
this table so let's come over to the CSSA script and actually get some styling.
So we make sure that we're actually seeing this table I'm going to give styling to the actual table
cells the T.D. And let's give it a height of 150 pixels and these values are pretty arbitrary.
So you could have put whatever you want it also give it a width of 150 pixels so they're squares are
going to text align center.
And the reason for that is when I put an X or an O inside of the actual cell I wanted to be center aligned
and then let's give it a border.
This will allow us to see it will say five pixel solid black border and then let's give it a font size
of 100 pixels.
And again this font size refers to what I'm actually going to be putting X's and O's.
So let's save this will refresh over here and now I see my tic tac toe board.
Great and let's practice manually putting in an X over here.
So let's put an X into the very first table cell.
Save this refresh and there's my X and it's text the line centered which is exactly what we wanted.
Great hopefully you're able to get this far with very few difficulties.
I know it may look kind of daunting when you see just what the browser but on the page Tim LNC is a
site.
It's definitely everything that we've done before and it's pretty straightforward.
Now it might not be so straightforward especially since we're just learning it is the actual javascript
code to manipulate the document object model to play the game.
So let's get started on that.
I'm going to have a few sections.
I'll have the restart game button.
Then I'll have some sort of a section that grabs all the squares that I also want some sort of function
that can clear all the squares
and then I want to create a function that will check the square marker.
So something like check the square markers or check if it's an X or no.
And then finally I want some sort of for loop to add event listeners to all the squares.
OK so those are the main task we have to do and our javascript code and I'm going to approach this in
the next lecture.
That way you can spend some time to review the TMLC assess in the next lecture will actually cut out
all the stuff script.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.