Hello everyone and welcome to part five attributes in this lecture we talking about.
Tim attributes would allow us to actually add more information to NHT melted.
And this includes things such as adding a link to another web page or referencing an image.
Let's get started all of this by jumping to the Adam text editor in our browser.
OK here I am back at the Adam text editor and I'm still using the basic study T.M. file.
You can you sort of reached him if you want.
You can also use the part 5 h HTML attributes file that comes with the actual course notes.
Is going to be editing basic studies Timo.
Now we're going to need a few things.
One thing we'll need is an actual image file.
When we talk about setting an image inside of our page HTML file and to do that we should do is either
find on your computer or download or just use the PMG provided for you in the notes a drop DNG file
and make sure you save it in the same directory at the.
Himself all you're working with isn't.
So you can see here I have this basic study to metafile that I'm playing around with in the exact same
directory.
I have this PMG picture here this image file.
So let me now close that and show you how we can actually insert an image into our h tim L and the way
we do that is if an image tag.
And that's going to be I m g.
So I'm just going to click enter here and you'll notice you get an automatic pop up that says S R C
and A L T and that stands for source and ultimate.
And we're going to explain those in just a little bit.
First thing is to notice that this is actually a self-closing tag meaning everything here goes into
this one image tag.
You don't see as we've seen before in the past.
This closing tag it just comes in one self-contained tags that's called a self-closing tag and we can
actually use this to source an image.
So the thing I'll type here and SIRC for the source of the image is just Django the P and G and then
I'm going to do control s save and then refresh this page and you'll notice I actually get this image
right here.
And later on we'll learn about resizing images or squeezing them or stretching them however we want.
Right now we're just using the default image size so you can see here I said image tag.
Check out the source jingle that PAGG and then an alternate.
We're about to discuss.
Something to note here is that if this file is not in the exact same directory as this H-2 hymnal file
you may need to put in the entire file path but we'll discuss that much later on we're talking about
Django when we actually want to link to a specific folder that has all our images and all our documents
in it.
Right now I'll keep things simple by keeping the actual image file in the same directory as they watched
him file.
Let's discuss this a LTE or alternate.
Basically what this is for is an alternate thing to display in case you can't find the PMG file.
So for example let's say I type in missing that P and G.
Now if you look at my directory here I only have Gengel that PNB I don't have some picture called missing
that pinchy.
Which means I'll actually have a broken link so if I refresh this we see that classic broken link picture
that basically says hey I couldn't find this missing PAGG which means it's always a good idea to have
something alternate here so we can say something like oh image not found.
And we passed that in in quotes as a string that will pop up.
Now if I save that and refreshed my page will say something like oh image not found next to this little
broken icon here.
So that helps us out because later on we're doing more advanced web sites.
I can say something like a little more specific missing.
TNG not found.
So when I'm debugging my web site or checking stuff I immediately know oh missing that PAGG is not found.
But you'll notice if I switch this back to Jingo that PNB which is there and I refresh my website I
don't get that alternate image or alternate text anymore.
It does show up the Django that PMG image and that's really all there is to sourcing an image so you
have the source SIRC and the alternate let me comment that out and refresh this page save this then
refresh my page.
All right.
So we just discussed how to use image tags.
The next thing I want to talk about is an atack which allows us to actually reference in other ASTM
whole file or another Web site to really show this however I will create another aged him file.
So I'm going to bring back my directory and then right click on whatever folder I'm working on this
project folder or I'll add a new file and this new file and going to call it new page h tim L or hit
enter and then this new page that to T.M. I'll start typing T.M. enter so I get all that extra stuff.
And then here the body is going to write a letter or heading one that says this is the new page save
that.
So I have to assume all files basics that studied smell that we've been working with and this new page.
H Tim L has just a single heading in it and if I copy this full page and put it in my browser then I
get this is the new page.
Great.
So what I want to do is try to link this new page or each symbol into my original Basic Set a simple
page.
So let's do that.
I'll come back to basics very simple and to do this I'm going to use in a tag which is just an anchor
Ted and this is going to allow me to pass in a reference there in a ref and I will pass in the reference
to the actual new page or a symbol file that will say new page dot h tim L..
And notice I don't have to pass right now the full directory path where the full file path to this h
tim l file because it's in the same directory as my basic start.
Tim L. If it was a different situation where this was in in other full there somewhere else on my computer
I would have to specify more detail the full file path.
But we'll discuss full file paths and how you should actually create those across different operating
systems.
When we talk about Django right now we'll keep things simple and make sure everything's in the same
directory.
Let me save this so I have my breath in my anchor tag.
But notice this isn't self-closing.
It has its own closing tab which means I can put stuff in between here and this is basically going to
be the text that is a clickable link and that's all an anchor tag so i can say click me.
I will save this refresh.
And now I have this attributes and this click me and I can click on click me and that takes me to the
new page.
So again with this anchor tag we keep a reference here have the text that we want to show when we say
click me and then click on that.
And this is the new page.
That's really all N.A. tag is something to know.
You can reference things that are not just local on your computer.
And that goes for images as well.
So let me show you what I mean by that we can pass in an actual Web site so I'll say something like
HTP that will be there though.
Facebook dot com and make sure you have to put in the full file path of HTP.
Otherwise this won't work.
And now let's change this from click me to something like Facebook.
We'll save that refresh over here.
And now I see Facebook I click on Facebook and that actually takes me to the Facebook Web site and my
browser will actually self-correct this to make sure it's secure so it goes to HTP S..
Cole and for Sless for Slash W.W. that Facebook dot com.
All right.
So that's how you can actually reference web sites that are outside of your project folder.
You can just pasand the full HCC or HTP s file path instead of a local file and you can actually do
the exact same thing for an image tag.
So for example if we see an image here so I see this image of let's say these little triangles going
to open this image in a new tab.
Here we have the entire image path.
So I'm going to actually just copy this image path and then instead of Jingo that PMG I'm going to paste
in that whole image path.
Let's save that and go back to our original web site refresh and we see here.
Now we have that image so I'm allowed to basically pass in an outside image and you can use something
like google image search to actually grab a link to an image and then use that as your source instead
of having to save stuff locally.
Now will be times when you definitely want to save stuff locally in case a link ever breaks online.
That way you make sure you always have a backup or you could just use the source online and then have
maybe an alternate link or an alternate text show up.
All right.
So that's basically it.
As far as attributes than covering images and anchor tags we've learned a ton of material to this point.
So it's really time that we take a step back make sure we've truly understood everything and tackle
an assessment exercise Thanks everyone.
And I'll see you at the next lecture re-explained the assessment.