Hello everyone and welcome to part four of javascript level 1 operators.
It's time to learn about comparison and logical operators with javascript and these operators are going
to allow us to begin to add logic to our Javascript code.
And as a quick note there are also five optional quick exercises at the end of this lecture and you
can find them under the part for underscore operators thought JS file that's under the javascript level
one folder.
OK let's hop to our consul and get started.
OK so here you have the editor open as well as my browser and I have the consul open in my browser.
Remember you can always just right click inspect and then go over to the consul in on the left hand
side and the actual course notes open.
So we're going to be doing as quickly reviewing booleans remember they're all lowercase.
It's just true and false.
And what we want to do is start off of comparison operators and comparison operators allow us to compare
two items and return a boolean.
And I want you to pay special attention to what happens when we actually reach equality and we test
if something's equal or not.
So I'll start off the simple ones which are things such as greater then.
So if I check is three greater than two.
Well that's true is to greater than three.
That's false.
So that's greater then there is also less then so one less than two.
There's greater than or equal to.
So is two greater than 2.
Well that's false but is too greater than or equal to two.
That's true.
So there's greater than or equal to.
And there's also less than or equal to.
So we can see here let me clear my consulate's come back up here.
And now what I want to do is take a little bit of time to discuss equality and its special quirk.
So let's say I ask is two equals equals two.
All that returns true.
And typically in a lot of languages this would be how you test for equality and this would also work
for things such as strings.
So if I have something like use or as a string and check equals equals user then it returns true.
But here's where it gets a little strange.
Let's say I have a string called two.
And I say equals equals two and I want to see if this is true enough.
If I hit enter on this javascript unlike a lot of other programming languages is actually going to report
that this is true.
And usually you do not want this to be true.
You do not want a string to be equal to the actual number two.
So how do we actually take care of the situation.
What will you end up doing is just adding another equal sign there.
So you report back.
Equals equals equals 2.
And this will be now false.
So if you want to check equality of not just the actual number here what its saying but of actual type
you want to use triple equal sign OK so let's take a little bit of time to discuss the real differences
between the triple equal sign which returns false and the equal sign which returns true in this situation.
And what's happening when you only use two equal signs is javascript is using what's known as type coercion
which basically means it's trying its best to convert both of the objects to similar data types who
actually perform the comparison.
And a lot of times you don't actually want that you want to compare two objects based not just on what
they represent to a user but what they actually represent in the data type space.
So one is a strange one is a number they shouldn't be the same as the way you do that is you add in
that extra equal scient have three equal signs there and you actually do the same thing with inequality.
So if you want to check inequality not just the value but also data type.
You do this.
So I want to check is five not equals.
So 5 the string that ends up being true.
So I add that equal sign there.
If I only used one equal sign here then I would have gotten a false.
So remember for most use cases we want to add in that extra equal sign.
So we want three equal signs to test for equality and then an exclamation mark two equal signs to test
for inequality.
So here this is saying that the digit 5 is truly not equal to the string fine if I only use one of these
in this case.
So I don't have that extra equal sign.
I'll say something like that digit is actually not not equal to 5 and it's a little weird because there's
a double negative here.
Falsely an equal.
So just to clarify.
You'll always want to use the triple equal signs and then exclamation mark to equal signs for inequality.
OK.
So we always want to check for equality inequality not just the value but also of type.
So let's talk about a few more situations.
It's really common in programming languages for 0 and 1 to be substitutes for true and false.
And let me show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to clear this and we can actually scroll down the notes and see what I'm talking about here.
If I say true is equal equal to one I actually get true back and if I check as true equals equals equals
to one I get a false back.
So this is just a quick note that a lot of times we can see one as far as the type coercion and how
javascript's trying to get types to compared to each other.
I could have also used one to kind of act as true and the same goes for zero and false so false equals
equals zero that returns true.
But if I'm checking not just for value but also for data type then I get false here.
OK.
So that's a little bit of a quirky behavior if you haven't seen this before in other programming languages.
And there's also a little bit of a weird behavior for null undefined and and a n values.
So if I check there's no equals equals undefined I end up getting true which is a little bit strange.
And if I use triple equal signs I get false.
So that's just something to keep in mind.
And if I say is any then equals equals to any n actually a false there.
Which is kind of weird behavior and we'll be talking a lot more about that later on.
But I do want you to be aware of there's some funky behavior when you're checking for equality and you're
just doing comparison operators with these null undefined and any values.
So keep that in mind.
We'll touch on this later on.
But this is just something for you to be aware of.
To begin with all of our problems won't even deal if null are on the find values so don't worry about
it too much right now.
Let's clear that out and let's begin talking about logical operators logical operators.
Just allow us to combine multiple comparison operators.
So let's say we wanted to know if one is equal to 1 and we also wanted to know if two is equal to two.
Well how can I combine both for those typically you would use an AND operator and in the case of Javascript
the and operator uses to ampersands which is a symbol right here.
So here I can check is 1 equal to 1 and is 2 equal to 2.
In that case they're both true.
So in order for this to return true both of these statements have to be true and actually actually tack
on more than that.
So I could say is one triple equals to one and is two equal to two end is one equal to two and this
returns false because while these first two were true this last one was false and because they're all
ans they all have to be true then we clear the screen here.
We can also use or operators and or operators are written with what's known as the pipe operator and
they only need one condition to be true to return true.
So for instance is one equal to two
or looks like that pipe operator usually find it above the enter or shift key on your keyboard and you
just do shift backslash.
So you actually get that pipe operator.
What we see is one equal to two or is one equal to 1.
And that's true because only one of these conditions had to be true.
And then we also have the not operator so not operator.
That's not as common to use no pun intended there.
But let's also check it out.
It's basically a way of checking the opposite of a condition.
So for instance put this in parentheses following a check is 1 equal to 1.
Well that's true.
What if I want to check if the opposite is true.
Well then I can add an exclamation point in front of this to check.
So this exclamation mark will return the opposite of whatever is in here and the opposite of true is
false.
When I hit enter I should be false there.
So again it's basically a way of checking the opposite of a condition.
And you can also stack these.
So you can do.
Exclamation mark exclamation mark.
One equals equals one.
But this is definitely not that common to use and hopefully you never see just a bunch of exclamation
marks like this because really this kind of makes no sense and this is just bad code but it is functional
code.
OK.
So that's really all there is to discuss about comparison operators and logical operators for the most
part.
They're pretty straightforward.
The only things I really want you to pay attention to is the use of this triple equal sign versus just
the double equal sign.
And I want you throughout the course to be extra vigilant about that especially when you're working
of Javascript.
And I also want you to be aware of this kind of weird behavior with no undefined and any and we don't
run into this that often throughout this course but I do want you to be aware of it.
And then scrolling back down all the way to the bottom of the notes we have some exercise here.
So let me just expand this and show you.
So here are a few.
There's five quick exercise questions for you on what I want you to do is knowing that x is equal to
1 in y is equal to 2.
Mentally evaluate these expressions right here.
So there's five expressions for you to mentally evaluate them.
Once you think you know the answer in your head just copy and paste this line to the consul to actually
see if you're correct.
So let's do the first one together and then all it should do the other four on your own.
So if x is equal to 1 and Y is equal to 2 we'll see what we have here on this left hand side I see is
the string two equals equals to the number two.
What we learned previously that doubles equal sign instead of triple equal sign will only check for
the value not the actual data type.
So I know this side is true.
And then I say end is X triple equals to 1 so that's checking both for value and data type.
Well I know that the number one is equal to the number one.
So I believe that exercise one should return true since both sides of this and statement are true.
Let's check it out.
I'm going to copy this and paste it into my Consul so I have those two variables.
And let's copy and paste this line.
Put it into my console.
It looks like I was correct.
We got.
True.
OK.
So it's basically all I want you to do.
Mentally violate the other four here and you can check your own solutions against the console commands.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
Do you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums.
I'll see you at the next lecture.