Well everyone welcome back to part for a re exercise.
It's now time to practice using arrays in a more realistic situation.
And we're going creating a very simple student roster at using the javascript code that we know so far.
Go ahead and check out for Array exercise se him I'll file open it up in your browser and read the instructions
there.
I'm going to hop over to my browser with that file open to explain the actual exercise.
OK so I have here the h him l file for open in my browser and like I mentioned for this exercise we're
making a very simple web app that contains an array of student names in a javascript file using an array
and the Web site is going to prompt you for four possible commands Add Remove display and quit.
So those are things that you're actually going to type in and this web page will prompt the user for
one of those commands.
And then here's what these commands should do so.
And it will then create a prompt for a student name request.
Then we add this name to the student to the array of the student names in the script file.
Remove will create a prompt for a student named requests.
Then remove this name from the roster array display will print out the roster using console log in quit
will end the while loop of prompts.
So let me actually show you what this would look like.
I'm going to refresh this page and run through what this may actually look like.
First off it asked me Would you like to start the roster webapp Y or N..
Yes or no.
I'll enter y.
OK.
And then it says Please select the action Add Remove display or quit point to add and what name would
we like to add.
And we're going to be worried about single word name so first names only.
I would like that Jose.
And then it says Please select an action add remove this player quit so I will say this play and if
I hit OK I can see here in the Consul that I successfully added Jose incident roster.
Now annoyed to add another name.
Let's add Sam and Naledge display the roster again.
I see now I have Jose and Sam in the array the consul.
Now let's add one more name and I will add Franki books that he selects and action ad now it like that
Frankie analogise display.
I have Jose samen Frankie.
Let's see what remove does.
So it says Please select the action I type remove and then it says what name would you like to remove
or remove my name Jose let's display aere.
And here we see Sam and Frankie so I successfully removed Jose and then to end all this.
I'll just quit and it says thank you for using the web app.
Please refresh page start over.
OK that's it.
All right.
So there is a javascript file that actually has a bunch of hints and comments.
It's basically a walkthrough guide to help you out with this project going to take a look at it now.
So the file you want to use and link to your east him file is called part for underscore array.
Underscore exorcized javascript.
This is a javascript file that just has a bunch of comments in it.
Comments and hints.
It's optional to use if you want you can go straight into the exercise without referencing this javascript
file at all.
But I would recommend that you check out the javascript file for the hints and the structure it provides.
So again this is available to you.
It basically tells you what to do.
So for instance we've already created the roster for you.
The variable roster and we want you to create functions for the tasks so add in use today.
Create a function called add new that takes in a name uses that push to add a new students to the array.
Then the remove student and we actually have hints here on stack overflow.
We haven't shown you how to write a function called remove that takes in a name and then finds its index
location that removes them from the roster.
So there is a link here a stack overflow that will tell you how to remove a particular element from
an array.
Now we have the splay roster.
Just create a function called display that prints up the roster con..
That's pretty easy it's cons. that log basically and then start by asking if they want to use the web
app yes or no.
And now at the very bottom this is where all your logic is going to go.
Create a while loop.
It keeps asking for an action.
Add Remove this player quit and then use if and else if statements to execute correct functions that
we created above for each of those commands are right.
You have any questions on this.
Feel free to post the Kewney forums.
You can always check out the javascript solutions if you get stuck on something or just hop straight
to the next lecture.
Run be coding through the solutions to this exercise.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture.