Hello everyone and welcome to part five of the social club project.
Now we're going to begin by setting up the views your and template files for the groups and post applications.
And given that they're interconnected we're going to have to work with them concurrently so we can't
just do posts first and then groups first.
Otherwise it won't make too much sense so I have to do both at the same time.
We'll try to keep a focus primarily on one application at a time.
But keep in mind we're going to be working on both at the same time.
We're going to start off by just setting up the files we need and then the next lecture will actually
start programming.
OK let's suppose that a text editor and create the directories and files all right to begin actually
creating the directories.
I first need actually make the applications so we will go to jingo admin and say Star app and it will
create the post application.
So say start out for posts and then I will say jingo dash admen star app and I will start the groups
app so we'll will say group say you could call groups whatever you want.
You could call it something like subeditors or communities etc. I'll just choose the groups they insist
that's pretty simple.
Now we're all going to do it inside each of these.
Let me kind of collapse accounts and collapse simple social and expand and expand groups.
We are going to create the files necessary.
So let's start off with posts so in posts we're going to make templates.
So instead of post I will say new folder and then say templates hit enter and then inside of templates
I'm going to create a new folder called posts and then here are my posts templates and I'm actually
going to create the empty H-how files for now.
So let's start off with that.
We will say whoops that new folder in your file.
So inside of this I'm going to create a couple of new files one will be my base h team l file for my
post which I'll call post underscore base that each T.M. and then I also create a post underscore confirm
underscore deletes but each T.M. they'll be the view that you will confirm and then we're also going
to do.
Let me expand this just a little bit.
We're also going to do a post detail so you can kind of tell.
I'm already kind of thinking of class based views right now.
You will see a post underscore detail thought HTL and then a couple more here.
We'll create a post form so when someone actually wants to type out the post to go to that post form
and then if we want to actually list the full list view I will create a post underscore list that each
T.M. And then finally we'll create a new file and this will be called user underscore.
Post underscore list.
And if you click on a user we should see all their posts.
Kind of like seeing someone's Twitter feed so we'll have user underscore posting or score list.
Now we're also going to create one more file in a format that we haven't really seen before and that's
the underscore post-START T.M. And the reason for that is I'm actually going to use this underscore
postdates html file to inject it into other posts that HTL files.
Sometimes if you're single it's team elth page or your simple template is actually getting too big and
overly complicated.
Sometimes you can just break it up and inject it.
And I'll show you how to do that later on.
But right now we'll just keep that thought in our heads and will keep underscore postdates T.M. as are
actual templates we have those template files and the next we're going to do is actually create a few
more files inside of posts.
So instead of post right now I have models and views but I'm also going to add a or else top pie any
forms that pie will say.
Post your apply and then impose new file forms that apply.
OK so that's what we're going to do with post for now.
So we created those templates and you can always just copy and paste the templates or check out the
notes for the directories of what those templates actually look like.
In case you had difficulty following along.
But now we're going to do kind of the same thing for groups.
So in-groups we're going to do now is create that templates that victory I'll say new folder templates
and then under templates I'm going to say new folder groups and then under groups I'm going to create
a couple of each team.
All files will say new file group underscore based studies T.M..
So that would be my base h HTML file for the groups and I will extend from that I'll create a new file
called Group underscore detail each T.M. then I'll create any file group form.
So when someone wants to create a new group to come to this forum page again class based views here.
And then finally we should see a list of all the groups so he will say group underscore listed HTL and
hit enter.
OK so those are my four template files for groups and then I also want to create a profile here so we
will say underneath groups new file you URLs that pie.
OK.
And then save all those changes.
Close these now.
And we should have our basic structure or skeleton for dealing with posts and groups and we're going
to do in the next lecture is start off by actually focusing on groups first since there's fewer team
l files or template files to work with.
And if the structure is going to be a little simpler and that will kind of dictate where we need the
posts to look like.
So we're going to try to focus on groups at first but eventually we're gonna have to work on them both
at the same time.
But to make it a little easier we're going to try to focus on groups.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.