Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture will be cutting through the solutions for the coffee
lover bootstrap project that I explained in the previous lecture.
Let's show her editor and browser and get started.
OK so here you have my browser open just a quick reminder we're going to do is create this Jumbotron
add some content to the Jumbotron.
Have these two paragraphs here.
These large sums add the pictures the coffees the thumbnail class and then make sure that we have the
nav bar.
And then if I click on the sign and it takes me to the form we also want to make sure that we get the
grid system right.
Or actually adding these thumbnails of the coffee pictures and we have the links to these coffee pictures
right here on these links right here.
So one two three takes it to images of coffee.
OK let's get started.
All right so I have my editor here open with my browser behind it.
I've opened up a new project thirty's Tamil file so I'm going to just link to it now.
So I've copied its full path and I'm going to paste it here into my browser.
So right now it's blank.
Let's add in CMH T.M. code.
It's called the title of it Project.
And let's also add the link.
We're going to need for bootstrap itself.
So I'm just going to copy and paste that from the Web site already have it open on another window on
another screen so I save that and then let's add an just the heading here to make sure things working
well stay connected.
Refresh over here and I can see I'm connected.
Great.
So the first thing I want to take care of is probably the nav bar.
So we know that's going to be just here on top of the page all we have to do for that is add an NAV.
And remember we have a class here and it's going to be nav bar and I'm going to also add an nav bar
dot or dash Inv. which is going to allow us to have that darker color here refreshed that I can say
I have my nav bar Inv. doesn't have anything inside of it yet so let's add in those things.
In our case it's just one other item.
So we'll end up doing is putting an unordered list in there and we can give it the class nav bar dash
Nev..
And before that actually Nev. space for that.
And then the list item I want to here is an anchor tag with an H reference of my Sign-Up page and I've
called my Sign-Up page and I'm working right now.
New underscore Sign-Up thought HTL and this is going to say seinen.
Let's save that refresh.
Now I can see here I have seinen but notice here I also have this welcome.
So let's add that in as well.
And that's going to be a brand.
So let's put that in.
Which means it's going to be underneath the nav tag or create a div and this one takes nav bar dash
header.
And again I don't expect you to memorize these.
Just be able to reference the documentation for what you need and then we'll put an anchor tag here.
The class that's going to have
is the nav bar brand and the ATRA if we wanted to have just the hash tag and we'll say something like
welcome let's refresh make sure it got in there and there's our welcome sign in if I click sign in it
takes me to the new Sign-Up.
All right.
Looks like a nav bar is working as we want it to work.
We come back here at the bootstrap project.
It's a little bigger here than what we have here.
That that's actually because I'm zoomed in on this page.
Suffice zoom in on this page will get the same size.
So you can see here I have the little plus thing if I just actually reset the default.
I'll get the same size that I have on the screen.
OK so now bars taken care of if I click sign then it takes me to that and you sign up page.
Let's actually just copy and paste this code that we have so far and put it on the news sign up page.
In fact I'm going to copy this entire page.
Put it on my news sign up HTL page and then instead of taking it to sign in I'm going to change this
to landing page and then have it take me to the original HMO which is new underscore project.
We'll save that refresh over here.
And now I have this link to the landing page on my sign up page and the note kicks in takes it to the
landing page to see how it's changing it back and forth.
OK.
Great.
So let's come back to our main new project buddy Tim Page.
Check out the bootstrap project.
We still need to add and this Jumbotron.
So let's go ahead and do that.
First thing I want to do is put it all in a container so I have that deal with the container class and
then I'll end up doing is putting in the Jumbotron here.
So say Divx put in the jumbotron
and then we'll say H-1 coffee lover projects
and then let's just add in some paragraphs of lordship some here just so we have a little bit of content
on the page.
We'll save that refresh our project and we can see here we have coffee lover project Lorem some larm
some.
So we come back to a bootstrap project we've created a general landing page for Jumbotron.
We created an avatar on the page at least the other ASML we added two paragraphs and Lord of the Jumbotron.
And next we used a grid system to add in the thumbnail pictures of coffee and we have all those links
right here one two three four five six.
So coming back down I'm going to need to add in those pictures.
So how do actually do that.
Well since I want to take advantage of the grid system for the resizing of that I want to make sure
that it's in a container and then in a row.
So create a new div have it be container.
I could have also just put it in here in this container but sometimes it's nice to separate out your
code this way.
Put heading 2 and have it say pictures of coffee and then all manually code out the first actual row
and then we'll just copy and paste for the rest of them.
So the next thing I want is the row class and then here I'll make another div
and let's put this all in one line I remember.
I want it to be at least three columns of pictures across on the largest setting.
So if I expand this I see three pictures across the largest setting and on the smallest setting it should
just be two pictures.
So you can see the pictures actually get smaller to adjust for that as I go on so expanding this again.
Three and at the smallest it's going to be too.
No matter how small it gets.
It's always two pictures across.
No matter how big it gets it's always three pictures across which means I want something like this.
I won't call on large.
I want each picture to take up four units out of those 12 units because four times three is 12.
And then at the very smallest call extra small.
I wanted to take six units so six times two is 12.
And then the next thing I want to do is add in the thumbnail class and the thumbnail class allows us
to actually make these pictures of the thumbnails and let's explore what that looks like in the documentation
coming to get bootstrapped.
Com I can click on the components and over here on the right hand side I'll see and look down that there
is thumbnails.
So clicking on that I see I can extend this Tripps grid system with the thumbnail component to easily
display grids of images videos text and more.
And this is kind of going to look like almost like Pinterest style photos and they show you an example
here of what these actually look like.
But the main thing to notice is that all we have to do is say class thumbnail and what thumbnail allows
you to do is actually expand the call to the class on the outside.
So by default these tropes thumbnails are designed to showcase linked images with some minimal required
markup and then you can also put in custom content which we won't be doing here but you can see that
I could even add in this little heading some paragraphs statements and some buttons as well.
So those are two examples of what thumbnails look like.
Basically all you had to do was add in the thumbnail class.
So coming back to our project we're going to add in here a thumbnail and then we're going to add an
image tag right here and we want to make sure that our source matches up to the coffee picture and all
those coffee picture sources are available to here on the Bitstrips she can click on one of them and
I'll take you to this link right here so I can just copy and paste this link.
And then put it as the source of my image.
Save this and then if I refresh my project I can begin to see the first picture of my coffee.
So now instead of just repeating those steps over and over again I'm going to copy and paste all these
from the solutions.
It's basically just duplicate.
Over and over again.
So I copy and paste these Let's shift tab over and I can see here I have everything the same.
Just linking two different images that I have on the solutions so let's save that refresh over here
and I can say I have my pictures of coffee three across three at cross.
Everything's looking good.
OK.
Now that's actually all I really needed for the project itself as far as the main sign up page.
Delivering a check now is if I begin to decrease this it turns into two columns which we see it eventually
that's great even as it gets smaller states too.
Now I just need to fix the sign up page which is currently blank right now.
So let's do that.
Let me click open my new sign up page which is right here.
New underscore sign up each T.M..
It only has NEVER right now so we need to add in the forms.
If we take a look at what the solutions looked like.
So coming back here clicking on seinen I can see there was actually a large Jumbotron saying to log
in and email password.
So let's add that in to our sign up page.
It's going to come outside of this.
Now I've been going to say whoops div put in a container.
Another day with the Jumbotron itself and then I'm going to just put it heading on log in and then the
paragraph is going to say Enter your email and password.
So let's save that.
Make sure it actually registered a far site refresh.
Great.
So there's a log in and three email and password.
Now it's time to just add in the form Selsey form and there's an action here in this study.
Tim L. We really don't need to worry about any action because we're not actually going to lead anywhere
and we don't need to worry about the method.
If we wanted this to lead somewhere else to another page and the back end we could have filled that
in.
But we don't need to worry about that.
The class however we do need to worry about.
So we'll say form that group member that's the class we've been working with for bootstrap forms.
And then I want to add in a label and an input first one is going to be my email and put.
And we're going to give this class formed dash control member the two main classes we were working with
and we were working with inputs and forms.
It was Forum group and forum control and then the label I want for this is email and I want to make
sure this has a name so we'll give it a name user E-M for user email and make sure we assign it the
label user.
E-M now we don't need actually give it a value.
Instead let's give it a placeholder and we'll say email just looks a little nicer.
Let's save that.
Make sure it worked well refresh.
Great.
Here's our email but notice it's going all the way across.
It's actually not in a container class which means I need to come back here and either put it back into
this original container or create a new container.
It's up to you depending how you want to organize your code.
But I'll just put it in a new container.
Well scrap this form put in that new container refresh and here we have it in a nice container.
OK so we have our e-mail looking nice the container.
Let's come back up here and actually add in to our form the password the checkbox and the submit button.
So this will look really similar for the password so I can actually just copy this pasted in here and
change the things I need to change.
So for instance I want to change the actual label to say password and also change for instead of user
E-M I'll say user pass which means I need to change this name over here to user pass and to change the
type to password.
I'll keep class form control the same and then placeholder.
We're going to say password here.
Let's save this refresh make sure it all worked.
And there's our e-mail there's a password.
Looking good.
Now it's add that checkbox.
Remember that checkbox just said something like keep me logged in.
So I create a div and will give it the class checkbox we'll call a label will say it's for user check
say keep me log.
Then it doesn't matter if we capitalize everything and then I want the input to be a checkbox input
with the name user check.
Let's save that and see what we get when I refresh this.
So it says keep me logged in but know that it's actually on top of my checkbox.
So let's fix that.
The way to fix that is by actually putting in my label wrapped around the input.
So I'm going to grab this input over here.
And make sure I call in the correct form.
So I'm going to pass it in before the keep me logged in.
So now let's save this refresh and I can see here.
Now I have my check box before the actual label keep me logged in.
So again the way I did that if I expand this window scroll to the left here is I called the label said
input type and then had the techs keep me logged in and closed off that label then I just want to add
in the submit button.
So I will call button type is going to be submit.
It could have also set input.
It's up to you.
And let's give it the class between between defaults and that's just something you can reference off
documentation depending on what you want to look like you could have styled it as a success button or
a primary really up to you if we refresh this.
You can see now we have this button here Our it doesn't actually have anything in it.
So let's add in something like submit save it refresh.
And here we see submit and now are Web sites looking pretty good.
So we'll come back to the landing page we see coffee lover project the pictures of the coffee company
to sign in.
We see a log in.
I can put in an email and I can put in a password select to keep me locked in and submit.
All right that's really all you have to do for this project.
I know it can seem really intimidating at first when you see this version of the project the actual
official one.
So everything of the instructions but hopefully you saw from what we learned here in the solutions video
that it's actually pretty straightforward.
We didn't even reference the documentation that much for what we had to do a lot of it was just covered
in the videos.
Now I know some things such as remembering what these classes are such as forum group or forum control
may seem tedious at this point in time but these are things we're going to be using often enough when
you're working a bootstrap they'll actually remember them.
And I know I keep saying that you'll reference the documentation a lot but even for simple things like
this which is actually a pretty good looking landing page.
You don't have the reference documentation that much with the mount of practice you're going to be getting
of bootstrap in this course.
OK.
So I hope you enjoyed the project.
I will see you at the next lecture.