Hello everyone and welcome back to for Array exercise solution and in this lecture we're going to be
coding through the solution for that student roster Auray exercise project.
Let's head over to the editor and get started.
OK so here with the javascript part for Array exercise file open.
Let's start off by actually creating the functions.
The first thing we need to create was the add new function for adding a new student so call the keyword
function and we can just get it by typing F-you when hitting enter and we will say add new and add new
will not take any parameters.
Instead we're going to do is create a variable inside of add new called new name and we will prompt
the user for what name would you like to add.
Question mark and then once we get that new name we're going to push it to the roster.
So we'll grab roster push and then push in that new name and that's all there really is for adding the
new student.
Now is talk about removing the student and this is actually quite a bit trickier and you definitely
have to visit the stack overflow link if you're going to do it the same way I do it right now and that
that overfilling basically has the answer of removing a particular element from an array.
So again we'll create a function we'll call it remove and I'm going to say a variable we'll call it
REM name for a move name.
And we'll ask what name would you like to remove.
Question mark and then I'm also going to create a variable called index and this is going to be roster
dot and the method here is index of.
And that was in the stack overflow link there so roster that index of REM name.
And then the other thing from the stack overflow was the splice method and the splice method takes an
index comma one
where one is just how many elements who want to delete.
Starting at.
This index.
And that's all there is for the remove function.
Let's continue on with the next one.
I actually want to do is display rosters.
That was actually quite simple.
It's basically just logging the roster.
So we're going to say function display doesn't take any arguments but we will just log the actual roster.
Now it's time for basically the hard part which is actual all actually programming all that logic and
lines create a couple more lines here just so I can see everything clearly.
We're going to start off by creating two variables called Start and star.
It's just a prompt.
That says Would you like to start the Ruster web at and will only accept why or.
And so will tell the user wire and there and I will also create a variable called request that is equal
to empty and we'll see a request for as in just the second.
But basically it's going to be a string and I'm going to say if Star is equal to y meaning the user
did want to start the Web at while
request is not equal
to quit I'm going to do the following.
I'll ask for a new request by prompting them.
Please select an action add or remove display or quit.
And here is where I'm actually going to start testing for stuff all inside this while loop.
So if the request was equal to add.
Well in that case I'm going to call add new and add new has the prompt asking for the new name and pushing
it to the roster.
So all I have to do is call add new nothing else.
LCF request
is equal to display.
That's quite easy too.
I just call display
and then LCF
what say request
is equal to remove.
Well in that case I just call the remove function that I created earlier
and if we scroll all the way down we can see the rest of these brackets to make sure they're all balanced.
And I'm going to have an alert here that says Thanks for using the web at.
Please refresh to start over.
And as a quick note I don't have an else statement here.
I technically don't really need one for this entire thing to work.
And the reason for that is because they're all in the while loop here.
But something it could do is say.
Else.
And then just have it be quick.
So say request is equal to quit.
And basically what this does is if request is not add remove the player quit.
So maybe the person typed something wrong.
It will automatically quit.
So we probably also want to say an alert here not recognized
we'll quit or we could just say not recognized and then comment this up and then we'll continually ask
for the prompt here.
All right.
So that's really all you have to do.
Let's actually run this and make sure it worked.
We're going to open up my browser.
OK.
Here is my browser.
I've refreshed the page says Would you like start the web app.
I will say yes please select an action.
Let's add something we'll add.
Jose let's display to make sure it works.
There is Jose.
Let's add one more we'll add in Sammy display Jose and Sammy are there.
Let's remove Sammy and Alex display again.
There's Jose.
And then let's try just typing some random and it says not recognize great.
That's exactly what we wanted.
And then we will quit and it says thinks reason the web please refresh to start over.
OK.
So that's it.
Looks like everything works correctly.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.