Hello everyone and welcome to the registration of a lecture for a Level 5.
A lot of the coding for working with the users and authorization happens in the used up by file.
The basic idea is that we check if there's a POST request and then perform some sort of action based
off that information.
Sometimes we all want to save that information correctly to the database.
Other times we will commit equal to false inside of the Save method so we can manipulate the data before
saving it to the database.
This helps prevent collision errors from saving it twice.
So instead we just commit to false the first time and then save it after we're done manipulating the
data figuring out the registration views as an extension of what we learned about when discussing Gengel
forms.
So make sure to review that content if you don't remember it.
This entire process is best shown through code.
So we're going to jump to have used a PI file and cut through it all.
We will also fix a small mistake made in the previous lectures when working with the forms and how to
keep an eye out for those errors.
So we'll start by fixing that small mistake and then we'll jump to the views that profile.
Let's get started.
Looky here I am at the Adam text editor and I have my views that Paey file open in.
I can also check my forms that py file and there's actually a small error in this file.
And we're going to walk through how we can discover the sort of error we have working with these up-I.
So what I'm going to do is start off by creating the most basic view which is our index view.
That's for the home page.
So I will say request and then I'm going to return render.
Now I will say request and then passen basic app slash indexed h T.M. and then the next we I want to
make is for the registration page.
Now we'll start off by saying DPF or we'll call this view register.
It's going to take in a request and we'll create a variable called registered.
And I will set equal to false and then go into the Penland is variable to tell if someone's been registered
yet or not and they will say if request that method is equal to most here's what we'll do.
And I should say to equal science here as I'm checking for equality we're going to do is get information
from both of the forms just like we would if any other form.
So I will create a variable called user underscore form and this matches the variable and going sent
back with the context dictionary.
And this will grab information from the user form and we'll set data is equal to request that post and
then the other form we had was the profile underscore form and we'll set this equal to user profile
info.
And this is where I caught that mistake.
So notice here I want the user form and the user profile info form and then I want this data to be equal
to request post.
But I notice that since I'm using the forms I should import the forms.
So I come back up here and I go to import them and this we're going to kind of catch a little bit of
a glitch or error.
I'll say from basic app forms import the user form Khama import.
And I see here user profile info but remember the user profile info is our model.
So if I come to models that pi I have user profile info as the model I should have that as the same
name here under the forms that Highflyer file.
Or have the user form and the user profile info.
So what I need to fix is changes to say instead of user profile info the user profile in FO form then
save that and then come back up here.
To views up high and changes from user profile info to user profile info form and then save that so
the main mistake here that was made was instead of saying user profile info form we XLE used the same
model name and that's kind of a big no no.
What you should do is there is always at some sort of term form when you're dealing with a model form.
That way it doesn't get confused on this line or it says model is equal to the form name.
Otherwise it's thinks it's a self-referential call.
All right if you have any questions on that.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forum.
There should have been a note about that.
However before I even saw the mistake being done.
So welcome back to views that pi and continue working on this point to collapse the trees we see a little
more room so have that user form that profile forum created those two variables.
Now I want to check if both forms are valid and if you ever have questions on any of these steps you
can always reference the note code as well.
I will say user underscore form is valid and profil form is underscore valid this or we're going to
do stuff if they're valid.
So we'll do some different actions as the user form versus the profile form.
So I'm going to set the user equal to user underscore form and I will save that information directly
to the database that I'm going to say user and I will call a set password method on this and I will
set user the password.
And this is essentially hash in the password to go into your settings up-I file and it sets it as the
hash.
And then after this we're going to say save.
So basically what this is happening is we're grabbing the user form saving the database.
Now we're hashing the password by saying set password method and then we save that hash passwords of
the database so we save those changes to the user.
And now we want to actually deal with that extra information.
Remember that was their website link and their profile picture.
So we will say profile is equal to profile underscore form.
And I'm going to say that save but here is one point to passen commit is equal to false.
I don't want to commit to the database yet.
Otherwise I may get errors with collisions where it tries to overwrite this user.
So we're going to do instead is say profile that user is equal to user and that sets up that one to
one relationship.
So if you come back to models remember over here the user profile info that user is equal to a one to
one relationship with the user here.
So this one to one relationship is defined in the views with this line of code profile that user is
equal to user which is the user form which you come back here is this original form model vehicles user
so follow up the steps.
It's a little hard to show because it's kind of all three of these files linking at the same time.
Hopefully you can kind of get the idea of how we're relating the extra profile information those extra
attributes to the original one to one relationship.
And then what we want to do is check if they actually provided a profile picture and we will say if
profile underscore pick in request post excuse me request that files because it's an actual file we
will say profil profile pic is equal to request files and this is basically a dictionary if all the
files they uploaded in the request.
So you'll use very similar tactics when dealing with other types of files not just images but if you
want to upload a C S V a PTF the resume is set up.
You're going to be saying requests that files actually find those and you'll be dealing with the key.
Based on what you find in the models So say if the profile pic and request that models we set the attribute
profile pic equal to the request or files which kind of acted like a dictionary and then profile pic
and then we going to save the model after doing that we'll say profile save.
And if they've done all of this so both forms are valid we save the user and we save their profile set
up their picture then I'm going to set registered
equal to true.
So the registration was successful.
Else what I'm going to do is print the air.
So if I get an L statement here that means the forms were involved.
So one of the forms or both of the forms were invalid.
And what we can do in this case is just print out the error so I can see a user form.
There's And then we can also just do this almost like a tuple So say a profile form errors and there's
more.
There's other ways we can do all of that later on we'll show especially during the Clone project.
But right now we could just print out the actual errors and then we'll say.
Else.
And this else winds up not with this if the over here with the IF request that method is to post so.
Else That means the request was on an HTP request so it can actually post anything.
So it will do here is set everything up.
So we'll say User Form is equal to an instance of user form and we'll say profile form is equal to an
instance of the user profile form or a user profile in full form.
And then once this is all done we're going to return
a render of the request and then what we want to do is show them what file we want to import this into.
And this is the registration file.
So registration that is T.M. let me confirm that's what it called that looking under templates basic
app.
Yes it is registration that H.T. mail.
So that's good.
And then finally I need to pass in the context dictionary.
So if I take a quick peek at registration that is T.M. remember we used several things here.
We used user form profile form and then registered.
So those are three things I need to pass along in the used up by file as my contex dictionary.
So the first thing we can actually start this on a new line is so it's a little more organized.
The first key is that user form.
And that's just going to be equal to the user form we created.
The second key value pair I want is the profile form.
Again that's just going to be the profile form we created.
And then finally the third thing I want is that registered key value pair.
And that again matches up with registered and it's very common to have the context dictionary keys match
up exactly with the values.
That way it's really readable.
And you remember what is what.
OK so that is it for the registration view.
Now as I mentioned it is a lot of coding and it's going to be kind of another round of a lot of coding
when we talk about logging in and logging out.
But if we scroll up here we should be able to see the steps.
So first we have the registration view.
We check if they're registered as we said equal to false so we kind of assume at first they're not registered.
Then if the request is equal to post we grabbed the information off the forms we check of the forms
are valid.
If so we grab everything from the base user form then we grab the profile form and we got a double check
that to see if there's a picture in there before we actually save it and then we said registered is
equal to true.
If they did type in a post there but there was an error.
So they were both not valid or one of them was not valid.
Then we'll just print out the errors and then else.
So that means there was no request.
The request method.
Is that equal to post that we just set the forms so was that user form and the profile in full form.
And then finally we return the render.
OK.
So let's save all of this.
And let's actually test this out.
I'm sure there will be some bugs to fix but let's see how we do.
So I'm going to clear this should be CLX.
And then what I'm going to do is say Python managed pie and I'm going to just for safety because I was
fixing some of those mistakes going to migrate.
All right.
So no migrations apply.
But let's also check with the make migration come in basic app so there's no problem kind of being extra
paranoid about this.
With one of these migrate commands even if you don't think you need to.
So there we go.
OK.
So we applied all migrations we should be good which means I'm going to actually try to run the servers
so I'll say Python is up high.
Run server.
And let's see if we get any errors.
Well no errors on actually running the code.
Let's see if we get an error on the Web site so bringing in the web site looks like that is working
as well.
Let's see if the registration page works.
Click on register.
OK so register is also working says user name and there's some auto stuff that gets filled out based
off the validation requirements.
So we'll will say new user e-mail address will just say hello at gmail dot com password.
This going to be whatever pie's Taipan test password portfolio site all say HTP P.S. W.W. the Google
dot com and check of the documentation for validation of these inputs we discussed inputting or validation
input when we were talking about forms and in other jingoes section of the course.
But for actual Your airfields it usually requires you to say HTP.
So most people won't put that in and it will give an error.
So what you can do is when actually working with that file in the views you can check if it sorts of
that.
If not you can just injected in then for the profile pic you can just choose any file I want shoes on
for now instead of just going to click register and see if it works.
So we hit register great and it says thank you for registering.
So we need to do is actually check if this person now is in our database.
But in order to do that if I click on admin We need a super user.
So let's go and create that song.
Drag this guy away and let's do Control-C to kill this.
And then I will say Python managed up high create super user enter and we'll say Jose like usual.
Any email address is fine.
Trini hearing date of the and then password all use test password is password OK.
Superuser was created successfully.
Now let's run the server again.
So say Python manage that pirate server going to come back to the home page and bring it in.
So there's our home page and we should have already register that person says Click on admin type in
our username and then type in the password log in and see if we get everything.
OK.
So here we have our basic app.
And if you don't see this it's because you probably forgot to actually register on the admin that PI
file.
So make sure you do that.
But will hit user profile info.
Great we have that new user you can click on it and we can see all their information.
User portfolio site profile pic.
That looks good.
So let's go back and if we go to wups home under site administration we can hit here on users and now
we have Jose which has me this super user.
And then we have the new user which is a hello at G-mail dot com and if we click on that new user we
can see their quote unquote password but we actually can't see the password.
And that's because of the hash algorithms that we used and the particular hashing algorithm we use with
that are gone to makes us pretty secure.
In fact that's very very secure and you can see that even some of the information is censored to us
as a super administrator.
So there is no way to actually get this user's password.
And essentially there's no way if someone ever asked for your password that you would ever be able to
give it to them.
So this is so secure that even you as the administrator are not going be able to see the password.
You can see their salt their hash some of it censored et cetera but you're never going to actually be
able to give back to user their password if you do want to change the password.
You can eventually set this up automatically but you can get this form and create a new password and
then enter that password again and then change the password.
You'll never be able to do is just tell the user what their original password was.
The security is too high for you as a super user to even find that out.
OK.
So there's some other information here and we'll talk about more stuff with jingo administration in
a future lecture but successfully We've registered someone to the site which is pretty awesome.
Coming up next we want to talk about is them logging in and logging the site.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.