Hello everyone and welcome to the templates features and filter's lecture before we complete jingle
level 4 in our understanding of templates.
Let's quickly touch upon Django template filter's imagine that you had some information from your model
that you wish to use across various views or pages on your website but perhaps you wanted to make a
slight edit to the information before injecting it maybe like a string operation or basic arithmetic
for example maybe on a certain web page you wanted the string to be all capital letters but on another
web page you just want to be in lowercase.
Well how do you actually deal if that luckily Gengel provides a ton of easy to implement template filters
that allow you to affect the injection before the splaying it to the user.
And this allows for flexibility from a single source.
So you don't have to worry about editing the source on the Python side.
You can actually edit it using templates on the Web site.
So the general form of a template filter it looks like this.
Previously we just had those set of brackets and then the value we wanted to inject here we can say
the value you want to inject have the pipe operator that straightline the name of the filter and then
the parameter that the filter takes in.
Now not all filters taken parameters and we'll see examples of them as we continue on throughout this
section.
Many of these filters are based off of common built in Python functions.
So you're already going to be familiar with them.
They're naming operations and what they can actually do.
OK let's show you the documentation on them so you know how to reference all the various filters.
There are a ton of them.
So a lot of times will just be go into documentation seeing which one you need to use and then copying
and pasting from there later on will also show you how you create your own filters.
I'm going to jump to documentation.
You can go to this specific link.
This is the documentation link for templates for 1.1 0.
This version of Django or you can just google search Gengel plus templates and it'll probably take you
to this page and hop over there now.
All right so here we are at the documentation page for Django templates and this is a really great reference
if you ever have any questions on templates.
And as I always mentioned the jayega documentation in general is really good.
So the templates page it starts off by talking about different support for template engines.
By default we use the Django template language or DTL.
It's more than enough for our use cases.
So if you're just learning Django as you get more advance you can always check out popular alternatives
for template engines such as Jinja too.
And this tells you how to connect them how to download them etc..
So a lot of really useful information here.
But we're going to be concerned about is template filters.
So if you come over here on the right hand side there should be a link under syntax to filters.
You can click on it and it will show you what filters look like.
So as I mentioned in general look like this I'm going to zoom in a little bit here to see the filters
Museum and one more time.
Scroll back down to the filters.
And here there.
OK.
So the filters in general look like this.
Remember we have a context dictionary that is actually calling a key value pair.
And then we pass in the key here that's the actual variable or value we're passing in.
Then you have the pipe operator and the name of the filter you want to apply.
So in this case we have Django where the context of jingle being the key and it's attached to the string
that's in all lower case and then the filter name we're using is called Title and title if you're familiar
with Python string operations it's also a python string operation where it basically capitalizes the
first letter and every word in a string.
So you can see how converts this to this right here.
And as I mentioned some filters also take an argument or a parameter and that would look like something
like this you would say my date that belongs to some context dictionary.
The pipe operator and then the name of the filter date's colon and in a string whatever argument you're
actually passing in this case the format of the date you want to display and there's a reference for
all the built in filters as well as instructions for writing your own custom filters.
Now there are so many built in filters that we don't have enough time in this course to go through them
all.
Really what you're going to be doing is clicking on this link and referencing them yourself.
But there's also a way to write your own custom filters which will also show you how to do in a future
election.
But that's all we're going to cover for now.
In this lecture coming up next we're going to talk about just some few examples of basic built in filters
as well as talking about how to create your own custom filters.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.