Hill every want to walk up to part seven of the blog and project it's finally time to actually start
filling up all those email templates that we've created in the previous lectures and we're going to
start off with the base HTL templates.
So that's the one we're going to be using by extending it to all the other templates and we'll also
be setting up some of the C Ss and Javascript calls.
We're going to be making through up to future lectures.
Let's get started by helping the editor and also be showing you the resources in the browser so we're
kind of back and forth between those.
Let's get started.
All right.
Here I am at the editor and I opened up the base that each team l file.
So far we don't really have anything in it.
We just have this doc type H Tim L and I've gone ahead and added load static files that way I can reference
things such as the blog CSSA file we did using template tagging.
So I can say that static template tag.
So coming back to the base that each team l we're going to add some stuff to this.
So the things to add after adding a title is bootstrap saw type that in as comments so I want to add
in Bootstrap.
I also want to add in this medium style editor and that's going to be the thing that allows us to kind
of mimic medium calm editing and we'll show you what that means in just a second.
We also want to have some custom CSX and then probably some Google fonts as well.
So we'll grab those as well.
And then the other thing that I want is over here in the body will probably want a nav bar eventually
so I'll be adding that in this lecture.
And then since this is going to be the base likes him will probably also have some content so I'll have
some sort of body block here.
I believe you called it the concept block so we'll call it concept block.
OK so let's say that and let's come back up here and show you the resources and how to grab the rethinks
for bootstrap.
We've done this a bunch of times before but just come over here to get bootstrapped back.
And then I'm going to grab these CD ends.
I will copy this and then I'm going to paste it here.
And here we can see the latest bit if I see a SS and also an optional theme is what I've copied and
pasted those are the only two lines we need.
And then the collapse directory tree to get myself a little more room.
Now the next thing we're going to add in is the medium style editor.
So in case you're not familiar medium dot com Let me show you what that looks like and then we'll explore
some hub libraries that are open source for us to use to mimic this song.
Hop over to my browser here and close this get bootstrap.
And here we can see a page if you go all the way atop.
Check out these links.
But it's just that the user Y A B W e slash and then the medium Ed. And you can see is actually a library
that has a ton of commits.
It's actually updated pretty recently as far as this feeling.
At least a month ago it was updated.
And if you keep scrolling down you'll see it it supports most major browsers but to actually get an
understanding of what this is I'm going to go to medium dot com to kind of show you.
So if you're go to medium com right now I'm logged then.
So I can see particular articles that median dot com is basically where anyone can just write an article
or a blog and everything has the same style and formatting.
So if we click on one of these articles such as this one how machines make sense of big data.
Obviously you can tell that I follow a lot of data science and technology articles you'll click on it
then it looks something like this in every article or blog on a medium that basically has the same look
and feel you have images and you have this text editor and you have kind of these wide margins.
So it looks kind of like a blog post.
And if you want to write your own story you click here and write story after you've logged in and then
you have the sort of editor to say some stuff here and then you can highlight this and it gives you
the option to either make it bolds make it a taluk head or one heading to where you can put a link here
and then say I don't know Google dot com etc. and they can see it's underlined and now it's a link.
So that's the kind of thing we want to mimic in our own blog posts.
So if we come over here after some searching I was able to discover that a lot of people wanted the
sort of functionality and it's already here for a client for us to use.
And if you scroll all the way down you want to make sure that whenever you're working with open source
files that you found online that there is some sort of license agreement so we check on the license
make sure that we have permission to actually use this.
Now I'm just using this for educational purposes so you can see that this is copyright but there's also
a particular license so there's permission free of charge to any person obtaining a copy of the software
to deal in the software or any sort of restrictions.
And then is subject to the following conditions.
Usually the conditions are for you just to source an attribute who you actually got this from.
So here's the actual information here on this license we're just doing this for educational purposes.
But whenever you're doing something in a production you should always make sure that you have the rights
to this software.
Obviously things are hosted on get hub in their open source things and get a little fuzzy if you ever
have any doubt you'll get the message to the person directly.
Coming back to the actual whoops let's go back here.
Are you coming back to the actual medium Ed. home page here on the hub we can see that if you scroll
down.
It's essentially a javascript library that mimics exactly what the medium Viacom was doing.
It has modern browser support which is good and it shows you some basic demos on basic usage.
So we're going to be doing is using this for text area and eventually you click on the demos you'll
find this demo.
So this under medium Ed. demo text area h team L and you can see that after you've imported and linked
everything the javascript in the CSSA you just have to create this script here to create a new editor
object.
And you also have to make sure that has this class this editable medium Ed. text area which we actually
did back when we were creating that we just dictionary attribute in the forms classes and then coming
down here we can see that there's various ways to actually add this in as a file in our project.
And there's a service called JSE deliver which kind of acts like an external CDN.
So if you don't actually want to download everything and link it up manually you can just copy and paste
these two right here.
So one is a javascript file and then one is the CSSA link file so I'm going to do that.
The other option is if you're having trouble getting the CD ends to work then just do the manual installation
which you just scroll down here.
And then you click down where it says latest releases will take it to the latest release page and then
I'll say OK is 5.2 3.0.
And then we can do is find there all the information about that.
And then just download the source code itself and then just use the linking which we already learned
about HTL to link the javascript and CSSA files.
So I'll come back here to my editor and I'm going to copy and paste that medium style editor.
So there's only two things there is that javascript.
And then there's this C Ss So coming back around here.
Those are the two links I'm going to need to actually implement the medium style editing and later I
will see the template tags I had to set up that widget class and then also call that script that we
kind of just talked about.
Then finally for some custom CSSA make sure that any custom C Ss goes after all these other CSSA calls
and I'm going to link it here to this blog that si SS So luckily I've already inputted static files
meaning I can just say add a link here.
It's a style sheet and then from a trip on you use static template tagging which you've seen before
and just say static and then call something like see SS blog about CSSA.
Because if I look at her Churi that's where it is.
We have static C S S log that t ss and right now.
Our blog about C Ss is empty and if you remember back to what the blog actually looks like we have those
sort of color changes that the text does and I'll show you how I discover that.
So what's a really fun Web site to check out which we probably mentioned the very beginning in the course
as a way to share your code for Front-End stuff is code Pendar.
I know that c o d PTEN.
I know and you can come here and there's lots of pens and essentially this is just really nice fun front
end stuff.
So using three Front-End technologies that's him LCAC us and Javascript and CSSA is actually really
powerful.
You can do a lot of C Ss that you would think would be limited to Javascript.
So what I was doing I was just messing around code then I kind of wanted to add some nice CSSA this
maybe something that was a little fun for the blog project.
Eventually after searching these if you find something that interests you for instance maybe you want
it.
Well not the box solution that's all too crazy.
Let's say you wanted to have this little guy this rainbow preload or so you click on this.
You'll notice that it has noted it's only supported in Chrome.
But if you wanted to add something like this to your site we could do just copy this VSS and then copy
the same Elche.
This is an example of how to use a CSSA and that would be an easy way to have that on your site.
So I ended up doing is I discovered this little loading.
So it's a simple loader and we can click on it and what it does is the background changes Hughes and
I want it to instead of have the entire background change hues.
I would have the letters themselves change hues and I didn't really care too much about these three
dots that are loading.
So basically what I want to grab is just the color changing and this was actually all done with SS So
I'm going to copy and paste this.
And since we're using this for educational purposes we don't have to worry too much.
But the license but in case you want to use a file like this in production it's always a good idea to
contact the creator and make sure that's OK with them.
Obviously their hosting this all open source and there's no real license agreement here.
We should always check and make sure.
So all you do is copy this and note the class.
It's the class loader and we're going to be kind of calling that on everything later on.
So I'm going to come back here after copy and paste that and I'm just going to put that into our own
blog about SS So will paste it here and then scroll back up.
And I don't actually need the BE1 be to B-3 cetera.
So all those were is if you kind of check out this.
We had class B one B and B-3 that's for these three little loading bars.
What I really want and am concerned with is just this loader and then these keyframes.
So I'm going to get rid of these BE1 classes scroll all the way down and then kind of get rid of them
just to simplify my CSSA script a little bit.
And then what I want to do is last thing I don't want to change the background I just want to change
the color and we'll be exploring this later on as we actually implement this OK.
So there is my loader and we actually don't need this left right top either erroneous position or fix
kind of simplifying this.
These are the three things they only really care about.
The hue rotates or it's actually coming from the linear gradient of the color and then the animation.
So I will save this and then we'll see if we have this H-1 call which we can leave.
We want it to but I'm actually going to get rid of it since we don't really need a heading one.
So that was Felix over here this loading or somehow it's also changing.
I don't really want that so going to say save it.
So the main things I care about are loader and then keyframes if you keep the other stuff in you may
get some different behavior than what we've seen in the blog so far.
And after we've set up our blog about CSSA file with that extra code the last thing we have to do is
set up Google fonts.
So coming back to the browser I have Google fonts or Fahnestock Google dot com and I can search for
the two fonts I used.
Obviously have a lot of flexibility over which ones you want to use.
I use one called The Russo one look kind of interesting to me.
And then I also use one of my favorite fonts This maps Mazzara.
And then we're going to add that as well.
Two families are selected to open that up and then copy and paste the link here.
So I'm going to copy that and insert that into fonts.
And now I have the stylesheets OK.
Perfect.
And now we're going to do is set up our nav bar.
So we'll come down here.
And we're going to set up our nav bar.
So there's our next.
And let's set up the class calls and I would expect you to memorize these.
I basically was just looking at the bootstrap documentation.
In fact a lot of this was kind of just like copy and paste from Bootstrap documentation.
So we use nav bar space nav bar dash default.
And then I'm going to create another class called Tech fonts which is going to allow me if I go to blog
about C Ss and that and now that's going to allow me to actually edit the fonts of the actual nav bar
so that that.
Going to say the font family of that is.
Russo one that was the font from Google that we just got.
And then it's also going to be sans serif.
And then I'm also the font size to be I should say 1.5 E-M And then of course you have a lot of leeway.
If however you want to do this and to give a little bit more margin here so I will save that.
So coming back to base that is simple.
So that's my tech funds.
And then the other thing I want is custom nav bar so custom therefore is a class that I'm going to be
using in case I ever want to customize anything else on my enough bar.
I'll leave it blank for now on the blog about C Ss.
I don't believe we actually ever really need it or use it.
But sometimes a good idea to just add in another class while you're building at the base HTL template
in case you ever want to mess around with it.
So we'll save that and then we're gonna do have a div here and we're just going to give this a container
div that way anything we put in the nav bar will actually be contained.
So we're gonna have quite a few links here.
First one is going to be effect let's give it a class Personal going to be our brand.
So we'll call this nav bar dash brands and there's something else you can add in here we'll add another
class big brand and that way we can link that to our CSSA file if necessary.
And Big Brown is just something to make it a little bigger.
So don't come over here and add an big brands class Elisha's have this be font size of 1.5 E-M.
That way it looks a little larger than the rest of the text so if you notice back when we were running
the blog project the brand font size of a little bit larger than the rest of it so that's what the big
brand is for and then continuing on with this.
What I want to do is set up the link.
So if you go to the if you click on the brand I should take you back to the home page or remember the
home page for us is the actual post lists also your all post list.
And let's call this something like my blog OK.
So I'm going to expand this.
We don't really need to reference the browser anymore.
And Addinall a little list item.
And you can kind of fast forward for this if you don't want to watch me do all this just as a heads
up.
And then we went in about page either about yourself or the company.
Now we'll just have to say about it can copy and paste all these links to make sure you get the spelling
correct and then have two references so we'll have a reference outside reference that is to have dot
com Maybe we're using this for your own portfolio site or your company's web page.
We'll have something like that.
And then let's have another one to link then
and we'll have the say only then.
And let's put this all in an unordered list.
So on are list here and so be in their class loop's nav nav bar Sneath and all grab all these list items
and put them into this an ordered list
and I will save that.
OK so now we have to make sure that if the user is logged into the Web site they see those other options
and there's other options we're creating a new post drafts and then logging out and something that says
something like welcome user welcome Jose cetera.
So in order to do that I'm going to add in in other unordered list and I'm going to also give this class
and will say nav bar actually nav nav bar dash nav nav bar dash right so everything's right aligned
as far as the log in information.
And here's we're going to add in some template tagging for some logic so we'll add an if statement and
we'll say if the user is underscore authenticated which comes from our imports of the Auth. library
in Jingo and whenever you have and if you always got to make sure you have an and if so have that as
well.
Now what kind of leave this towards the bottom.
So if the user is authenticated what are we going to do.
Well we should have a list item right.
And that list item which is give it a anchor Ted and the anchor tag is going to be your template and
the template is going to say oh blink to post-New and we'll have it say you post.
So I'm going to copy and paste this because I want three more really similar things.
I was sort of post-New to go to your draft page.
So that is post draft list and associate new posts.
We'll just have it say drafts to there's the unpublished blog post and then we also want some sort of
log out button so I have log out.
And then this will just say log out.
And then finally after all that I want one more of these which is a little simpler that just says sexually.
Sorry we're going to have a link.
Just going to say Welcome saying welcome and we'll inject our name.
So that's going to be user the user name save that.
Now if you have an if statement you're probably going to have an else statement in order for this to
all work correctly.
So if we don't have any of that what is the right Bargen to look like.
So we'll say
else we'll have a list item or 10 give it's a link that says in which makes sense.
So if you're not logged in you're going to want to log in and we'll say this template tag of your el
log in and let's give this a class Alliance rights
nav nav bar dash right.
And if you can see here I believe it should fall under the unordered list class anyways but just because
I'm a little paranoid add it to that particular item as well.
And let's scroll over here and what we could do is just have something that says log in but instead
we'll have a cliff icon which is essentially that little icon.
And these are free icons that come with bootstrap.
And in order to use them you just use the span and then give this band a class and the class name just
matches up the actual icon you want to use.
So in our case it's g l y glyph and then
Sakal can dash user and that's a little kind of Facebook looking face that little profile.
All right.
So that should be it for our number so you can see here if we can review it.
We have everything on the left hand side of my blog with the brand page about Herb Linked-In and then
everything to the right.
If the user is authenticated.
We have these three links you post drafts log out.
If they're not authenticated else or we're just going to have pay go to the logon page and it's a picture
of someone it's not even some text now outside of the nav bar we're going to do is set up our actual
content.
So let's do that.
Let's put all the content inside some sort of div and we can say have a class called content and then
have another class called container in case we ever want to use it.
And if we're interested in collapsing things like if it's on a mobile display this is where you could
start adding and things like gross.
So we don't really worry about this too much since we don't intend for people to really read or blog
posts on immobile.
But you would just have the Rosen here and then you can start saying well this class is going to be
something like call medium A and then maybe have another class for the blog post that we can link it
up to any CSSA that you want to affect.
But eventually after you've done all your divs what you're going to want is the actual block itself.
So it's going to be block and then contents
or body block whatever you want to call it.
And then we'll have an block here.
OK.
So basically you can add in a bunch of divs here that refer to the bootstrap ability to actually collapse
things correctly according to whatever the grid system you worked out with.
OK.
So that is it for the base that each team M-file.
It was a lot of typing but stuff like save us some time when we actually work with other templates.
And that was hopefully a good enough explanation of where we got this medium style editor from as well
as the Google fonts and as well as this custom CSSA if we go down here for the color changing and the
key thing here to know is that we're going to be using this lower class at the very end to get everything
done.
OK.
Make sure you copy and paste this from the notes if you're iffy on actually following along my coding
here.
Thanks and I will see at the next lecture where we begin to extend this to all the other templates.