Hello everyone and welcome to the logons lecture once a user is registered.
We want to make sure that they can log in our site.
This lecture we will go through the entire process of creating log in and log out functionality for
users that are registered in your database.
This process involves the following main criteria we need to set up special log interviews and also
show you how you can create views for access and we can do that with built in decorator's.
So a lot of that functionality Gengel makes really easy for you.
Things like making sure certain views require a log in can all be done if a simple decorator call.
Then we also need to make sure to add in the log in your l and settings up py file.
We need to actually create the log in a page and then we want to edit the PI file to actually match
to your L mappings to our log in that age T.M..
OK let's get started.
OK here I am at my Adam text editor and the first thing we need to do to actually set up logons is to
set up our log in your l.
So we want one dedicated page for the user to log in from.
So what we're going to do is go to settings up-I and scroll all the way down on this.
So I can actually go all the way down and at the bottom we're going to do it just like we added static
or L and media are all going to add one more variable in here called loggin.
Underscore your L and set it equal to the log in page.
In our case that's going to go under the basic app folder under templates and then we'll call this user
logon.
So we will save that and file that under settings.
The next thing we can do is set up or H-2 him l files.
So coming back to that basic app we have our base studies T.M. and our logged in each T.M. and we're
going to play around of both of these.
The bassée seem to actually add in the logging and link and log out.
But for the log in each team male we can start that right away.
So first we want to actually extend.
So we will say extents and this extends from basic app slash base but HDMI will and then will call the
body block walk body block and then we also want to have an end block whenever we called it.
So we'll say and block here.
And then we're going to do is call a container.
Actually I don't believe we need to do that because the base calls a container in the body itself.
So we can go directly into a Jumbotron class and this is just going to be where the user can log in.
So it's put a header in here that says Please log in and if you're doing this on your own web site you
could add a button that takes you to the registration page that says something like register here.
We'll start our WIPs.
Let's create a form in the form we don't need to have a class for now.
And we're going to do is actually show you how you can play around the action this time.
So we're going to do is on the action a call a moral template to an ongoing passen basic app and then
user underscore logon so that your template tag is going to go to basic app user logon and this will
make more sense when we actually see in the views.
But keep it in mind for now.
We'll come back to this later.
And then with any form remember we need the CSR token type and see SRF underscore tokin and then lets
create some labels here.
So this is going to use kind of more HVM style form because we dont actually create a form for the log
in.
At least we did it in our case.
So lets create a user name and then will say user name.
So thats the label for the user name.
Hopefully it feels really familiar kind of like a blast from the past from the HCM l sections of the
course.
User name is just a text and then we'll give it the name usernames that matches up with that label and
then it doesn't need a value but we can give it a placeholder the placeholder can say enter username
and then we're going to do is create another entry for the actual passwords all say for password and
then we'll have that person type in their password there
and then we'll give it an input password.
Call it password and it doesn't need a value and it doesn't get a placeholder because it's a password
and it finally will have an input for submit.
So we'll give it the value of log in.
All right.
And this is actually basically all we're going to have in our logon page.
So a couple of things here.
We're using a lot of the HCM mail that we learned about were actually grabbing information we are importing
from the forms up-I file because it's such a basic form.
And also we're calling a form to action.
So here we're calling your RL basic app user logon and we'll show why we do that later on.
And then we're also going to be playing around with the base that H-2 him efile.
Well we're going to do is inside of the baseline.
TMF I won't do it yet.
We will come back to this later is we'll have a link that either says log in or log out depending on
if the person who has already registered is logged into your site or not but to do all of this we really
need to start focusing on the used up-I file.
And that's again where a lot of the logic is going to be taking place.
And so we're going to be doing the majority of our coding for the actual lecture.
So let's go over to used up pie in our basic app and we're going to be typing a lot here.
So be prepared for it if you ever need a reference you can always check out the notes.
So first thing we're going to do a lot of imports because we're going to be using a lot of jingoes built
in functionality so we will say from jingo contrib.
You r l resolvers going to import reverse and we'll show how to use that in just a little bit.
But then whip's this actually should not be from contrib.
This should be from core.
There we go.
So from jingled the core that your resolvers import reverse and now we're going to say from Django that
contrib a you th for authorization decorator's and I mentioned that there are a lot of decorators that
make your life a lot easier.
And one of them is called log in underscore required.
And this is basically something that's super awesome about Django if you want a view to require the
user to be logged in.
You can decorate it with this log underscore required.
And Django has a bunch of authorization decorators that really help you out like that.
The main one being loggin required.
And then we're going to do is keep things a little more simple instead of using render we use the HTP
response and we'll also do an HTP response redirect which we may not have seen before but will say from
Django HTP import HTP response redirect
comma and we'll also import HTP response wups response.
So we've already seen this guy a bunch times Fishley back in the beginning but we haven't seen a redirect
so I'll see that as well.
And then finally we'll see from Shingo that contrib the th for authorization import and then here are
the three kind of key functions which are authenticate log in and log out.
All right we can save that and now let's actually go and create our log in view for the user logon page
and then we'll show you how to use this decorator to show you.
Kind of like a simple example of sput some pages where the user log in is required.
So start off by going all the way down here under register and create a new view point to put in a bunch
of new lines here and we will collapse directory tree give us a little more room and we'll see if user
underscore loggin now pasand request and here's a quick note.
Sometimes jingoes can't complain.
If you decide to clear a view log in especially if you're importing you scroll all the way up here.
If you're importing a log in then you don't want to overwrite it here and the views file.
So make sure that the view doesn't share a name with anything you're importing.
So don't call the view authenticate log in or log out or log in required.
So here try to make it something a little more unique.
So here we're calling it user underscore logon and then this is actually going to look pretty similar
to the request as a lot of code.
Excuse me pretty similar to the registration.
Again it's a lot of code but they'll get the job done.
So I'll say request method if request method is equal to host then the user has actually filled out
the log in information.
So first thing you need to do is get the username and password supplied.
So I will grab from the request that post and I can use the get method and get the name of that.
So the reason I use the DAT get is because over in our logging Lowry's to email file We're just using
simplest DML and we call that name equals username.
So I'm going to get from that post username and then I'm going to create a variable called Password
is equal to request that postop get password and there we're going to use jingoes built in authentication
function and this makes your life really easy.
So all the work of the authentication is going to happen for you automatically.
So I'll say user authenticate and the person user name equal to user name.
And then the password equal to password.
And again sometimes jingle complains if you just passen username comma password.
So actually tell it the variable username is equal to username password Ezekial the password.
So type in what the parameters are equal to and this will basically automatically authenticate the Sezer
for you which is awesome.
One line of code.
Thank you Django.
And then if we have a user so I will say if user remember user is going to check if they're actually
right here authenticated then what I'm going to do is check the account is active.
So later on especially in the Clones We'll talk about deactivating users if they spent too much time
on the site or having them reactivate their accounts etc. in case they lost their password.
But right now I will say if I were a user so they passed the authentication process and then if the
user is active We're going to log the user in.
And that again is one simple function.
Thanks to a lot of the built in stuff Django.
We just say log in function we imported and then pass the request and then pass through the person the
user object that was returned by authenticate and then we're going to send that user back to some page.
So once they're logged in you send them somewhere.
Sometimes we'll be there own profile page to our home page et cetera and we use HTP response redirect
to redirect them to some other page and we can redirect them and call reverse on index.
And basically what this is going to do is going to do a redirect if they log in and it's successful
and their account is active.
It will reverse them and redirect them back to the home page.
And then else.
So if their account is not active will return HDP response and it won't be there will just be a response
and we'll give them something back like accounts not active.
And then on this if user call we can say else we might want to print something out just for us in the
con..
So something like someone tried to log in and failed.
Now we can also prints if you want to username.
So again this is a very simple site so you probably wouldn't want to do something so they read on your
site but I'm going to print out maybe someone malicious try to log in with a username and password but
it wasn't right.
So he could either print straight into the console or have some sort of error log and we'll talk about
logging later on in the course.
We can say something like print username password that format a username and password.
So this will be.
What they tried to log in with now is not so bad that we print it out because technically this username
and password combination isn't already in our database and they will say return and T-P response of
invalid log in details.
Supplied so else which means the request that method wasn't equal to post so they haven't actually submitted
anything.
Then we just return the actual render of the request and then the logon page which is basic slash log
in Tamil and we can passengers an empty contex dictionary if you want.
So we'll save that and then should be ready to go for user logon.
And now what I want to show you is imagine what a page would look like if you want to require the logon.
So will scroll all the way up and add two more functions here.
It's kind of up to you where you want to add these views.
And if you get over piled of views here sometimes some people separate them into different views and
then import them all here.
PERINO We're keeping things so basic that we'll just add in two more views.
These are much smaller but we want a logo.
So we'll call this E-F user underscore log out.
We don't want to call it just log out because if you notice we imported log out.
So we'll call it user underscore log on instead this takes in a request.
And what this happens is you pass on the request to that built in log out function and that automatically
logs out the user.
And then we return and HTP response redirects reverse back to the index page so pretty simple except
for one thing we want to make sure that only a user who is logged in can log out the way we have right
now is a little confusing because it doesn't actually require a user to be logged in in order to log
out.
So this would probably cause some issues and problems with the page.
And this is what's really awesome about Django in order to make sure that any view requires a person
to be logged in to see it.
All you do is decorate it with this log in required.
Now we imported.
So you say at and review the Ducrot the decorator's lecture if you don't remember how to do this but
you just call it directly above the function.
And it has to be directly.
So one line above.
So if I'm on line 16 b should be at line 15.
So here we see at log in required and now suddenly this interview has a log in required.
So let's imagine that you had some sort of special page or you wanted to return something special just
to kind of reiterate this you have some other page that requires a log in and you can say something
like return in HTP response that says you are a log then nice.
All you have to do is say in order to make sure that view requires a log in is passen log on are required
as Degrader and that's what's pretty awesome about Django the fact that authenticate log in and log
out and log in required are super easy to call.
It's just a function call for log in and log out and it's just a decorator for logging required.
And that's really what's going to save you a ton of time when you're developing your own web applications.
I know the process to actually understand how to use those takes a long time but once you understand
how to use them the process of using them definitely shortens your development cycle OK.
So views that pi should be taken care of.
Now let's go a mixture are you or else actually point to the user logon page.
So let's come back to our Uriel's in our project and scroll all the way down right now points to Addleman
basic app and then the home page index page and what we can do here is add in something for let's say
log out page and that special page we just kind of made that silly view.
So we'll do something for logo since that's actually we're going to be using and we'll say logo slash
dollar sign and we'll just say get views use or log out you know we will give it the name equal to Wargo.
And if you want to see an example of setting that special view that someone requires to be logged in
and as a practice problem if you want you can set in other HTL to go to this special page but we'll
say special slash Due's the special name is equal to special.
So that's some sort of special page that we haven't really done anything with that theoretically a user
would have to be logged in to even see this page.
OK.
So that's what the project would look like now as far as the Oreilles up file meaning that we added
is this log out page for the user log.
So let's come to our project or sooner applications or else that py file.
Right now we only have that register view.
What I want to add in is the log in view.
So we'll say your all our current user log in slashed dollar signs and then I'm going to save used user
underscore log in and we'll give it the name user underscore logon save that in our Your all pattern's
is done.
So we have something pointing to the log in page and log out page or I'm going to do before we actually
get started is come to base that HVM L and over here add in another link with some logic to have the
user either log in or log out once they've registered.
And we way we're going to do that is I'm going to zoom out just a tiny bit and also collapse character
strictly tree to get a little more room here so I can show you what I'm going to be doing.
So I want some logic to actually display one more list item which means I'm going to use template tags
so I have Django.
I have admin register and I'm going to say this
user is authenticated I make sure I spell that right.
A You authenticated.
And basically what this says is OK the user passed that authentication function that we called in the
view.
If you go back to view and scroll all the way down to the logon.
So here's user.
Right.
And then here is authenticate.
And what we're going say is if that user is authenticated then we're gonna do something here.
I'll add an A-list item to that nav bar.
It's going to be an anchor tag.
They'll have the same class.
The class will be nav bar bash link and then the ref is going to beat you.
Whoops.
Let's make sure we do this right.
A Your old templates to log out.
And if we look back at our project so under learning user we have log out here.
Its name is log out.
So that's what we're pointing to here under our template tagging so your L log out.
And then let's give it some actual text text which says log out.
Else so let's imagine that the user was not authenticated
then I'm going to say create a list item create an anchor and we'll give it the ref versus give it the
class.
It looks the same as everything else.
That's again another bar ash link.
And it's going to have an H ref of your l.
So it's another your template and it goes to the basic app and it finds the user log in view
OK so remember in the Urals PI file for application over here we named this user logon and it's under
basic app and that leads the actual user log in view that you are all mapping which means I need to
add one more line of code here and hopefully you guessed it it's the end.
If so whenever you have an if you need to have an end if and I'm not using any sort of plug ins to help
me autocomplete Django I definitely suggest those on your own computer when you're kind of developing
instead of learning.
I'm not using any here as far as Jingle plug ins because I want to manually code everything out to explain
everything on my own personal computer when I'm not teaching.
I definitely have a lot of plugins that do special autocomplete and highlighting syntax here.
OK so let's add one line of text theory that says log in and save this.
Let's run the server and see if we actually got everything to work and we'll debug if we have to say
less and then let's start typing Python managed up PI runs server enter.
And that's good news it's actually attempting to run some things so let's copy this and bring in our
browser when I'm going to do is bring that here.
And let's register a new user to make sure that still works.
And so I can actually remember how this person's going to log in.
So we will create a user name we'll call him Samie email address Sammy at gmail dot com lips g mail
com we'll give them a test password
and then their portfolio site or we can just provide one does it really matter.
We give it Google.
You can upload a picture and let's actually get some practice uploading a picture so they choose File
and let's upload a picture of the hub.
Octo cat and let's register this is thank you for registering.
That looks good.
Let's log in as an admin and verify that that person registered successfully put in your super user
name and then let's check on the user profile info there Sammy.
And here he can see they have their profile pic and they're at Google dot com for their portfolio site.
So we will log out now.
Now let's go back to the home page and let's log in as Samie So it says enter username.
We'll type in Samie and then let's enter their password test password.
And we should be redirected to the home page and no what else happened.
Now we get this changed to logo.
So I'll show you that again.
Click log out it changes to log in.
We can also have that redirect to another page if we wanted.
But then I can log in says log in and Samie says password it log in.
And now I see the log out change.
Great.
Then I can always click log out and that can redirect to some sort of thank you for visiting page.
And that's basically all there is for logging in and logging out later on in some of the clone projects
will also talk about sessions but maybe as a good exercise for you is to see if you can have a link
and create a nav bar link to the special page that we created.
So we created a view called special and linked it in the Urals but we never actually really did anything
with it.
It was just the check that someone had to be logged in to see it.
This entire process of creating users having them log in log out register and creating sessions for
each user is something we're going to explore a lot more during the Clone project so will definitely
get a lot more practice of this but hopefully solve the very basics are actually quite simple things.
Jingo.
Okay thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.