Hello everyone and welcome back to part 8 of the blog clone project.
So now we're going to continue on by filling out the rest of the templates.
Let's hop over to the editor and get started.
OK.
Here I am at the editor.
I have the base studies team l file open here and what I'm going to be doing is opening up the rest
of these team files and I can double click on them to open them up in new tabs I'm going to do that
and then and basically all of these what we're gonna be doing is extending from the blog base raised
him L. so have already here in the About page so it's collapses directory tree and put the Slyne in
all of these since we're going to be sending from baseline T.M. for all of these.
And we see as files so we don't need to put it there.
OK.
So let's start off with probably the simplest page is going to be our About page.
So in this about page is just an empty template and you can really put whatever you want here but we're
going to add in a call to the content block.
So say content and then we're going to end that block say and the block and then here you can just put
whatever you want.
Just keep things simple.
We'll have an H1 heading and I will say about this company.
Or you can say about me the pending.
That's a personal blog and then I'll say thanks for checking it out and maybe you could put in a Jumbotron
a thing etc. but we're going to do is copy and paste this real quick and grab this block call and LME
delete the end block.
And I'm also going to pace that into all the rest the aged him else to set up the actual blocks.
So we'll do that as well.
Wups and that's because we're going to be using that in essentially every single page him Al file since
that includes the nav bar itself.
So we'll do that and all of these.
OK.
So let me go across the board and save these and the next one I'm going to work on is post list.
Remember post lists is just the list the view that lists all the posts so it should be pretty simple
to work with.
We're going to do is after calling block content I'm going to create a DIV tag here called center stage
and that's going to allow me to kind of center these a little more.
And so over here and blog about C Ss I will create something as a new class called center stage where
anything inside this center stage I'll call margin left to be auto to center it as well as margin right.
And you could also just call it margin auto but this kind of just to make it a little more clear what
center stage is about.
And hopefully the name is also pretty clear but will have that this isn't necessary you don't need to
do that.
We'll just kind of be offset if you don't.
And we're going to do is have a for loop with Django template.
So say for post in or remember the default is post list whenever you were a fatalist view.
It's that name of that model underscore list and then when you have the four you've got to have the.
And the four and then we're going to do is let's create another div and we'll have this be the class
post in case we ever want to do anything with it and we'll say H-1 have a link here.
And this is going to be a moral effect let's make sure that template tag Yoro and Ill take us to the
post detail.
Page with the piquet primary key equal to post-up piquet and essentially it is going to do is add in
the temple injection here of post-Idol.
And this says OK if you are able to click on that post-Idol since it's an anchor tag it's going to take
you to that post detail where the primary key of that post detail is equal to postop Piquet or post
is being returned for Postum post list.
And then after that let's create another div and we'll give this the date class we may or may not use
it just kind of keeping us organized here and then we'll have a paragraph that says published on and
then we're going to have the date.
So I'll say post the published and then I'm going to use some template filters and remember that's basically
string functions or date time functions that are from Python and you can use them with template injections
and I'd like to use date just for some formatting here so I'll say a capital D space am y.
And note the spacing here you sometimes get errors if everything here isn't touching together.
So there's no spaces here.
And then finally what I can do is after that div I'll create one more anchor tag that links to the comments
so I'll say here you are I'll post underscore detail Piquet is equal to postop Piquet's to the exact
same thing wrote there and then I'm going to say have some comments.
Leps comments.
And then what I'm going to do is inject the comic counts so I'll say post approve underscore comments
and then what I can call for that is the kind of count attribute or count method.
So if you go back to the blog post wups page.
Basically what this is saying is if I were to click where it says comments won or comments too it would
take me back to that post detail page.
Just like clicking the title would which kind of make sense because if I click on comments I probably
want to see the detail page that actually has the list of those comments and that's it for the post
list page.
And this is essentially our home page for the Web site.
So we're all done with this now.
So let's go ahead and pretend someone clicked on it which would bring him over to the post detail page.
And this is going to be from a detail view.
So let's get started on this one.
So we're going to be probably one of the more complicated views or at least the view that has a lot
of content with it.
So we're going to create inside of this block in H-1 tag and we'll give it the class we'll give it the
class equal to will say post-Idol and then we'll say lower here.
So remember Lowder is that coloring class Sophie come back then here.
Lowder That way the actual colors change and we'll show later on a kind of a quick fix to get everything
to change color especially the highlighting which is essentially just coming back to the baseline each
symbol.
And over here you go to body you can just call class and then say loader here which is going to add
a lot more coloring effects.
Now be careful of this because you don't want to set everything to have like the background color.
So make sure this is set to color OK.
Coming back to the post the page after doing those changes.
What I'm going to do is have the heading 1 be the title of the post and then what I'm going to do is
have an if statement that says if the Post published date
I will say else and then I'll have an end.
Just to kind of set up my logic.
OK so what are we going to do if the Post published they meaning there's some sort of publication.
Then I'll create some sort of class here.
Pasand day the post day and then I'm going to inject the postop published date
else which means it's not published or going to do is say.
Else.
And have a button here.
So this button is going to be.
We'll give it a class.
So it looks nicer.
We'll say between beats and the fall.
Just one of those bootstrap classes and what it's going to link to is a button that asks you oh you
want to publish this or not because it does have a published date meaning that it passes if test it
hasn't been published yet.
So we're going to do is if you click on that publish button I'll take it to you or El to the Post
publish where your primary key is the post-primary key.
There we have it.
And then we're going to end this.
So let's save that.
And then after that once that little post-Idol is done or you have the publish button all we're gonna
do is add in a paragraph here with the class equal to post content and we'll be adding these classes
to the C S S file later on.
Some of them we won't use some of them we will.
I always think it's a good idea to add in more classes than you may need.
And then once you fill that CSSA and your website looks good you can then go Ramoo classes but it's
really helpful for organizations have these classes here whether or not you're going to use them right
away.
And what's going to be here is going to have the post title and then we're going to have a safe on it.
And basically what safe does is since we're going to be using that medium javascript editor if we select
something as bold we won't want it to show up.
For instance in the Web site looking like this like oh bold text with the tags.
So if I don't have safe here and I've affected it using the medium editor it's going to look like this
included the tags if I have save that it's going to translate that is T.M. to actually look like we
expect it to look.
And if that doesn't really make sense you can basically just take off safe here and they'll immediately
make sense as far as what I'm trying to convey.
And then we're going to do is call one more says line breaks B.R. which essentially there's a line break.
The team Elbel so-called break there.
And then we're going to have another statement that's going to check that the user's authenticator not
souls.
If user is authenticated we're going to do some stuff.
But as always if you've got to END-IF so to create some new lines here.
So these are authenticated.
We should probably have something or let's say a two buttons one to edit the post in one to remove the
post.
So the first line is going to be an anchor tag and we'll give it a class
and the class is going to be a primary button.
So say between space between primary
and then we'll your L posts underscore it will pass and the primary key is equal to the post-primary
keygen.
Just as we them before and then we're also going to inserts inside of this icon.
So let's do that.
We'll use a span tag for that will say span and we just have to give it a class.
So the class we're going to say is this glyph icon or Cliffie Econ. the penny how you pronounce it.
And then another glyph icon
Pensil.
So that's going to look like a little pencil.
So in case you want to actually edit the post you click on the pencil icon then I'm going to copy this
and let's do another one for removing the post.
So instead of it it will take you to post remove and then instead of a pencil glyph icon sort of we're
going to just say remove which is a little X..
OK.
So that's all we need to do there.
Let's continue on song.
Kind of a separator here.
I'll say actually you can do a horizontal break there.
Or horizontal row and then we're going to say is have a class here and let's have a button that allows
us to add comments.
So I'll say this is an H ref that takes it to your L that is add comment to post with the primary key
being equal to the post-primary key.
Let's actually get the bootstrap class.
It looks nice.
We can say something like between beats and primary wups
PTEN comments.
So if we ever want to do stuff we can add it to that and then coming over to the right we have add comments.
Post and let's have some actual something in this link that says like add comments.
So we'll save that and then I'm going to put everything else here inside of a container class.
Everything that's left and basically inside this container is going to be the list of the comments.
So I'll say for comments in postop comments.
All and because I have this I want to and for.
So it's now well say and for and that after that we're going to do is absolutely close that in we're
going to end up doing is saying this.
So for every comma and post-doc comments I'm going to add in the break that we've got a little bit of
space and then another check of the user's authenticated or at the comma is an approved comment.
Otherwise I don't really want to display it.
So I'm going to say if the user is authenticated
or the comments isn't approved comments going back with that model and since I have an if statement
it's a good idea to just take care of the END-IF right now.
I'm going to pass in the comments created day so let's inject that in a comment.
Created underscore dates and they want to do is say if nots comments prove prove underscore comments
all have two buttons here.
One to remove the comment and then one to approve the comment.
This is going to be really similar to what I have here.
So it's going to copy and paste these
and let's line these up.
So I need to add this.
So here at the end this tab these and so they look a little more clear.
And I like to paste isn't.
So let me give this one more here and it's copy and paste this one more time.
And then here will have remove but instead of a post remove it's going to be a comments remove and a
sort of a poster to move here or actually you can just say this is comments or move instead.
So at the top on the comment remove So comment remove Piquet is the comments
primary key and then this Spanish class will just have it be removed so that stays the same and we can
have this being said of a primary button the default button and then the second one is going to be in
approval.
So instead of saying Kamens remove all change it common to prove so common to prove and the piquet does
need to be.
Comments.
Piquet's well and then the other one is going to have to be Cliffie Khan and you can really choose any
clip icons you want but we'll just say OK.
All right.
So a little if statement to kind of check everything's OK as far as what buttons we show.
And then below that I'm going to actually add in the information with some paragraph tags where I will
say put in the actual text of the comments.
Pass it through Safe case to use any special T.M. and then say line breaks so that we actually take
care of new line breaks and below that we'll add in one more paragraph tag or this paragraph tag is
going to say who is posted by.
So I posted my.
And then going to inject the comments author and we can passen as bold if we want but that's it.
And then what we can do is in between this and if this and for have a template tag to check if something's
empty meaning if there was nothing in the post comments at all.
We'll just say ok.
Empty.
And then it's a nice easy tag call for if this is empty what you can post in this case will say no comments.
OK so this was definitely one of the most complicated views we had to do throughout the entire project
so let's quickly go over it.
And if you want to actually reference any of this I'd highly recommend the kind of just copy and paste
from the notes provided to make sure everything matches because there's a lot of stuff we could have
possibly gone wrong here.
But essentially all we're doing is we're saying OK put in the post title if the Post has a publication
date.
Start the post date and then actually place it the publication date.
Else we're going to have a button here that says hey do you want to publish this.
And they'll take it to the Post publish page after that you have the actual post content which you start
off with just the post title.
Make sure it's safe and then have the line breaks if these are authenticated.
There are going to be able to edit the post or remove the post.
So that's what this block of code is doing.
Below that we're going to be able to add comments to the post.
And in this case we have this container for all the comments that are released to that post because
we are postop.
OK.
If the user is authenticated or the comments and approved comments we're going to show the creation
date.
If the comma is not an approved comment so I'm logged then I should still be able to see these comments
but they're not approved.
I can either remove the comments or give it the OK that it's been approved.
And then once that's done we're going to show the common text safe with line breaks and then show who
actually posted that comment.
So that's actually all this post the tail is doing.
So lots of code.
But the idea is pretty straightforward.
OK.
We'll continue on this in the next lecture.
We go the other templates.
Thanks and I'll see you there.