Welcome to partake of the social cloning project now we're going to do is connect the views that we've
already created in groups to some murals.
We still have two more views to create in the group's application but we'll worry about those later
on.
Right now we're just going to connect the user created to some Urals and we're also going to register
the group models that we previously created to the admin that PI file.
Let's hop over to Adam and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the text editor I have the model's views and the various templates are created.
What I want to do now is go to your not pie.
This is the groups your URLs up py file and here's where I'm going to basically connect all the views
I just made.
So we will say from Django figuration your Elle's import your L and then I'm also going to save from
Daut import views to actually access the views we just created specifically those class based views
and then we'll get this app name group so we can reference it later on with your template tagging.
Now I'm going to make a list of your all patterns and we're going to say the first pattern is just going
to be the very basic groups page and that will be the list groups page.
So we'll actually just call it carot dollar sign.
So when someone actually goes to your Web site dot com slash groups it shows you the list of all the
groups so say views list groups start as a view and then we'll give the name we can just keep it all
and then we're also going to say your L and for this one this is going to be the Create page so you
can either call it slash create or call it slash new and then we're going to say views and that will
be the create group as a view.
And then we'll see name is create
it will create in other Euro function this is going to be for the actual detail view and it is going
to be a little more complicated.
We're going to do is say PPOs slash and slash and then this will actually be the group and we're going
to use regular expressions to plug in the slug there.
So it goes.
Question mark capital P and then open tag close tag with slug.
And then in brackets here we'll say minus backslash.
There'll be you know we'll say plus And after all of that forward slash dollar sign and Bisco it's just
going to say post in and then it's going to slug ify the actual group name and then that will lead to
the actual single group there.
So there will be views dots and we called that single group will say as a view and we'll give the name
and collapses this we get a little more room which is called This single and save we still have two
more Uriel's and two more views to make about Leni leaving and joining groups.
But right now we don't really worry about them we'll take care of that when we actually create those
views blessing.
I want to do in this particular lecture is assigned the admin file for the models created so remember
previously we created the group model as well as the group member model.
So let's set that up in our admin that pie going to open that up and then go to Evan that pie from jingo.
And then I also want to say from datt import models.
So I want to register these models with the abdomen and I will say Adam in site thought register and
then I just passen models group and then the other thing I want to do is a little special with a tabular
inline and the inline class that we're going to be using basically allows us to utilize the admin interface
and or Gengel Web site with the ability to edit models on the same page as the parent model.
So our group member basically has a bit of a parent model with group and what we can do is we can use
a tabular inline class so that when we visit the admin page I can click on group and then see the group
members and edit those as well.
So let's see how we can do that.
All I need to do is say class group member and then I'm going to say in line then I call in tabular
in line and then I just do the assignment of model is equal to models group member and then I don't
actually have to register it because now the group member model is in line here and we'll see what that
looks like with more detail when we actually it is the Adamant site and that's all we're going to do
for this lecture.
Just connecting the views we've previously created in our Urals the py file which you can reference
in the notes as well as set up our registration for the models so the group model is just typical registration.
And then here we did a type inline which you're going to see later on when we actually visit the admin
page.
OK.
So much shorter than the last one.
So take your time with this.
Definitely a lot of stuff to type out and you can always copy and paste from the notes.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.