Have you ever wanted to create your own search engine? a platform that could rival the biggest names
on the web, like Google or Bing with Next.js 13 and Tailwind CSS
You have all the tools you need to create your own search engine that can search the web and images
and even show the user's country in the footer.
Next JS 13 is a powerful React framework that makes building fast and dynamic web applications easier
than ever.
And with Tailwind CSS, you can easily create beautiful and responsive user interfaces with next JS
13 and tailwind CSS.
You can create a search engine that looks and works just like Google with the added ability to search
for images.
In addition, you can even show the user's country in the footer of your search engine, giving users
a more personalized experience.
Next.JS 13 introduced the app Router, which uses new file conventions to easily create pages, shared
layouts and templates.
With this approach, you can organize your code in a way that is easy to understand and maintain.
Making it simple to scale your search engine as needed.
Next.JS 13 also introduced a new way to fetch and manage data in your application.
The new data fetching system works in the app directory and is built on top of the Fetch web API.
With this new system you can easily fetch data and manage it within your application without having
to worry about complex data management.
But that's not all.
Next.js 13 also introduced a new file convention loading.js to help you create a meaningful loading
UI.
With this convention you can show an instant loading state from the server while the content of a root
segment loads, the new content is automatically swapped in once rendering is complete, giving your
users a smooth and seamless experience.
You can also create an error UI by adding an error JS file inside a root segment which allows you to
gracefully handle runtime errors in nested routes using next JS 13 and tailwind CSS.
You can easily build your own search engine that can handle millions of users with fast and efficient
data fetching and meaningful loading UI.
So what are you waiting for?
Start building your own search engine today with next JS 13 and tailwind CSS and learn all the new features
introduced by next JS 13 with a hands on project.