Welcome to the project.
In this project, we're going to create an IMDB clone.
As you can see from the final version of the project, we have a header nav bar and the results section.
And also, we can catch the trending and top rated from the database you're going to use next js to
create this project. Next.js is a react framework for production.
And it's going to help us to create SEO friendly websites. in order to style the project.
We we're going to use the Tailwind CSS.
Tailwind CSS helps us to rapidly build our website, even without leaving our JSX files. For getting
the icons of our websites.
We're going to use a website called Hero Icons, which is created by the owners of the Tailwind CSS.
And also, we are going to use movie database TMDB to get the information about the movies.
And also, we're going to learn how to get their API keys.
Finally, we're going to deploy the website into the Vercel, which is completely free, and also we're
going to learn how to create our custom URL.
The complete source code of the project is available inside this repository, and the link will be available
for you in the resource section.
Also, you can access for the final version of the project in this URL.
In the next section, we're going to briefly overview the website, so see in the next section.