Welcome to the project.
In this project, we're going to create an Instagram clone using next js.
And Tailwind CSS.
As you can see from the final version of the project, we have two parts in the homepage, including
the header and feed section.
The header includes the Instagram logo, the search bar, and also the menu with the sign in link.
We can authenticate the users here.
Once we click on the sign in link.
We are going to be redirected to a custom sign in page here.
We can click on the sign in with Google Button.
And on the next page we can choose our desired Gmail account.
For example, I choose this one.
Once you're signing with the Google account, a session would be started and the picture of the user
would be shown in the upper right corner of the website, inside the mini profile, and also at the
beginning of this story section.
Also, we have the ability to like and leave a comment with this account.
Here on the top right corner, we see an icon, which is for creating a new post by clicking on this
icon.
A modal is going to pop up.
We are going to use React modal package to create this model.
Here we can click on the camera icon to upload an image.
For example, I choose an image from my desktop here.
Once we choose the image, we can see the preview of the image instead of the camera icon.
We can add a caption here.
For example, I say next js.
In this project, we're going to learn how to use Firebase for storage and database.
By clicking on the upload post, we are going to upload the image into the Firebase Storage first.
Then a new document is going to be created inside the post collection of the Firebase database.
You're going to learn how to interact with Firebase a step by step inside the project.
The post that we have created is at the beginning of the feed section.
Now each post has a header here.
An image.
Buttons.
Caption comments and input box.
Each person can only like a post once.
The number of likes is shown here.
If the post has more than one like.
Also the user can leave a comment here.
The comments and links are also recorded in the Firebase database and it's going to be fetch.
Each time the database is change using useEffect react hook.
For example, I write here.
Nice.
I press enter.
Once I press enter.
The comments would be appeared here in real time.
If you sign in with another account, we can like the post and change the number of lives into two likes.
Let me change the user real quick by clicking on sign out.
I can sign out from my account.
I click on signing again.
And here I, I can choose my another Gmail account.
I chose this one instead quote with hand.
Now if I like to pose the number of like would be two likes.
Let me leave a comment as well.
For example, I say amazing.
Always the new comment goes.
At the beginning of the comments section.
On the right side we have miniprofile which includes the user image and the user name which are
coming from Google and the user data inside.
This suggestion here and also inside this story section are created using minifaker.js package
all the website is styled using only Tailwind CSS version 3.0.
The entire source code is available in this repository, which you can find inside the resource section.
You can also have a preview of the project from this URL here.
insta-v4.100jsprojects.com
In the next section we're going to install next js and Tailwind CSS and create the beginning template.
So here in the next section.