Welcome to the project.
In this project, we're going to create a Twitter clone using Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and Firebase.
You're going to use Next.js version 12.
Tailwind
CSS
Version 3.0 and Firebase version 9 inside our project.
As you can see from the final version of the project, we have three parts in the homepage, including
the sidebar, widgets, and the feed sections.
The sidebar includes the menu and the sign in button.
We're going to use the next-auth package along with Google OAuth for authentication.
Once we click on the sign in button.
You're going to be redirected to a custom sign in page here.
We can click on the sign in with Google Button.
And on the next page we can choose our desired Gmail accounts.
For example, I choose this one.
Once we are signed in with a Google account, a session would be started and the picture of the user would
be shown under the menu here and also at the input section here.
Now we can post a new tweet.
Also, we have the ability to like and leave a comment with this account here.
Inside the input section, we can write our tweet with an image.
For example, I just write a new tweet.
And add a new image by clicking on this icon.
For example, I choose this image.
Once we choose the image, we can see the preview of the image here.
By clicking on the tweet icon, we are going to upload the image into the Firebase Storage first.
Then a new document is going to be created inside the "posts" collection of the Firebase database, which
is in our case Firestore.
We are going to learn how to interact with Firestore, including the CRUD operations, a step by
step inside the project.
The post that we have created is going to be shown at the beginning of the feed section.
Each post has a header and image and buttons.
Each person can only like the post once.
And delete its own post here.
The number of likes is shown here.
If the post has more than one like.
Also the user can leave a comment on any post by clicking on the chat icon by clicking on this icon.
A modal is going to pop up.
We are going to use react-modal package to create this modal.
Comments and likes are also recorded in the Firestore and they are going to be fetch each time the
database is changed using the useEffect react hook.
Let me leave a comment here, for example.
I say thank you.
And I press reply.
Once you press on the reply, you're going to be redirected to the page specifically created for the
post.
So each post has its own page and comments of the posts are shown here.
Each comments can be liked and also can be deleted by the owner of the comment like this.
And you can also click on this icon to come back to the homepage.
On the right side, we have the widget which includes the search bar, the What's Happening section
and also who to follow section.
These news titles inside the What's Happening sections are dynamic and real and coming from a news API.
By clicking on the show more button, we can see three more news titles each time.
These users inside the Who to Follow section are also created using a user generator API and by clicking
on to show more link, we can also see three more users each time.
All the website is are styled using only Tailwind CSS version 3.0 and the entire source code is
available inside this GitHub repository, which you can find inside the resource section.
You can also have a preview of the project from this URL, twitter.100jsprojects.com
in the next section we are going to install Next.js and Tailwind CSS and create the beginning template.
So see you in the next section.