All right.
In the last section, we have completed the search box.
In this section, we're going to create the search options.
The other things we have here is important because this is very similar to the search box.
As we have interaction with the users, we need to create these section client side.
So we have already created this part.
If we just close everything here and then we go to the Explorer section, we go to search header options.
We have already created this component.
We need to complete it and put it inside our website.
So the first thing I want to add here is to inside this debate we're going to have.
Another div four the each section.
So each of these places is the diff, including an icon and a text and this one as well.
So we're going to have another diff here.
And inside this tab we're going to have the icon and the text.
So the icon I want to use for the first one is the search icon, which is I.
Outline search.
We have already used this one before.
Which is coming from React icons for slash I.
So I'm going to close this one and the text for this one is going to be.
All.
So let's see.
We can see it inside our website.
So let's refresh the page.
Now we see the icon here.
I will show you this icon and this all we need to style it as the styling are very similar between the
two places I'm going to first style the first one.
And again, we can copy and use it for this second one.
So now for the.
This icon we just make it takes AMD, which is a text medium.
And for this all that is fine for the dev that is covering it.
We're going to first make it flex.
So we bring them next to each other and then we can use item center.
So we can just bring them and.
Vertically.
Next to each other, we can add some space between them.
Let me bring them here so we can see the changes in real time.
Let's close the left side.
So let's decrease the size here.
Kick.
So after the item center, I want to add some space between them using a space X and this is going to
be a space x one.
Just add a little bit of space between them.
And after that, we want to have some broader at a bottom
of four.
As you can see, the border.
But this border is going to be kind of limited.
But let's first continue and make it.
First, I want to set the colour of the border to be transparent.
The reason I'm doing that, because I don't want to see the border now.
But when we click on this icon, or if this is where I want to see the border, border blue.
And when we click on it, also when we click on which is active, I want to change the text to be blue
500.
So here when we click on it, we see the change in the color.
You see it becomes blue.
So this is kind of a sense for this users that they have clicked and let's set the cursor to be pointer.
So when we hover over it, we see a pointing hand like this and let's add some padding in the bottom
of three, some padding in the x axis of.
True.
K now.
But we want to make this one and.
Dynamic.
So we based on the search term that we see at a top or we're actually not searched based on this web
for slideshow and a search for the search web or forward slash image, We want to make this one active
or active.
So first thing first, we need to change this font to use client, because this is a client side.
We want to make it interactive.
So we must just make it client side and then we want to input something called.
And use path name.
So we want to import
use path name from next forward slash navigation.
And also we want to initialize it here.
So we're going to say path name is equal to use path name.
So we have initialize it here.
Now we can just make it dynamic.
So here, instead of just adding it like a static using the double clone, I'm going to add a curly
braces at the beginning and at the end.
I want to change this clone to a back tick, which makes us gives us the ability to add some variable
here and after here.
After this padding x two, we can add a variable using dollar sign.
A set of curly braces.
And we just say if the path name is equal to forward slash search for slash web.
If this one happens, if this condition is true.
We want to the text to be blue.
600.
And border bottom or border color to be blue?
600 as well.
As you can see now, we see this is blue and the text is blue.
The border is blue as well.
But if this search forward slash web, we change it to image.
For example, we press enter.
We shouldn't see the colors to be blue or.
And if you just see it normally, let's change it to web.
We see it blue, but sometimes this one doesn't work.
I don't know why.
So we need to.
It's.
I think it's a kind of block for tailbacks.
There.
I think I found a solution.
It's.
You just need to after this condition to make it important.
So you need to add a question mark.
So if this is this condition happens, you want to make this one important.
So make sure to add this one.
So sometimes I see that doesn't work in some browsers, so it's better to make it important.
So I always use this as styling instead of the normal styling.
So we have just created this part.
The other things we need to do here inside this, we want to add a event listener.
So when we click on this font, we want to change the URL as well.
So for example, if we are in the image.
Okay.
We don't see the blue line.
It's not selected when we click on it.
We want to change the URL as well, so we need to add an event listener Sorry, click event listener
which is going to trigger a function.
And this function is going to be.
Dynamic as well.
And this is going to push the person to that URL with the search term and also be deep web inside the
path name.
So here, here at this div, we're going to add an n click event listener.
This uncle event listener is going to trigger a function, but we want to add some.
Parameters as well.
So we're going to call the function select.
Tap.
And we want to pass this lip.
Or we just say all.
For example, this is for all.
So we're going to pass this all.
And we create this function at the top.
So we create a function called.
Select tab.
This is a we get the suggestion.
We we create a function called select tab, which is going to get.
This.
Name, which is a tap name, or we can just call it, for example, title or whatever.
This is actually this suggestion is for JavaScript, but for next year we're going to do a different
way.
So we're going to use just the router dot push.
So we need to just import the use router at the top.
And here, if we just just say router and we need to initialize it first, we initialize the router
here and then we just say router.
That push and we're going to push the person to this tab.
But we don't want this tab, actually.
We don't want to redirect them to search for slash, for example, or we want to redirect them conditionally.
We just say if the tab is equal to all.
Okay.
If this one happens, we want to use whip.
Otherwise.
Or we can make it this way.
We can just say if this one is images.
Like this.
If this one is images, make this one image.
Otherwise, make it web because anything else can be whipped.
Our default will be whip.
So now this one is going to redirect us to this year.
But actually, we don't have that search term.
We need that search term, too.
So we need to import something else as well, which is used search params here.
So I'm going to import use search params and I'm going to initialize it here and I want to get this
search term.
Which is going to be equal to this search for that get that search term.
So we get the search term and added at the end of this here.
So.
This one.
So we need to add some thing.
I think we missed some.
A dark curly braces here.
This is for.
The ads.
The dollar sign is open, but I didn't close it.
Let's close this one here.
So after that, we're going to add the search term.
So I'm going to add a question mark.
Search term and the search term is coming from here.
So we're going to redirect the person to forward slash search for a slash can be image or web and search
term, which is already inside the URL.
So now if you look at here we are in the first slash search, first slash image search term.
Hello.
And if you click on this icon, this is going to redirect us to forward slash web instead of image and
then search term.
Hello.
And also we have this selected to be blue color as well.
Okay.
So we have added this interactivity in our this part.
So I'm going to just copy this one and change it to B for the image as well.
So because because this is very similar.
So we need to just copy this div using alt shift error done.
And we're going to add we can just change this on click to be instead of all to be images.
This is should be similar to this images capital, K and uppercase.
And then, sorry, capitalized and then we just change it here.
If the path name is equal to search for slash image, this one is going to be active.
The text inside is going to be images.
All right.
And instead of this icon, which is the I earth aligned search, we're going to use a i r line camera.
And we need to import it as well.
So we have imported two icons from this.
As you can see, we have all we have the image.
If we click here we are in the web.
Now we are in the web.
When we click on Image, we should go to forward slash image.
And this one is selected.
Okay, It's working.
Now we want to style this one and make them bring them next to each other and make them some smaller.
So inside the div that is coloring both of them here we're going to add some styling.
First thing first, I want to make them flex so they come next to each other like that.
I want to add a space between them just using a space X to.
And then as you can see, and then you can see we are select when we select them, we see the cursor
here moving that indicator.
So I'm going to remove that one using select non.
And then.
Let's add some border for both of them.
So border bottom.
F four.
Fit the size four.
But see.
Actually the size.
Just the one is enough.
And then.
Now you can see the border now.
Just the size of one is okay.
After the border, we're going to add.
So we set the width to be full your 100%.
And then you can use justify center to bring them to the center in the mobile size.
I want them to be in the center like this.
But in the larger side, like the LG and above, I want them to be at the beginning.
So just say justify.
It starts.
So they are going to be at the beginning in the large size, but in the small size, they are going
to be at the middle.
And in the large size and above, I want the padding in the left of 52 for them.
Let's see.
Okay.
And then we can just change the color of these texts instead of to be too much black.
I want them to be.
Gray, for example, 700.
We make the text to be as small.
But that.
I think that's enough for this styling of this section.
This is if you remove the zoom level, that is okay.
As you can see, we are changing the page image, search page, and also we go to web search page.
So this is working fine.
And also the styling looks okay.
That was it for this section.
Let's go and add this one to GitHub using contour shift G, we add everything here.
Let's make a message for that one saying complete.
The surge.
Heather.
Options.
And we're going to commit and push it to GitHub.
Let's review what we have done.
We just click here to go back and now we have 11 commits in our GitHub repository.
The last one is complete the search filter options.
And then as you can see, we have created this page.
We have updated this search header components option.
We have created that one to be used a client side because we are using some hooks and there's some piece
of we don't have.
We have some folks here like use path name, we use router or use search params.
And also we have some event listener like on click.
All right.
So we have imported two icons from React Icons.
I.
Uh, first thing first, we have imported these hooks from next navigation, and then we have initialized
them.
We got the search term from the URL using search params dot git.
We've got the search term.
We have created a function which is going to redirect the person based on the tab, the clicking on
the tab, which is which can be.
Forward slash search, forward, slash whip or image based on the day click they do.
And also we have the search term, which is going to be at the end of the URL.
We have created two div, including two icons and to text all and images each of them they have on click
event listener, which is going to call a function called set tab, but with different
parameter here.
We pass the props like this and then we have a dynamic styling which is going to be different when we
have a.
Path name forward slash web.
Make this icon and the border bottom to be blue.
Otherwise, we do the other one which has the image and also the other one has the event listener,
which when we click, they're going to select the tab with the images here.
All right.
That was it for creating and updating the search header options in the next section, we're going to
actually work and get the Google API credentials and then we're going to fetch data from the Google
API.
And show the titles inside the our website.
So see you in the next section for this part of our project.