Alright.
In the last section we have completed the WHO to follow sections.
And we completed the major section.
Now.
Now it's time to start with the authentication part.
In order to do the authentication bill, we need to install a package called NICS off.
And let's go to.
Let's open a new tab and research for next off.
As you can see, Nick's authority is authentication for next year and the website is next.
Off list.
Dash off, don't start or G.
We click on this website.
And, uh, we click on Get Started.
First for installation.
If you want to install the last version, you need to go here on the left side.
On the upgrade guide version for.
And if you can see here now, we need to just.
Use an install next off.
So we copy this and we go back to Visual Studio code and inside a terminal we paste the code.
The next step.
If we come back to the documentation and we go to getting a start, that part on the left side.
We need to create a file inside pages api off next 30th.
This is the file we need to create and we need to create this folder as well and we need to copy this
code inside that fire.
So we copy this and we go back to Visual Studio code and inside Pages API.
We need to create a folder and the folder is off and inside the folder.
We create a file and we call it Dot, dot, dot.
Next off.
Dargis.
Sorry that.
J.S. And we paste the code that we have copied from the website here.
So let me explain this a little bit.
So we importing index off from next off and we're getting the GitHub provider from this link.
Actually, we don't need the GitHub.
We are going to use the Google provider.
So here we can change all the GitHub to Google by using contra d to choose all of them and we change
it by Google.
This Google should be lowercase.
And here.
We are exporting the providers here and the global provider just we need to get the client idea and
client secure.
So here we are using environmental variable to pass the data from there.
For this idea instead of Google idea, let's use Google client.
All right.
And make this Google.
Capital or uppercase.
Uh, this one, too.
And this one should be Google client secrets.
Okay.
Now we need to get this Google client idea and client client secrets.
So we just need to go to Firebase.
I use this for Fox because I need to be signing in my Gmail.
You two, you need to sign in with your valid Gmail account to create the firebase.
So here we search for fire base.
And uh, we click on Firebase start google dot com.
Make sure you're signing with your Gmail and see your image here and then go to console.
I already created, uh, I created a Twitter version to it and three for my practice.
Let's create another one.
And I call it for myself.
Uh.
Sorry.
Uh, Twitter version for.
They press continue.
Uh, Firebase is asking me, do you need Google Analytics?
We just disable it.
And for now, we don't need it for now.
We create we click on Create Project.
It's it's going to take a few minutes to be created and it's going to initialize and create our application
inside Google Firebase Console.
It's almost there.
It's finished.
So we just press continue.
Now.
We need to go.
We need to.
We are inside to, uh, to television for we go to authentication.
And we click on Get Started.
So first we need to actually initialize our app.
So let me go to setting, progess setting.
And here, as you can see, there is no app in the project.
There are no apps in your project.
You need to click here because this is for Web.
This is for iOS and Android.
Click here to create the app.
We named it app.
I name it's Twitter.
Version four.
And we click register app.
Now.
And Firebase is providing us with the API keys and etc. and asking us to install Firebase.
So we need to copy this code and we go back to Visual Studio code and inside terminal.
We installed the firebase.
And we need to create a file outside in this level.
And we call it Fire Bass.
That's.
And what we do here, we just go back to Firebase and we copy this code.
And we go we come back and paste it here.
Okay.
The things we need to do is to initialize Firebase.
This is actually a basic code and we need to add some other things because we need to add a storage.
As well and the storage and fire a store to our application.
So we need to initialize them as well.
So here at the time we were going to do an import to more things from Firebase app.
The first one is get app.
And the second one is get apps.
Then also we need to import.
Get fires or.
This is going to be from fire.
A store fire based fire forest slash fire store.
And let's copy this.
And here, instead of gift fire this store, we just write a storage.
And the storage is from fire bass forest storage.
Okay.
After this initialization of five x config.
So this is just basic.
But this fun each time initialize the firebase.
But we want to limit this and say if the app is already initialized, just use that one and don't do
it again.
So we make it conditional so we just seconds.
App is equal.
To get apps.
They're at length.
So if the.
There's no application.
So means that there's no nothing in the in there.
Just create this.
Uh, if this one happens.
So initialize this country.
Otherwise.
Just get the app that is already existed like this.
And then for initialization of the our.
Database we just said DB equals to five get virus or.
Photo storage.
We just say get a storage and finally we need to export.
All of the.
App DP and a storage.
That's it.
This is for initialization.
And in order to, uh, you know, to prevent your API keys to be in public, we can use environmental
variable as well.
So we we can just here create a file called that in that locale.
And we bring this instead of just saying, for example, API key.
We can just say.
Process that EMV that firebase API key and we bring this fun inside the.
Uh, environmental here.
We just need to say.
Next.
Public.
Underline fire.
A.
API.
Key.
And this is going to be equal to the API key that we just copied.
Now nobody can have access to it.
When we push our get up to.
Uh.
Get, huh?
And because, uh, this file never goes inside.
Get GitHub.
So now you can do it for all of them.
Just for simplicity.
I just did it for first.
While that is the most important one, then we need to bring the Google API.
And who will Christ ID that we the we have here too.
So inside the our application we just get all of them inside were firebase.
Let's go to council again and now we go to authentication.
We go to sign signing method and we choose Google here.
We enable Google.
We choose our email here.
We press safe?
Okay.
Now, if we can have to our API key the x axis, it's here.
So we just need to click here on edit.
And just inside the.
Web SDK configuration.
We have the web client idea and web client secrets.
We just need to copy this.
And we go to.
Visual Studio code, an environmental variable file, and here we're going to create a Google.
Client I.D. First they pasted.
And then we copy this with client I.D..
Here we create Google client secret.
And this is going to be equal to this one.
Now.
We have successfully installed firebase and nex next off.
I think that's enough for this section.
In the next section we're going to create the sign in page.
We're going to create a custom signing page and when the person wants to sign in, goes to that page.
And if the signing is successful, they will be redirected to the website.
So let's add it.
Let's add this together as usual.
We just say you create a comment with a message of.
In store next off.
And Firebase.
And initialize.
If fire breaks.
Okay.
We push it to get top.
I want to show you now that.
We didn't.
So if you refresh the page here now, we should see a new comment install next off on Firebase and initialize
the firebase.
As you can see, the person who is checking our website in GitHub cannot see the API key.
They just see posts that envy Firebase API key because GitHub never we never push the environmental
variable fire.
And also when we deploy our website to for example, we also.
Those websites have a section for environmental kids and they're going to protect our keys as well.
So we created the five stages when we initialized the fire.
So fire storage and the database we installed.
We have installed firebase and Nex off and also we have we have created this file inside the pages API
off and we provided the Google.
And we've got the Google and client identical client secrets from the Firebase website.
So in the next section, we're going to create this signing page.
So see in the next section.