All right.
In the last six years, we have installed Nicks off and Firebase and we've got two API key for the firebase
and also the Google credentials.
In this section, we're going to complete the signing page of our project.
I only have, uh, I only made one mistake last with you.
We can fix it quickly.
This way.
Here, inside the Firebase touch is.
For API key view wrote process start and be firebase API key.
But in India environmental variable we added the next public, but we forgot to add the next public
here as well.
Next public is added because if you don't do it, you're going to get an error when you're deploying
your side in production.
Mode and you're going to definitely get an error.
But in deployment or in development mode, maybe it's fine and you don't get any error.
Okay.
Let's continue and create our signing page by default.
Next off has a signing page by itself, but we want to create our own custom.
Signy page, so we should define it inside the next off thought.
Jesus.
So here, just after the providers, we can add the pages as well.
And here we just say this signing page.
You can write it like this or this way does not matter.
But the.
No, I think you should right here.
But here when you're defining the name of folks like signing.
You can add the hyphen here.
That's fine.
But you just leave it like this.
And now we inside the pages, we close everything.
Inside pages, we create a folder called off.
And inside this folder, we are going to create a page.
Call Signing Day at J.S..
We can use r, f, c to create a react functional component.
And, uh, let's bring it inside.
Uh.
We don't need to do anything, actually.
And the.
We can just visited now I think where let's start a server using NPN and rendezvous.
And let's open it inside.
The Chrome.
Okay.
Our page is loaded.
Now we can go to the page that we have created, which is for slash offering.
Slash sign.
Yeah.
You can see the pages created.
Now we need to continue at the complete this page.
So here inside this div.
Now, first of all, we need to get the providers.
As here we we we got the providers here from Google.
So we can get this providers using a building function from next off called get providers, but we can
use the server side rendering to do it.
And it's going to be very fast.
So here we just export.
It's in synchronous function because the get provide this function brings us a promise.
And so insulin a function.
And we just get server side prompts.
And inside this function, we're going to get the providers.
From.
Kit providers.
And we need to import this.
So let me import it at a top.
Just read the latest imports react from react.
We don't need it and we just need to import.
Get.
Providers.
From.
Knicks forward slash react.
And then we need to return it to pass it to our clients.
This is a server side.
This is a client side.
So we just return.
Props.
And the props.
We want to return is provider.
Now we can get this one inside our client's side as a props and restructure it like this.
Okay.
So inside this div first I want to add some image.
So let's search for an image.
Let me bring this one to the left and you can see our.
Page on the right side.
Its search for.
You know, Twitter.
And for images I want to image with phone.
But I wanted to be transparent.
So for tools, I go inside color and choose transparent.
This one or this one would be fine.
I just chose this one.
And then we right click on it and we click on copy image address and we pasted here.
And the alternative is to either.
Image.
Inside a phone.
Right now we see the image here.
After the image.
That's additive.
And inside this stair we're going to now we can loop through the providers because this provider is
not only one.
Depends on the number of providers.
For example, in next off we can add many providers like Google Gear, Top Facebook and etc..
So we have to loop through it.
So we just.
And a curly braces.
And inside this one we get the value of the providers using object.
That value.
Values and.
We passed the providers.
And now we can map through it.
It was just a map and we get each provider here.
Now we can return.
Directly.
And here we create another div.
And inside that there, I want to add some Twitter image.
We are going at the same image we have in our sidebar.
So we go to the sidebar dots and we copy this image from there.
And we go back to signing that.
Yes.
Piece pasted you.
We should see an image here as well.
This alternative for this one is just Twitter logo.
Okay.
After this image, I'm going to add some.
I'm going to add some paragraph.
Wow.
I just want to say this at.
It's created.
For.
Learning purposes.
The reason I'm adding this one, because we want to tell the official Twitter owners when they accidentally
visit our website that this is just for.
Learning purposes and this is not a copy or we didn't try to
do the copywriting or something like that.
So.
So we have that on.
After this paragraph, we add a button.
And that button is just say sign in.
But, uh, with the provider name.
So we should make like this.
You just say provider dot nay.
And we should see something.
Right there.
So I fixed this.
Let's see.
Yeah.
We're getting signing with Google.
Let me bring it.
Upper level best you can see you're signing with Google.
So that is correct.
And.
No.
I mean, we clearly nothing happens, but we when we click, we should be redirected to another page
to choose our G-mail account.
But first, let's star lists and then we do that functionality.
So for the above there.
Let's add a class now and you change the display to flags and we bring them next to each other and they're
like this.
But I don't want to see this image when we have a mobile size.
Uh.
We can do this one.
We just add a class name to the image and we make it hidden.
Now we don't see it.
But when?
The size is bigger than medium size.
I wanted to be in line.
Flex.
So now we can see it.
Let's remove that hidden for now.
And then I signed it.
And then we bring it back.
Okay, so we all want it to be object colour.
Because I don't want to change the aspect ratio when I'm changing the height and width.
And for medium size and above, I want the width to be let's make it 44 and height.
To be 80.
Maybe this is not completely correct, but it's going to.
Now you can see the size.
Actually, this is the size because the medium size we want to make this active and then.
That's it.
I think that's it.
We just.
I just wanna rotate it.
So just say rotate six.
A little bit tilted to the right side.
So let's add the hidden too.
So we don't see it in the mobile size.
Now.
And the bigger size.
We should see it.
Let me check.
A medium.
Like this.
Now we are seeing it.
Okay, let's bring everything to the center.
So we just say after these flags we just added justify center.
Like this.
And then we add a margin top of 20.
So they push them a little bit to death.
I think that is fine.
Uh.
That's decreased the size.
Let's establish logo.
So for the image here, we add a class name.
Let's say it's the.
Wait to be 36.
Then we make it.
Object cover too.
So prevent this.
Stretching.
And then.
Yeah.
That's it for this one.
For this for the div at the top here.
We make it flex.
But I want full flex direction to be color.
Then we.
Bring them everything to the center.
Using items centre.
It's a fresh two page.
There aren't incentives.
So I didn't see the results of.
J Items Center.
Still not centered.
Let me check.
That's for this Texas Athletics Center.
Oh, sorry.
I added this on here.
This one should be in this.
They're actually.
Now we can see the results.
Okay.
So let's continue with this text.
So text center, we bring it into center using that, then let's make it smaller using text to smaller
than we make it italic.
And now we can add a margin Y of ten.
So the space between.
That's on the button and.
Yeah.
And that's.
That's it for this fall.
Let's install the button here.
So we had a class name.
And we just changed the background color to be a red 400.
We make it around death.
Large.
Then, uh.
And a padding of three.
Let's change the text color.
So we make it.
Why?
I think that's okay.
And when we hover over it.
I want to the background color to be red 500 instead.
Like this.
So in the big size, it's like this.
But let's add some space between these two.
So that's.
I think we need to add a space.
X of.
Example.
Or.
Okay.
It looks okay now.
Let's add the functionality when we click on this one.
We go to Google.
The first thing we need to do is to go go to console.
Who will you just search for?
Counsel.
And we should go to a website called council that claw claw that Google dot com.
I want to add the localhost 3000 to the Google search.
It's as if to recognize our website.
So first we choose the projects here.
The projects are.
The name of my project was Twitter version four.
But you choose the name you you have chosen for your project.
Then here on the left side, we click on the hamburger menu.
Then we go to APIs and services and we go to credentials.
Now we should see our.
Uh oh.
Of information here of 2.0 client IDs.
So here we click on the edit.
And inside here we should see the website that authorized as you can see, the local hosted by local
post 5000 is authorized.
Let's change this 1 to 3000.
And save it.
Now.
Let's go back to our signing and uh, let's add in other things from next off.
Which is a function call sign, and it's going to redirect us to the provider that we are choosing so
we can use this one inside that button.
So here, inside the bottom, we add on click.
Okay.
And this oncolytic is going to trigger.
This sign in function that the we have imported from next off.
And this is going to get the provider I.D. because we want to know that which provided you want to be
signing so proud provided that I.D..
And the next argument.
Is, uh, we need to have a callback.
The callback means that when these are signing with Google, which page you wanna be re redirected next.
So we just say you are callback url and this is going to be equal to forward slash.
So when we are signing, I want to go to the homepage.
Okay, uh, let's try this.
See, we don't get any error or something.
So this is a localhost 3000, a signing page.
It's clicked on.
Sign in with Google.
Yeah.
You we went to the Google accounts at Google, but we are getting an error.
This is a common error you get.
It's telling us that you re direct.
You are a mismatch.
You just need to open this.
And you need to copy this earth.
This is a redirect.
You are you copy this one.
And we go back to the credentials.
People were here and we got there.
We change this on.
We just go to the edit again.
And in the redirect URLs we need to add this that we have copied, we save this.
And now if you try again and you go back.
If we try again, we should be going to to the correct page if this is going to ask us to sign it.
Okay.
I'm going to sign in with my email.
This just takes it's a hand.
And at G.M. dot com.
Let me quickly add my.
Password.
Okay.
Now we are going to be redirected to the homepage, which is localhost 3000.
So that was completely okay.
Now, now we are actually authenticated.
So we have we went by Google.
So we have we can get the now the information from Google as well.
So in the next section, actually, we are going to get the information and get the decision information.
And we we want to get this image is here and here.
From the real.
An image from Google.
So from your Google accounts image.
Okay.
Let's add the end everything to get off first as usual.
And the review, the pay review, the course of it and that's using it at DOT and we use get comment
and we add a message.
And the message would be.
Complete.
This signing.
Hey.
Okay.
And we push it to get.
Huh?
Let's check.
What we have done so far.
So we refresh this page.
Now we have 11 comments and if you click on it, we can see the last one is complete the signing page.
So we just fix this error.
That's the mistake I made.
We added the next public inside the next authorities.
We added the pages because we want to tell the next off that we we want this page to be our signing
custom page.
Then inside the signing that year we got there get providers and signing from next of our statutory
act get providers gives us all the providers like that, like Google, etc. We only have one providers,
but we need to look through the all providers here and get the.
Each provider.
And we added an image to images for a logo and a mobile image.
We added this text and the button.
We created signing with Google by just adding provided that name and.
We added on click, which is going to use this signing function from next off.
And we provided the provider I.D..
And we specified the callback URL.
So this phone was the homepage.
Okay.
And also we got the providers using the server side rendering functionality of next year's.
So in the next section, we're going to update the images of the this what's happening section and the
code we and this part, the mini files section.
Also, we want to create this quote.
We had a name and also the and user name.
So see in the next section for this part.