All right.
In the last section, we have completed the loading effect in our website.
In this section, we're going to work on the.
Card components and make the website like the one in the final version.
With this card, so I'm going to show you.
This is just a component.
With the image at the top.
We have this, uh.
Description of the movie, but is limited to only two lines.
So I'm going to show you how to do it.
And also, we have a title here with the release date and also the.
This section.
So this is one day and then we have the title and this one too.
So we need to create a component for that one and add it to the.
Uh, results is that we have created.
So if you go back to our website and we go to Explorer section using Contour shift E.
So we had a component here and it was called results that gsx.
But we just show the title of the movie, but we want to pass this data and create a card component
and add it here.
So I'm going to create.
A car's components here.
And we're going to just pass a few things like the key, which is the result.
Dot ID.
And also we have the results we passed, the result which we are getting from the map.
And then we need to close this card and we need to create this component inside this folder.
So I'm going to create a file called card dot JS X.
And this is going to be a React functional component.
For now.
And this is going to get that results.
From here as a prop.
So the result is going to be from there and we can just for now show something.
Inside this card.
So we're going to get the results.
And here I'm just want to show something like a result.
Dot.
So it should be inside.
A curly braces so we could just say result dot, for example.
For now we just say the original title or ID so I'll come just say result dot ID and let's.
Imported inside the results that JSX.
I'm going to use control space at the end of the card name and auto import it now inside our website.
So let's refresh the page.
We see the IDs.
So this is going to initialize it.
Something went wrong.
So we.
Which failed.
So let's try again.
So inside the.
Page 36.
So everything is the same as before.
We should.
We shouldn't get an error, actually.
So.
Let's try again.
Let's stop the server and we use MPN run dev.
Again.
And let's see now it's compiled the client and server side successfully.
Let's go to the home page and we refresh the page now.
So we got the error again.
Let me pause the video and I'll check the error.
I'll be back when I find the error.
All right.
I find the error.
Actually, there was no error.
My wi fi had a problem, so I couldn't fetch the data.
So now if you go trending, we get these data.
So if you go to top rated, you get different IDs.
The things I want to do.
I want to style this phone like a final version.
So we're going to have a great display.
So when we when we are in the mobile size, we get only one column.
And when we go to the bigger size like a tablet, we get two columns.
Then we get three columns in the large and four for the like a big screen and.
If we have a massive screen like a TV or something, we get five columns.
So I'm going to show you how to do it.
So inside the result is X.
We're going to style this.
Diff here at a top, and we're going to change the display of this one to great.
So.
Let's add a class name here.
And we just I don't want it to be great in the mobile size, but in the mobile size and above, I want
the it has a great display.
Great.
In the mobile size and above.
I want the grid to be to has to have two columns.
So we just say great calls, two in the larger screen and above.
I want to have a grid.
With three columns.
And for the ex large.
Let's have a great with columns four and four, the two x large, which is for the like a TV size.
We have a grid with the columns five.
And we're going to.
Limit the maximum width of this result to six Excel, which is similar to the header section.
And also we want to bring it to the center using Amex Auto.
And we add some padding in the Y axis of four.
So now in our website, we see the results like this, but we're going to replace each of them with
a card with all the information, like the image and other things.
But for now, I just want to show you how to make a grid system.
So let's go to our car section and fix.
Everything else.
So we get the results.
Now, instead of just showing the line, I'm going to work on the.
Other parts of the car section.
The first things I want to do is just install the card border and itself.
So we just add a class name here.
So what happened?
He had a class name.
And here we just.
I want this one to.
Change the cursor of the.
Mouse to pointer.
So when we.
So we see a pointing hand when we hover over it.
And let's.
Add some shadow effect as well.
So in the a small size and above, firstly I want to have some padding of three.
And I want to have some shadow effect as well when we hover over it.
So when we hover over it, I want to have a shadow.
With the color of a slate 400.
And also shadow.
So that was the color of the shadow.
Now we want the size of the shadow.
So the shadow I want to have is the medium size.
And also I want to make it rounded.
So rounded, large.
And also in the small size and above, I want to have a border.
So after the border.
Let's say, the color of the border.
So I want the border.
To be a Slate 400.
And also, I want to have some marching.
Of two.
And also let's add some transitions.
So we want to have some transition to the shadow effect.
So we just choose transition shadow and with the duration of, for example, 200 milliseconds.
So now we have some.
Cards for each of them.
It has a border, and when we hover over it, we see a shadow.
And the.
Let's refresh the page.
And in the dark mode.
Also, we have a shadow.
But the shadow is kind of a.
Writer here.
But here we see it like dark.
It's the same color, but in the different background color.
You see it like that?
So the card is just now a small part.
When we have we add the image and other things, you can see it better.
So let's go back and let's bring this one to the right side so we can see the changes in real time.
So I'm going to make it like a mobile size.
And now I want to add some images and etc..
So let's delete this result that ID for now.
And instead let's add a link tag.
So link tag is going to.
As you know, the link tag is coming from the next post slash link.
And this is going to.
When we click on the card, we go to a different place.
For example, the H ref.
Is going to be.
So let's create this.
This is going to be dynamic.
So add back take.
And it's going to be.
Movie.
Forward slash movie.
Forward.
Slash dynamic route, which is the idea of the movie.
So we just say result dot ID and inside the link.
We're going to have.
The image and other things.
So first thing first, I want to add the image.
The image we are using the image component of the next JSS, which has some extra benefit and ask some.
You can add a loading effect on other things.
So let's close this one for the CRC.
Of the image for the source of the image we are going to have.
And.
This URL.
As we get the suggestion.
Htmg bee forward slash TX forward slash p original and can be resolved at back drop path or result that
poster.
Underlying path.
So I'm going to use this one.
This is going to show the image.
We are getting an error because we haven't actually use the width and height for the image stack for
the next.
Yes, width and height is mandatory.
So for the width I want to use the.
500.
And for the height I want to use.
300.
K.
We still get an error.
The error.
The other error is this.
U.
R.
L.
Uh, let's see the height.
So let's refresh the page.
The other error is this URL image.
That team DB dot org is not configured under images in your next configs.
So we need to add this URL inside this file next dot conflict that js that we have here.
So I'm going to copy this URL.
I go to this next conflict, that is and we need to create some files here.
So after this experimental.
We have the app.
The directory.
True.
After that, we're going to have another thing called images.
And this image is going to be equal to a curly braces set of curly braces, which gives us the domain.
Domains and we open a set of.
Bracket.
And inside this, we're going to paste the link that we have copied from here.
So because we have changed a config file, we need to restart the server.
So we stop the server and we use NPM run diff to start the server again.
So let's see that we get an error.
Or not.
So I'm going to close this next conflict.
That is, let's close the left side, too, so we have more space.
And let's refresh the page.
It's okay.
We are getting the images for now.
Okay.
That's a good sign.
So we get the image.
Now.
And in the big size we see the images are smaller.
Okay, let's add some other effects as well.
So I'm going to show you in the tablet size.
So for the image, we're going to add some styling using 12 and CSS.
I'm going to add a class name.
First thing first, I want to when we have a small size and above, I want it to be rounded.
Add a top.
So only the top one.
I want it to be rounded, but in the large size.
So it's just say around the two large.
And the.
Let's see what else we can add.
So when we hover over this card, I want to.
This image to be transparent a little bit more.
But I want to, for example, in the final version, even I move on this part.
I want the image has a opacity.
So the easiest way to do that is to add a group at a top div.
We just say group here.
And then here inside the image.
We just say if.
We hover over the group, so we just say group dash hover when this happens.
So change the opacity.
To 80%.
So this is going to when we hover over it, we see 80% opacity.
But this is very fast.
So I'm going to add a transition.
On the opacity.
With the duration of Tour 200.
Okay.
Like this.
Even the we are outside the image.
We see the opacity.
And also I want to when the image is not there, I want to see a loading effect.
I don't want you to wait.
For example, if you go to the top rated now.
So this is going to let's refresh the page.
So as you can see, you just see an empty things.
But we want to add this same loading effect here.
The simplest way to do that in next year's 13 image tag is to add a placeholder and we need to set the
placeholder to blur.
And then we want to add some blower.
They tell you our Al?
And this is going to be.
Uh, that is Spinner.
We had this spinner dot SVG.
So now if you refresh the page.
So let's wait until this compiled.
Now, if you refresh the page, we should see the spanner.
In the image.
I'm going to load this one again.
You see, before the.
The image loads we see as banner.
Okay, this is too fast.
But if you have this kind of.
A smaller size, like you have a slower internet.
You can see the smaller in the longer term.
Okay.
So this is the simplest way to add a spinning effect.
And also, if there is no image, we want to have some alternative text.
We just want to say the image.
Is not.
Sorry image.
Not find or is not available.
The other things I want to do is when you refresh the page, we see that the size of the image would
change first and then we see the real image.
So.
Let's see.
And the Internet is off now.
Let's refresh the page again.
I just want to show you the image.
Size sometimes gets smaller.
So in order to keep the style and the width of the height of the image, we need to add a style here.
So we just write down style here.
And this is going to be we need to add another curly braces here because this inside the react when
you want to add this style, you need to have two curly braces.
And we're going to just set the.
Max width.
To be 100%.
And we set the height.
To be or to.
So in this way, the height is always going to be the same rate, even when we see the loading effect.
We should see the same height.
So let's refresh this.
Okay.
So now let's go to.
Other part of the card.
I want to have this.
Description, the overview, the title and the other parts.
So all the other parts is going to be inside it.
If.
Which is going to have a padding of two.
And here.
We're going to have.
A paragraph.
Scared the.
Result dot over view.
So we see the overview now.
Let's start this first and then I'm going to.
So let's go find the.
As I mentioned, I want to limit this, Tex.
To be only in two lines.
There is a way inside the 12 and six called TRUNCATE.
TRUNCATE is going to limit this text to one line.
But in order to have a tool, two lines, there is another official plugging for Taylor CSS.
Which is called the line clamp.
So I'm going to search here on Google.
Line clamp.
12 and cease.
And here you see a GitHub repository saying 12 and 12 and six line clamp.
And this is the official explanation of this plugin.
You can check this out.
So you can go to the GitHub page.
We can just copy this.
Line of code to install it.
So I'm going to copy this, come back to Visual Studio Code and I'm going to paste it inside a terminal.
The next thing we need to do is to go to Taylor Configs and we need to add this plugin inside the plugin
section so we're going to copy this.
Require logging.
We go back to Visual Studio Code, I'm going to open the Explorer section using Contour Shift E!
So let's go to Telvin, that configures and we added inside this plugin, so I'm going to paste the
require this.
So if we now run the server again using NPM run dev.
So let's close this.
So.
And then we changed this.
Instead of truncate, we can say.
Line.
Clamp.
And we just add two at the end.
So this too is going to be two line.
So if you wait a little bit, we see the results on the right side.
So after the compiling.
Uh, let's refresh the page.
Now we can see that we have two lines instead of one line.
This is going to help.
To just have the same card height for every card.
So and then I want to check.
I think is nice.
I want to change the text larger, but I feel we just changed the text to be medium would be.
Fine.
And after that, after the paragraph, I want to add an H to tag.
Just for the.
Re title of the title of the movie, which can be resolved.
That title.
And if this one is not available, we want to use title that name.
And let's style this until this one shows up inside the page.
So the Ford styling.
Let's try it again.
Yeah.
Let's see the error.
The title is not defined.
Oh, sorry.
I think.
This is a result of title.
This one is the result.
That name.
I write down the wrong one.
So this should be work now.
Let's try again.
Okay, now we can see the title.
Let's style it.
I want to just keep this title in one line in case the debt is very long.
So I just say to Kate to keep it in one line and then we set the text to be large here and we set the
font weight to be bold.
So after the title.
We're going to have the release date and the vote count.
So I'm going to add another paragraph.
Inside a paragraph.
We're going to have the result.
That release date.
Or if this is not available, we're going to have the result that first a air date.
Like this.
And then.
We're going to have an icon like the final version.
We're going to have the thumbs up icon.
So we go to React icons, website, react the icons inside the GitHub repository.
You're going to search for an icon called a thumbs up.
Sums up.
The thumb.
Thumbs up.
So I'm going to use this.
If I thumbs up this one.
I'm going to copy, click and copy it.
And I'm going to import it at the top.
You just say import.
Thumbs up.
Which is going to be from react icons forward slash f.
I.
So now we can add this icon here.
So let's check what we have here.
We are getting an error saying that the date is not defined.
Actually, this one should be released.
Underlined dates, not released plus date.
We need to fix this one.
Sometimes you get a suggestion from a GitHub copilot, but you need to check it.
One more time and be sure about that.
All right, Now we get the result, the release date here.
Uh, after the release date, I want to add the.
Thumbs up button.
Comes up icon that we have imported.
So I'm going to paste that icon here.
And the.
After that, we want to see the result.
That vote underlying count, which shows the number of thumbs up or votes for this movie.
So now let's save this and check it inside our website.
All right.
Now we can see the icon and also the number of vote counts, but there are on the top of each other.
Let's change the display to flex.
So we changed the display to flex, to bring them next to each other inside this paragraph.
And the.
We can bring them exactly on the line.
By just changing the items center.
They are now on next to each other, but they are just connected.
So inside the fit thums up, we can add a class name.
And first thing first, I want to change the height of this to be five.
And then I want to add some margin in the right of one and margin in the left of three.
So we have some space before and after these terms of icon.
So now you can see the space between the after and before and after of the thumbs up.
So everything is done.
The only things I want to add in this section is to remove this scroll ball here, which is going to
make our application more beautiful because.
For example, inside the about page.
When we are in the about page, we don't have the scroll bar.
And then when we go to the trending, we're going to have this global, which is going to a little bit.
Makes this one move and it's not comfortable for the users.
So in many, many websites like a Twitter, Facebook, they remove the scroll bar.
Okay.
Now the easiest ways to do that.
Intelligence.
Yes.
We need to go to.
And let me show you inside the Explorer section, we need to go to global stocks inside the.
Let's close everything.
We need to go to.
To the CRC folder app directory and then we go to global search.
Yes, we need to add these HTML codes here.
So we need to add the HTML because we want to apply this one to the HTML.
We add.
Dash.
Web.
Kit.
Underline scrollbar.
This is going to add.
We're going to remove the.
We change the display to non to remove the scroll bar and this sometimes this one works for the Firefox,
sometimes it doesn't work.
In order to be sure we need to add it to html only as well.
Which is why here we need to add a scroll.
A scrollbar.
Dash width to be none.
So this too is going to show that in all browser we don't see the scroll bar.
So because I have tested sometimes only use one of them, you get you remove the scrollbar only for
example in Chrome, not in the Firefox or other browsers.
So we don't see the scroll bar anymore and.
Okay.
So that was it for creating the cards of the page.
You can see that this is responsive in different sizes.
We get different number of columns of.
Cards.
So let's add this one to the GitHub.
So I'm going to review what we have done here.
So we add everything to GitHub and we just name and create a message for this comment and call it add
cart component.
And we're going to commit and push it to GitHub.
Let's go to GitHub.
Our.
Let's close this extra website.
I'm going to our GitHub repository.
We go back to the comment section, I'm going to refresh the page.
And this is going to show the new one, which is add card components.
And we can just review what we have done here inside the next conflict that we have added, the new
domain that we have used for the images.
That was the error we got.
So we have to fix it by using the budgets, adding images domain, and then the domain that we are using.
Inside the package that JSON became.
We can see that we have installed a plugin called Line Clap for tailwind CSS.
Is inside a global that says we have added to command for CSIS to be sure that we remove the scrollbar
of the browser by just changing the display to none or a scrollable width to none.
We have created a component called Card, which is going to import the image tag from next year's the
link tag, and also the icon from React to React icons.
This is going to get the result from as a as a prop here and we're going to create a link here.
Which is going to redirect the person to this URL.
I haven't tested actually.
So if you click on this, this is going to redirect us to this URL.
Movie four slash the ID of the page.
We haven't created this page.
In the next section we're going to create it.
But for now we just redirected the person.
If they they they click on the.
A cart.
Then we have added the image tag with the source, which can be a back drop path or the poster underlined
path.
If this one is available, we use this one.
Otherwise we use the other one.
We set the width and height of the image.
This is mandatory for next year's.
If you don't just sit there, wait and hide, you get an error.
And also, we have added an extra style for the setting up the max width and the height.
We have added a place older, which is going to blow over with this.
A spinner.
So if we don't see the if the if the image is loading, instead of just seeing the half an image or
something, we see a spinner.
And also we have added the alternative text.
After that, we have added the overview we have.
Limit that 1 to 2 lines using this line clamp two which we have installed as a plugin.
Then we have added the title and finally the release date, a thumbs up icon and also the vote count.
Inside the result of JSX.
We have added this card component.
We have passed the data here, the results, and also we have made this course to be in the grade system.
So we have we have changed the display to grid and in different sizes like tablet, larger screen,
the extra large to excel.
We have different number of columns here.
Inside the Taleban that conflict that is, we have added this plugin that we have installed like clamp
in order to be able to use it.
All right.
That was it for the creating the cart components.
In the next section, we're going to work on the page, the movie page that we get now.
An error saying this page could not be fired.
We're going to create this page, and this page is going to be dynamic and each time we can.
Just get a different information based on the ID that we get from the URL.
So see in the next section for creating the movie page.