All right, in the last section, we have completed the buttons section in this section, we're going
to start with the command and also the input comments section.
If I zoom a little bit here and withdraw, the things we need in the comments section is very easy with
just for this input section.
We have three parts.
First one is the.
This icon, the happy icon, then we have the input, which goes all the way to the end.
And finally, we have a button that's just saying post.
The button is in the disable mode, but when we write down, it goes to them and working mode.
We're not going to cover in this video about this because later when we are really adding the comment
functionality using the database and be connected, we connect our website to Firebase database and
we're going to implement all these features.
But for now, we just make the
user interface.
So let's go back to.
Our.
Visual studio code, and we keep open the our website on the right side here at the bottom.
We will add another section and we call it post comments.
Under this.
First, we add a paragraph, and inside this paragraph, we just add.
Spam just adding the user name.
So adding the username and the caption, so the user being will be inside a spare.
So we just say spent.
And inside this span, we have her use of.
So we should see something now, first refresh the page.
Yeah, we've got the user and after the username, we add the caption.
All right.
So here this is different.
So let's style it a little bit.
So in the top class, a top paragraph, you add a class name, which does add some padding.
But just saying P five.
And we just in case someone drives too much, we just, uh, truncated.
So if the comments is more than one lie, it's going to be truncated like the one we did here.
In fact, you.
So that's it for the paragraph, for the username we want it to be.
So we aren't font pulled.
And we added marching to the right to add some space.
To the right side.
And, uh, for the caption, that's fine.
So that looks OK.
So let's go to the next part, which is the.
Which is the input box.
So we add a comment here with, just say, post.
And.
Box.
For the for this part, we need an.
This happy icon, so we import another icon from the.
Hero icons outline, and with just the name would be emoji.
Happy.
I've come.
And we just had it inside form here, which is first we make a form.
Inside the forum at this emoji icon.
It should be a huge icon now, but we're going to need a salad.
So let's just first, we finish the ports and then we have an input.
And the.
The tide would be class, and we have a placeholder for this input.
Just saying, for example, into your comment.
And just add some dots.
So we have it here.
And after that, we have a button.
Just saying posts, so we just at the bottom and side of the button, we just like post.
All right, now, it's time to style it.
So first, we establish form, we make it flat.
Let's first decrease the size of the icon so we can see it clear what we are doing.
Just switch and make it.
They're high seven.
The track here.
So by by using Flex, we bring everything next to each other.
Inside the phone.
And then.
These two are next to each other, but before the emoji icon, we're going to use something, uh.
This one should be fine.
Let's mate, make the item center.
And then we have that paragraph, sorry, we have a padding of four.
You don't see any change or just refresh the page.
Oh, I'm I'm putting this one into action.
Yeah.
It's silly.
Yeah, the class name now, everything next to each other and.
That's fine.
And, Moji, we have here.
Let's style the.
The input section.
So we just had a class name.
And, uh, we just remove the border.
We don't in the border for this one as we have the placeholder, then we use the our favorite one Flex
one.
That push this post to the right side and has some space.
So now we can see that the airport is occupying all this space between two.
Then let's remove it, remove the this blue line as well, so make it more beautiful.
So just say focus ring zero.
All right.
Then let's Dolly Parton make it blue.
So the four blue collar was just ticks blue.
Four hundred.
Then let's make it bold as well.
We just found both.
All right.
Looks fine.
And we are going to add the disability, disable functionality and later when we're at the.
If that database to our websites, so that was it for this part, so everything looks fine.
And let's see in the next section, we're going to go to the right side.
And first, we're going to make this responsive because now our our web site.
It's covering all the.
Space in the.
In the in the page, but you want this to be like a smaller and we have a when we have something at
the right.
So now if you've checked the final version first, it's just the one column and we don't see the right
side of the feet section.
But after the medium size hits in the we have this one at the right.
So let's first, we push everything to get her just to get at and get commenced with the message of.
So we did two things to we at the.
Caption.
And in truth.
Box of the post components.
Let's push it to get up and review the code.
So we just refresh the page.
And we checked the last comment.
You can click here directly to the last one.
So then the last one to add the caption and input box of the post component, we added an emoji happy
icon.
And in the post comment, we added a paragraph.
And inside the paragraph, we had a span that shows the user name and the caption outside the span.
In the post section, we added a form that covers an emoji icon.
And input.
And finally, we have the button.
So in the next section, we're going to start first.
Make this fun responsive.
So see in the next section.