All right.
In the last section, we have created the cart components.
In this section, we are going to create the page related to the each movie.
If you look at the final version and if you go, for example, to trending and we click on one of the
movies, we see that each movie has a URL for itself.
And based on that, we're going to get the full overview, the title, the release date and the rating.
And.
So and seeing that one is an instance.
So we're going to use the paging dynamic paging system of next year 13.
So we need to go to Visual Studio Code and we go to app the app directory.
We need to create another.
Folder called Movie.
I'm sure I'm going to show you a trick so you can create a file.
But instead of naming the file, you can just write down movie.
And add forward slash.
And ad ID because we want to create a page based on the ID.
And after that, we're going to have forward slash page.
Dot js x.
This is going to create two folders, the movie folder, the folder called Bracket ID, and also inside
this folder is going to create a file called page dot GSX.
Let's create this page using RFC, we create a React functional component.
And we can just call this one.
Page or.
We can just call it movie.
Page.
Now, if you go to our website and we click in any of these cards, we're going to be redirected to
that page.
So when we click, we go to that page and we see that movie page and we also get all the layouts that
we have created before, like before.
So now we still have the header, we have the Napa, and here we see the movie page.
So how we get to each movie based on this idea that we have passed, we can we can request again to
the ten DB API.
And based on this ID, we are going to get the.
The movie data.
So here.
We can just pass.
The premise here.
And based on this prams, we can get the ID.
So, for example, if I.
Uh, let's.
So we can get the ID and we create a constant and we call it.
Movie.
ID and this is going to be equal to this params dot ID.
So now we can use this ID to create and ask for the database and get the result.
So we create a constant here and we call it response.
And this is going to be equal to a wait fetch.
And we're going to.
Get the information that based on the suggestion from the GitHub copilot.
So we're going to await phage.
This is the URL API that.
The movie DB dot org.
We're going to pass the movie ID and we're going to pass the API key, which is coming from process
dot envy.
API key.
We don't need that next public actually.
And we can just get the we can get rid of the language because here we don't need the language and we
just get the result, we get the response.
We can just get the data of the movie by changing the response to a JSON file.
Like this.
And we we just get each movie.
As you can see, the get up copilot is not so smart.
It's getting all the information, giving me all the correct one this time.
So now.
We can just get the.
So we have requested now.
So we can do this one or we can just call this function.
It doesn't matter to both work the same way.
By this function should be asynchronous because we are using a weight inside it and we want to use the
server side rendering inside next year 30.
So this one should be asynchronous and we're going to fetch database on the print parameter ID.
So for making it a little bit cleaner, I'm going to just, uh, go at the top, create a function,
a synchronous function.
I'm going to call it get movie, for example.
And then.
We want to I want to bring all of them inside this function.
Let's close the function.
And we bring everything inside there.
So I have to get the movie ID here.
So I get the movie ID here and then I'm going to call the function that we have created.
So.
Let's check.
So now we need to get the movie by calling that function and passing this ID and actually this ID we
don't need that ID here because this prompts is get everything inside this ID so we need to remove this
ID.
So sorry about that.
So remove this ID, this params is actually is movie ID and we pass the movie ID and we call this function
which is asynchronous as well.
And finally, we're going to show it, show it inside this return.
And also we need to return here as well.
So here, instead of saying movie, I'm going to return this.
Await response.
Dodgson.
So this is going to return.
And we get the movie here and we put it inside this.
All right.
So now we can show it inside this day.
For example, I'm going to show.
The H one tag with the movie title.
Let's see that we can get the result.
So I'm going to refresh the page here.
And based on this ID, we should get the title of the movie.
Let's save it again and refresh the page here.
Well, let's try another movie.
For example, this one.
So we are not getting the title.
Let's check.
So this movie we get we have passed the title here.
So.
Can be a title or if the title is not available, we want to get the movie.
That name, for example.
So now it's just.
Tested.
Let's refresh the page.
It should show here.
Let's check what mistakes we have done.
Okay.
You hear this premise?
We got it directly.
It should be inside a curly braces.
Okay.
Okay, that's fine.
Now let's check it.
Let's go to the other pages.
Trending.
And then we click here.
All right.
So let's see what problem we have here.
Now, I think this prams should be prams dot ID, actually, because this is the name is ID, and the
programs can have different variables.
So this ID should be added here.
Now we see the title of the movie.
Let's try a different movie.
For example, this one.
Okay, We see the title.
All right.
So now we need to install this one and create a beautiful page for this one.
Instead of just getting the title, I'm going to create some page here.
So first thing first, I want to add
a full weight to this day.
So I'm going to add a class name.
And just set the fit width to be full.
And instead of this insert inside of this tape, we're going to have.
Another death.
And in this stiff is going to create a two column for us.
So we're going to.
So let's add some padding in the y axis padding of the four in the medium size and above.
I want the padding top of eight.
Let's change the display to flex.
So by changing the display to flex, we can change the flex direction to column and bring after the
medium size and above.
I want to change the flex to row.
So when we have a smaller screen, the image would be on top of the.
Ticks.
But after the medium size and above, we're going to have them next to each other.
So this is going to mix, makes it responsive and we can use items.
Dash center and justify Content Center or just a content center.
Content center is equal to align content center.
This is going to help us to bring them exactly in the center.
We set the maximum width of the size of this to be six x LX, which is equal to the header section and
everything would be in a line.
And we're going to add a mach margin x auto to.
Keep them everything in the center and in the medium size and above.
I want to have some space in the x axis between the two columns of six.
So we have this div now we're going to add the image and the description on the on the right side.
So first we're going to have an image here, the image tag which is coming from the next.
Yes, 13.
This is similar to the one that we have created in the cart.
So I'm going to copy that image.
I'm going to copy.
Let's close this and I'm going to copy this image tag and put it inside this.
So this is going to save some time for us because it's exactly the same.
And the weight and height.
The class name.
So the class name, we're going to change it a little bit.
We don't need everything here.
We just I just want to make it rounded large.
So delete everything and add the rounded.
Round that.
So let's see.
Dash.
LG.
And the style would be the same.
The height is also we can change the height to be 100% as well here, so we can get the full quality
of the image here.
And the alternative for this one.
Is going to we can say the image is not available or we can just say the movie.
And poster, for example.
Okay.
So this is going to have this banner as well.
So the image should be here.
Now, let's let's check and we try again.
So this is going to show us the image for us.
Now.
Let's see.
Okay.
We are getting an error.
Let's see the error.
So the image is not defined.
So we need to import this image tag.
So I'm going to use the contour space to auto import the next forward slash image.
So now we shouldn't get this error.
So let's refresh the page.
We got another error.
Let's see.
We still get the same error.
Image is not defined.
Let's refresh the page again.
I think I didn't save this one.
Let's save this one again.
Now, as you can see, we have imported the image tag from next forward slash image.
It should work.
Now.
Let's wait until this is reloaded.
So we get an error again.
The error is the result is not defined.
So probably we didn't get the result yet.
Let's see what result.
So this one is resolved, that puzzle that this one should be movie because we we have changed this
one to movie.
So I'm going to copy this movie instead of results.
I'm going to say movie dot pack, backdrop, underline path and movie poster, underline path.
So this one should solve the problem.
Now let's check the browser.
We refresh the page here.
Okay, now it shows the image for us.
So let's check it for the other movies as well.
So I'm going to come back to the trending page.
It's this is always happened when you're in the development mode because it's always compiling your
next year's code at this point gets a little bit slow.
And also I'm recording as well at the same time.
So this is all depend on your CPU and the RAM.
So let's go to the trending page.
Okay in the trending page.
Let's choose another movie.
For example, the first one.
As you can see, they're loading.
It's working as well.
So after the loading finish, we're going to see the image here.
All right.
So you can see the image now.
So let's move on and create the other part of this page.
So I want to bring this one on the right side and the code on the left side.
So after the image, we're going to add the other parts of the page.
I'm going to add another div here.
Inside this tip.
I'm going to add some other parts.
The first thing I want to add is an H to tag.
With the movie title and movie name.
So this is going to be.
Movie.
Got title or if this one is not available, this is going to be movie.
Dot name.
So we're going to style this one first.
So that's let's add a class name here.
Let's add change that takes to be large.
And also let us add a margin at the bottom of three.
Sorry, the margin bottom of tree.
And also we want to add a font board for this.
This should be like that.
And for the top tip, we're going to add a padding of two.
So we have the title now.
After the title, I'm going to add some other things like the overview and other parts.
So I'm going to add a paragraph.
The paragraph is going to have a.
Uh, expand inside it because I want to have a title for that.
So for the spam, I want to just say over view clone.
And after this is spam, we're going to have that movie dot over view.
And let's style this hair graph as well.
So this one should be overview.
Not over views.
And then the class name we're going to add here.
It's just we want to add the text to be large.
And we add a margin bottom of tree.
For this overview.
I want to make it bold or semi bold, so I'm going to add a font to be semi bold.
And we add some margin at the right of one.
So this is going to add some space here.
Now you can see the.
Explanation and other things.
So inside.
The mobile size.
We see it like that in the big screen.
They are next to each other because we have added a dynamic flex.
Hey.
And let's add the other parts.
So after the overview.
I want to add some.
Real estate.
So I'm going to another paragraph with the spam inside.
It is spam is going to say date.
Released.
It clone.
Let's add.
Because, uh.
So that is fine.
So we're going to create we're going to add a margin bottom of three for this one as well.
And let's.
Make this a span to be.
Semi bold the font to be semi bold.
And we add some margin at the right of one.
And then also after this, this ban, we're going to have the information of the movie.
Release date.
So we just say movie Dot.
Release underline.
Date or sorry date or if this one is not available, we're going to see the movie.
Dot first underlying.
Air underline dates.
Okay.
This one should work now.
So we see the release date after this one.
We're going to have another paragraph for the rating.
I'm going to copy this one.
So this is very similar.
So I'm going to copy this paragraph and instead of date released, this one should be rating.
And this one instead of this, it should be.
Vote.
Underline.
Can't.
You can get more information about the movie and add it here.
So make it more informal informative.
But for simplicity, I just got this for information.
I just want to show you in next year's 13 how you work with the dynamic URL's, how to get the information.
So let's test this one for another movie.
We go to top rated.
I just want to choose, for example, the Godfather movie.
This is going to show us the all the overview.
See, said another one, for example, this movie.
All right, So.
That was it for this section for creating the page.
And also we can see that this is also works on the dark mode as well.
So in this section we have completed this.
Part the creating the page.
Let's add this one to GitHub and we review what we have done.
So inside the source control using control shift G.
I'm going to add everything and create a message for this one.
Say add movie page and we're going to commit and push this one to GitHub.
And after that I'm going to go to my GitHub.
And go to the comment section.
As you can see, we have now a new commit.
Add the movie page.
So we have created a page inside the app directory with the with a new folder, movie and other folder
for ID.
And also we have just named the file page that asks.
We have created a function here, a synchronous function, which is going to fetch the movies with the
ID, and we get the response by fetching this URL.
And then we're going to return the movie by changing it to the JSON file and we change this file to
asynchronous as well.
We got the params here which is going to give us the movie ID based on the name of the folder.
And we also get the movie by bye calling that function.
So inside here we have added an image tag which is similar to the one that we have created for the card
component, which has the source of movie that drop path and has everything similar to that one.
And after that we have added the title, the overview and the release date and finally the move the
vote count.
All right.
So that was it for creating the page.
In the next section, we're going to add the search ability.
As you can see from the final version, we can we have the ability to search.
For example, if I search for Wolf, you're going to see the movies related to this search.
Term, this is going to be very easy because we already have created this card component.
And the result, that G6 component file, we just have to create an inbox.
Then input.
And we just redirect to this URL search, for example, for Wolf.
And based on this keyword, we're going to search the IMDB API and get all the movies related to that
search term and show it inside the results.
That component that we have created before, because we have created these files before, we can easily
finish this part.
So next in the next section, we're going to work on this search box.