All right.
In the last section, we have got the information from the session and filled this mini profile and
this picture.
In this section, we're going to upload and add information to the firebase and using this input.
Before starting to do that, we need to activate our firebase.
And uh, actually for the input we don't need, but for the image upload we need to activate our firebase.
So first, let's make the input and add it to the fire saw.
So, uh, for doing that, we need to get this information here as it states.
So we go back to Visual Studio code and inside to close this sidebar.
And this next off and we go to input.
Yes.
Insight input that just we we create a state and we call it inputs.
And, uh, this input.
We have this set input.
To change the value of it.
And this is going to be equal to use a state.
And the initial value would be an empty string.
So let's import user state as well.
So I'm not getting any other imports, so I import it manually here at the top.
We just say use a state.
From.
Reacts.
Okay.
Now.
We can change the value of the input based on this input.
So in the text area.
We can add a value.
After this place holder we just the value is equal to input
and the next things that we need to add.
Is just there aren't change, which is a.
And tracks the change.
And the change is going to be equal to a function which is get the value first.
This one is the value of this text area.
And then.
We get the value added as an input.
So we just set input and we pass this e.
We just it that target dot value.
Okay.
No, we should track our.
Let's refresh the page.
And let's track this state.
I open my def reactive tool.
If you haven't installed it, you can install it via the chrome marketplace and just search for React
diff tools or React developers tools.
And here you can click on components.
Now if we click here and we write something, we should see a change here.
And this is this state.
So whatever we write here first is an empty string.
And then if we write, for example, hello, we see it here.
Now we want to.
Now when we click on this tweet, we want to send this information to fire a store.
Okay.
And firstly, I want to I want this button to be disabled when there's nothing inside the input.
We can simply add this charge, this one in the button.
We just say disabled is equal to when the input is not there.
And also, I don't want someone just at a space and can submit.
So we add a trim at the end.
So now here you see the tweet is disabled.
And also if we added space, we also add the tweet is disabled, too.
So when now we write something, we can tweet.
And also this is space not going to send as well.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
It's going to be sin.
But when we don't have any space, we don't.
We cannot send anything because the button is disabled.
No, let's create the function that we want to send this information to fire the store.
So here in the button, we add on click as well.
And oncolytic is going to be.
Actually a fire function call sent.
Most.
We should get an error because we don't have this file.
We should create this function.
So we go at of top and here just delete this console.log.
We don't need it.
And here we create the function.
We just saw a concert and we named it for the a name it send post and this is going to be an asynchronous
function.
Because we want to wait for the data.
We want to wait for the data.
Data is going to gives us a promise.
So we need to edit async here.
And first thing we need to do, we need to create a reference for our document for a fire store.
It means we need to have a reference.
And then based on that reference, we need to update our.
I have fired Firestone.
So let's create a we just say doc ref.
Okay.
And then this is going to be a weight.
And the method we want to use is at Doc.
So this one should be camel case and we need to import all these things.
And Doc from Firebase and Firebase Forest or.
Okay.
And then the other things we need is just the.
We need to create a kind of collection.
And the collection is going to be from our database that we have created here inside this fire base
that, yes, if you remember, we created this and we export our database data so we can get this one
and add it here.
We just say DB and we can import it from Firebase, that is.
And the name of the collection would be posts.
Okay, now.
After this, what happens after adding the doc?
What we want to add to the documentation is these things.
We want to add, for example ID which is the we can get it from position that user dothe user ID.
So let's test this 1/1 and then.
We continue or we just add another field, which is.
The text, which is coming from inputs.
Okay.
Let's, uh.
See what error we are getting because, uh.
We didn't import something.
So we submit this beginning error that the attack is not defined.
Let's see, we can get the auto suggestion.
Yeah, we can auto import at dark from Firebase Fire Store.
Here we add it and we need to import collection as well.
So let's test it again.
So we didn't get any error.
So let's go to the firebase.
So let's search firebase or if you have it, I have that phone open.
You can go to Firebase, that Google dot com.
And be sure to sign in with the account that you have created the database.
So let's go to console and here we go to our project, which is Twitter version for.
Now we can go to Firebase database.
Now we check that the post is created or not.
So as you can see, I need to.
Initialize it.
So I just say it started with the test mode.
And, uh.
Create the.
Location.
It takes a while.
And, uh, maybe the first attempt didn't bore.
But we can test it again.
Let's see.
Maybe we have it.
I'm not sure.
Okay.
Now let's refresh the page.
No, we don't have any actually collection, so let's try it again.
So we took this on again.
The first two page.
Yeah.
We created the first one.
A post.
We created a collection called Posts.
Then we have a document.
This is a unique ID that is created by fire, face or fire store where we have an ID, which is the
user ID.
We are getting from the session and also we have the text.
So now, for example, if we do something else and treat.
Now we see in other fields.
But I wanted to actually make this one again empty when we when we tweet.
So we can simply do that after this function is triggered.
We can set inputs.
To an empty string again.
So let's try it again.
So we just say hello.
Retweet it now it's gone.
Let's check the database.
Yeah, we have it here.
Let's complete this one more.
We get the image.
We can get the.
Other things, the user image.
So let's go back here and complete this field.
We can get the user image.
Which is coming from cision Dutch user.
That image.
Then let's add timestamp timestamp.
We can get it by using a server.
Timestamp, which is the building function from the firebase.
We need to import it.
Server timestamp.
Let's.
We already imported here in our store.
Here.
Okay.
Uh, the other one the other things I want to add is the name, which is a session dot user name.
And finally, let's add the user name as well.
So let me just say user name.
We need these things actually later to get it.
When we are getting the information, we fill the post section.
Okay, we got everything.
Let's check it tested again.
Just say.
Uh.
Just a nice a treat it.
Okay, let's check.
I think this is and this is the one we get.
Now we have the I.D. name.
Text timestamp.
User image.
So we can get it, for example, test.
You can see the user image, the address, and also we have the user name.
So in the next step.
I want to be able.
To upload an image as well with their input.
So in order to do that, we need to add a reference.
We added input to this image, but we cannot add it inside the image tag.
We can make it an input by the hidden input and then we add a reference to it.
So when we click on this image, we trigger that input and that input is going to open a window that
we pick our image.
Then we create a link of that image.
And firstly we upload it to the Firebase as storage.
Then we add it to our database to link the link that we get from the storage.
To here.
Let's do it step by step that you can understand it.
So now.
We just go to.
To week we go to.
Input that.
Yes.
And we go to that photograph icon.
Uh, let's add a Dave here because I want to add the input inside that Dave.
So here after the photograph icon, we add inputs.
And a type of the input, as I mentioned, is it's going to be filed because we want to upload the file
and I think we can see it now here.
But as I mentioned, I want to hide this file.
This is working, but I want to hide this from.
And when we click on this icon, I want to upload the image.
Let's go back to the input touches and Visual Studio code.
And we change this input to Hidden.
So we we don't see it by default, but we add a reference for it.
So we want to connect this one to this one.
So the reference.
We want to choose.
We want to chair and a name for it.
Just a full file.
Picture ref.
And this reference we need to create it using use the ref a hook of the react.
So let's create it at a top.
Uh, here.
We create a constant and we call it fall, pick a ref and this is going to be equal to use ref and the
initial value should be null.
And uh, let's import this user F as well.
Oh.
We're just here at Youth Reform.
Now, inside this input that we have added here.
We added on click that is going to trigger a function.
We recall this function at.
Image ref.
Okay.
Or we just call it an image.
To post.
And now when we click on this photograph or we click on this div, I want to trigger this input.
So here inside this there we add unclear.
And this oncolytic is going to trigger a function.
Which refers to that file.
Pick a ref, and we just have to, uh, we need to add current.
And we click on it.
We just see click.
We use click method.
Okay.
Now.
Let's test it.
You just saying to add image to post is not defined.
We need to create the function that we called here.
So let's create it real quick to get rid of the error.
So here at the.
Here at the bottom, we create a constant.
We call this fun and image to post.
It's created just living like this.
And, uh, we need to add the error as well.
Okay, so let's test it here.
Now, we should.
So don't, uh, we just click if you click on the image now, we should trigger the inputs, as you
can see.
Now, we did.
Okay, that's working.
Now we need to get to your L for this one.
You created your alpha.
Or if you, for example, choose this image, we need to create a URL, a temporary URL, then we use
that URL to upload to fire storage.
So let's create the URL first.
So inside this F function that we have created, we create a reader.
And we just saying new.
File reader.
This is a built in function from giant JavaScript.
And when we create the reader.
And we also want to get their input off that phone, too, or the input that has a file.
This is the this one this it has the information of the file that we're uploading.
And we say if the that file that e that input has a file.
So we just e that target that files because we want to see all the files, but we want to just get the
first one because we want to upload only one image and if there is a file.
So.
Just put the read.
As Data, Earl.
Add it to this reader and this is going to be this e.
The target that file this one.
Okay.
Now that we did this one, we need to add on load.
Through this reader and this is going to get the the reader event.
And this one is going to give us the earth.
So like this we can now console.log reader.
Event.
Dot target dot results.
Just now we go back to our website and we just upload an image.
Just choose one.
We can open the console log.
You can see the URL here.
You can not see the image with this one, but this is just the data.
But we can use this one to upload to.
Uh.
Let me test this.
I don't.
Think we can see any image here, actually.
Yeah, actually, we can see the image, but you can just see a little bit of the image.
But, uh, this is just saved in the browser.
But we need to upload this one to the database.
So let's close this.
So now we understand that we got the URL for the image.
Now we can use this URL to add it to the a storage section of the firebase.
So we need to.
Let me just delete the console log.
And instead of this, save this one in there in a state.
So we create a state here and we call it.
And selected file or just say sit.
Selected.
Uh.
Sorry.
Just say.
Selected.
File.
And we can set it to set selected file.
Okay.
And this is going to be equal to user state.
And the initial value should be.
Should be null.
And now after we got the URL.
We said it.
We say it inside this hook.
So we're just a set selected file is equal to this.
Let's test it.
We open the reactive tool.
Right click on this.
And, uh.
Now, when we're writing something, we're still getting to this state.
Let's upload the image.
We should see a change here.
Still?
No.
Yeah.
I mean it, I think to click on this tweet party.
No, we got the euro.
Uh, let's try it again.
Refresh the page.
To be sure.
So we go to the inputs.
Select the input to see the hooks.
So we write something you see here.
We select the image.
When we click on tweet, we should see a URL.
Uh.
We don't.
Let's try it again.
No.
Is it?
I don't know what's happened.
It has a delay, so it's fine.
Uh.
Let's first initialize the storage.
So inside the firebase, we go to a storage section.
We just need to change the rules here because now nobody is allowed to read or write inside this storage.
And so let's just remove this part and we publish it again.
Now let's go back to Visual Studio code and just after.
Uh.
The place that we want to and the center post.
Just here.
After this, first we create a reference for the.
Storage is just a.
Image ref.
And this is going to be equal to a riff raff is a building method office storage.
And we just say we get this storage that we have created in Firebase.
This is storage data.
And then we say we want to save it in this address.
And the address is dynamic as well.
We just say save it in a folder called posts.
Then forward slash.
We at that reference we created here doc ref because each document has a reference as well and we want
to get the it.
Sorry.
We want to.
Yeah.
We want to get it to I.D. So each person is going to upload to its own
I.D. It's going to be like a very tidy and it's very easy to read later.
So we just say just the path will be like this.
So.
And after that.
We just put it inside another folder called Image.
Okay.
Now we have the image reference.
Now we can upload it.
So first we say if there is any file, if there is a selected file, is if there is a link that we we
created here, if there is something in the hook, then.
We need to wait for this method just to upload a string because we want to upload a string now.
Uh, it's a URL which looks like a string, so.
And then we just say image ref because we want to put it inside this.
Address.
And what we want to add is that selected file.
Okay.
And finally.
Which method we want to use is data URLs.
So we just say data or save it as a data.
You are.
After this one happened.
When this one uploaded completely, then.
We make another function, we just say a sink.
And this is going to be.
At first we can get the don't download the URL, so we just download.
You are our.
And this is equal to weight.
And we can use a function called get download URL, which is this one is coming from the storage to
it.
So we need to import that later.
So we just say image ref.
Okay, then.
No, I think.
So let's try it now.
We add the image?
We write something and treat it.
So now we are getting error because we haven't import this thing.
So the ref is going to be found.
Firebase is storage then it's storage is coming from Firebase, that is.
And now we have the dark rear.
We we need to import upload string from the storage get.
You are from a storage.
Uh.
I think it's fine.
You just try it again.
So we write something, we add the image.
I retweeted.
So we didn't get any error.
So now we are getting error actually file storage.
Server response.
Okay.
This a fresh page.
Try it again.
I cannot read the property of.
No.
Upload streaming.
Let's check it again.
So here.
We have an image ref we are getting from here.
So far pick.
This is correct.
That is fine.
And.
Know, we don't need this selective fall here.
We just need to get the download you are from the image risk.
Now we tested.
We just write something, choose an image and retweet.
So we didn't get any errors.
So we go to a database and we go to files.
Now we created this post folder and inside this we have the.
User ID if sorry post ID.
This is the post I.D. if you go to if you check now in VR queue, if you go to file store database.
We have it and we are Q Here.
So we got this one and then.
Now.
Inside this, we have a folder called Image.
We have a file called Image and then you can see the image here.
And also this is the URL.
So we click here, we see the URL here.
Okay.
Now we want to add this URL to this virus store here as a new.
Uh, document here.
New field.
So inside this new week in our Q, for example, we add another field called image.
Okay, so here we are.
We finished this one, and now we need to update our documents.
So.
Instead of deleting it when we create it, instead of making a new document, we update our previous
document and we add a new field.
So we need to create and wait here.
And then we just say, Update doc, which is a building method from the fire store.
We need to import it.
So let's say I think we can import that now from foreign store and this is going to get some information
from document.
First is the database and then we have the collection name, which is posts.
After that we add we just said in the post.
Just check the document reference.
With this idea.
Which is here.
And we are getting from the document that we have created.
So go to this one and then add this field here, which is image download.
You are out.
Which we are getting from here.
Okay.
Let's test it again.
And before testing, let's, uh, delete all the everything.
So.
We can.
Uh, see the difference, because we have created too many posts.
So let's delete this.
Let's do this search as well.
Okay.
Now let's test it.
We go to here.
We just write, for example.
Hello.
We had an image.
And we tweet it.
Let's go to.
Here.
We refresh the page in a storage.
Yeah.
We have the post.
Uh, we.
This is the post I.D. and we have the image here.
Right.
This is the image.
And the Earl should be inside the fire starter.
So we go to fire store.
This is the same ID.
And, uh.
Now we don't see it.
It didn't add the image.
Let's see what Sphere Mystic we have done.
Oh, I think.
Yeah.
We didn't import the dock and up to our building for the dock, so we need it imported from Firestone.
So let's test it again.
So just say.
Nice.
And the image.
He tweeted.
Let's go to now.
We have a different post, the new post this year and this post has the image field as well.
If you check the image field.
It pasted here.
It should be the image of the.
Picture that we have uploaded.
Okay.
The other things I want to do when, uh, no, the tweet button is, uh.
Disabled.
As you can see, I want to make it disabled.
When we when we have we don't have an image to.
Or.
Um, maybe that's not a good idea, because in Twitter, you can just tweet without any image.
That's, uh, yeah, that's not a good idea.
So, uh, let's move on to the next step.
The next step I want when my upload the, when I'm uploading, I want to see the preview, the image
of the image as well.
So we have the URL in the set.
We are saving it here in the selected file.
We want to use that one and show a preview of the image here.
So let's do this one.
So you go back to Visual Studio code.
Just after the.
Input it takes area.
So the text area is inside.
Uh.
They're after this.
Dare we just say if there is a selected file?
If someone selected a file, then.
Just share add a div.
We added their fear.
So we cannot do it like this.
Let me add a parenthesis here.
We additive here and in scientist there.
We're going to have our image.
So we just see the ad image and the source would be that selected file.
Let's test.
Test it.
It's a fresh two page.
Let's write something and choose an image.
Choose the same image and retweet it.
Uh.
Let's see.
The problem is, no, I understand the problem.
The problem is when we choose the image, it takes time to be fitted as a.
Sit?
No.
You're here instead of sitting sits.
If sit selected fault exist we should stay selected for.
That's a problem.
We are getting some error sometimes.
So now we go back to our code.
We choose an image.
Now we see the image.
Actually, let's refresh the page and be tried again.
So we write down something.
We choose image.
The image should come now.
So, uh.
Taking too long.
Let's see.
Let's delete this phone.
I mean, be sure that you're uploading something.
So you're right on.
Uh.
But there is some problem here.
After this completing the center pose.
We should actually set the.
Set the selected fall to null again.
Let's do this 1/1.
Let's refresh the page.
No database is empty.
Let's try it again.
We choose an image.
We write something.
So I don't have any upload, but when I'm uploading I want to choose.
Again, we see the image here, so it should be a problem in our code.
So let's test check it again.
Let me pause the video and check it and come back.
All right.
I find the problem inside the input that's inside next to the.
Photograph instead of unclear, we should say unchanged.
That was a problem.
So now we tested again.
Now if you choose the image.
Just quickly after that, we see the image as a preview here.
The other things I want to do, I want to add a cross icon.
So when I click on it, I remove the image.
So when someone is change his mind, they want to add another image, he can just remove it.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code and just, uh.
Here that we're showing the image.
Let me see.
What was it?
You're just here.
Just above this one, we add.
Icon, we can use the icon from hero icons.
So we just need to import it.
So just the x icon and the auto imported.
Let's see it now.
It's huge.
Let's just style this.
He had a class name.
We set the heights to be five and we changed the color to be white.
So let's see.
We don't see it because it went.
Uh.
I think, uh, color lists change the color of black.
And they tried.
Yeah, we see it here, but I want this to be on the image here.
So we changed the.
Position to be absolute and we change the position of this diff to be relative.
So this is absolute based on that.
So now if you test, it's came on the top of this.
Uh, let's make it a little bit bigger.
So just say maybe seven.
And that's fine.
And then let's just style it more.
For example, we change the cursor to B pointer.
Then when I click on it.
So we add it on, click on it.
So when I click, I want to close, remove the image.
So we just say on click and this is going to trigger a function.
We're going to set this selected file to NULL again.
Okay, let's try it.
So when we click on this, you should remove the image.
Now we can choose a different image.
Maybe this one.
Okay.
So we can remove this.
Oh, yeah.
We can also added some shadow effect too.
So they can say text shadow.
Or because it's just a shadow, I think.
Shadow minion.
And the shadow of cholera.
One of be white.
So at least in the dark places, the problem is we see that around the earth.
So we can make it a circle using the for.
Like this.
So we can see the see it better.
And, uh.
Let's close this and add another image.
Um.
Doesn't look that much nice, but, uh.
No, that's fine.
You can you can check it later or I can I can add it as an update.
Let's move on.
And, uh.
So we we've done all the parts, so let's test it again.
Just say test.
A tweet.
And uh, when that, uh, it's uploaded.
Uh, we don't see the image and that the text is gone so we can see it inside the virus or.
So.
This is the test.
This is the image.
Everything is working.
And I want to add some loading effects.
So when I'm uploading so it's not going to this doesn't look like a freezing something I want.
This has some loading effect so we can add a loading stage here at the top.
Uh, just after this selected, we create a constant and we call this loading and we just say, Set
loading.
And this is going to be a user state and the first value is going to be false.
Okay.
Then when we.
Want to send a post.
Just.
That's fine.
Before sending first, we check if the loading is happening.
So if the loading is true.
Then.
We.
We want to return.
We don't want to continue this and fire this loading, so we want to return.
If the loading is false, we want to set it to be true.
So here is just this set loading to be true.
Okay, now and then, after everything happened, everything.
The image is uploaded.
Everything is done for the database.
We want to set the loading again to false.
Okay.
Let's see it inside the.
Reactive tool.
So we click on here and we see we've got two components.
Let's add something like Hello and add the image.
Now we see the image url and this false is loading probably because.
And then when we tweet, the loading will be true.
And when the loading or when it's uploaded, it should come back to false like this.
Okay.
Now we can use this as state to add some loading effects.
The loading effect, I want to add.
I just want this image.
That's, uh, we choose.
Oh.
Refresh the fish.
I want this image to be and to have animation when it's uploaded.
So.
Let's go to the Amish.
I think it was after the Texas area here.
And we will delete this and we just add a class name and this class name is going to be dynamic.
You just say if it's loading.
Now is a valuable.
So let's see what's happening here.
Oh, here should be a dollar sign.
So we say if the loading is true, then.
Let's add it animates of uh.
Just a.
We have a different we have a pulse animate.
So let's test this one.
It's closed this and we add image.
We write something and we tweet.
When it's loading, we see that we have a pulse effect on the image.
Okay.
Now the loading finish, the image is gone.
Uh, the other thing I want to do is when I'm loading.
I don't want to be the person able to tweet.
So I want to remove this part as well.
So, uh, here in this div.
That we had at the bottom.
We can just say if.
It's loading.
Uh, even if it's not.
Loading that show.
It's like this.
So we bring everything.
Inside.
Uh.
I think until.
At least this year.
And this is what we need to add.
A fragment, empty fragment.
And we just until here we bring it and it's not here until the bottom.
Okay.
Now we tested again.
We shouldn't see these buttons when we are uploading.
So we try.
Now it's gone.
It's working now.
Okay.
It's working nicely.
Uh, so that was it for the input section.
I think we have already completed this far.
In the next section, we are going to get the post that we have uploaded and show it here dynamically.
These are just a static that we have created before.
So before finishing the video, let's add everything to get by using it at all.
And we made the we make a message.
They're using get commands.
And the message would be.
We just.
Send.
Data to fire.
Base.
And ad loading.
Effects.
So we push everything to get half and we check what we have done so far.
So we go to get Hoppy.
Refresh the page here.
Now we have three comments and the last committee sent it out.
I made a mistake here.
But that's fine.
So we we've done quite a lot, actually.
So three stages.
We have done the first stage, first uploading just the input section.
Then we added the ability to upload the.
Image.
And then we completed by adding the loading effect.
So it's quite a lot.
If I want to explain it, it can't fix a lot.
But uh, so these three parts we have done so just uploading the input.
You can watch the video again this part.
So we have input, then we have the image and then the loading part.
So see in the next section for getting the information from the database and show it inside the post
section.