All right, in the last section, we have completed the comments and the input box of the post component
in this section, we're going to make this ft section responsive.
If you look at the final version of the project, we see that we have actually three columns.
If I show you here.
This is the.
S..
And we have three columns.
This is the first one.
This is the second one.
And this is the last one.
You can see that this story and the.
The post section occupies actually two parts.
And all and this part, the suggestion and also the mini profile just covers one one one column.
So we have one column here and two columns in the left side.
But if you decrease the size.
In some point, which is the medium size.
Now, still, we have three columns then when we are a smaller than the medium size, we go back to
the one column that's and we just remove this suggestion.
Part.
All right, we go back to visual studio code, and in order to make the website responsive, we just
need to have changes inside the feet that Jesus.
So in the city, yes, we have.
In the men's main section at a top, we make the display great.
And in the mobile sites, we just say the grid columns are only one.
But in the medium size and above, we want to make the grid columns three.
So here.
The first part, which is this story and the post, the great columns are won at the mobile sites.
We don't need to add anything but in the medium size of an above the column.
The column span is to.
So now if you check.
First, we have one caller.
And then and after the medium-size.
This the total is three, and this part is occupying two columns.
Until the end.
But it's all right.
It's completely connected to the left side, so we can avoid this fine by just adding Max with, we'll
just say the modern medium-size fix the max with.
Uh, six.
Excel.
And then we want everything to be at the center, so at the margin IGs photo.
So now if when we increase the size, when we pass the six excel, we see that we have some space at
the left side for everything in the center.
So for this many, many profile fiction just.
We're going to.
For the section, we just, uh, we just say a class name and then we just say after the medium-size,
make the column spin one.
But before that, we want it to be hidden.
So after the media side, instead of being, hey, then we want it to be in line.
Correct.
So first, we don't see that section, but after the media sighs, we see this part.
But now it's completely empty.
But we are going to create it in the next section for the many poorer part fiction.
So, all right, so let's add everything to the guitar by just saying it at and gifts, come it it the
message of make the feet thick and responsive
and they push everything to get top.
So in the get half, if you go here and refresh, you go to the last command.
Let me zoom a little bit.
So we're just at three styles to defeat that.
Yes, we make it.
Having one columns when it's in the mobile size, after the medium size or tablet size, we have three
columns and it's if the meaningful files section is hidden.
But after medium size.
It becomes a one column in the next section, we are going to create the right side there, we start
it a mini profile this section.
So see you in the next section.