Alright.
In the last section we have completed our website.
In this section we're going to deploy it to the internet and the website we are going to use is Verso.
So we need to go to Google and we search for Versal.
In the search results, we click on the website with the URL virtual dot com.
And here this is a free.
Website for your deployment.
And then you can just if you have an account, you can just go to the virtual dot com and here, click
on the Add New and click on project.
And here, if you are, sign in.
And also you are you sign in with your GitHub repository, you can see your GitHub here.
So I can see my IMDB GitHub here.
So I can click on import to auto import this GitHub repository to the internet.
So I'm going to click here on import.
So he's asking me for the project name.
I just say IMDB clone and the framework I'm using is next.
Yes.
So we're going to use the root directory because we don't have an extra root.
This is one is going to use the root directory.
And also we need to add our environmental variable here, which is coming from if you go to the Explorer
section, we put our environmental variable inside this file, dot IMV, dot local.
So I'm going to copy this API key and put it as a name and we just copy this one and put it here as
a value and we're going to add it.
So Versal is going to protect this API key for us and nobody can use it and see it inside the internet,
especially if you use it only on the server side.
So actually next.
Yes, is actually a backend as well.
So even the all the producers and creators of the next year in the last webinar they said virtual next.
Yes.
Is a backend actually framework, not the front end.
So this is going to do for you something that Node.js four two for us protecting and just nobody see
anything that is happening inside the server.
So now that we have added the environmental variable.
And we just put the project name so we can just click on deploy to deploy it.
If there is no error, this is going to take just a few seconds to be finished.
And we can see our website online.
I already deployed here so you can see it inside the IMDB 100 projects dot com.
So if you want to compare your projects and see the final version, but I'm going to show you how to
deploy it again here.
And after the deployment, you can also assign a new domain, if you want to, a specific domain or
some custom domain, you can do it here.
It's very simple as well.
So now I just you can see that we got the congratulation and our website is.
Uh, deployed.
So we can just click on here to go to see our website, which is now inside IMDB.
Dash Clone, Dash, Flame, Dash, ETA, dot dot app, which is the randomly created by Verso.
So let's test, for example, I go to this page.
Yes, you can see it is much faster than the when we we are in the development mode and you can just
go to the about page and then go to the top rate.
Even you don't see this banner.
It's very fast is still we can see this is working here as well.
Let's search for something, for example, Wolf.
As you can see, it's super fast.
And yet.
So if you want to use, for example, a custom domain name, as I mentioned before, you can add it
here.
So, for example, if you click on the continue to Dashboard, you can go to view domains and use a
new domain here.
So example, you add the domain here and then you can add the data inside your domain and see it here.
So you need to go to the DNS of your domain and then add the domain here to easily deploy it with actually
free sstl.
So also you can edit the domain here.
For example, anything that is available.
For example IMDB clone dot Versal dot app.
Let's see.
This is not available.
R&amp;B.
Clone, for example, Dash.
Whatever.
For example, version two.
Okay, now this one is available.
So this is your new address.
So whatever is available you can use, but you always get the dot versal if you don't use your custom
domain.
That was it for creating the project IMDB project.
I hope you enjoyed and learn many things.
See you in the next project.