All right.
In the last section, we have completed the styling of the results related to the web search.
In this section, we're going to work on the image results.
So when we go now to the image part, we don't see anything.
We just see the image search page text here.
We're going to work on it.
The fishing part is very similar to the web search.
The only difference is we need to add some extra parameters inside the fetching URL.
So I'm going to go back to Visual Studio Code and we just copy whatever inside the page that's inside
the web.
We copy this one and we can easily change this one and make it.
So I'm going to copy everything inside this web.
We go to image page statistics.
Select all and paste that one.
And here I'm going to change some things like this Web should be image.
And then
the the URL, the difference in the URL.
We just need to add another parameter here.
We just say and and we just say search type image at the end.
And then.
The error is completely similar.
We still get the items and if the results I mean the data item is not existed, we just say no result
find.
We come back to homepage.
But we want to create another component with a different name, and we want to create another format
of results.
So here, instead of saying web search result, I'm going to say image search results and then let's
create it and let's change the import.
First, this is going to be image search result.
I'm going to create this component as well.
So we're going to create a component called image search.
Results.
The TSX.
And for now we just say ref c e to create a react functional component so we don't get an error.
Now let's check.
So we see that.
We just say something went wrong.
Try again.
So let's try this.
For example, I search.
Hello.
And if you remember, we have added like a ten second of wait.
So the error is image search result is not defined and the search results.
Image Search Results.
Let me copy this one.
It's fine.
I think it's so we have created this one mass search result.
Let's check the imports.
So we go to page that G6 are for the import.
I think this one is broken.
So Image Search results.
I hear this one should be image search results.
Okay.
So probably now we should see something.
So let's try again.
So we need to wait for 10 seconds because we have added another promise here that takes 10 seconds to
be resolved, which is making a delay before the fetching.
Now the fetching is working, but we just get the image search results.
But the things we want to do here, we want to get the results.
Inside the.
This component that we have created in search results.
We get the results here as a props.
And then we can just as style it here and then we get the desired result that we want.
For example, I want to get some for example, let me show you inside the final version.
So inside the final version when we go to the images.
We see that our research for some, I think.
So it's just a we see the image next to each other.
We have the title and we have the formatted URL.
And if you look at the terms down here, you see that the URL is different from the formatted URL.
And we could just to that website if you click on that and then we have some shadow effect as well when
we hover over them.
So this is kind of similar to Google.com.
And let's create this.
So inside this step, we're going to have another div.
First thing first, we need to create another div.
And here we're going to map through the results.
So first things first, we just say resolve that items that map and then we get the results here.
So let me close this.
Okay.
And then.
So we get the results.
And then inside this one, we're going to have a diff.
And also this one should be grouped because when we hover over it, we wanna see the underline inside
that section.
This is similar to the one we did for the other part.
So we need to close this div.
Okay.
Very insider's tip.
So we made the group here.
Okay, We need another dip at the top here.
So just made me create another diff.
And this step is going to be inside that diff.
Okay, so here I'm going to add some key because we are loop through something.
So we're going to add a key which is going to be unique.
And I think the results.
That link is unique.
And then let's.
Let's add something here so we can see inside the page.
First, we want to see the image, but the image should be inside the anchor tag or link tag from the
next Edge's.
So I'm going to add a link tag which is coming from next for Slash Link.
We're going to close this one.
The Edge rift for this one is going to be the result resultant link.
K.
Now, this actually this link is for the image, but the one that we want to go and see, the image
is result.
That image dot context, context, link, context link should be uppercase.
So inside this link, we're going to have an image tag.
We cannot use the image tag of the next yes, because these links are completely different from each
other.
And the rules of the image tag for the next year is to be is to add the URL inside the config file because
it's always different.
We cannot use that in tag image text, so we cannot optimize the images actually.
So the CRC for this one is going to be.
Result.
Dot link.
So this is going to give us the image actually.
And then the for the alternative, we can just add the title.
So we just say results dot title.
K So now probably we can see something inside the our website.
So let's refresh the page.
But we are getting the result, the images.
So the sizes are different.
We need a stylus.
So when we hover over it, as you can see here at the bottom, so we see the URL, each of them, if
you click, it's a different website.
So the link is actually working.
So we just need to style it, make it smaller and something like that.
But before that, I want to add some the other parts first and then we can style all of them together.
So we're going to add another anchor tag or the link tag, and then we can just add the title at the
bottom of the image.
Like the final version.
We're going to have the title and also we're going to have the this link, which is display link.
It's different.
So we're going to have two more links tag.
So let's come back here.
We can just copy this link tag two more times because the other ones are similar.
They are just link.
So I'm going to copy this one two more times.
But instead of image in the second one, by the way, I use all shift arrow down to copy like that.
And for the image instead of image.
In this next one we're going to have.
There's something else.
The link is different because anything we click, we're going to go the same place.
So.
But instead of the image tag in the second one, we're going to have an H two tag we just say.
Result the title.
And finally, for the last one, instead of image, we're going to have a paragraph with the results.
Dot display link.
And you're wondering why I know that display link or title or link or whatever.
You can simply console.log the results and check which one is the image, which one is the link, and
then you can just know how to do it.
Uh, it's very simple.
You can just simply castle log here.
I just assume that you know the basics of.
JavaScript.
So but in my other projects, I'll show you how to do it too.
So here I, you can just use F 12 to go to console.
So after refreshing the page and after 10 seconds you should see the console log.
Let's wait a while.
Okay.
So this is going to.
Hey.
So we're getting an error.
So we get the title actually with the display URL, but we get actually the because this is a server
side component, you get the console log inside the terminal, not in the browser.
Sorry about that.
So here we are going to show you how I choose the display or something like that.
So in each result, for example, we have title here, we have H HTML title, we have the link that
is going to go to that image.
You can see the format is dot jpg.
We have the display link, which is the just the display link.
We have different things.
You can, for example, have more things in your image, more information.
So as you can see, this is the way you get.
So you know that, for example, a title is going to get the title display link shows the display link
and the etc..
Kate.
So this was for the showing the console.
Let's click the delete the console log.
We don't need it and let's close this one.
And then we are getting an error here showing the old property is missing.
I think this is the solver in our code.
We forgot to add the old property.
It's not an important actually error.
We can fix it.
So this is it.
Now, we got all the information, the image, we got the title and also the display name.
Now we we need to style this.
So we wanted to something like a grid.
We want to make it display grid and we show in the mobile one columns.
In the medium size, we want to see two columns large.
We want a three and x, large, four and etc..
So we can simply do that by changing the display here.
The things I want to do, as I mentioned, because this one goes under this footer, some of them.
So we want to have some padding in the bottom of 24 to fix that one.
Always in the each page you have to do it.
So here at a top div, we're going to have a padding bottom of 24, which is going to remove that x,
add some extra space for the footer.
And also we want to add some padding at the top as well.
So after saving after 10 seconds, you're going to see the change.
But so for now, we'll just keep continue.
So for this step, we want to change the display to create and we want to change in the mobile size.
We want to have the create columns of one for the small size and above.
We want to have great columns of two for the large size and above.
We want to have the great columns of three.
And you, you know, the next one, the X large is going to be the great columns of four.
So in any size we have different number of.
Images inside and in columns.
We want to have some padding in the x axis of three and we want to have some space between them.
We can just say space x four.
So let's see what we have here now.
So we already have this space here for the footer.
So this we can see this one.
So we should wait until there is new results.
Come after ten second.
So we we have now in the largest screen for image.
K in this smaller size mobile size, we only have one.
That's fine.
Then we have.
Two in the medium.
In the last we have three and in the x large we have four.
Let's search something else so we get some better.
Images.
For example, we search for hello.
And because these images are a bit long.
So we get a different row here.
So we are getting an error.
Something went wrong.
So let's.
Okay, We are getting, again, too many requests.
So I'm going to say wait a little bit and try again.
So for the rest of the styling, I'm going to stop the server so we don't request too many times.
So let's continue styling everything and then we can see all the results together.
I'm going to show you and explain you, all of them.
So inside this diff that is having the key.
We're going to have some margin at the bottom of.
Eight.
And this is a group that is fine that they have, but the link tag for the first one we're going to
have this one doesn't have any styling, but the link, the image inside it, we're going to set the
height.
To be 660.
So we set the height of this one to be 660.
And when we hover over the group, all these things.
We're going to have a shadow of x large.
So this is going to be a group.
The width is going to be full and we want to.
Make the image to be always in the same aspect ratio.
So we just use object, contain.
And then if you want to, some transition for the shadow effect.
So I'm going to add some transition.
So transition for shadow, we just add some transition to the shadow.
Okay, that's fine.
Is fine.
So after that, for the next tag we're going to have.
Instead of shadow.
When we hover over this group, we're going to have the underlined for this tag H two text.
So for the H to tag.
Or, uh, let's make it for the link tag.
Actually, not the title.
This can be the same thing.
So.
So we're going to add this one to the edge to tag.
So when we group, hover it.
We're going to have the underline.
K.
On the line.
And then finally, we want to truncate if if the title is too long, we want to truncate it to one as
single line.
And let's make the text to be ex large.
For the next paragraph, we're going to have similar things.
You're going to have the group hover effect, which is going to be underlined.
And then we want to make the text to be gray.
600.
Craig So yeah, I think it's finished for the styling.
So let's start.
Start the server and see what we have done using NPM run dev.
So let's see.
So we get an error or not.
So we waited for a while.
Okay.
Let's try again.
First, refresh the page.
Very.
Like this one is in the web.
I want the image.
So we go to the image first.
Okay.
We're still getting the two many requests error.
So I'm going to stop and then come back when the error is gone.
All right.
Now it's working.
I have waited for a few minutes, so I.
This is the result for next year.
For example, if I search for tailwind cease.
First is going to go to the.
When we search, we go to the web.
The delay is for the ten second delay.
We have added.
It's it can be very fast, actually.
And then if you click on image, this is going to be an image.
As you can see, we are waiting for the result.
But in the following section, I'm going to add the loading effect like the final version.
So we're going to see a loading effect.
So it's going to be more nicer for users.
So we are getting the results and we set the height to be 60 for all of them and then this is more beautiful.
So some pages or some images are longer, some of them are shorter.
And also when we hover over it, we see a shadow effect and also underline for both of them.
All right.
So a.
KING That was it for creating the image section.
Let's add this one to GitHub.
I'm going to stop the server so we don't make any requests again.
So we're going to go to the.
To add all the changes here in the source control and then we can add it.
Message saying just add image.
Results.
So let's commit and push it to GitHub and review what we have done inside our GitHub repository.
I'm going to refresh the page to get the new results.
Now we have 15 commits inside our GitHub repository and the last one is ad image results.
As you can see, we inside the image that G6, we have modified this page similar to the one inside
the web page that G6.
The only modification we have done is to add the search type equal to image here to get this search
related to images.
Then if the result is not okay, you're going to just throw an error and see the error.
For example, we had the error of 2 million requests so we could see it inside the console log.
It's very similar to the web.
So if there is no result, we're going to have a no results find and then we can go to the home page.
Then we have changed the also the this component name to image search result.
And we have created this component here inside the components folder, which is just the mapping through
the results and show it in three parts, the image and two links, which one of them is titled and one
of them is the display link for the image.
We have used the result link, but for the link that we go to that page, we're going to use the context
link which is inside the image.
Right.
That was it for creating the image.
In the next section, we're going to work on the pagination of our projects.
So similar to the one in the final version.
We're going to have a pagination next are icon.
So when we click on the next, we're going to see the next page.
First thing first we see the start is different here inside the URL.
Now it's 11.
So we got the first ten image, then we get this second ten image.
And also we have the previous button after going to the next page and we're going to create this one
for the web as well.
So when we go to the Web.
But you're going to have similar things next and previous.
So see in the next section for creating the pagination part of our project.