Alright.
In the last section we made the fifth section responsive.
In this section.
We're going to start with the mini powerful section of the feed that J.S..
In this section we just the here we added there and we put everything inside this there.
Because the reason I'm putting this two sections inside is because we want to make the.
There's a meaningful qualification fix at the top, at the right section.
So when we're going down, we always see this path.
And the right side.
So let me zoom out a little bit so you can see that there's a fix completely on the right side.
And also, if you look at the this one closely, you can see that we have.
Uh, one div that covers.
This part.
And then we have the profile image we have here.
The username and the welcome to Instagram and also we at the end we have the sign out button this two
part actually they are on the top of each other.
So there are two sections as well.
So we have one and two parts.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code and here inside the mini menu profile.
Section.
In order to see it, we have to decrease the size.
So I put here in this website, I have to be high and I open it here so you can see the changes at the
right side.
So here first we have, as I mentioned, we make it fixed and we give it a width of.
380 pixels.
And inside this we have to create the mini profile components.
So inside the components folder, we create a new file and we named a file meaning profile.
Doug.
And we use RF C to create a react functional component.
As I mentioned before, you can get enough this part because in next year we don't need to import react.
So for now, we just add something like.
Many profile and in scientific touches we can import this component, which I say many.
Profile and the use.
Control space to author imported.
And now we can see at the top.
Because both are located at the same directory.
If you just need to write a dot slash menu for a file.
All right.
Now we can see it meaningful at the right side and you can see it fixed at the top.
Now.
So inside the army pathology.
Yes.
Instead of just having a H1 tag.
We create.
An image tag.
And inside the image we just use the same image we use for the header that just this, this image.
But later we are going to actually get this one from the database.
But now we just hardcoded.
I think this is the warm.
Yeah.
This is the one after the plus circle icon.
That image.
You just copy this.
Now we go back to meaningful politics and we pasted inside this 30.
We should see the image here now.
It's huge, but that is fine.
Later, we're going to.
Make it a smaller using children.
See if this the alternative name will be user image and after the image tag we have.
Another diff that has two things.
As I show you here in this day, we have two things.
The user name and also the will come to Instagram.
So inside this thing we have one inch to tag.
Which thing?
Just same code with Farhad.
This is a hard coded.
And later, as I said many times, we need we can get this one from the database with the real user
that sign up in our website.
So we sit here cold with the hand, and just after this tour we have another tag heading tag, but this
one is H3 and it just saying welcome.
To.
Instagram.
And finally at the end, we have a button.
Bottom.
Just saying.
Sign out.
All right, so let's stall everything.
First, we decrease the size of the image so we can see everything clearly.
So in the image tag, the added class name and the classes we are going to use is just the edge.
16 for height 16, which means height 64 pixels.
So we make it smaller and then we make it rounded by using rounded four.
Then we add a border.
Let me assume a little bit.
You can see it nicely.
We added a border, and between the border and the picture, we're going to add a padding.
So we just added padding of two pixels.
So we pushed the image a little bit inside.
We have to pick something.
And also we have the border.
That's it for the image.
Next.
Uh, let's, uh.
Let's first decrease the size.
The next, we're going to start this quote with a hand.
Uh.
We just need to add these classes.
We just need to make it actually only bold.
We just see font bold.
Four.
Welcome to Instagram.
We change the color of the text.
Uh, just the class name.
The font will be the same.
Just make the text a little bit smaller, and the text color would be gray.
And 400.
Next we do the styling for the class.
For the baton.
So we're just a class name.
We make it semi bold.
Not completely bold.
We just font semi bold.
And we change the colour to be blue, but not the very dark blue.
We just saved 400.
And we make the texts a little bit small, like the welcome to image built from the Instagram.
So now everything is next to each other.
We just need to add a flex, add a top in this diff.
That is.
Let me.
Dented a little bit.
So we have image here and we have a div that covering these two things.
Then we have the button.
So in the div.
We have.
A class name, a flex.
So you bring everything next to each other.
Then for bringing everything to the center we can use item center.
And we just use just the five between to have a space between these three tanks, then decrease the
size so you can see it better.
All right.
So we added just the five between to we added the space between there.
But uh.
We just the idea marching at the top of 14 pixels and marching to the left of ten pixels.
For this to hear these two.
We use Flex one to Occupy.
This area completely.
So it pushes this one to the left.
But we can use margin left for four to bring it a little bit at the right side.
So, no, we have the sign out button at the right side.
We have this part which is occupying this size in the center and the profile image.
In the next section we're going to create.
Despite this suggestion part.
So this suggests so far it's similar to story fiction.
We are going to get all this information from the fake M.F.A. package that we already installed for
this story, and we're going to get the username and also we're going to get the jobs after each username.
And these images are coming from this that PR avatar, that CC website.
So let's say first we push everything to get HOF before for getting.
We can't commit and to commit would be.
Create the Mini.
Paul.
Component.
And we push everything to get hot.
Let's review our code.
So we go to our code and we check the last commit by clicking on the now.
So as you can see in the feed that.
Yes.
We?
Added this part.
Here.
We make the class name fixed and also we add a width of 380 pixels.
And also we added the meaningful component here and then we created mini pathologies.
And in the mini pathology pathologies, we have the.
The diff that covering everything, which is Flexbox.
And also we have an image.
For the profile.
And in order for that to pass the work squad would send and welcome to Instagram and also we had the
bottom at the end.
They only think it was a little bit difficult with the flex one.
And I think everything is fine.
It wasn't new.
This fix was new as well.
All right.
In the next section, we're going to create this suggestion part.
If you if you see that's actually when we refresh the page, we always get the new users and the new
images.
So see you in the next section.