All right, in the last section, we have completed the presentation of the page for the results section.
In this section, we're going to complete the image images, just tap.
When we click now on the Images tab, we see the result for the images, but actually in the form of
the video results.
We wanted them to be like the final version that we have created here.
We want to have like a grid showing the preview of the image with the URL at the bottom.
And when we click on, then it goes to the related page.
And also, we have the pagination at the bottom as well.
So first thing we need to do is to change our mark because our mark now is based on the web search results.
Now where we are in this search for the Telvin CSIS with the images, let's copy this object from the
console using.
We open this console using F12 and we have the object that has the items related to the images.
You can see it's all images, so we copy this object and we go to Visual Studio Code.
We go to the response.
Dutchy is here.
And after the export default, we choose everything, we select everything, and we delete them instead,
paste the new.
Objects.
And inside the search statue, yes.
We've changed the mark data from first to true, so we have the data for the image now.
And we can start styling without exhausting our API requests.
Now, in both in all and images, we get the images data.
So let's go to Visual Studio code, and we create a new component.
And we call this.
Image results, Duchess, and we use the RF C for React functional components.
And let's add this one at the end of the.
Results section.
Actually, at the end of the search, that is if you remember in search that, yes, we had the header.
Then we created the search results, and this is going to be a search.
Search where and.
Images, results.
And this is going to be two components.
One is the image results.
And one is the search results, but we want to add some kind of ternary operator to show the search
results.
Bend your elbow has the search type of empty, but when you have this search softer image, we want
to see this component instead.
So here we can add a.
We already have the use router and router, so we can use the router to detect that that query search
type is equal to image or not.
So we're just here.
We just say router does query Dot.
Search time.
If this one is equal to image.
We want to see.
This image results.
Otherwise.
We want to see the search results.
Also, we want to pass the results.
Here, as well as a props.
Now we get the props inside, the image results in image results we can start.
Image resolve is not defined.
Let's see image results.
Duchess, yeah, we didn't import it, yes, so we can use control space to import it, so we shouldn't
get an error now.
So now in the image just tab, we see the images result in all the tab, we see the normal results.
So now we are working in this part.
Let's start our coding inside the image.
Image result is inside this, but you're going to have another day.
And we're going to get the results.
As the props here, so we just the results and here we are going to loop through the results.
Actually, we're not going to look through the results.
We're going to look through the results that items.
Let's check the object again inside the console.
Yeah.
As you can see, inside the items, we have 10, an array of 10.
So each of them, they have different things like this play link format, file format and image.
We're going to use this context link.
Context length is the length of the page that Google's showed the image from.
So if you're going to use this one to click on the image and go to this link.
We can get the thumbnail as well, but it's not necessary, you can use this same, uh, this uh.
You know, this link to get the image as well, but in high quality, but it's fine for now, but if
you want to have a very small thumbnail, you can use inside images, you can get the thumbnail link.
And also, we have the title here, so we're going to use as well.
So that's it.
So let's uh, let's get the look through the result, that item.
Items, result items.
So here we just see results.
Dot item dot map.
And this is going to gives us each individual result.
And we're going to return.
First for you, when to return, it did.
And if you remember, we always have to add a key when we are using map.
So here in cientista and a key which is equal to the result, that link, which is a very it's a unique
things to use.
Now you're getting an error because we use item, it should be items.
And also, we can protect this one by adding a question mark here.
So if sometimes if we did, we didn't like it fitted correctly.
So if this one is not available, we don't get an error.
All right, so.
Here.
And let me show you inside the final version when we hover over this image or here or here we see underline
on under this links, so we need to create a tier with a class of group.
So we put everything inside that there.
And when we hover over that div, we we can we add the underline under these two things, like a title
and a display link.
So.
So let's add that deer here.
They have there is a class of groups and insiders there.
We have an attack.
To with the link and the link is.
As I mentioned, we need to use the result that image dot context linked.
Contacts Link is the link that we used to go to the place.
Uh, here you see, when we hover over it, just pay attention here.
This is the final link that goes to that place.
This is.
It's a first offense.
This is coming from here.
Items.
And inside each one, we have image and inside the image we have.
Context link this link.
Inside this and AMP attack, so we have the.
And image tag and the source for the image is just the result that link.
We should see now 10 images.
As you can see here.
Getting.
And out of boredom is.
We just don't ask for this because the variable.
We can act like a result of the title or something.
Let's see.
So inside the object, we have items so we can see the result.
Yeah.
Title for the year.
Alternative search results dot title.
So we have the image now after the image, we are going to have another amp attack, another attack,
so we have this one as well.
We have the same result that image, that context link.
And inside this EMP attack, we have.
Now we have an itch to tag just we get the result, the title.
So you can see the title under each image, no.
Here.
Next, we have.
Another one in our appetite, let's copy this.
And this one instead of H two.
We're going to have a paragraph.
And inside this paragraph, we're going to have results that display link this play.
Link.
So this is not actually the link we going, but it's a short version of the link.
We call it display link.
All right.
Now we can start adding our styling to the this thinks.
As you can see, not only we have one column and when we increase the size, actually the images get
super huge, but we don't want like this.
We want it to have four columns when we have a big screen.
Then we have three, two and finally one.
We can achieve this one easily using a grid system.
So here in the second.
They're at the top here.
We had a grid.
So we changed the display grid and then for the mobile size we we make the grid to have a one column.
All right.
This is a default for mobile.
Then we say if the screen is bigger than a small.
You change to create two two columns.
Then.
In the, uh, in the large.
If screened, we want.
Three columns.
And finally, for the ICC's largest screen, we want to have.
Four columns.
So let's check.
Now we have one as soon as we got to a certain point, we get to the end.
Here we should get three and finally, we should get four.
Yeah.
So, no, everything is nice, but we don't have any space between the images, and it looks a little
bit messy here.
So let's add some space between these tanks.
So here at the end, we can add this.
First, we added padding x axis of tree.
So we is squished them next to each other, and we had a space between the items of.
For the space of four, so now we have some space between the items.
And you can see here.
And also, the size of the some of them are longer, some of them are shorter, so the heights are different,
so we're going to fix these things as well.
So we have a very neat display, so let's finish with this part.
So we have we have already finished.
Let's add some space between the these options and the top by just adding at a top the margin top of
four.
So you see space then for the image itself.
We have a.
We just have a class name.
First, we will just add a shadow when we see someone hover over everything.
So when they hover over the group off, I mean this, they're in everything.
When someone or hover over them, we want to add a shadow.
Of X large.
This one.
So no one, we hover over this.
Yeah.
Shadow.
I see the sizes of difference.
So are you going to fix this one?
And after that, we changed the width to be full to we always have a full size.
We had a height of 60.
And we add the objects.
Contain to always have this if it don't scratch it, stretch the image.
You see now the images in the similar high of 60, and some of them are smaller, but we have a space
on top and bottom equally, so it's quite nice now.
Actually, I had to choose something else, like we have a different images, so look better, but we're
going to test this one with the real data, so.
OK, so that was it for the image.
Let's solve these titles as well, so.
The first title is here to tag.
Uh, let's uh, uh, for the for the image here we have it a tag that covers everything.
Actually, that's a tax she didn't cover.
So we have to bring this one outside.
So now.
This this is the correct one.
So this attack includes the image, this attack includes an H2 and the other one is the P-TECH.
So this is a correct way.
Up doing that, and then we have a diff that covering everything with a class of group.
For the first, a tank.
Let's.
The first one was just and for the first one, we don't need actually any classes for the second one.
We have, uh, we just changed the size of the tax.
Uh.
Well, I think the size this fine, we just added on the line when we hover, so we just say if someone
hover over the group.
We want to add the line, so we just say under no.
That's fine now.
And then we have, uh, the same things for the next one.
So we copy this for the other eight targets for.
Now, if you hover over, we see the underline under them.
And then the other things I want to do is just in the H-2 tank, I want to add some.
First, we want a truncated.
So when we have a longer title, we want to have a small like a truncated, especially in the bigger
screen, you see, this one is truncated here.
So when we have a long title, we have truncated.
Sue, this down again.
After the tragedy, we have other things, we just change the text size to be x large.
So we have a bigger title.
Then for the P tag.
Here.
We had a class name, and the classes we want to use is first, we want to change the color of the text
to be 600.
Now it looks.
Yes, sometimes the images get big in the small size.
So here.
That's fine for the mobile screen.
Let's add some margin bottom, so we have some space between the images.
We can do it here inside this there, that they're just under the map.
Here we an emerging bottom of faith.
So we have a little bit of space between them.
That looks fine now.
So let's go at the pagination as well.
The bottom that is very simple because we are the created the patient issuance button.
So just under this year, we added dear and inside this therapy at the pagination bottoms component.
And we're going to imported using contour space.
We have the pager page initials here.
But in the larger screen, we see that it connects to the world because now we don't have the.
This tiling that we had before in the.
In a way, we will limit it to here, but in the image we don't have, that's fine.
We can just add a margin, laugh at this there.
Of 16 to fix this one.
Now we see this one here and also when we have a bigger screen, we have a little bit of a space you.
So let's try our real data.
Let's go to the thermostat, yes.
And here.
In front of the constant, constant mock data, we change the true to false.
So we're using now the real data to refresh the page.
Let's search something else, for example, next chance.
Now we end it first in the whip results.
Let's go to the images now we see the images.
The first image is from Wikipedia, so we go to the next page and this image is found next just to watch.
So everything's working correctly.
So that's the that's that was it for the Web site.
We some some small things left us still.
For example, in the home page, we still didn't link these buttons like about store Gmail and images.
We're going to fix them in the next section, and we're going to deploy our website after that to virtual.
So first, let's and everything to get off.
So we just get at.
And we add the comments with a message of.
And.
Image results component.
And we push everything to get half.
Let's review our code.
So we refresh the page here, and we go to the last comment by clicking on this.
So we're going to be created a component called image result.
Yes.
So this one is just the way we look through a results that items we added three links, one for the
image, one for the title and one for the just the display link.
And also we added the page pagination button at the end.
Furthermore, we added a ternary operator inside this search duchess.
We just said if the router that Quarry does search time is equal to image.
The.
Image results, component, otherwise show search results, components.
We just changed our mark at the beginning.
So we just changed the mark from the normal weight result to the images result.
Yeah, that was it for this section.
In the next section, we're going to first fix these bombs and then we're going to deploy our website
to restore.
So see you in the next section for the deployment.