All right, in the last section, we have created the mini profile section of the FT that J.S..
In this section, we're going to create this suggestion area.
If you look at the final version of the project, it can see that the suggestion area has a few parts
resume a little bit.
And we can see that.
We have a part at a time that's just a suggestion for you, and there is a bottom and the riots saying
seal, then we have.
And in other parts.
Which has.
Few sections first is just a profile.
Image, then we have the username.
Yeah, we're going to create using minifigure package and also we're going to create these job titles
using minifigure as well.
And finally, we have.
A follow button at the right side.
OK, let's go back to our visual studio code.
And first, we create the component.
With the name of suggestion.
So this is our website.
So we close the mini for fall of that year and the head of the chief.
Inside the feed that yes, we need to at the suggestion.
Suggestion part.
So we go to the components and we create a new component called a suggestion or suggestions.
But yes.
And then we create a.
React functional component using RF C.
We can delete this import, react from react and inside a return part.
It create another div that covers the suggestion for you part.
Before continuing on this suggestion that, yes, we need to import suggestions that as to this year,
so we create an attack here suggestion and the use counter space to auto import this component.
All right.
So we go back to suggestions that, yes, and here you create the Etch three with a hardcoded same suggestion
for you.
We can see here after that, we have a button.
Saying.
See are.
Well, just this.
Yeah.
So let's say a little bit, establish fun.
So let's make it flex, so we bring everything next to each other.
And we used just the fight between to have a space between the two elements.
We push them to.
Each side of the place and then at some margin button.
In Button of the five.
So we can add that.
The next part.
And also, we make the text the size of the tanks.
To be a small.
So the next one is just the let's establish its three part.
We make it.
Bowled by using font balls, the next thing is just to change the color of the text to gray.
Four hundred.
And for the bottom, we just need to.
Have we changed the text color to?
I think this color gray would be fine.
The gray 600 and we changed the boldness of the font.
To symbols, so we just say found a semi bolt.
All right.
We need a little more space at the left, so at the top level here because we want everything to have
the same amount of space around there.
So we just imagine top of four.
So they push it a little bit down, and we use the margin lift of 10.
Now, everything is aligned nicely, so we need to go to the next part, which is here.
Creating our suggestion section.
So in order to have these things, we need to first install the many fake hair, but we have already
installed for this story's part.
If you remember false stories, we used many fake as well.
We just need to import minifigure here.
All right.
We just write down in port.
M.F.A..
From Faker.
So here.
Just before they return, we create a state and we call it suggestions and we just say sit suggestion.
And we call it to use the state.
We import use the states using the space.
Before getting the auto suggestion, we can see it here at the top.
And the initial value of this stage would be an empty array and after that we use.
Use effect to fetch data from the, uh, from the minifigure.
As soon as the page is loaded, so first we put to use effect as well, and we.
Creative callback function and in scientist function, we create the constant color suggestions and
the equal suggestion to minifigure.
I think you are already familiar with these things because we have done this one before for this story's
part.
So in order, we want to create five.
A profile, so we need to just use array and amount of area is fine.
And after that, we get the number of index.
So here we can see it now.
We used minifigures era to create five array and we get the index of AI for each of them.
Then we return.
And object here.
The object includes username, which is equal to a mini faker.
Dot username, the username is a function internal function of fake package.
And, uh, as I mentioned before, we need to specify to the language that we want the user name to
be, we use the locale of English.
And also, we want to use a name to be lowercase, so we just say to lower.
Case, and we need to open a set of parenthesis because the function the next one is.
Job title.
And the job title will be equal to.
You can't see that I'm getting the suggestions from Tap Nine.
But the job site doesn't have any local.
Look.
And uh, yeah, that's it.
We're using a job title function of the minifigure to get the job title.
And also we want the idea which is equal to AI, which is this AI is coming from here.
And finally, after these things, we set this suggestion to it, this suggestion constant.
So we feel this state.
OK.
Let's console.log.
So just see the result.
It's a fresh page.
We're getting an error of saying fail to process, A. L., A. Unreachable, McCaw.
An object letter is invalid.
We made a mistake here, and we need to put a clone here to fix this fire and refresh.
Beginning another era, they're saying that
failed.
Yeah, that's fine.
So let's open the.
Dev tools and console using F12.
Now we're getting an array of five here that has the user name, job title and I.D. Yeah, everything
looks fine.
So we just need to look through this array to to show them here.
So in after this.
There, which is for this part, we create.
We look through the suggestion.
And we just the suggestion that map and we get each suggestion.
And we return it.
We create a tiff here, and in cientista, we just need to get an image.
Image tag and S4C would be, uh, if you remember we were using before the PR avatar in the story that
as here for the image.
So are you going to use the same thing?
So I copy this.
Code.
And bring it here, but I explain you for your.
For your review, you just saying.
So the.
So, yeah.
This phone book.
Yeah, we have the basic URL, which is here.
PR Avatar does CC and Dennis four in front of the IMT, we put.
A random number between one and 70, because this website only offers 70 images.
So we are getting randomly five images from these 70 images, so now we're getting these images here,
but there are huge.
So we are going to install it soon, so after this image.
But first, let's make it a smaller so we can see the next parts better.
So we have a class name here and the size of the image, the height would be 10.
We make it circle by using round full.
We add a border and we add a padding of.
Two pixels between the border and the picture.
And this is similar to this image, but besides is a smaller.
After this image, we have another div that covers both the user name and the job title.
So for the username, we use it to tag.
And we put the suggestion.
Dot.
User name.
So if you remember, we created this username here inside this suggestions, but we are getting each
of the suggestion here using math.
So now you're getting the user names as well after the user name.
We use each three tag to get the job title.
So it's a suggestion dot job title.
OK.
Let's solve this one as well, so we bring them next to each other using Flex.
No, actually, we don't want them to be next to each other.
We want these two to be next to each other, so we use the Flex at the top.
All right, and then let's bring them to this center using eye test center.
This is for horizontal and vertical level, then we use.
Justify between to push everything to the other side.
And we have a margin of three.
But we want this to be next to the image.
That's why we use Flex one here to occupy the place from here.
And after that, the ad a marching left off for.
For H2, we at.
The class name.
Uh.
We just want it to be semi semi bold.
And also the caller.
The color is OK, we just, uh, yeah, make it the Texas small.
OK.
For the job title.
I'm getting a lot of suggestions from top nine, but some of them, OK, yeah, we keep the text, Greg.
Four hundred make it great, but I don't want to be.
I don't want it to be bold.
We just make the text as small as four.
And in case someone
has a big job title, we truncated.
And we we maximum width of this part, I want it to be 230 pixels, so it would be around here.
So after this day, we have.
The bottom that's saying follow.
So here we just say follow.
And let's establish and make it blue.
So the font is semi bold and the text color is blue.
Four hundred.
And make the Texas moral as well, so.
OK, that's one looks fine.
No, each time you refresh the page, you're getting a new username, new job title and new image.
And here.
So in the quote, we just don't need the.
Console.log anymore.
And let's push it to get her using get at and get command for putting a message, and the message would
be build.
This suggestion, part of the.
After each component.
And we push it to.
Get her.
Now let's review the code, and but we have done here, we refresh the page.
And this this is going to be the last commit, which is build this suggestion.
Part of the faith component.
So in feta cheese, we added this suggestion here, and we import it there.
And in suggesting that the imported.
We have imported the minifigure, the minifigure, local use, the state and use effect, and we made
a state here called suggestion and used.
Use the fact to.
To call the M.F.A. package and create five profile.
User name and job title.
And finally, we set to this this suggestion is stay with the constant suggestion and then we return.
And we map through this suggestion array.
And we got the image from the P PR amateur website, we create a random number for each image.
And finally, we we put the user name and the job title inside the issue and industry.
Yet that was it for this part.
In the next section, we're going to start with the authentication, and I'm going to introduce you
to and next off, so see on the next section.