All right.
In the last section, we have completed the delete functionality.
In this section I want to add some transition effect.
When we delete or add a new post where we don't see it suddenly pop up or remove, I want to add some
transition effects.
I want to add a package called Framer Motion that gives us all this transition and opacity animation
easily so we can search for frame or motion.
And this is the website for Framer Dotcom Motion.
But we can have the NPN package.
Here if you go to NPN just dotcom and frame in motion.
We can't get the instruction how to install it.
So as you can see, it's a very popular package.
It has more than 1 million downloads or installation weekly.
First, we need to install it.
So we go to get support and for a quick start.
We just grabbed this line of code and we got back to Visual Studio code.
We stopped the server using Control C and we pressed Y and.
We just, uh.
Paste the code that you have copied.
In order to use it, we just need to.
Wrap the things we want to have, for example.
In 50 years we have a mapping and to the posts.
We just need to wrap this one with something called animate.
Presents.
See if you're getting the suggestion and it's coming from frame in motion.
We need to wrap this map.
Here.
Okay.
Then we need to wrap this.
Host inside motion that this it's just a motion.
Uh.
But if you close it and.
I mean.
We need to import it too.
So we import it.
Animate presents from frame in motion.
We just need to add motion to make.
Simple as that.
Now we need to add to what type of animation we'd like to have.
First thing first, we need to add a key here, because all the map, everything inside the map should
have a key.
And then we can add a initial value.
So initial value for this one and should be inside the object and the opacity amount to be zero.
The initial value when we this animation starts then I want to animate and has animation.
Until the capacity you get one.
And then when the animation finish, I want to exit it.
Bit capacity zero to.
Okay.
So first you start with zero, then one and then zero again.
So let's see it inside our application.
Let's add something.
For example, I just say let's start the server first.
Let's refresh the page to be signed and.
To be able to add a post.
Okay.
No adipose.
You just.
Check.
When they added, we see that a pause comes with a transition.
You see that's flashing.
We can actually increase the duration of the animation by just adding here transition.
And we changed it.
Time of different transmission duration to, for example, 1/2.
So now see, it's different.
For example, let's add something else.
Hello.
What?
See when we deleted also it.
It will be deleted by transition.
That is more nice because suddenly remove it.
It's not going to be nice.
Now let's add the same transition to this.
What's happening in section two?
When?
Now we add it.
Click on show more.
We see as suddenly new news comes.
We can add the same sort of animation to this one.
It's same things we did.
Uh.
So we need to go to widgets.
And inside the which is let's see where we wrapped our news.
Uh, yeah.
This is the new section.
So we should have the animate presence wrapping.
All the map section.
And we have the motion Dave rapping inside.
So just a motion.
That's their.
Wrapping this.
And we need to import them as well.
So we import animate from frame in motion and also.
Motion.
So Grandma emotion too, I think we are the important or not was just added manually.
Okay.
So as we did before, we need to add a key and the key would be the same article, the title we can
use.
Then we add the initial value, which would be a opacity.
Uh, zero.
And we have the animals.
Opacity one.
And finally, we have the exits.
All right.
That's why.
Initial opacity.
Yeah, we missed the.
Curly braces here.
Okay.
And finally, we have the exit.
Each has the capacity of zero.
Okay.
And also we can add the transition to.
So a transition.
With the duration of 1/2.
Let's take it inside the browser.
Let's reload the page.
Now you can see already the transition.
We can click on more.
It it.
Beautiful faith trance animation.
Okay, let's do the same things for the world to follow.
Six year.
So who to follow we can copy these things so we don't need to get is so hard to follow section it starts
from.
Uh, this deer.
This is the map.
So we covered this map with the.
Animate presents.
Until here and then we copy this motion that there and the.
They sit here and be close it.
At the end.
Uh.
It's here.
Okay.
Let's check.
Here.
We added a key article, the title, but the key should be the same as the key here.
So if we replace this one with this.
Let's see it now.
Now we click on here.
Now see, it comes with the transition.
Okay.
The other transition I want to add is for this menu because it's as you can see, the hover effects
quickly change from one to another.
You can simply add a transition here as well.
So we need to come back to Visual Studio code and we go to we close everything and we go to a styles
global set CFS.
This is that hover effect.
At the end, we can add a transition.
This is just telling us this class.
It's not related to frame in motion or something.
It's just to say transition and a duration.
We're just say 500 and we we want the effects to be is out.
Okay.
Now, you see, it's a bit different and also affects the other one as well here.
These icons now, they have a phase transition effect.
Okay.
And see.
Yes.
Okay.
And also, let's add the transition for having effect on these restrictions, like how to follow.
You see the gray, however.
Let's do it for them too.
So we go to.
Widgets.
Uh.
For the news.
We should go to news that Jesus.
And.
Let's see where we have we have a our effect here.
Actually, the duration is 200.
Let's make it 500 and is out.
Okay.
So let's test it again.
That's better.
For the whole to follow.
We need to go to visit.
And, uh, here, when we have a hover effect, it's at a transition.
With the duration of 500 milliseconds, which is just a half a second, and then with the ease out effects.
Okay.
Let's check.
Yeah, we can see the transition effect.
Okay.
That's it for this part.
Let's add it to get half.
We just take it and all.
And we may make a message by just saying get.
Comments with the message of ad animation.
Effects using framer motion.
Okay.
And the push.
Everything to get to.
Let's check what we have done so far.
We refresh this page by clicking on this tweeter.
Now we have 18 commits.
The last comment was committed, right, 11 seconds ago.
Which is an animation effect using frame and motion.
In fit that we added.
We brought.
Animate presents and motion from frame in motion and be covered the posts that map with animate presents
and also covered the post component with the motion that can be added the initial value animate and
exit.
And also we add a transition of 1/2 duration.
Okay.
In news that is, we added the same things we did with, uh, in.
News that.
Yes.
Yeah.
We just added this transition, I think this part but in which it that yes we we added the animate presence
and motion dev for the.
Well to follow section.
Here is the full to follow section.
Here is the new section.
This one was the new section.
The first one is the.
Uh.
Yes.
Why?
We had a two times.
News that.
Yes, I read it that.
Yes.
Touché.
Now.
He did it out of here just two times.
Okay.
And finally, we in global success, we added transition duration 500 and is out of favor and we have
installed frame and motion to our package dot JSA.
Okay.
So, uh, I see you in the next section for more functionality.