All right.
In the last section, we have completed the transition effects, the feeding effect to our website.
In this section, we're going to add a model pop up.
If we open the if you click on the comment section, we want to open a window at a top that let the
users to add a comment to our website or to this post particularly.
Uh, in order to do that, we need to add a state, but we cannot add a component level of state.
We want to add the global states because we want to add it on top of everything.
Not only this component.
In order to do that, we need to use we want to use a package called Recoil.
Recoil is estate management library.
And it's just created for React.
And it's let us to easily add global states to our websites.
So let's search for recoil.
And the website is Recoil Jazz Dot G, which is a state management library for React.
We click on this one.
And in order to start, we can just go to a get started.
And we already installed our application.
We need to install recoil first.
And then we need to add it to the route there after two years.
We cover our apertures with the recoil root.
And finally we need to add atom atom as a piece of state.
For example, here, as a example, they have a Texas state.
They made an atom for it.
Each atom has a key and also the default value.
In our case, we want to have a state that is open.
And we want it to be false by default.
And the name would be open to states or something like that.
Okay.
And finally, we can get we can get that to state in any component using used recoilless state.
And we can change the state using CET that the name of the state that we have created.
Okay, so let's start installing first.
We just copy this MP and install recoil.
We go back to Visual Studio code, we stop this server and we paste it here.
And before going to the next step, let's add the component model component and add it to the index
that.
Uh, J.S., let's close these things.
Inside index.
The Jazz.
Which is the homepage.
Inside the pages.
We added a section before for model.
So we create a component and add the components here.
So here, inside the component, we create a component called.
We just call it.
Comment model j yes, we use rf c.
To create a reactive functional component, we can delete this import.
Then let's import this and bring it inside the index that just so just here we just say comment model.
And we need to import it as well.
Okay.
Let's just start the server and check it on browser.
So let's go back to our website and we refresh the page.
Now we should see that probably comes around here because it's after that.
So now we can see the comment model here.
This is not going to be here because we want to create a window later.
We're going to install a package called React model and replace this one with that components.
But for now, we can see it here.
So we have installed the recoil.
Now.
The next step for the recoil is just at the recoil route.
Our wrap our application with recoil route.
So we will need to go to after J.S..
Underline underscore after test and recover.
First we import.
Uh, recoil.
Recoiled, Ruth.
From Recoil.
Then we we need to wrap our application.
Just here.
It's fine.
Yeah.
So now we can use in every component.
This is all the components in our website.
We can use the whatever we define inside the recoil.
Now we need to create the atom.
If we look at the documentation, the next step is create an atom.
An atom represents a piece of state.
So adults can be read from.
And return to from any component.
So we create the atom, but we can use it in all the components.
So we just copy this line of code.
Uh, just, uh, example one and we go back to our, uh, application.
We close all the folders and we created outside here in this level, for example, we just create a
new folder.
They call it Aton.
And inside the atom, we create our model atom.
So we're just a model atom.
Dot js and we paste a link.
Okay.
And the state we want to add is model.
So we just changed the text.
Tomorrow.
And the initial value, the default value would be false because we want the model to be close.
When we are, we just come to our website and then when we want to open it, we press on that like a
comment chat icon and open it.
Okay, now we can access to this anywhere in our application, in any component.
So for example, comments model, we can have access to it.
So if we go to comment model and here we import, you need to import two things.
First thing is to use a recoil.
A state.
So instead of use a state, we used to use recoil of states.
And this is coming from recoil.
And because we want to use the model estate that we have created inside the atom folder.
So we just get the model estate from where we created and outside this folder.
So we come back one folder, we go to it inside the atom folder and we choose model atom.
And here at a top inside our component.
First we create a state.
The name of this state is open.
And set off an.
And with you, we just use.
You use.
This is going to be equal to use recoilless state and the.
Even the initial value is coming from the this more at home too.
We define it faster, but we don't need to say false here.
We just say model estate.
Okay, so we use this model state.
Now we can just show it here, for example.
Uh.
And scientists there.
We added each one.
We just first we just set up the comment model.
And under this, we just say if this is open.
Dan?
Just add one.
And we just say.
The model.
Is open.
Okay.
Let's check.
It should be closed now as a default.
They say item is not defined.
Let's check.
So which file was it?
Sorry.
Uh, in moral atom.
That.
Yes.
Uh.
We didn't import ATM, actually.
We just copied this one.
So we need to import.
At home.
From.
Recoil.
This is just a built building function from recoil.
That should work now.
So this refreshed.
Uh.
In another era.
Invalid argument atom or centre but got undefined.
So.
Model stage one of the stage.
Let's shake it again.
Yeah.
We didn't export this.
We need to export it.
Yeah, that's a problem.
When you copy paste from a website, you don't check.
Okay, so don't copy paste.
Uh, here.
Let's check again.
Okay.
That's okay.
It's not showing.
This model is open because the default is false if you change the default to true.
We should see it.
The model is often okay.
And but we don't want to do it like this.
We want to when we click on this comment, we want to comment icon.
We want to open it.
Let me add another.
Small ones, so we can easily click here and open this.
So we want to add on click on this chat icon.
And each time we click on this one, we want to change the.
Uh, the open.
S estate to true or false depends on the previous estate.
So we go back to our post.
Yes.
And we just search for chart icon.
Here.
First we add on click here.
And this is going to have a function that is going to set.
They're open, but we need to create the set open first at a time.
Just leave it like this and be created out of top.
We just a concerts.
Often.
Set up an and this is going to be equal to not use a state.
Use recoilless state.
Now we need to import recoil a statement from recoil here.
And this is going to take that model.
State's death is coming from at home.
So we need to import model state from atom to now.
Uh, in the chat icon.
When we click on the chat, we should open it.
So now we click here.
We open the.
The model is open.
Okay, but when you click it again, nothing happens.
But I want to just say.
If the of whatever is open is just do the opposite like this.
If the open is to make it false and if it's false, make it true.
So now we just can, uh, reverse it.
Each time when we click opens, click on.
Okay.
So that was it for the recoil part.
In the next section, we're going to install the package called React model and we're going to have
a real model with the information of this post and the person can reply, okay, so we just add whatever
we did in this repository, in this command to the our repository.
And we just create a message.
We just say install.
Recoil.
Install.
I just say install.
And in Parliament require it, push it to get half.
Let's check.
We refresh the page.
You go inside the Twitter.
Now we have 19 commits.
We have created 19 videos so far.
And the last one is install and implement recoil.
So we we created a aton, which is this piece of state inside a folder called Atom.
We imported Atom from Recoil and we export mortal state.
The initial value is false.
And the key for it is model states.
Okay.
It should be a unique I.D..
Then.
We create a component called Common Model that yes, we have imported or used.
We call a state to create a piece of the state.
And we got the initial value from the atom, which is the model state that we have created inside atom.
And we just say if the state is true, sure.
The model is up.
Okay.
And so posted GSV added an on click.
Two set to open in the opposite estate opposite of its previous estate.
So we created the estate using used record estate here.
And also we have imported use record estate and model estate here as well.
We have installed.
Recoil.
Okay.
And then inside, after two years, we wrapped our application with the recall routes because we want
to have everything inside the recall in every components and inside index that yes, we just added the
component that we have created which is common to model.
Okay.
So that was it for this section.
In the next section, we are going to create the, uh, model we have.
We are going to install a package called React model.
Okay.
So in the next section.