All right.
We'll come back.
In this section, we're going to install next year 13, and we're going to have the first template.
I have put the final version here for our reference.
You can visit this on Google dot hundred JS projects dot com.
As you can see, we have a whole page similar to Google.com with the header.
We have the search box with the I am lucky button as well.
And also we have a footer here which shows the location of our country.
And we can search here, for example.
I can search next JJ's.
Which is going to redirect us to another page, we can see a loading effect first.
And first we see the result for the web.
And also here we have the pagination.
So when we click on next, we go to the next page.
And also we have the ability to see the images for this search term.
We have the loading effect is specifically for the image.
And also we have pagination here as well.
The other things we can do in the home page, we have the I'm feeling lucky button, which is going
to fetch.
A random word and it is going to show us the result related to that random vocabulary.
So we're going to start by installing the next year 13.
So if we go to Google, so we have Google, but I'm going to search here in the real Google next J's
13.
In the search results, we see that we have a website with the URL better dot next year dot org.
This is the documentation related to the Nexus 13 because it is in the beta version.
They have their special URL for that.
So we click on that.
We're going to.
Their documentation, as you can see here.
Let me zoom this a little bit.
So as you can see, the next day's documentation is divided into two sides.
The first one is the beta one, and the other one is this table.
So the next year's version that we are going to work on is the beta version.
So we're going to work on this version.
And here on the left side, we click on installation, So we go to the installation part.
For the system requirement.
We need to have Node.js version 16.8 for later in order to be able to install next DJs.
So I'm going to open the common prompt.
This is the terminal I use.
You can use any terminal you prefer.
And here we can just write down Node dash V to check the version of the node JS that we have.
We have the version in my computer.
I have the version 18.13, which is enough because 16.8 is enough.
If you don't have that version, you can simply search Node.js on Google.
And here just in the search result, go to next year dot org.
Here.
You can download the latest version, which is the long term stable one version 18.14.
So this is the version I recommend you to install.
And this is the beta version which is not stable yet, so just install this version once you install
it.
Come back to the documentation and here you can see the automatic installation.
So to automatically create a new Nexus project using the app directory, we can use this command inside
the terminal.
So we can copy this one, which is include the NPCs utility Create next app app add.
Latest dash dash experimental app.
This experimental app is going to add the app directory for us and also some some codes inside the next
step config file.
So I'm going to copy this.
And I go back to the terminal.
I go to inside my desktop and I want to go inside a folder called Force.
You can create it anywhere.
So I want to create it inside a folder called course.
I'm going to paste the code.
You can press enter, and this is going to ask you the name of the project.
So I'm going to call this, for example, Google.
Clone next.
Uh, next year's version.
I just say next year's 13.
So I'm going to.
Uh, press enter.
This is going to ask more questions.
The first question is.
Would you like to use TypeScript with this project?
So I don't want to use TypeScript, but if you want to use Cypress Grove, you need to say yes, I'm
going to say no for this one and asking me to install SE link, which is going to help us for the.
Some suggestion about the vocabularies and the RA it suggests use some coding correction for you.
So I'm going to have this in my project.
And also the next question is would you like to use CRC directory with this project?
So I'm going to say yes, this is going to create an extra folder called CRC and the app directory would
be inside this folder.
And also what import alias would you like to.
Would you like configure?
So this is going to have an alias for example this add sign over slash the star.
The ad sign for Slash is going to be the root of your projects.
And for example, if you want to go to the components folder, you just write down add forward slash
component for Slash, for example, the name of the component I'm going to show you later inside the
project, but you can just choose this one for the alias.
So now the selection process is started.
This is going to install packages like React React next, next font, SW link and SW link config next.
I'm going to stop the video.
I'll be back when the installation is completed.
All right.
So the installation process is completed.
Now we can just go inside the folder that we have created, which is in my case is Google Chrome next
year 13.
So I'm going to write this one after this CD, CD Dash clone.
So you can just press tab to get the suggestion and then we press enter to go inside the folder.
And here we can use code dash dot to open the Visual Studio code with the this folder to be open as
the default folder of the VTS code.
So I'm going to press enter.
This is going to open the Visual Studio code.
But I'm going to use Visual Studio Code.
But you are free to use any text editor you are familiar with.
So we wait for the installation and initialization of the Visual Studio Code.
I'm going to show you the folders that is created for us.
So let me zoom this a little bit.
So inside the left side you can see we have this folder is for the installation, like a node modules.
We don't need this folder to check.
The next one is the public folder.
The public folder contains the assets that the user can have access to inside the browser.
For example, the fabric on the images and etc..
Then you have the C folder that is created for us.
This folder is included includes the app and the pages folder.
The pages folder is actually for the next year's version 12, but still you can use it.
And also it still works for you.
But the new version.
Next is 13.
It uses the app directory.
It's kind of simpler and more neat to use.
And also, if you want to have API, you still can use this folder.
We're not going to use this folder.
I'm going to delete this folder for now.
So you can delete it.
But inside the app folder, inside the CRC, we have few files.
First file is the global.
This is the global styling of our projects, which is going to be replaced by the styling of tailwind
CSS.
So we're not going to use CSS in our project.
So I'm going to teach you how to deal with this one.
So I'm going to completely delete everything inside this globals that CSS.
So another folder is page that modulus CSS.
This is still when you want to use CSS in your project.
You use this kind of files, but we are not using we are not using CSS.
We are going to use tailwind CSS.
So I'm going to delete this file as well.
So I'm going to click on it, press delete.
Then we have three more files.
Page, that is.
Which is let me decrease the size.
Page that is is the home page.
So this is going to contain everything that we see in the forward slash box of our website, the home
page.
Everything here is going to be there.
Well.
So this is having the initial template of the next year that is created for us.
We don't need any of them.
We can just completely delete it and we can use RFC to create a React functional component and we can
just change this font to form.
If you cannot see the RFC working for you, probably you haven't installed the extension for the RFC.
I'm going to show you which extension are used.
You can use contour shift X to open the extension part.
So let me briefly show you which extension are used so you can get the idea.
And if you need this, these extensions, you can simply search the name of the extensions here and
press install to install these extensions.
The first extension I use is auto rename tag, which is going to change the closing tag name based on
the opening tag.
So automatically change the tags name for us.
Then we have the code, a spill checker, which is going to check the spelling mistakes in our code
and suggest correct spelling.
The dark low contrast team is the team of that I'm using for my VTS code.
It's optional for you.
You can install it or you can just keep your own thing.
The next one is is seven React redux React Native snippets, which is going to suggest us that for example,
RFC four the React functional component are some other useful shortcuts for us to easily create a components.
The next one is GitHub copilot.
This is created based on the Git GPT three and this is going to suggest use some codes and some.
For example, when you are typing something or for example you are here, this co-pilot always suggests
you something.
For example, let me show you here something.
As you can see, it's just suggested me dev home, for example.
So this is suggested by GitHub copilot.
So I'm going to use this one.
This is not a free extension.
You need to pay $10 per month for this extension.
But if you are if you are a student, you can get this one for free.
So I'm using it because it makes the coding much faster.
So I use this GitHub pilot for my everyday coding.
The next one is inline fold.
This one we use, especially when you are using Tailwind CSS, we, we write down many classes in our
code.
For example, we write down classes related to colors and hover effects and etc. and this is going to
mess up the code.
This extension is going to close the classes by three dots.
So we're going to see the effects of this one in the next section when we install tailwind CSS.
But for now, if you need this, you can install this extension that which is going to help you to have
a clean code.
The next one is live server, which is going to create a server when you are creating an HTML, CSS
and JavaScript projects.
But for the next years, because next year's is creating the server for us, we don't need this extension.
The next one is prettier, which is useful when you are saving your code.
This is going to automatically format the code so it makes your code clean and easy to read.
And the last one is 12 CSS IntelliSense, which is a very useful when you are using Telmex, CSS.
This is going to suggest you many classes based on your typing.
For example, if you want to create a text to read color, you just write down text.
And this is going to suggest you all the colors available and this is very useful.
I highly recommend you write to you install Tailwind, CSS, IntelliSense.
All right.
That was it for the extension part.
So let's come back to the code.
You go back to the Explorer section using contour shift E.
So the page that is that we have created, I would like to the extension to be jsx x, so I'm going
to rename this one actually hs x.
This is exactly the same.
But the.
Uh, this is my preference.
I want to have JSS X as an extension.
And then we have layered the cheese, which is the we use when we have a different pages in next year's
this layer, the cheese is going to help us to have some layers.
For example, if you have a common header or footer in your website, you can have this layout that
cheese, so you can have the children, which is the this page and you can add the head and other things
here.
Let me change this one to JSX.
I'm going to explain this layout in the header section more so just for now.
We know that this is for creating layout and this is only an exclusive for next year's 13.
Then we have the head JS, which is going to have our title metadata and the link tags, and this is
going to cover all the pages that is under this folder.
For example, we have a page.
And inside F if you have another folder called for example post, this hit is going to cover that page
too.
So I'm going to explain you later when we have different pages, how we can have different headers and
meta description.
This is very useful for SEO and you, you don't have this ability inside react.
JS But in next year you can have it SEO friendly website.
So here I'm going to change the title to.
Google.
Cologne.
Next.
GS 13 and then.
Did this description.
This is the first metadata tech is going to set the width of the.
A browser to devices with.
For example, if you have a mobile screen, the width of the screen is going to be a smaller than when
you are using the bigger screen like desktop or tablet size.
And the initial scale is the initial zoom level of the browser, which is set to be 100%.
Then we have the metadata tag related to description.
So I'm going to create the description for this file.
For example, I say Google clone created by.
Next.
Case 13.
So and then we have the salon, which is going to see inside the browser in order to see our website
inside the browser.
First, let me change the name of this file to hit that gs6.
Then in order to see this one inside the browser, we can open the terminal using contra bektic.
Or you can go to I think for you.
And open the terminal here.
As you can see, I have used contour practic.
Then here we can just write down NPN run diff to start a server and see our website.
So this is created a server on port 3000.
And the URL is local host clone 3000.
As you can see, we have a warning saying that you have enabled experimental features app directory
in next that config that DJs.
First they thank us for testing that and ask us to please leave our feedback at this URL.
If you see any mistakes or any suggestion you can give the feedback to.
Virtual team that you created.
The next day is framework.
All right.
So.
And actually, they warn us that in the experimental features, there may be some unexpected or broken
application behavior.
So actually, there is one mistake in the next year 13, I'm going to tell you later when we deploy
it.
And there is a solution for that on the Internet.
I'm going to show you that.
Don't worry about that.
So everything is going to work finally for us in the app directory version.
So now we can just keep the control and click on the localhost 3000 to open it inside the browser.
My default browser is chrome.
As you can see, only we have all here, which is the page that gsx.
And let me zoom it.
You can see the all and we have a title Google clone next year 13.
And if you open this extension, which is a quick source viewer extension in in the crawl, we can see
that we have a metadata tag.
Description tag saying Google clone created by next year 30.
So.
This is completely seal friendly.
So that's it for installing the next year's 13.
And the other things we need to do before going to the next section.
I want to create a GitHub repository for response because we need to have GitHub when we want to deploy
this website to Versal.
So this is going to help us simply deploy our website.
So I'm going to show you how to do it and it is completely free.
So we go back to our website.
I'm going to stop the server using Control C and press Y here, let me clean it using CLS.
As sorry.
Clear.
So now we're going to create a GitHub repository for this.
The first things first, we need to just write down Git in it.
And then this is only this.
You can see it better.
So I'm going to create a write down.
Get in it, press enter.
This is going to initialize a GitHub repository and then we're going to add everything to GitHub using
git add dot, which means get add all.
After that.
They're going to have kids commit.
And let me clear this and you can see it there.
So we're going to have kids commit.
And we can add a message to it and we just say install.
Next case and create.
The first template.
So now.
Let me clear this again.
Now we need to create the GitHub page.
So we need to go to GitHub.com.
So we're going to go to GitHub, we're going to search GitHub on Google and we go to GitHub dot com.
And here you need to sign in with your GitHub account or create an account.
I already signed in with my account here.
And here we click on this plus icon at a top and we click on new repository.
Here we can create the name of our repository.
For example, I just call it Google Clone next.
JS 13.
And the description is going to be Google Cloud using next JS 13 and tailwind CSS.
You can keep it public so everybody can see your GitHub, see your progress.
For example, I keep it public so you can go to this URL which is GitHub.com forward slash provider,
slash Google clone.
That's next year 13.
And you can check the codes that we are working on.
Or you can keep it private so nobody can see your repository.
It's it's totally up to you and you just can come down and click on.
Create repository.
So this is going to give us some instruction how to create a repository.
We have created the first part.
For example, we have initialize it added created a comment.
We go to the next part, which is creating a remote and add the origin and this URL.
We are going to copy this.
Go back to Visual Studio Code and paste this one.
And then the next line is creating a branch in the main directory.
So I'm going to paste this one as well.
And then the next one is going to push this one to the origin may.
So now, after pressing enter, this is going to upload our codes to the GitHub page.
And now if we refresh this page, we're going to see that all the code is uploaded to GitHub repository.
And now.
Now we have.
Two commits here.
And if you click here, we can see that the first commit is automatically created by Create Next app
20 minutes ago, but the last one is created by us.
Which is installed next year and create the first template.
If you click on it, we can see the codes that we have created or changed inside the GitHub repository.
So this is very useful.
When you create a section, we create a commit.
You can come here to the GitHub repository and check what you have done and review the code.
I'm going to I'm going to explain the code one more time, always after each section in the GitHub repository
briefly so you can have a some overview and bigger image of the code.
So as you can see, we have deleted everything inside the globals that CSS.
I'm going to close this.
The next section.
We have changed the name of the DJs to hit the DJs.
And also we have changed the title and the meta description here.
Now close this one.
The next section you have created.
We have changed the name of the layouts to layouts.
Then also we have deleted.
I'm sorry.
We have changed this file.
Page that changes to page G6, and we have deleted everything inside this file, and we replace it with
just a div saying how.
Then we have deleted the file called page that module CSS.
We have deleted this complete folder pages folder inside the CRC.
So that was it.
That was it for creating and installing the Nexus 13 and create the first template of our project.
In the next section we're going to install Tailwind CSS and start installing our project using Tailwind
CSS.
So see you in the next section.