Welcome back in this section, we're going to start installing next year and Tillmans CSIS and a start
the template of our project.
So first, let's go to the.
Next year's flipside, we just in Google search next.
Jill, yes.
And in the in the results section, we go to next year, that or.
This is the official website of Neches, which is a brand of verse, all that later we're going to use
to deploy to our application.
And here we just click on documentation.
And as you can see, you need not just 12 or later as a pre installation for this project.
So I assume that you already installed notches in your computer and also NPN.
I'm using NPN, but you can use your phone as well.
So here as you can see, in order to have the latest version of the next year, we can use this
command in our terminal.
So we copy this and we open our command terminal.
I use common prompt.
So let me increase the size of this so you can see better.
All right.
So we've paste the code and create Nick's app.
Athletes actually forgot before pasting this on, let's go to our inside.
I would like to create a project in my desktop, so I just write this stuff, see the desktop and inside
this stuff, I want to create the project.
So we have.
NPCs create Nick's latest.
And after this base, we write down the name of our project.
Which is, in our case, is inStar.
I just like that Insta version, I already practiced this application.
Yeah, I think three times, so I just tried version four, but you can name your application anything
you want.
So I press enter.
So the installation process going to start the first we asked me to.
Proceed.
So it just right.
Why?
So as you can see, react, react and next are.
Are being installed and the.
So while this one is installing, let's go to a children's CSIS website, and because we're going to
use till next year, as for installing our project, so we go to tell them, yes, yes.
We need to click on tailwinds, yes, have stuff come?
Pegasus is rapidly building modern websites.
If you go to get started section now, we need to use that framework, so the framework guides here
and the Tab Installation tab, we have frameworks guides.
And here we can see next year.
We click on next year.
And.
The there are some steps to do it.
First thing is just install the next year that we are already done this part and then we need to go
to the folder we have created, which is the name of our project.
And after that, we need to install Taylor's office.
By this comment, and also, we need to initialize it by this one.
Finally.
We need to change the children's systems config, file it like this.
Which has the gist and Typekit scripts.
And we changed the color of altered CFS to this comment, and also we can run our application using
NPR on this.
So let's go back to the terminal.
We see that the application already installed, so we see the inside our application.
The name of my application was install version four.
So I see the into it and I can use or you can use.
Could.
Dot to open up the Visual Studio code, which is the default code editor of me.
This command's going to open a visual studio code with the current folder that's already installed using
an.
You can use any text editor.
And if you want to if you are comfortable with others, it's up to you.
If you go to package such as songs, you can see that we already have.
Knicks react, react on.
And also, we can use and pin Ron there to install to start our application.
In a development mode, so.
Before starting our application or you just opened the terminal and I want to show you what the application
looked like now so empty and run there.
And let's decrease the size of this.
We closed this terminal, we don't need it.
And the open.
The local host, 3000, you just keep control and click on it, and it's going to be opened here, as
you can see now, we have a welcome page of next year's.
And the associated links for the documentation of next year from vessel.
The next part, as I mentioned, we need to install.
So we go back to the children's CSF website and the second step.
Is this installed, Taylor says a copy this code and paste it inside the terminal, so we first we stop
the server using Contra See?
Let me decrease the size of this.
Yeah, and the clear their terminal.
Let's make it better, bigger.
All right.
So.
We paste the link and install it.
It's going to take a few seconds because it's not a big package, actually deal CFS.
And then after that, we're going to initialize it to get these Tilman Cece's config files.
We don't have it now, but after installing and initializing see if it's using this command, we're
going to have some files, including children that can't take that.
I hear.
So we click on tailwind that config dot, yes, and we copy this code and we replace this previous code
with death on.
So this is going to be we can use all the JS and G6 files inside the children's success.
After that, we go to source folder here.
Global studies CSIS and replace everything with these three lines of code.
All right.
But if, you know, run the server using and can run, if we're going to get some errors because we
deleted some of the fiercest styling.
That we were using in this page.
So as you can see a little bit, we can see a lot of a change inside the temple template.
Uh, let's delete this home.
That module that says we don't need it because we are using children's for styling and we're getting
an error because inside the pages and index that, yes, we're using this, uh, home that module that
consists.
So it this.
I also hear.
And yeah, we use it in many places, so we delete everything from the main to the future.
And.
Now, our application is completely empty, we just use an H1 tag.
Saying Hello, world.
So we can see here.
Yeah.
Let's change the title of our application, which you can see here.
Create next app to.
Instagram.
Application Instagram app you can see here.
All right.
So now I want to show you that in the final version of our project, which I have here.
We have some.
Sorry.
We have some sections.
I show you.
Yeah, we have.
A header at the top.
And they have.
Feet section at the bottom, so the feet section includes.
This section to this story.
And the posts and also we have a mini profile here with this suggestion as well.
So the things we are going to do to, we start with the header section and we keep continue with the
feed section at the left side and then we could finish it on the right side.
So uh, let's.
Yeah.
So let's do this the same template in our project.
So inside the index that yes, instead of this hello world.
You're going to create.
360 also, we have another fictional forgot to mention, if you want to upload an image or a post,
we have a model this this one is called model.
So uh.
So we have hit our feet and modal inside index that use.
So we just add header.
Here we have.
Feed.
S..
Now finally, we have the model, so we're going to start.
With the Heather section in the next section, and we're going to divide the hair section to three parts
the the the logo, the search bar and also the menus with the image icon.
So in the next section, we're going to start.
Creating our Heather S. and.
We're going to use tailwind cases to style, and we're going to use image.
And.
The image, a component of the next year to to get this Instagram logo and also this image here.
So see in the next section for the header component.