All right.
Let's start our project.
First, we need to install the next year and in the following we need to install Telvin CFS.
So this is the final version of the project.
I just keep it here as a reference, so we know that what we are going to do in the next step.
So let's minimize this and we go to Google Chrome.
This search for next year and in the search result, we click on next year's that all Archie.
So are you going to use?
The next year, the new version, which is twelve point one.
Which includes the undermine ICR and other good stuff.
So we need to go to documentation.
And as a I'm supposed to you have already installed MPN and notorious all you have a yawn if you're
interested in yawn.
So.
And then we need to use this comment line to install next year, so we copy this line of code.
And we open our terminal.
I'm using common prompt.
Let me increase the size a little bit, so we paste the link.
And after that, we need to add the name of the project.
Or just the first we need to.
A specified the folder we want to create, I want to create the project in the desktop
and I want to create it in this folder here, of course.
So I see the end to course and I paste the link.
And after the link, it would be the name of the project.
Our the practice two times this project.
So.
I named this one, Google.
Version three.
So.
And after that, I show you here, I really created two projects.
So I.
Press enter.
Can you just need to press enter and sometimes is going to ask you to verify and you should just press
why?
So we just wait for this one.
No, I was just installing the dependencies like React, React next.
And finally, some diff dependencies like installations as length conflict necks.
So it's going to take a few minutes.
At the same time, if you go to tailwinds CSIS website, the search for Stillman's CSIS and we click
on Tailwind CSIS dot com.
Rapidly built modern website, this link was already on the, I think, version three of the hill on
CSF.
We go to get started.
You know, you can see that now the version is.
Three.
As we are installing on the framework we need to hear in the installation, we need to create click
on the framework guides.
And here we click on next year.
It's already done the first part.
Already installed everything we need to just go to the folder, which is to see the Google version three
and we open the Visual Studio code using code.
Space Dot.
And this is going to open the visual studio code with the folder that is created for next year.
So we maximize this.
We close the gifts, start a time.
We opened a terminal using control of Bektic.
We can toggle the terminal.
I think you can use control as well.
So here in the terminal, we need to install tailwinds to assist, so we go back to see if this website
here, they're suggesting that first we installed the pyramids.
Yes, this sort of prefix fixer.
So we copy this line of code and we go to back to the we closed the terminal.
We don't need it.
We go to the Visual Studio code and we paste the code.
So after this, this is going to take a few seconds just to tell us this, this is a very small package
and the.
After death, we need to initialize it, so we use this children to assist in it.
To initialize the toilets cases and get this some folders that we need like, you know, you just pay
attention to here, we get some folders to post cases that config and also Kelvyn that country and we
need to change the config files a little bit to tell them that we are using next year.
So here they're suggesting that in the content section, you changed the pages and the components to
cover the jars and test files tests for Typekit script.
So.
This installation is OK for both next year and Tavis School.
So we can copy all of them, and we go back to visual studio code and the.
Choose everything using Control A and B paste.
Here.
So the conflict file is fine now we can close it.
Next is the globals, that's USIS.
We need to replace everything inside the next year school boards.
This file?
And with these three basic components and utilities, so we copy this and we go to the folder sales
folder.
We go to global stats CSIS, and we choose everything using control a delete them and replace the new
codes that that this is just enough for the Tillman cases to work.
We don't need to home.
We note that we don't.
We will not know.
We don't need the home that module that to this anymore because you're are using Felix's so we can delete
them.
Here.
And in the pages, we go to index that, yes.
We can see that there.
We have the template of the next year.
We don't need any of them.
We just from the main to the future, they're going to delete everything.
For the title, we change it to.
Google version three.
This is tiling removal.
We don't need these to marshals the stealth and the image now.
So this is the things we have, and let's just write down something here like, Hello world.
And let's start the server using npm run, Dev.
This is going to initialize the server on localhost three thousand so we can use control click to go
to the.
Localhost three thousand.
This is going to open it in Chrome.
You can see that we're getting a helloworld in Tillmans yourself, a stylus.
So that's it for the children's services part.
And installation.
For deploying our troops now later, we need to get home.
So let's.
Just go to get her and we create a new repository.
I sign signing with my account, which is this one.
You're in the top right.
You can see the plus sign we need to right click and click on new repository.
So the new repository, which just the.
Put the name for it, I call it Google.
Version three.
And the description is.
Google Clone using next genius and.
Tailwind, yes, yes.
We just keep it public.
If you want to keep it for yourself private, it's fine.
It's up to you.
We just click on Create a repository to create our new repository.
So these are the common lines we need to do inside the terminal to initialize our GitHub.
Uh, first, we need to hear we stuff the server who was in control, see?
So the first step is just initialize the kids.
We just take it and it.
And now we add everything to the.
Geared to using get at.
We create a message using Git Commit.
And we just say and so next year and and.
She insists, and now we need to use the lines here, so.
This is going to get remote and in just a sign your ear, which is the URL of the new repository.
So we need to.
Paste this one here.
And then we need to.
Just push it to the original.
We use this line, so.
Yeah, no, we just paste this one.
This is the first time you're using the next time we just need to use, get at or get come in and get
push.
So in the next section, when we add more things, I'm going to add to use it again, and the only things
we need to use is these three lines of code.
Now, if you go to our getup now we refresh the page, we can see that we already push everything to
get hot.
We already have to come in.
The first one is from the next year itself that is automatically created and this is ours.
Which is installed next year and help us to assess the things we did is just installed next year in
the index that, yes, we deleted everything.
We changed the title and we just put.
Hello, world.
And in.
Some config file be created using cassettes and using telescopes initialization.
In global of these cases, we treat everything and replace with this three lines of code.
And in conflict that, yes, we've changed the content to include JavaScript and of script.
So in the next section, we're going to create the header.
Off our website, this is the final version.
So in the next section, we're going to start with the header.
And you're going to like make it.
Uh, to, uh, to the left and to, uh, to links on the right side, and also we're going to add this
user.
So see you in the next section for the header part.