All right, in this section, we're going to overview the IMDB movie app, as you can see from the final
version of the project.
We have three sections.
The header, which includes the menu with hero icons and IMDB logo.
Then we have the navbar with two taps trending and top rated.
When we click on Trending, we can see that genre is changed to fetch trending, and the result is shown
accordingly.
And if we click on top rated, we can see that the genre is fetch top rated now and the results are different.
In the results section, we have a thumbnail that includes an image, an overview, the title, the
release date and the vote count.
If we decrease the size of the browser, we can see in the mobile screen, we have the menu and the
logo on the top of each other.
And also we have only one column in the result.
We're going to achieve this using CSS grid, which is coming from Tailwind CSS classes.
If we increase the size of the browser a little bit to tablet size, we get the menu and the individual
logo next to each other, and we have two columns in the results section.
If we increase more, we can see three columns and finally, four columns.
And if we decrease the Zoom level of the browser, we can see we get five columns.
This is going to be achieved easily using grid system that is provided by Tailwind CSS classes.
In the next section.
We're going to start installing the Next.js and Tailwind CSS, and we're going to learn how to achieve
the first template.
So see in the next section.