All right.
In the last six year, we have implemented recoil and we created a component called upload model.
And here we could achieve the let me increase the size you could achieve to the state, a global state
by clicking on the plus circle icon.
You can see that the model is open in this section we're going to create.
The model completely using a package called React model, if you look at the final version of the project.
Here.
You can see when we click on the.
As Circle Icon, the plus circle icon, we can see that the model is open and we have a blurry background.
And also when we click on the other side, except it the model, the model will be close.
So we're going to call this state by clicking here and the other side, except for the model itself.
First, let us search for a React model.
If you search, just react the model.
We can't seem to resolve section, we have an Olympian package called the React model.
So if you click here.
We can see that the installation process is like this, we just need to install, save, react more
or if you're using your, you can use your Act React model, and the examples are very easy.
You just need to have this model component in portrait.
And inside this model, you're going to have all your codes or everything inside the model.
For opening, he used this attribute is model and for closing the use on request close.
So let's do this one, let's install it first, we copy this command.
Here they come in.
We copy it.
We go back to Visual Studio Code, the stop the server using Contra See and we place the command.
It's a very light price package is going to install very fast.
And no, we can't add the model.
The React model at the top of our.
Upload model, duchess component, we just here say import.
React moral.
No, sorry.
Uh.
You just say import model from React.
Moral.
And this is all lower case, but this is upper case.
And instead of having just this one upload model or.
Here we delete this section.
We don't need this.
But when it is open, we want to have the model.
So you make a parenthesis and inside the parentheses, we add the model component, which is coming
from React model.
So because attack, we.
And inside this, you're going to have the things we need.
So here, let's first add just the H1 Singh model, and as I mentioned before, we have some, uh,
props sorry attributes here.
The first one is is open.
So it's going to stay open it.
But how do we know that is open?
We're going to use this stayed open here.
So this is open, is equal to open.
So when the open is true, the model is going to open.
I think we can see it now.
MP and run there and we check our application.
I hope you can see it.
That's refresh the page.
All right.
I think.
Yes, still.
Refreshing, yeah, that is fine now.
So let's click on here now we can see the model in the middle.
But if you click on the outside, you still model is open.
So let's add that under on request clause and the request clause is going to.
Trigger a function which changed to sit open.
To floss.
So now when we click outside the model, we should close this.
Well, as you can see now, we opened a model, we closed it by clicking outside.
You can see it better here.
This size, we're going to fix it by using Tillmans, yes, but the functionality spoke.
So let's.
Change this model, a style.
To make it a little bit small when we have a just we just see Max with to be large.
So in the big size, we want it to be like that.
And also if the mobile size, let's make the width to be 90 percent of the width.
And let's at a height of 300 pixels or now because we don't have any content.
OK.
Still cannot see it properly.
Yeah, we can see it here, but let's position it exactly in the center.
So.
Uh, we can use the position in absolute and we just say top fifty six and left.
And left just say 50 percent, but actually 50 percent.
It's bringing the edge to the.
Centre.
We want it to be exactly in the centre, so we're going to use trance.
Translate X.
Of minus 50 percent.
If you're familiar with the thesis.
So when we position left 50 percent, if this is a box at the edge of the box, we'll be in the center
and then we use Translate X to bring the exact centre of the box.
So that's should be fine.
Let's change the background to be white so we can see it nicely.
No, you can't see it, but it doesn't have a border yet.
So let's add some borders so we can see it even better.
So we add a border to.
All right, Ceci, nicely.
And let's make it rounded.
Just the I think medium would be fine, run the media, and let's add some shadow so we can see it better
as well.
We just wish media to.
Okay, so we have the model here now.
When we click our sites close, when we have a bigger size, it's this much.
Because we set the max with to be large.
And it's almost in the center.
All right.
So that's fine for this part, and we had this model as well.
Uh, let's cover this model with the deer so we can bring this model to the center.
So we we just change the display to Flex and makes the Flex column and for bringing it to the center,
we can justify center.
And this is for.
And then we just say items sent to.
So these to bring them to the center both vertically and horizontally.
But because we don't, we didn't make the heights within a set.
The high so did not come to the center this way vertically.
So we just say hi to 100 percent.
So.
This is going to bring everything to the center.
So now we just have a basic model.
For our website.
And it was very easy to implement if you want to really make with make it with JavaScript, it's going
to be very hard.
But with the React model package implemented, everything easy.
So let's push everything to get up.
We just take it and get command of it, the message of change, so.
And.
Plan.
Implement reacts.
More.
OK, so we push it to get up using Kit Push, let's check to what we have done.
We review our code.
We just refresh the page and go to the last comment by clicking on this.
14 seconds ago.
As you can see, we just installed the React model first.
And then we import it and the covered everything with the more moral component.
And the U.S.
Is open and honest.
Quest closed for opening and closing their model.
And we just center it using this as well, so.
In the next section, we're going to complete the model part by adding this icon, the input and the
this button.
So see in the next section for this part.