All right.
In the last section, we have completed the model part.
And we put the etch one inside model that when we click on this circle plus icon, we can see the model
here.
And when we click outside the model model, you can see that the model is disappeared.
In this section, we are going to complete this model part and make it like the final version if you
look at the final version.
Here, when we click on this plus circle icon, we can see that we have a camera icon with the background
of pink.
And we have an input here and also button when we click on this camera icon, the file pic hair trigger
triggers and we can upload an image there.
So.
Here.
To we just when we write down to something, the file.
Like the caption, if it's going to be recorded, so all the information is stored and then when we
click on the upload post, it goes to the the the Firebase database.
But now we just want to create this UI, and in the next section, we're going to start connect this
model to the.
All right, let's go back to Visual Studio code and.
We open our.
Terminal, our local host, three thousand on the right side.
First, we bring the camera icon at the top.
So here we import.
Camera.
Icon.
From Hero Icons to react.
Outline, so now we have to fight if we have it.
Let's show it inside the model.
Let's keep it open here.
So.
Inside the model, let's remove this.
H1 tag.
And here inside is the the kid, the camera icon.
We can see it's huge now we can install it using tells us, yes, this it just.
At first, we create the cursor.
To be pointer, so when we hover over this camera, we can see a pointing hand.
Then let's decrease the size of it by changing its height 14.
And let's add some background color to it.
The background color is red.
Two hundred.
And let's add some padding.
So we have some we push it inside and you want to create this around it, around this, so we make the
rounded.
Full, so it's going to be a circle.
And finally, we at a border of two.
To make it like a button.
And we just changed the color of the camera to red as well, but.
This thread is going to be five hundred, which is a little bit darker.
So that's it for the camera icon when we click on the camera icon, we want to open the file picker
so we cannot connect this inside icon.
What we do is we add an input here with the input is going to be.
The type would be.
So we create the.
Input, but the tie up is final.
But how do we know that we click here and actually we don't want to show it?
So we first we make it.
Hayden, which is right down here, Hayden.
So we completely hidden it, and then we created reference to it, and we call this reference.
File picker, ref.
The reason we gave the riff referenced, if you want to when we click on the camera, we want to click
actually on this.
Fire.
Let's refresh the page to be signing again.
It is the same that the file picture is not defined.
So we should go out and add top and bring it here.
So after this open, it creates a constant and we call a file picker ref and be using a use ref from
react.
To.
Get the reference, and then the first value would be no.
And let's import to use if as well by using counter space and we click on, the first author suggests.
Now we have it here.
Now we have the uh.
Fall picker, Jeff.
But when we click, we should connect to that inputs so that the way we do it is to add an enclave to
the camera.
So in the camera icon, we add on click and the on click is going to be.
If function.
There.
Triggers the file picker career.
And we just can't.
That click.
It means that click on the file picker, if so, when you click on the camera, actually they are clicking
on the inputs, but
the input is not shown because it's hidden, but it's going to be work.
So when we click on the icon, this one, we should open the file picker.
As you can see here.
So.
It's working nice now.
Let's go to the next part, which is the input for the.
Because it is inputs here for caption.
So we had two inputs.
The top is ticks and.
Let's limit the max length to be 150.
And so they cannot write down more than 250 words here.
That's the limit.
Mostly, the Instagram post has so.
And then we have a place holder of just saying, please.
Enter your caption.
Yeah, that's fine.
We just need to style it using children to assess.
So first we add a margin of four, so we push the camera a little bit upper.
Then we remove the border.
We just said border, none.
And which we make that takes center.
And finally, we added, when we click on it, you want to we want to remove this focus too.
We don't want to see that phone as so.
So first, we just change the width to be full.
So when we actually its covers are everywhere until here.
But, uh, people write down.
It doesn't go to the end because it has a margin of four.
Right, so but we just need to remove that blue line around it.
It's very easy.
We just need to have focus.
Rink and the rink would be zero.
Now we don't get that.
All right.
Let's finish this moral part by just.
Adding the button as well, so here you add a button.
Which had which just saying upload.
Post.
And let's start with.
With a class name of, uh, we just make this one fall as well with a full.
We cannot see it yet, because it doesn't have any background color, we just see background red.
And the darkness would be 600.
No, since see this all the way to the to the end, and we can at some margin here as well.
So the the we just firstly, let's make the text white.
And we add some padding up to so we have some space around it.
And.
Let's make it at some shadow effects.
We're just a shadow medium, so it can quickly see a shadow under it and.
Let's add some hover effects as well, so when we hover over it, we want to decrease.
Their brightness.
So we just say hover and let's set the brightness two hundred and twenty five.
It means two hundred and twenty five percent.
It means 25 percent more so when we hover now, we can see it's brighter.
Twenty five percent, right?
And in the disabled mode, because we want it to be disabled until the person upload the image and write
down the caption.
Otherwise, they can click on it.
So let's make it disabled and see how we are.
Uh, let's close this left part.
So we have more space.
OK, let's make it disabled so we can.
See what we are doing.
So here we just say if it's disabled.
We just said disabled is equal to the background, correct color instead of red.
We want it to be gray.
Two hundred.
And.
We wanted the cursor instead of a pointer
to be.
Not allowed.
So just a note.
Allowed.
You can see they're not allowed, and we don't want to have a hover effect when we are in the disabled,
more so in the disabled mode.
The hover effects.
The brightness would be instead of one hundred twenty five at the 100, which means no change.
All right.
And.
So let's ask some padding to the model there, the top level.
If you remember at a height of hundred.
Uh.
And a top.
Not this one, the the model that the top, so I added the height of three hundred pixels, let's instead
of this, we just and padding up six.
And this way, even the button is not connected to the ground, and it's everything looks fine.
So everything is fine.
No, we want it when they choose an image, we want to show it here in the screen.
Let's let's let me show you in the final version.
In the final version rhythmically.
When you click on the file picture, let me just choose the image.
So when we first, we just showed inside this park and then we click on this image again, we see we
can change the image.
So for example, we choose another.
All right, we want to achieve this one now.
So inside this.
More.
First, we create a state.
We just a cost.
And we call the state.
Selected file we just selected.
File.
And the next one would be set selected that file.
This is the function that's going to sit here and we use the use of state.
And the first value, the initial value would be not.
Let's first import use a stage.
And then in the input we created as a hadin to pick the file we added on change because when we want
to change, some change happens.
For example, if someone is uploading, if something is changing is happening, we want to trigger a
trigger, a function called at image.
To post, and we're going to create this function at the top.
So after this selective file, we create a function.
And we call it this ad image to post.
Which is going to get the event and the information inside that input.
And, uh, first we create a reader.
And the reader will be a new fall reader.
This is a built in function from the JavaScript that is going to read the files inside the input.
And we just say if there is a event so that events that we're getting at the top.
If there is an event that fails, miss any falls is uploading.
We just if because we want to upload only one, which is we have to just specify zero here in the array.
Just say if there is a fire and choose the first one, and so it means that there is a file.
But we want the first one, actually.
And then.
And we're going to read that file, which is here.
So we just saw that the reader at a top.
We want to read it as a.
Theta, you theta URL, so you can read it as a different things.
Like a string of buffering attacks, but you wanted the you are out because we want to get that you
are well and show it on the screen so that your health coming from here.
And vendors loading part finish when we get the URL, so we can know this one using a reader on low.
So as soon as the load finished, we wanted.
That reader, if you get the reader events.
And this this is similar to the event we got here.
Whatever information we got here, it comes to this weather event and we get that through the event
and he said it inside this estate, this selected fire.
So this set?
Selected file would be equal to reader that event dot target.
The results,
so we got this.
You are here and we get this early from this event, as I said, as soon as it is, it is loaded.
And after that, we can get the hell.
Here and set it to send it, said selected file.
Now we have this information.
Which is a URL, uh, we can uh, probably we can console log it.
Let's do it here.
Now we just know we quickly want to show it on the screen, so.
So instead of showing the on only camera, we want this to be eternally ternary operator.
So when we have this selective file, we want to show the file, the image file, otherwise we want
to show the.
It camera icon, so we put the camera icon inside at ternary operator, we just say if this selected
file exists.
Then.
We have we have that image showing otherwise.
We want to have this camera.
So you just put this camera recorded.
And we pasted inside this.
And here should be an image.
So we just added image tag, and the source would be the selected file.
Now, let's test it, see.
You choose the image.
Now we can see the image, so but we don't see the camera.
But if we click on this image, we want to remove this image and show the camera icon.
But before that, let's install the image as a first.
So we add a class name for a styling it.
We just need to sit there with to be full, and we set the max height because some, some people maybe
choose an image that is very tall, like a tree.
And then, uh, this is going to be very big.
So we don't we want to prevent this by just saying max height of
let's set it to be two hundred and.
50 pixels.
And let's keep the aspect ratio by choosing objects cover.
And also, we want the cursor to be.
We want the cursor to be pointer, so when we hover over the image, we can see a pointing hand.
So now let's at the UN, click here.
So when we click on it, we want to remove this image.
So here.
It's very simple, we just need to add and click and unplug is going to trigger.
A function which just set the.
Set the selected file.
2P, no.
So when we click, no, we can we remove it again, we choose another image this year here.
Yeah.
It's working fine and.
The other thing is, when we click on side, we want to close the model, but when we open it, we don't
want to see the previous image, we want it to be just the camera so we can achieve this one simply
by this on request.
Clothes actually only close to.
Kloza just said the open to be false, but let's add something else as well.
So we can return this one.
In a way that we can add to things, so we just say this one.
And also we want to set.
Selected file to be null as well.
So now, after saving, you can see a very neat, very neat and.
Let's try it.
So now we have an image here.
Let's close it open.
We don't see an image.
Let's try it again.
We try a different image.
We close and we don't see.
Image.
So that was it for this part for the model, part with the image.
In the next section, we're going to upload this image and also this caption to the database, which
is, in our cases, Firebase.
So let's stop this server and B push everything to get off as usual, and we review the code together,
so we have the message of.
You just say complete the.
Upload model.
Component.
And we push it to get her by using get push.
Let's check it, and we review the code together.
Let's refresh this page.
We should see 22 commits now, and the last one is this one.
So as you can see, we got A..
Camera icon from Hero Icons.
And the use used, we have and use this state here, it created an estate.
A state of select that file to record your Elda of the image we're uploading and use this function to
read the file first, and then we get the URL and then we pass it to selected file.
So, uh.
The next thing we did, we just added the image at the beginning of the model here.
And.
If there is no image, we see an icon which has an eye which has an unclear which select an input which
is hidden and the Typekit file.
And when did we upload?
We trigger a function called ad image to post that we have reviewed now and then we have input, which
has the caption in the next section.
Actually, we are going to get the reference for this input as well.
And uh, we have a button at the point at the bottom of the model part.
Which is now in this disabled mode.
And we started using Telnet.
So in the next section, we're going to achieve this.
Like uploading to the database.
So soon, the next section for connection of our model part to the database, which is, in our case,
Firebase.
So see in the next section.