All right, in the last section, we have completed the moral part of our application.
So by clicking on the plus circle icon, now we can see and model and we can upload an image.
Choose an image and you can see the preview of the image here.
So let's.
Check the final version of the project and.
No, I just emptied all the posts, so there's no post here.
And let's go to the database and show you to how we upload and hand new posts to the database.
So for being doing that, we just search Firebase.
We go to Firebase that google.com.
Make sure to sign in with the right account, and my account is this one.
So.
And then you go to console.
So in the council.
This final version actually working with this database east of version one and no.
Our application is on instead of version four.
So just don't get confused for this.
No, this is the final version.
This is the one that we are working on.
So we click on install version one.
Make sure here you have installed version one at the top.
We go to we have to work with two things now in this application.
First one is Firebase Database.
Which is now it's completely empty because I have deleted everything.
And also we are working with the storage.
And storage is should be empty as well.
So when we upload something in our web site, let's try to upload an image.
And then we just added a caption like.
Sunset.
And we applaud the post.
Now, all we can see the post in our application, and if you check the database and we refresh the
page for the first time.
We should see a new post.
So we just wait for a while to get loaded.
And see what happens, yeah, now we have the cloud in the Firebase database, we have the post collection
and the Post Collection has one post the first one this it's automatically generated by Firebase.
So as you can see, the the first one, the first post has the caption sunset.
It has the image URL, which is coming from the storage part.
So if you go to the storage?
We can see there is a folder is added called posts inside of the post we have.
An I.D..
For the image and we have an image.
Which?
The URL should be the same as the one here, because you can see the URL at the bottom here.
This section?
So the number is 75 at the end.
And if you look at the.
Database.
The URL should be the same as the seven five at the end.
So we upload the image to storage and we get the your URL and add it to this collection.
The other things we have is the profile image, which is coming from Google.
This image here.
That could be used here in the post and user name, which is this one.
And also we have the time stamps.
The time stamp actually is the current time that the time that the post is uploaded to exactly that
time.
So, uh, let's upload another image with different accounts.
So we go out, we sign in with the.
My other two male.
This one caught with the hand.
No, we upload a different image, for example, the second one.
The nice.
There.
And as soon as we click on Upload Post.
We see the image here with the capture and then you check the Firebase database, we have this second
post.
Which has the caption, the image, URL and everything.
And a storage to a storage should have a two.
Yeah.
Two images, the first one and the second one.
All right, now, we can click here and see the image inside the browser as well.
All right, so let's do the same things for our own applications, so our applications name was instead
version four.
So we go to installation for.
And first, you create the database.
So this is the thing you you're going to see if you're doing the first time.
So we create the database.
We start with the test mode that doesn't have any security rule, but people can see your database public,
make sure to change it later.
So but for now, for one month, that gives us the chance to allow to have our data deleted.
Read it.
Other things So we just go to the test mode for now.
And just leave it as us or whatever you want, if you're in Europe, you choose Europe and we enable
it.
So it takes a few minutes to finish this.
And then after this, we're going to do the for the storage part as well.
All right.
The database is created, no, it's empty completely.
Then we go to a storage part.
Make sure to change the rules here as well, because the rules.
And.
We just allow, read and write.
Uh, we don't need this phone to we just delete this one.
So.
This this way, you can be can easily do our uploading, reading everything.
But this is not the way this is.
We're going to change this and update this on later.
But for now, you just allow, read and write.
And now also, the files are completely empty as well.
So now we are ready to applaud.
So the first thing is we need to do.
I want to add to the image.
And if we look at our website, the.
Here we want to get the caption and the image and also the user name.
Image and the username and also the user profile.
So first, we need to get the caption we didn't do it.
In the last video.
So in the input related to caption.
Here we had a riff.
Reference to.
Caption.
Riff, this is similar to what we have done to to the other input, we added the file picker here.
Here we add the caption riff and we need to create it at the top as well.
So here we created the if you remember, we did.
For yeah, here we did for five, take care, the U.S user.
We should do the same things for the caption riff as well, so we create a stir.
And we call it caption riff and we use use riff.
And we said it to be no at the beginning.
As we are uploading, we need to add another estate called Loading, which helps us to prevent the.
The user to upload more than one image at the same time.
So here at the top, we create another stage we call it loading.
As we get this suggestion from Pep nine.
So we have loading, said loading, and the use uses state and the first to initial value is false.
So it's not loading.
So and then in the bar, in the button, we we made it this table.
Let's check with you.
So it's already it's disabled by default, but we don't want it to be disabled always, we want it to
be disabled when the person is loading the.
An image or when when there is no caption or other things, so so here we just say we we we must be
equal this to we just say if there's no selected file or.
Loading, It's true.
So it would be disabled, otherwise it would be enabled.
So now.
This is disabled, but as soon as we, uh, we write down something in the caption, and it should be.
And then the file is in there, the image you get enabled.
So we try this, we choose an image.
You can see that when the image comes, it's enabled, we can upload the actually post without any capture.
That is fine, but we can make this rule as well.
So we have to add another state for the caption to.
But it's it's not important.
Mostly, people can upload an image in Instagram, as far as I know.
Without any capture.
All right.
So in the bottom, the other things we need to add is an unclear to call a function and if the function
would be upload.
Post.
Let's create the function at the top.
So just under loading, the created loading.
Yeah, here.
We create another function.
This function is async because we want to be sure that the that the post is uploaded.
So we create a async function and we call it.
Upload post.
So.
He added the loading and we say if it's loading, it means that if the loading is true, if somebody's
already loading, something just returned to their function, so don't upload anymore post.
This is going to prevent their users to upload more than one post at the same time.
So first we wait until they're loading it off.
So and then if the loading is false, set the loading to true.
So now it's the time to.
Load.
So said the loading to True.
And we're going to add the post to the database, so we create a constant.
And we call it Doc.
Riff.
And a dark rift is going to be and wait.
And we use at Dark I Talk is a building function for Firebase.
So we open a set of practices and.
We use country space to import that.
We don't get any suggestion for importing at from Firebase.
So we're going to import it manually.
So here at the top, after the news, we're here, the import.
A few things we we import at Doc.
Which is coming from.
This is coming from Firebase.
Forward slash fire store.
Probably we should get the import suggestion from now.
So we got the start, let's continue with our.
Could here that this function?
So we're going to add a dog, but where do we want to do it?
So it's going to be in a collection.
The collection is a function as well, so we import it from five bags, five store.
We click here and the collections would be a database.
And the name of the database would be posts.
So if you look at the final version.
And the place I mean, the Insta version one, we can see that we have collection, the collection has
a database, the database name is posts, and then each post has something called the.
That document that these are documents, so we have a collection document and we have to field, all
right.
So let's go back to our application version for.
So this is going to add.
And the post to the database.
And after this.
We're going to specify the things we want to at the inside a set of curly braces.
We're going to add this one.
So.
So the things we want to add here is the first we get the caption.
The caption is coming from a caption riff that we have created now.
Katherine RRIF current.
Value current, that value.
So let's try this and see if it works or not, so we go to our application and refresh the page to be
signed in.
So now we we just add an image.
We are sorry about that.
Yeah.
Image.
Oh, OK.
Let's do it again.
So we had an image here.
And you just right.
Sunset.
The upload the posts, so we're getting an error, we said DB is not defined, DB is actually coming
from, uh, Firebase as well.
This one.
So let's add it manually at the top.
So TV is coming from.
If you remember, we created a Firestorm file.
Before here, maybe we can see it.
It's not here.
We often explore using controversy.
If you remember, we created a file called Firebase that Jesus and the exported DP here, so exported
DP is storage an app from this file.
We need this one.
Here, so we just imported from that place, which is coming back and the foul name is Firebase, that
is good.
We don't need to port put the duchess at the end.
So uh, let's do the uploading again and see get any error.
So we.
Just right down care.
So we checked the database.
Refresh the page.
We didn't hear it yet.
Now, I think we didn't.
Return.
Let's check.
The reason we are not getting that data.
Is that in Firebase that yes, when we defined the environmental variable in next year in particular,
not in react in next year, we need to at.
Nick's underlying public underlying before this environmental are valuable.
So we I paced this one at the beginning of all of their.
And this is in Firebase touch, yes.
And the concept is Firebase config.
Make sure to add to all of them and environmental variable, file the foul call.
That envy Ducklo call.
We need to do the same thing as well.
So here you're.
Here, here and this one.
So we save these files.
And we closed them, and we need to restart the server because we changed things in the.
Inside the in the fire, so it clear this.
And we just used NPR and did to start the server again.
Let's refresh the page in our local three thousand.
And we now we add another image, we just write something like sunset.
When we click upload posts, we should go and see it added to cloud five.
No, it's empty.
But if you refresh to Page.
We should see a new.
Collection, which is posed inside this collection, we have a document with this I.D., which has the
only one field, which is sunset.
The caption So it was successful.
Next thing we need to do is to add more things like username, images and etc. forgetting the user name
data we we can use, uh, a session.
So we need to import session.
Here we just write import.
Used.
Session from next hour.
Forward slash react.
And just.
Here after the loading.
We can create and get the fish data, so we agree on getting it as a data, but we named a data session
and we call this to use.
And.
Now we can get the other details and add it to the database, too.
So the next one, the next day, the user name, which is equal to session, don't use it to use any.
Let's add in other things and see the results, so we add another image.
We just.
Nice pick.
And upload the post we go to.
And now you can see in other posts, document is added to the post collection.
Which is nice peak, and it has the username as well, which is called it's the person who uploaded
this post.
Let's continue for the other things like.
Profile image.
Which is equal to sition death user, that image.
And also the the last thing we would like to I would like to add is the time that the post is uploaded,
but you can get this one easily by using built in function that fire base provides.
So we just say time stamp
is equal to server.
Time stamp.
And this is coming from Firebase forward slash firestorm.
And we need to add apprentices at the event.
No, we try a different.
Image.
Just choose one of them and just say.
Bert.
We upload the post.
You go to the database, we can see a new one at a just and the caption is, but we get the profile
image.
And we are getting this timestamp, which is showing the current time.
They've cut the time that is uploaded, which is a few seconds ago, and we have the user name.
All right.
So we finish with this part.
Next one is to upload that image, which is here to this storage.
So we haven't done that part yet.
So our storage is completely empty.
Uh.
Yeah, actually, we have the something.
Yeah, that is the positive test I've done.
I can delete this, so it should be empty for you.
So you go back to our code and we start implementing that.
So in order to get upload the image after this adding the document.
We will create a constant called image.
Image with.
And you call it the riff raff, is it building function as well, which is coming from the fireplace,
a storage?
Uh.
That's you, we can all train imported, yeah.
It's just, you know, it's the ref is from Firebase former slash storage, so we import it at a top.
Here.
And inside the riff, we need to.
Get the historic data.
Which is inside the Firebase 30th, if you remember, we export it as storage from gear to storage and
exported from this file, so we're going to get this fund because we need the information of this storage
because we need to lock a storage packet data or something like that.
So here in the riff, we just write a storage and the important.
Storage.
It should be lower case and the imported from.
It's not suggesting yet.
But let's continue.
So we add a comma here.
Yeah.
This is storage left added manually at the top.
So we get the TB and the storage here.
All right.
So now we have this storage and then we need to specify the folder.
We want to save the image.
So we add a back take and we call the folder posts.
Forward slash and we added that.
I.D. and beach I.D. that the I.D. that we used.
We are getting from here this talk riff.
So we created the document.
This document has an ID.
So we will is storing the the image inside that I.D. document, the renamed the document Death I.D.
to use the same I.D., which is DOC.
Ref, I.D. So we have this talk, ref, you have created this and we get the idea.
And after that?
We just called the called the image.
Just image.
This is just the name.
All right.
So.
This is the image where now we need to upload the image using a weight, and we just use a building
function of upload string because image is a kind of string as well because of the data type.
And then.
What what do you want to upload?
The upload is imagery of which is it created at the top?
I mean, inside the imagery of the place?
And what do you want to upload?
The upload is this file.
This file is already saved inside this state called selected file.
So selected file has a URL.
We just write down the selected file here.
Selects.
So selected file is the URL of the image and the type is data URL.
So we have to add data at the end.
So at the time of this one is data you are if you want to add in a different way, you write down the
different time.
So we have the data.
The address is selected file and we're going to upload it inside imagery of the address here.
I hope it makes sense.
So when it uploaded.
So let's try this first.
So in a freshness.
We try this image.
We just write down something here.
You low.
This upload thing we need to import this is coming from Firebase for flash storage.
I'm getting this auto suggestion using control of space.
OK.
I hope that this fun this refresh.
Just so I found something you upload.
Let's check the storage.
Yeah, you got the.
We created the folder post and inside the folder.
This is the idea.
Let's open this one a different path.
So in the database we created.
And you.
Yeah, this is just created, so this is the bird.
The caption I created and the idea is here.
The ideas here, H L, X Q and storage.
This is HL x q, so this is saying this is the same idea and inside this idea.
We have our image and the name of the image is just image, because used specified here.
The name image.
All right.
So the image is here.
And the Earth is at the bottom here, you can see, and we can click and check the.
Image, so the image is successfully uploaded to the storage, and now now we need to get the URL.
We need to get the URL and update our database here with the URL.
All right.
So here after we we uploaded, we need to wait until the upload finished.
So we add this den here.
So we just say after this one, upload it completely, then do these things.
So after this one, we open a parenthesis.
And here we create because we want to get the data from the database.
We need to use something called a snapshot.
A snapshot actually is the piece of data we're getting from the database.
It should be a sink and inside the sink.
We create the snapshot, so we are getting the data here using a snapshot, actually not shop.
And this is going to give us the URL.
So we create it, cost that and we call it download.
You are all right.
And we wait and wait to get this information and you get this information using a building function
called Get.
Download your album, which is.
Which is a function from the Firebase for a slash, a storage.
So this is going to be so rich, your argument to give.
Actually, we should define it, so we need to add the imagery of fear.
So this is the address.
We just say, give me the date.
Give me the URL of this image with this address.
And then.
After that.
We get the URL.
No, we need to update our document.
We can easily update the document using weights, and we use a building function called Update Duck.
So update talk is actually coming from Firebase, pushed forward slash fire store.
We are getting here.
Uh, yeah.
Update is from five fires, five.
So how we do update and which one we want to update, which which file we want to update.
So we need to specify the document document is the function.
It's coming from Firebase as well, artists by storm, so that we just say the data, which is from
our database, which we are getting from Firebase 30th.
And the name after the database, the name of the collection is posts.
And inside the post, just search for the documents.
With the idea of Dock Riff I.D., which we have created just now at the top.
So we created the document.
Now we're updating that document.
So we put the dock reform idea.
I know that it's a little bit confusing and complicated, but I'm trying to explain it a step by step.
And just by practicing this one a few times, I'm sure you will be a master of this ethics.
It's not that difficult if you do it a few times, so we know how we want to update it.
We just say, just add this, download your air.
So and this one is going to be the image.
So the image is equal to download your app.
All right.
So what we have done here, actually, we uploaded the image.
Then using Snapshot, we got the download your URL and updated document.
He added This image, as you can see here, no other post doesn't have any image field.
But now let's upload something else.
Refresh the page.
And we choose an image.
Which are, say, nice.
View.
Upload post.
We wait for a while and, uh.
This one is just added.
You can see we have nice for you.
We got the image from the storage updated and other information.
And also if you check the storage.
We should have known to be full refresh.
Inside post now, we should have two ideas, and the idea would be to.
Double double T movie M, so double T mbm this one.
And the file name is image.
And if you click on it, you can see the URL, the URL here.
You can see that said, the number at the end is 61.
And here the image is 60.
Want to?
This is the same euro.
So that's that was the things we needed to do.
Yeah.
And uh, if if you may notice now it's still showing upload post.
So it's very simple.
We just after everything we've done.
So outside this at the end of this function.
We set the open.
To be false so close to this window.
And also, we sit the loading.
To be false as well, so it doesn't load anymore, and we set this selected file, which is this image
to empty as well, so we just set that fire and we set that to be no, no, when we.
This time, if you upload an image.
Let's choose the third one.
They just they.
Bert.
And upload post.
Now, after the upload finished, the model should be close, as you can see here, and uh.
Let's check the database.
We should get the new one.
Yeah, this is the birth.
We uploaded the image and everything looks fine.
That was it for this part that we uploaded our thanks to the storage part.
But then the next section, we're going to show it here instead of this dummy dataset that is always
static.
We want to see what's inside the database and what is what are the post and one by one.
We show it here at the feed section.
Let's save everything to get, huh?
I know that became a very, very long video.
But uh yeah, we needed to finish this one.
But the next part would be easier because we already done the hard part.
So let's add everything to get her comments with the name of.
We just create a post.
And I add that to.
Fires tore
and.
Get.
The download.
You are out.
We just push it to get a job, and let's review the code.
So here you refresh the page.
Now, 20 comments.
This is the last one, so we imported a few built in function, or we call it utilities from the Firebase
store, Firebase and.
Firebase storage.
All right.
We created a state called Loading, and we got the information from sition and we created a function
which return when the the loading is true.
And if it's false, we set the loading to true and we
create the document with these informations and then.
We upload the image.
We all saw the image to this address with this documentary, if it.
And once we uploaded.
We get the download your our.
And we update our document with this download, Yiaga.
And finally, we set everything to false, like open loading and selected fire.
Yeah, that was it.
The things we did and the things we need to know is the button will be modified the disabled mode and
the edit the function on Click.
Which triggers a function, and we fixed a few things in the fireplace that, yes, we added the next,
probably at the beginning, which is necessary for next year's applications.
And we cannot see here, but an environmental variable to be fixed this path as well.
So see in the next section for showing our everything inside the feed section like the one here in the
final version.
So see in the next section.