All right, in the last section we have completed with the uploading path and we uploaded the information
to the database, we got the we uploaded the image began to download You are and we updated the post
in the database.
Let's go to the database now.
This is the cloud forest or here, and the this tab is the storage.
Let's delete them all because I want to make some.
A
beautiful post, and then we try to look through this post and show them inside the feed section, so
I delete this.
Fine.
And delayed all this collections, so sick the collection, they asked you for confirmation and read
them all.
So we don't have anything now.
Let's upload some nice posts like the.
We have three images, so just a.
Sunset.
Then we have the next image.
Which is the bird, that's a nice.
Bird.
And let's do another one, and let's do the other one with the other accounts.
So I signing with my order in Gmail account.
First, let's do it with this one.
Because I want to show you that how they are shown.
And the fifth section.
So the last one, we just choose the other image and we just say, nice pic.
All right.
So now if you refresh.
Let's let this one finish.
If we refresh the storage.
We should see a folder post inside it.
We should have three images.
And then in the Cloths file store also we need we should have three posts now.
You can see the nice bears.
And then sunset and finally, nice pic and then you see that they have a different time stamp.
He thinks we want to do is show this post in the feed section, but we want to sort them by this time
to stop so that the newest one comes first in the feed section.
So let's do this part.
So we go to our visual studio code and we open the localhost three thousand on the right side.
If you remember we we were getting the information from the database using something called a snapshot.
So we're doing to we're going to do the same things here as well.
So in the post, let's close everything.
First.
In the posts that James.
If you remember, we created some dummy data to date, as we can see here.
All right.
We don't need them anymore, so we delete them all.
I didn't hear.
So we shouldn't see them now in the food section, the fifth section should be an empty.
That's page refresh to page.
Yeah, because we don't have this post, so we create this one, we create a state called posts and
we say sit post and we call this one to use the state.
And we make it an empty bracket.
For the beginning.
And now we can see that we are getting an error saying, use this state is not to fire, so we import
you as a state using control space here and we get the auto suggestion.
Here, so now we imported the act.
Actually, we don't need the reactor itself, so we delete that one.
So now our fifth section is completely empty because this is empty at the beginning.
So no, let's create a use effect.
So when the page is loaded, you're going to get the data using this use effect.
So this is going to be a function.
Out of function, and we're going to use it.
Utility called on this snapshot, so this is a built-in utility or function from fire base.
That gives us the information from the database.
And this is going to give us something called on subscribe.
This is the inside that function, that is the return from this function.
So we create a constant here.
Call it on sobs cry.
And we're going to use that on stuff on a snapshot.
So we need to just import our snapshot.
It's not suggesting us, so we manually import on snapshot from its.
This is from Firebase Forest Fire Store.
So we just tried Firebase Forest Flash Player Store.
So just ignore this error because we haven't completed this one yet.
So inside this on snapshot, we agree we are getting the collection and this collection is a utility
from five Vista and a collection is coming from deep that we created in fire and fire fireplace that's
exported from here or imported to.
So we import this file from Firebase that yes.
And the name of the collection is posts.
OK.
This is going to get all these posts.
And then what happens next is we get this snapshot, we get this data.
And now we can sit the posts.
To that, a snapshot, and the snapshot actually has something called ducks.
So did all the documents are inside deception.
Now you can see it here.
You can see something because we have three.
Post, but the information are empty, so we need to get the information.
So here, instead of saying post that user name.
All right.
Uh.
Instead of saying post that username, we should say post that data.
That he is in now, we are getting the username.
And the next one would be the same.
It's better.
And then that phone wasn't a user image, and inside Firebase, we define it as a powerful image.
I show you here.
So that was profile IMG.
Profile by chief.
So you're seeing the profile.
And for the image was post the data.
And it was an image, it was image.
You can see here image.
OK, we've got the image, we got the username.
Let's get the caption as well.
So we say that to.
So we got the caption, too, but this is not based on the new one, if you remember, the last post
was this one from my son.
I mean you username.
So in order to.
Sorties post by descending mode, we need to use a built-in utility called.
It's called order by and Kurri Kurri actually covers everything.
So here.
We cover so we make and apprentices here, and then we just say.
Query.
And the import quality from Firebase for research, Forester, you can see it here and here we add a
comma and then we just say order pie and we need to import order via spell the import order pie from
fire bass forward slash forester here.
And how we order it.
We just ordered it by descending, so we had a.
Apprentices here.
And to this, this is this is should be based on the time stamp that we have.
And the.
The order would be descending, so we just write down D e f c.
So what's the error here?
So let's check in with phone, so we have the post order by.
And we have the time stamp that is correct.
The sending, yeah, the parent parenthesis, we missed a parenthesis here.
So we need another parenthesis.
Uh.
In other parenthesis here or the order by.
After just another practice, this.
Let's check again, so the country has a parenthesis until here.
That is correct.
And then the order by.
Should have apprentices, not that that's OK, fine.
That was just the yeah, apprentices problem.
So now we've got this post at the beginning and this is the last one.
And if we add now another post.
It should come first to our I and other emerge.
This.
Justice for.
And just say.
Hmm.
The best.
City.
So, yeah, it should take a few minutes to a few seconds to upload the image mostly and then get the.
Data depends on the images size.
So let's check that database.
Yeah, we still have three.
So let's try to find one.
It came the image of the problem.
Because I think it was very big.
So let's try a different one.
Let's try this.
Some say next.
Yes.
Of course.
Let's check this.
Uh, let me check the.
The data base, what happened to this storage?
Sure, the rules.
The thing looks fine.
Yeah, I took it myself, the problem is we didn't return this unsubscribe, so we returned this one
at the end.
So this because this one is going to be a loop.
And it made a problem, so we returned it on scribe here.
Unsubscribe here, so we try again.
We choose an image.
For example, this one next chance cause.
Applauded.
Yeah, came at the beginning, no.
So then we fixed this part so we could get we are getting all the posts when we are uploading it and
uh.
In the next section, we're going to hide this whole section or these buttons when we are not the sign,
you know, when the sign out.
We can still put their comments or other things, so we fix this part, and then after that, you start
creating this comment section.
So let's bring everything and push everything to get up.
So just take it at the use of gift.
And the message is.
Creates.
Creative post.
And and it's.
To the fire.
Mr.
Actually, we did this on the last part.
This is just get the pulse data from the database and show it in the feed six.
So let's, uh, push everything to get off.
And we check the final version.
I mean, we checked the repository.
So we have now for comments, and the last one is get the data from the database and show it in defeat
section.
Let's review what we have done.
So we imported some utilities collection on snapshot ordered by a query from Fire Space five store.
We got the database from Firebase Duchess.
We created a state.
Card posts and use use effect to get information from the database using on snapshot encourages collection
by the sending mode.
Using ordered by utility and also we got a collection of posts.
Finally, we got all the information as a snapshot and is set to post by snapshot that ducks.
And inside the post the component.
We passed the data using post that data practices, and we just added data apprentices to get that data.
Yeah, that is that was it for this part in the next section, we're going to hide this.
Thanks.
OK, a comment section are buttons when we are not signing.
So still in the next section.