All right.
In the last section, we have completed the comment section.
In this section, we are going to deploy our website to where sold by us before going forward.
I want to add a transition when we are in the comment section as well.
When we delete or we add a new comment, we want to just have some fading effect, fading animation
for that.
We did this one for the home page.
So as you can see here, we have a transition.
We can do the same things by copying that section.
For example, in, uh.
I feel it's in fits.
We map through the post.
So but we added the animate presence and motion that there to cover this section so we can do the same
things for the comment.
Comments as well.
So we just copy this animate presence and we go to it.
That's.
Here.
We pay staff while we cover all of them here.
And we import it as well.
We just get the auto import and be imported from framer motion the package that we have installed then.
We just need to copy this circular motion that Dave.
I've put it here.
And also we need to close it as well.
So I caught this on.
I put that.
Inside this.
Okay.
It's just, uh, I have to change the key, because the key here is comment that if we change this one
to comment that idea as well.
So initial values are positive zero.
Then we animate to one and we exit with a positive zero as well.
And also we have a transition of 1/2.
So let's import emotion too.
So we have imported animate presents.
Let's import motion as well.
And, uh.
Let's try it.
Let's go inside, for example, at this post.
We can see now the transition.
And if we delete this post, we should see it fade away as well.
Like this.
Okay.
Looks good.
So we need to insta deploy our website traversal.
But before that, we need to do the final.
Uh, final commencement.
And also we need to add a secret to the.
Next off to inside the.
Uh.
Yeah.
Next.
No inside the off API off.
No.
We have sign in.
That is also.
We have.
Inside API.
Ah, we have next a30s.
We need to add a secret for this.
Otherwise we get an error.
Or we can just deploy now on see an error and then we fix it after death.
So because I want you to see the error as well.
So we go to verse all.
We are so dot com.
Make sure you sign in with your account and go to your dashboard.
Then we need to create a new project.
So this is the our repository.
And we just need to import it.
We just call it Twitter, and now we just need to add our environmental variables.
Now let's go back to Visual Studio code and inside that dot envy file, we copy.
Our environmental variable valuable and pasted here.
And the key as well.
That's coffee.
The Google client I.D..
Think.
They sit here?
Or do they?
And the last one is the client's secret.
See what?
Okay.
Let's add this one now.
We can deploy it.
We should get an error because I want you to see the error.
If you encounter the same error as you can, you know how to fix it.
Okay.
So it's building now.
If you get an error, we can see it here.
Now it's still installing.
Okay.
So far so good.
Yeah, we got an error.
Inside signing that.
Yes, we missed the key.
Prop for the element.
So first we fix this, then we go to signing that.
Yes.
It's just here.
If.
Let's see the.
Their team.
Yeah, we.
We did a map, but we need to add the.
Prop here.
We need to add a key.
So the key would be provider.
For example, we just provided that name because the provider name is unique.
You can use it.
So let's deploy this.
Let's check the other areas first.
If we have other error, we can fix it inside news.
That is, we should use, uh, no referrer when we are using at target blanket.
So we need to copy this.
We go to news that years.
And here we we use the anchor tag.
So we have to add this one too, because we are using Target Black.
Okay.
Let's check the next error.
Inside widget that yes we use that this.
One.
We need to use this one or just delete it.
So we go to widget that.
Yes, I think I believe it's in there.
What's happening.
So we just delete this.
Okay, let's see what else.
Now we don't have any more errors, so now we can add this one to get half.
And with the message of.
Fix deploy.
Man.
Errors.
Uh.
Okay.
And we push it to get hot.
Now automatically works, so it's going to deploy again.
So we just check here.
We go back to homepage.
So now refresh the page.
We should see the new commitment here, fixed deployment errors if we click on this.
And we go to deployments.
The new deployments is building.
Let's see, we get an error or not.
That's easier to fix your errors.
You just wait.
And if you see an error, you can check the errors, fix it, and push it to get up again and fix the
error.
But the error I was talking about the index of and adding the.
Yeah, let's see what's there.
Again.
Okay.
Uh.
Insight idea, Dr. J.S..
Module not found.
Okay.
Let's check.
Yes.
I think this comment is capital.
This is lowercase.
It should be that prominent probably.
Uh.
Let's close everything.
Inside the.
She touches.
Yeah.
I think it should be that problem.
Okay, let's.
Add it again and make a comment.
Just say two and we push it.
So let's go back to the homepage.
No, the new deployment is a start at the 5/2 past.
Okay, well, we see that one.
Yeah, I was telling that the next off adding the secret problem is not going to prevent deployment,
but when we are going to the signing page, it's it's going to give us the error.
So we'll see in a second.
Just wait until the deployment finish.
Okay.
This one.
I think it's fine.
Let's go inside.
And also I want to make a custom domain.
So we go to domains that Google that content is my domain this year and I purchased my domain from Google
100 just projects this website I want to put it inside this so I go to DNS and I go to manage custom
records and I'll add a new record, I want to call it, just to either.
And the type would be a and the IP, I use my virtual IP.
You have to use your own virtual IP.
Okay.
This time it's fine.
We deployed it.
Now let's add that domain here.
So we go to manage.
And the domain is.
Well, let's save this up first.
Okay.
Uh, the name was Tudor.
That's hundred genius projects.
Dot com.
I added, No.
So probably now we can go.
Okay.
Our website is fine.
This background color.
Let's open this font in a chrome instead.
So.
They shouldn't see that background color.
But the background color.
I was testing for the.
We can you can easily fix that and you got a widget and I added this background red color.
You can delete this one.
That's fine.
So instead we go to crawl.
Okay.
Now, the error I was talking is here.
When we try to sign in, we get an error server error, but we can easily fix that by just going to
API off next 30th.
And we add a secret here.
We just a secret and this is going to be equal.
To.
Should be like this process that Ian dear dot secrets.
And inside environmental valuable.
Here we add the secret.
And this can be anything you just a random things you just put here like this.
And then we need to deploy deployed to.
We need to push it to get up first.
So this is the fix.
Secret.
Error.
And we push it to get her.
Now in the next deployment that happens inside their vessel, that is automatically going to happen.
If you go now and inside the deployment, no new deployments is happening.
In this deployment.
We shouldn't get this signing error.
But we were going to get another era, just wait for it.
That is natural that they said, Yeah, we need to get that error to fix it.
So just bear with me and this is going to be fixed as well.
So just wait.
No, the deployment is done.
We go inside.
Uh.
Let's see.
Yeah.
The background colour here is finished.
It's fixed.
We go to sign in page.
I was still getting the error.
Let's.
Let's check it inside.
Here we go.
Text time to be applied to the custom domain.
So we have to wait a little bit.
Oh.
Oh, sorry about that.
I forgot to add the environmental variable.
So.
We need to come back here.
We go to the setting and we go to environmental variables and we add that secret.
Uh.
Sorry about that.
I forgot.
I added inside the, uh, Visual Studio could not hear me.
Whatever you.
You can write it.
It's not important.
It's one.
So we add it here and we go to deployment and we click here and we deployed again.
We just redeploy.
And we press redeploy.
Okay.
This is going to fix it.
I was kind of sure that is going to be fixed by forgot the environmental variable.
Okay.
Uh.
The image here.
I don't know why we cannot see the image.
Probably this is for a problem of Firefox is uh, blocking some elements but uh, it's an important
thing in the.
Graham.
We can see the image.
Okay.
The building is almost done.
That's finished.
It's ready.
We can check the.
Let's go to the Chrome and refresh the page.
Now we try to sign in.
It should redirect us to the correct page.
That's correct.
Now, that's correct.
We should get another error.
Now, when we sign in with Google, we get an error.
We just say redirect your error mismatch because we changed the URL.
We didn't add it to the error cloud console.
So we need to copy this redirect URL, this file until here and we go to cloud.
Console.
We go to.
Console, that cloud, that Google.
Make sure to sign in with your phone with the correct email that you have created the project.
And.
You just select the projects.
The project's name was Twitter version four for me, and then we go here in the menu, we go to API
and services and finally in credentials.
And Insight credentials.
Here we click on edit or client and you should paste the link here inside the redirect URL.
So we add it here and also we copy the URL itself and paste it here as well at the top.
Now we go down our savings.
Okay.
No.
When?
Uh.
In our website, we go back.
When we click on sign in with Google.
We should go to the signing correct signing page and we click in any.
Email.
We want.
Let's test the website.
Let's put a post.
Let's choose the image.
Whatever.
We just say hello.
We tweeted.
Hmm.
And this is going to be uploaded to the fire.
Fire.
Uh, Firebase.
And, uh, we can delete it.
Probably.
I don't try this on.
Okay.
It's fine.
You deleted.
Yeah, that's fine.
Let's write another one.
We don't image.
We can like it.
We can like the other ones.
We can add a comment, for example, we just say Nice.
We should be redirected to the Post page.
We cannot act like we can delete the comment.
That's fine.
Everything is working okay?
Yeah.
That was it for our project.
I hope you enjoyed and learned many things.
Please wait for the update.
I'm going to add more functionality.
And also.
And in the meantime, you can check out my other projects that I have uploaded before, or I'm going
to add more projects as well.
Thanks for your interest and see you next time.