All right, in the last section, we have implemented a way that we hide the buttons and the input box
when we are not signing in this section, we're going to implement the
comments feature and we can send the comments to the database.
Let's start the server using npm run dev.
And bring this one to the right side.
All right.
So if you look at the final version of the project here.
Now we are signing with the.
My Gmail account quote with sand and in the first image, which is this account's honor, I write a
message, for example, say.
Just beautiful.
Just say nice.
And as you can see.
We're getting this a few seconds ago.
The user name and the profile image, and if you look at the.
Database and we choose the final version one, which is instead version one.
Now.
The one with the nice bird one, we have another.
S..
In other.
Collection, which is the name is comments, and it has the idea.
And the idea.
If you click on ITV, you see the comment, the time stamp, which is the time that comment is posted,
then we have the user image and username.
Let's do it with the other image.
So, uh, fantastic.
And if you check the first one now, it's a minute ago.
This one in a few seconds ago.
This is all automatically created by a package called Moment.
So let's go check.
So if you go back to the other post, this post has a comment collection, too with that document.
And the field is fantastic as a comment, and they have the time stamp user image and username.
So let's do this one in our own project.
I mean, the one that we're building now, so we go to Visual Studio Code, we open our website at the
right side.
First thing we need to do is to just this, uh, this button, which is related to the comment section,
you want it to be disabled when there is nothing inside the comment section.
So in the bottom.
This is for the signing, this is the header that you have in the post that in the button section which
has which is saying.
Post, we need to add a.
Disabled more.
And before turning to this one, we need to add a state here at a time called comment, so we know that
if there is no comment, we want to disable the button.
So we just say sit comment.
And we call it to use this stage.
And it's would be empty at the beginning.
Let's import you this state from react.
And here now at the bottom button section, we say if there is no comment.
Make it disabled and also we want disabled when there is no.
When there is no moon summer at its base, just imagine someone put two men in space here and post to
post it, so we prevent this one by just saying comment that.
First would trim it and then we check so.
So now.
That's fine.
It's it's disabled now because there is no comment yet.
And also we are not tracking the comments are still disabled, even after writing something.
So we go to the input section.
Here and in the input.
He set the value for us to be equal to the comet, so whatever comment, this would be the value.
And also we want to say if there is a change in the comment section.
So we added on change, we trigger a function and we get the event here.
So we can we want to get the information inside the inputs and when we get it, we set the comment.
To be equal to events, this event that target death value, so any value inside the inbox will be set
as a sad comment.
So, you know, if you refresh the page.
We go to comment section and we write something.
We see that the button is enabled.
But if there's nothing, it's disabled and if we.
Just to put this faith is still is disabled, so you cannot post it.
Let's make this one a little bit dimmer when the.
When it's in the disabled mode as well, so we just said disabled.
So we changed the text color to blue, but instead of 400, make it 200.
So we can now differentiate between disabled and enable what?
All right.
No, we want to add on the bottom, so when someone click on the post when the Post Linda button is
enabled, we want to trigger a function that send the information.
This this comment to the database so we can edit and click here.
Which trigger a function call, send comments, and we're going to create this at the top.
So let's go at the top.
Here, just after the comments we created after the state that we created here, we create a sync function
because we want to wait for the information going to the database, so we made it as a sync function
and we call it send comment.
Let's get the event here as well beyond that, because we want to prevent refreshing the pitch when
someone click on the button.
So we just say here, event dot prevent default.
So this is going to prevent the page to be refreshed when someone click on the button and then.
We're going to create.
A constant and we call it comment to send, and we equal this to this comment here.
So whatever the comment, if we create a constant and be equal, that one to and after this we cleared
the comment section and we set the comment to be empty.
So when someone click.
Then someone write any comment.
Click on this one.
So, uh, the reason is the refresh the page is refresh is the the button here doesn't have the time.
So we create a tie and we set it to be submit.
Now if someone comments and press, enter or click on the post, yeah, still refreshing.
So this is the wrong that clicks should be.
This should be a cap in capital.
So the envelope should be in a camel case, not only test should work out, that's now be it the patient's
not through fishing.
And yeah.
So now we have the information, all the information we get, the comment and the empty the comment
section.
So here.
We we we use it a way to get the information from the database and we use at dark as for use before
and the dark is coming from the.
Firebase, so we should add it at a top.
So we just import at dark, and this is going to be from a Firebase
Forest slash firestorm.
And after that, at dark, we just need to add a collection, so because we want to specify the connection.
This one is coming for Firebase Forest, Ash Forest or two, then this is going to be from a database
as before we did and from the collection post.
And after the post, we specified I'd.
And.
After that, the other collection's name is comments.
So now we created this part.
So they think the next thing is just to create the object.
And the object is going to have a few things, first is the comment.
And the comment is equal to.
And this comment sent.
After that, we have user name, which is coming from sition.
Doth user the death username.
Next, we have user image, which is equal to sition that user that image.
And finally, we have the time stamp.
The time stamp for time, which is we can get from server time to stem utility, which is coming from
fires based, so we need to import this to.
It should work.
Let's check the imported everything.
We didn't import this tbh.
This is coming from.
Fire Firebase, that.
Yes.
So are you going to import it manually here or just import?
And this is coming from.
Here the five is that yes.
Let's try this.
We put the comment.
Just a nice horse.
We've posted we checked the database.
This is the final version we choose the institution for.
So the one, uh, that have a comment.
Mixture, of course, now we have another collection, vicious comments.
It has that idea.
And.
The comment was nice costs.
And this is the time stamp user image and username.
So let's try this with another one.
So this one say, uh.
Well, just say whatever.
Just say.
Green, I'm very bad at commenting, so let's check the.
Nice, big one, now we have comments.
We stay the comments is grim, yet we we implemented correctly.
And in the next section, we're going to show this.
Information from this comment section inside the posts related to that comment, so.
If you look at the final version, you can see that as soon as you write a comment.
So just write a random comment.
We see it at the top because this is the newest comment, so it comes at the top.
And.
The other one goes down, and if you add more, you see that this is a scrollable.
And we don't get the height more than this part and the first one comes and at the top.
All right, in the next section, we're going to achieve this.
First, let me put everything and get half.
So we just take it at and create a comment.
Get comments, and the message would be.
Add comment.
To the.
Fire.
Base.
Database.
And we push it to get her.
Let's check and review what we have done.
You just get it here.
So it was very simple.
So.
As we did with for the most part, we use at collection as service time stamp.
To create an asynchronous function.
And.
We got the information from the input, and we pass it here to the collection with these with this format.
And also we added the value and unchanged to the input section and for the button we added the Typekit
you submit and click and disable it.
So in the next section, we're going to bring all these comments to the to the associated post.
So see in the next section.