All right, in the last section, we have completed the ability to submit a comment to the database.
In this section, we're going to look through those data that's in the database and show it here, either
at the bottom of the caption.
So in order to do that, we're going to use the same method we used to get the post, which is the use
effect.
And uh.
You're going to look through the fetch data using map method.
So look at the if you look at the final version of the project here.
We see the comment section here, which is scrollable, and let me sign in with another account and
we do.
The.
His signing with.
This account.
And here I put another comment.
Just a nice press enter, if you can see that we the the last comment comes first and at the top of
other comments and we can see the time here.
The previous one is two days ago.
This one is a few seconds ago.
And if you wait for a minute, we see that this might change to a minute ago.
We're going to get this status from the time stamp of the comment that is created and show it with the
package called a react moment here.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code, and we open our local host 3000 at the right side.
And we go to post that, yes.
And here at the comment, at the top first we get the data.
No, we have only one stage S. comment.
Let's create another state.
Let's copy this one using all shift Oradan.
We changed his font to comments and this font of comments.
And if first, initial value would be an empty bracket so we don't have any comments at the beginning,
then we're going to use use effects to get the data.
So just here, we create a use effect and hope that it can fetch the data.
So don't forget to add the dependency so we don't request too many from the database.
So as we we did before, we should create a constant called unsubscribe.
And this is going to be this is going to be from on the snapshot.
So we just create a snapshot and this snapshot is coming from Firebase Restore that the use effect is
coming from react.
So we imported both of them.
And, uh, let's.
This fund would be inside.
So we create a collection and a collection.
It's from our DP, which is coming from fire base 30, yes.
And we have the collection of posts.
Inside the post, we want to target the IED, which is coming from here.
Which is the idea of the post and then we get the collection comments.
But this one, we want it to be ordered by the Senate, so we had a query here.
I recover all of their.
And here we add an order by.
The order by IS based on timestamps.
And it should be descending.
So we need to bring these things and see we're getting an error saying courey is not defined.
So we just import Corey after that.
The Import Collection collection is already imported, so we order order by.
Yeah.
Shouldn't get any error.
And the ATP as a dependency.
As well as the.
Anything that is valuable, we should.
And there's a dependency.
OK.
So and finally, we need to get this information using a snapshot.
So when the courier is finished.
Here.
We get the information, the data using the snapshot and the snapshot.
If inside the snapshot, they're going to set the comments to the state, we have to set the comments
to be a snapshot.
Dot dock.
This is the similar to the one we did for the post.
Are you already familiar with?
So.
We just using it on Snapchat, got the data from the collection and we started using curry.
And finally, we put it inside the comments using set comments.
Hook here we use the user statehood and using set comments, we got the value for the comments.
No, we need to show this comment inside the.
After this caption, so let's find the caption.
The caption is here.
So after this paragraph.
We we just create a ternary operator saying if there is a comment, so we just say comments that Lance.
More than.
Zero.
If the length of the comments on more than zero.
In other words, if there is a comment, then show these things.
First, we create it.
Year.
And inside this, they're going to use.
A map map method to get all the comments.
So it's just see comments that map and maps is going to give us each comment.
It's like this.
And inside this.
We're going to have another day.
And inside the day, we're going to have if you look at the final version, we have the image username
and a comment.
And finally, we have them the moment.
React Moments package.
So first, let's get this image.
So we have an AMG.
Which this source is.
Comment.
But if you remember, we need to add data parenthesis to achieve the information and the user image.
Because in fact, the.
Firebase, if you look at the data.
For example.
We.
Let's see which here we added a comment.
So.
The comment has an idea, and inside we have the fields which think green and it has the user image.
So we are using that one.
Inside here.
But we need to add the data.
To get the information.
The alternative is user image.
All right.
And, uh, let's do the other one.
Let's see that we are getting the data now.
Yeah, we're getting the image here.
So after the image.
We need to add a paragraph for the username.
Let's see if we can.
Yeah, we just need to add the username here.
Here would be.
Comment dot data dot.
If you look at the database, it's.
It's comments.
We just need to write comment.
So it would be two comments to comment that data.
That comment?
So let's see.
Yeah.
So we got the comment.
Sorry, we need to get the username here, so just copy this and the above would be user name.
So we have the use and then we have the comment.
And finally, we need to get the time.
So we need to install a package called reacts.
A moment.
So let's search for this moment first.
So here in the Google, the search for react.
Moment.
At just one a.m., So there is a champion package.
Called the react moment.
If you click on that.
For installing this package, we just need to copy this line of code.
And pasted here.
And for using it, we just need to import moment from react moment.
And finally, we need to wrap.
We use like this a moment, and we add the date and time for other things.
So let's run the server and run.
Did I just add the above we import?
The import moment from React moment and here.
Let's do that.
We did.
The comment section here.
Just here, we need to at the moment, we just say moment.
They close it, and here we need to add the information and also inside it.
We have
comments.
That data.
The time stamp.
So we are getting from here the timestamp.
But this time, Pakistan looks doesn't look good, if we put it like this.
So if you look at our web site.
Now.
We are getting the time actually saying invalid date.
But.
First, we need to protect it, because maybe maybe the time is not available, so we don't get the
error and then we should convert this fun to faith by using to date function.
This today's function is actually a built in function from the JavaScript.
So we are getting the time like this, but this is not cool and nice for the website, and it's very
hard to understand information.
We have the date, we have the time, everything and time zone.
No, this is different.
So we have a Tuesday, but we wanted to show this how many minutes ago this it came.
So for doing that, we just right here.
From now, this is the attribute that is building for the React moment.
As soon as we add this one, we can see this is it two days ago, two days ago?
And if you add another one?
That's amazing.
It should come to do the beginning and says a few seconds ago.
All right.
So let's install this one to make it look cooler and nicer.
So at the top, they've.
That is covering everything we need to.
We just say the Max.
Sorry, the margin X.
Would be 10.
So we just push them a little bit to the right side and from the here and now we just see max height
to be 24.
So this is going to limit the place, see?
But you cannot see it.
We cannot even scroll it.
We need to add something we did before.
So a scroll.
For.
No, the first we just make the overflow.
In the y direction to be a cruel.
Now we can school here, but we don't want this ugly scroll bar.
You don't see it in websites like Instagram.
So we if you remember, we installed a package called.
Show you here and package that, Jason, if you remember for previously for this story section, we
installed a package called Tillman Scrollbar.
This Tillman Skirboll allows us to remove the scrollbar by just saying a scroll bar.
None.
So we hide it, and it's just you can just ask for.
All right.
Let's change the other styles we have.
So for the image.
Just after all this debate that is covering everything, first, we need to create a flex.
So we bring everything next to each other.
So we changed the display to Flex so you can see everything is next to each other.
And then we center everything using item center.
It brings us to the center.
And let's add a space between them using a space x to.
And finally, we had a marching button of two and a little bit more space at the bottom.
So let's install the image now.
The image would have a height of seven.
So make it smaller, and then we're going to run it or make it circle using round it for.
And if someone upload a image that is not like a square, we can add object cover to prevent is stretching
the image.
So that is just in case someone put the bad, bad image.
All right.
Let's do it for the.
This username.
The username, we just make it semi-public both.
We just say font semi bald.
All right, and then we.
We push this one to the end by using Flex one for the common section.
So we just say class name.
It's late this.
So this is going to be Flex one.
So push this one to the end, and also, if someone's right, too many, too much things, we wanted
to truncate it, so suggested truncate.
Truncates, so if I write so much
like this.
This is going to be truncated.
So that was it for this part.
I think that's that looks fine.
Let's test it to the other section and compare it for the final version.
Yeah, we just increased the size.
Yeah.
Now you can see, not even the comment is not truncated because we have more space.
So let's try it here.
Nice image.
All right, it's working nice.
Amazing birds.
So that was it for this part in the next section, we are going to add the lack of ability.
So if you look at the final version, this one when we like this post, for example, with this account.
The like button would be.
And also we it's showing one likes.
So let's see it for the next one, too.
So we have one light.
And then if we go with the other accounts, I want to show you that the number of the lights would increase
if we.
So the other icons.
It's signing with quote, it's a hand.
So now if I.
Lie, because if you can see that I didn't like this one before with this account, but we still have
one like you.
But when we like now?
We should see too lax.
So if more accounts for more people like this since on day, this number is going up, going to updated.
And if I dislike it, it's, you know, it's bollocks, so it's going to calculate the number of the
likes.
And also if checks that if I liked it or people to change the color of the like button.
So in the next section, we're going to achieve this first, we just add everything to the guitar and
the reference and we review what we have done now, so we add a message of
show.
Comments.
In the.
Comments section.
From the fire.
Base.
Database.
And just say.
And get.
Data from five tested, yeah, so we just push everything to get half and which we refresh the page
to see the new comment.
So let's review what we have done, so we create a use effect to get the data from the database using
on snapshot, we sorted everything using courier and ordered by.
And finally, we show them inside this section after the caption, so we look through the comments.
And we showed the image, the username and also the comment itself, and we use a package called Moment
or React Moment to show the time that is passed using from now attribute here.
So here we can see that the stealth and react moments.
So this is actually installing Moment two.
So this is based on the another package called moment.
All right.
So in the next section, we are going to achieve this.
They're like functionality and we're going to save the lights inside the database and get the data and
shows.
Show it here.
And before the the user name caption, so see you in the next section.