All right.
In the last section, we have finished installing next year and Tillman CSIS for our application.
And also, we made our initial template for the index, such as file.
In this section, we're going to start with the header section and be able to finish the left.
Section of our project before starting this part, I would like to.
And to get.
GitHub repository it for my application also.
And you can do it as well because beneath GitHub for deploying our application at the end.
So here in the Google.
I search for guitar.
And in GitHub, that can.
Let's sign in with our.
Account, my account is Sarhan Capital.
I sign in, so we're on the right corner.
You can see a plus sign here.
We add a new repository.
And, uh.
And we just named the repository.
I just write down the same as the application and install version for the description will be Instagram.
Clone using next.
Two, yes.
And.
Tailwind.
Yes, yes.
It's going to be public and they're going to create the repository.
So here this is the commands we need to initialize to get up and push our application inside it up,
so we go back to Visual Studio code.
Let's clear the terminal.
First, we need to add everything to the kit.
Using kit at.
That which means all.
Then we have to commit it.
I mean, put the message for the comments and the message will be installed next year.
And tailwind CFS and create.
The.
First template.
Ben?
We go to.
Uh, without a guitar, and we copied this line up, could get remote at.
And we paste it here.
So now we just use get push to the first time when you're pushing your application, you need to call
the it's just telling you you need to use this line of code.
So we copy and paste it here.
But the next time you're committing and pushing, you don't need to do that.
So now we already created our GitHub page, as you can see here.
Uh, we just uh.
You need to adjust the refresh by clicking on this installation for, as you can see now we the get
hub automatically created our right me.
And we have already two commands.
First one is automatically created by the next chess application and the next one is ours, which is
installed next year until the CIUSSS and create the first template.
Click on it.
They see that we installed.
Tilman CCIs.
And also, we changed the title of our application that.
Header feet and model.
And also, we changed the.
Conflict that is.
And global first.
Yes.
All right.
So now we can start.
Creating the hair section here.
Let me demonstrate you again, that's.
Here we have, uh, three parts.
So we have a header section here, which includes three sections the logo, the search bar.
And also we have the menu and the profile icon.
So in this section, in the in this video, we're going to start with the the this part.
All right.
Now in the package touches on level.
They create a folder with coloured components.
All our components will be inside this folder.
And the first component is Heather 30th.
In order to create the functional component, you just need to right after see.
And we click on the first auto suggestion.
In order to get this suggestion, don't forget to install the package.
Ash, the package here is seven React Redux.
React native.
All right now, we just yeah, we just right.
Hannah and we go to.
First, we go to the Explorer section and we go to index searches.
And here we are at the header component that we have just created.
In order to import it, you can automatically import using country space at the end of the header.
A word here.
You just need to go at the end and.
Use control space.
So we get the auto suggestion.
Every click on the first author suggests, and we successfully import this one.
All right.
And then.
We don't need this image, I don't know.
All right, so we already have our header components inside next year inside the index, such as so
we start this server using npm run dev.
So we're going to see the change here.
So as I mentioned, we have three sections inside her left middle and the right section.
So inside the header component.
Instead of this, we're just at three.
Uh, just say left
middle and.
Right.
All right.
We start with the left section.
Which is just a local.
Here we at the some.
Diff, because we need to install them later and use Flexbox.
So we have to death, and inside is the second, do we add the.
Image component, which is a component created by next year, we're going to optimize our image and
make them responsive as well.
So we're going to all imported using this sort of suggestion at a top here, and it has a source attribute
as see.
And the source is going to be the image we're going to find on the internet.
So we just search Instagram on Google, we choose images.
And.
Yeah.
I choose the color to be transparent, which means doesn't have any background.
And we can choose this one.
Shack.
Or this one at this?
This one would be fine.
We just right click on it.
This is from Gen X Gen Explorer stocks.
Com We right click on it and they click on copy image address.
We go back to Visual Studio code and we added double codes and inside a double code.
This set of color coded pasted link.
This is going to give us some error, and this is normal.
Everybody gets this error.
It's showing that because the image component of the next year, if a little bit is secure, it doesn't.
We have to define the.
The links that we are going to use, so.
We need to add this link.
Jan Explorers dot com to next that conflict?
Yes.
So we copy this.
Link.
And we go to hear stuff conflict that yes.
And here we just add images.
And in fact, images the ad, the domains, domains.
And, uh, inside.
And Ari, we at the dummy.
Because this is a conflict file, we need to restart the service, so we need to stop the server using
Contra C.
And we just use campaign Ron Diff to start the server again.
Now we are going to get another error, but this one is already fixed, but the next error is we need
to act with or ha and height or we need to add layout fill.
So we are going to use the layout to fill.
And later, we're going to add the height and width using tailwinds to assist.
So we just say layout feel it means fill the the area it's you can see it's a huge.
Now, but we just can add a class name here and the children's justice.
A class that is going to make this on the keep the aspect ratio off, the image is object.
Contain.
Now you can see the image looks fine.
Let's make it a little bit smaller using.
A height of 24 and width of twenty four.
And it should be relative to be applied.
As you can see it very nicely at the top.
We don't want this logo to be shown firstly in the mobile size, so we just see hidden and in the large
size we want.
We just want to see this logo when the page is in its large scale.
So we just right in line with for the large.
Now, if we increase the size.
Off the page, in some point we should see the logo.
This is the large size.
And if we decrease, we don't see it.
And when we are smaller, we want to see another image.
So let's ask first the cursor pointer.
Before getting to the point that actually it's just at a pointing hand when we hover over the element.
You can see.
All right.
We just need to copy this and the second image that we want to replace with this one when we have a
smaller size.
So in this search result, I want to get.
Another one from Wikipedia.
Just let's make it any color.
Yeah, this one, the first one from Wikipedia dot org, we click on it and we copy it.
Copy the image address here.
We go back to.
Visual studio code, and we replace this as I see the second assassin with the.
This one in the new address, obviously, we're going to get an error because we need to add to Wikipedia
that already to the next that conflict that yes.
So we copy this.
And we go to.
Next, that conflict that is and added here.
Once again, we need to restart the server because we will change something in the config file.
So we can see here to find a change in next aticonfig that restored the server to see the changes in
effect.
So we just started and run their.
We shouldn't get any error now.
But we cannot see the image because this image.
Sorry, so here.
It's healing as well, so we just need to.
Instead of being hidden in the mobile side, I want to be see the image, and in the large side, I
want it to be hidden.
And also, it's too big now.
Let's change this to 10 with the 10.
So, yeah, that's looks better.
So when we.
Now we go to the over the large size, we can see that the logo replaces with.
Instagram.
Yeah.
All right.
So let's a little bit work on the.
Let's add something on the right side, so we can assign it a little bit more.
So we just write down something here like.
Right.
Five.
OK, so.
Let's make it flex the top, the top div that contains everything you make it flex to it, bring everything
next to each other.
And we use Item Center to bring it to the center, uh, horizontally or in y axis.
Then the use justified betveen to push everything to the side, and we make a space between the.
And when we have a bigger screen, I don't want to.
All of them to connect to the.
Well, we just met set the Max with to be.
Six Excel.
All right.
So now we see that this one doesn't connect to the wall.
Is she is still getting the effect of Instagram?
I also that one is in the right side, both in more than six excel.
We are not getting to, we are not touching the ball.
We're going to bring them to the center in the next section.
When we add more things.
To the header, it makes more sense.
So in the next section, we're going to do this search and a search bar, we're going to make this search.
Search bar, we have to install a package called, uh, Tillmans thesis form to get a beautiful, uh,
beautiful form.
So let's before doing finishing this video, let's add everything to the guitar.
So just to get at and we make a new commitment with a message of.
Add insult to.
Instagram logo to the left side of the hardware components.
All right.
And, uh, we just push it to the guitar.
Using Get Push.
Let's check the changes now, if you refresh the page, we should see three comments.
That is done only 18 seconds ago, and the last comment is an Instagram logo to the left side of the
header component and you can see the changes we created.
Heterogeneous.
We finished the left side.
And we added two images.
And also in the next that conflict that yes, we added two domains to not get any error when we're seeing
the images and inside the index that, yes, we added the header component.
Yeah, that was it for this.
S. In the next section, we going to start creating this search bar.
So see you in the next section.