All right.
In the last section we have installed next year and Tilman says and we got the first template of our
project, we got the Hello World in the browser.
In this section we are going to create the sidebar component of our project.
If you look at the final version of the project here.
We can see that we have a logo here, the Twitter logo.
Some menu icons, a button button and also a mini profile, including the name of the person and also
their user name.
And if he decreased the size.
We can see the responsiveness of the sidebar after hitting the.
A large break point.
We see that the menu changes only to icons and also the menu profile is included.
Just the image of the person.
And also the button is disappeared as far.
And after another break point, which is the mobile size, a small size, we don't see the menu anymore.
All right.
So let's start by just creating this sidebar component inside Visual Studio code.
So we go back to Visual Studio code.
Here we go to index searches and we just delete the hello world and we break down our project first.
If we look at the final version, we can see.
We have three main parts, including.
This sidebar here.
We have the feed section.
And also we have the.
Widgets on the right side.
The other one.
The other things we have is the model.
If we want to reply to a post.
If you click on this icon, we can see the model pops up.
Here as well.
So we have four main, main sections in the project.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code and here we break down the project.
So first section is sidebar.
Then we have the feed section.
We have widgets.
And finally, we have the model.
Let's create this sidebar components first.
So inside here, in the main section, in the section like package, that JSON label we created, we
create a folder called Components.
And inside this folder we create a file called sidebar that Jesus.
We can use rf c.
To create a react functional component.
I'm getting this suggestion because I have installed a extension called the new.
Let me show you here.
If you go to view extensions.
We have an extension called iOS seven React Redux, React Native snippets.
If you install this one, you get these kind of suggestions like React.
Functional component and etc..
I highly recommend this.
Uh, extension.
Alright.
So now we have.
The React functional component actually in next year, we don't need this import reactor from reactor
so we can delete it.
So let's import this component inside index that's here.
So here we just say sidebar and we get an author's suggestion that that vehicle is going to auto import
sidebar components.
So we click on this.
You can see that the sidebar component is imported from.
A components folder.
We closed this.
And if you look at our browser now, we can see that their hello world is changed to sidebar, which
we are getting from here.
So the next thinks actually we should put everything inside a.
Another tag, a main tag.
So I'm at a main tank here and we bring everything inside this main tech.
So now we have we should get the same result because we just added an empty div called Main.
But it's better for the search engines to find our content inside this kind of text, not only just
the death.
We call this kind of tax, semantic tax because they have a meaning.
If you use only div, it means that you are using non semantic tags.
All right.
By the way, let's continue for the sidebar section of our project.
Let's break down this sidebar.
Well, one more time we go to the final version.
So here we have it.
Sidebar component here, which includes.
A logo here.
Then we have the menu.
They have the buttons and also we have the mini profile.
Let's break down it inside the Visual Studio.
So this dev, first we have the Twitter logo, then we have.
The menu.
Then we have the button and finally we have the mini profile.
All right, so let's first create the logo of our sidebar.
So here we add a.
Dev.
And inside scientist there, we added a next year image component to use this image component.
This is the built in component of React and we need to import it as well.
So just click at the end of this image and we can use contrast space to get the auto suggestions.
This second auto suggestion is going to import image from next forward slash image.
You can see here.
Yeah.
Let's close this.
Uh.
The left side.
And also we bring this one.
Here too, and we open our localhost 3000 on the right side.
As you can see, we get in an error.
The error is saying that the image component is missing required SRT property.
So SRT property is mandatory in an image component.
So here we added SRT.
And as SASE would be, we just search for the tutor.
Inside Google and we go to Images tab.
So I'm going to use this low, uh, this one here.
So here we right click and we click on copy image address and we can paste it here.
Now we should get another error.
Then the next error is that we need to have a width and height or we need to have layout equals to feel
though this is mandatory as well.
And for image tag.
So here we add the width.
Let's sit there with 250 and also the height to 50 as far.
Okay.
So the next error is and they said that helped the Twitter dot com which we have used here is not configured
under images in your next account fictitious file.
So we need to configure whatever website we use for image task that is mandatory as well.
So we just need to copy this help that twitter dot com.
And we open the Explorer section.
We go to view an explorer.
And we go to next that conflict that is here.
And we should add that domain here.
So.
We just need to add images.
Equal an object.
And the domain.
Domains is equal to and an array and the first.
Uh element is help the Twitter dot com.
When we change something inside the conflict that next that conflict that, yes, we need to restart
the server because we need to see the effect in this way.
So we stop the server using contra see.
And uh, we can use NPR and Ron there to start the server again.
So he is restarting the server now.
There.
The error, uh, should be removed by now.
We refresh the page.
Now we are getting the logo.
So everything worked fine.
Now let's continue.
So we have added the logo.
So in the menu section.
We will start creating the menu item items.
I would like to create a component.
Separate components for each item and then import them inside the sidebar component.
So here we open the Explorer section and we create a new component and we call this component sidebar
menu item.
So we just say sidebar menu item that just.
So we can use our AFC.
RBC for React Functional Component, we can delete the import react from React and we can inside the
sidebar that is the import that.
But first we create a diff and inside is there we import that here this sidebar menu item we can use
contra space to get the auto suggestion.
Let's make it self-closing.
And we can import it by using country space again.
So now we have imported side bar menu item from the same folder, which is components.
And let's check the browser now.
Now we are getting sidebar menu item.
That we have here for the icons.
Yeah, the home icon and etc..
We're going to use a website called Hero Icons.
Hero Icons has the same owner of the Tillman CSF, so it's completely compatible with Tillman CSF.
So let's search for.
Here are our comments here.
So in the search results we click on hero icons dot com.
First we need to install this package, so we need to go to a documentation.
And we just scroll a little bit and for using reaction.
Yes, in our case we can use NPM, install hero icons for a slash react.
So we copied this line of code.
We go to Visual Studio code is stop the server and we paste the code.
And for using the icons.
For example, here there is an example we can use the breaker icon, for example, we just need imported
from here.
Icons for slash react for slash solid or artillery solid is like a thicker and outline is.
So the installation process has been completed.
So we just need to run the server again.
We don't need this.
Here are cons menu.
Uh, tap anymore.
We close it.
So here before the first one, we add a prop.
And the first one is the name and we just a text because I want to add the home.
I care.
I want to stay home.
And the icon.
So let me just add a text and a text would be home for the first one.
It's going to be home.
Arcon.
Like this.
And we need to import it from here.
Are we just import?
Home icon.
From.
He comes first for us to react.
And also because we want to use the home, the thick one.
We use solid.
So we just added forward slash and we just say, solve it.
Let's refresh the page.
We should see the result now.
Yeah.
We already passed the prop, but we didn't use it inside the sidebar menu.
Let's go to sidebar menu item, duchess.
And here we we can get the props here like this or we can this structure it and we just get the texts.
And also we want to get the icon.
So.
So here inside a diff now.
The ad icon here.
You can see the icon here, but it's huge.
So let's decrease the size by just adding it to this class, which is just set the height to be seven.
Now we can see it is smaller here and after the icon we added span and inside the span we just add the
text.
That we're getting here.
Yeah.
That is home.
So we go to we go back to Sidebar Digest and we copied this one few more times.
In the final version, we have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight items.
So we need to copy this seven more times using alt shift A.I..
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
So now we need to change that.
Just two ticks and we add a new icon.
So the next takes would be explore.
And the icon is hashtag icon, just like the hashtag icon.
So we getting this suggestion or to suggestion, but we don't want it from solid.
We want it from outline.
So we just manually we can get it.
So we just go up.
And we import.
Hashtag.
Icon.
From.
Hero icons of life.
Let's refresh the page.
Yeah, you can see the hashtag and explore.
The third one is notification.
Conventions and the icon is built.
Which is from outline as well.
So we're getting the suggestion Bill I can't outline as solid so we choose outline here.
We can see now here.
The next one is messages.
And the icon is inbox icon.
I think I imported.
Oh, my God.
Hashtag.
Sorry.
That's fine.
So let's go.
Let's continue.
The next one is bookmark.
Yes.
I puke, Mark.
And the icon is bookmark icon.
PwC.
And this is going to be from offline as well.
So we can see it here.
Let me increase the size here.
You can see a better.
The next one is lists and the icon is clipboard.
Clipboard.
KLEPPER.
I come from Oslo.
And then we have profile.
Which is use user icon.
And finally, we have more.
Which is the dot horizon.
That circle who an aka?
This one.
All right.
So we have created the menu you have completed next.
Let's go to the next part, which is the button.
We just create a button.
And, uh, we just saw a tweet.
We can see here later, we're going to style it.
But just for now, we'll leave it here.
And then we we have the menu profile, which has the dev.
And inside the div we have it.
We have an image we have then like another div that is covering a user name.
And so the user first name, a family name and also the user name.
And also we have another icon which is that dot that that horizon icon.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code and the and the image.
First we use images tag.
Let's just bring an image.
I just choose my image from online.
So you can you can put your own name.
Your own image.
So I just get this image copy, image address and we go back and put it inside.
So see.
We can see it here.
The old would be user image.
And then after the image we have.
As I mentioned, we have another diff that is covering two things.
The name and the username.
So for the name we just added edge for tag and I just write my name.
Then we have a paragraph.
We added, uh, my twitter username, which is code with sahand.
Yeah, we can see it here.
And also at the end we have that that horizon.
Uh.
Which is dot or rise in.
And it's going to be from out line as well.
Know, we can see that this is very huge.
Let's decrease the size.
Just adding height of five, for example.
All right.
So we have completed the sidebar components and the items.
Now let's just start styling it.
If we look at the final version.
We can see that the icon and the menus, they have a hovering effects.
So when we hover over them, we can see a different color in the background.
So but the background color of the menu is gray, but the icon is blue and here is gray, too.
So if we do a styling for each of them individually, it's going to be a lot of work.
But we can use it.
We can use the a costume, a style of tailoring cases, and create one class that is covering all of
them so we can use for all of them.
So we can if we can do that and simply add one class to each item and we get the same result for everyone.
So let's do this and see it inside the real example.
So.
For creating a custom class we need to go to.
Inside the Telvin.
Our goal was a global ceasefire.
So first let let's add this constant missile here and see the effects in real time when we are doing
the crisis.
So.
We have the logo.
So this div that is covering the logo.
We had a class called Hover Effects.
I would just make it this.
And we can use this one for the other places as well.
For example.
For the mini profile.
We add this one too.
And also we we want to add it to a sidebar menu item as well.
So in this of that is covering everything, we add this hover effect class as well.
Now if we we create this hover effect class, we can see the results in all of the.
So for creating them.
We need to go to Global.
That's CSIS.
So we opened the Explorer section using Country B and we go to a styles folder here and we go to globals.
That's the SS.
Here we can add our custom at.
Custom styling component.
We just need to add a layer here.
And just two components.
And inside is it's going to be that class that we want to define.
And the name of that class was Hover Effect.
So if we open up a set of curly braces and we apply our classes using.
Apply here.
Let's refresh your page and see the fix.
So now we're just going to just add our first class.
I want the cursor to be pointer.
When we hover over the element.
If you now if you hover over the elements, we can see occurs a point in hand.
So next one is change the background color of when we hover over it.
So we change the background color to Gray 200.
You can see the gray color.
Then let's make it rounded.
So the the added rounded corner.
You can see the rounded corner here.
Then.
Let's change the width and height.
So wait, it would be 52 pixels.
And also this is when we have a mobile site.
So this is a small but when we have a larger screen in the in the larger breakpoint like Excel, the
breakpoint prefix.
We want the width to be also.
So now if you, uh, increase the size of the browser to larger screen, you can see that the.
Uh, with is auto.
It's the size of the screen.
But when we have a smaller screen, we have a smaller rounded one.
Maybe now looks a little bit weird, but if first wait we keep continue and complete their styling and
you can see the result.
Very nice.
So now we want to add the height.
So for the mobile size, I want the hide or less an x large size.
We want the height to be 52 pixels.
And.
For the.
Excel.
Break point prefix.
We want the height to be auto as far.
And when we have a larger.
Size over x large.
We want the rear and a padding of three.
So in this size, we have some padding.
All right.
So let's keep this one bigger and life sized and let's bring the base code on the right side so we can
see this section.
Better so we can install it in the.
Big sighs first.
So we finished with the hover effects.
Uh.
Sale We closed this global assets.
Yes.
And let's continue to sell our sidebar more.
For example, we bring this home next to the icon and also this one as well.
So we go to sidebar menu item, which is for the individual items.
Let's bring them next to each other here by changing the display to flex.
You can see now they came next to each other, but they are not aligned with each other.
So we can change two items, a line item center, or you can say item center for Talbots.
Yes.
So we bring them next to each other.
I mean, horizontally.
Then we changed the text to be gray.
700.
A little bit brighter.
And, uh, we changed it.
Just, uh, justified content to be center as well.
Now.
It went to the center of the screen, actually, but.
Actually, we want I want them to in the larger screen to be at the beginning.
So in the x large and breakpoint prefix, we changed the justify from center to a start.
So it comes to beginning.
Then let's change this to the size of the text to be large.
And also let's add some space between the icon and the text using a space x three.
We can see this space now.
I want this home to be bought, but I don't want the others to be both.
So for cyber ninjas, for the home section, the cyber menu item home, I add an active attribute and
be imported from sidebar menu item.
Here.
And here in the Texas, a span.
I had a class name, but make this fun for using variables.
So I use it back.
Take.
And I just say if.
It is active.
The active is true then.
Make the font bold.
So you can see the only home is both now.
And the next thing I want to do is make this text hidden when this is and when the borders screen is
smaller or less than x large.
So first we make it hidden so we don't see it now.
But for the x large and above, I want it to be in line so we can see it.
Now, if we have a smaller screen than this, we don't see the pics.
Let's keep continuing install this button, the tweet button.
So we go back to sidebar notes and in the button section we add some styles to the button.
So we had a class name and the first class.
We just want the background to be blue.
400.
Which is similar to the real Twitter.
Then let's change the text colour to be white.
And we make it rounded using a rounded full.
And we need just to add some.
At.
Like a weight and height to make it similar to the tweeters one.
So the width would be 56 and height to be 12.
We make the font to be bold.
And we can add a shadow effect as well using terms.
Yes, easily by adjusting shadow and B, make it small and medium shadow like this.
And for A hovering, I want it to be a little bit darker when we hover over it.
So you just say hover.
And they change the brightness to be 95%.
So 5% less when we hover over it can see now.
And also, let's make the tweet.
Text to be a little bit larger.
But just seeing ticks large.
Similar to one we did it is text.
I want this button to be hidden when we have a smaller screen.
So I make it hidden.
When we have a mobile size and an x large and breakpoint prefix and above, I want it to be in line.
So now when we have a smaller screen, we don't see the button.
Okay.
Let's go.
Let's continue for a minute for a full section.
So inside sidebar, the chess.
We go to a menu for a fall section and after this.
However, in fact, let's first change the text color to be gray 700.
Then let's change the display to flex.
To bring them next to each other.
And similar to what we did before, we bring them horizontally next to each other using items center.
And, uh.
We can use Justified Center to bring it to the center.
Horizontally that the items with the, uh, thing vertically.
This is horizontally.
Yeah.
Justify.
Center.
It's fancy across the middle.
But the.
We can.
Fix that.
Uh, just say, uh, we can say more than a large.
Me just to justify a start.
All right.
Let's add some margin top off auto.
This is going to help us when we have a smaller zoom level.
This one comes to the end, but now it's not happening because we need to set the height of the screen
to be at least at the size of this screen, like a mini height screen.
So inside index that yes, we go to menu.
And we had a class there.
First we changed the display to flex because I want all of them to be next to each other.
Then we changed the min height to be a screen.
So.
Now and then.
We set the max with to be seven Excel.
What does it mean?
First, let me change the mix to auto.
It means a major margin exporter.
So it comes to this center.
You can see let's add a just background color of red hundred.
You can see it's what's happening here.
So we change the max with to be seven excel.
So for 200% a zoom level we have some space here and here equally.
The reason we have equal space because we use mimics auto.
Yeah.
And we have this read to the end.
So because we have the minimum height screen.
So let's remove this background red color, which as I just added for explaining that.
So that is fine now.
For a sidebar.
For the top level there was because every half here.
That is covering everything.
We had a class name and we want to.
We changed the display to flex, but I wanted to first to be hidden because in the mobile screen I don't
want to have a menu, but in the mobile screen and above, let's change the display to flex so we can
see them.
But Flex bring them next to each other like this so we can change the flex direction to column.
Legs direction to column.
So they come back on top of each other.
Now the mini profile is at the end.
So as I mentioned, I want this always to be at the end.
So that's why we added the margin top or to.
For as many powerful.
So let's do the increase the zoom level to 100%.
Then you can see them because the width is very high, because this is very long.
But we can fix it here.
We just say, what is there?
First, we add a padding of two.
So they a little bit they pushed to the center.
And let's.
Uh.
For X large and above.
We changed the items to star instead of items center.
And I want it to be fixed because.
When we if you look at the final version, when we're scrolling down, I want this side menu, sidebar
menu.
It's always be.
There.
I don't want it to scroll down.
So I change it to be fixed here.
To do that.
Okay.
It's fixed now and then.
Let's set the height to be for the reason I'm doing that.
Because now because we change the f f position to be fixed so we don't have this margin top effect anymore.
So that's why we need to change the height to be full.
Yeah.
You can see now the effects you.
Let's keep continuing for the user profile section.
So we go back to mini profile.
This increase the size of this again.
So now.
Uh, let's make this a, uh, name.
I have to make it bold using font.
Bold.
You can see here.
Now let's decrease the size of the image.
So the image should have a class name and we set the height and width to be ten.
So just say height ten with ten and we make it rounded.
My picture was rounded actually by default.
But if you're using your image, probably if you don't have a rounded image, make this fun.
Rounded for.
For this user name.
Let's.
Change the color to gray.
Uh, just say ticks.
Gray 500.
And let's add some space between the image and these things using for the x large and above.
I want wanted margin right off to to add here and for the dot dot horizon, I want the margin left.
So for the x large and above, we add a margin left of eight.
They can't see.
Looks like this.
And I think that is fine.
But I want this.
And to be a little bit next to each other so we can add a leading five.
So add a space of five here between the.
So did the same things we did for here.
We do for this minute for.
So I want this text user name and depth horizon to be hidden when we have a smaller screen.
So we're for this one and it's this fun together.
So I add a dual cursor here using Alt.
And first I wanted to be hit in, but in the x large and above, I want it to be in line.
So now in this smaller screen, we don't see the.
So.
And then also for the logo, I want the background to be blue instead of the this color is just gray.
So let's go style this logo first.
Let's remove this padding around it.
It's just coming from the image problem we have.
So we we removed the padding using padding zero.
And also let's change the background color when we hover over it from gray to blue.
And just a hundred is enough.
Like this.
Alyssa It looks like Knots Circle so we can add some padding in the x level x axis.
We just say if it's bigger than x large, let's add a padding itself.
One.
So now it looks better.
And also so let's add some space between this menu and this button.
So for the for this state that is covering all of the items, first we add a margin top of four.
So added space between them and the logo and the added margin bottom of.
2.5.
2.5 is equal to ten pixels.
Now we have this space.
Then also in the.
And.
Ex large and above.
I want the items to be at the beginning.
So this item starts now.
You cannot see the effect, but when we are adding to all the other parts like Feed and other section,
we can see the effect.
But just for now.
We have everything.
Okay.
That was it for the sidebar menu.
Let's add it to the get up now.
They stop the server using controversy and we add everything to get everything get at dot and with the
message off, which is just get commands.
Dash am and the message is create.
Sidebar component.
And we push it to the top using get push.
Now if we go to guitar and we refresh the page by clicking on this tweeter, we should see three comments.
And the last one is create a sidebar component.
So as you can see, we created this sidebar, case file and side components folder.
We created sidebar menu item for each menu and for the next that conflict that yes, we added our add
the Twitter link.
We installed hero icons and finally indexed the GSV.
We added this sidebar component and for the global stats, yes, we added a custom utility custom a
style for the details.
Yes.
And the name was Hover Effect.
Yet that was it for our sidebar section of our project.
In the next section we start with the feed section.
So see in the next section.