All right.
In this section, we're going to start creating our project and it starts with our terminal and installed
the next genius app.
So we open the terminal.
We just.
We are going to use a common prompt.
Or any Trong Terminal app you would like to use.
So we click on the comment from let me increase the size a little bit so you can see it better.
And let's check the next year's Web site.
What we need to do first for installation.
So we open the Google Chrome.
And here we search for next year's.
In the results section, we have a website.
It's the next year, that --, next year by Verso, so we click on this web site.
As you can see, the React framework for production.
And we can just start learning or we go straight to the documentation.
In the documentation we have.
All the parts like getting started, basic features like page jazz, data, fishing, building services,
support and layouts for getting started and make sure that you have all the requirements there.
You just need to notice twelve point two twenty two point.
Zero or later and macOS or Windows or Linux.
Then for creating a next year, and we just need to run.
Knicks and trade Knicks app, and for the latest version, we just need to add that latest.
So we copy this code and we go to our terminal.
And we go to the folder that we would like to create a project, I would like to create a project in
my desktop, so I go to my this sub by city.
Desk top.
And once I'm in the desktop, I paste to code and also after a space, I've specified the name of the
project.
So I already made like a seven version of this project for my practice, but I just I write down here
movie.
All we have.
Version eight, but you can call it anything you like.
So we press enter and we wait for the installation to be finished.
As you can see, let me increase the size decreases, so yeah, we're going to install three tanks.
Are you going to start next?
React and react, Dom, because next is based on React.
So we need to have these two packages, but NPC's is going to install all of them.
And also in this script, we have Div, which runs that the next year under development mode.
So in order to run it, we just need to write down npm run dev.
OK.
Until this one is installing, let's go to the telephone CSIS website as well, because we need telephone
CFS because we are using tailored CSIS for styling our project.
So research tells us to assess.
So in the search results, we see Tellement Tillmans cases that come.
And we click on this website.
Rapidly build modern Web sites without ever leaving your HTML in our case, you're not leaving our JavaScript
file because we are using next year.
So that's a great feature of this, uh, framework.
It's going to help us without needing to leave our code to style our project.
As you can see now here.
The demo that's this writing just in the class names.
And everything is changing based on the class name.
So we need to go to the documentation here as well.
And.
This is a like a tutorial for installing televised cases for normal material, but we as we are using
framework and.
Like, next year, we just need to go to the framework guides in the installation, and we just choose
next year here.
If we look through this tutorial, you see that first, we need to create a project that we have already
done.
We just need to do that, create nicks and Nicks app installation and go inside the project folder and
later we need to install.
Tailwinds, yes, by this code and also initialize it with this code.
So let's check that it's finished.
Yeah, it's finished already.
So we just opened this in the beer school.
Uh, the text editor that I'm using and you can open this folder in any text editor you like to use.
So we just see into the folder that he created creative movie.
App version eight.
And inside this, I just use code space.
Dot.
To open the visual studio code to this directory as soon as I enter, we see that the Visual Studio
code is open and all the folders and packages are here as well.
So we maximize the window.
We close the Get Started tab.
Now, in order to install the turbines, yes, we can use the internal terminal of the Visual Studio
Code.
Here you can see what for opening and closing the terminal, we can use control tactic.
So here we call it, press control back take or also we can open the terminal here from the View menu
terminal.
All right.
Let's clear this.
And increase the size that you can see it better.
And we bring it.
In this corner, and we open the.
Children's to on the right sides.
All right.
So we already installed this section, and now we need to copy this line of code and paste it here into
terminal we press into.
This one is very quick, maybe takes a few seconds to be finished.
All right.
That's already finished, so we clear the page and buy this line of code.
We're going to initialize the Taleban CSIS.
So this is initialization actually creates two files posts CSIS that conflict artists and tailwind.
Uh, that conflict, Duchess.
And here for configuring our template for next year, we need to copy this code.
And we pasted inside to Tillman that conflict such is.
So we go here, let's meet to decrease the size.
All right.
So we just delete everything here and paste it here.
This is just the mayor saying that we can.
Except all the JavaScript files inside the pages and components that justice for Typekit script, G6
and TSX, and also in the components as well.
And we don't have any plug ins yet, and the team is empty as well, so next, we need to copy this
three line of code and paste it inside the globals that CSIS, which is in the south folder.
So we open the Stalls folder here.
You can see we have two sisters files.
One is the Globalstar thesis that all the templates scores here like a style in the body and everything
that we want to apply to all the website.
But as we are using Taleban CCPA, we are not dealing with any specific files.
We just delete all of them and paste these three line of codes here.
Now, everything has been finished for tailwinds to this part, and we just need to use relative to
run our application.
So it's just right down here, NPN
let's clear this npm run dev and we press enter.
As you can see, the servers this is it started on Port three thousand.
And we can have access to the website in this URL HTP.
Localhost three thousand, so we in order to open this one, we just you can just keep the control and
click on the link.
And now if you wait a little bit to see our website with the Taleban to templates on the right side.
So this is just the template.
And in the next section, we are going to completely remove and put our own components and everything.
So before doing anything else, I'm going to show you how to use GitHub to push our website through
our application to the guitar.
And later, we're going to need this.
To deploy our website to traversal.
So let's stop the server using controversy and press why.
Let's clear this so you can see it better.
And here.
I go to my guitar, so we search, get half here and in the website called Kip get hot dot com.
Let's maximize this and we go inside.
I already have their count.
If you don't have yet, how account can make sure to sign up otherwise signing indicator with your username
and password?
My username is every day and I just quickly write down my password.
And I sign in.
So and the riots and the top rise and the increase the size a little bit on the top right.
Here on the plus icon, we click and we click on new repository.
And.
We are going to create a new repository, and we're just going to name it here.
I named the file, we just call it.
Uh, movie.
App version eight, but you can call it anything you like, it should be unique in your projects and
the description would be.
This is it.
A app.
Created by next DOT.
Yes.
And tell.
And CSX.
Using I am TV.
Database.
Just quickly fix this.
All right.
That's it.
We just keep it public or in your case, you can keep it private if you don't want other people to see
your call.
But, uh, I live it public and we don't need to check any of these things.
You just click on create a repository.
Now here, GitHub suggests some.
Codes to push our code to the guitar directly, so we go back to.
Fear Visual Studio code, and we just use get in it to initialize, get at and commit our website.
So here we just uh.
You get in it to initialize our.
Kids and we use Kit and two to add everything.
Let's clear this again.
And finally, we say get comments because we want to have the message that which we want change we have
done to the project in this stage.
So this is just a.
First video and the first the part that I'm going to call it just the.
Install.
Next.
You know, next year and Taleban CSIS.
OK, so now we just need to go back to the.
Get her.
And.
This line of code we need to copy.
So we need to specify which getup you are l, we want to connect with our application so we can copy
this and we go back to the Visual Studio code and we paste it here.
Then we just need to right get push.
And it suggests us the first time that we use get push as City Stream Origin Maine, so but the next
time we don't need to copy and paste it, so we use this line of code.
But the next time we just write down, get push.
So I'm going to show you in the next video how we do it.
So if if we now call back to our.
Repository and we refresh the page here by clicking on this, we see that our application is completely
uploaded to the get half.
And we have to come it's if you click on the comments.
This is the initial comment that comes from the next year's application, we didn't do this one, but
it's automatically done and we write down installed next year until next.
So here if you click, we see all the changes we have done to our projects.
So in the package that Jason, we installed the this is related to Tilman CSIS.
We installed these things in the post this conflict that yes, he added this line of code.
And in the global south, as we delete everything and we added the Taliban CSIS base component utilities.
Intelligencia says that conflict that we added this codes and finished, so in the next section, we
are going to start.
Having our own template and.
Remove this kind of the next year template and have our own template based on the final version of our
project.
You can see that in the final version of our project.
We have.
Like a header and now four and also the results section, so we're going to divide our code to three
parts and start with the header and continue with the NAF bar and the results section.
So see in the next section for the templating, our website.