All right.
In the last section we have completed installing Tailwind CSS.
In this section, we're going to work on the header section of the home page.
If you look at the final version and we go to the home page.
We can see that we have a header here that is only common for the home page, because if we go to other
pages, for example, inside the pages related to the result, we have a different.
Uh, format of the header, but this header for this page is common for all the pages, like for example,
the image page or the web page and also the footer is common between the home page and the.
That page related to the results.
So we don't need to add this header for the home page inside the layout that is, but we need to add
the header of the result page in the layout just for the.
A result page.
So I'm going to show you later how to add it to the layout for the result page.
But for now we just add this header inside the home page.
So if we go back to Visual Studio Code.
We can open the Explorer section using Contour shift E and here we just go to inside the app page six
inside the app directory.
And instead of this div, we're going to return just the component.
So I'm going to delete this div, I'm going to create an empty fragment.
And inside this empty fragment we're going to have the that component that we're going to create.
So I'm going to create a component here with the name home.
Header.
And we need to create another folder here inside the SRT folder.
Cause components inside the circuit.
You just choose SRK folder.
And here we click on the new folder icon and we just call it components.
And inside this folder we're going to create another file and we call it home header.
That gsx we can simply create a React functional component using RFC and we press enter.
We have a component now, so now we need to import this one inside the page that Gsx just after the
home header, you just put the cursor and use contra space to all to get the auto suggestion and click
here to import it.
And if you remember, we have an alias add sign forward slash for the root directory, which is the
SRT folder.
And so instead of just going back and just choose.
The component.
We just say add sine forward slash component components for slash home header for importing this component.
So now if we go to our website, we go to the local host and we refresh the page, we just see the home
header which we have created.
All right, So now we just bring this one to the right side.
So we're going to work on it and we bring the paste code on the left side so we can have the and see
the changes on real time.
So I'm going to close this one as well.
So we have more space on the left side.
Let me increase the size of this one as well.
So let me show you what we are doing in the final version.
So let me draw it for you.
So we have a.
Yeah.
Header component at the top.
So let me change the colour here.
So let's make it red.
So we have a header.
Tag.
Which includes another div inside it.
And this tape is going to have these three places.
And we're going to push this tip to the right size.
So it's going to be this side.
And then we're going to have a link tag for the Gmail images.
And we're going to have this icon, which is going to get from a package called React Icons.
And then we're going to create this button.
And these two, when we hover over them, we see a underline.
And also the cursor is pointer.
So we're going to create a custom tailored CSS class for these two.
And also we're going to create this hover effect for this one and this for the button.
So we go back to home JSX ex sorry, Home header six.
I'm going to change this diff to header tag, which is going to help for the SEO purpose because we're
going to tell the search engines that this is a header inside the website.
So as you can see, we are getting some suggestion from the GitHub copilot.
So I'm not going to use it now, but sometimes they are very helpful, so I'm going to use them on type.
So I'm going to create another diff.
As I mentioned, we're going to have a diff here and inside the diff we're going to have to link and
I'm going to use a link tag from next JS.
The next chess link tag actually helps us to go from one page to another without refreshing the page.
And also it's very helpful for the SEO purposes because it's going to add automatic anchor tag inside
this tag.
So I'm going to create a link tag which is coming from next forward slash Link U.
We got the auto suggestion, so we we need to close this tag.
And inside this, the first link tag.
I'm just going to say Gmail.
So let's see it here inside our website.
Let's refresh the page.
Sometimes the auto refresh doesn't work, so you need to refresh refresh it to yourself.
And we got an error saying that the H shift property is empty, so we need to add it.
H ref tag.
So I'm not going to send places any places.
So we just kind of want to add.
Now we can just add some.
Where you are.
For example.
H.
T.
P.
S.
And we just send them to mail dot google dot com.
This one should be h t t ps.
All right.
So now we see that Gmail here.
It has a hover effect, but it doesn't have underline.
So it probably we don't need even to have the custom term CCIS as well because we just need to add some
underline for it.
So I'm going to add a class name here.
And then we just want to add some underline here.
If we just write Down Under.
When we hover over it, we want to add underline.
On the line.
Now, when we hover over this Gmail, we see.
And the underline.
So we need to have two of this one.
Another one for the image, as you can see from the final version.
So I'm going to copy this one using alt shift arrow down.
And this one is going to be images.
Which is going to go to image that Google.com.
So, for example, here, this Gmail or image, when we click on images, this is going to go, Oh,
I think this one is image image.
All right.
So when we click on images, it's going to redirect us to images that Google does come.
Okay.
And if you just redirect the person to your own pages, you're not going to refresh the page.
It's just going to be instant because this is coming from the next year's forward slash link.
And also if you check the SEO for if you check the quick source viewer.
You can see that an anchor tag is added automatically inside.
So the link tag is actually a div and also an anchor tag inside.
And the class that we have added is added to the anchor tag.
So the edge strip is there.
And also you can see the closing tag.
And so this is very good for SEO purposes.
Oh, sorry.
This device we have already, we added the link tag is only added the anchor tag, but this one behaves
differently in in our own website.
It doesn't refresh the page.
So we go back to our website, we bring it to the right side.
So let's add the button as well at the here.
So just under the link tag, first we need to add this icon.
So I'm going to create this icon using a package called React Icons.
So we need to go to Google and we search for.
React.
Icons.
And in the search result, we see a GitHub repository.
Called uh react dash icons dot GitHub, dot io forward slash react icons.
This is a GitHub link and if you click on it.
We see that this website.
Risk icons any.
If you want to have any types of icons you can find here, they have a collection of all the places.
For example, if you are familiar with the hero icons or material design icons and also even found awesome
icons, all of them are here, so we don't need to install them individually so we can find them separately
here.
The first thing we need to do to use this package is to install it.
So we need to just write down MP and install React icons.
Dash v dash save.
So I'm going to copy this.
Go back to Visual Studio Code and we stop the server using Control C, press Y, and we can paste the.
Code.
To install it.
This is going to install the package.
And for using that, we just need to search the icon here and imported from React icons and add it as
a component inside our website.
So I'm going to search for that icon that I want to add is called Grids Grid Dots.
So you just for example, you want to find something similar.
You just write grid and find your icon.
And this is from all these places.
So we just say, I want it.
My icon is called Grid Dot, so I'm going to search for that.
And if you click on it, this is going to copy the the tag for you.
And if you come back here, we can start the server again using NPM run dev.
And here we can add the icon.
So I'm going to open a tag, paste the icon and close it and we need to import it as well at the top.
So we're just going to import.
As you can see, we get a suggestion like that.
But this is going to be inside here and it's coming from.
Reacts.
Dash icons.
Forward slash.
This one is this started with TB so it's going to be react dash icons slash TB.
So if you get it from font awesome, it starts from f b and you need to add PHP at the end.
So now we should see the icon inside our website after refreshing the page.
Okay.
We need to wait after the.
We start the server.
Okay, Now we see the icon here.
So let's add some effect to the icon.
So here inside the icon, I'm going to add a class name.
So the.
Classes we need to add is firstly think First I want to change the background colour to be transparent
in the normal time, but when we hover over it I want to have a different background colour.
So transparent for the background.
Then when we hover over it.
I want to change the background color to be gray.
200.
So now we should see the grey colour here, but it's completely square.
I want to make it rounded, so I'm going to add rounded fold to make it fully rounded, which is equal
to border radius.
It at 10,000 pixels.
All right, so.
After this, we're going to make it a bigger by just saying takes.
Four x.
L.
The reason you see it so big, because I have added a zoom level 3000.
So for you to to see it better, but actually this is three times or four times as smaller than you
see here.
And then.
We want to add some padding of two pixels, so add some space between the background and the icon.
So now we see it like that.
So after that, we're going to add the button here.
So as you can see, this class became three dots because we are using that
extension called inline fold.
If you haven't installed it yet, you can solve it.
And this is going to help you to have a when you don't see this class, this is going to be disappeared.
So it's going to help you to easily read your code.
So after this icon, we're going to add a button.
Saying, sign in.
And then we're going to style this button as well.
So the style is background blue.
We change the background color to be blue 500.
And then we change the text color to be white.
And after that, we're going to add a padding in the x axis of six and in the Y axis of two.
And we can change the font weight to be medium, which is equal to font weight.
500.
So now after that, we're going to add and we want to make it rounded a little bit in the corner.
So we're going to add the rounded to be medium.
And when we hover over it.
We want to have a brightness.
Of 105%.
So now when we hover over it, we see it gets a little bit brighter.
So like this.
And also we want to add some shadow, too.
So when we hover over it, we want to have a shadow of media.
You see a small shadow under that.
So if you want to make it a little bit smooth, that changes.
You can add some transition.
For example, transition on the shadow.
So when we hover over it, you see the changes a little bit slower.
All right.
So now let me decrease the size.
So this is the actual size.
Now, the things we want to do is just bring them to the right side.
So we need to install them using the diff here we have at the top.
So we need to first think first we need to install this dev.
First, we added the class inside the header.
We're going to bring them next to each other by changing the display to flex.
So actually this is going to be a.
Because this is a diff, we need to change the flex here to bring them next to each other.
But this flex is going to help you to push it to the right side.
Now displays flex here.
And then we can just change the just to fly content and to push them to the right side.
And also we can add some padding of five so we have some space between them and the role of the browser.
And also we can use the text is M to make the text a little bit smaller for these two text.
Then for here we want to add some space between them.
So we just say a space X for, for these icons.
Now they, they get a little space between them.
This is a very useful.
And it's exclusive for 12 seasons.
And if you check that and see this syntax, as you can see by for adding this simple class, we need
to work a lot in the CSS part, but the services automatically create these classes syntax for us because
this is going to add a space only between the icons, not before or after.
So this is very helpful.
So after that we want to bring them all of them in the same row vertically.
We want to align them.
So we're going to use something called Items center, which is going to bring the items.
Exactly.
In the center vertically.
So this is the mobile screen.
And in the bigger size, we see them like this.
Okay.
That was it for the creating the header section for the home page.
Let's add this one to the GitHub by using contour shift G opening the source control.
And here we can add everything to GitHub using this plus icon and we just create a message for that
which is going to be add.
Let me.
Pipe down at all.
Header.
And we can just see components here.
So we can just commit and push using this icon and click on the commit and push.
This is going to apply the changes inside our GitHub repository.
Let's go back to our GitHub repository.
We click here to go back to the home page of our GitHub repository.
As you can see, we have.
Now.
Four commits and the last commit is add home header component.
So let's review what we have done here.
We have installed a package called React Icons.
To get the icons for our website.
We can use this for later as well to add more icons inside and different parts of the website.
Then also inside the page that we have just selected this whole text and we have added our home header
component.
Inside we have created a component called Home Header dot JSX, which is importing a link tag from next
forward slash link, which is helping us to create a link tag for our Gmail and images.
And also we have imported an icon from React Icons.
Then you have to added the header tag for the parent.
And inside that we have a dev which includes the to link tag to gmail and images.
And also we have an icon grid dot icon.
And finally we have a button saying sign in.
So in the next section, we're going to work on the body part of the home page.
So we're going to create this section here.
So see you in the next section.