All right, in the last section, we have finished the local part of the header in this section, we're
going to start creating the search bar.
Let's check the final version of the project.
Let's zoom a little bit.
So we can see it better.
Yeah.
We have actually here.
There, which have an input inside it.
And the input.
He's a little bit pushed to the right side.
Here and we have an icon which we're going to get from hero icons dot com and the icon is has the position
of absolute and it's relative to the.
Dave, that is covering the inputs.
All right.
Let's go back to our visual studio code and open the.
Our local hosts on the right side.
And also there.
In order to have this beautiful input, we are going to use a package called children's services forums
to have at the basic forms, a styling.
So we just search here on the Google.
Tailwinds, CSIS forms.
And we just search for a get up.
So it's a GitHub that can tell when labs 12+ CSIS forms.
We click on this link.
And if you scroll down a little bit, we can see that we can use Indian installed children's, use this
form to install the package.
And also, we need to add this package as a requirement inside the plugins of tailwinds that conflict
that yes.
So we copy this line of code.
And inside the terminal.
First, we stop the server to clear the.
Terminal and replace the.
Court.
So.
We need to add this requirement.
To tell us that conflict, that duchess here.
Now, the plug ins are empty.
We just need to paste this inside the array of plug ins.
All right.
And just in the meantime, we go to Tillman's hero icons to get the icon.
So we search you icons on Google and we go to the hero icons dot com.
You are actually as part of Tilden CSF Project.
And tell us, yes, this actually owns this website, and they're going to add more and more icons soon,
and it's very compatible to tailwinds to assist.
In order to install it, we can go to documentation here.
And for installing, we just need to copy this line of code and then install Hulu icons slash.
Uh, Ricky, react.
So we posted here in the terminal and for using that, you just need to import the icon from here.
I react if you want the solid, we need to write down a solid if you want the outline we need off-line
and the different if this is outlined, this is solid.
Just this solid is filled with the color.
OK, so here we just copy this one as a reference, and we go to Heather de Jesus and at the top, we
paste it and we change this font to search.
I.
Search, I.
And this is we want to use the artillery, so we changed the solid to artillery.
All right.
Yeah, let's fix here and let it be.
And we don't need the diff at the top because we use the Flexbox for the top there.
So in the header, we delete the diff here and here, and we move this lift here.
This is the left side.
The two images.
And then we have the middle here and.
This is going to be the right time.
So that is correct now.
So in the middle, we want to add.
Uh, Dev.
And inside that day, another day for the icon, and we add the search icon here, let's run the server
using A.N.
Diff to see the changes inside our website.
And.
They're getting an error.
Know icons react.
Imports, which are nothing.
Yeah, unexpected.
Yeah, I did actually to.
Double code your.
Yeah, that should be fine now.
Let's refresh the page.
The element type is invalid.
So let's see what we have done.
Iraq announced last week that it's fine if search, I can't be made a mistake.
And here.
Two emergency search.
Always when I'm typing, I.
Do this kind of a fix?
Sorry about that.
So we cannot see the icon yet because it doesn't have any dimensions, so we're just at a height of
five.
So now we can see the icon here.
Let's change the color of the icon to tex gray.
Let's do it.
Five hundred, it makes it dark gray.
And after that, let's add the input after this stuff, so we had to input.
With the type of.
Tax.
We don't need the name or I.D..
So we can see the impact here.
And let's add the position of absolute for the icon that div that covers the icon, so the position
would be absolute and it's going to be relative to the div that is covering both of the.
Icons and also the input, and you can see we have some basic styling from the Taleban CSF forms.
But let's add more things like a placeholder.
We just say place order search.
If you're wondering why I get a lot of other such yes, yeah, I installed it at a package, an extension
called Tap Nine, and I bought the actual diff pro version of the tap, known on tap, known based on
my previous coding and also the codes online.
Gives me suggestion, and that helps me to quote faster.
I highly recommend Tableau.
Even the basic version is going to help you a lot.
But if you are a student, actually, you can get it free if you can use your student email address
to get a provision for free.
All right, let's continue.
And yeah, for the input section, let's at some styling.
Just add a class name.
Let's change the background color to Gray.
A light gray like 50.
And it would be similar to the original Instagram website.
Let's add some padding left of tin to push this search placeholder to the right so we can position the
this icon to the center.
Later, and let's change the border color to be gray as well, but a dark gray, similar color as the
icon and.
Let's make it a little bit smaller using Tex as an.
Next, let's add some.
Uh.
We just want to make the border rounded and also we want to be focused on it instead of blue.
We have a black color for doing this.
We need to add to.
Tailwind faces classes.
One is focus ring black.
And also, we need to focus.
Border black.
Now we get a black border, if you don't if you miss one of these two classes, you're not going to
get the result.
So bear in mind to have both of them and let's round the border using rounded, empty medium brown that.
I see no.
Everything is finished with the input path.
Let's position this.
I come to the center here.
It's very easy, we just need to add here after this absolute we just say top two to bring it a little
bit down.
Uh.
But yeah, it's not positioned to their.
Let's see.
There isn't.
It's not relative to this device because we made a silly mistake here.
Actually, I'm celebrating just a relative.
Yeah, that's fine.
Uh, now we need just at the left to just left to be completely in the center.
You can do it now could top 50 percent left and then you have to position a bit transform translate.
Minus 50 percent.
That is a lot of writing.
This is going to be very simple.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's it for the.
Our search for let's bring it a little bit down using here, marching top one to be completely in the
center.
Yeah, looks.
Now looks very fine.
Yeah.
In the next section, we're going to start creating the the right side, which have.
Two icons from Hero Icons.
There they have a very beautiful animation.
And also, we're going to add around that image.
On the right side.
So see in the next section for the actually, let's add.
Let's do that getup before forgetting all this, I forget.
So just quickly add everything to get with the commencement message of at.
Search.
For.
The header com.
Component.
And we just shifts can't get pushed to push everything to the guitar.
Let's go to our GitHub and see.
Yeah, we added a new commit.
Ten seconds ago, which is had a search bar to the head heather component.
Let's review what we have done.
Now we just in the.
We added something in the middle section, actually, because we removed the operative, we see the
change, but actually we change only this part.
And we just added a search icon.
It positioned it absolute in the upper tier.
And also, they added an input for installation.
We installed, you know, icons and children's spaces forms and in the tailwind that conflict that.
We added the Children's Services Forum plug in.
Yeah, that was it for the this section.
In the next section, we're going to finish the right part of our project.
So see in the next section.