All right.
In the last section, we have installed the next year and a tailwind assists, and we've got this template
here.
In this section, we're going to start adding our own components and make our website the template you
would like to have.
So we go back to Visual Studio code.
And we closed this global thesis now, for now, we don't need them, and we just go to the pages and
index such as this is the file that we we are seeing here inside the browser.
Let's decrease the size of the browser to see the changes simultaneous tenuously and B to the npm.
Rendezvous to have our server running and see the changes in real time.
For example, in this index, which is if I change this.
Uh, Qualcomm.
To learn is see the.
We see the changes.
In real time on the right side, so we we don't need anything except a hit section, hit sections,
just a title and the major tech and a link to the favicon that is here.
So we don't change them, but we delete all the main section and also the footer.
So all of them.
And we're not going to use if salt that contain a kind of this styling in our project, they're using
tailwinds to assist, so we delete the home that module that sees this fall completely.
And with the latest section.
As well.
And we it is to import section that we haven't used yet.
All right.
That's completely clean.
Let's get some closure to be sure that everything's working perfect.
You can see the hello here.
The reason we get this small size in each one is because we're choosing to see this and this stalling
is completely different.
All right.
So let's create our components.
And first we check the website.
We have already have the final version.
Now I'll show you.
That we have three sections in our projects first section is this one at the top.
Which we call it.
Then we have the nafaa, which is this section.
And finally, we have.
Uh, like, uh, this result section, which is here.
All right.
So we go back to index search.
Yes, and here instead of this low war.
We asked three sections, so let's define it first.
So we here we add a comment using contra forward slash and we just say header.
And then we have another one called NAV Bar.
And finally, we have the results section.
So for each of them, we're going to create a component react components, and we're going to just.
And export and one with saying like header that or end result, do you usually make the components inside
the components folder?
So we go to this package that Jason level and to create a folder called components.
And inside this components folder, we're going to create three, uh, three, uh, GSX files for header
four and the results.
So we just click their components and we click here to create a new file.
And first file will be Header Dot J.S..
And we just can't have a template using underline rf c.
And as you can see, we are getting a suggestion of react functional components.
So when we click on this, we get the export default function header and we return an empty diff.
And here we can add.
Each one.
Sane head, if you cannot see this hour of see, make sure to install the extension.
That we have here is seven React Redux Kraft EULAR, make sure to install this extension to get this
kind of, uh, like a quick installation templates without this extension, we don't get this suggestions.
All right.
We already created the component just exporting each saying header.
So we go back to our terminal and we go to index suggests and we import that header here.
So we just write header.
We close the tank and in order to import the header automatically at the top.
Let's increase the size so you can see everything.
So in order to import it, we just need to click on the at the end of this header and click on.
And we just press conference space when we click Contours Space.
We have the auto suggestion thing import header from components.
Slash it.
If you cannot see this one, make sure to.
To keep this head of the GSA open on the right side here.
So if if we don't have this one here, we don't get that.
Suggestion, as you can see.
So we keep this one open.
And here we click at the end and the press on counter space and we click on the first auto suggests.
Now in the browser that may increase the size, we wish we can see the header.
And let's create the same team for the Nafaa and the results section, so we click here.
Create a new file called.
Now for that.
Yes.
And inside this file, we just right underlined of.
We press enter to accept the author's suggestion, and we get a functional component.
And the added hitch one here saying that for so we go back to index searches and we import the nafaa,
we're just right now for a close attack and we're using contra space to alter import.
This is you can see here we imported Heather and Nafaa from components you have for and you can see
it in real time on the right side.
Next, we have the result.
So here we click the components and created the call results
that yes.
We create the component, uh, and using underlying RF see and here in the diff, right?
And each one.
Without saying just results and into index, it's.
You just write results and we use contra space to get the auto suggestion and the importance.
All right now we have all the sections we need, according to the final version of our project, which
is here.
In the next section, we are going to start with the.
Heather S. And before doing that, we just need to one more time.
Push our website to the guitar, so we stop the server.
We clear this.
Let me increase the size a little bit so you can see it better.
So now we just need to have it at all.
Then be committed with a message, the message will be.
Creates.
Components.
And just to create.
Uh, components and create and.
Finish.
The templates.
So we press into.
And we just finally, we have to just say, get push.
Now, everything is uploaded if we go to our repository.
GitHub repository.
I think it's.
Yeah, it's here.
Yeah, if you refresh the page now.
They see that we have three comments, if you click on this, we see that we have to create components
and finish our you made them stick in the finish.
That's fine.
Finish the template we click here.
And you see that we created the Hitler Jesus.
Now for that, yes.
Our result that, yes.
And inside the index that she has imported all the three sections.
And also we.
We just.
At the.
Tax here.
All right.
Yeah, that was it for the templating, our website and the start in the next section, we're going
to complete the.
Heather S..
Here are the top.
We're going to get this I am logo and also we're going to create this, get these icons from, you know,
icons dot com.
And we're going to like a a solemn bit using.
Taleban CSIS and at this kind of active and hover effect.
So see you in the next section.