All right.
In the last section, we have completed the sidebar section of our project.
In this section, we're going to create the feed component of our project.
If you look at the final version of the project, we can see that for responsiveness if you have a smaller
screen.
See these feet section is just this much away from the wall.
But in the bigger screen it's just in the center.
And when we go to the smaller screen in the mobile size, it covers all the screen.
In this section, we're going to create only the header part of the feeder and also we're going to create
this at borders as well.
So with that we have a diff here.
Which we can make a component for it.
And also we have.
Here.
The header at the top.
The header itself has two parts.
Just this home.
And also, we have an an icon which we can get from the hero icons as well.
The icon has a hover effect similar to the one we created for the items so we can use the same hover
effect for this icon.
So let's go to Visual Studio Call.
Let's increase the size and we go to index searches.
We don't need the sidebar anymore.
So we close it.
And here, just after the sidebar.
We create another component.
So we open the.
Explore section and inside the components folder we create another.
Component.
Andrew Collet, Ft.
Duchess.
We can use RF C to create a react functional component as we did before.
We do not need this import from React because we are using next year and let's import this component
inside index such as we just write feed and be it get this auto suggestion and be by clicking on this
auto suggestion we're going to automatically import feed from components folder.
Let's close this tag.
Now if you'll check the browser.
We can see their feet here.
The reason why it's just under.
The sidebar because this sidebar position is fixed.
If you remember.
Inside Politics.
We made the top layer dev here.
We made the position fixed.
So when you do fixed position.
This stiff goes.
Outside the original deer.
Which is the this death here, the main death.
And just goes on top of everything.
So in order to fix this, we can just for the feed, we add some.
Marching left.
So we push this.
This section, the feed section to to the right side.
So let's do this first.
So in the top div here we add a class name for adding the tables and spaces classes.
And for the.
It's large, which is the big size is.
We add a margin left of.
370 pixels.
Let's save this and see it in the browser.
Now, this part came here.
Let's add the border too, so we can see it much better because we only have a text here.
It's very hard to understand what we are doing.
So let's add a border to the left and right.
So we just say border.
Left.
And border, right?
And we sit there.
Men with to a certain position because we don't have any content.
So it's going to be shrink so and so in order to prevent this.
So we added in the x large.
We set the mean width to be.
For example, 576 pixels.
Actually, these numbers I find by trying an error.
So you can do it for yourself too.
So now we have a border in the left and the right.
So you can see this is a minimum 576 pixels.
And the.
But the problem is when you have a smaller screen.
You see that again?
It connects to the world so we can.
Another one, another.
Thanks.
Martin let me just say above the smallest green.
In Mobile, it's going we don't have we don't want any margin left, but after that, we want a margin
left of.
73 pixels.
Now if you check.
This is the field.
This is the right border.
This is the left border.
So this is correct.
But we still see that it's very small because we don't have anything there.
So we need to have a.
Some something.
But we can fix this one instead of doing mine with.
We can add the flex grow instead.
So we just say.
Flex grow.
Flex grow is going to push this fun to the end.
But because we don't have anything on the right side.
So this is covering everything.
Now we can add a max with it said the maximum with I want it to be x large which is equal to 576 pixels.
When we added the min, if you remember, we added the min with 507 six.
Now we added the max with us and this is the different way you can use both of them.
So we see that now we have this size in the big, big, big screen.
We have the same size as well.
And when we have a smaller than mobile size, it covers all of the.
All right.
That's it for the.
Positioning it.
Let's start with the header part.
So instead of feed, we're going to have a death.
And inside this, therefore, you're going to have extra time, which is saying, oh, let's bring this
form on the right side so we can see the sun on the left side.
Let's close this.
Okay.
So now after this H2 type B, we get another DIV and inside this step we're going to add that icon to
a sparkly icon so we can just write this spot.
Yes.
I can.
It's it only has one s actually.
So this is the suggestion we are going to import it from hero icons for slash react for slash afterlife.
So impressed that the death rate delayed this on and we should see it now it's huge because we are getting
the full size.
So let's set the height to be for example.
Five.
Now we can see it here.
So now here we can add a flex to bring them next to each other.
And also we can.
Luckily we at the.
Flag padding in the Y axis of two.
So I push them this way and you have a padding of three in the x axis.
And also we can, uh, we want to make it a sticky position is sticky helps us to keep this fun always
at the top because we don't have any contact.
We cannot show it here.
But in the final version, they can see it.
Just pay attention to the top section.
When I'm scrolling down, this section is always at a top.
So we need to make it position it as sticky.
So we.
Added this sticky position here.
Then we can add, uh.
We wanted to keep it at the top so we can't just change the top to zero.
And also, I want it to always be added at above others.
So we changed the Z index to 50.
And also we changed the background color to whites because as a default.
It's transparent.
The deaf and empty there is always transparent.
And also, we want to have a border at the bottom.
So you can see the bottom border and the border color should be gray.
And just 200.
Yeah.
That was it for this part.
Let's start this home.
So the home has a takes off large when we have a mobile screen.
And for the bigger sizes.
Let's make that text to be large and sorry, extra large.
Because we we already have large nets set the font to be pulled.
And uh, let's think, set the cursor to be pointer.
So when we hover over it, we see it pointing here.
So when we have a bigger screen, we should see it.
Bigger.
Because we set the text to be ex large after small.
And for this, a spotless icon.
I want it to be on the right side and has that hover effect that we had we created before.
So we added the hover effect now.
So now we should see a background color of gray, but this icon is still not in the center.
We can use Flexbox to bring it in the center.
So we just say flex and item center and.
As you know, that justified center.
So bring it exactly in the center.
And also I wanted to make it smaller.
The circle around Earth.
So we added we remove the padding ex.
They make it zero.
And the.
Let's set the marching left to alter, to bring it to the right side.
At this.
Set the width to be nine and height to be nine to.
So now it's a smaller.
And on the right side, there is an I added this padding zero.
If you don't have it.
In the larger screen, you see that that icon.
Gets very smart like this.
This is for the default margin.
So when you have this margin.
Sorry, pending default padding.
If you have a padding of zero, we always see it the same size.
The only thing we forgot is to put the border colour for the main feed as well.
So we just say border grey to hundred.
It's a little bit different, but you want to keep it consistent.
So the same color for here and here and the down section.
Yeah, that was it for this design.
Uh, in the next section, we're going to create the.
Inputs section of the feed component.
So let's first the.
And stop the server and add everything to get half.
So get add or adding it, get commit for a message.
And the message would be.
Create.
Ft.
Component.
And it's.
Heather.
All right.
We push it to get, huh?
Let's check it here.
He refresh the page?
Now we should hear another comment.
So we have four comments and the last one is create feed component and it's header.
So the only things we did is to create it.
If fit don't just component.
And we just created a div that is covering the header section that that has an edge to tag and also
an icon.
And also we added this component to the index purchase.
So in the next section where you're going to create this input fixture.
So see on the next section.