All right.
In the last section, we have completed the header section of our project.
In this section, we're going to work on the dark mode button.
So inside the.
We have to put this dark mode switch inside the header section.
So we go to we go back to Visual Studio Code, and here we go to.
This file, this header, that G6 and just next to this icon that we have created here, we're going
to add that switch.
But we're going to create another component for this switch.
So I'm going to call this component dark.
Mode switch.
I'm going to close this.
And we simply need to create this file.
So we go back to Explorer section using Contour Shift E and inside the components, I'm going to create
another component with the same name dark mode switch.
Dutch G6.
So I just use RFC to create a React functional component for now.
And I'm going to import this one in here.
So I can just click on the at the end of the name of the component use contra space and auto import
it.
Here.
So now let's start the server and see.
The dark mode switch here.
So let's go back to our website in localhost 3000.
Now let's refresh the page to see the changes.
So you can see the dark mode switch at the top.
We can just bring it next to that by working on this diff that is covering both of the dark mode switch
and the link.
So here we change the display to flex.
We changed.
Let's see.
Let's.
Let me show you in real time.
So I'll bring this one to the right side.
So I changed the flags.
So this is going to bring them next to each other like this, and then we can align them.
Using items.
Center.
And also we can edit space between them using a space x five.
Which is equal to.
Uh.
This CSS code, which is going to calculate the distance between them and just add the space between
them, not before or after.
So this is the good things about using the tailbacks.
As you can see, a lot of codes here.
Just you can use this space X instead.
So we just bring them next to each other.
Now perfectly.
So let's go work on this dark mode switch.
And before doing that, we need to install a package called next thing to be able to use the and change
the dark and light mode in our websites.
But actually, you can do that by just adding some variable inside your local storage and save your
current mode.
But the next thing package is going to do all these parts for us and we don't need to create these functions
or anything else.
And it uses the use context.
So it is going to create a global variable for us.
So anywhere inside our website, if you click on this.
Button, we can change the light mode of the website.
So I'm going to search on Google.
For.
Next.
Themes.
And there is a package.
AMPM just inside this website.
Let me zoom this so you can see it better.
So the website is just an MPLM package and the package name is next thing.
So we're going to click the in here.
For installation.
It's very simple.
We just need to have NPM install next team.
And for the usage, we need to cover all our website.
And with the team provider.
So we get a team provider and cover everything.
But the problem is because this team provider uses contacts, so we are not allowed to use contacts
in.
A server side component in next.
Yes, we need to use it in client side.
So if we just put this one inside the layout that JSX, so all the layout of JSX would be.
A client side instead of server side.
So what we do, we recreate an extra provider and put this one inside that provider.
I'm going to show you now how we do it.
So let's first install this.
So we just copy this code and we come back here, we stop the server, I'm going to paste it here to
install this one.
And what we do.
We go to layout the G6 and here we add our providers.
So we just create a provider.
And we just put the provider inside the body section.
So I'm going to create a provider.
Providers.
And I'm going to put everything inside the provider, so I'm going to cut.
All the things, including the children, and put it inside these providers.
And I'm going to create this provider.
We need to put this provider inside the app folder.
So I'm going to create this file providers that G6.
And we create a React functional component for now.
And we go back to layout the JSX.
And we import by using just count control space and click on the auto suggestion.
So now we have the providers.
And inside the providers.
We can create this provider client side without changing the layout or anything inside it.
So the next yes is so smart.
The next is 13 that even this provider is client side the header and the children would be still server
side.
So that's a good things about using next year's 30.
So we need to create this provider here.
So this is going to return that theme provider that I mentioned.
So we need to.
As you can see, we need to use this team provider from next teams.
And let me close this.
Let this one.
So this is going to cover everything inside our website, which is in layout.
We are covering header and children.
So in providers, the theme provider is going to cover all of them.
And this theme provider because is using the context, we cannot use it as a server side.
So if I start the server now and P and run there, we should get an error.
So let's see.
So now if I refresh the page.
We should get an error saying that we cannot use team provider inside a server side.
Component.
Let's see.
K.
Any time you start the server, you need to wait until the initial sell until the website loaded.
So.
Okay.
Let's see.
So until this one comes, let's add some other things inside the theme provider.
So I'm going to show you here inside the next steps.
So this team provider, it's going to cover everything inside our website.
And it has some a.
Default.
And default kind of coloring if you want to use.
And there is something else called use team from next teams that is going to change the theme of the
website.
So it actually this hook is going to give us the theme and the.
We can change it using this function setting.
So, for example, we have two buttons.
One is light and one is.
At dark.
So when we click on the light button, we're going to set the theme to light.
And when we click on Dark Mode, we set the theme to dark.
And the current theme is the one that we are getting here.
All right.
So let's see what happened to our website.
So probably some problem happened.
The other things we need to do for the providers and put it their theme is we need to pass the children
as well.
So we need to have the children here because we want to pass everything inside from the layout, digest
and put it inside the.
Team provider.
So inside the team provider, we're going to pass this children.
So let's save this one.
So now if you check the our our website, we can see that we get an error.
That is a type error.
Saying create context only works in client components at the use client directive at the top of the
file to use it.
So as I mentioned before, because they are using contacts, we cannot use them in, in the server side
component, it should be in client component.
So we need to add use client at the top.
So I'm going to copy this or I'm going to go here at the top.
We need to add this.
Use client.
So we just right here use client.
And this is going to solve the problem for us.
And if you go back now, you refresh the page, we shouldn't get this error.
Kit.
So now we don't get an error.
So everything is the same because we didn't do anything.
Actually, we actually covered all the website with providers and inside the providers covered everything
with the theme provider.
So they think actually we need to do is start from now.
So we go here.
The first thing we need to add as an attribute inside the team provider we need to enable.
The system.
We just say use the system and theme.
And we said it to be true.
So this is going to use the system's dark mode.
For example, if you're using light mode or dark mode inside your browser setting, this screen provider
can use that for.
And the other things we need to add is attribute.
Class.
So what is what that means is when we are using Tailwind CSS, we want to add to a class called Dark.
To add our dark mode for the dark.
So we need to add this attribute class here and we go, We can.
We need to go to the 12 in that conflict that is.
This file.
And here inside the sorry, after this team or anywhere outside of this one, we need to add the dark
mode.
Equal to class.
So in this way, if we add something.
Inside our website.
And added dark at the beginning.
We can just say use this class only for the dark mode.
So I'm going to show you now.
So first we add the necessary things.
So we need to add these two attributes, as I mentioned, enabled system and attributes.
Now.
We we can just add our.
Button to change the light and dark mode.
So we go to this, uh.
So let's see what this error.
Ah, we are getting an error because we have added something to the tailwind config, but we haven't
actually restart the server.
Anything you add inside the config file, you need to restart the server.
So I'm going to restart the server now.
Probably the errors should go away for now.
Let's refresh the page and see.
No, it's okay now.
We don't get any more any error.
So let's go to.
Our start mode switch and add our switch and other things so we can work on the the changing the thing.
So we need to actually button.
So if you go to react icons, I'm going to use two icons for our website.
One is the light.
We search for light.
And this the search for light mode.
So I want to use AMD light mode.
So I'm going to copy this one and bring it to this.
So let's add it at a top.
So I'm going to import it.
Import empty lite mode.
And this is going to come from react icons forward slash empty.
The next icon I want to add is this.
It's called.
Moon.
And we just search for moon.
And the name of that is BS.
Phil.
Let me find this.
Be is field, Moon Field.
This one.
So I'm going to copy this one, too.
I'm going to add it here.
And this is coming from React Icons for Bees.
So now we have two icons here.
Let's add them here.
So instead of dark mode, let's remove this diff.
And here.
We just add the icons.
For now, I want to show you the icons.
So the first icon is empty.
Light mode.
And the second one is peace.
Phil Mon.
Phil.
So if you now check our website, we should see two icons.
Here.
Let's refresh the page.
So we can see the two icons here, the light.
Let me zoom this.
You can see it better.
So it's light and the dark mode.
A button.
And the things we do, we get.
The theme.
The other things here I want to show you, because we want to use the use and estate and use effect
and also the use theme from next teams.
We cannot have this component as a server side.
We need to change this one to the client side as well.
For example, if I use any user state or let's actually bring that here, for example, import.
Use team.
If we import used steam from next steam.
And we just.
For example, get the use team.
We create a constant, we get the theme set theme from the US theme, and also we want to get the system
theme as well.
Okay.
So we should get an error here.
I want to show you the error so we get an error.
Lester.
As you can see, we get an error again saying contacts create contacts only works in client components,
so you cannot use any hooks inside the server side component.
So here we need to add the use client at the top.
So we convert this component to the.
And client side.
So now we change this one to the use client.
And we should get rid of this error for now.
As you can see, we don't get an error now.
So now we want to check the system thing first.
So we create a variable here.
We just say if the current thing.
So let me show you here how to do it.
Let me delete this one.
So we get the system team here.
And we want to create a constant.
We want to create a constant, and we call it current theme.
All right.
So this one is going to be as we get suggestion from the co-pilot.
This one, if the theme is equal to system.
We want to use the system theme.
Otherwise you want to use the theme that we are sitting by clicking on these icons.
So first we get the theme using the US team.
This is going to give us dark light or system.
If it system, it is going to use the system, the system which can be dark or light.
Otherwise, we use the theme that is set by us.
So now here we just say current theme.
If the current thing is equal to dark.
We want to just close this.
So this is going to be conditional.
If this is one is dark, we want to see this icon.
If it's light, we want to see the other icon.
Okay, so let's see.
We should see only one icon now.
So let's refresh the page.
We are getting an error.
Okay.
I probably put too many.
I have to remove this equal sign here.
So let's refresh the page.
We see that we get we should see the light actually the moon icon now, because the my.
System team is the light mode.
I usually use a light mode and.
So now we are just seeing this icon.
All right.
But we want to change the the theme now.
So if we click on this light mode icon.
We want to change the theme to light.
If we click on the other one, we want to change it to dark.
So we added on Click here and this and click is going to call and set that theme.
This team is coming from here.
They use team and we want to set the theme to light.
We want to use the same things for the moon icon we added on click.
And we want to set the theme.
To dock.
Great.
Now, if we.
Go here now.
It's a moon icon if you click on it.
It's going to be.
The other icon.
And also the theme of our website is Change to Dark.
If you click again, comes back to the light mode
and the other things we need to do, I want to install this icons first, so I'm going to add a style,
but I want to add this style for both of them the same style.
So I'm going to add the cursors to both of them using alt and click and just add some class name.
First thing first, I want to increase the size of the text to be x large the size of the icon.
I want to change the cursor to be pointer so we see a pointing hand when we hover over them and also
when we hover over them.
I want to change the color of the text to be amber 500.
So now the icons are bigger and when we hover over it, we see some.
Color change.
And the other things we need to do is the very important for when you are using dark or light mode.
Sometimes when you refresh the page, if the page is not mounted or didn't start, this font doesn't
work.
So for example, you change the page and then you click something quicker.
Sometimes it doesn't work and makes an error.
So the mounting means we want to complete this page to be rendered.
For example, if I this the dark mode when we refresh.
We see an error here.
You see that the UI does not match what was rendered on the server.
We get an hydration error.
This error is because the system is light mode and this is the dark mode.
When we refresh, it gets some conflict.
We say we want to use the system mode, but you already saved it like a dark.
But when we wait until the page completely loaded and then we change the light mode and dark mode,
we don't get an error because we already know.
The the mode of the website, especially when we are using next.
Yes, we have server side and client side.
In the client side we have, for example, light mode.
In the server side, we have dark mode and this is going to mismatch.
In order to prevent that, we need to first be sure that the page is mounted, It's loaded completely
and we we decide to be in the dark mode or light mode.
So I'm going to fix this one by just adding a user effect.
So here.
We can add a user fact.
Use.
The fact is going is come is coming from react and they use effect.
Is going to.
So sit.
The mounted.
To true when this one, you know, they use effect when the page load is weights completely page renders
one time and then set the mounted to true.
In this case we prevent using this.
Mode and other things.
So now we need to create this hook.
This piece of estate called mounted.
And first it's false.
And when the page is loaded, I think I added an extra.
So this one is for this one.
I think that's okay.
So when the page is completed rendered, we set the mounted to true, but first is false, and then
we're going to prevent using these things.
So I'm going to say, if the pages is mounted and it's true, then check the content team or other things.
So I'm going to put this one in a parenthesis.
Okay, Now this is going to check if the mountain is true, then then they're going to check the current
thing and put the light mode or dark mode.
So let's check it now.
So if we go here and we refresh the page.
So the error is used, state is not defined.
So we need to import user state from React.
So let's try again.
Okay.
Now it said seat mounted is not a function.
So let's.
Let's check what's what's the mistake?
So set, mounted.
Set.
Mounted.
You're getting this one here.
Now, it should be fine.
So let's refresh the page.
This maybe that's a previous error.
Said Martin is not a function that's a.
So we got the use of fact use state here.
We created this function set mounted.
We have mounted, set mounted.
And then we have used this set mounted here inside the use effect.
The problem is we have used the we should use the bracket here because we are creating a piece of state.
So let's bring this one.
When you're using user set, you need to use a bracket.
But when you are using, for example, we are getting the use theme, something we need to use a.
The curly braces.
All right, so now we shouldn't get an error here.
And as you can see, there is a delay.
Then we see the icon.
So when you refresh the page, we don't see the icon first and then the icons comes this time.
It's safe to use it because it's already this page is mounted, so now we can use it safely.
So even in the dark mode, when we refresh the page, we don't get an error.
Because there is no mismatch.
And we are they are the page is rendered and we can get the data.
All right.
So now we have created this button.
Let's add some styles to our main div.
What I want to do.
I want to just have a style like a.
Dark or I want to change the background color.
I don't want it to be completely dark.
I want to use a gray color.
And also I want to have some dark and mode using tail and CSS.
So inside the.
Providers.
Let's close the unnecessary things so we can see what we have done.
So inside the providers that GSA, we have added this team provider, but we just directly put it inside,
put the children inside this.
I'm going to add a diff here.
And this div is going to cover these children.
And I'm going to add the Estelle to this.
So I'm going to add a class name to here.
I just want to say if there is a dark mode.
I want the background color to be gray.
700.
If there is a dark mode, I want the text to be gray.
200.
And also in the light mode.
I want the text to be gray 700.
I.
And also I want to have a transition when a light mode and dark mode happens.
So I want to have a transition on colors with the duration of the 300 milliseconds.
And and also I want the mean height of the screen to be.
When you use mean etch a screen, it means the minimum size of the screen to be 100% of the viewport
height.
So now if we check our website, we see all the screen is kind of gray.
And in the light mode is light in this mode is gray.
And also we have some transition.
It doesn't come suddenly change.
And also I don't want people be able to select this text.
This is very annoying, especially in the mobile size.
If you want to click on some button, this is going to be very annoying.
So I want to use a select.
None.
So nobody can select the text.
So now you can select it.
But now after the save, you can select the text.
So this is the things we have added here.
So that was it for the adding the dark mode in our website.
So let's add this one to GitHub, but I didn't need to actually stop the server.
But you can use control shift G to open the source control and we click on this plus icon to add everything
to GitHub and we create a message for that one, which is.
At dark mode so we can click and commit and push and push it to get up.
So now if you go to GitHub and we come back.
And refresh the page.
We should see a new commit.
Ad dark mode.
So let's review what we have done.
It was a lot of work, So but it's very simple actually.
We have just a actually install a package called next teams, which is going to provide us with some
hooks and some theme providers.
And we have created a provider.
File, which is in client side.
Firstly, because we are using team provider which is using contacts like a hook.
And we have covered all our websites with team provider.
See.
So we put the children here and also we have added a div with adding the dark mode colors for all our
website.
And also we have added some transition.
So and also we have enabled systems.
So when the system is, for example, dark mode, the website is automatically be dark.
And we have added this one for the Taleban and CSS.
Inside the layer that gsx we have imported that provider, which is going to cover all our website,
including the header and the children.
And we have created a component called Dark Mode Switch, which is also in the client side because it's
using some hooks.
Like use steam and use state and also use effect.
So we have imported two icons from React, icons for the light mode and the dark mode, and we have
imported use team from next teams, which gives us system team.
And we can change the theme using set themes and get the system theme or our theme.
It depends on the hour choice, because if the theme is equal to system, we get the system theme.
Otherwise we get the theme that we have set.
And also we have used use of effect react hook.
To.
Apply and change the amount to true after the page is rendered.
To be sure that we don't have mismatch between the server side and the client side and we have added
a condition.
We just say if the mountain is true.
So when the page is rendered, then check the current theme.
If it's dark, show the light mode button, Otherwise show the moon icon.
So and then we have added an on click, which is going to change the theme by clicking on these icons.
We have also imported this dark switch mode component inside the header and we have added it.
Uh, next to the logo.
And inside the 12 Inconspicuous, we have added the dark mode, and we set it to be class.
All right.
So that was it for the dark mode section.
In the next section, we're going to create the about page for now.
When we click on the About, we get an error four or four error.
So let's refresh the page.
So I've stopped the server.
But I've shown you before, when we click on the about page, we get an error saying the page is not
existed.
So we're going to create this about page.
I'm going to show you how to put it under the app directory and how to create pages inside next.
JZ 30.
So see you in the next section for creating of the about page.