All right, in the last section, we have finished with the search bar in our project, in this section,
we're going to finish the right side of the head.
If you look at the final version of the project.
Let me increase the size, you can see it better, so we have actually.
And menu, including two icons from Hero Icons.
And also, we have an image rounded by Italian SS Starlee.
So totally, we have.
One big fear, which includes.
The menu and the.
The image.
All right.
Let's go back to Visual Studio code.
And in Heritage's.
In the right section, we just.
Delete the right side.
And we had a death here and inside this death.
We need to add the icons, so we need one icon onthe arts line, which is.
Uh.
Spur Plus.
Circle icon, and also we need an icon called home icon, but the icon is not so artfully.
It's solid.
So we just bring it from.
Hero icons react.
Forward slash solid.
So here we are at the.
Icons.
First, we add the home icon.
It's refresh the page.
We cannot see it yet, because it doesn't have any height or weight, so the height which is said to
be six.
You can see the icon here that's changed the cursor to be pointer.
So we can see a pointing hand when we hover over the icon.
Let's at the hover effect.
So when we hover over the element, we want to increase the size of the elements so we can do it a bit.
You need actually at double.
Claw and just add this skill here, and you just add 25 percent to this scale.
You can see here.
And.
We need a transition for this to be a little bit more smooth, so we add the transform fission to transform
property, which includes this scale function.
And let's do the duration of 100 or 200 million milli seconds.
So now we see a small things just to add is the fact.
So we went to remove the.
Mouse, we see is out for the effect.
All right.
Let's copy this and and the plus circular as well.
Plus soccer icon.
We can see they are on the top of each other, we can bring them next to each other by adding flex to
the top level dev.
And just after them, we can add an image tag.
To add a hardcoded image, so we just need to search for, for example, your own name.
My name is Sam Gambino.
So.
I just saw an image for myself.
This is from.
Just copy the.
Image address you can get, you can put any image you like, including your own image.
It's up to you.
So here in the source section, I paste the.
Paste it.
So we go back to our website, we can see the image.
But it's a little bit huge.
First, we add the alternative name, which is we just say user image, let's add some styling.
We just need to change the hunt to be 10.
And they change the way you make it circle by using rounded.
Full.
We can add some space between the icons and the image using.
In the top level, there is just add a space X.
For two, at a space between them, and we can bring them horizontally next to each other.
Using items center.
All right.
That's looks fine.
Let's add just a cursor pointer to the image.
So we see a point in hand when we hover over the image, and let's remove this.
Home Bar, when we have a smaller screen and added when we have a bigger screen so we can do, we can
achieve that easily by just adding at the beginning of the home icon hidden class.
And we just say if the size is bigger than medium size.
Just change the in line.
To Flex.
So when we have a bigger screen, we can see the icon, but in the smaller screen, we hide it.
The next things I want to do is just to add some space between the icons and the this profile icon and
the wall of the browser, we can achieve this easily by in the top there next to the return.
At the end, we're just at margin X of four.
And when we were in the ICC's largest space, like its large size like this, I want them to be centered.
So we just use the we just say in the large and above, just change the mix.
To be auto.
So now we can see everything center.
And let's increase the size and slowly you see that the icon appears after medium sized and in the largest.
Well, we see a change in the icon.
And when we get bigger in this size, we have.
Everything centers like this.
That was it for the part of the the right part of the header.
Let's.
Push this to the guitar using get at all and get command with a message of.
Uh, and the menu and profile image at the right.
Side of the head, and we just push it to get her.
You can check now here.
We just go to install version four and we have no.
Five comments.
And the last one is add the menu and and profile image at the right side of the header.
As you can see, the imported two icons, including plus soccer icon and home icon.
We make the header.
A centre using this auto mix, and also we added some marching to the left and right.
And, uh.
We just add the menu at the right side here, we can see.
Just the home and the plus icon and also the image.
All right.
So in the next section, we're going to make this.
Header a sticky or make it sticky to the top.
So when we when we scroll down there, the menu will be always at the top.
And also, we want to add some shadow effect at the bottom.
So see in the next section.