All right, in the last section, we have finished templating our project and we created all the components
necessary for a work like that header.
Now for and the results section in this section, we're going to start creating this header section.
If you check here.
We have.
To actually separate there with this size and this size one has to.
There I am, the local and the other side is the Nafaa, and each of them has separate component.
Like this one and this one and this one?
And finally, the fourth section, and we're going to bring these kind of, uh, logos from the, you
know, icons.
All right.
So.
Let's go back to our code section.
And let's decrease the size a little bit and clear the terminal.
And we go inside.
We just run the server thing and pan around.
If.
Now we just press enter.
And we opened our.
Browser here.
All right.
So.
So the things we are going to do now is just change this header section here.
This header at the top.
So we go to the head of the which is here.
And.
As I mentioned inside the final version, we have two separate parts.
And so we just need to add a diff here for the top level.
And also, we add the image here, we're going to use the image tag, which is specified for the next
year.
And we're just right here.
Image this is different from the I am tube attack.
It's optimized and it's completely created for the next two years applications.
That's why we're getting the error.
Firstly, we didn't import the image, so we just need to click on the end of the image and we just
press counter space and be imported from this auto suggestion, which is saying next slash image, we
see it on the top.
Now we get a different error.
Actually, the error is because we need this image tag has three mandatory attributes.
First is SRT, and then we have to add the width and height.
All right, so here we just ride SC and SLC will be the image we just go to Google and search for Ion.
And we got two images section.
I just want to get the first image, which is from the Wikipedia dot org web site, so we click here
and on the selected image, be right click.
And we click on copy image address.
And here in the starting at s to the double coat and inside the double coated paste, the link.
All right.
We close this school.
We don't need it, and we get another error saying that this your ill upload that Wikimedia.
Dorjee.
So it was risky.
Yeah.
So this one is not configured on their images in your next, that conflict that you use.
So in that conflict that yes, which is here on the left side?
Next, that conflict that yes, we need to add this up to that Wikimedia that authority you're.
So we copy this.
And here we add something like images.
And the openness to the curly braces and here at Domain's and inside.
And it's like an air raid as a raid, we just attack double code and inside the double copy paste the
link.
As we change it, config file, we need to restart the server, as we can see here, said restart the
server to see the changes in effect, so we stopped the server using Contra C.
And once again, we do the NPR on death.
As soon as we press enter, we can see the changes inside the browser.
Now we should get a different error.
Saying that we don't specify the width and height in the image.
So we close this next, that conflict that J.S. and it go to.
The index suggests, and inside there, this image tag it added with.
We just said it to be 100.
And height.
To be handled as well.
We should get the image now you can see here I am deep.
The next thing is just at the menu section, which is on the left side, so it should be upper.
And inside this stuff.
But as I mentioned, we need to create components for each of them.
So.
We just the.
Create a component inside a components folder and we call it header icon.
Duchess.
We had the template using underlying RF C and.
We just inside the Heather J is.
We add that an icon, so we just say header.
Icon and being auto imported.
We can see at the top.
And we're going to pass some.
Props here.
The first problem is just, say, Icon, and you're going to use hero icons to fill this part and also
we're going to pass title.
The title for the first one was home.
Which we can see inside the final version here.
So we're going to get this icon from the Hero Icons website.
So here inside the browser, we open a new tab and search for new icons.
And in the search results, we have, you know, outcomes that come.
As you can see, we have two types of icons the art line and the solid.
All right, so the solid one is filled with the color and the outline is just an empty icon, so we
go to documentation for the to, uh, to see how we can install the hero ikonso in the as we are using
react.
So next year is a framework that react.
So we just need to do an python install hero icons.
Forward slash reacts, so we copy this and.
Inside the terminal, we we can just open a new terminal, we don't close this one, so by clicking
on this icon, we make a new terminal and just be pasted here.
And for importing this icon, we just need to add import the icon name from that hero icons slash react
slash solid if you want to, to be solid, which is solid.
And if you want this outline, be read just right outside.
So we copy this and we go to hero icons such yes and the.
Uh.
Now we just in the heritage's we pasted at the top.
We don't want the baker care, I can't we just want to home our car, so we just sit home and, uh,
we can.
Just here, we get a home here.
All right.
So we're passing this to the heather icon, so we go to Heather.
I conduct yes, and we get that as a prop.
So we just get the props like this, but we're going to distract it.
First.
And we get the icon and also the title.
All right.
So here inside a return.
So probably everything will be fine.
Because we have already installed, so we close this terminal.
Fish, it's.
It says that the module not found, but we have already installed it, but probably we need to restart
the server to see the effect.
So we just say imperative again.
Let's see that we get the error or not.
All right.
We're not getting the error, and that's fine.
So inside the header icon, so we get the icon.
And also, as you can see, it's an icon is huge now, but that's fine if you're going to style it using
Kolben CIUSSS.
And for the title, we just right on title, you're getting it from here.
All right.
You get the title and the icon and you're going to start styling it using Telvin See assists, and let's
add more.
Uh, let's first decrease the size of this.
So for children, she says we just need to add some classes that it's already have some meaning and
tell us to assess how easily we can get it from the material.
So for example, for the heights, we just need to right edge and for the value we just cite, for example,
height five.
Let's reset the.
And it looks it looks a little bit small, we just changed it to eight and four meaning and we see what
does it mean to be each?
Dash eight.
So we just need to use control space.
To get the meaning so you can see here, it says that the Class H.
Dash eight means height to R M or thirty two pixels, so it means that we're sitting the high to be
thirty two pixels in order to get these explanations.
Make sure to have the extension called.
I think.
Let me.
It's still tailwind.
Yeah, this one, the Tillmans, USS IntelliSense.
Make sure to install this extension to get all this information and a suggestion inside the Visual Studio
code.
All right.
So we're getting the whole we need three more icons, as we can see in the final version of the project,
we are getting account content and about.
So we go back to the Visual Studio code.
Let's keep the browser open on the right side and you go to header that, Jeff and.
We just copy this.
Three more times using all Chief Arradondo and.
It just changed this home to.
Contacts.
It was yeah, it first is account, so this third one is contact this, the second one is count.
And the last one is about.
So let's get the icons as well, so we have home icons.
The second one is the user icon for the account.
Then we have contact, which is the phone icon.
And last one.
Is.
The information.
Information.
Sir Carl Icahn.
All right.
So now we just need to change this three to this one user icon for an icon here and inflammation circle
like it can see the change inside the browser right away.
And the next thing we need to do just style this section.
I think it's enough for this video in the next section, we're going to install this.
Heather S. Let's do the guitar.
So we just use contrasty to stop the server to clear it.
And we use get to add everything.
We use gets comments to add the message, which is.
Create.
The header component.
Component.
All right.
And finally, we do get push to push everything to get up.
And let's check it inside to get here.
They open it, see, it's better, they go to a movie Dash app, Dash VH.
And we see now we have four comments, so we clicked on this and we can see we have create the header
components so we could be open this one and see the changes.
So we created the header that year, and we added the hero icons at the top and also the.
Sorry to hit icons and the import hero icons, including home user phone and information circle.
And also we created the header icon separately and we passed the props.
Which is title and icon itself.
And finally, we have the image at the end, which is this it has a source to Wikimedia that -- and
the additive width and height.
And also inside a hidden icon.
We've got the props and we just made the icon.
And the title.
In next, a conflict that is the add the domain upload that Wikipedia that allows you to don't get the
error, that's the mandatory for the next year's website.
And that's it.
And we also in package that, Jason, we installed the hill icons.
Yeah, yeah, that was it for the creating the header section in the next section, we're going to style
this component.
So see in the next section.