All right.
In the last section, we have completed their section, we added the authentication.
Far from cool.
Well, we've got this image from the Google data.
So in this section, we're going to start with the with the forest section.
And if you look at the final version of the project.
We have a.
We have a form here.
Which includes three things a logo at the top.
We have a.
Kind of input with the two icons, the Magnifier, art icons and microphone.
And finally, we have a.
These two buttons, one here and one here.
So the these two buttons, they have the same kind of styling, so we just make one custom a style for
one of them and we apply it to the other one.
So and then the forum has some shadow effects.
And you can see when we focus also, we have a shadow effect and these portents, they have kind of
shadow factor.
So let's go to our visual studio code and the open, our local hosts three thousand on the right side
so we can see everything in real time.
Then we go to index that you use and we start with the body section.
As I mentioned, we have a forum that covers everything you don't need to add action photos for.
And inside this forum, we have an image input and also some buttons.
So let's first we get the image.
The image is similar to the image we got.
Here in the logging place, if you go to the logging page, this image, they're using the same URL,
but here I'm going to introduce you to the image tag from next year, which is a gives us the ability
to have a responsive image optimized and also kind of a lazy loading as far.
So we had that image tag.
This is just a self-closing, and we need to imported from next forest slash image.
So we imported image from Nick's first four slash image, and the image has some.
Let's go to the homepage.
When we add the image to it gives us two error.
The first one is telling us that the SRT attribute or actually property is required.
So here.
We need to add this FRC, which, as I mentioned before, it's the same URL as we used in the signing
piece, so we go to this signing that, yes, and we can.
Copy the URL.
And the pace that here.
So after adding this, we're going to get another error.
So this is fresh this.
We get another error saying that the.
This URL is not configured.
I'm sorry in this one.
First, the error is the width and height is mandatory.
So we just give a width and height here.
So we just sit with.
And I think it 300 is enough.
And the heights would be.
One hundred.
Now we get another error, so we just say this, your EL is not configured in Nick's de-conflict.
Yes.
Which is this you are we copy this earlier.
Simply, we copy it.
And we go to next start conflict conflicts, yes, this fire year.
And just under the restricted and React Restrict mode, we add something else, we just add images.
And inside these images, we had the domains.
Two domains is equal to like an array and the first your L, the end is this one.
All right, so refresh the page.
Now, because if you change the conflict file, we need to restart this server, so we stop the server
and we run it again, using and run dev.
And now, if you refresh the page, we should see that image without any error.
Yeah, we got the image.
So after the image, we need to add the input as we want some and to add some icons inside the input.
Let's add some div here and inside that to be at the icons and the input as well.
So here we need two icons.
The first icon is search icon and the second one is microphone icon.
I'm going to use a website called Hero Icons.
Hero icons is actually created by children, yes, so it's completely compatible with children's cases
and.
Actually, let's search for the hero icons.
This website, they're in the search result, we see that hero icons dot com beautiful handcrafted SPG
icons by the makers of the tailored access.
So we click on this, as you can see, there are two types of icons the first one is offline.
And the second one is solid and the difference is just filled.
So these are filled here and we call them solid.
Let's go to documentation.
And in the documentation, we need to run this line of code to install, you know, our costs, so we
copy this.
You go back to Visual Studio code, we can stop the server or we can create another terminal.
Well, let's start the server.
Just the quick installation.
So that's it, I think.
We we just need now to import the package, the icons, if you want.
So we start the server again using npm run dev.
And here.
At a top are import icons.
Both of the icons are from solid.
So we just right down here in port.
Search.
Icon.
And also, the next one is microphone icon, so we just have micro phone.
All right.
And both of them are coming from.
Here are costs.
Yeah.
You know, I cast forward slash reacts, you can't see this suggestion.
Now we can use the icons in our.
Project let's.
Bring back our.
Website to the right side, so you can see the changes.
OK.
So after.
Inside a stiff.
We add the search icon, justice search icon.
We should see a search icon now.
This man finished a page.
Yeah.
We didn't specify the solid or outline, so after this here, I can't react.
We just need to write down solid or outline as I want to use the solids, so I just write down solid.
So that is the error we're getting.
So I think this is fine.
Just refresh the page.
Yeah, now we got the icon here, which is huge.
But that is fine.
We're going to style it soon.
Well, let's at just some heights to make it smaller.
The height you just said it to be a fire.
That would be OK.
So we're going to style it later.
So let's finish our form.
We added input, but a type of text.
Inputs with the type of text, so just uh.
Yeah.
And then the input is going to have.
It's just the you cannot see the impact, how it's here and see.
So we have the input.
That's fine.
So we don't need any placeholders.
We want to make it exactly like the Google wants.
So the Google one doesn't have any placeholder.
So let's add the next icon, which is the microphone icon.
And let's add some height to the height for the microphone is five as well.
So we have all of them, these things like we have to search our car, we have input now we have also
the microphone.
Next is the icon buttons inside the phone.
We have two buttons, the first one.
It's just saying Google search.
All right.
And let's copy this, and the second one is just saying I'm feeling lucky.
All right, we have two buttons here.
As I mentioned before, we were going to style these buttons exactly the same so we we can use the layered
components of the to to do it.
All right.
Let's start styling our body section.
We just the ad flex display flex to the forum at the top, so we had a class name.
We want to bring them to the center so we can use the Flex first.
Flex brings them next to each other, but if we change the flex direction to column there, there will
be on the top of each other.
And after that, we can bring them to the center.
We're just using items.
Center.
And I want to push them a little bit down.
So it gets a little bit more beautiful.
So we just add a margin top of 40.
You can do it in other ways, too, like you add a body height of 100 percent.
I just use Justified Content Center.
But this is just for simplicity.
I'm using this margin top 40.
That is fine for one page.
If you have only one page application.
So and now let's go start with, uh uh, we just add here to the image object.
Fit cover, because I want to prevent this just stretching off the image, so object fig cover.
Maybe you don't see any changes, but a subtle movement you saw in the image.
So that is going to.
Prevent the stretching.
All right, so next, we have this inputs.
We want to bring them next to each other.
So we start with the let's first some styling for this icon.
Let's let me zoom out a little bit so you can see the changes.
So for the search icon, we have a we just want to add something like a tex gray.
It's just a tax.
Gray.
Five hundred.
So it's not going to be a complete black.
Yeah.
Text Gray.
Five hundred.
So this color.
Then we want to some marching to the right.
Off because we don't want to completely connect them to the next one and maybe be added later so we
can see the results, so first we at the diff here we make them flex to, they come next to each other.
All right.
And after that, we just changed the width to be full.
That they're so it's a full size now.
I can't see they went to the left, so let's bring them to the center.
Uh, just uh.
Let's add some space to between the logo and the input by adding marching top of five.
And then we.
We bring them to the center using Amex Auto, mismanaging its auto.
So do you see the change here and decrease the size?
It didn't apply yet, because.
Let's add some.
And Max, with we added Max with.
Of just just in 90 percent.
So we don't want to this input connects to the wall, so we added the 90 percent, so it's not going
to be more than 90 percent, but still it's not in the center, so.
Let me continue so we can see the results more so the next thing we need to add is just the we want
to add some border.
All right, so we add some border to just a border.
Now you can see the actually the diff, actually the div is in the center and it's full size.
But the inside is in the left.
So if you're going to fix it soon, so the border.
Is grey colour in is in grey colour, and it's just that two hundred.
It's very subtle, and that's see it, but that's fine.
And we want the size of this input to be like a flex grow.
You know, the Flex Grow is like we want the size of this input to go to the right and push this icon
to the right side.
So let's add this to the inputs.
So we just a class name.
And the input.
Oh.
It's going to be flex grow as soon as we do this one, you see that no, the input is covering everything.
And push everything other icons to the right and left.
And the other thing is, you want to do in the input section is when we focus, when we click, I don't
want this.
And black a black line.
Instead of this, we want to add the shadow in the diff outside, so we remove this fund using, we
just say when we focus.
So we just like focus when we focus.
We don't want the outliers, so we just aren't lying.
No.
So we don't get that on.
So it looks a little bit better now.
So let's continue with this debate at a top.
So the other thing is, when we hover over it, we want to have this shadow shadow of large.
So now when we hover, we see the shadow also when we focus.
I want to have this shadow as well, so.
Uh.
We can achieve this easily by just staying focus within mainly focus within when we focus inside this
there.
We want to after this window, someone focus on within it.
We want the shadow to be largest for.
Same thing.
So now when we hover, you get --, shadow.
If we click.
Which is focused within which includes the input we have the shadows.
All right.
Let's add some margin or the.
Padding.
Let's add some padding to push everything inside.
So we add some padding of fire, so in the x axis, we push them to the inside.
And for the y axis, we just add three so that it looks much better.
Let's add some rounded corner.
We just say rounded.
Fool.
So we have the full rounded.
It's like a circle in this side, so you have all the fooled around it in all directions.
All right.
So this one looks.
Nice now.
And the other thing is just the.
We add we added everything.
Let's bring everything to the center.
And using item center.
We just want these icons to be in the center.
And when no, it's in the moment it's going, but when it's bigger, I don't want in the input to be
that much big.
All right.
So after the mobile size?
After the small size?
We want the Max with to be.
Let's say it's large.
So when we passed the mobile five.
We get this maximum size.
All right.
This is a maximum size.
But when the screen is large?
All right, Bindi, skiing is more than large, so we want the Max with.
To be even bigger, like two weeks lost.
So just pay attention to the size.
No, it's this is a small screen.
So we have the X large.
As soon as we go to the large, we get the bigger size here.
This points.
All right.
I think that's it for the input section.
That is fine.
Remember, I said I want to add the margin right later, so you see that this at this point is very
close to the icon.
It means so much a little bit.
At some margin right to the icon.
So we push this cursor to the right.
So let's.
We should change the search icon here.
The Aston Martin writes, let's say not too much, just that breathes fire.
Now we we have some space between.
All right.
So everything's fine for the input section.
Let's create a style icons.
These buttons, Google Search, and I'm feeling lucky.
So as I mentioned, we want to at the same.
Missiles, so we add a class name here for both of them.
He had a class name and name it, Peter.
All right.
And inside the colobus ceased globals.
That's yes, we add another layer component and we call it Peter.
Now let's stall here, and then we see the result on the right side.
So here we need to apply, as we did on the top.
The background color, we can add a custom background color is similar to the Google, which is if eight.
If known, if a.
So this is kind of gray, but it's different from the we cannot achieve this on using the gray colors.
So we can add a custom color like this and then we add some padding of three.
We make the buttons around it, but the medium size.
Let me zoom there so you can see the curve.
All right, so next week, Max, the a small.
And the.
Changed the color of the text to Gray.
Eight hundred.
And when we hover over them, I want to have some boring, you know, similar to what we see in the
real world side.
So when we hover over them, I want to have a ring.
For one pixel.
So you can see the link, but the ring is blue.
I don't want it to be Blue Origin.
The real website has a ring of gray, actually, so we can easily change its approach to hover ring
and we change the color to gray.
Two hundred.
Next, we have when we click on them.
We see they don't have any change.
But when we click, uh.
So, yeah, no.
First, remove the outline.
First, we remove the outline, we just see a focus
outline.
None.
But we want to add our own outline.
So, uh, when we when it is active.
So this one should be this when it is active, it means someone's click on it.
I want the ring to be gray, but a little bit darker, sort of like a.
Three hundred.
It's refresh is still getting an error.
Ring Ring.
Grain.
Outline known focus.
Our line is strong.
Now, when we click, we see a little bit different change inside the No.
You see the ring is a subtle gray.
When we click, it's a little bit darker.
And when we hover over them, I want to ask some shadow.
So let me show this a little bit.
So however, we want to add some shadow.
Of medium empty.
So now you see the shadow on the right.
All right.
So everything is fine now.
We just need to bring them next to each other when we have a big screen.
And also, we have some space between in order to do that.
It's very simple, we can put the buttons inside a beer.
So we created the we bring the both buttons inside the.
And here we add a Flexbox.
All right.
So they come next to each other, but Wendy, this screen is small.
I want them to be actually on top of each other.
So we just take Flex column.
But when the screen is bigger than a small, I want them to be next to each other.
So when it's a small.
You can easily change the flex direction to like a column in its column you can change direction to.
Tomorrow.
So now, when we have a bigger size, they come next to each other and then we add some width of.
For example, one one, one a half like a one.
One half, or we can just say 50 percent doesn't matter.
Correct.
See the the bigger.
And then we add some space.
In the y direction y axis of two.
So we have some space between them and then we add a margin top of this to add some space between them
and the input section.
And when we are bigger than a small size.
I mean, to the window and next to each other.
So we don't want to have this piece by, so we just see a space fly off zero.
So they are completely next to each other.
But when the uh, it's a small we want, they have a space between and it's expense.
They have a space in x axis and it's going to be for.
But still, they are not center.
All right, we can easily fix that one using justify center.
So just to justify center.
All right.
It looks very nice and neat.
So that was it for the body section.
Let's add this one to the guitar.
So was just kid kids and kids come in.
And the message would be.
To create body search.
And they push it to get tough.
So let's check our GitHub and we review our code.
This section, I want to mention that this section is completely optional.
If you are completely understand the code, you can just skip this one and go to the next section.
But just for people who want to have some preview on the code, I briefly explain it.
So now we have five commands.
And the last one is create body fiction.
Let's click on it.
We can see that in the next conflict that, yes, we added the domain because we got the error for the
image tag up the next next, next next year.
Yes.
So.
And then we added a package called Hero Icons for our icons.
We've got the icon inside the index, such as search icon and a microphone icon.
In the body section, we added a forum and inside the forum we added an image, which is the Google
Image, and we just add some with high on object fit.
After that, we added a diff, which includes our input, the input includes a search icon, microphone
icon and also the input itself.
We style it through using Tillmans to assess.
And finally, we added two buttons.
Well, Google search, and I'm feeling lucky.
So, uh, and also we use a custom, uh, CIUSSS or Terrence's as a styling, we call, we call it,
uh, Beaton and we sell it here.
Yeah, that was it for the body section.
It just this is just, uh, the shape of the body, the functionality.
It starts with the next section.
In fact, uh, if you look at the final version, uh, this is the final version actually to our website,
this next in the next section.
First, we complete our new page, the UI of our page.
We add the this uh, footer, and after that we're going to start the functionality like getting the
input and pass it to the Google API, get the information on and et cetera.
So in the next section, we're going to do this dynamic footer.
So I'm going to teach you how to.
Just keep the water always at the bottom of your pitch, so see you in the next section for the future
part.