All right.
In the last section, we have completed that audio section, in this section, we're going to complete
the footer.
Yeah, if you look at the final version of the project, they have just the text here.
Copyright copyright sign.
This is the No.
This is the year, but it's this is dynamic.
For example, someone comes next year is going to see 2023 instead of 2022.
And this is just minor.
That's fine.
So we go back to index that year.
Yes.
And a button for the future, let's create a component inside a components folder, we just call it
future touch.
Yes.
And we use our C to create a react functional component.
And.
Let's change this thing to footer.
And inside the photo, we add a paragraph just saying first.
Copyright.
And then for the copy sign, you just need to add impasse send.
Copy and semicolon.
So let's add this photo component inside the.
Index that you use, and we import it here.
Just say food can be imported using counter space, we get the author suggestion we imported at the
top.
So we should see it now in our page.
Yeah, you can see it here.
Copyright the copy.
A simple symbol.
And after that, we're going to have a dynamic here.
We can just say 2020 to next year.
We need to update our page.
So instead of doing that, I'm going to teach you how to do it.
Dynamic these two women add a bracket to add JavaScript here.
Or J6 and we just a new date.
All right.
It's a function, there's a building function for JavaScript date, and then we just get the full year
to get.
Full year.
This is a method to.
So now we are getting the 2020 two, but this is completely dynamic.
This is a big year change and we don't need to update our website.
And after that, we just can't see Google or just add my name and I will give it.
So let's bring this copyright just to the bottom and stick it to there.
So how we can do it.
It's pretty simple.
We need to change to the position to be absolute.
For the future, so here at the top, we're just a class name, absolute.
Absolutes.
And we changed the bottom to be zero.
This is going to push us to the bottom of the page.
So let's bring it to the center by just saying left.
50 percent.
This is actually bring the age of to this paragraph to this center here in the center, in order to
bring this center really into center, you can use Translate Transform X minus 50 percent as we do inside
the CFS.
But until this year, we just need to say translate.
Higgs.
Minus 50 percent.
But inside the brackets.
As you can see, it came exactly in the center now.
And.
If you Zoom, you see that they come in into two lines.
We can prevent this using white airspace.
No rap, so we can just see why this space, no rap for preventing this and we can add some padding
to.
Push it a little bit upper, let's remove this resume the chickens and all five, that's fine, and
let's decrease the size of the text to small.
And let's change the color to be gray.
So let's just say Tex Gray, and we said it to, for example, of six hundred.
That's that's for it, that's it for the.
Uh, food restriction, actually, this is not similar to the future of the Google Real clone, but
it was just a waste of time to make our website exactly like Google Twitter because just, uh, if you
check the website itself, the search team works not.
Is see that the future is just the sum terms of service, privacy and something like that.
So for simplicity, I just kept our website like this.
But we're going to work mostly on the functionality and search and also the the routing or something
like that that is more important for next year and learning Telmex CCIs and next year.
So in the next section, we are going to get the term from the input here.
For example, whatever we write here, we want to get this information and we redirect the page to the
related page.
So we just say, for example, localhost 20.
Let's show inside the final version, for example, here, if we search something like, Hello,
this is going to redirect us to.
Forward slash search that term is Helo, and the search type is empty, which is the web page and inside
if you click on the image.
The Search tab is image, so in the next section, we're going to change this URL here, so we redirect
our page to these pages.
So before doing that, let's add this photo to the get help as well and review our code.
So we just said get at and we get comments.
And I would just say.
Curious.
Router components.
Components.
All right.
And then we push it to get.
If you look at our getup and refresh the page, now we have six commits and the last one is here is
saying now we click on it.
We just created a component called Photodex.
And it has only a paragraph.
And we use the date constructor to create to get the full year dynamically.
And we just use absolute button zero to stick and stick the footer always at the bottom of the page.
And we added the components inside the index, that genius, so in the next section, as I mentioned,
we're going to get the data from the input and every right we redirect to page.
To the related page.
So see you in the next section for this.