All right, in the last section, we have completed the Heather section.
And the added the menu and profile image in this section, we're going to make this header a stick to
the top of the page and also we want to add some shadow effects.
If you if you look at the final version of the project, you can see that the header is at the top all
the time.
And also, if you zoom a little bit, you can see that we have a shadow between the header and other
sections of the website.
So it's very simple and we can do it in a short video.
We just need to go to header chase and we wrap everything inside one diff.
So we I bring everything inside the header that yes.
Inside and empty there and here, we just add a shadow first.
And we just say shadow eSIM, which means a very small shadow.
Now we can see it.
It's not clear yet because they're both colors are similar.
Later, we're going to change the color of the.
The main feed section, a little bit gray.
And which we can see that is different here in the final version.
All right.
And the other things we need to do to be sticky.
Is to at.
Let's add just a border at the bottom.
So we can see it better.
So you see a difference now.
The border be.
And.
And see the difference.
And also make it a sticky to the top by just adding a sticky.
And we need to just say top zero.
So let's add something inside our index that, yes, so we can see the sticky part.
Let's add just a paragraph with your lorem ipsum, just hundred learn if song and we copy this a few
times, so now we can see the effects.
It's sticky at the top, but we can see that it's transparent and the text goes inside the header.
The easiest solution is just to add a background.
We add a background color of white.
And just to be sure that the header is always at the top, if we have more things like a model or other
things, we just change the Z Index to 30.
The normal Z index is zero for everything, but when you put it higher than zero, it means you're at
the top level.
All right.
Looks fine now, let's delete the dummy text, we added.
So, OK, and let's add this one to the guitar, and we can move to the next section, so we just add
everything to the kit.
We make a comment.
Of.
Just saying implement.
It's sticky.
Header.
And we just push it to the get tough.
Let's check that we will refresh this page.
And now we have six comments, and the last one is implement sticky header.
And we just add another div at the top that is covering everything.
All right.
So these changes are just the first when we see some automatic changes happens, but it just is.
This is the change we have done in the next section.
We are going to start with the food section.
And uh, so the food section.
This is the food section, and the food section has actually four parts, so the first one is the.
Story, the story part, then we have the post part.
Many profile.
And also, we have this suggestions, so in the next section, we're going to start with the story part.
We're going to use a package called Mini Faker to produce these fakes.
Uh.
Profiles and we can use another website for producing profile images.
So see you in the next section for the feed section and also this story part.