Well, right in the last section, we have finished with the header section.
We got these icons from hero icons dot com and we've got this logo from the Google.
In the news, in this section, we are going to start styling this Heather section using Telvin CSIS.
So we go to our code visual studio code.
And inside the.
Let's bring this to the right side.
So we can see the changes and we start with the styling and bring this everything to the center and
also change the background color as well.
If you check the final version, we see that the background color is dark gray and it colors are white,
are gray.
But when we hover over them, we see a.
If we see a white collar and also if we click on the buttons, we see a red colour.
And also if you click on the logo, we see that the logo gets brighter.
So we go back to.
Heterogeneous and inside this is the divide that contains everything, all the headers.
So we change the background color in this section.
So we just add a class name and the class.
The the classes we want to add first is the background color.
So if we just write peachy gray for the gray color.
And we said it to be, if free press conserve space, you can see the suggestions, a different number
of colors and different colors.
If you installed the tailwinds to assist IntelliSense, so we start from the 50, which is the brightest
color and two, 700 or 900, which is completely black.
Two 700.
And let's start the server to see this change.
So we're just two a.m. around death.
OK, now see that the background color has been changed to dark gray.
Let's change the text.
Using just just a text, and we just say the color would be gray, but two hundred instead of seven
hundred.
All right.
And let's.
Change the display to Flex, to bring to bring them to the center using justified content and item center.
As you may know, in Telvin cases, we start with the mobile size.
So no, actually these are for mobile size and for the bigger sizes we have to specify.
The classis by and for a small, we have medium large x large, and also we have.
Two weeks last.
Now we want to flex, but we want the items at this iPhone to be at the bottom like the final version.
If we check the final version, when we decrease the size, we see that the logo goes under these buttons.
You see here the trigger point.
So the in the mobile science.
We have this forum, so in our code, we change the Flex to column.
And we sit here and let's bring everything to the center using.
Items.
Santa.
You see and.
And let's bring these icons next to each other, but the container that covers these things is.
This class here, it's covering all the icons.
So here we change the display to Flex.
And.
That's that's it.
And for that, I don't want them to be very close to each other.
So in the header icons.
Here.
We are going to change that with or add some margin, so.
We just and the margin fix for.
And in order to bring them back exactly in the center, we changed the display to Flex and we change
the flex direction to.
Column.
No, you can't see everything is centered.
Let's add some padding to the parent in the head of that, yes.
So at the top, it just adds some padding, like padding six, which is 24 pixels, so it pushed everything
in the middle.
And now.
And also, let's go to this Heather Icon.
And for the title, I want the title to be a little bit.
And have a space between the title and icon, so we change the class name here and we sit to March.
Why?
Or marching into horizontal.
To.
Which is marching to it means eight pixels.
All right.
The things I want to do is just, I don't want this.
We can select the.
The characters, because this is going to be very annoying when your.
Watching a Web site inside the mobile, because when you clicking on a button, it's going to select
the.
The characters, and it's very annoying, so usually Web developers remove the cynic selecting ability.
For the mobile size or for menus, something like that, that's this that's not necessary to copy.
So.
And the heritage is in the top level.
I mean, the div that covers everything, we just add something called.
Select no.
So it removes the ability to select the items, no, it cannot select them.
So it's going to be very convenient when you're watching a website in the mobile version.
Next, I want to add some clicking and things like changing, hovering effects and active effects.
So.
In each icon, header icon.
We're going to ask something called harbor effect, so we just say hover through the glass.
So when we hover over this icon, I want to change the ticks instead of gray to be white.
So you can see now by hovering.
Let me increase the size now, if you hover over the I can see see this change.
All right, so and then let's change the cursor to be pointer, so when we hover over the elements,
we can see a pointing hand.
Well.
And.
No, the.
The margin is four, but when we, uh, the website is.
Bigger in a bigger size, I want that's a little bit they have more space between them, so I say just
when the size is.
Bigger and over large, I want the.
They width to be six instead of four or margin, X to be six.
So when no, we increase the size of the.
Is she the trigger point here?
Bigger than large, we have more space between the icons.
All right, so the next thing I want to do would be increasing the size after the small size.
I want these icons to be at the left and the logo to be on the right.
So we need to change the flex direction of the header that chase.
From column to row when we are increasing this size.
So here we say, if we have this size bigger than the small.
We want to flex.
To be real instead of column.
Me tested for you.
See the change after this small.
This is the trigger point, so for the tablet and the bigger screens, we have been next next to each
other, but less change to justify to be.
Between.
This is similar to justify content between so you can see that this is like justified content, a space
between.
So when we are increasing the size more than the small, we see that the icons scores to the left and
the logo goes to the right.
All right.
The next thing I see on that is the active effect when we click on the icon, I want the color to be
red.
So in the header icon that James?
If you remember, we had the hover effect, takes flight after that.
We add the active.
They say when the active or in someone, click on the icon, change the text color to be read.
And just four hundred like this color.
So now when we click, it should see.
They're color changing.
The next thing is, I want to change when we click on this icon, IMDB icon, I want to change the brightness
of the logo, so indicator that yes, we go to the images, you go to the image tag.
And here we are.
Lastly, the class name and we just first we change the cursor to be pointer.
And so now we see a pointing hand when we hover over it and then.
If we someone click on the icon, it means the active shooter class, I want to change the brightness.
Two hundred and ten.
Here you can see you see no, the Tillmans, this is very easy to.
Use everything is similar to CSIS, but we don't need to go to CSIS all the time to change everything
and make different classes.
And it's very simple to use, but you just need to practice more to remember all the syntax.
So, no.
If we click on the icon.
We see that changing in the color.
All right.
But that was it for the now, for sick, for the Heather section, we have finished it.
It's responsive and also we have this, however, an active effect in the next section.
We're going to start with the Nafaa section and we're going to create it's like.
This section, the trending and top rated that we have in the final version.
So before, uh, finishing the video, let's do the.
Get half fiction.
So we just add everything to the repository and commit.
With the message of finish.
Or we just say hostile to Heather.
S..
And we push it.
Did it gets hot?
Now, let's go and check.
You're fresh, and we clicked on this movie app version eight.
Now we have five comments.
If you click on them, you see that the last comment is a solid header section and.
The things we did in the header.
That, yes, we add some class names for styling.
And also in the heroes I conduct is we just changed the class name and something we didn't do too much.
It was just a stylish and.
Just I want to, uh, to, uh, mention that using GitHub is necessary for all web developers, in my
opinion.
It has two good things.
First is just you can see what change you have done to your code.
And also, if someone comes to your GitHub page and if you want to hire somewhere, that's the best
place to show.
You're a lucky lucky your supervisor or person will interview you said that you are really working on
your projects every day.
Yeah, that's my recommendation.
And also, when we want to deploy the website to the Web, so we need to get help to connect our application
to a.
All right.
That was it for the styling part in the next section, we start with the.
Now for our section, so see in the next section.