All right.
In the last section, we have completed the post section of our project.
In this section, we're going to start creating the widgets of the project.
If you look at the final version of the project, you can see we have a search bar at the top and when
we scroll down, the search bar is always added to.
So it's, uh.
Let me show you here.
By trying.
So we have a div here at the top.
Actually we have a diff that is called, uh, that is for the wages component and then we have a diff
here at the top that is, is sticky to the top.
Then we have another div that is covering both of the input and also the magnifier icon.
Well search icon.
So we're going to make the position of the input absolute in relative to this dev their red dev and
add a margin left to it.
So we bring it a little bit right and we set this as search icon in the left side.
So let's go back to Visual Studio code and we create our widgets component.
So here in the components folder, we create a new file and we call it widgets.
Don't just.
We can use our MFC to create a reactive functional component.
We don't need this import.
React from react as we're using.
Next year.
Then inside index that is just after the feed component.
We add the widgets.
And we we can import it using contrast base and click on the first auto suggestion.
Let's close the tank.
And let's test it here.
Now, if you refresh the page in the localhost 3000, we see that on the top.
We have widgets which is coming from.
This takes.
So.
Here.
As I mentioned before, we have a div that is covering all the fittings and we have a div that we're
going to use for making the.
Search bar is sticky and another div that is having both of the magnifier icon and also the input.
So let's bring the magnify icon or in hero icons.
It's called search icon.
So here you can get this suggestion.
Search icon from here, icons for slash react post slash outline.
We cannot see it.
I think the size is, uh, very big.
Let me.
Bring this phone here so you can see everything in real time.
So we change the size to be five, so now we can see it at top.
Let's add the input here as well, which just said input.
And, uh.
The tie is text.
That's fine.
And we have a place holder.
Of search.
Twitter.
You can see now.
So as I, we use a plugin before for this input, this plugin is applied to this one as well.
If you remember, we installed a plugin called Tailwind Success Forms.
So it has the basic styling now.
Let's continue a style and more where we can and let's.
Yeah.
Mick, let's bring these two next to each other first by just using flags.
Display flags here.
And we can just use our time center to bring them center and very clear.
Like this.
Then.
Let's add some padding of three.
So push them a little bit inside and let's make it rounded.
Full.
So you cannot see it yet.
But if you add a background color of, for example, red.
300.
You can see the.
Their color.
And the.
Now I want this input to be exactly the same size of this, Dave, but.
We can just only do this if we do their make this input and make the position of this input absolute
in relative to this death.
So we the added relative.
To the dev and here.
For this import, we add a position of absolute.
Now you can see that it exactly went there.
But.
I still have left zero or rather zero.
We can remove that one using instead zero instead.
Zero means if you look at here, it means top zero, right?
Zero.
Bottom zero.
I left everything.
So as you can see now, we cannot see even the sea, the death, because it's exactly like that there.
But it's a square that there is round it.
So we add the round it for this one as well.
Surrounded.
Well.
And let's, uh, add some width and height or other things so we can see.
Make it bigger.
So here inside the input we add.
We can add with.
And height, or we can add that width and height.
To the above death.
Death.
This death.
So we can add.
For example.
A with.
For example, we say the weight would be 90%.
But we can add the upper tier, we add the with.
For the x large and above we add the width to be because in actually mobile size, uh, we don't want
to see the widgets.
So as you can see now we have 600 pixels here and I want it to be hidden.
When we have a mobile screen and in the largest size and above, I want it to be in line.
If it tests it.
Now, we can see that when we decrease the size.
The reason we are seeing this one is small because we don't have any content here yet that this is going
to be okay.
Don't worry about that, because in the final version we have what's happening on Hulu to follow.
So this size will be exactly like that.
Then.
When we have this size and that in the mobile size, we don't see it.
Okay.
Let's continue styling this one.
So we want to wait to be 90%, but in the x large, I want the dead to be 75%.
Their with to be.
75%.
So you see, it's a smaller now than, as I mentioned before, I want this section to be sticky at a
top.
And she was just at Sticky and Top Zero.
And, uh, I want the background to be white because, uh, the default is transparent.
So if you don't make it white when we are scrolling down, we just see the other content inside the
search bar.
Then we have a padding y of one and a half.
They push it a little bit down and let's make the Z index 52 because I want it to be always at a top.
But as you can see, we cannot see the magnifier icon or a search icon anymore.
So let's make the Z index for this 152.
So now we can see it.
And let's change the color of the map.
This, uh, magnifier to be Tex Gray.
500.
And as I mentioned before, I want this placeholder, too, to be pushed a little bit to the right side.
So here in the.
Not here.
In the inputs.
We just add a margin left.
Or padding left.
Of 11.
And this is going to be okay now.
And, uh.
Let's change the border color.
Yes.
Say border.
Gray 500.
And then we have texts.
Gray.
700.
This text, the one that we are writing.
So.
That's.
And then we have.
Uh, when we focus on it, and then we click to it.
I want to add a shadow of large.
Like this.
See the shadow at the bottom.
Then when we focus, I want the background color to be white.
It's white already.
But let's make the background color as a default gray 100.
So now it's gray.
When we click on it, it becomes white.
Let's push a little bit, this one to the right side.
So in the top there.
Here, we just add a margin left of eight.
It can't see it like that.
The other thing is when we add the other things like what's happening and who to follow.
I wanted all the items.
To have a space in the Y axis of five.
You cannot see the result now, but later you can see it.
So that was it for the search bar.
Uh, let's add it to the get ha.
Real quick by just saying it at all.
Let's add a message using can't commit.
And the message would be.
Create the widgets.
Component.
And this search bar.
Okay.
Let's push it to get.
And we check our code.
So here, if you refresh the page by clicking on this Twitter, we can see now we have seven commits
in our repository.
And if you click on this, we can check our last repository, which is create the widgets component
and the search bar.
As you can see, we created a widget, that genius component, and we added a div that is covering all
the bridges, one for it being sticky and one to cover this icon and the input.
And we added this, which is that you asked to index that.
Yes.
Here.
Yeah, that was it for the search bar section.
In the next section, we're going to create this What's Happening section?
And we're going to use an open API.
Which doesn't need any API keys for getting these news.
This news is actually.
It's coming from an API and it's always getting a new.
Every day new news comes and if you click on show more, we can see more news.
And each time we are going to fetch 50 headlines from this API and show it here.
So we can just go on till 50.
Okay.
See you in the next section.