All right, in the last election, we have completed the.
For section of our project, in this section, we're going to get the information from the input and
movement to redirect the page to the related page.
So in order to do that, we need to use something called use router from Nick's router.
So inside the index that you use here?
The place that we have the former, the input at a top we at that used around her for the import use
throughout her.
From.
This is going to be from next forward slash route.
All right, so and then we can get the router here, so here, we just can't create a constant and we
just see a router and we call it to use router.
Simple as that.
But now, if you want to redirect a page to somewhere, we can just use a rather dark push and we will
be very direct to anywhere we like.
So because we want to redirect person to somewhere, we need to get that information here.
If you look at the final version here, it says hello and in there you are ill.
We have forest.
Search, which is the which is the file we're going to create later.
This is a page inside the search.
We have another query called term and we call that term to hello.
But how we get this?
Uh, how do we get this?
Hello.
We can use something called use riff from React to get the information from the input.
So inside the index that yes, we have the input here, we add something.
Called ref.
And we equal this referred to.
And then they just put the name for it.
The name would be in, for example, search inputs, riff and we're going to create this riff at the
top.
So here, just under this import, we're going to import use we have.
From.
React.
So this is just a built-in utility from React.
And then here we can just create that.
If you remember, we just called it the search.
Import tariffs, so we create this constant here, and this is going to be equal to use with.
And the default value would be no.
So if nobody write down anything in the input, their value is no.
But whatever you write down here, you can't get later.
And we want this when we write down here and press enter.
We want to submit this information and get it or when we click on this button, it doesn't matter in
the form.
If you add on, click to the button.
We can get the information off the input even by entering.
Yeah, press enter.
So inside the forum first button is a Google search, we added on Click here.
And this enclave is going to trigger a function and we called a function search.
And now we are getting an error saying search is not defined.
So we need to define this search by creating a function.
Just under this search input, ref, we create a function.
And we call it search as we be triggered under this, and this certainly is going to gives us something
called event.
For example, we want to.
Get the values or we want to prevent the refreshing of the page, we can use this event.
So first thing we need to do is just say.
And now before doing that, if we know clicked that Google search, they see that the page is refreshing
at the top, you can see the pages refresh.
In order to prevent this, we can use events.
Don't prevent default.
As simple as that, it can't prevent the fishing if it's not the sea that we don't see any refresh,
but actually the function is working, so we don't want to refresh the page.
We just want to change the URL.
So we can't get the term here in the input, just saying we can just turn is equal to death riff.
The search input ref dot current.
Don't value.
So this is everything inside input we can get and put it inside the term.
After defining the term, we can say if the term is not existed, just return.
So just if the term is not existed.
All right.
We just the.
Return in the function is great, is not going to work, so it's going to go outside that function.
Otherwise we're going to push to the that place, but this is actually now.
This one is not working, but if someone at a space.
This is going to this is not going to work.
All right.
So in order to prevent adding a space at the beginning, we can just add a method called terror trim
that is a building method from far from JavaScript.
So this is going to remove all this space before the thinks, even the person and a lot of space and
then write something.
This is going to remove all of the space.
All right, so.
And then if the term exists, if someone writes something, this is going to change the writer and mean
they redirect the page.
To solve it, so we just say rather that push and we're going to add.
Back to work to have a manual, so we just redirect a page to the the page search.
And just add the curry.
So we need to add a question mark, the quarry name is term and term is equal to.
This term that we're getting from the input here, so just a term.
So you know this.
This one's going to be yeah.
Dollar sign, yeah, so now we're getting to a variable term.
And also we want to trim it as well.
So you want to remove the S-based at the beginning of it?
No.
If you write down something, we click search.
We're going to redirect to the page, which is search term, is this one?
But this is because this the page search is not existed.
You're getting an error saying the page could could not be found.
That is, don't pay attention to this error.
We're going to create that this search page in the next section.
So now we just got successful to get the term.
And if we add only space, see only adding space.
This is not going to work, but even we add a space.
And then you write down something like, Hello.
The page would be only hello, we remove this base at the beginning.
So this is the functionality of the trip.
But that was it for the redirect thing.
Yeah.
Using rather.
Let's add everything to get home and review what we did, we just get at and we commence a new message
which is saying.
Because say.
Kids.
The town.
From input.
And I.
Directly related page.
It's related.
So we pushed to get off.
Let's see what we have done in refresh the page.
We have no new comments.
So that we just in the index that, yes, we added the user after and use where we create a function
to which is getting the information from the inputs, serving it first in a constant and we have a condition
if the term is not existed, we return and otherwise be pushed to the we push or we direct to the search
and we get the terms here.
And we got the information from the inputs using search input with using use actually and rename the
file search input the.
Yeah, that's it for the redirection and getting the turn in the next section, we're going to create
this header.
This header is different from the home page.
This is the home page header, but the page.
This search result, Heather, is different, so we have here.
An icon, a search bar again.
With the icons and the ability to delete this term.
And also, we we have this this signing, a sign off ability here as well.
And also we have some options, all or images.
All right, so in the next session, we're going to start with the header part of the results section.
So see you in the next section.