All right, in the last section, we have made the heinous S. Heather component is sticking to the top
of the page and also we added a shadow effect in this section, we're going to start creating our feed
section.
And as you can see from the final version of the project, we're going to create all these sections,
including the stories, the posts, mini profile and also the suggestions before starting with just
first, let's change the color of the fit section like this gray by just going to the index that year
and a top level div the one next to the return.
You just add the background and background color to be gray.
50.
Let's refresh the page.
And you can see the color yet because it doesn't have any dimension.
So we just say, mean hide.
2B, the screen size.
This is similar to we just say, midnight.
100 percent of the viewport might be used in CSIS.
All right.
Let's keep continue and create our feet section in the index such.
So we need to create a component called feed inside the components folder.
So we click here and we click on the this icon to create a new file and the not the name of the file
would be.
She dot J.S..
We can use our IFC to create the React functional component.
And, uh, we just as we are using next year, we don't need to import react from vehicles so we can
delete it or it's optional, we can leave it, there still works and inside the feed section.
If we have.
A main tank.
Let's change a stunted man.
And we have two sections one in the left and one in the right.
So in the fit that we just create a section.
And the first section includes stories.
And posts.
The second section.
Includes the many profile.
And also the suggestion part.
All right.
So let's create the stories, let's first import this one inside the index, such as here.
So we just say feed.
We can use control space at the end of the feed and import the feed components so we can see at the
top.
And also, let's create a stories component as well.
So the story is that, yes, and we use our sea.
And we can delete the.
Import from React.
Here in the story section.
Uh, we were going to have many stories like we have it.
We have one historic component and we're going to loop through an array of stories in order to create
the.
Where did these fake, uh, users with the username and the profile image, we can use a package called
Meaning Faker.
So if you search here.
On Google, we just a mini Fakir together like it should be together and in the search result, we see
an npm package called Mini Faker.
We click on this and they scroll down a little bit.
He's.
We can see that many fake or generate fake data, and also it's an alternative to a fake of the GST.
Actually, I used to use fake or touches for populating fake data, but.
Actually, it's, uh, the fake duchess owner decided to delete.
It's package and the package you can see it's completely empty now.
So nobody knows what happens to that person and why he decided to do that.
There are some stories on YouTube you can check, but it's not important.
I found it very good package called minifigure that does similar things and show you how to use it.
So in order to install.
Fake.
We just need to you and pan install minifigure inside our terminal.
So first, we stop the server and we the implant.
I mean, if Faker.
So you just need to import.
M.F.A. at a top.
So important, any figure from any figure and.
Here we create a state.
So we we just create a state with we just a story.
Users.
And since a story uses.
And the vehicle is to use the state.
So we are going we are using Hook to create the users, the state, and it's the initial value will
be an empty and empty array, and we need to import use this state as well.
So we just use counter space to automatically import, use this state from react.
So after this, we can use use effects.
To populate this information, just the time that the page is loaded, so use effect is actually is
from reactors, so we need to import it.
And the way it works, we just need to create a function.
And inside this function, we're going to create the.
This story, you users using any fakers, so we just take a hands.
Its story users and.
Magnifica has.
A function called pray that it's going to create a number of arrays that we define.
OK, we just need to write mini fake hair dot array.
And we can specify the number of array we want to create.
We want to create, for example, 20 users in stories, so we just need to arrive 20 here and we can
get the index of this each one using just saying apprentice's instead of parenthesis inside a set of
parentheses.
Just right.
All right.
And.
We just had an area and open a set of parenthesis and inside this function.
We are going to create an object, including the information that we want to have inside this.
Story, users.
The first information is user name.
You want to create and the user name will be.
We can use the user name function of minifigure yesterday M.F.A..
Dot username.
This actually, this is going to create, uh, if you check here.
Inside the manufacture.
We can just assure you the user name.
User, yeah, yeah.
User name, the user name can be in English or French, so we for you, which is if you want to create.
A random username, both English and French, you can just leave it like this.
But if you only want to make English users, you just need to specify your look.
So we open this sort of parenthesis and inside instead of curly braces, we just write local and we
equal it to English.
But we need to import local.
From manufacturers.
So here we just import.
Directly, M.F.A., faker slash locals.
And the locals will be English.
Simple as that.
All right.
After this username, we can create.
The image part for the image we are using, we can use a website called PR Avatar.
So if you search PR Avatar on Google.
We begin to see a website called PR Avatar or Avatar that CC.
So we click on this and we can see that, yeah, I have a lot of avatars.
The fake people we can use in our web site.
There are there is a method we can get it to image by using this, uh u r l and the R if you see the
all the images.
There are 70 images inside this website, so by using this.
Uh, you're out and changing the number of image from from one.
Or from zero to 70, we can get the, uh, different types of image.
I don't know one or.
Yeah, yeah, from one to 70.
All right.
We just copy this.
You are our MVP, sit here as a back take.
Inside the back deck, because we want to make this tree valuable so we can use a dollar sign and sort
of curly braces to create a valuable and we can use math.
Dot Random.
To create a random number.
And we can multiply to 70 to create from zero to 70.
And, uh.
But this is this is not around the number we need to run this number using math.
Dot seal.
So this is going to be from one to 70, because, yeah, if you use math that floor, you're going to
create from zero to sixty nine.
But math the still makes the number from one to 70.
So we create let's add.
The comma at the end, and then next thing is just the.
Already, you're getting the idea here.
I just need to equal eye to I, so we get the ideas.
So now we created the story user inside the use effect.
Let's add the dependency for the users as well.
We just make it an empty array.
And here we sit the story users to.
This.
Constance, no, we actually we saved our state and we can use it in our application.
Let's first console log in and see the all the users information.
So if you go to our website and you use NPR and Rhonda to start.
The server.
Now, if you open the console using F12.
That's a fresh two page.
We didn't add this story component to fit sections, so in the future, we just need to add this story
to hear.
And we just need to use counter space to import it now when we refresh the page, we can see inside
the console.
We have.
Let's bring it up a little bit.
Yeah, now we have an array of 20 users, so it starts from zero to 19.
And each of them have an I.D. image.
I don't know what it was.
None.
So probably we made some mistake here.
Let's check own math to see.
After a random.
Let's change this year to floor.
Still, none should be.
Some.
Yeah.
We forgot to add apprentices here.
So because the random is the function, so we need to add apprentices at the end.
So if you check now we have the I.D. and image with a random image number and the username.
The the problem is the username is capitalized.
So let's add, uh, two lowercase.
Function at the end of the.
Use a name to make it lower case now in the new era.
We are getting all the users lowercase because an Instagram official, the user's names are in lowercase.
All right, so we got all the information.
Let's look through this array and show it inside there.
A story component.
So inside the witness section, we loop through the story users.
By using Map.
We get each user here and.
We just directly return it.
And we create a story.
Component here.
So we just see a story that, yes, and we use honesty to create the functional component.
And we imported inside this story section.
So we just saw a story.
The EU's counter space to import the story component.
And we need to pass these three information, so first, we need a key.
We just say user I.D. for the keys, so we don't get an error inside the console.
Next, we need to pass the user information, for example, the user name would be.
User dot username.
Then we have image.
Which is user that I am.
And inside.
And inside this story.
We can distract it and the kid I am, she and user name.
This is a props, so destructive props.
Are we getting it like this, so let's close this console and see the images first.
The image ASIC is set to be I am G.
The alternative is just a username, and we have a paragraph of.
Use of name.
All right, now, we're getting the images and also the username at the bottom.
And each time you refresh the page, we should get a new image and different user name because it randomly
creates each time using use a fixed.
So, yeah, that was it for this part in the next section, we're going to style this story section
and make this beautiful story section inside our website using Telvin CSF before finishing the prayer.
This video let's add everything to the get
created comments, using an image, using a message of saying.
Uh.
We just populate fake data using.
M.F.A..
And.
Map two at.
A story.
Components.
Let me just, uh.
Yeah, just sick, populate fake data using minifigure and create feet and story components that could
be better components.
All right.
Use, get push.
To push everything inside the.
Get you refresh the page inside, get how we see a new comet.
So we did a lot actually inside this video inside this section, so we create the feed that.
Yes.
And the added all the sections and we created the stories that GST imported minifigure and we create
an estate and use effects to create and populate the dataset using minifigure array.
And also we map through it.
And we passed the information through the props inside a story that you use and the packages we installed
was M.F.A..
Inside the index that we just added the color, background color, and we set the mean height to be
this great size.
All right.
In the next section, we're going to create and style this string section.
So see you in the next section.