All right.
In the last section, we have completed to the ability to get the data from the input and send it to
the URL.
In this section, we are going to start with the header section of the search page.
We have a header section for the home page.
And if you look at the final version of our project.
Here, when we search for something, we get the turn into this input
and we have it Heather here.
And also the results section is at the bottom.
So if you look at carefully what we have here, let me try it.
Or you?
So we just checked.
We have this is the head of.
From top to the bottom.
And we have a logo here.
And we have an input actually to form.
Which has a few things, the input itself, which is here.
We have a button to clear the this area to clear the form.
We have a microphone icon.
And we have a search icon.
They're good at getting these three icons from hero icons and and on the right side, we have our logging
thinks we don't need to create this one again.
We just, uh, add the user component here so we can simply have our authentication and user here.
This is for this section in the next section, we start with this options here, which is a.
Let me try it with a different color, so we have option here.
It has the whip search and also the imitators.
All right.
So let's first create this search page now in the final version, we have something called perch.
So when we go to.
Uh, let's go back to Visual Studio code, we open our site on the right side.
Let's start the server using npm run dev.
So now if we search something, for example, hello.
We get to tell at a top and then we go to the page called search, but the page is not created yet and
we get a forum for error saying this page could not be found.
So we create this page you see in the pages.
We create a new file and we call it search 30th.
We can use RF Sea to use to create a reactor functional component.
We don't need to react here and.
Here we start creating our page.
So let's go to that page now, as you can see now we have the page.
No, you're not getting the error anymore.
So for the page, because it's a separate page, we need to hit tag.
This is a hit attack from.
From next year.
Just be sure to to to be capitalized here.
So, uh, this is a hit track and we need to imported from the next.
So we, you know, we get the auto suggestion.
We're getting it from next forward slash hit.
And inside the head, we can add, for example, at titre or method tax so tightly, we just say first
like a search page.
Now we should see it at the top.
Now I can see the search page.
All right, so after the attack.
As you hear, you can see we have the header and also we have the results section.
And finally, we have the patient issue.
So for the year, we just add the.
So we have to search harder because it's different from the our home header.
And then we have search results.
Let's create a component and we call it search header.
So here in the Components folder, we create a component and we call it a search
header.
That's Jed James.
And we can use our fear to create a reactive functional component.
And let's delete this part, and we go to search that, yes, and we import that.
So we import search.
Header.
And we imported automatically from components search.
So now we can see in the search page and we are getting this search had.
So let's continue our work inside the search for the tech genius.
So this did we change it to header tank?
And this Heather Tagg is going to have some intelligence classes if we want the hitter to stick to the
top.
So we make it sticky.
So because if you look at the final version, when we're scrolling down, the here is always at the
top.
And the hitter has a background color of whites, so it's not transparent, so we need to do two things.
First, we need to stick it to the top by using a sticky top zero.
And we just need to change the background color to whites.
So now.
We have the hill now at the top, so whatever we do, we always add a top.
Then we added Div to have everything inside us.
So in the final version, we have the local input and this user.
So let's create these components, these elements.
So.
Let's start with the image.
The image is very similar to the one that we created for the home page.
So we can copy that one, if you remember in the home page.
He added.
Image.
Here.
We want the same image, but with the different width and height.
So we copy this image here.
So we don't need to create it again.
So if we go to Senator Grassley, we can close the search, said yes and floater.
So we pasted here.
So let's go to our page.
There's something.
And we need to import the image from the Knicks forward slash image, and we should see it right now.
Yeah.
Just we changed the width and height, the width, we just said it to be 120 and height to be there,
for example 40.
And we can't we can change the object, faith.
We can keep it covered or we can choose to contain.
So now the size is fine.
And also, when we click on this image, we want to come back to the home page, so we need to edit
and click to this image tech.
So it's very simple we need to click, but before that, we need to use our router to do that so we
can use user data from next.
So we need to import to use about router.
From next Phobos-Grunt.
And then here at the top, it creates a constant.
And we call this content constant router equal to use throughout.
Now we can use on Click.
And we create a function, actually, which returns rather.
The push and the page we want to go is homepage, so we just and a forward slash.
So now if we click on this logo, we should come back to the homepage.
Simply, so let's go back to that page and let's add a cursor to be like the Ateca cursor to be pointer
so we can see a pointing hand when we hover over the.
Local.
So we just at a.
Class name.
Cursor point.
Now, when we hover over the logo, we should see a pointing.
All right, so that's it for the image part.
Let's continue with the forum and the.
Input.
So after the image, we create a form.
We don't need to action.
And in scientist form, we at.
And if you think we need the input, we need three and we need three icons.
This icon, the microphone and also the search icon.
So first, we create the input.
We just say input.
And the time is.
The type should be ticks, and then this one has a reference to it because we want to create and we
want to get the information from this form as well.
Now we can see the input here.
Should be sorry.
Yeah.
Can't see the form and the input.
But we want to we want to what we want to get is we want to get that, uh.
When we, for example, we write hello here, you want to see the hello inside this inputs?
And also we want to get the information later using use ref.
So first, we need to define the default value to be we can get the information from the crowd.
Rhonda, you are using and it's.
We can we can get it using router.
Dot query.
And we just need to add the term, so when we do this one, we get the hell out here.
And if you go back to homepage, we search for something else, for example, uh, background image.
Although something similar is simple, the search for nice.
We see nice here.
All right, so.
And then, uh, next is we want to get the information as well, so we need to create a riff and we
call it.
Similar to the previous one, we call it search.
Search input, ref.
And we need to create this one.
Now you can see we are getting an error saying search input ref is not defined.
Let's create that one at a time.
So we create a constant and we call it search.
Input riff and we equal it to use with.
And the initial value is not.
And we need to import Youssef from React.
Similar to the one we did for the homepage.
So now we can have access to this information, are you going to use it later?
First bullet and the buttons and other stuff so we can when we submit the form, we can get the information
as far.
So you can change the route or that time.
So we got the input.
No, let's import the icons, the X icon.
The ex-con, the microphone and the search are upon.
So at a top.
The import.
The icons, the first I found this microphone.
Our car, this second one is search.
Search icon, and then we have the X icon.
And all these things coming from here are icons.
First, react, former Soviet.
So let's use these icons here.
So after the inputs.
They have the X icon.
Let's make it a little bit smaller so we can continue.
Later, we're going to completely astound the pace first and everything and then be we do there just
to be at the height of seven for this.
Next, we have the microphone icon.
We set the height for this one.
Six.
And then we have the.
Search AKA.
Let's set the high to be successful.
So everything is fine, and then the final thing we need is just the user after this form, the we add
the user component that we created and we're going to import it.
From the same level, so as you can see now, we have the signing and sign of that bill.
All right, so let's now.
It style our pitch.
We already start the Google Image.
First, we make the display to Flex to bring everything to next to each other.
Then we change the width of this diff to be full.
And finally, we add a patty of six to push everything a little bit inside.
And we can center them using items center.
So now you can see everything looking good, except this part that we're going to fix it.
And I want this user to be on the right side, so I want this user half the class of margin left auto.
But if we go to user and do this fine, it's going to affect the other header as well.
So we don't want to do it.
We just want to do a valuable
class.
So here we can add a class here.
We can add a clip and we just add our the class we minute just margin left auto.
So you're going to push it to the right side.
But in order to see the effect, we need to add this class stamp to the user.
So if we go to user touches.
And be at this class name here and get it.
As a prop.
So we get the class name and we add added to the birth of things like, we want the image to be like
this one.
So we add we change this.
Uh?
Class name.
To the back takes so we can add a.
Valuable to it.
And inside this, we add a variable and we call it class.
We should do the same things for the.
The other return as well, so.
And here in the class name.
We changed the tactic.
So.
And yeah.
So we add the class stamp here as far.
Now we can see that the signing went to the right side.
So this is only been affected for the heinous action, not for the home page.
So this is the trick you can use for have a dynamic and class four component.
All right.
So before we finish for the user, this and this part, let's style this form.
So we want the forum to have some classes.
We want to bring everything next to each other using Display Flex and.
Let's add some border.
As well, so we can see what's inside.
And we want the borders to be.
Gray hair color would be gray, so we just say border gray.
For example, two hundred.
Let's make it rounded using rounded full.
And we add some shadow effects, so we just a shadow.
And we make the Shadow Lodge.
And finally, we we can we need to add some padding in the X level x axis of six.
So push me here and then we have a padding on the y axis.
This one is three.
And we have a margin left of 10.
So we have some space here.
And then we have a margin right of five.
So we have we just continue with we need to add flex growth, so we want this have a kind of completely
get this space.
So we use flex grow and we use max width of.
Three weeks now.
So when we have a like a bigger, a bigger screen, the maximum is three weeks out like this.
Then finally, we sent her everything using items center.
So push these icons a little bit down to make them center.
So don't worry about this logos, we're going to fix it.
Soon and then for the inputs.
We had some class name.
And this is going to be a very simple, we just add this with a full.
So you can see that the icons came back and then we have to focus.
And when we focus, we don't want to have this ring around it, so we just say ring and we can say at
line.
None.
So we don't have any bank here.
So as you can see, it's not that's beautiful to have this like icons.
When we have a smaller screen.
So if you look at the final version, when we decrease the size of this grain, let me increase the.
Make it bigger.
When we go to the mobile sites.
We don't have this microphone and the.
This search icon in this point.
And then.
So we have this sign in page, and we can fix this one using water white with space, no rap.
No problem, and then, uh.
The logo itself is getting smaller.
As well.
So let's just remove these icons and also let's fix fix this signing.
First, we go to.
This sign in, we can add something called white to space, no wrap.
There's always like this.
And then let's remove these icons when we have a smaller screen, so there will be heat in when we have
a.
A smaller screen.
But when it's bigger than a small.
When they're bigger than they are in line Flex.
Let's add this phone to the microphone as well.
And then we should see them in this.
So let's style these three icons first, so make it a little bit bigger so we can see all the icons.
And then I put this one at the top.
Let's close the left side so we can have more space.
So the icon?
The X icon we have, we can change the color of this using text gray, just fix it to be maybe five
hundred is fine to just have a sun grey color.
And then we have we want to have something like.
We want the cursor to be pointer.
So when we hover over this year pointing hand and then the other things we can add is just the.
When it was just added when it is smaller and this screen is bigger than a small like this, this size,
we want to have a margin.
Uh, margin right of three.
So we have a little bit of space from the X icon and this one, and we want to add something like a
border here as well.
So you use the microphone icon for adding the border for the microphone icon.
We changed the color to be blue.
Actually, both of these a search like on a microphone, I find they have a blue color, so we use dual
cursor to put two and four, both of them, so we just ticks.
Blue 500.
For both of the six blue, five hundred.
And then let's see what we had they have.
So that's fine for this.
This search icon looks fine.
Just the microphone icon, let's continue for that.
Then we added more padding left for.
And then we add a border
in the left.
And also, we said it to be two, which is two pixels, so we have a border.
Here and then we want the border to be gray.
So we just changed the border color to be gray.
And three hundred.
So we can see it more clear.
Then we can add something like marching right after three, so have a little more space from the search
icon as well.
Next, you want to add the ability when we click on this.
OK, but I can't.
We want to remove whatever inside this input, so I have something here.
When I click here, it should remove it.
It's very simple to do so.
We in the X icon, we can add unclaimed.
And it is going to trigger a function which is going to return.
If you remember, we got the information from the inputs using search input, ref.
So we can change the current value.
Of this, we just a current that value.
Equal to an empty string.
So now, if you click, we should delete whatever insight.
The simple as that.
OK, now our uh, everything looks fine, we just need to get the information and show it on this screen
as well on the URL, because then we are typing something, nothing is happening.
In order to get the information inside the forum, we need to add a bottom, so we just add a button,
but I don't want we don't want to show the button so we can make the button hidden and we just add a
type of submit for the button and we trigger a function.
So we add a button here.
The Typekit would be submit.
And.
There is nothing to write down, and the.
We just use the hidden tax review to make it hidden.
And the add oncolytic.
The anklet is going to try to call a function like the one, the previous one we did for the homepage.
Now we need to create a function because we are getting an error saying search is not defined, but
at the top we can create the function function is completely similar to one we did in the home page,
but let's create it again as a review.
So we create a function and we call it search.
And this is going to get some thing like events.
We can use that event to prevent refreshing the page.
So we just say events that prevent default.
Then we can get the information from the input and we put it inside a constant called turn.
This term is equal to that search input, ref.
The current value.
All right.
So we get the term.
Now it's time to check the term existed or not, you just say if the term is not exist, it.
Just return, but you want to know this, someone is using the website doesn't put this space, so we
can trim it, so this trim is going to remove all the spaces before the return.
And finally, if the term exists, we want to go to death.
You are out, so we just see rather that push.
And we can specify it with the back tick, because it's dynamic.
You are out, this is going to go to the search page.
With the Korea term, which is equal to.
That term, but we want to remove the space bit before that, so we use trim.
So let's try this.
So we go here and search, for example.
Hello.
And if you look at the URL now, we have the term hello.
And in the search pitch.
Yeah, that was it for the header section.
It's fine you can go to the Logan.
Who just fell?
And the.
Let's search something.
Now we can see here that so.
Yeah, that's that's it looks fine.
And let's put everything in, get her first.
And we just, uh, just and everything using it, and we can commit it with the message of.
Create search.
Heather components.
Components and we push push it to get.
Let's go to GitHub and check.
And the review of a code very briefly.
So we go to the last comment.
As you can see, we created a new component called search filter that yes.
Which we are just a.
A death.
Which has the image of the Google icon, then we have the form that includes input and tree icons.
And when we submit the form using a hidden button, we call it function if it's going to route the URL.
To the this font to search term, and we get the term using use ref.
And also we inside the user that, yes, we've got that dynamic.
Classes using we just got the class them using props, and we added to the both of the image and also
the button so we could bring the set.
That's it.
User to the right side using margin left auto.
And in the search, such as we just added component search, yeah, that was it for this heather part
in the next section, we're going to create this.
Options and we call them search header options.
So two options are available.
One is all and one is images.
So when we click on all this, we should see the web search and then we click on images.
We should see the.
Images of deaths tour, which is now as Hella.
So in the next section, we're going to do that, so, sir, in the next section.