All right.
In the last section, we have created the header section for the web and image pages.
But they haven't completed this search box.
And in this section, we're going to create this search box.
If you look at the final version, you can see that the search box include an input here, a cross icon
for deleting the word that is existed.
For example, if you click on this file, because to make this input empty, then we have two more icons,
the microphone icon and also this magnifier icon.
So also between these two sections, we have a border here, so we need to style it like that.
And.
So let's go back to Visual Studio Code and we go to inside the search box.
So the things we want to do here is to create a form.
So we just delete this.
Dave and I create a form here.
Inside this form we're going to have.
Uh, the input.
And also the three icons.
So first I want to add an input.
After the input we have to three icons.
We're going to search for the icons inside the React Icons package.
The first icon I want to find is the cross icon.
So I'm going to search cross.
And they want I want to use these are x cross to.
So, Ryan, it's just our cross to that.
Copy that and go back to here and paste pasted.
And the let's import that one as well.
So we're going to import.
Oryx cross two from React icons First flash r X.
The next icon we want to have is a microphone icon.
So we're just going to search Mike and the one I want to use is B, is Phil, Mike, Phil the first
one.
So let's add it here.
So we can just import that on as well, which is coming from React icons for slash bees and just you
need to match the end with the beginning of the icon.
The last icon is going to be the magnifier, which is we just need to search the word search.
And the name of that is I line search the second one.
But just copy this one and we go back to Visual Studio Code and we paste it here.
So we need to just import it at the top.
So we get the suggestion from GitHub Copilot, which is helping us to quickly style our project.
So let's check what we have here.
Let's refresh the page.
Now we have three icons here.
Let me zoom it a little bit.
So we have the three icons.
And the input is here at the top, so we need to style it.
So let me bring this one to the right side.
And now we bring this one to the left side.
Let's close.
Okay, it looks good.
So now with the things we want to do is to let me.
The.
First, we style these
icons.
So the first icon to cross icon.
I want to make it bigger by changing its text to two x large.
And then let's make the color of it to be gray.
500, and let's set the cursor to be pointers.
So when we hover over it, we see a pointing head.
This?
Yeah.
Now we can see a pointing hand when we hover over it, and the color is gray.
And also, we want to add some margin on the right side when we are in the bigger size.
After the mobile size, we have margin right of two.
Okay, let's keep continue and we go to the microphone.
Here.
For the microphone.
I wanted to be hidden when in the small size, I don't want to see the microphone.
So as you can see, it's hidden now.
But after the mobile size, I want it to to be visible.
So I just change the inline flex.
So in the bigger size, we should see the macro fork.
So essence and line flex.
Think you need to save this one.
Okay.
You can see the microphone here in the bigger size, like a medium, but in the small size, we don't
see the microphone.
Let's keep it this size so we can see the changes.
Cook.
So let's keep continuous styling the microphone.
Let's make it bigger.
We just say takes for Excel.
I want the color of this microphone to be blue 500.
And let's add some padding in the left size four for.
And also we want to have some border on the left side.
With the size to.
And we can just change the color of the border to be gray.
300.
I can't see the border.
But if we bring them next to each other, you can see it better.
So I'm going to bring them next to each other by changing this form display of the form to be flexed.
Okay.
Now you can see them next to each other.
Let's keep continuous silence.
We come back again and complete the form.
So for the microphone, we have created this border color.
We can add some margin on the right axis of three as well.
So we have some space between the microphone and the magnifier.
And finally, we style the magnifier.
I want to change the text to be two x large.
So we make it bigger.
And also we want to make this fun hidden in the mobile size, But in the mobile size and above, I want
to see them.
So I'm going to change the inline flex here.
We changed the color of this one to be Tex blue.
500.
And also we set the cursor to be pointer.
So when we hover over it, we see a pointing hand.
Practice.
So now we have completed the
icon, so let's style this input.
For the input.
Let's add a class name.
Let me fix this one, actually.
So let's close the left side and we can have some more space here.
Okay, Now let's add some class name to the input.
And the input.
We wanted the width to be full.
And when we focus on it.
I want the art line to be null.
So we don't see a border.
So now the the input is here, but when we click on it, we don't see anything else.
So now it's time to create and solve the form.
So we see the changes in the form.
So the things we want to do in the form is to add a border for the form.
And let's make the border color to be gray 200, and let's make it rounded
like a rounded full.
And let's add some shadow.
Compete the large size.
And in the we just added padding in the x axis of.
Six.
And padding in the y axis of three.
We add some margin in the left size.
Of ten.
So we have some space between the icon and the.
Inputs.
Also, we want to have some marching in the right side.
So the right side of five.
And also we changed the flex to grow so we can occupy all the places from the icon to the right side
because we are using the display to justify content between for the this part.
So we just use the Flex scroll and also we can set the maximum width to be three Excel.
And we can use item center to bring everything to the center vertically.
I think now you can see the input here.
So everything is centered vertically and also this is flex grow because it starts from beginning.
It's not in the center and the input looks okay in the small size, we don't see the icons.
We can type like this.
We can customize it more and make it smaller for the mobile size, but I think it's fine.
It looks okay.
So now that we have completed the styling of the input, we want to add functionality to that.
The first things first, we want to when we come to this website, we want to actually track the input
firstly.
And then we want to have the initial value of this input to be this a word that we have inside the URL.
But as we are adding interaction inside the input, we cannot use it as server side because we are going
to use an click and submit for some piece of state or hog.
So we cannot use it server side because the user is interacting with that section.
We need to create it client side.
So first thing first, I want to change this one to client side so we don't get an error.
So we just say use client at the top.
So we make it client side.
Then we can use something called use search params to get the parameters of the URL.
So I'm going to import that one.
So let's import the news.
Search params from next forward slash navigation.
The next navigation is completely new for next year and its includes exclusive for only next year 13.
So when we have the used search prams, we can initialize it here.
We just call it search prams.
This is going to be equal to use search prompt.
So we're going to initialize this one.
And this is actually a hook.
So by the rules of next year 13, in the when we are using hook, we need to.
Keep the component client side.
So this is another reason we use client side here.
So after that we got this search params.
Now.
This search prompt is going to give us, for example, that search term at a top here.
So let's refresh the page.
We're getting an error.
Kate, we need to get this search a search term so we can just create a constant.
And this is going to be search, for example, term.
Which is going to be equal to search programs that get and turn.
So if it's not existed, we are going to make it empty string.
We don't need it, actually, because later we are going to use a user state book to set the initial
value of the term to be empty.
So that is enough.
So now we get the search term, which is this word at a top.
Now we can show it inside the input.
So inside the input we can set the.
Initial value of the input by just.
A sitting.
Its value to a variable called, for example.
TER.
And then we need to create this term here at a top, we just create a piece of state called term.
And this is going to be equal to use the state.
As you can see here.
So I'm going to import you this state from React.
So now.
The initial value of this one.
Is going to be a search term that we are getting or if the search term is not existed, we can just
set it to be an empty string.
That is true.
Now, if you refresh the page.
But let's see.
So we got the term we have imported use the state.
We got this search term here.
Search firms that get we get a sorry.
This is not shouldn't be termed the students should be searcher because we are getting the search term
from here.
So now probably when we refresh the page, we should see the search term here inside the input.
So if you come back, for example, to the home page and we search for something else, for example,
hello, and we press enter, this is going to show us the search term.
Hello.
And also the input is hello as well.
So.
So always we get the turn inside here and show it here so the user can use this word or modify it,
or you can they can delete it by using this icon.
So the next thing we need to do is to use this icon to delete this term.
So we need to add an event listener to this icon.
So when we click on it, we're going to set this one, set this term empty.
So let's go back to Visual Studio Code, and we go to that cross icon.
And here we're going to add an and click event listener.
This is going to trigger a function which is going to set the term
to an empty string.
Okay, now.
Let's refresh the page.
Now, when we click here, we should make this one empty.
All right.
But when we refresh the page, we get the search term again from this one.
So we can click this one, empty it, we can write down something.
But now we cannot write anything because we haven't had any unchanged events listener to the impulse.
So we need to go back to input.
Here, and then we add an unchanged event listener.
This all change event listener.
Is going to trigger a function to this function is going to get the event first, and this is going
to set the term that we have.
The piece of state to e dot target dot value.
So anything the the value of the input is going to be set for the term, the piece of state term that
we have at the top.
So I also we want to change the value of the input to otherwise we don't see any, we cannot change
the value.
So we need to change the value of the input to be equal to the term that we have.
So let's see.
Okay, So I think that is fine.
So let's check now.
We can change the value here.
For example, if I write down nice, I press enter.
This is going to refresh the page is submit the form, but it's changing the value of this piece of
state.
But we haven't able to submit the form and change this URL.
So.
The things we do is to add an on submit event listener to the form.
So we just gonna add an unsub meet event listener which is going to trigger a function.
And we call the function handled.
For example, submit.
And we need to create this function here at the top.
Otherwise, we get an error.
So we create a function called handle submit.
So as we are getting the suggestion.
So.
The next.
The second one is not okay.
We just need the first one.
So we get the event.
We prevent the default behavior of the submission, which is refreshing the page and the things we want
to do is to push the person to that particular page.
First thing first, I want to check if the term is not existed.
We're going to return.
And also if there is if the person just write down a space.
So we use a trim function to remove the space.
So we remove the space and then we check if there is a term we're going to return.
So if this one is empty and we press enter.
But it's.
If you press enter, nothing happens.
But if we write down something, this is going to submit the form and submit the form.
And also we're going to.
Redirect the person to the page that we are desired.
So we're going to use another hook called use router from.
And the next navigation.
So we have the next navigation here.
So we're going to use use router as well.
And first thing first, we need to initialize it here.
So we're going to let's create this one on top.
So after this initialization, I'm going to initialize the router, which is going to be equal to router
use router.
And then we're going to push the person to that particular alt, which we're going to push the person
to forward slash search forward slash web.
And then search term, which is which is have to be that term that is inside here.
So now if, for example, if I write down hello and I press enter, this is going to redirect me to
search for slash web search term.
Hello.
If I change this form, for example, to nice press enter, we get the nice at a top.
So that is that's it for submission for the form.
But I want when I click on this magnifier I want to submit the form to that is very simple as well.
We need to just go to that icon, this search icon, and we're going to add an event listener which
is going to be an on click event listener, which is going to just call that handle submit function.
So now.
Let's test this one again so we have the noise.
Let's delete the noise here and we just write down.
Hello.
We don't press enter, but we click on this icon.
This is going to submit the form and also change to redirect the person to search term.
Hello.
All right.
That was it for completing the search box.
Let's add this one to GitHub and review what we have done here.
So I'm going to use Contour shift G to open this source control so we can just press on this plus icon
to add everything using Git at all.
And also we can add a message here saying complete.
This search.
Box component.
So I'm going to click here and click on Commit and Push to push everything to GitHub.
So let's go back to GitHub and we.
Just click here to refresh the page.
Now we have nine commands in our GitHub repository, which is the last one is complete the search box
component.
So the only things we have done is to update this search box that JSS X, as I mentioned before, B.
S, we are using some hoax and some events listener.
And this is going to be interactive.
Be it the users.
So we have to use the use client at the top.
So we make this component client side.
And next year 13 is a smart enough to detect that everything else here at the top is server side.
They're going to be prepared.
Server side.
And also only this part is going to be client side.
So this is going to make our website faster to be loaded.
And it's better for the search engine optimization because these HTML files are is already prepared
and pass to the browser.
So the search engines is going to check this HTML part as well, which is completely opposite of the
react.
React doesn't do that.
Also, everything in the React is client side.
So now let's continue.
We have imported use search params to get the parameter of the URLs.
We have used the use router to redirect the person using router dot push.
Do we have imported three icons from React icons to add to our input and the form?
And also we have imported user state to create a piece of state called term.
So we have initialized the use search params and the use router here.
We got the search term by using the JIT method of the search params.
And we just get the search term from the URL.
Then we have created a piece of state called term.
And we have added a function to change this term.
And the initial value of this one is going to be this search term or an empty string.
We have created a function called Handle Submit, which is going to firstly prevent the default behavior
of the submission, which is refreshing the page.
Then we have added a condition.
If there is no term in the input or there is only the space in the input, we're going to return.
We're not going to redirect the person.
Otherwise, we're going to redirect the person to the this URL.
Search for slash web search term.
The term that we get from the piece of state that we have, then we have created a form.
We have added an on submit event listener which is going to trigger a function called handle submit,
and we have added an input with the type of text.
And we just set the value to be the term estate.
And then we have added an unchanged event listener.
I think I have added two value here.
So I'm going to delete the one of them.
So we have added the change event listener, which is going to get the event and set the term the piece
of state term to E to target that value.
Anything is here is going to be inside that piece of state.
And we also we have added the cross icon which is going to set the term to be an empty string.
When we click on it, then we have the microphone icon and finally we have the search icon, the magnifier
icon, which is going to submit the that function as well.
So let's delete this value here.
I'm going to.
Delete this some extra value here.
That's why we were getting an error.
And then we're going to I'm going to just add this one to GitHub and just send us a fix.
Double.
Value and input.
I'm going to commit and push it.
Okay.
So that was it for creating this search box.
In the next section, we're going to work on this tab icon tab section.
So when we click on all, we see the web result.
And when we click on the images, we see the image results.
Are we going to work on it?
And also, we, as you can see, when we are on the image and here we see the image, this place is
selected with the blue color.
So we're going to work on that and how to do it.
So see in the next section for creating this search options.