All right, in the last section, we have completed the Heather part.
We added the logo, the input and also the user component in this section, we're going to make this
options, which is all an image.
If I see him a little bit more, you can see when we hover over each of them, we see and at the color
of the text and the logo is changed to blue and also we have a border at the bottom.
So and also, if you click on each of them, the other one gets black and no border.
But the other one, it stays blue.
So we can achieve this one using the selected attributes of the components.
So here.
So let's go to our visual studio code, and we start.
Creating these options.
We want to create them inside a component called
circular options.
So we open the.
Explorer section, we create a new component and we call it search.
Heather?
Options 30th.
We create a reactor functional component using RF C.
And we are going to add this fund to this search.
Heather itself, let's close this index that she is.
So here at the bottom after this, did we added this search?
Heather Options be imported from Dart Forest, Leicestershire, fitted options.
At a top.
We should see it here.
No.
Let's refresh the page.
We can see that we have the search and search the options at the bottom.
So let's continue to create and to create the both of the options.
Now, before doing that, we're going to add something in country, no, we have the quarry, which
is term.
But if you look at the final version of the project, we have another quarry called search type, which
is empty when we're searching for where.
But if you click on the images, we should see the search type image.
This one actually is going to tilt the API of the Google that we are searching for the.
Image and they're going to give us the images result.
If you remember two places we added this term here in this input, when we submit this input and also
when we submit the input here.
So two places we need to modify our quote.
What is in the home page, which is index such as.
And the index in that year when we been we are calling the router into this function.
We added the query term, but we didn't add the query search time, so we can add it here, just simply
adding an answer.
So.
Because first one is the question mark, but after that, you should add and sign, of course, and
a quarry name is search.
Type camel case, and we just say equal.
Because we want to search the Web, we don't need to add any tanks.
You know, I will show you later in the year when I show you and how to use the Google API, Google
Search API in Google Search API.
The rule is if this one is empty.
The Google is going to search the Web.
But if this one is image is going to search the images.
So because in the home page, if you want to search the bit first, you just make it empty.
No, if he says something like hello.
Not here in our our.
Website.
So if we go to homepage, if search something like hello, we should see the term hello and also the
search type, which is empty and nothing is going to change because everything is the same, but we
only have the another query here.
Let's do the same things for the header and in the search page as well.
So in the search header?
Inside this function, which we're calling this search.
We can add the curious law, so co-researcher, because so, no, if is there something here, for example,
research nice, the term is nice and then the first type is empty.
So we got this one.
No, when we we want to create this search, other options we can base on this, the information here,
based on the value of the search type, we can select any of the, uh, any of the options, for example,
in the final version.
Now the all the option, all is selected.
If I add image here at it at the end and press enter the tap images is selected.
So based on the information here we can choose which option is selected.
So here how in order to get this information, we already know that we need, we can use the router,
rather that query.
So we got the information off the channel bit router that query dot term for getting the search.
That was just a router that search time dot sorry router that query that search type.
Let's do this.
So inside here, let's create our options.
So we're going to return at deer, which has two things.
Two options, but let's create another component for each of them.
So we just create a component called search.
Option.
A search.
Search, Heather option, but this option is different, it's not options, it's option.
Without this, it's singular.
So this is a.
Here we create a search header options that yes, this is search header option that is.
We create this file using our FC, and here we're going to use these components, so we a search filter
option.
We need to create two of them, so we create two.
First, we import this.
OK.
Let's make this on a smaller.
Bring it here.
All right.
So now we have two options.
Let's look at some props for it.
So each of them, they have a tie to us, so we just set the first one.
The title is all.
All right.
And the second one, the title is images.
So we're going to get this props inside that search, Heather options, for example, here we can have
the.
All the props and we can get the title here, and we can just simply show it inside a paragraph saying
same to.
Now, we should say all images, we've got it.
The other things we want to pass is icon that this search icon and the images icon.
So we're going to get them from the hero icons first.
So we just import.
Search icon.
And also, we're going to import another icon called Photograph.
Photo.
Graph icon.
And this is coming from.
Here are icons for Sasha React forward slash.
Bottom line, this is not solid, this is utterly.
All right.
So we're going to pass this option as well, so the icon which we should pass it like a camel case because
this is all himself a component.
So the first one is the icon, a search icon.
And the second one, the icon is.
Photograph icon.
Let's get this information and show them.
So inside the search, Heather, option singular above the paragraph, the import, the iconic smell.
But first, we need to get the idea as a prop so we can get it here.
So much done.
If we got an error, but the.
Everything is fine, except we.
Here we search icon.
It didn't make it to capitalize.
Here, a small.
So now we've got these two icons.
Let's let's make them a little bit smaller.
Just adding a class name, the height of four.
So now we have everything.
Let's add more.
Props here, you've got the title, we've got the icon, but it didn't specify the selected mode yet,
as I mentioned before, we need to specify the selected based on the search type.
So in order to get the search, we need to use Raptor.
So first we import right after we return.
It is react, so we delete it, so we import a user after.
From.
And from next.
Forward slash, I think, or to.
Yeah, that's correct.
And then we will create a constant here and we call it route, which is equal to use USERADD, then
we just say, select this one.
Just make it selected if.
If the router that query.
That search time.
Is equal to an empty string.
Or we don't have any right.
We don't have any thing like that, anything, if you don't have around to that query, Dusters just
do to make this more selective.
So if someone, for example, comes and there will be no search type query, we still want to select
the all one.
All right.
So the next one is for the image, for the image we just selected.
Selected.
You get this auto suggestion selected, if this rather that query does such time is equal to image.
All right.
Simple as that.
And then we're going to style this one based on this selected.
So let's go to search.
Uh, let's start this fun first here at the top, so we bring them next to each other.
So here we add a class name.
We make this one flex.
So they come to next to each other, let's add some space between them using a space X of eight.
All right.
And let's.
I don't want this, someone can select this one because this is going to be annoying when someone is
clicking on this buttons.
So especially in the mobile screen, so we just change you select to none.
I mean, nobody can know nobody can get this.
Information.
Copy it.
So this is going to help some women in the especially in the mobile, when someone click doesn't selected
the text.
So are we going to make the width to be full?
And we can bring them the center using Amex Auto.
Or we just can say justify center, that's easier to justify.
Centre.
But let's change that.
Takes to be a small and we change the color to be gray as well, so just a text.
Gray.
And if he specified the.
Color to be seven hundred.
And the next thing that we can do is just.
In the larger screen.
Now in the largest scandal in the center, that is not beautiful, we want it to be here.
All right.
So.
We can change this for Manchester in the largest screen.
And change the.
Having left of 50 to.
But in order to see that, we knew we need to remove the Justify center.
Picking simply do that using large justify.
Justify start.
All right now in the larger screen, these pixels are here.
But when we have a smaller scheme like this.
It's smaller than large, we go to this center.
Let's add some border and a bottom, so we can.
Easily say border bottom.
Which is going to add one pixel at the bottom, you can see here.
Next, we need to install the the item itself, so we go to search his options here.
We bring them next to each other by changing the flags to be displayed to be flags.
Like this, and then we bring them to the center using items center.
No, they're next to each other and the space between the ticks and the icon using Space X.
I think one pixel would be fine.
It's just a space x one.
Then we add a border button.
For.
You can see here.
But we don't want to show the border now when we hover over them.
We want to see that, but the border, so we make it transparent as a default, so we just see a border.
Transparent, so we don't see the border, but stare.
But when someone hover over this elements.
And we want to first, we want to change to change the color of the text to be blue.
Five hundred.
Mark, this.
And we want the cursor to be pointer, so we just see cursor pointer.
So we can see a point.
And when we hover over the element.
Then we went to hover, we want a border that is transparent now to be blue.
Five hundred similar to the text.
So now we see the border.
All right.
The only things left is it's very close to the border at the bottom, so we can just add a padding bottom
of three, so add some space here.
And this is all right and here as well.
OK.
No, we just achieved this one when we hover over it, but you want to add this effect, it stays when
the when the option is selected.
For example, if the.
Search Typekit image if you want to select this one, then the search type is empty, you're going to
have this one.
He already has specified the selected rules here.
We just selected rules here.
But we can.
We can at the InStyle inside, but in order to make it like a variable, we need to change this.
To the back take.
So we changed this tactic.
The ad, the curly braces here.
And we add that.
Ternary operator here just said if it is selected.
Then.
It's not defined because we haven't imported yet as a prop service at the selected here to test this
selective.
Let me check here.
So have you got the selected and if the selected.
Is existed.
Yeah, we missed the E!
Selected.
All right.
If it's selected, we want to Pat's, we want the change to the color, to the blue.
The text color to be blue.
Five hundred.
And also, we want the border to be blue as far as just safe border blue.
Uh, five hundred.
No, he's selected to this one.
And if he.
Let me search something.
For example, hello.
Now we have the search of empty.
But if we aren't the image here.
And enter.
This option is selected, but this is just the from the default value.
But we want them to click on this one.
We wanted this one to be selected to so this ability, we can add it by just adding on click.
Here.
We just added, I click on this one and this there.
But this is going to call a function, we call this function select tab.
And this is going to pass.
The title, as far is just you want to know that what is the title here because we want to change the
route based on the title.
So let's create a function here, so we just function and rename the Functions Select tab.
And this is going to get the title as well.
And based under title is going to change thereafter.
But in order to change the writer, we need to import the use water.
So the import.
Use out her from.
Knicks forward slash router.
And we create the router here, so it's just a cast router is equal to use router.
And here we just see if we can, we just get the title here.
So we just see router that push.
And we create.
Push, not put.
Push.
And inside it back to we can make this well to go to this search page.
With the term.
With the term, which is equal to.
We can get the team as well, we can say rather.
That query.
Dr.
So we get the term here and also we can add the search type here.
Just say Alperstein.
Search.
Time and this is going to be equal to.
That we just say if to try to.
Is equal to images.
Because we are passing the.
Passing the title here.
We have to talk to us if the title is images we want to route to the.
We want to out to image.
And maybe you ask why the what's the difference?
Images or image?
But the Google API only understand image if you put images is going to gives us an error.
So images is not correct for calling the API later.
So because we need to call the API using the information that you are.
So now we just say images, otherwise an empty string.
All right.
So now.
Let's save this one.
We tested.
So it's this.
The reason we got the error is we calling this function all the time, even without clicking.
We need to create a function and return this select tap as a function.
So now if the.
Go to home page.
Administrative service getting very slow.
Yeah.
I go to the homepage.
Refresh the page.
Now we will go to the homepage and then the search for something like, hello.
This is going to change our URL to a term halo search time equal to just the empty strength, which
is choosing the all as a default.
But when we click on image, the search type changes to image and also this one is selected as well.
So, yeah, that is working perfectly.
The only thing left is just getting the results from the Google API, let's add everything to get her
for this options.
So we're just to get at.
They create her comments with the message.
Of.
The message is to create.
Search further.
Options.
Components.
And we push everything to get.
Let's check what we have done.
And let's refresh the page.
Now we have nine comments.
And the last one is create such better options components.
So we did we've done quite a lot in this section.
So we in this search for the Duchess.
We change this to we change this routine.
And we added this search type as well, which is empty for whip search.
And we did this one in the index that as far as we did to add to changes in index that year and also
to.
Search dogs, two inputs.
And we have this we create we created the search for the option of search options.
This search for options past the data to this search had an option like title.
And the icon and also the.
The ternary operator was selected, so the selected we just say if the search time is empty, just select
the first option, but if its image.
Choose the second one, which is the images option and the image in the images options.
We got that data as a prop inside the tide here, the time you've got the title icon and selected.
And based on this information.
We we created a.
It did, which includes an icon and a paragraph.
And we just say just a style it like this.
But if they select it, change the text, the blue and the border to blue.
Then we added an oncolytic function and click, which triggers a function called Select Tab.
And based on the title, we're going to change the route.
So the router that push is going to change the router to to the turn and also the search time, which
is.
It can be image or empty now.
That was it for this part in the next section.
We we're going to get the information from the API of Google.
So based on this URL that we have, which is which can be any terms or search type you're going to request
to the Google API.
And we just say based on this term and the search type gives us different information, as you can see
here, if you search for the search for the word hello and the choose the search type two image, we've
got the images data.
And if you click on all, we get the different types of data.
So it also also we're going to get these kind of data.
So how many search results and in how many seconds we got the information?
So in the next section, we're going to achieve this.
So see you in the next section.