All right, in the last section, we have created our server side function, and we got the information
from the TMD database by providing this URL and our specific genre.
Then we got this props and send it to the client side here, and we passed this data as a props to the
results that J.S..
All right, here, we map through all the result, and it just.
Shows the title, as you can see here.
So.
Let's run the server MP and Ron Dev.
Yeah.
Now we refresh the page, we should get the.
Yeah, just getting the trending now, then we get the top rated when we click on top rated.
If you if you look at the final version of the projects, we see that in the results section, we have
something like a car like here.
Which are actually.
Responsive.
So when they're small, they're they're in one column.
And then when they get bigger, they get two and finally three and four.
And when we are.
And in a very big screen, we have five columns.
All right.
And each of these things are something called.
He chopped down like this one.
Is a car.
So we're going to create a component called car, which includes the image.
Here, the image and this is the overview and we have the title.
And here we have three section to date.
And make changes.
Yeah, we have that date.
A like button like icon and also we have the, uh, the number of likes.
So let's first recreate the cart component.
We get all this data.
And finally, we we're going to make them responsive.
All right.
Let's go back to Visual Studio code.
And.
It create another component called car.
So here we click on this, create a card that yes.
And it create a component, a functional component using underlying RC, and we click on the first auto
suggestion and in the results, J.S. Heap instead of like showing the title.
Weakening, we're going to import this car.
First, using counter space being imported.
And we passed this result as a props.
Inside this car.
And here in the car, we can't get that one as a props.
So first, we're distracted and we just get the.
Results.
Yeah, now we can.
Just like before showing down.
Inside the head, each one to test tested, this is working.
So results are tighter.
All right, we are getting the same same results as before, but with the and other components.
Let's before forgetting.
We just go back to this attachés chase and the ad a key because this is a map, we should provide the
key and the key will be results that I.D. because each of these, uh.
Each of them, they have an idea.
Let's check them inside their console, in the console.
If you open the array, be getting and if you open one of the movies, we see each of them, they have
a unique I.D..
All right.
So we just use this unique idea as a key, so we don't get error later when we're deploying the website
to Verso.
All right, let's go back to Carter Chase and here first we get the image.
So we use the image.
Tag.
Of the next two years, the imported at the top.
And as you remember, we have three mandatory.
Attributes for image, which is SIRC c width and height.
So for SIRC.
This is going to be the results.
Dots.
Let's check it inside the console.
I show you in a second.
So.
It just right off first, so I'll start it.
Don't get error so we can get the array, so here.
If you open, one of them is see that we have a link to the J P T file.
This file is the path to the to the image of the movie.
All right.
So we just copy this back through our path and paste it here.
But this is just the slash.
Dot jpg.
But we need a base URL for this one.
The pace you are, l, we just put it here.
Let me just quickly grab it.
Uh, so we have a constant called base.
You are out and.
The base you are is just excited to be, yes.
Image Dustin be that -- forward slash t four slash p amphora slash original.
And after that, this beck tip is going to this backdrop past is going to give give us the image.
All right, so instead of just writing down this one at the base, you're out at the beginning.
And we just.
At this festival at the beginning of the backdrop path.
Now we are not getting error, but we are getting the same interview we were getting when we were making
the logo.
So we have to add this.
You are al to the count, to the next touches that next that conflict that yes.
So we copy this URL and we go to here to next that conflict.
Yes, and we add it here as the new domain.
All right, we saved the file and we need to restart the server because we are changing the config file,
so we just use contrasty.
And.
This clear it is and is just.
NPM run dev again to restore the server.
Now, we shouldn't get this error, but we are going getting another error for the high 10 with the
image because we haven't provided yet.
So we just add the width to be that is not important because we are making them responsible later.
So we just say with 200 and hide.
One hundred.
So we don't get error now, and we should get the images.
One by one.
So in order to instead of giving the width and height to be precise and calculated, we're going to
use something called layout in the image and we set it to be responsive.
So.
No, we should get the image into full size.
So we've gained the images of the.
Our.
Yeah, movies.
So this is for trending.
If you click on top rated, you should get the images for the top rated.
And as you as you are aware, the image tag inside the next year gives us the some lazy loading for
the images.
So when we go down, you see that the images under is not loaded yet, and this is going to help us
to have a very fast website.
As you can see, when we scroll down the new images loaded, otherwise we just have the images we have.
And also, if you go back, you see that the spider is here.
This this is going to this is something called catching in the next year.
So it's when the one time you go in it.
In a and we get an image, it's going to be a story somewhere like cash, so it's not going to get one
by one always.
But this cash has some limits.
So some of the images, estates and some of them loaded again.
All right.
So now we have the image, the next thing, as if you check the final version, we have the image,
we have the overview title and date.
And also we have some.
Icon and vote count.
So.
He go back.
Yeah.
So now we have let's get other things.
We put them in a death.
And the first things we're going to get is the result.
Dot overview.
Which is this one?
Each movie has an overview, but we don't want all the overview, we just want the first line of the
overview, so.
We just put this one inside paragraph.
And.
We can add a style to it.
They're using Tillmans assess truncates function of transit class to make this one in just one night.
All right.
Later, we're going to style all of them.
But first, you just finish getting all the data us.
So next one is we have an itch to.
Which is the title?
And you just say results.
The title.
So we're getting the title, but I want to show you that we not we're not getting all the titles in
some movies, they don't have a title, but they have title in a different way.
So if you go trending.
And to some movies like.
I mean, this movie doesn't have.
Results the title.
Or this one?
So let's open the console and check the array.
So I think it was seven, the seven one seven has a title.
Six, if six doesn't have a title, but it has something else called name.
All right.
So we can see if the result that title exists, show them otherwise show something else, which is results
dot net.
Let's check that we get all the titles or name.
Now we're getting the name here.
And not all the movies has a name or title.
All right.
Next thing we want to get is.
The date of release.
Let's check it again inside the council using if to.
So this array.
They have something called.
Release date.
Or some of them.
They don't have a release date, but they have.
Uh.
But yeah, they have.
And yet this one has.
I want to find something doesn't have a release date.
Yeah, this one doesn't have really the release date, but instead it has 1st air date, so we're going
to get either the release date or the first air date.
So we just say results don't release.
Dates or.
Result Dutch.
The.
First.
There.
Date.
If first air date and this should be fine.
So we are getting the.
Release date for.
Yeah, I think we are getting it for everyone.
Yeah, no, that's correct.
Let's get the.
This icon, the thumbs up icon, we're going to get this one from.
Hero icons.
So.
Let's import.
Yeah, some.
Up icon from hero icons, we're not getting it from solid, we get that font for artillery, we don't
want solid icons, OK, so we copy this and be.
After this date.
I'm going to get this.
Inside this paragraph, we get the Tom Tom soap icon.
OK, we're getting it.
This is huge.
So we quickly add this class name of height of five.
OK, after this, we need the vote counts, so we just the results.
That's.
Both.
Can't.
All right.
So we're getting everything.
Now that we need, but it's still not as styled in the next section, we're going to start styling the
current section and make it responsive.
So first, we just add this one to get half.
So we just take it.
At.
And we have can't come in.
So we created.
Create car components.
All right, and you push it to the guitar.
Let's shake it an overview of what we have done, so refresh it.
You go to commits.
And you go to creates cart component.
As you can see, we created a car that chase.
And we got the image, we imported the image from Nick's image, Tom Tom of Icon from Hero Icons, and
also we create the image and we've got the information for the overview title release date and also
the vote count and also in result that, yes, we remove the H1 and we added the card component and
also in next a conflict that as be at this year as the domain.
So we don't get any errors in the browser.
So in the next section, we're going to install this component and makes our website responsive.
So see in the next section.