All right, in the last section, we have finished with the story section, as you can see here.
He made a scrollable and also we removed the scroll bar using Tailwind the scrollbar plugin.
In this section, we're going to start with the post sections of the feed that yes, if you look at
the final version of the project and if you zoom out a little bit.
Let me draw for you the.
Things to be neat, uh.
All right.
So now we have a post here.
Which has the header at the top.
With the profile and the username, and the other side is the horizontal dots icon.
At a bottom we have.
The buttons.
Which is which includes the heart button, the comment, and also the save button.
Then we have the.
Uh, comment section.
Here.
And which shows all the comments, and also we have the the input for putting the comments, so I think
I ran out of the colors.
It's fine.
You can see it here.
All right.
So let's go to let's go back to our feet, which is let's create a component called.
Posts, Duchess.
And we use our sea to create react functional components.
And inside this post, we're going to have all the post.
And first, we need to create some data and then look through it.
I showed them in the post.
So let's bring this post inside the FT's Jeff imported here.
Using control space, we can all imported.
You can see it now at the top.
Inside the posts that U.S. posts that Duchess.
First, we need to create some data.
At the end, we are going to use databases like fireworks we're using inside this.
Inside here.
But now.
We just need to make some dummy data that we can use to create our UI and design it using Kelvin CSF.
And later, when we create our database, we can fetch the data, the fish, the data from the database
and just replace this dummy data with the real data.
So let's create some dummy datasets using.
I just created a constant call post, which is an array, but inside the array we have a couple of objects.
So the first one has the just say idea is one.
This is all just the made up information later.
As I said, we're going to get them real data from the database.
So we just create a username, for example, my, uh, Instagram I.D. code.
It's a hand and the user image.
I just use the same image I use for the header and the header, that genius I use, uh.
At the end, I use this on.
Data from the Skillshare, my profile so pasted here, we don't forget the comma at the end of each.
One and.
We have an image so you can see the final version, we have image and profile image.
So we have to bear in mind, have all of them.
So the image, we just get an image from a.
Website, for example, we can get from the.
Unsplash, that's come.
There are plenty of free images we can choose from.
Let's just add some.
And like any sort of image, would be fine.
This is fine.
Just copy the link.
We go back to Visual Studio code and we pasted you.
And in other things we have.
Is this caption section, so the caption also this is the comment that the owner of the post puts.
You can see here this picture.
So we have the.
Caption.
So.
We just say tanks or you.
Oh, yeah, it's just a
nice picture.
All right.
And then let's make this, uh, we copy this one using all chief.
Error, Don, I make you make it, too, so we can design it better.
So the second one, the username, I use my other username.
And the powerful image can be the same.
That's fine.
The image, which was another image from unsplash.com.
Let's just choose this one.
It replaced it.
And just say new.
New picture from my city.
All right, so now we have the all the data.
Also, don't forget to come out here as well, so we separate them from each other.
So now we have to use her to post inside our dummy posts.
And here we can look through it and show them inside and component.
So inside the return, we look through the posts using map function.
That gives us each post separately.
And we can return it.
With the new component, let's create a component, we call it post that, yes, we use RF C to create
the React functional component and here, uh.
We just put it inside here post.
We imported auto imported from post and first, the first things we need is just the key.
The post that it will be the key, so here we can say key calls, post that ID.
After that, we have.
The idea itself that is post-up, I'd.
You have username.
You just say user name equals the post, that username, as you can see the top nine, it suggests to
me very nicely and I don't need to try too much.
I highly recommend.
No, the first time you create the project maybe doesn't suggest you too much, but based on your coding.
And this API extension is going to suggest you for your for your next projects, you can code less and
less so.
We have user image.
Which is equal to post that.
User image.
Then we have IMT.
That's his image, the post image.
And finally, we have the caption which is post the caption.
All right, now, we pass the props through this component and we can get them here as a props, but
they can distract distracted.
Uh, distracted and like here, we just first we just say, uh, yeah, we can get all of them.
It's just the image, we get the user image.
I think it was user, I am G.
Yeah.
And let me see, use it.
I here.
We have captioned, we have user name
and uh.
The idea that's that's you just get the idea as well.
All right.
So here inside this return, we can just return.
Anything we like.
Let's just see the username first.
We see that it's working or not, so username.
Let's check our.
Yeah, we can.
We're getting the both the user names.
So it's working perfectly in the next section.
We're going to start with the.
If you check the final version.
We start with the header.
Header off the post, I mean, the profile image and also this icon.
So see you in the next.
First, let's uh, we all.
I always forget this.
Put this one in the gift shop, so we just take it AB and just get comments.
And this one is great.
Posts.
And post component.
And make.
Some dummy data.
This push it to the guitar.
And we check.
I think I close to get how so?
Let's go inside to my top.
All right.
In the repositories.
Instead, version four.
We have now nine comments, and the last one is create post and post components and make some dummy
data.
As you can see, we just created posters inside the feed that, yes, we had posted post component.
We created post as and we just show the username and in posts such as, we created some dummy data.
A post with two objects.
And we just returned it and look through the post using map function, and we passed all the information
as a props to the post component.
In the next section, as I mentioned, we going to create the header part of the post, so see in the
next section.