All right.
In the last section, we have achieved getting the data from the API and show it here inside the home
page.
In this section, we're going to add the.
Error message when something went wrong.
For example if the API doesn't respond or.
For example, if there is an error from the API, we don't the our website doesn't crash.
It just show an message saying something went wrong.
There is a very simple solution from the next.
Yes.
13.
So inside the next year 13, this app directory, we have this page that JSX, which is four.
The homepage, we can create another file.
And this one is called error.
That G6 and this file.
Is going to replace the error.
When error that happens, this file is going to render instead of this page that J6.
So this one should be client side as well, because we need to use the use effect from React.
So I need to create let's first create a React functional component.
And here at a top.
I changed this one to client component.
I just say use client.
And then.
We need to import.
And use the fact.
From React.
So we need to use it.
And also this file.
This one should be capitalized.
I change this on to this.
And this file is going to give us two things.
If you do structure here, this one gives us the error and also gives us something called reset.
So we can get catch the error.
If an error happens, we can console, log it and check it.
And the other things we need, we can do.
We can reset by, we can create a button and reset the fetching.
As well, for example, here.
First, let's do the use effect here so we create the use effect.
And this use effect is going to.
Firstly, console.log.
The error.
And also.
When an error happens, we are going to render this and console.log the error.
So this use effect is always checked.
If an error happens, it's going to.
Console.log for us.
And also let's create that message here.
So I'm going to create an H two tag or H one tag saying something went wrong.
So as you can see, we get the suggestion from.
Uh.
Get up, co-pilot.
So something went wrong?
I'm going to, uh.
And I'm going to add a button here.
The button is going to say, try again.
And when we click on the button.
So I'm going to add a click here.
When we click on the button, we want to call that reset function.
We just say reset.
You need to call this function.
Okay.
And let's see.
Let's see what we see here inside our website.
Now we get the result.
But if you purposefully, for example.
I changed the API key to a wrong one.
For example, I add a letter here.
So this is going to get an error.
We see this one in the development mode, but in the production you do you don't see this error here
at a bottom.
And this is saying something went wrong and try again.
If you click on try again, this is going to fetch another time.
So let's style this one first.
I'm going to bring this one to the center.
So let's go back to the G6 and bring it to the left side and let's close the left side as well.
So here inside the diff I want to add, I want to make this one and bring it to the center using text
center.
Now I want to add some margin at a top of.
Ten.
So we have some space here at a top.
And also when we hover over the button, I want to see a different color.
So I'm going to just say hover.
Change the text color to amber 600.
Like this.
Cook.
So now if we fix this API key.
And we click on Try Again.
We get the results.
So if the problem goes away so we can get the correct result.
So that was it for creating the error message.
So.
It's very simple.
You just need to get the error and reset.
You can console.log it for your reference and you just create a message.
Something went wrong and also you can create a button to reset it.
So let's add this one to GitHub as well so we can have a reference later.
So this message is going to be handled.
The error.
So let's commit and push it to GitHub.
So let me go to my GitHub IMDB.
So now we have nine commands and the last one is handled the error.
So we just created a file inside the app directory called Error dot JSX, which is client side because
we are using a hook here.
And also there is two reasons it's use client because it it is using use effect, which is a hook.
And also we are using on click.
If you're using any of them, you need to change the component to client side.
Okay.
That was it.
For this section.
In the next section, we're going to create the loading effect.
So I show you in the final version.
Let me go.
Go to the final version.
So when you go to the final version, when we click on trending, you see a loading effect, a spinner.
This happened very fast because the Internet is fast.
But if you have a slow Internet instead of waiting for the empty.
An empty page, you're going to see a spinner which makes a better user experience.
For our and the users that use our website.
So in the next section, we're going to work on the loading effect.