Hi,
it's Wojciech Lesniak again. In this module, we will look at persistent login.
You have probably seen the Remember me checkbox on many login pages.
This allows your users to stay signed in even after their session is closed,
and that saves them from having to reauthenticate the next time they access
the application. In a traditional application, this is quite simple to
implement with the REMEMBER_ME cookie; however,
in a distributed system, one that uses OAuth 2 with an authorization server, as
well as perhaps a social sign‑in provider added to the mix,
it can become a little bit more complicated as you now have to deal
with multiple sessions between multiple parties.
Then there is the access and ID tokens as you might need to access
stateless clients, and services, and APIs. Well, the access token
also has an expiry time or could be terminated at the auth server,
hence, in this module,
you will learn about the different strategies you can
use to implement persistent login. Let's start with Remember me.