Hi, it's Wojciech Lesniak.
Welcome to the final module on authorization.
In Spring Security, on the authentication token,
there is a collection called GrantedAuthority,
which, well, represents authorities granted to the user, plain and simple.
Spring traditionally had two types,
authorities and roles, both stored in this collection.
Authorities are your more fine‑grained authorization,
generally representing a single task, like,
for example,
portfolio:read or portfolio:write, and roles are
like containers for authorities.
So rather than individually assigning a new admin user with
all the authorities related to their role,
you can just assign them a role of admin,
which kind of represents that level of access.
Now, scopes come into play when you're dealing with OAuth,
which is for delegated authorization, so what a client
application can do or access on behalf of the user. OAuth 2
defines scopes as groupings of claims.
So if you look at the OpenID Connect specification for scopes,
you can see the logical groupings of claims about the user.
So rather than requesting each individual claim,
you can request a scope and get the related claims back.
You can also use scopes to define actions,
so portfolio:read would mean read access for a portfolio, and
portfolio:write could mean write access to a portfolio.
Now, the main difference between roles and scopes is that roles
are what privileges the user has and scopes are what the client
can access or do on the user's behalf.
So you could have a user that's an administrator in an application,
giving them authority to perform administrative functions, a client who
would hold an access token for this user,
and let's say the access token has the scope of user profile and email.
Now, this gives the client access to the user's profile
information and email address, that's it.
The client can't perform any admin functions on the user's behalf.
Now, they would need an access token with the correct
scopes allowing them to do that.
You can actually see this in Keycloak.
Scopes can be assigned to clients, whereas roles to users and not vice versa.
The GrantedAuthority collection, again, is effectively a list.
You will find that the roles are prefixed with capital ROLE_ and scopes
with capital SCOPE_, while authorities have no prefix. The prefixes are
basically like a namespace for the different types. Next, let's look at role‑based authorization.