Hi, it's Wojciech Lesniak again.
In the previous modules,
you learn how to add OAuth2 login into an existing application's authentication.
That was a lengthy module, and it didn't even include building
the user registration and form authentication.
That is another course in itself.
If you're interested, you can check out my previous course on how to do that.
But what if I told you that you can get all this done and
more with just a few lines of configuration?
Yeah, authentication without coding, and your
application's architecture will be more secure.
You can achieve all this by outsourcing your authentication to an identity
provider, known as an authorization server in the OAuth world.
When an unauthenticated user accesses your application,
your application will simply delegate authentication of that user
to the authorization server. The authorization server will then
notify your application of the result.
The auth server will handle all the heavy lifting, identity brokering
with SAML, Kerberos, user federation with OAuth and LDAP, or Active
Directory, or any custom user store that you use.
It will even handle social login with Facebook or Google for you,
not to mention user registration, management, you name it.
Now, from a security perspective,
all your user passwords, and authentication data, and code will be
isolated from your application, so any injection vulnerabilities
introduced by your development teams will not result in lists of users
and password hashes being sold on the dark web.
And as you add more applications and services,
you avoid having to duplicate authentication logic in every application.
So adding a new authentication requirement, like two‑factor authentication or
even biometrics in the future, will only be done in one place.
The trend also seems to be towards distributed
microservices‑style architectures,
which are polyglot in nature, hence this approach is perfect
for that environment as your application can be an OpenID
client of the authorization server,
making the interactions technologically agnostic, and you can have
dedicated security teams working on just this part.
I could go on, but I'm sure you get the point. Next, let's look at your options for an authorization server.