If you look at our controllers, such as the PortfolioQueryController,
when the user requests their portfolio,
the controller uses the following annotation to retrieve the
principal object in the method argument,
and Spring will map the principal object to it.
You can then use it to getUsername, the id,
or any other data you want about the user.
In this case, we get the username, and look up the portfolio for the user,
and return it; however, now there are three different ways of authenticating,
there's form login, OAuth 2, and OpenID Connect,
so this won't work as the CustomUserDetails object is for form login.
If we were to try to retrieve the portfolio for an oauth2User,
it will throw and null pointer as it will be a different type of object.
This is because when the authentication request goes through the filter chain,
it gets intercepted by an authentication filter.
Now, our application has two,
the UsernameAndPasswordAuthenticationFilter that deals with the
traditional form login and OAuth2LoginAuthenticationFilter,
which deals with the authorization requests sent back from the
authorization server to the following path.
And after the user is authenticated,
the filter places the AuthenticationToken in the security context object,
which is a thread local,
making it accessible in your application anywhere
in the same thread of execution.
You can get access to this authentication object and the principal within
it using the SecurityContextHolder in the following way,
and this is effectively what the AuthenticationPrincipal
annotation is doing for us and conveniently casting it to
the CustomUserDetails object.
If you just need the unique identifier for the user,
then you can just simply use the GetName method on the authentication object,
and this will work for all types; however,
if you need specific attributes,
then you need to cast the principal to the correct type.
This is where things can get messy.
Let's try and get the user's first and last name.
The principal object can be one of three types,
so first, check if it's an instance of CustomUserDetails for form login users,
and here, we can retrieve the name.
Next, we have to check if it's an OidcUser, and extract the name.
Finally, we can check if it's an oauth2User.
Now, our oauth2User is Facebook,
so we need to check the docs to find out the name of the fields.
Now, as you can see, this is quite messy,
so what I like to do is create a user principal interface for the
application with the getter and setters fields that we require,
and I also like to match the names as much as possible
to the OpenID Connect specification.
Then I can make the CustomUserDetails and FacebookUser
class implement this new interface.
For OpenID Connect, it's a little bit more complicated.
Let me explain why.
As stated before, there are many ways to authenticate,
so each way will have its own flavor of an authentication filter,
which knows how to intercept and pass that specific authentication request.
The filter will create an authentication request token.
At this stage, tokens are not authenticated.
An auth filter will then delegate the
authentication to the AuthenticationManager,
which, as the name suggests, manages authentication.
Now, there are many ways to authenticate.
In our application, we're using three ways,
form, username and password, OAuth 2 for Facebook,
and OpenID Connect for Google.
For each implementation,
Spring will configure an appropriate authentication provider
and add it to the AuthenticationManager.
The manager will simply delegate the authentication token to the
appropriate provider that deals with that type of authentication.
Now, in debug, you can see all these components,
the UsernameAndPassword and our OAuth2AuthenticationFilters.
Each have a reference to the AuthenticationManager,
which has three providers configured.
The OAuth2 and OpenID Connect providers will swap the
authorization code for an access token and then call the
/userinfo endpoint to retrieve the user's data,
while the form user details provider will retrieve this data from the database.
Now, the providers do this by using a user service,
which returns the principal object.
Now, after the user is authenticated,
a new authentication token is created with the
authenticated principal added to it.
That token will go up the chain and find its way to the security context.
The OidcUser service returns and OidcUser implementation.
We need to create our own version that implements this interface.
First, let's create a wrapper, CryptoOidcUser, that extends,
brings default implementation,
and now make this new wrapper implement our interface.
Next, we create a wrapper around the OidcUserService,
overriding the loadUser method.
This time,
we'll call the parent class' load user and wrap the OidcUser with our new class.
Finally, we can plug the OidcUserService via the OidcUserService login builder.
So now, each principal object will be of type CryptoPrincipal,
and we can extract the fields we require regardless of
which way the user was authenticated.
So let's also refactor our AuthenticationSuccessHandler.
There, much neater.
Again, you could also achieve something similar with using utility classes, etc.
You're probably starting to notice that things are
broken up into these endpoints.
The redirectionEndpoint, as the name suggests,
handles redirecting the user's browser to the
authorization server to authenticate the user and
authorize the client to access the user details,
the tokenEndpoint where the auth code can be exchanged for the access token,
and finally,
the /userinfo endpoint where the access token can be used
to access to user's protected resources.
Now,
all these endpoints are customizable via the builder in
the web security configuration adapter.
Next,
let's look at how we can customize the default configuration by adding additional scopes to the request.