Spring Boot conveniently configured some of the key OAuth2 providers
for us in the CommonOAuth2Provider enum; however,
it used some basic scopes, and these will probably not suffice.
Say you need the user's friend list from Facebook or their gender, then you can
override any of these settings in your application.yml file.
Let's try to get the user's friends, which according to Facebook documentation,
is the scope user_friends.
We just override the scope in our application.yml file.
If we try to log in with Facebook again,
Facebook now prompts the user that cryptoportfolio wants this new scope,
and if we approve the app getting our friends list. Notice
that we did not have to reauthenticate.
This is because we still have an active session with Facebook; however,
the user has not yet consented for cryptoportfolio to
have access to user_friends scope, so Facebook asks the user.
Most providers will keep track of previously approved scopes; however,
there is one alert,
which says that some of the permissions below have not
been approved for use by Facebook.
Basically,
the client, cryptoportfolio, is not approved to request user's friends
list even though the user has approved the access.
This is why OAuth2 is not exactly an authorization protocol.
It's a delegated authorization protocol.
The fact that the user consented to allow cryptoportfolio
access to their friends doesn't matter.
The client is still not authorized to access this data as Facebook has a
policy that new clients can only have access to limited scopes,
such as the user's public profile and email.
If they want more access,
then they will have to go through a vetting process with
Facebook and agree to certain terms and conditions on how
they're going to use that data.
So again, even though the user delegated authorization to the client,
the client still was not authorized to access the protected resource.
That's the difference between delegated authorization and authorization. Let's wrap this module up, next.