Welcome back to the final module in AWS Developer: The Big Picture.
In the last two modules,
we've covered 10 different services in AWS that you'll be using regularly.
In this module, we're going to look at how you'll be interacting with,
developing for, and monitoring those services.
We'll start by looking at the web console.
This will likely be your most commonly used interface to AWS.
You can do everything from spinning up new resources to configuring
and monitoring those resources with the web console.
Next, we'll look at the available software development kits supported by Amazon.
These kits are the main way you'll program your applications to interact
with services in AWS. And finally, we'll cover the AWS command line tool,
which can achieve most of the same operations as the web console, but in a
terminal capacity. Throughout the module,
I'll be showing you examples of each method.
But since this is still a big picture course,
we won't get too far into how you'll be using each.
This module will just give you a good overview that will help you understand how and when to use each method.