Traditionally,
a software application is a collection of compiled lines of code
delivered and running on a computer in front of you.
This used to be all there was, how it all worked.
With the introduction of the World Wide Web,
however,
a new paradigm emerged where software applications would run on a
different computer miles or continents away.
Users of said application would access it with the HTTP protocol
and interact with it through a web browser.
This is what we will call the web application.
Now let's imagine a scenario where our friend Lisa
is starting a new web startup.
She's got some shiny code, a real nice product,
and she's running the entire web application from a server
connected to the internet located in her closet.
As customers flock to Lisa's product,
she realizes her server in the closet isn't working out so well.
It's getting hot, stinking up her wardrobe, and starting to run slowly.
The overhead of her on‑premises hosting solution is hurting her business.
The difficulty in being flexible and scaling up quickly in response to
customer demands is costing her sales. Lisa's friend Gary works at a large
enterprise company, and there's very similar complaints.
His small team has to interact with a bureaucratic process to have virtual
machines provisioned every time they want to test out a new feature. Due
to overhead costs of each hardware instance,
he's forced to share a physical box with so many other teams that his
workflow is impacted and slows down development time.
But hey,
at least it gets him a lot of time for ping pong, right? Web
applications practically cry out for a different solution to solve
the many woes presented by on‑premises hosting.
Modern business won't wait for physical demands, and speed to
customer becomes a serious edge for competition.
The cloud industry began to provide a solution to small and large businesses
alike that needed an affordable and flexible way to serve web content to
customers. By abstracting away the physical hardware,
removing much of the configuration both virtually and geographically,
the cloud is able to get companies up and going quickly.
Most pricing models allow companies to pay for what they
use instead of a physical machine.
And as cloud service providers improved,
deploying an application to a new machine became as easy as a single click.
It's no surprise that the cloud grew as fast as it did.
It's especially popular with startups, enabling them to move quickly.
But enterprise companies are flocking to the cloud more and more.
Enterprise companies are finding a lot of value in the different
pricing model and the reduced liability when they don't have to
manage physical data centers. The cloud has truly solved the web application's biggest conundrum.