There was one more characteristic of AWS that I only
mentioned briefly in the last video,
mainly because I thought it deserved its own section. And that is the
ability to deploy to different global locations with AWS.
This is done as easily as scaling, just selecting a few different options while
deploying your application, and AWS takes care of the rest.
Why would you want to have your application deployed
in different parts of the world?
There are two common reasons that this is absolutely essential for any serious
web application, reducing latency and adding redundancy.
If your application is not a web application,
meaning users don't access it remotely via a browser or other protocol,
then latency is probably not as important.
But with users,
the latency or time it takes for requests to cover geographic
distance is one of the hardest challenges to overcome.
Latency with a web application is essentially the time it takes to get bits
from your server to the user's browser and vice versa.
The biggest contributor is the physical distance
between the server and the user.
And basically, the only way to reduce latency is to get
your web application closer to that user.
If you are self‑hosting, you would have next to zero control over that.
Well,
I guess you could drive around the world installing
servers in gas station bathrooms,
but I'm not sure that's a feasible growth strategy for your business.
The ability to have servers running in different parts of the world closer
to your customers is a huge advantage in this industry.
AWS has the most data servers and the most geographical areas of any
other cloud service provider that I could find.
That means that you can solve that latency problem best with AWS.
I thought this would be the perfect time to explain how AWS is
organized geographically speaking. AWS has many regions throughout
the world as roughly displayed on this map.
Regions are physical locations where certain services are hosted.
These regions increase often, and in 2016 alone,
AWS has announced they will launch 5 new regions,
bringing their total region count to 17. Usually, having a server
instance available in the same country or continent as the user
is a sufficient reduction to latency. Within each region, AWS
also has availability zones.
An availability zone is a collection of data centers that have
completely separate power, networking, and connectivity, but are
connected via hyperfast fiber optics.
This allows an availability zone to be extremely fault‑tolerant.
If someone forgets to pay the electric bill at one data center,
the others provide a redundant failover. By scaling your application
across several availability zones and/or regions, you can achieve
nearly unlimited uptime for your application.
Although there have been instances in the past where AWS
region connections have gone down,
there has not yet been a scenario where multiple
regions have gone down simultaneously.
It can be a little scary the thought of an AWS region going down and taking
your app with it, so let's talk a little bit more about that.
After all, this web application may be your livelihood, and
any loss of connection means customers can't access or
interact with your application.
AWS hosts a page showing both current service statuses across regions,
as well as status history at status.aws.amazon.com.
Looking over it, you'll be hard‑pressed to find a performance issue,
not to mention a connection issue.
Each AWS outage is a major news events since it impacts popular sites
like Netflix. And so far, in the past, there has not been more than
one per year lasting a few hours each.
Frankly, that's surprisingly good stability.
And with the option to easily host your application in multiple regions, I can't imagine a more trustworthy service to depend on.