We've reached the end of this module and this course on AWS.
Thanks so much for sticking with me through it.
I'm really hoping you've learned a lot about AWS and
are inspired to keep going with it.
Let's recap the AWS access methods that we covered in this module.
We first took a look at the web console. Depending on
what role you'll be playing with AWS,
this may be where you spend most of your time.
I seem to learn something new about the console every day
because there's just so much in there.
Next,
we looked at the software development kits supported by Amazon. With
these SDKs, you can do almost anything in AWS with your language of
choice. Using the code that Amazon provides,
you can interact with AWS services as if they were in your own application.
And finally,
we looked at the AWS CLI. Although the syntax can be a bit
more obtuse than the console or SDKs,
the tool really expands the possibilities of how you can manage and use AWS.
It's a welcome addition to Amazon's robust suite of tools
for working with AWS. And that's it.
There's so much more to learn with AWS, and Pluralsight has many,
many more courses available that can help you learn the
skills you need to work with AWS. Again, my name is Ryan Lewis, and I hope you enjoyed this course.