Well, we've wrapped up the four core services of AWS.
After this overview, I hope you have a better understanding of AWS as a whole.
These four services cover a lot of the essential functionality of AWS,
and I'd be surprised if you were using AWS and not using one of them.
Let's go back through the core services to recap what we learned.
First, we looked at Elastic Cloud Compute,
shortened to EC2, which is the computing platform on AWS.
By creating instances and selecting images,
you're able to run third‑party applications or your own code on a
scalable and affordable virtual machine in the cloud.
Next, we covered Simple Storage Service,
also called S3, which is Amazon's cloud storage service.
The uses are endless.
And with a very low bucket cost and subsecond responses,
it's a great place to store anything from static assets to file uploads.
The third service we covered was the Relational Database Service,
or RDS,
which enables you to select from several Amazon‑managed hosted database types.
The benefits to using a managed solution like this in regards to security,
resiliency, and convenience makes it a no brainer.
Finally, we took a look at Route53, Amazon's solution for DNS management.
Route53 is how you expose your AWS resources and instances to users,
and it interacts easily with other AWS services.
In the next module, we'll be continuing to look at services available in AWS.
These services aren't core services,
but will augment or be used in conjunction with the core services.
Elastic Beanstalk is an application service that will
take your application written in Java, Python,
Node, Ruby, or any other language and get it running on an EC2 instance.
Lambda is a service that allows you to run simple
functions and return the result.
Lambda functions can be invoked from many different sources and
can be written in many different languages.
DynamoDB is a managed database solution offered by Amazon that
is a little different than those in RDS. DynamoDB is a managed
NoSQL document database service and, due to being managed by Amazon,
offers many benefits over rolling your own solution.
Virtual Private Cloud is a service enabling you to control access
and secure your instances and services in AWS.
It's used by almost every service in AWS,
and it's the best way to ensure that your data and application is safe.
CloudFront is a CDN service available from AWS, and it enables you to
edge your files so users can get to them super fast.
It can be used in conjunction with S3 as mentioned previously or
with a web application behind a load balancer.
CloudWatch is a logging and alarm service used with
almost every AWS service available.
You can set up alarms to let you know when instances are down, EC2 CPU is
high, or when S3 charges reach a threshold, for some examples. There's
any number of things you can do with CloudWatch. Once we've covered these
extended services in AWS, we'll have touched on all the services we'll
cover in this course.
AWS has over 165 available services as of right now.
So we're really only looking at the tip of the iceberg. Still, we're
covering the most commonly used services, so you'll have a solid
understanding of the majority of what AWS has to offer. I'll see you in the next module.