[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
My name is _______ was Callie will come to my court
managing and monitoring access to AWS.
I'm a senior network and cloud architect.
In this course,
we're going to explore tools and best practices to securely at the minister.
Access to AWS results is some of the major topics that we will covert include
locking down the route user with multi factor authentication,
deep dive with AWS authorization framework and I am policies
managing access to external applications with AWS cognito
monitoring access to AWS resources with cloud trail.
By the end of discourse,
you'll know how to properly manage AWS Kevin Great account according to a
well defined set off Amazon guidelines and best practices.
Moreover,
you'll be able to grant access to AWS reduces in a very granular and
efficient way in a way to win jobs scenario involved in cross account
results to share in external users and authentication with social identity
providers before beginning of discourse.
You should be familiar with AWS foundations in terms off the main
tools Dashboard and Seelye and the main services.
Consider also that having a basic knowledge of rest full AP I fight on and
JSM topic will help you to easily tackle the material,
I hope youll joining me on this journey to learn Amazon web services with the managing and monitoring access to AWS.