[Autogenerated] let me introduce one off the most important AWS service
we're going to explore across this course AWS I am,
which means identity and access management.
Let's go for the definition first AWS Identity and Access Management
is a Web service that helps you securely control.
Access to AWS results is you can use I am to control who is a syndicated,
stagnant in and authorized has permission to use the results is in simple words.
This is the cornerstone off AWS cloud environment,
since it provides a set of tools to verify identity of
users and to provide privileges to access resorts is let me
provide a quick review of AWS.
I am Yes,
I am provide a septal tools to manage authentication and
authorization in a very granular way.
This is done by means of the following objects.
Users are the entities created across your AWS account,
which requires interaction with AWS resources groups
is a collection of users heaven.
The same privileges rolls identity objects with permission, roles.
The rule do not have any credentials,
so the role has to be always associated with an identity and
finally we have policies which are objects which the fine
permission and that can be applied that the users groups are
roles By leveraging on these objects,
AWS I am can be configured the to shared access to your AWS
account by granting other people permission to the minister and
use of resources in your AWS account without having to share your
own password or access key.
You can grant different permission to different people for different resources.
For example,
you might allow some users complete access to Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud,
Amazon Simple storage service,
Amazon Dynamodb or Amazon Red Shift or whichever aws services you can use.
I am features to securely provide credential for
application that run on easy two instances.
AWS I am is totally an easily integrated with all a doubly as resources,
making easy to enforce access policy on all your AWS services.
And finally aws I am is free to use so you will never be charged
for how many users or policy you are creating.
Everything in AWS environment starts with someone
creating a brand new AWS account.
The county is associated with a root user.
This route user is a unique user,
with the following the rooty user as super user privileges.
Basically,
the root user has the privileges to do everything with every AWS resources.
Root user is always associated to a mail address into a
created card for building purposes.
On the route to user is the entry point to bootstrap your AWS account.
Please note that you can have multiple free normal users,
also called I Am users, according to AWS terminology.
But there is only one route user.
Now let me introduce AWS best practices,
which explained how to securely handle the root user.
First associate,
the root user with the multi factor authentication to
prevent the credential stealing.
If someone can steal root user credential is able to do
everything with your AWS resorts.
Is someone could boot 1000 easy to machine and guess who is paying for these?
And worst,
someone could also prevent you from accessing the account to fix the issue.
Second, delete the access key associate ID by default to the root user,
and this can be even more dangerous if your access key are stolen,
someone could programmatically user Seelye ap I or even sdk against your AWS
account with full access to your resources ____ create.
I am users and groups to operate the your AWS resources.
Never, never,
never used root user to manage your AWS resources and
fourth established a policy for password.
Standard policy continues the minimum land,
special characters and expiration time. Let's now run a couple of them or to see AWS guidelines or inactions.