[Autogenerated] in this section,
we will cover a special class off policies associate
ID to s three and s three glass, your services,
lifecycle policies and the Volt lock policies.
Let me start with a street as usual.
Let me go for the definition first and as three lifecycle
configuration is a set of rules that the fine actions that
Amazon s three applies to a group of objects.
There are two types of actions expiration actions which defines
when objects expire in transition actions defining when objects
transition to another storage class.
Now the exploration part sounds very clear,
implying a scheduled election off objects by means of a policy.
The transition part can be more obscure.
Transition to what?
Let me try to clarify.
Let me recap the different classes off s tree storage.
We have standard as three storage the bark.
It's that we have used the so far as three standard infrequent access.
You pay less for storing, but pay a feat with reviewer that a street standard,
infrequent access one availability zone.
You pay less for starting you pay a fee to retrieve data
and the services as less availability.
A street glassy,
which is currently there archive with the lower cost but high latency to
retrieve your data and finally as three glassy deeper five,
which has the lowest cost and the highest late.
And see going from Howard's two days to have your data back.
Now it is clear what life cycle policies are about there
about saving money by moving data on the basis on the
importance off the different data sets.
Let me show how to implement a lifecycle policy.
The scenario is very simple.
Has a global Mantex idea Administrator.
You must ensure lower usage costs off yours three boxes.
My taking into account the relevance of the data and how
much frequently they are accessed.
Your task is to create the for living a rule Move all objects in the
develop folder to AWS glassy after seven days,
let me go to s tree service dashboard and let's move to our target Back it.
We have already our develop folders in place.
The here Now we move to management and let's create a lifecycle policy.
Let me provide proper name.
We specified the folder or perfect where the policy applies in the drop
down menu with specify our target as three storage class.
We acknowledge that we will incur in additional cost.
Now we move all versions to glassy storage as well.
We leave the expiration policy as it is and done.
The rule is created.
This was very simple.
Now let's move to the next.
The topic.
Glassy volt lock policies.
A ST Lucie Volt look allows you to easily deploy and then fourth compliments
Control for individual s tree glass evils with a volt lock policy a ST Lucie
and forces the control set in a vault Look,
policy toe help achieve your competence objectives.
For example, For data retention, we have the following scenario.
As an 80 administrator of global Mantex,
you are asked to ensure that your archived the data are
compliments with SEC Rule 17 a four F,
which dictates a retention period of one here for your data.
Your task is to create a volt lock policy to forbid
objects election before one here.
This kind of policy is also known as W O R m Write.
Once, read many.
Let us start with the glazier a dashboard.
We create a new vote with a meaningful name.
Let us use the full value and keep notification disabled for the moment.
As you can see, the Volt is set up in Frankfort region and done.
The vault is created.
Now let us create a volt lock policy.
We add permissions.
We specify a principal Ellis in this case will feed just for them a purposes.
We specified that the action delete archive is denied and the other
condition which says that the dis applies within one year from the
uploading off that specific archive.
When we initiate the vault lock policy, As you can see,
we are provided with Bolt i d.
Let's take note of it.
Finally, we complete the world lock policy.
We provide the Devote i d.
And once we acknowledge our vault lock policy is created and cannot be deleted.
A list can upload archives to this glacier vote,
but cannot delete any file until the archive has
been stored in the vault for one. Here