[Autogenerated] Now that we are at the end of this module,
let me finally rip up all the topics we have discussed so far in
this model we have explored AWS I am policies,
objects which provides a set of tools to regulate access to
AWS resources in a very granular way.
Remember, with the policy,
you can see who does Watson given a set of conditions and most important,
the policy are perfectly coupled with AWS resources,
meaning that you have proper semantics to build the policy.
Taylor, the toe well defined the results is off a specific AWS a service.
Finally,
it is worth observing that aws I am policy are able to
possibly cover near all use cases that you can find one working in real world aws cloud environment.