Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
The second big step of this implementation we have already created one brain.
The brain of the generator.
And now we're about to create the second brain of our deep convolutional Ganns.
I'm talking of course about the brain of the discriminator and we're going to proceed exactly the same
way as we proceeded for the generator.
We're first going to define a class that will define the architecture of the neural network for the
discriminator.
Then this class will also include a forward function to forward propagate the signal inside this new
network.
And then once the class is made we'll create a discriminator object that is will create the brain of
the discriminator.
So let's do this let's tackle the second big step of our deep convolutional gets.
So we are starting with Class Of course then we need to give a name to this new class that will define
the discriminator.
And since we called the class of our generated G We're going to call this one the thing that makes sense.
And so d again is going to inherit from the end in module and so inside we use again and then that module.
All right then Kallen and then we go inside the class to start with the init function that will define
the architecture of the neural network.
So that's the same we start with Def and then double underscore in it that will underscore again and
some parenthesis.
And inside we only put self which will refer to the future instances of our class that will be created.
That is the object and that will allow us to associate the specific variables that are attached to the
object that is I'm talking about the properties of the object.
The object will be the neural network of discriminator.
So these properties and variables will be the different modules composing the architecture of the discriminator.
All right so now Collen we go inside the function and same we start by activating the inheritance using
the super function which takes as arguments are discriminator class and our object self.
Then don't forget we had a done here double underscore in it double underscore again.
And some parenthesis.
Perfect inheritance activated all right and now things are going to get interesting.
I'm going to try to make you guess what we're going to start with.
We have to start with the first module of this architecture of the neural network of the discriminator.
And so according to you what is going to be this first module is it going to be an inverse convolution
like before or is it going to be a convolution or is it going to be a fool connection.
Well think about this for a second.
And until then I will get my main again which represents the metal module that will contain the different
modules composing the architecture of the neural network.
So exactly like before.
So cells that main and this module will be a big sequence of layers.
That is a big sequence of modules.
And therefore I'm setting this main metal module to be an object of the.
And in that sequential class parenthesis.
And here we go.
Let's see if you got this right.
For this first module of this architecture.
Let's see.
All right so to answer this question right.
Well we need to understand what the discriminator is going to do.
It's going to take as inputs a generated image coming from the generator and return as output a discriminating
number which will be of value between 0 and 1.
Therefore since it takes as inputs a generated image the generated image created by the generator.
Well that means it takes as input an image and therefore the first module of our architecture is simply
going to be a convolution not an inverse convolution.
That's only for the generator.
But this time a convolution it's going to take as input an image an image created by the generator and
through the convolution.
And then of course some more convolutions we will get in the end a simple vector of one element that
will contain the discriminating number a value between 0 and 1.
So there we go.
You have the idea and now it's going to be the same as before.
We're going to add a series of different convolutions with different parameters and will best the feature
maps.
And of course we'll apply some rectification.
And we'll let you find out about some surprise regarding the rectification.
It's not going to be a real it's going to be something a little more sophisticated.
We will see that in one or two minutes.
But let's start with our first module that is our convolution.
So to get this first module we're going to create a new object of the comp to the class and therefore
I'm taking my and then module that and then I'm getting the code to the class.
Here it is perfect.
There is now something less easy.
The parameters of this convert to the class.
So it's actually not that hard and I'm going to give you something else to get what do you think is
going to be the parameter we have to improve here.
For the first argument of this comes to the class.
Remember that corresponds to in channels that is the dimensions of the inputs.
So as we just said the input of our discriminator and therefore of this first module that is the conclusion
is an image an image created by the generator.
So to answer the question what is going to be the inputs of this first convolution.
We simply need to look at the output of the generator and the output of the generator.
Remember is these three channels here of the image.
So the input of our discriminator is nothing else than three to three channels of the generated image
created by the generator.
Perfect.
And then it's going to be the same.
We're going to specify a number of feature maps kernel size astride a padding and choosing true or false
for the bias.
So here we go let's do it.
We're going to choose 64 feature maps then a size of 4 for the Colonel's so.
So these are going to be squares of size four by four then astride of 2 and abetting of one.
And eventually Last but not least we choose to have no bias and therefore like before I'm choosing by
as equals force.
All right.
First Mudgal done congratulations.
Now second module What do you think the second.
Well operation is going to be we're not going to apply a budget yet.
We will leave that for the next convolution.
However we always need to apply rectification and that's the surprise I wanted to keep from you but
I'll tell you it right now we're not going to use a rectifier activation function.
We're not going to use the release function.
We're going to use a leaky reglue.
So what I'm going to do now I'm going to go to Google
here is Google.
And here is the leaky really leaky Leakey who is very close to the loo.
But besides having the max of zero and X which actually is the formula for the reglue we have this addition
of the negative slope multiplied by the men of zero and x.
So that's a slight change in the formula.
And if you put that into a graph you can see the difference.
There really is a horizontal line equal to zero here for the negative values of x and then the straight
line y equals x y for the leak.
We have this slight change here which gives some negative values for the negative values of x.
So that's the slight difference.
I thought it was good to show you this and now why do we choose to use a leaky review instead of a clue.
Well again that's an artist's job.
It comes from experimentation and research basically for the convolutions of the discriminator.
It works better with the leaky reglue than a simple really.
So I'm getting back to by then.
And therefore if you all agree with the leaky Renu Let's apply a leaky really.
So to a player like you we take our end in Mudgal and then that and then we will find very easily the
like really.
Here it is.
And we need to put several arguments of course the negative slope and we'll choose not 0 point zero
one but 0 point two.
Again a value chosen from experimentation and research.
So 0.2.
And then we have a second argument in place because false but why not set the value of in place to false
will set it to true again if we go back to the PI torch stuck documentation by the way yes this is the
PI torch documentation that I highly recommend to go through while watching the tutorials or even any
time.
That's a great documentation it's very clear.
And so if we look at this second argument in place well you can see that's an argument that if set to
true can actually do the operation in place the default value is false.
But we chose to set it to true to benefit from this option.
All right.
So let's go back to Python.
There we are and we are done now with the leaky well.
All right.
Let's not forget the comma and let's move on to the next module.
So the next module is going to be another convolution.
Rest assured we'll get many convolutions as we got many inversed convolutions.
So we have a long way to go before making the architecture.
So let's do it let's add the second convolution and then that comes to the third is.
And let's specify the arguments.
So now you understand clearly the logic the input of this new convolution is the output of the previous
convolution and therefore it is going to be the 64 feature maps.
And now we need to choose a now output.
So since it's actually the inverse operation as the previous one which was inverse convolution.
Well this time we're not going to reduce the number of feature maps each time for each new convolution
as you might have guessed we're going to do the exact opposite.
We are going to increase.
And more specifically multiply by 2 the number of feature maps in each new convolution.
Therefore the size of outputs here that is the new number of feature maps we're getting as the output
of this convolution is going to be one hundred and twenty years.
There we go.
I think now you can almost finish it yourself but we'll never know.
Please stay with me.
Then we're going to choose a size of four for the kernel strive to a padding of one and no bias bicycle's
false right.
Second convolution done.
Perfect.
Next step next step.
As I just gave you a hint is to apply a batch normalization to batched normalize each of the 128 new
feature maps and so that's exactly the same as before.
We're going to take our end in Mudgal than dirt and then we're going to apply a batch norm to D.
And since we're Bache normalizing the 128 feature maps will be exactly two inputs.
One hundred and 28 exactly like before.
No new mystery come the next step.
All right.
Now that's going to be the same we're going to apply a new leaky reglue.
So I'm copying this.
I am pasting it right here.
And good news.
We have the exact same arguments.
We don't have to replace anything.
We choose a slope of 0.2 and in place.
Next step the next step.
As you might guess and I strongly recommend this game to try to type the next module in the architecture
before me the next module is going to be end that and a new convolution of course comes to the parenthesis.
And now of course you guess what we're going to input and what we're going to output.
We're going to input what was output by the previous convolution which was 128 feature maps.
That becomes the new input of this new convolution and for the output Well we increase this time.
The number of feature maps multiplied by two.
So we're going to get the new output of two hundred and fifty six feature maps are right.
And then again we choose a kernel of size 4 as tried to and a padding of one and again no absolutely
no bias bicycle's false perfect come up.
Next step the next step is to guess what well to apply a budget normalization.
So we take our N and module that batch norm to D.
And as arguments we are going to input the number of new feature maps that we got and that we want to
batch normalize.
And since what we've got is 256 new feature maps.
Well we're going to input here 256 to batch normalize these new 256 feature maps perfect next step the
leaky renew again.
So in that leaky reglue there it is.
And that's the same I don't know why I'm typing this again.
I just need to copy and paste it and there we go.
Now another convolution again.
So this time let's not miss it and copy this copy.
Based So this time we have 256 feature maps for the input and we double it for the output.
So we get five hundred and twelve new feature maps in the output of this new convolution and then same
kernel size for a stride of two and a pairing of 1 and No bias.
Great then our batched on again and copying this.
I'm basing it just below.
I am not forgetting to replace the 256 previous feature maps by the new 512 new feature maps that we
have to batch norm.
Then we apply our leaky reglue with the same parameters.
So I just need to copy this pasted here.
I hope you are doing all this faster than me.
All right then almost over.
We have one final convolution to add.
This is the last one and pasting it here.
And so we're going to get now 512 feature maps of the input and now the question is since this is the
last convolution what is going to be the output.
Please don't answer 1024.
We're done with the convolutions here.
We stop playing the game of doubling the feature maps.
No this time we have to specify the final output.
Therefore the discriminator.
And so if you understood the role of the discriminator you should be able to guess the output here.
Well I'm going to tell you right now it is actually one.
One.
That's because the discriminator is returning a discriminating number and number between 0 and 1.
So that's a simple vector of one dimension containing this number and therefore that's why we have a
1 here and then just a little trap you can not really guess that but we're going to keep a curl size
of 4 but then we're going to choose a stride of one and a padding of 0 and then that is the same no
bias.
All right we're almost done.
We have one final thing to do for this architecture.
If you look at what we did for the generator.
Well you can see that after the last inverse convolution.
Well we applied an activation function again to break the new narrative and we going to do the same
for the discriminator.
But this time it's not going to be a hyperbolic tangent.
According to you what is it going to be.
It's actually a very classic activation function to use at the end of a neural network.
It is the sigmoid function and if you went deep into the theory of the deep convolutional Ganns and
especially the part related to the discriminator.
Well you would understand that the sigmoid function is the best choice because it returns some values
between 0 and 1 and for the discriminator we actually want to be between 0 and 1.
Why is that.
Well the answer of that question is in the name of the discriminator it's for discriminating reason.
The principle of the discriminator is that zero corresponds to the rejection of the image and one corresponds
to the acceptance of the image.
So 0 means we reject the image and one means we accept the image.
Therefore the name discriminator and so basically we want to be between 0 and 1 to do some discrimination.
And that's why the output is actually a value between 0 and 1.
Because then using classic threshold technique well for the values below 0.5 we will consider it as
zeros who will reject the image and put the values above 0.5.
We will consider it as one and we will accept the image.
So that's very important to understand and therefore the sigmoid function that not only break down in
the area but also returns a value between 0 and 1 is the optimal choice for the activation function
at the level of the output of the discriminator.
All right so if you're convinced we're going to get R and then module and then that and then we get
our sigmoid activation function.
So it's an object of the sigmoid class which will represent the sigmoid activation function itself and
we don't have any argument to input.
So congratulations you are done with the architecture of the second brain.
You have to create for this sequence.
So now are DC again had the two brains.
Let's make the forward function to propagate the signal inside the second brain.
We'll make it in the next tutorial and until then enjoy computer vision.