Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
All right now things are going to get slightly more difficult.
We're going to get into the heart of that as is immoral.
So make sure you understand this model first.
I highly recommend to watch Carol's intuition lectures first.
So if that's the case and you're ready to go and you're all fresh let's tackle this.
So first of all let's remind the context we got the output of the neural network SSD which is why.
And then from this output why we extracted the important informations that we need and we extract them
in this detections variable which is a tensor by taking the data of Y which corresponds to the tensor
part of the torch variable.
Remember the torch marble is composed of two elements a torched answer and a gradient.
And by taking the data attribute of the output Y which is a variable.
Well we get the first element of this torche variable which is the torch tensor.
And now we're going to see what this tensor contains exactly.
So what is this information exactly.
What is this detections tensor and what does it contain.
So this detection sensor I'm going to try to come in here to make sure everybody understands this detections
tensor right now contains four elements.
So I'm going to put them into brackets.
The first element is the Bachche because we created this fake dimension of the batch with this and squeeze
function here.
So the first element of this detections tensor is this batch.
So I know I told you about a batch of inputs but that's the same for the output.
We also have batch of outputs associated to the same batch of inputs.
That is the batch of inputs contains several inputs.
Of these inputs we get the outputs and these upwards are all into about and that's where this first
element of detections is you can write sections here detections equal.
All right.
So for us Almont the batch.
Now the second element is the number of classes.
So what do I mean by classes.
I simply mean the objects that can be detected.
So for example one class will be the dog.
Another class will be the plane.
Another class will be there but another class will be the car.
So each class corresponds to each object that can be detected.
And the second element of this detection sensor is the number of classes that is the number of objects
that was detected in the input image.
So a number of classes and now the third element is the number of occupants of the class.
I'm going to write it down number of utterance of the class.
So what does it mean.
Well it means that for example for Class Number two the class number two which let's say a response
to the dog.
Well the number of arguments will be the number of the utterance of the dog.
So in the video of the funny dog that we watched in the first title of this module there was one dog.
But imagine there are several dogs to detect in the video.
Let's say there are two dogs.
Well we would have two numbers of occupants.
The first occupants of the dog that is the first dog on the video and the second argument of the dog
corresponding to the second dog in the video.
So we would have the actor in zero and the occupants won.
But in the video we only have one dog.
So we will only have one number of utterance when accurate.
All right so that's the third element of this detection sensor and the fourth element will be a couple.
It's up all of five elements.
So I'm going to write them now or we will get crazy.
This is a couple of the following five elements.
First Ullman's is the score.
Second element is x 0 third element is y zero then fourth element is X.
And the last element is why when and why does this double the belt.
Well for each occurrence of each class in the batch we will get a score for this argument.
And of course the coordinates of the upper left corner of the rectangle defect in the end and the lower
right corner.
And what are these scores about.
Well these scores are going to go from low to high.
We will have a score for each arguments of each class such that if the score is lower than 0.6 then
the arguments of the class won't be found in the image if it is higher than 0.6 then it will consider
it to be found.
So that's what this course is about.
It's like a threshold for each occupants of each class.
We will get a score if it is more than 0.6 then no arguments will be found.
And if this course hadn't 0.6 the arguments will be found and we will get the coordinates and the upper
left corner and the lower right corner of the detected object.
All right so now that we clearly understand what's inside the detections tensor we can move on to a
for loop.
Yes there we go we have to make a follow because we have to iterate through all the classes and then
through all the arguments of the classes we're going to look for a certain number of occupancies for
each class.
We're going to get the score for each of these other answers and we'll make an IF condition to say that
if discours had an open six we keep the utterance and if the score is lower than 0.6 we reject the accurate.
All right.
Are you ready.
Perfect.
So let's start this for you.
So for then as I just said we're going to iterate through all the classes and therefore I'm going to
add here.
I for I in range detections that size 1.
So detections that size one is exactly the number of classes.
So this that I highlighted is the number of classes so we're just making a full loop from 0 to this
number of classes.
There is a number of detectable object.
And so for all these classes we're going to go inside the for loop and we're going to start by introducing
the variable J which will correspond to the utterance exactly the utterance.
So why is the class and j will be the utterance of the class.
And now we're going to start a second loop not a fluke this time it's going to be a while loop because
you know we're going to put that condition into the loop which is actually more efficient.
So it's like a loop combined with the if condition at the same time.
And the trick to do that you're going to see is very intuitive is to do this well loop.
And since we only want to keep the occupancies for which the score is higher than 0.6.
Well we simply need to take the detections of the utterance J of the class I.
But then let's not forget the Bache zero zero and then we're going to get the score which is the first
element of this double here.
So we simply need to add zero therefore since zero corresponds here to the index of the score Jaker
response to the index of the occupants of the class I.
Well this detections of 0 0 is exactly the score of the occurrence J of the class.
And therefore Well the score of the current state of the class is larger than 0.6 than what are we going
to do.
We're going to keep this accurate and how are we going to keep it.
Well we are going to keep it in the variable that we're going to call Peetie for point because we're
going to keep that argument by keeping the point and therefore the coordinates of the upper left corner
and the lower right corner of the rectangle detecting arguments J.
The class II.
So Peetie will be the detections and we're going to take the same is zero.
That is the Bache then the class II then the arguments J and then be careful try to guess what I'm going
to type here.
Well it's not going to be zero because we're no longer interested in the score.
We are now interested in these four coordinates.
Exit row 1 0.
That is the coordinates of the upper left corner of the rectangle and X one y one that is the coordinates
of the lower right corner of the rectangle.
And therefore we want to take the last four elements of this table.
And so we're going to take the range from one to the end and the trick to take the range from one to
the end is to use this the range from one colon and nothing and nothing means to the end.
Perfect.
So here with this trick we're taking X you are wise you are x 1 and white 1.
So now we have our coordinates.
That's perfect.
But now remember that we created this scale tensor to do this normalization of the coordinates between
0 and 1.
And that's exactly where we're going to use the scale tensor and to use it we simply need to multiply
all this by this scale tensor and that will apply to normalization which will give us the coordinates
of these points at the scale of the image.
And finally we need to do one last thing we need to transform this tensor for coordinates that is all
this you know all this is a tensor right now it's a torch tensor.
Well since now we're going to use open Svea to draw the rectangles thanks to the upper left corner and
the lower right corner coordinates that we have.
Well we need to put that back into an umpire.
Because open sea works with an array.
We're going to use the rectangle function you know to draw the rectangles exactly like what we did in
the first module but this rectangle function works only with non-pay arrays and not with torch tensors.
So we just need to convert that back into an umpire.
And to do this there is nothing more simple.
We just used a pi function like that.
And here we go we have Arnon by Array containing the four normalized coordinates of the upper left corner
and the lower right corner of the occurrence J of the class.
And now since we have these coordinates Well we can draw the rectangle we're going to do that still
in the well loop obviously.
And you know how to do that.
We take open city CB2 then the rectangle function and remember the arguments we first need to input
frame the image.
Then the second argument is zero.
And that is Peachi of index 0 because pittie contains x 0 1 0 X Y N Y one.
So PITI 0 will be zero.
Then the third argument to be y 0 and that is P-T 1.
Then the next argument is x 1 and that is Peachi to and the last one is why one.
And that is P-T three because zero pity one 52 and three are exactly these four coordinates in the same
or x y z x y y y.
And now we're just going to add a safety.
We're going to convert these values of the coordinates into integers.
It's always safer to do that and to do this we're going to use the int function to convert them int
int
and and now be careful.
The second argument of this rectangle function from open city is actually the coordinates of the upper
left corner of the rectangle.
So these two coordinates here should go into the same second argument.
So I'm going to put some parentheses around these two coordinates and same for these two coordinates
that should go into one same argument.
That's the third argument of the rectangle function and these correspond of course to the coordinates
of the lower right corner of the rectangle that is detecting the object.
So again I'm putting some parenthesis around them.
All right so first argument frame second argument the coordinates of the upper left corner.
And third argument the coordinates of the lower right corner of the detector rectangle.
Now next argument there is two more arguments to go the next one is the color of the rectangle.
And we're going to choose the red color that is coded in the RGV code by 255 0 0.
All right so that's our next argument.
And now the final arguments of our rectangle function is.
Remember the thickness of the text to display and as in the Mudgal one we're going to choose to.
All good.
And now let's move on to the next step which is to print the label onto the rectangle because we will
have several objects to detect.
So we want to print the label Doug onto the rectangle that is detecting the drug and then the label
person onto the rectangle that is detecting the person.
So it's indeed quite useful to print a label so to print these labels we're going to use open city again
CB2 and then we're going to use another function.
You can see that open city has many functions but the function we want right now is called put text.
There we go.
This one put text and this function takes several arguments.
Not exactly the same as a rectangle function but pretty close.
The first one is of course our frame.
The second one is the text to display and to get this text we need to use the label map shortcut name
that we gave to classes remember what lessors is this dictionary that maps the names of the classes
with numbers and we can get the label of the text we're interested in.
That is the class we're dealing with right now which is a Class I.
Well we get the index I minus one y minus one it's because indexes in Python started 0.
So the index minus one is actually the index of the ice class.
All right.
And then a third argument will be the position of the text where we want to display the label.
And we're going to display it at the upper left corner of the rectangle just above the upper left corner
and therefore we need to take these coordinates because they correspond exactly to the coordinates of
the upper left corner.
So that's our next argument then we need to choose a fund.
That's our next argument.
And we're going to pick the following fund which we get from our open library.
And the name of the fund is called fund her say and not complex but simplex.
That's a nice one right.
Then we need to choose a size of the text.
We're going to choose size two then a color of the text.
We're going to choose the following color 2 5 5 5 5 and 2 5 5 then a thickness of the text.
We're going to choose two again.
And finally we want our text to be displayed continuously you know with continuous lines and not little
dots.
And to make sure we get this we need to hear the last argument which is going to be C-v to that line.
Right that will just give us some continuous lines to display the text and not little dots and that's
it.
We displayed a nice label onto our detector rectangles and now eventually we have one last thing to
do inside this while loop.
And then after that one final thing to do over all this one I think you have to do inside this while
loop is of course to increment J because right now we're dealing with the arguments 0 because Jaycar
0 and we did not do a for loop we did a while loop and then a while loop we must not forget to increment
the iterative variable that is J.
So in other words we just need to deal with the next occupants of the class.
I and to do this we just need to increment J like that J plus equals 1.
Perfect.
So now we can get out of this while loop and also get out of this for loop because we did exactly what
we had to do for all the objects that can be detected.
And now the final thing that we need to do is just to return the frame and that's it.
We have the frame returned with the detector rectangles on any object that is part of the training and
as is the model.
So you know that as the model was trained to detect between 30 to 40 objects here in this loop we look
for all these objects and several possible occupancies of these objects.
We approach them as core and just matching scores high enough.
We keep it and therefore we have several objects detected on this return frame with the rectangles and
the labels.
So congratulations.
That was the hardest part.
I hope that's OK.
Now the rest will be much easier and soon enough we should be able to see that output video with the
several detected object.
I can't wait to show you this.
And until then enjoy computer vision.