All right.
Welcome to a new module.
And in this module, we're going to be making a beautiful BMI calculator.
And in the process, we're going to learn all about how to customize Flutter widgets so that it will look
the way that we want it to, and be able to implement our custom user interface designs. And by the end
of the module, we will have something that looks like this. A beautiful app that has custom components
and styling, and it's going to help you calculate your BMI or your body mass index. The actual functionality
of the app is incredibly simple.
It's just a few lines of code.
But the important thing is we're going to learn how to not just use the widgets that come out of the
box that are made by the Flutter team, but we're also going to be building up and creating our very own
custom widgets. Now,
the design here is inspired by something I came across on Dribbble, which if you don't know about, it it's
a fantastic resource to get inspired by designs all created by some of the world's top designers. And
you can see these incredibly innovative and beautiful user interfaces that you could think about implementing.
And going through some of these websites, looking at what people are creating,
it really makes you want to step out of the box and go beyond what Apple or material design provides
you with, and to start experimenting and creating your own designs and your own branding and your own
look and feel for your apps.
And I'm going to show you in this module just how easy it is to do this using Flutter and Dart. So we're going
to be implementing the design from ribbon vaults.
And it looks really clean really beautiful and we're going to be doing our best to try and mimic the
look and feel that we see here. Once you are ready, head over to the next lesson and download the skeleton
project so we can get started right away.