All right guys.
Welcome back to a brand new module.
And in this module we're going to be building a to do list app called Todoey.
It's going to help us
and in the process of building it, we're going to learn all about state management.
Now this is what our app will look like.
It's gonna be pretty simple but I think it's got a pretty beautiful interface and it's going to allow
us to add new tasks, to check off tasks, as well as to delete tasks from our To Do list.
And in the process, we're going to be exploring what state is and how we use it in Flutter. And then we're
going to be looking at various ways of managing state as well as organizing the architecture of our
app.
So we're going to be looking at set state and stateful  widgets which we've already seen and we've
come to love.
But now in this module, we're going to take it one step further so that we'll know how to manage state
for more complex apps through the use of callbacks by learning about how to lift state up as well as
learning about the provider package, which is what the Google Flutter team recommends us to use when
we're thinking about state management.
And if you're wondering, "What is state and why do we have to manage it and exactly how do we do it?"
Well all of those questions will be answered very shortly in this module.
So once you already head over to the next lesson and let's get started.