We know that the simplest type of Dart functions look like this. Where we have a keyword void
at the beginning, we have the name of the function,
we have a set of parentheses which will keep empty,
and then we have our curly braces.
And inside these curly braces are all of the instructions that are repeated that we need to use in different
places in our code. And when we want to call this function to activate it,
we call it by its name like so. Applying that to our code,
let's go up here and create a new function. To start off with the void keyword, we'll call it,
you call it anything you want, but let's call it changeDiceFace.
And I'm going to add a set of empty parentheses.
Now it's a complete building our function,
all we need to add now are a set of curly braces.
And it's inside these curly braces where we'll add the blocks of code which are repeated across our
code namely updating our leftDiceNumber and updating our rightDiceNumber.
You can see that all of this is the same.
So let's cut that out of the onPressed and let's paste it into our new function. And we can now, instead
of having to write all those lines of code, we can simply call it by its name, which is changeDiceFace.
So now when our flat button gets pressed, the onPressed listener gets triggered and it looks to find this
function with the name of changeDiceFace. It finds it right here and it calls set state, changes the
leftDiceNumber, changes the rightDiceNumber.
So now we can put that in here as well and we're gonna call changeDiceFace down here too.
And now this code is no longer repeated in two places.
Or maybe if you had more dice, there'd be more places that it would be needed. Now,
if you were wondering why we couldn't take out the expanded widget and the repeated flat button widget
or the repeated onPressed, we're going to answer that in a few modules because we need to learn a bit
more about widgets before we can do that. In the next lesson,
I've got one final boss level challenge for you. And it's to build an app of your own.
So once you're ready, head over there and be ready to face off the end of level boss. And I'll see you
on the next module.