Hey.
Well done for completing yet another module.
This is really exciting.
You're getting really into the course now.
Now I want to share with you one of my ways for building a good habit.
Because if we think about it learning to code, it requires daily, almost constant effort, right?
Ideally if you could spend 100 days and you spent one hour a day learning to code or coding something
of your own, then you're going to become so much better than if you just, you know, did it one weekend and then forgot
about it,
right?
So the difference between these two scenarios is if you're able to build a habit, and once we have a
habit, you almost don't have to think about it anymore,
right?
You don't think about in the morning like do I want to brush my teeth or not.
I don't know.
Is it one of those days where I brush or not? You don't think about that because it's a habit.
You just wake up, and you just do it.
So how can you make coding, or learning to code, a habit?
One of the things that really helps me is to mark a line in my calendar, and I think this
is actually something that came from Jerry Seinfeld, like the comedian dude, where he said that every
day he writes a new joke, he puts a line through, you know, his calendar, and, by continuing that line, at some point
you're not going to want to break the chain, because it's like, “Man, I've done like a 10 day streak.
How hard is it just to do one more day?”
And I don't know if it's because I'm kind of OCD like I just like seeing things like completed.
I sometimes just write to do's in my to do list that I've already done which I haven't written in my
list but just to be able to tick it off.
Yeah yeah let me know if you can relate.
But if you even if you can't.
Most people actually benefit from continuing a streak and by about 30 days or 40 days that thing that
you have to constantly think about, like, “Do I have time today to code?
Do I want to do it?” That kind of just becomes a habit and you just know, “Oh, this is the time where I get
sat down and I start coding.” And it doesn't actually take that much motivation anymore. So try and give
this a go and see if that helps you.
But the most important thing is to just keep going.
I keep saying it but at the end of the day if you show up if you do the work then you're gonna get the
results.
So I'm here cheering for you.
I'm sure other people are.
I think you're doing great and you're going to do even better.