All right.
So for those of you who are Mac users, this is the track where we're going to install Flutter and all
of the related components on your Mac.
So first things first.
What are the minimum system requirements?
Now you're going to need to be running macOS and you should have at least 700 megabytes,
if it is just for the Flutter installation. Now, because when we build our Flutter apps, the whole point
of it is that we're going to be able to deploy it on iOS and Android.
It means that you'll need Android Studio and Xcode, which are both large applications.
So I would say that at least have around 10 gigabytes free on your laptop, if not more, so that you'll
have a smooth experience setting up and installing.
Now you should be running Mac OS 10 and ideally, you should really be on Mac OS Mojave, which is 10.
14.
And the reason for this is because if you want to be running your iOS  app onto a, say a physical device
that's running the latest version of iOS , iOS 12, then the only way to do that is through having Mojave
installed on your laptop.
Now however, you can still get away with having a lower version of Mac OS if you want to either just
develop Flutter apps. Flutter is not that picky about your Mac OS version but the one application does
care is Xcode, which is the software that we're going to need to be able to deploy our apps onto the
iOS simulator or an iOS device.
So if you don't mind so much about running on the latest iOS versions, then you can also get away with
just having High Sierra as your Mac operating system.
Now as I mentioned in the very beginning, if you're running macOS Catalina, then be sure that you've
completed all the steps in the test lesson at the very beginning of this journey, so that you've changed
your terminal from Bash to Zsh before you continue.
Now first things first, we're going to get started by heading over to flutter.dev/get-
started and you're going to choose your installation track.
So a good point to mention at this point is that if you're based in China and the Google servers are
blocked, then the Flutter development community have actually setup some mirrors that will allow you
to download everything you need just the same even if you're based in China.
OK.
So once you're ready, go ahead and choose Mac OS and you'll see a very long list of installation instructions.
But don't worry, we're going to go through them together.
And I'm going to share my tips with you as well just to make it a little bit simpler a little bit easier
to get set up.
So first things first, you're going to download the installation bundle which is a zip file and this
is going to contain all of the Flutter code and all of things are going to enable you to build Flutter apps.
So give that a few moments,
and once it's done you should be able to find it in your downloads folder and it will be a zip file.
So you're going to double click on it to unzip the compressed file.
Now once extraction has completed, you should end up with a folder called 'flutter'.
And if you double click to open it, you'll see all sorts of things that have been shipped.
Now, it's important that we move this folder out of the downloads folder and into somewhere permanent.
So the ideal place to put it is under your username and maybe in a folder.
So down here you can see that here's my Macintosh hard drive,
there's a folder called users.
And here is my current user username, and this is where we want to navigate to.
Now you can either double click down here or if you can't find that, then simply hold down COMMAND and
press the up arrow continuously until you get to Macintosh HD, and you should be able to go to users
and find your username. So once you've got your home folder open,
so the one under your username, then here
go ahead and create a new folder and you're going to call it developer, and then hit enter.
And now we're going to move that Flutter folder that we had previously from our downloads into our developer
folder.
So now you can see the full path is Macintosh HD.
So this is the root of our computer.
Then it goes to users, then to our username, then to developer, to flutter.
Now once you've done this then you're ready to move on to the next part which is a little bit tricky
because we have to tap in to the terminal.
So over here go ahead and launch spotlight and you're going to search for the terminal app.
And then once you've found it hit enter to open it up.
If you are using Mac OS Catalina, then follow the steps
I'm going to tell you now. If you're using an older Mac OS such as Mojave or High Sierra or Sierra, then
continue on in this video.
And at 9:22, I'll show you how to do the same thing using those operating systems.
Now once you've got the terminal open, then go ahead and just check to see that you've actually got the
Z shell enabled, and you should see zsh at the top of your window.
Now if you look at the Mac OS installation instructions that Flutter has provided, and you scroll down
to the section that says Update your path,
this is exactly what we're going to do.
So we're going to find a file called .zshrc and this lives in our home folder. So to open it, all
we have to do is type 'vim ~/.zshrc' and notice that there's a
space between vim and the rest of this line.
But inside this line, it should be a complete path with no spaces.
So now hit ENTER, and it should now open up this file called zshrc using a text editor called vim
which is always installed by default with all Macs.
Now in order to start editing this file, you're going to hit the 'i' key in on your keyboard in order
to start inserting text.
And now we're going to add this entire string over.
So go ahead and copy this code here and go ahead and hit COMMAND V to paste it into this file.
Now notice how there's this part which is enclosed in square brackets,  [PATH_TO_FLUTTER_
GIT_DIRECTORY] You're going to delete it and remember that you're only deleting the part inside the square
brackets.
So you should be left with $PATH:/flutter/bin
So if you remember, previously we had extracted the entire flutter folder into our username/developer
/flutter.
So we have to provide the path to actually get to this flutter/bin folder.
So in my case it's my homefolder/developer.
So in my case I'm going to type $
HOME/Developer/flutter/bin
And this, you'll notice, is going to correspond to going to the home folder which is this username/
developer/flutter.
And inside this flutter folder, there is a bin folder which we need to point to.
And that's what this line does.
So once you're done with this, then go ahead and hit the ESC key and then :wq
!
Now the next step, once you've done that and you're back in the terminal, is to actually close down the
current window and start a new window either by going to Shell, New Window with profile or simply just
hitting COMMAND + N.
Now once you've opened up a new window, then you can go ahead and run the command: flutter
--version to confirm if your installation was successful. And if at this point you see something about
Flutter, channel stable... something like this then brilliant. You're done for this lesson and you can skip
to the next lesson. But if at this point you see a pop up saying something about 'dart can't be open because
the developer cannot be verified,' then you have to make sure that you go back to the Flutter installation
website and download the latest SDK.
So just go ahead and click download again and replace what's in your developer folder the current the
current Flutter folder, delete it and replace it with the latest one that you've downloaded and extract
it.
Then once you've done that you can go back into the terminal and run that command 'flutter
--version' again.
And it should now work. So for the next part of this lesson, I'm going to show you how to add the path
to your computer
if you're using an older version of Mac OS such as Mac OS Mojave or High Sierra. And the way that we're
going to do that is you should see your username right before a dollar sign.
This is what we call the prompt and you're going to type in 'vim .bash_profile'
Now make sure that you spelt it exactly the way you see it here, and then you go to hit ENTER and, you're
going to enter what's called vim.
And if you're not a vim user, then it can seem a bit weird at first because this is actually a text editor,
and some people even write code here.
Now here is where we're going to add this line.
But this part where it says [PATH_TO_FLUTTER_DIRECTORY] and including those square brackets, we have to
replace with the actual path that we have that navigates to this Flutter directory, which is Macintosh
HD users/username/developer. So we're going to do this in two parts.
We're first going to copy everything up to the colon, so not including that dollar sign.
So starting from export all the way up to and including the colon, I'm going to paste it into this
batch profile here.
So that's the first part.
Now the next part we need to get the path to our Flutter folder.
So this one right here.
And the trick is we're going to hold it and we're going to drag it into our terminal.
So it'll put in that entire file path that navigates to this folder into our terminal.
And now we're going to add /bin to the very end of our path, and close it off with some
quotation marks.
So in order to insert tags and start typing in vim, you have to hit the 'i' key, and i stands for insert.
So now we can type /bin and we can close it off with some double quotes.
So this is the entirety of the path for me anyways.
And I'm obviously using my colleague's computer because I already have Flutter set up and ready to go.
But I wanted to be able to show you how to do this because it's kind of fiddly.
So what you should end up with is export  PATH=
and then here is where we specify that entire path.
And the first part came from dragging and dropping the Flutter folder.
Now, of course, inside the Flutter folder, we have a folder called bin and this is what Flutter needs to
locate to be able to work from anywhere on your computer.
So once you're done and you're happy with this, theoretically the only parts that should be different
for you is just your username.
If you had saved a Flutter inside the developer folder as we did in the last step.
But now that we're done we're going to hit the ESC key.
And then you're going to type :wq!
And this saves this file and quits the file in sort of crazy vim lingo.
Now there's all sorts of jokes about people never being able to get out of vim.
I hope you're not one of them, and I hope you'll be able to continue with me along the course. Once we're
done adding the path we're going to go ahead and quit terminal, and we're going to restart it again.
And now I'm going to check that everything worked by typing in flutter --version.
So now if I hit enter it should
tell me which version of flutter I'm running. At the moment it's 1.2.1.
It also tells me which version of Dart I'm running which is 2.1.2.
Now while we're here, the other command that's really useful in the terminal is 'flutter doctor'.
And this will diagnose our little Flutter and see how it's doing.
Now if you get a pop up like this just simply go ahead and click OK.
And you should
now be able to  see what is already set up and what's not yet set up. So you can see we've got a whole
bunch of crosses in here and we're gonna go through them in the next few lessons.