so there's several different programming
paradigms and up until now in this
course we've been mainly using the
imperative style of programming
imperative programming involves
providing a series of instructions for
the computer to follow in a defined
order now object oriented programming
aims to combine data and the processes that
act on that data into objects which is
called encapsulation
before I continue it's important to
realize that the different paradigms are
not necessarily exclusive and
object-oriented programming makes use of
imperative programming within the
methods that objects used to manipulate
the data also as we will see shortly our
imperative programming in Python has
actually made extensive use of objects
we just didn't know that so the approach that
we've been using so far in the course is
very similar to a recipe for cooking a
meal so the recipe starts with the
ingredients and utensils it will be need
which corresponds to a programs data
and then continues with the description of
the steps that must be performed on that
data to produce in this case for the
recipe
finished meal an object oriented
approach relies on the objects such as
the eggs milk spoon etc knowing
how to perform certain operations so
the program just tells them to do so
concept of an egg that knows how to fry
itself is a little bizarre but that
really shows that the imperatives
approach to cooking a meal is more
appropriate than an object-oriented
approach
now a good example of the encapsulation of
data and function might be self lighting
cigarettes well actually its a
bad example and I certainly wouldn't
want to suggest that smoking is good but
it does demonstrate the concept quite well
so without object oriented programming
the steps to smoking a cigarette might
be place cigarette in mouth that's number
one number two light match number three
hold match to cigarette and number four
inhale now encapsulating the functions
that can be performed on the cigarette
into the cigarette reduces the code to
place cigarette in mouth and inhale so
the cigarette knows how to light itself so
that's not something that the smoker
needs to be concerned with
the details of how it lights itself are
built into it when it's manufactured or
in the case of programming it's
programmed into it when it's defined
and the actual implementation is of
no interest to anything that uses the
object now I've exercise a little license
they're self lighting cigarettes were
produced for short time the 1960's
coincidentally around the same time that
object oriented programming was
conceived and had a igniter
built into them that had to be struck like a match
the advanced type that I described only
existed in science fiction stories now
modern electronic cigarettes take this
concept a little bit further but it's
only the details of the implementation
that have changed so the method use
remains pretty much the same as the
science-fiction variety now that's important
concept of object oriented
programming as we will see replacing one
object with another one that performs
the same task without having to concern
ourselves with the details of how it
performs the task is central to object
oriented programming so another and
hopefully much more healthier example
might be an electric kettle now the
imperative approach to boiling water
for hot drink might be step 1 fill kettle with
water
step 2 light stove step 3 place kettle on stove step 4 for monitor kettle until
water boils step 5 make the drink now it would then have to be a function that
deals with lighting the stove which might
involve further functions to collect
water or coal or was switched on the gas a
function to light the match and so on but
in object orientated terms a kettle would have a
boil method that is triggered by
operating a switch so the object
oriented program comes down to step
one fill kettle with water
step 2 switch kettle on step 3 when kettle switches off make drink so the
imperative approach will also have to
identify the type of stove being used as
its futile and probably a bit dangerous to hold a match to electric cooker
now these examples may make it look like
we've got something for nothing because
performing the tasks using an object
oriented approach involves fewer steps
but there's no magic involved here now the
steps are still had to be programmed
but their built into the objects
so that anything that using the object doesn't have to be
concerned about them so the object orientated kettle has been built to contain an
element or whatever method it employs could
be a ceramic disc or even a small
nuclear reactor and the operation of
the heating mechanism has been wired up to
the switch where the kettle was made so a lot
of work has gone into the production on
the kettle in other words far more so that
the work that goes into making a kettle
for use on the stove but subsequent use
of the kettle is there much easier
because it knows how to perform its
function itself so one thing that may
not be obvious and I haven't yet mentioned is that
everything in Python is an object so Python
is unusual in this respect because even though Python uses objects extensively you
don't actually have to be aware of that
to use so Python can be used for
object-oriented programming but can also
be used to write purely imperative
programming code so in fact the
Wikipedia entry for Python which I'm going to just load
up the screen now you can see the link
in the top left hand corner you can see
just down here it says that Python
supports multiple programming paradigms
including object oriented imperative and
functional programming or procedural
styles so in Java which is considered a
class-based object-oriented language
there are primitive types such as an
int and a double so if you've come to Python
from Java the following code which I'm
about to show might seem very odd at
first so lets just go back to IntelliJ and I've created a
new project here and a new Python file so if
you come back come from Java type in
code like this....
....so if we just run this see that it does
work and we get the same result each time so line 3...and
that's pretty normal for a programming
language like Java
but the code on line 4 would probably be a bit bizarre and that's because the a even though
it's been defined as you can see on line
12 as a number you could see that a has
got an add method even though its an integer so if I command click add
and that is control click on a PC or Linux you can
see that there's a method this is the
built-ins definition of the add method and
interestingly enough if I go back to oop
our file and click on the plus note that it has gone to the same method in the built ins
so what you can see by that is that whether
you use this __add__
or use a plus it's calling
the same code that is built-in
builtins.py file and in this case add
two numbers together and smart enough to
figure out the parameters you can see
there that the second argument in the
case of line 3 is then added and line 4
the parameters b is added to the value
of a now if this is your first
programming language and either you see
nothing at all strange about this
or it will make very little sense but don't worry
I'm gonna explain what it all means but
I wanted to warn you that you know if
you've come from other programming
languages such as Java or C++ you
probably gonna see some aspects of Python that seem surprising to you at
least initially now when I said that
everything in Python is an object I meant
everything even types are
implemented as classes now I will come
back to that but for now I'm gonna focus
on making sense of what I've just done
their so object-oriented programming uses
classes and methods to provide object
that encapsulates both data and the
functions that operate on that Data now the
method is just another word for function
and you have seen me use those terms
interchangeably in this course but being big
correct here when a function is part of
a class in Python we call it a method
now in Python there is a slight
difference between a function and a method but writing a method is the same
as writing functions now what we gonna
do is start with a very simple example
to introduce the concept of a class and
show how classes work in Python now this
example be a simple implementation of
the electric
kettle so let's go ahead and do that's
so close the run window and I'm just gonna
delete this code and we start by creating
a kettle class and its gonna model an
electric kettle
so.....and notice how its has been indented for us
automatically and we're going to create a
method so....
....
....will talk about this shortly...
we just type in the code for now so...
....
...so looking at this it can be helpful to
think of a class as a template from
which objects can be created so when we
create objects of this kettle class they
all have a name and a price now they won't
have the same name nor the same price
each instance of the class will have its
own values for name and price so classes
as I said is a template from which objects
can be created and all the objects
created from the same class will share
the same characteristics now an instance
is just another name for an object created from a
class definition so if I now create a
kettle called Kenwood then Kenwood will be an
instance of the kettle class you can also
say that kenwood is an object of
type kettle so I'm gonna create a couple of
kettle objects so we can see this in
practice so let's continue typing and
we will go to line 8 here and type...
....
.....
.....and lets make another kettle...
...and I should really have two lines there
separating the class definition to be
consistent with our code so the code on
line 9 creates an instance of the kettle
class and we've given it the name
kenwood and other instances is created on line 16 and this time it's called the
Hamilton so each instance has its own
values for naming and price and their access
by using . annotations so we type in Kenwood.price or Hamilton.make for
argument sake to access that information
so a good analogy here is for plans for
building a house so the plan itself just
describes what the house will look like
its size how many rooms it will have etc
now this is similar
the plan to the class which is just a
template for creating objects once you
have a plan you can then create it as many
houses as you want based on that
plan and the same is true of classes
once a class has been defined like how
kettle class that we define on line one
we can then create as many instances of that
classes as we want now just as you can't do
anything with the house plan other than
build houses based on it you can't
really do anything with the class other
than create instances of it once the
instances have been created you can then call
their methods and access their variables so
on line 11 Kenwood.price retrieves
the price from the instance called
Kenwood and Hamilton.price will get the
price of the Hamilton instance we can
also give the price a new value as we see on line
13 where we set the price to $12.75 so we've been
using dot notation extensively in our
programs in this course
when you seen that when we've used the
append method to add items to a list for example
also all the TK widgets are objects
that have .pack and grid methods amongst
many others to allow them to be placed
in the window manager so lets add another
example in this program so I'm going to start typing and put on some code on line 18
gonna type...
.....
....and you can see here models kenwood equals$12.75 and Hamilton equals $14.55 so it's
retrieved the values out of each
instance of the 2 kettle objects that
we've created so the parameters in the format
method are the make price data attributes of
the Kenwood and Hamilton objects
another bit of jargon here the
attributes so we've become used to
talking about variables but when a
variable is bound to an instance of a
class then it's referred to as a data
attribute in Python now their other
object-oriented programming terms for
the same things you might find variable
attributes also called fields in
languages such as Java or data members
in C++ now I'll introduced yet another term
shortly probably in the next video one
that's been borrowed from the small talk
language but lets end this video here and in then next
video we'll continue our discussion about
objects see you in the next video