so in this video I'm gonna do is install
the Python timezone package pytz
and will show you how to do it for various platforms so first platform I wanna show you
how to get this working on is windows
so what you need to do is open a command
prompt and when you open a command
prompt you should have something looks
something like that and once it opens type pip3 install as you can see on the screen
and one other thing to note is that you
need to open or you need to
run the command prompt as an
administrator now on Windows 8 and 10 you
can do this by pressing the Windows key
and x and choose command prompt admin from
the list and in windows 7 and Vista type cmd
at the start menu search box and
when a result appears right click and
choose Run as Administrator either way
you get a screen that pops up similar to
this with a black background and on
that screen you need to type pip3 intall
pytz and that
will install the Python timezone library
into your system so at this point then
press ENTER and once you press enter you
should get the following screen pop up
and you can see it says collecting pytz starts downloading and you
should find it will start downloading and
installing the Python timezone
library and then once that's finished you get
that screen or something similar
you can see it successfully installed pytz
and the version number which may end
up being different
to what you can see on the screen
and noticed in the bottom in gold you've got
your using pip version 7 however version 8 is available so depending on which
version you got you may get a message
similar to that you can safely ignore
that because what we've done is we've
used the version of pip to download and install
the right Python timezone library so if you do get that no problems you can
continue knowing that you've actually
installed so at this point if your on Windows
and you follow these instructions you
should have the Python timezone library
installed and you can move on to
the next video where we can start actually
using it the next operating system
I'm going to show you is Linux so if your running
Ubuntu Linux here are the commands now just in
addition to that what I didn't show you
in the previous video
was how to install pip as
well as you may need to install pip on your
Linux distro because it's not installed
by default so what you need to do there is
open a terminal window as you would normally
open in Ubuntu and you should see something
like this and typing....
....so you do that and then press
ENTER and you will find that it will start
downloading and you get something like this
and you can see that its gone ahead and
downloaded the packages and then install
it and on the bottom the last command
you can see...
....and that just
confirms that were actually running the
right version of pip so you have to do
that if you're running Ubuntu and if
you're running another version another
distro of Linux you need to do is use
the appropriate package manager installation
mechanism that is use to install it so
that's installing pip and you need to
use the pip tool which incidentally
again stands for pip install packages
so that we can install the Python timezone
library
now we've done that open a new commandant
or we can use the same one and you get
something like this and type this
command so you can see I have type...
...which again is
the Python timezone package that
will go ahead and install that so
once you've done that press ENTER and
then you get the following screen so you
can see it's downloaded the relevant
file and the version again may be
different depending when you're running
this and you can see it say installing collected
packages pytz and successfully install
pytz cleaning up and you back to the
command prompt at that point you've
have now got that installed and you can
continue on now to the next video if your a
Linux user and we can start using this
Python timezone packaged ok last but
certainly not least is Mac users I'm
going to show you that live and it's
because I'm running this on a Mac so what
you need to do is open a terminal window so
type terminal press
ENTER then to get it installed this is a
assuming that you've installed pip3
you should have done that based on
the previous videos if you
haven't done that go ahead and do
that then type....
.....
....press enter and type in the regular password
to your account and press enter and you should find it will
go ahead and install it for us and you
may get that warning message but you can
safely ignore there is no problems there
the main thing was that downloading as you can see installing
collected packages pytz successfully
installed pytz-2015.7 so at
that point we've now got the Python timezone library and we will be able to use
that in the next video so that's it
that's how to go about installing the
library and you be able to use this
mechanism for any library that you install
in the future obviously just change the
name of the library that you want to
install now that you've got the tools
installed on your computer and you can
see a mechanism of doing that so I'm gonna end
the video here in the next video we are going
to start making use of this some library
that we just installed so we'll see you
in the next video