So in the previous video, we started
talking about variables for Python and
thus, we ended talking
about operator precedence.
So you saw that by using brackets we can
make sure that the calculations we think
work, use the correct order or
actually are processed in the right order
to avoid getting us incorrect results.
And that's mainly by putting brackets
around each sort of section.
Now there's another way of doing that,
that would be easier, and
in some cases you may wanna
instead look at something
that's relatively complex, like you
can see with that print statement.
You can actually use variables
to hold the intermediate values.
So for example, we could say,
a variable with the name of c = a + b.
And then we can also do d = c / 3.
And then we could do e = d / 4.
And then we could do print(e * 12).
Now if we actually run that, we should
get the same result in both cases.
We get 12 for this line here.
But we also get 12 for this line here.
And that's because we've broken up
those individual components, and
assigned them to different
variables, to get the same result.
So definitely there's gonna be times where
it makes sense to break up an expression
like this into smaller parts.
It's really gonna be up to you to
compare the two examples to see which
one works better for you.
Once you start getting used
to the concept of brackets,
it's easy to see actually at a glance
with that one, as to what's happening
with this one because you're
introducing different variables.
It can take a bit of work to look at that
because you've actually got more output
to look at.
But the bottom line is there's no right or
wrong here.
It's whatever's more appropriate and
more readable for you.
So, moving on now, let's actually start
talking about another data type and
that's the data type string.
Now you've seen us use strings in earlier
examples, to print messages on the screen.
But I want to go through now and show you
some of the other cool things you can do
when you're actually working with strings.
So strings are one of Python's what
they call sequence data types,
which makes sense because
that's what it really is.
It's really a sequence of characters
that you can put together
that form an actual string.
So we've seen how to print them out and
concatenate strings together.
But we can also pick out individual
characters or substrings.
So I'm gonna delete some of this now,
and let's just see how that works.
I'm gonna type parrot = "Norwegian Blue".
We can print(parrot).
And no surprises there, if we run
that to see what actually happens.
Norwegian Blue, we should expect, we can
actually do print(parrot[3]) like so.
If you run that, you can see, what's
happened is by doing that it's
actually printed the letter w.
Now you might be looking at that and
thinking, "well why is that w?"
because we specified the third character,
so shouldn't that be counting from left to
right, N is the first character,
o is the second and r is the third.
And in actual fact w is
the fourth character.
So why did that work?
It's actually usual for programming
languages to start counting at zero,
and not at one.
So that's parrot zero is N.
So we can actually go to confirm that.
Parrot[0], if we actually
run that is an N.
So you'll find that in most languages,
as I said, they'll actually start counting
from position zero and not from position
one as we would normally do as humans.
So there's 14 characters in
Norwegian Blue, numbered from zero to 13.
If we try to print(parrot[14]), we get
an error, string index out of range.
So if we actually try and do that So 14.
We'll actually get an error.
And that's because as far as it's
concerned, there's no character
at that position, because there's
only characters in position 0 to 13.
The other thing you can
actually do is count backwards.
So, you can type print(parrot[-1]).
And if we actually run that,
negative one gives us e. So
what's happened is that it started here at
position zero and went to negative one.
Negative one goes all to the way
to the end of the string and
starts counting from the end.
So we get the letter e coming up, which
is the last character from the string.
And we can work backwards like that.
We can also print what
Python calls a slice by,
instead of providing one number,
provide two numbers separated by a colon.
So in other words,
it's gonna be like a range.
So, we can do print(parrot[0:6]),
if you run that, you get Norweg,
which is the six characters starting,
which is the length of six characters
starting at position zero.
So the first number is the number in
the string to start, printing out, and
the sixth is how many characters
to actually print out.
So it's actually two
ways at looking at this.
First, you could say that
printing parrot[0:6] starts from
character's position index zero up to but
not including index position six.
But we can also say the six
character starting from index zero.
But in Python, the first is technically
more correct even if it seems to amount
where they both seem, well actually both
do end up with showing the same amount.
If the first number is omitted,
the slice is gonna start from
the beginning of the string.
If the second number is omitted,
it's gonna run to the end of the string.
Just to show you what I mean by that.
Type print(parrot[:6].
That's gonna start from automatically,
because we haven't
specified a number here.
It's gonna start from
the start of the string.
That's gonna print the same
as the previous line.
But if we also did print(parrot[6:]) and
didn't specify the second number,
it's gonna run to the end of the string.
So if you run that, you can see it's
moved, started at the position, so
it's actually went to effectively
the seventh position, so it's counting,
zero, one, two, three,
four, five, six, ian Blue.
So ian Blue and it's going along because
we haven't specified where to end,
so it's actually moved on to the end,
continued and done the entire string.
And if you start dealing
with negative indices,
it quickly becomes apparent why
the second definition is not gonna work.
So in other words, if we start
trying to do this, print(parrot[-4:2])
that's not actually gonna print anything.
That's because you can't go back
from the starting position in this
context.
But if we actually go back and
put a -2 there, and run that.
You can see it's actually started and
produced Bl and that's because it
started from the start of the string, it's
gone back four characters, up to and not
including the second to last character
in the string which was the u.
Another thing you can actually do
is you can actually do a print.
You can actually do funny slices that
skip characters, counting in steps.
So I could do print(parrot[0:6:2]).
And that should give us the answer Nre.
So we run that, Nre as you can see.
So starting from index position zero,
extract all the characters up to, but
not including index position
six in steps of two.
As you saw in the first example and
that started on N.
And skip to r and skip to e.
And we can change that and
do something like print(parrot[0:6:3]),
so make the step increment three, and
we should get N and w in that case, and
w because it's skipping
three characters at time.
So slightly useless application, but
I'm gonna show you an example.
Type number = "9.
And there's numbers here,
223,372,036,854,775,807".
And if I actually do
a print(number[1::4]) with two colons,
if I actually run that, you can see how
it's actually skipped the numbers and
actually just printed out the commas
at each position automatically.
So that's a good way to step through
and extract portions out of the particular
string that you wanna work with.
But using a better example,
let's just try numbers = "1,
2, 3, and notice I'm putting
one space after each, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8, 9" like so.
And if we actually do, print(number
print(numbers[0::3]).
We actually run that.
You can see we've quickly
extracted out the numbers, and
we've avoided the commas and
the spaces there.
So you can see how it would be useful, if
you wanted to extract information out in
a particular format.
So moving on, let's talk a little
bit about string operators.
So we've talked about operators before,
and
you've seen the plus operator when
we use strings to concatenate.
So if we had something like this.
String1 = "he's "
String2 = "probably ".
We could do print(string1 + string2).
We've seen that before.
If we run that, the two strings
get added together, he's probably.
But if you're using a string literal, and
that's when you're just typing the value
in direct and you're not using a variable,
you don't actually need
to use the plus sign.
So we could do something like this,
we could do
print("he's " "probably " "pining").
We can run that.
We can see how Python quite happily allows
you do actually do something like that.
Now I'm mentioning that just
to show you how it works.
I wouldn't think you'll ever wanna do
something like that because it's a little
bit totally confusing.
And probably not really useful because
you can obviously just do this,
you can actually delete that out anyway
and obviously you get the same result.
But it's just that, showing you
that it can potentially be done.
So next,
you can actually multiply strings.
It sounds a bit weird because
multiplication generally is only on
numbers, but if you do something
like this: print("Hello " *5).
Python will give you,
Hello Hello Hello Hello Hello so
it will give you whatever's
in the string.
And it will do that five times.
It's sort of like appending
to that five times.
And operator precedence applies.
So if we do something
like print("Hello " *5
+4) remembering what we know
about operator precedence.
We try and run that.
We actually get an error, can't convert
int object into a string implicitly.
And that's because, hello,
the times 5, this part here,
that actually evaluates to a string, and
the attempt to then add 4 to it fails,
and that's really not the way to do it,
so if you want to do something like that,
you'd actually either put it brackets,
like so.
And if you run that you then
get the correct result.
Alternatively you would type
print("Hello " * 5 + "4").
If you run that, that's
actually if you wanted to append the number
four onto the end of the strings that
have been modified out five times.
There's also an operator
to check if one string
is a substring of another, which can
be useful for searching purposes.
So we did something like today = "friday".
We can do print("day" in today).
So that's the in operator.
So that should return True.
Returns a true or
false to indicate whether it thinks
that whatever we've typed here, day in
this case, is actually in that word.
So if we run that, we should get True.
And so you've got True there on the screen.
If we did something like print("fri" in
today) we should also get a True,
which we'll test shortly.
And if we do something
different like print("thur" in
today) we should get a False for that.
And lastly, if we did something like,
("parrot" in "fjord") that should
obviously be a False as well.
So True, True, "day" in today,
if "fri" in today. if Thursday or
Thur is not in that variable called today.
And, obviously the word,
parrot, is not in fjord either.
So that's you got some basic
information about operators.
And I hope you got a lot out of
the two videos on variables in Python.
In the next video,
we're gonna take it to the next level.
We're gonna look at various ways that
we can format strings, and also some of
the string methods that are built into
Python, to allow us to manipulate them.
So, I'll see you in that next video.