so it's now time to focus on the album
classes add song method that we've
delegated the task of dealing with the
song too you can see that currently when the
artist class we wanna go to the album
class in the file that is obviously this
one starting on line16 so obviously it already
exists but we need to make some changes to
get this to work so we are gonna change the
arguments a little bit different it's
going to be the title..
and we need to make some changes here at the moment
we've got some very basic validation
here so we need to use the find object
function in this code to find the
song if it even exists the track so put...
...so we are looking for the song tracks if it exists in
the list and if...
...so we are creating the new object for the song then
below that we gonna put.....
....
...so the else is going to be....
.....so what we doing here well the methods have now change to accept a string for
the song title rather than a sing
object after all the method is called by
the artists class which doesn't know
about songs and the body of the method is
similar to what it was but this is just
that extra step that I added to check if
the songs are already present and then to create a new
song object if it isn't and if the song was
already present and no action is taken
now this may or may not be the correct
thing to do
bonus tracks on CD is often have the
same name as the track in the main album
and in this case it will result in the
bonus track not being added so to deal
with this we probably include the track
number and the data file and check that
rather than or possibly as well as
the title so that's pretty much it the
method uses the same find_object function to check the list and
find_object relies on items in
the list some searching for an
attribute called name which you have seen a
few times now in the previous videos so
if you run the program now we will probably get an error
and I'll just run it show you and we do get an error
song object has no attribute name and
there's a reason for that again find_object relies on
items in the list that its searching
having an attribute called name and in this
case the songs title is stored in an attribute called title rather than name but
that turns out to be pretty easy to fix
we can just change the self.title to
self.name so come here to line 11 self.title equals title again
initialization for song and will make that self.name instead of title....
so we are now using names as an attribute for title and we also want to change the create_
check file function so right down
here
on line 141 so at the moment that's got title their we want to change the title to be
name as well so of course thats printing out the title attribute from
song object but we're now
changing that to use the name attribute because we renamed
the attribute
and we will just delete the checkfile.txt....and lets run this again
and we can see its now processing as we expected to do and we can see theirs 28 artist
now because the program hasn't been
released and nobody's relying on the
song class in the code changing the
attribute in this way that we've done in
this video is fine but if we hadn't
released the program and their was a chance
that other people could be importing it
you know to use our classes in changing
attribute wouldn't be a good idea and
would have to
take another approach instead but I'll
come back to an alternative approach to
that in a minute but the program is now
taking an object oriented approach and
as a result it's a lot
easier to understand it's also easy to
modify if necessary and theirs less chance of bugs creeping in when we do so simpler code is
generally more reliable and by
delegating tasks to other objects we've
kept each step much simpler and more
focused on a single task rather than
having that huge load_data method that we did previously so hopefully seeing how this
program is changed
was trying change to use object oriented
techniques help to demonstrate some of
the advantages that object oriented
programming can provide now it's not
essential to use object oriented
techniques and sometimes an extra
overhead that goes with it can impact
performance and a functional imperative
approach might be more suitable but when
used correctly though object oriented
programming can result in simpler code fewer errors and ultimately
faster development now before I finish with this example for now anyway
we are gonna removed the secular references from our
objects and also make this program work
without renaming the song classes
title attribute or at least show
a way to allow code that used title to still work even though our code expects the
attribute to be called name so first we
need to do is go back close this window
down go back to line 11 again and
we're gonna change the self.name back
to title so we can see that
alternative approach back to title again
and obviously the program will crash and we go down and change checkfile
again as well change this back to title as
well
and by doing that the program is back in
the state where it wouldn't work because
the find object functions expecting its
objects to have a name field or
an attribute which if won't have of course because we just
changed name back to title now because
we want to run the program after
removing the circular references we have
to fix the problem with the title attribute first so that
it can compile at least so I'm gonna explain this
next step in more detail on a later video but
for now I just want to show that this is
possible now also anyone who's
experienced in object-oriented
programming might be concerned that our
classes are allowing direct access to
the attributes now this isn't
necessarily a bad thing
remembering that Python does things
differently but this is also good
opportunity to show you that you can
allow access via getters and setters and
you can even restrict access so that
getters and setters are the only way to retrieve
and change attributes so to do that we need
to go back up to our song class and
come down here we need to introduce a
new method and put...
....
...
so as I mentioned the get_title method is a getter for those people who are
used to object oriented programming and
if this is your first experience of
object oriented programming then don't
worry if you don't know what a getter
is because I'm going to be explaining all that
later but below that on line 18 I
defined a read only property called
name that uses the getter to return the
value of the title attribute so in this way
existing code such as the create_check
file function will still work but
we've then be able to use the find
object function as well so if we run this bearing in mind that last time we run this with the self.title
changes in here
the original code it crashed because It
couldn't find the name attribute
but now we've added this on line 18 and I'll add another line to keep IntelliJ happy if we run this now we see that
the code now does work nicely even
though there isn't technically a name
attribute in our song class so what we've done is
we've added a property called name to
the song class to allow it to be used
without find_object function
and we've done so without breaking any existing code so you can see that that's another alternative
that would be very important if your
code had been released and being used by
other people and as I said I'm going to be covering getters and setters in this method of defining
properties in later video and when I do
that you'll also see why I didn't just set
self.name = title in the init method
so in other words I didn't do something
like this..so when I do show
you that in a video I'm gonna demonstrate why
I didn't do that do that approach and why I used property instead so remove that for now so
we are back to the fact that we've got
a working program so the next video we
going to go through remove the circular
references and then we'll move on to a
challenge so see in the next video