In this video, we're going to look at operator precedence.
It's something you'll have learnt about in basic maths class, and we're going to see how it applies to expressions in Python.
Before I start that though, I'm going to delete lines 16 through 21 in our program.
I added those just to show you what the for loop was doing,
but I don't want to leave it as an example of how you should code,
and in fact I'll take this opportunity to delete the for loop as well.
Alright, so our examples so far have been very simple expressions,
but they can be much more complicated.
So consider the following line as I type it, and see if you can work out what will be printed, before you run the program.
So I'm going to type, on line 13, print and in parentheses I'm going to type a + b
divided by 3 minus 4 multiplied by 12.
Then we've got our closing parenthesis.
So if you can figure out what the answer will be, let's actually run the program and see what happens.
You can see we've got the answer: -35.0.
Now if you're surprised that the answer is -35.0 rather than 12,
then maybe you weren't paying attention in school.
Don't worry, your computer isn't broken
and you can reliably perform arithmetic in Python, but like with all programming languages,
you have to understand some basic rules of the arithmetic operators.
Operator precedence is a fancy term for the relative importance given to each of the operators.
If they were all equally important we could just read the expression on line 13 from left to right,
and we would get the result 12: a is 12 + b which is 3, is 15, divided by 3 gives 5, minus 4 leaves 1 times 12 equals 12.
However multiplication and division have
higher precedence than addition and subtraction,
so those operations will be performed first.
Now many programming languages work in the same way.
This isn't just a peculiarity of Python.
So b divided by 3 is 1.0, and 4 times 12 is 48
So the expression, therefore, is evaluated as 12 plus 1.0 take 48, which is -35.0.
Now if you want to make your expressions clear and unambiguous, you can use parenthesis freely,
even when Python doesn't specifically require them.
So, along those lines, we could revise our
example from line 13, and instead type
print parentheses a + and another set of
parentheses and b divided by 3 in those parentheses,
then a minus, then parentheses 4 times 12. Then we've got our two closing right parentheses.
I'll just space that out a little bit so it's a little bit easier to read.
So if you run this code again, we get the identical answer -35.0 printed twice.
So in other words, both these expressions evaluate to the same value.
Now, if we had intended the earlier expression to reduce the result 12,
we'd write it a different way.
We could do print parentheses,
and we're going to add another three parentheses here, so we've got four in total to the left hand side.
Then a + b, closing parenthesis, divided by 3, closing parenthesis,
- 4 closing parenthesis, multiplied by 12, and there we've got our last closing parenthesis at the end of the line.
And now if we run that, we correctly get the result of 12.0,
or, we could revise that because dividing by 3 is higher precedence than subtracting 4.
We can actually remove one set of parentheses.
So what I could do is change that to print, and we want three left parenthesis this time,
and it's going to be a + b, closing parenthesis, divided by 3 - 4,
closing right parentheses, multiplied by 12, and the final closing parenthesis.
If you run the program again now, we get the same answer, 12.0.
Now we could also use variables to hold the intermediate values if we wanted to.
So if I come down here to line 18, I could type c = a + b. On the next line,
d = c / 3, and e =  d - 4,
and we can do a print, in parentheses, e multiplied by 12.
Now if we run that we,
we also get the value 12 outputted.
So there will be times when it makes sense to break up an expression into smaller parts, as we've done here.
I think in this example, though, the code's harder to read, and difficult to work out what's going on.
Compare the two previous examples and see which one you think's easier to read.
Okay, so I mentioned learning about operator precedence at school.
Unfortunately, many schools use acronyms to help you remember the order of evaluation,
but the acronyms are ambiguous.
So common acronyms are;
So multiplication and division have equal precedence, which is higher than addition and subtraction,
and addition and subtraction have equal
precedence.
Because multiplication and division are equal, expressions using those operations are evaluated from left to right.
So let's go ahead and on line 23, I'll do a print, left and right parentheses to give us a bit of space.
Then on line 25 I'm going to type print parentheses
and within the parentheses I'm going to top a divided by, then another set of parentheses, b multiplied by a,
closing parenthesis and divided by b, closing parentheses.
and if I run this program,
we get the result 0.1111111111
and that's 12 times 3 is 36, and 12 divided by 36 is 1/3 divided by 3 is 1/9.
If you were taught using those acronyms, make sure you're interpreting them correctly.
Alright, so in the next video we're going to look at the string datatype in more detail.
See you in the next video.