Alright so this is the if challenge. So
the challenge is to write a small
program to ask for a name and an age.
When both values have been entered, check
if the person is the right age to go on
on an 18-30 holiday. They must be over 18
and under 31. If they are, welcome them to
the holiday, otherwise print a, hopefully,
polite message refusing them entry. Our
programs expect valid input.
We'll see how to handle invalid numbers later
in the course. You don't need to deal
with that at the moment.
Remember that human languages aren't
always very precise. Someone counts as
over eighteen from one second after
midnight on their birthday. Their actual
age equals 18 but they're counted as
being over 18 when considering
things like voting or getting a credit card.
Alright so that's a challenge. See how
you go. We'll go over the solution to
this challenge in the next video.