We left the previous video with three different ways to create the same output,
and the question: "Which way performs better?".
So the code's in compchallenge2b.py
But before we start comparing how fast the three approaches are, we should make sure we're comparing
like for like.
And in this case we're not. Now our "nested for loops" creates six lists, and discards each list before creating
the next one.
And you can see, here on line 18, that new list being created each time through the loop.
Now that "List comprehension inside a for loop", this next section of code, that does the same thing each
er each
time around the loop, the comprehension assigns a new list to
exits_to_destination_2
You can say that happening on line 30.
And thirdly, the "nested comprehension" builds up a nested list containing all 6 of the other lists.
This is the code down here, starting at line 36.
So before we can perform any meaningful analysis, we need to decide what we're trying to measure here.
Now if we want to use the lists somewhere else in our code, then we're really interested in how efficiently
the lists can be created - and only the third method is creating the complete list here.
But on the other hand, if we're only interested in displaying the result, then we can measure the code
as it is at the moment.
Now as we're learning about all this we're going to do both
here. We'll start by measuring how quickly the results can be displayed, because that's what the code's doing
at the moment.
But there is one change we have to make, to keep the comparison fair.
So our nested loop is printing the list twice.
So I'm going to start here by looking at line 40, and actually delete those three lines. So printing out the
exits to Destination 3.
And also that print there as well. So I'm actually going to delete those lines. Like so. And that's just again to make
sure that we're keeping the comparisons fair here.
All right so let's have a look at the timeit module.
I'll open up a browser.
This is a good place to start.
Now if you want to run tests from the command line, the documentation shows how to use the timeit
module that way.
So that might be fine for testing a single line Python statement, but it gets increasingly complex when
testing larger or longer blocks of code.
Remember the indentation's vitally important in Python, which means you need to start multiple strings
with the correct number of spaces.
So by all means experiment with a command line interface if you want, but we won't be doing things that
way.
So to use timeit in our code, we have to import the timeit module, then either use the timeit function or
create an instance of the Timer class.
Now the timeit function is one of three convenience functions that make use of the Timer class a bit
easier.
Although there's just not much difference in the code you have to write.
So I'm going to use the timeit function, because printing the result is slightly easier.
So coming down here to 27.5.2, the timeit function is passed a statement to
execute. And we're going to start off by passing a statement as a string,
but you can also pass a function instead.
As long as the function doesn't take any arguments.
So that's the first one.
The first statement argument there. The next one is a uh the next parameter is a string containing
setup code.
We're going to come back to that in a moment.
Now the default timer, you can see over here, the third argument, that can be changed if you feel the need to.
Although there is very rarely any need to use a different timer.
Now we looked at the time.perf_counter function in an earlier section, when we were investigating
the time module. That's now the default timer, since Python 3.3 and as I said, there's
rarely any need to change that.
Now this fourth argument, number, is how many times to execute the code.
Now the default value is, as you can see there, is 1 million; which means your code will be executed one million
times.
Now that might seem like a lot, but it does give good results.
But one thing we probably shouldn't do though, is leave it set to the default
when our code prints things out. Now at the moment, each of our methods prints the lists, and printing is
quite a slow operation.
Now if we leave the default number there, it will take about 1 minute to execute each block of code 1
million times.
And lastly this global argument, the final parameter, that's used to specify the namespace that our code
will run in. Now I'm going to come back to that when we look at the setup string, because it's easier to explain
by seeing an example. Alright, so that's the timeit function.
Let's get back to our code.
Let's start setting this up, so first things that we need to do is import the timeit module.
So we'll do that, obviously, on line one
Ok, so import timeit.
Right, so at this point we've now got a choice; and which one you choose to do is entirely up to you.
Now we can either turn our three sections of code into functions or we can wrap them in quotes to turn
them into strings.
Now I'm going to use strings, because turning each code block into a function's easy.
Now there's a couple of things to watch out for when using strings.
First, use triple quotes.
That way any reformatting of your code can be kept to a minimum.
So let's go down and start running some code.
I'm going to call the first string nested_loop.
So I'm goint to start by putting some code here, on line 19. So we've got nested_loop equals and then three quotes and backslash.
Then I'm going to come down here, to line 27, and I put the three quotes again. Like so. And again, notice
the backslash at the end of the opening quotes, here on line 19.
We don't really want our code to start with a blank line, and the line continuation character avoids
that.
Now be careful when typing in code, rather than converting existing code to a string.
The code must start with
no indentation, then be correctly indented relative to the first line.
Incorrect indentation causes an error when timeit tries to execute the code, but because it's a string
you won't get any help from your IDE.
OK.
So that first bit, that's fairly straightforward.
We've now got a string containing our first block of code.
So we want to do the same thing with the other bits of code that we want to use in our test.
So for the "list comprehension inside a for loop" then it'll go below the prints there.
Well call it loop_comp equals, three double quotes again, and a backslash.
Then we go down to just before the print and we put three double quotes.
OK so that's our second one.
And our third one, for the nested
comprehension, below the two prints again.
We're going to do nested_comp equals three double quotes again, backslash, just scroll down
a little bit.
Then we want to do three double quotes after that for loop.
OK. So we've now, at this point, got three strings, that we can pass to the timeit function to see how their performance
compares.
Now we're going to get an error.
But I'm going to go ahead anyway, because it's a good way to explain about
those setup and globals parameters, that we saw in the documentation earlier.
So what I'm going to do is, on line 50, we're going to put a bit of code in here.
I'm going to put or type, result_1
result_1 is equal to timeit.timeit and in parentheses we're going to put nested_loop.
And then we're going to do print("Nested loop colon backslash T for a tab character,
left and right curly braces, ending double quote, dot format and in parentheses result_1, and closing
off the two parentheses. Blank line on line 52.
So if we now run this
Scroll up and have a look at the top
and you can see we've got some errors, but right down at the bottom we've got this NameError: name 'locations' is not defined.
Now that seems strange, because we can clearly see our locations dictionary, if we go up to the top here
on line 3, that's been defined, and it is at the top of the file.
But the problem is that timeit isn't aware of anything defined in your program, except for the arguments
we pass to it, of course.
So that's why it provides the setup and globals parameters, to allow us to set up the environment that
our code will execute in.
Now I'd normally use setup when possible, as it allows you to be more specific about what you pass
to it.
So I'm going to start with globals here though, because it's a simple change to the code. And once you've seen
that working, I'll change the code to provide the dictionaries in the setup argument.
We've already seen how to get the global variables for our modules,
earlier in the course, using the globals() function.
So we can pass the result of calling globals() as the globals argument to timeit. so I'm going to do that, and go down to
line 50 again. I'll close the Run Window first
And here, what we're going to do, on line 50, we'll actually pass that. So we're on the next line
after nested_loop comma globals equals, then a call to the globals function: globals().
So our code snippet will now execute in our global namespace, which means that everything defined in our module
will be available to the snippet.
Now, that could well be overkill, for testing a small snippet of code, but it can be useful if the environment's
too complex to set up in a small block of code.
So there's another reason I prefer not to use globals to set the namespace, and that's because it was
introduced in Python 3.5, and so therefore it won't work in earlier versions.
So what we've done here will work, but I'm not going to run it right away.
And that's because the default number of times for timeit is 1 million runs of the snippet, which we
talked about earlier, and that would take about a minute to finish.
And that's a long time to stare at the screen.
I'm going to reduce the number to 1000 before running the program.
So to do that, we're going to put a comma after the parentheses, and number=1000.
Now just to be clear, I could've left that set to the default.
And you'd normally want to do that.
I just don't want to spend a minute in silence on the video, while we wait for it to finish.
Let's run that
And you can see, down the bottom, that it's printed out the time it took for our snippet to be executed 1000 times.
Now the exact time will depend on your processor speed,
how much memory your computer's got, and all sorts of other factors. Python version, for example. And if you've
got other programs running, that will also have an impact on how quickly the code executes.
It's likely that your computer's streaming this video, and doing that will certainly be taking up a fair
bit of your processor's time as well.
Now my Mac's busy recording this video, at the same time as I'm performing these timing tests.
So these aren't really ideal conditions to be doing this, for either of us.
I'd be very surprised, frankly, if you got the exact same value as me; but that's actually not what the
timeit module's for.
It's used to compare different code snippets, not to work out exactly how long your code took to execute. So
running different snippets on the same computer will give a good indication of which one is the fastest.
But be aware of what else your computer is doing at the same time, and ideally close down any other programs
that aren't essential to the test. Alright, so let's finish the video here. In the next video,
We'll start looking at that setup argument, which I talked about as an alternative, to fix that error we got
with locations.
So I'll see you in the next video.