So in this video, we're gonna start
talking about an object-orientated term
called inheritance, or called inheritance,
and specifically how that applies to Python programming.
So I'm gonna start off by explaining
what inheritance is,
and then we'll move into some coding
to go through some examples of inheritance,
and inheritance in Python,
and also gonna give you an overview
of the benefits it can bring to your code.
So let's swing over to a slide and go through that.
Okay, so let's talk about
a real world example of inheritance.
Now, different types of objects in the real world
can have a certain amount in common with each other.
For example, a seagull, a crow, and an eagle are all birds,
and so are ostriches and penguins.
So in other words, they share
their being-a-bird trait, so to speak.
They all have a beak and wings,
things that they inherit by virtue
of them being birds.
Another example is Monopoly, the board game,
Blackjack the card game, and Halo the computer game.
They're all inherently games,
so again, they share that trait,
the trait of being a game.
But they're also different as well.
Now, while they do share similarities,
they are different in their own right.
And as I mentioned, Monopoly is a board game,
Blackjack is a card game, and of course,
Halo is a video game.
So the point here is that they share similar properties,
being a game in this case,
but also they've got differences as well.
Now, for example, Halo, being a video game,
as I mentioned, and it works
on a video game console or a computer.
Likewise, Blackjack is a card game,
and Monopoly is a board game,
but of course they can still work on a computer.
There's a computer version of both of those games.
Now, getting back to the birds example,
now our birds do share a lot of traits.
They all have feathers, for example,
and that's one of the things that makes them birds.
So what we can do is, we can define a base class
that objects are based on in Python,
things that are common for classes
that derive from the base class.
And then we can allow a class
to define the unique characteristics of itself.
So in other words, we have a base class,
then something that inherits from that
to make it something else again, making it unique.
Now, the base class in this example here is bird.
You can see, you can see the bird example in the image.
And from that, all the birds inherit a beak and wings.
But each type of bird also has things
that make it different from the others.
Now, eagles have incredibly good eyesight, for example.
Now while you may be pleased
if you spot a MacDonald's from 400 metres,
eagles can literally see things two miles away.
They can see a rabbit two miles away,
which is pretty amazing.
So all our birds inherit some base properties
from their base class,
which is often referred to as the superclass.
Now they also inherit methods,
so all our birds can walk and eat,
but the individual bird classes also have
their own unique properties and methods.
So in this case, penguins can swim,
and ostriches can run, for example.
Now these individual bird classes
are referred to as subclasses.
So crow is a subclass of bird,
which makes bird a superclass of crow.
Now the idea of subclassing can be taken further,
so we could add subclasses of bird,
such as flying bird and flightless bird.
Now, eagle is a subclass of flying bird,
and ostrich is a subclass of flightless bird.
In our example, eagles, crows, and gulls
inherit the ability to fly from the flying bird superclass.
Ostriches and penguins aren't inheriting anything
from their flightless bird superclass in this example,
but they still inherit their beaks and wings
from the bird superclass.
Now, ostriches have a run method,
and penguins have a swim method,
so a class can introduce other properties and methods
in addition to the ones that it inherits.
So a class can have more than one superclass in a hierarchy,
like in this slide.
Now in Python, classes can inherit directly
from several superclasses,
which is known as multiple inheritance.
Now, many programming languages don't allow this,
so the class structure ends up being
strictly hierarchical, as I've shown here.
Java classes, for example,
can have more than one superclass,
but it has to be hierarchical.
Now, Python does allow multiple inheritance,
but I strongly recommend you avoid it
until you're really comfortable
with classes and inheritance.
And once you're really comfortable
with classes and inheritance,
I recommend you avoid multiple inheritance. (chuckles)
Seriously, though, I do recommend you
really look at avoiding multiple inheritance.
Now the sphinx may have inherited the head of a human,
the body of a lion, and the wings of a bird,
but you don't see many sphinxes wandering around.
So if nature's decided that multiple inheritance,
is a bad idea, who am I to argue?
Seriously though, having said that,
multiple inheritance can be an extremely powerful tool
when used correctly, but I'm not going to cover
multiple inheritance in this course,
but what I will do is mention it now and then
to point out places where you could really
hit some of the pitfalls,
if you decided to use multiple inheritance
or a multiple inheritance relationship in the future.
So coming back to our examples here,
flying bird is a subclass of bird,
and eagle is a subclass of flying bird.
Now eagle is also a subclass of bird,
because its immediate superclass, flying bird,
is a subclass of bird.
So just to labour the point one more time,
flying bird is a superclass of the three classes
eagle, crow, and gull, and it's also a subclass of bird.
So you might be asking at this point,
"Tim, why should I bother to go
"through all this level of complexity?"
Well, in answer to that, firstly,
it allows you to write code once,
and then for that code to be used automatically
by other classes.
Now, if we created an eagle object,
it would automatically get beak and wing,
and wings properties,
together with any methods that we'd created,
or we had created, in the bird class,
and that's without us having to write
any code in the eagle class.
So this leave you to define
the unique characteristics of a class,
rather than having to reinvent the wheel
each time you create a new class.
So in other words, you can write that code once,
put that code in the super class,
and then any class that extends or inherits from that class,
they're the same thing effectively,
is going to be able to take advantage
of the properties or methods
that are defined in the superclass.
All right, so that's our overview of inheritance.
Let's go back to the code
and start working at an example in our game project.
All right, so we're gonna continue with the game project
that we created in the previous video,
just to make sure that,
so make sure you've got that class,
that project open.
Now, we're going to open the project pane,
and we're going to create a superclass called enemy.
And this'll be the base class
for all the things our players will have to fight
in this fictional game.
So I'm gonna right-click on the project here,
and we're gonna create a new Python file.
Select Python file, we're gonna call this enemy,
making sure it's a lowercase E at the start there.
And click on okay, or press enter.
And we're gonna work on this class now.
Now we're gonna store hit points
and also the number of lives,
and we're gonna need to initialise the attributes for those.
And we should also give the enemy a name.
So let's start with a class definition, class enemy.
And we'll do a def, parameter constructor, init.
And we're going to include some extra parameters,
so name equals enemy,
and hit underscore points is equal to zero,
and lives is equal to one.
Then we're gonna do self.name equals name,
self.hit underscore points equals hit points.
And then self.lives equals lives.
So this is a superclass,
and any class that extends this class or inherits,
or inherits from this class, enemy,
should always have name, hit points, and lives attributes,
and in the game scenario, it's probably quite reasonable
to assume that any enemy would have those attributes.
But let's also add a method,
which we'll call take damage.
So we're gonna do a def, take underscore damage,
to create a new method.
And it's going to have one parameter, damage.
And we're gonna do remaining points
is equal to self.hit underscore points, take damage.
Then we're gonna put if, remaining points,
is greater than or equal to zero,
then we're gonna do self.hit underscore points
equals remaining points,
then we're gonna print a message.
Print, I took, placement field points damage,
and have, in another replacement field, left.format.
We're going to do damage comma self.hit underscore points.
And we're gonna have an else there, else,
self.lives minus equals one.
So what we're doing here is we're subtracting the damage
from the number of hit points that the enemy has,
and then checking to see if they've still got any left
after that damage is inflicted.
Now if the number remaining is zero or more,
we update the hit points and print a message
showing how much damage was taken,
and also how many hit points are still left.
But if, however, their hit points drop below zero,
then we take a life off instead.
Now we should probably check to see
if we've got any lives left,
but we're demonstrating concepts here,
we're not creating a full game.
This could be a useful exercise
for you to try it yourself, though,
to make sure you've understood
what we've covered in this tutorial.
All right, so we've got a basic class here.
We're storing the name, hit points, and lives,
and we've got a constructor where we can set,
where we do set the initial value of those attributes.
So I'm gonna add another method,
which is basically a copy of this
string method from the player class.
Even though I could probably just copy it and change it,
I'll just type it in, 'cause it's fairly short.
So underscore underscore string,
underscore underscore, self,
and then we're gonna return,
and it's going to be name, colon,
starting your left replacement field,
which is left curly brace, zero.name,
right curly brace, comma, lives, colon, space,
left curly brace, zero.lives,
right curly brace, comma, space, hit points,
colon, space, left curly brace, zero.hit underscore points,
right curly brace.format self.
Okay, so that's actually it.
So okay, and we're using this to print out the attributes,
so we don't have to keep writing long print statements
to check that everything's working.
Okay, so that stuff, that's similar to stuff
I've already covered in earlier videos in this section.
Now, we're not going to actually
create enemy objects directly,
although we could do that if we wanted to.
But this is really just for use as a base class,
so that all the specific enemies
have these basic properties.
So think about like a bird class.
You don't get animals that are just birds.
They're a particular type of bird.
So I'm gonna create one enemy, enemy object,
just to test the class, though,
to make sure that everything's working
before we go extending the class.
So I'll go back to the main file.
We're gonna delete all the code, now,
that we've used to test the player class.
So let's just delete all of that.
Then we'll start on line five.
And line five we're gonna type from enemy, import enemy.
Then we're gonna do random underscore monster
is equal to Enemy, capital E.
And we'll just say, we'll call it basic enemy,
then pass 12 for the number of hit points,
and one for the number of lives.
Then we're gonna print the random monster,
then we're gonna do
random monster.take underscore damage four,
then we're gonna print random monster.
Okay.
Let's just run that and see if it's gonna work for us.
And see, we've created the basic enemy,
lives one, hit points 12, took four points of damage
and they've got eight points left,
eight hit points left,
and we got confirmation at the second printout.
All right, so let's take the,
or let's test the take damage method a bit more.
Let's see what happens when the hit points drop below zero.
And actually, I'll clean this up completely
and put this back onto line one.
We don't need a player at all for now.
So let's add a couple of extra lines here.
So we'll do another eight there.
It should take it to zero hit points,
and then we'll do another one that takes another nine,
just to see what happens.
So let's actually run this.
And you can see, we've got a basic enemy 12,
lost four points, eight left,
it had eight and then lost eight to have zero left.
And then we've just got the printouts.
The lives, you can see there, has dropped down to zero.
So that's working fine.
I do suggest you always test all the paths
throughout your code.
So if you put in some conditions like we did,
when we check for the hit points dropping to below zero,
they'll make sure you use data
that will test the alternative path
to make sure it works as well as
the path you're assuming will work most of the time.
All right, so I'm gonna finish the video here.
In the next video, we're going to start
getting into the good stuff.
We're going to start inheriting from that class,
and this is where it's going to be getting interesting.
So I will see you in the next video.