In this video we're going to go ahead
and download and install Python or
rather get Python 3 working on this
computer. Now we don't actually have to
download and install anything on most
Linux distros and that's because it
normally comes pre-installed with both
Python 2 which we won't be using in this
course and the newer Python 3, so to
confirm that till you've got python on
your Linux distribution and I'm running
a bunty Linux 16.04 in this
example, just open a terminal or command
window I'm going to click on terminal
and so you can then type Python to see
whether something comes up and you can
see in my case I haven't actually
installed anything but Python 2 was
installed as a default program with this
version of Ubuntu Linux. So version 2 as
I mentioned isn't what we're going to be
using in this course, so I'm going to do
a ctrl D to exit out of that. The other
thing we can check it is we can type
Python and then the number 3 on the end
without any spaces press enter and that
also shows that we've got Python 3
installed as well. So you can see there's
two separate versions that are already installed
meaning that unlike the Windows and Mac
versions, we don't need to do any
installation, we can use the version of
Python that is already installed.
Now Python does get updated and in fact if
you went to the website right now for
python.org, you'd see that the latest
version is python 3 point six point two,
so we've got a slightly older version
but look it'll work just fine in this
course and there's no sort of reason not
to rush an upgrade and just a warning
actually if you are thinking about doing
that, be careful because python is
heavily used within the GUI of many
Linux distributions. So if you
accidentally uninstalled Python or
start you know installing different
versions and so on and so forth you can
get yourself into a situation where
Linux won't boot or at least I won't
have a GUI interface and that can be
really difficult to recover from. So for
that reason our recommendation is just
to stick with the version of Python that
is already in your Linux distribution,
so long as it's three points something in
my case you can see I've got three point
five point two, we're actually good to go.
Alright so I'm going to do a control d
to get out of that, the other thing we
need is something called idle which is
an editor that
we're going to be using at least early
in the course to test some Python code
out. So we can type in idle,
idle and that doesn't work because it
hasn't been installed and that would
have been the older version that suits
Python 2 and Python 3 would use something
called idle 3 but you can see that's
also not installed, so we need to go
through the process of installing that
for a Ubuntu Linux, so to do that I'm
going to type in sudo apt - get a space
between those two words space install
space idle3 or idle3 press enter,
I'm going to type my password, I can top it.
Okay, so now go through and it's actually
asked if I want to install it so I'm
going to push yes or top y and press enter
it's going to go ahead and install idle3
for us and you'll be seeing how to use
that program in the next video. Now it's
complete as you can see there, so I can
then just go ahead and type idle 3 and
you can see that's now popped up a
Python shell and within that window now
we can start typing some Python commands
but I'm going to finish the video here
now. In the next video we'll go ahead and
start using this Python shell to type in
a few commands so see you in the next video.