so continuing on from our previous video
so we ended up talking about variables
but saying that when a variable is
bound to an instance of a class in
Python its referred to as a data attribute now their other object orientated
terms  for the same thing so you might
find variable attributes also called
fields in languages such as Java or data
members in C++ and I'll introduced yet
another term shortly
one borrowed from the small talk
language but I over simplified things
here and now we will be talking
about different kinds of methods and
attributes later but that's the basic
jargon relating to classes which you
should probably become familiar with
now before I summarise these terms
there's another way to use a string
replacement fields that is useful when
dealing with classes so because Kenwood
and Hamilton are objects we can specify
their attributes in the replacement
fields and let's have a look at that
to see how we can do that so we are gonna add
that on line 20 we type....
....
...so here because Kenwood and
Hamilton are objects we can specify
their attributes in the replacement
fields so if we run this just to confirm
we should see the identical results the
print out as you can see their exactly the same but looking at
the code I will argue that line 20 is easy to read because
you can see immediately which attributes
are being used at each point in the
string and of course on line 18 you couldn't see
that because there wasn't anything in the
braces so just to summarize where we are at just gonna paste in that code in their now paste in those
comments to be more precise so a class is a
template for creating objects all
objects created using the same class
will have the same characteristics
object is an instance of a class instantiate we didn't used the word instantiate but
that is how the process of creating an
instance of a class method is a function
defined in a class and attribute is
a variable bound to an instance of a
class so as you can see here a class is a
template for creating objects the
template defines the attributes and
methods that all instances of the class
will have now although this is not
true
of other object oriented programming
languages in Python a class is also
exactly the same thing as a type other
languages might refer to Kingwood in
our sample program is being
of type kettle but they also have
types that are not classes but in Python every type is a class which is why we
were able to call the add method of our int object at the start of the previous
video
an object is another name for an
instance of a class then once the class
has been defined it is the actual
instances that are used in a program to
store the values of the attributes and
perform actions on them and you saw
instances being created on line 9 and
line 16 on the screen so when
creating a new object from a class
definition the terms uses instantiating
an object and that's just a fancy word
for creating an instance of a class but
you should be familiar with that term
now method is a function as bound to an
instance of a class now in the Tkinter
videos you might recall we created
instances of the back label and canvas
classes and we used their grid and pack
methods to place them on the screen and
finally an attribute is a variable that
is bound to an instance of a class so
the kettle variable and kenwood can keep
track of the values of its making
price without affecting the attributes
of the Hamilton object which has got its own values for those attributes so as I
hinted at earlier this is a slight
over-simplification in the last two
definitions and i will be explaining a bit more
about that a little bit later on in the
section but we have to walk here before we
can run so those definitions will give
us something to work with while we get
the hang of classes and object oriented
programming in general so continuing on now with our kettle class at the moment
it has 2 data attributes make and price and a single method called init
__init__ which you can see is
showing on line three and if you look at
that lit looks like it's sets the values for
the attributes but also looks a little
strange
now as I explain what's going on here I'm gonna be
referring to quite a few things whos names
start with and end with 2 underscores and
it's going to get a lil bit tedious
if I keep saying __ all the
time so I'm just going to use the name
of the object and you can see on the
screen that its got underscores around
it but I will review this use of
underscores and how it relates to
classes later on but just keep in mind
that time when we refer to something for
example on line 3 as init I'm referring to __init__
now we looked at
most of the users of underscore around
variable names in the previous section
and theirs a little bit more to add to that
once we get more into classes now this
class
obviously doesn't do a great deal and
theirs not really a lot going on and it's
not really a lot you can do with a
kettle other than switching it on and wait but
I will add a method to do that before looking at
more complicated classes now the Python
style guide pep8 by the way
recommends just single blank line
between methods inside a class which is
different to the recommendation and
there should be two blank lines between
top level functions in a module so if you
use 2 blanks lines then IntelliJ will show
warning and personally I like to leave 2
blank lines after class definitions
but this is not covered in the style guide
and you won't get a warning unless you leave more than two blank
lines and
I'm gonna add a second method now
and if we start this....and notice as I press the left bracket
IntelliJ automatically added the self parameter
so as I mentioned functions that are bound to a
class called methods and main difference
between a method and a function is the
presence of this self parameter that's been
added automatically just go ahead and
finish this method....and just a reminder if I go to and add that as a
second add 2 lines between methods we get
the warning from IntelliJ 2
blanks lines so if your in a
class only have one line between methods
to remove that warning and you might be
wondering what is the self parameter well so there's nothing really special
about the name self or the parameter and
you have called it anything you wanted avoiding
name conflicts with other objects of course
but unlike to key word this in Java for
example self is just the name of a
parameter the important thing is the
presence of the parameter not what its
called so having said that the
convention is that it's called self and
although this is not enforced in any way
it's not a good idea to change the
convention is so well established that
tools may expect to be called self and may not
work if you use another name in fact
as we have just seen IntelliJ automatically use the
name self for it
when we are defining the method just now so what is
self
well the answer is that it's a reference
to the instance of the class now if you
used to C++ or Java then you can think
of it as equivalent to this and it's
used to refer to instance variables and
you could see that we're doing that
on lines four five and six and again on
line 9 and although we've use many methods in the early
lectures in this course we've never had to
specify an argument for the self
parameter and this is because Python
supplies the value automatically when
calling the method now I will talked about this
a little bit more in a minute but first
let's call the method and check to see
if it is a kettle or not so we type....
....and notice that again when I typed that....
....you can see the definition shows the
self parameter but when I press enter it automatically
there's no parameter passed in the
brackets and if we just confirm that....
...and if we run this first
time we ran it on line 33 was false
that's because up here on line six we defined it as false second time after
calling Hamilton.switch_on the variable the attribute in this case for
our hamilton instance was set to true in other words
the value of the hamiltons instance on
started off as false because that's what it
was initialized to in the constructor
and calling the switch-on method on line
34 set to true which is the value of
course we are getting when we print out the value for the second time on line 35 now the
term constructor by the way refers to a
special method that is executed when an
instance of a class is created or
constructed in Python this is the init
method that you can see defined on line 3
and as you saw when I typed in line 34
we don't provide a value for the
self parameter when calling the switch_on method when you call a method
on an instance
Python automatically provides a reference to
the instance as the first parameter to
the method now we can see this in a bit more
detail by not using and instance but
calling the method the class itself
instead so we come down here and put this
on lines 37 we can type....
...so if we run that you can see that we got the value true
and of course Hamilton initially when we created the instance of the
object was then constructor made it the value false that by calling this method in an
alternative ways you can see they're
using the class definition initially you
can see what's happening there and the
parameters has been passed so instead of
using an instance of kettle to call a
method we've use the class itself because
there is no instance here the value for self
has to be specified and failing to do so
would give an error so the two forms have
exactly the same effect and as you can see
when we ran the program kettle switch on
ended up returning true so we can see
that it was updated correctly so lets go
back to the definition again I just want to
go back and delete this out...just to confirm that we may have miss this the first and when I add the bracket not the parameter
showing up there as self so its asking for
that parameter in this case and I can
change it too kenwood but again just to confirm if we do the
alternative syntax......so when I do that
noting that the self parameter
is showing at the top of the pop up but when
I press enter notice how it didn't ask for the
parameter in this case because it knows
we've already got an instance that we're working
on
so the implementation of classes in Python can create and some unexpected
behavior
partly because it's a mix of modular
three and C++ with some small talk thrown
in for good measure and once again if you are
learning object oriented programming for
the first time using Python then you'll
probably be quite happy with the way
things work that's not to say you won't have to concentrate but there shouldn't be
any surprises but for C++ and Java programmers it might be a good idea to put what you already know to the back
of your mind and be prepared to learn a
new way of thinking about things when it
comes to classes and object-oriented
programming in Python
now just like everything else in Python
classes are dynamic and it can be modified
after their created now to see this in
action and reinforce my previous comment
about surprises for C++ and Java
programmers I'm going to add a measure
for the keyword kettles power and
kilowatts let's go ahead and do that so
come down here to line 41 a bit more
space so we can see.....
....
so this case now the Kenwood instance
of the kettle class now has another
data attribute called power with the
value 1.5 now remember that variables
in Python come into existence the first
time they're assigned a value and the
same thing is true for instance
variables which is the small talk name for data
attributes so here I created a data attribute for the Kenwood object called power
and I gave it a value of 1.5 so the term instance
variable is useful because it describes
power as a variable that is bound to an
instance of the kettle class so as a
result the following code I'm gonna add
shouldn't be surprising.....
...and if we run this we get an error message attribute kettle object has not attribute power so if I close that
down again and that's because the Hamilton
instance doesn't have a power attribute
because if you're not created one by
assigning a value to it on line 43 we added
an instance variable for the Kenwood
instance of the kettle class but of course we didn't
do that for the Hamilton instance and
that's why we got an error when we run
the program
alright so I'm going to finish this
video here now in the next video we're going to talk more
about objects and find a bit more
about instance variables
and continue on generally speaking in our discussion
and in our journey finding out more
about object oriented programming in Python see you in the next video