Alright, so let's now create the first
Python file for this project. We're going
to call it lists_intro.py. In Python, a list is enclosed in square brackets.
Back in the previous section, we
saw a slide with a list of computer
parts, so let's type that in again. So
computer_parts
is equal to left and right
square brackets, then in double quotes
each item, so it can be computer in the
first one in double quotes, comma monitor in
double quotes comma keyboard
in double quotes with a comma.
Then mouse in double quotes with a comma, and
finally mouse mat in double quotes and
then we've got the right square bracket as
well. Now you'll often see list literals,
which these, are split up, so that each
item is on a new line. I'll be talking
about this later, when we've got a more complex list.
For now what I'm going to do, is press ENTER after each of the commas, to split the list up,
and also, the last right
square bracket, I'll put onto a
separate line as well. Alright, so that's
a very simple list. So computer_parts
is a list of strings here - the names of some common computer
parts for a computer. I mentioned
previously, that square brackets are used
in three places in Python and this is
the third use. We've seen them, previously, being
used to index a sequence and for slices.
They're also used to create lists, as we're
doing here. So inside the square brackets,
we've got the items in the list,
separated by commas. Alright, so that's a
very simple list, but because it is a
sequence type, we can iterate over it,
using a for loop. So let's go ahead and
do that. So I'm going to type for part in
computer_parts: and the next
line indented, print parentheses part.
Run the program, and you can see we've got
each item of our list displayed in the
output pane. So we can refer to
individual items in the list, using their
index position as well. It works exactly
the same as we've seen with strings.
The third item in the list is keyboard, so
that's at index position 2, remembering
that indexing starts at 0. So let's have
a look at that: print left and right
parentheses here, to make a space between lines, and then on the next line, print computer_parts
left square bracket 2
right square bracket and right
parenthesis. So if you run that, you can
see we get the keyword, or the word
keyboard, printed out. Now you can also
slice a list, and that works
exactly the same as we've seen for strings. What
I'll do is print out a couple of
examples to revise what we've already done.
So print parenthesis computer_parts left square bracket
0:3 right square bracket then right
parenthesis, and on line 15, print
parentheses computer_parts
left parenthesis minus 1. We've got our
right square bracket and right parenthesis. So if you run the program now,
you see that the first slice - that's
the code there on line 14 -
that's produced the first 3 items from the list,
in this case, computer, monitor and
keyboard. Note that the output here is in
square brackets, and that indicates that
slicing a list produces another list. Now
line 15 is a Python idiom, and returns
the last item in the sequence - the last
item in the list, in this case - which was
mouse mat. And we can confirm that by
looking at our setup on line 1. Alright, so
that's all been revision so far. It's not
surprising that indexing and slicing
works the same with a list as it did with
a string, and that's because they're both
sequence types. But there's one big
difference between strings and lists:
strings are immutable, which means they
can't be changed. Lists, on the other hand,
are mutable. In other words, you can
change the contents of a list.
I'll explain those terms in more detail, in
the next two videos, and then we'll look
at ways to change a list's contents. See you
in the next video.