so far we've been writing programs more or less largely contained every
everything they need in a single
Python file now there were a couple of
exceptions when we imported random to make our
guessing game more interesting and of
course when we also imported shelve in
the last section dealing with
file input and output now the Python
documentation refers to a file
containing a Python program such as
we've been creating as a script but that
said it's also possible to produce
Python code that is not intended to be
executed directly instead to the
provides functions classes and
variable definitions etc that are
designed to be used by other programs
we managed to do quite a lot without
importing modules into our scripts
the part of power of Python
is that it allows us to use modules to
provide that extra functionality there's
nothing to stop us from creating our own
modules and will be looking how to this
later in this section in order to use a
module we have to import it into our program
using the import command and of course you
saw that in the last section this
can take a couple of forms actually so
let's have a play with the Python turtle
module just to really understand how
import works so create a new file
and setup a new project
create a new Python file and call it Turtledemo
now the turtle module is based on the
educational programming language from
the late 1960's called logo and that
allowed amongst other things children to
control an on-screen turtle by giving
it simple instructions to move and turn now
there is a pen attached to this turtle so when it
moves it draws a line behind itself to
so let us type in a simple example that's
gonna move the turtle around the screen
gonna start with importing the module.....
....and we type a few commands first things first will type in
the command to go forward so...
...we can get it turn right 250 degrees....
......can try going getting it to go forward again.....
....so a simple example moves the turtle forward
turns right 250 degrees and it moves
forward again so run it and did you see what
happened briefly you saw the command
come up on the screen or little box come
up on the screen, and you can see
drawing something and then quickly close
the program down and that's how it
works because our program ended the
graphic screen closed down so
there is a good way to prevent this and we can
import another module to do that called time so we can type...
...below the first import and then create another line of code on line 8.....
we will get it to sleep for 4 seconds so we type time....which is getting to
get to sleep before seconds so we should
be able to see it now so run it again  and you
see what happen was that it went forward turned
250 degrees to the right and then
continued on as you saw that it slept for
4 seconds giving us a time to see the
turtles drawing on the screen before the
program ended and it close it down now
interestingly enough there's actually a bug
in the IntelliJ product both IDEA and Pycharm
and that causes them to display a warning about
cannot find reference forward in  turtle.py so
if we hover this and have a
I'll fix that part because it needs a blank line in the end
here is the actual error itself you can see it saying it cannot
find reference for two turtle.py and as you saw
the program is fine so clearly not a problem
with the code but IntelliJ can struggle
with importing from some modules and
noticed that importing the module from
time using time module I should say using the
the sleep method had no problems it found
that ok so warnings are useful or will
become less useful if they are incorrect because
ultimately that can detract from the
ones we should be paying attention to
and start ignoring them all together so
in this scenario where you convinced
it's a warning
that it is a bug where we're pretty sure
that it's a bug here right now with
IntelliJ we can suppress them so they
can be safely ignored what we can do is
do that and one way is on a statement by
statement basis so come up here and add a new
line for we can put a.......
you can see what happens as soon as I finish typing that the
a warning disappeared so that handles
suppressing the error or the warning I
should say just on a single line it would
soon get annoying having to do that with
each line to get rid of each warning message so what you can do is
disable it for all future turtke commands which  isprobably be wise in this
case
because we still got 2 warnings here to the right hand side so we
come over here to line 6 click on
right on line 6 see that little pop up comes up so we can
select the pop up and use the third down here mark all
unresolved attributes of turtle as
ignored click on that you can see that
then disappeared all the warnings and we got the green tick which means
as far as IntelliJ is concern everything is ok so after doing that
you could delete line 4 because the
command on line 6 when we right
clicked it overwrote that command anyway
we have taken those warnings off let us just say for
some reason IntelliJ fix that error
and it's now something you want to put
back on again you want to enable
warnings again to do that it is on a file by file
basis so you open the file you want to deal with come up here to
code to analyze
click on Config Current File
Analysis
click on configure inspections and what
you need to do is you need to scroll
down and there will be a list of all these other bits
and pieces you want one that says Python
and if there has been a change made you will notice
it will be showing in blue it is showing
in blue here because we have made that
change so what I'm going to do is come down
to unresolved references and
that's showing in blue again and if we want
to get rid of that you can see here the ignore
references we can add some more here
if we have some but otherwise we can click on it and click on minus
to remove it and the warnings then come
back
and if we go back in to analyze again
analyzed Config Current File Analysis
configure inspections
and looking back here now notice now its not in
blue anymore and also come up here too
Python that is no longer in blue either so that's a quick way to
determine whether you actually made that
any changes to this particular model or not
so I'm gonna re add that again because it's
just an annoying warning we do
wanna get rid off so I'm gonna click on right here and select the
pop up click on mark all unresolved attributes
of turtle as ignored again and we get your green arrow back again
so just running the app again so you can see we got our
drawing sits there for a few seconds
four seconds to be exact and closes down
so the pause is a bit arbitrary so the correct way to
give us time to view the reptilian artwork is to use the turtles module done
method this also me so we can get rid of
the time import so I'm going to
delete the time import and instead of time.sleep we are gonna put....
essentially now
the masterpiece is going to stay there until
we close the window so we just sit here for a few seconds
to make sure you can see nothing's
happening so we literally had to come
over here and close it down for that
change to take effect and for our program to
exit the other thing to remember was
with using the import command to import
the turtle module we can then use all
the objects it provides by prefixing
them with turtle and a dot so turtle.forward as you saw turtle.right etc
because we also saw that with time.sleep until I just remove the code there now there is another way to import
from a module specifying just things we want to
import as supposed to doing an
import of everything and what I mean by
that is I'm going to delete that line on the
first line the import and we could do
something like this instead of we can be
more selective we can say from....so we are only going
to import the first method called for and
then by doing that I can get rid of
this turtle. at the start and notice how it has found
forward because its found and look for it
in the turtle module so again essentially what we're
doing is we're telling Python to import
just the forward method from turtle and
doing it this way means that we don't
have to keep prefixing forward with
turtle. all the time and if we run
this we do get some errors and the errors on
lines for 4 5 and 7 saying that
turtle is not defined but we could fix it if we
wanted to by changing our import on line 1 putting a...
for the right method and done for the right one as well and
if we run that again we should find it
works fine and sorry had to get rid of
the turtle. before our commands and
notice how these are all enabled now
so it has found those now if I run it we find that it works
quite nicely and we only imported those
functions from the
turtle module that we actually need to
so close it down so doing it this way can be useful for
using a particular object a lot in the
program but the problem is it only
import things that are specifically
listed on the import line and as you saw
those errors until I remove them the other ones aren't available so what I can't do now is to do something
like....
....which is a valid command
if we run that now that is not going to work, unnamed turtle was
not to defined because again for that reason we
only specified the specific things
we wanted and we don't need to specify turtle.
and in actual fact turtle. doesn't
work because as far as Python is concerned that
module doesn't exist and the other things
we can't do either is type...try to run that...we get the error
turtle circle and if I comment this line and run it again we name circle is not
defined as well that's because we
haven't specified circle up here on line
1 so if wanted circle. to work I'll delete line 7 because we know how to do that we
could just add circle up here on line 1 to fix that after the comma but if want to get line 5
to to work like this what we can do is
below the from turtle command we can
also put an import....so we should find if we run it now everything works fine
and you can see we got a different result there we got a circle
created and then we went on and plotted
or started plotting the triangle
so that's good so that works fine
so this does demonstrate the two different ways
an import can be used and the effect each
it has on how you can use the imported
objects generally speaking you wouldn't
want to mix methods with the same module so
in our example what you wanna do import
turtle
on line 2 you don't only just have an import turtle like on line 2 or you import the existing
individual methods class variables and
variables but rarely combined both
because obviously that can lead to
confusing code especially because turtle
.forward would also work as well as
forward now and that could be quite
confusing to someone reading your code and
wondering why things are different and
why you've done things sort of both ways so it is
good to choose one way or the other now there is one way
to use import that's definitely not
recommended
so it's possible to import everything
or more actually almost everything from the
module using import star
so we could do something like here change our references here from turtle
import I put import * and get rid of this
import turtle on line 2 and I've got to delete line 5 as well so
we are left with our commands and i'll put the circle
command back.....so we should be able to run that so you can
see that work ok and depending on
your operating system you may get
some errors here in my case i didn't get any
errors and there was a tick their but IntelliJ may struggle when underlining the
method calls in red but as you saw the
program will still totally run anyway although you
can import from a module in this way
with a star which will import everything
who's name does not start with an
underscore doing so is frowned upon it's
very useful to save typing when using an
interactive session in idle for example
but other than that you should really
avoid this way of importing now one
reason for that or you don't want to do that
is that you actually have no idea what
is being imported so an imported name can hid
one of your objects or you can hide
one of the imported names that
you need and just to give you an idea that
in this example we got to
demonstrate why this could be a problem
so lets just say we're going to use
the import start so what I'm going to do is put
something on line 1 ill put.....and we got our from turtle
import....
on line 3 we got our import I come to line
10 we have our done and we wanna do....so if we run this
we get a picture drawing just fine nothing
happens until we close down but once we
do closed and you can see that we
you get the message printed is a
function address of the turtle done
method and not the string message Well
done you have finished your drawing like you would expect
so that could be confusing but if we did it the other way as
well things could get even a little bit worse so if
we put the import on line 1 and change them around
so literally just changed lines 1
and 3 around and done nothing else if we
run this again it will work it will draw the picture or
starts to but then there's actually a
problem and the problem is when it
reaches the done line which is on line
10 and it says string object is not
callable so what's happening of course
is its trying to call or to treat the string as
a method and executing it rather than
using the done method from the turtle
import now of course this second
example in particular but also the first
one before I swap them over are really quite
contrived because we called the done method
with only a few lines defining the
string variable so that would be very
hard to miss the fact that something
wasn't right ordinarily but however if
you consider a program with hundreds of
lines of code mistakes like this would be
much easier to make and harder to find so
bottom line here is that unless you're
working in an interactive session do not
do an import star so I'm gonna finish
the video here now and in the next video
we are gonna start talking about the Python
Standard library so see you in that video