Okay, so here's where it gets interesting
when we look at extending this class
that we created in the previous video.
I'm talking about the enemy class.
So let's talk about having specific types of enemies
because the code work
that we've currently got in that enemy class
is of a very generic nature as you can see here.
So let's assume that we've got several
different types of enemies.
For example, let's start off and create a new class
and we're gonna call that one troll.
Now one of the enemies our player will have to face
will be a troll.
Now the reason we've been using a separate file
for our player and enemy classes
is to make it easier to switch between them in IntelliJ
so that we can examine the code
without having to scroll around too much.
Now there's not actually much code
in this enemy class at the moment
and troll is gonna be a subclass of enemy
so what I'm going to do is put our new troll class
in the enemy.py file which I've got activated now
along with the enemy class.
Now the Python style guide recommends
leaving two blank lines between classes.
So therefore, I'm going to actually start on line 20.
All right, so class Troll Enemy.
So that looks a bit different.
What have I actually done here?
Well, as I've said that troll would inherit from enemy,
you've probably guessed
that this is how you create a subclass.
Now a subclass remember is a class
that inherits from another class.
Now you may also hear it described
that troll extends the enemy class,
they both mean the same thing.
Now in fact, our enemy class is itself a subclass
and that's because each class in Python 3
ultimately inherits from a built-in class called object.
Now we haven't specified that on line one,
but we declared the enemy class
and that's because Python 3 allows a shortcut
for a class that has no super class other than object
so a class, in other words, inherits directly from object.
So in Python 3, we've got on line one this class enemy.
I'm just gonna comment that out.
That's exactly the same as typing it this way,
class Enemy object.
So both declarations do exactly the same thing.
They define a class called enemy that inherits from object.
Now the reason I've been saying in Python 3
is because this wasn't the case in Python 2.
Now in Python 2, that commented out declaration
would produce an old style class that behaves differently
to the new style classes you get by subclassing object.
However, in Python 3, there are only the new style classes
and they automatically inherit from object
even if you don't specify it
so even if you use a commented out form
in other words on line one.
Now this is a Python 3 course
so we're not really interested in the difference,
but I wanted to make you aware of it
so that you always use the second form
with object in parenthesis if you have to use Python 2
and wanna use the new style classes.
For that reason, it might be worthwhile
developing the habit of always using the second form.
Of course, if you find yourself working on Python 2 code
that uses the first form of the class without object,
then don't go refactoring it
without a great deal of thought.
In Python 2, you could change
the entire behaviour of the programme
just by changing class enemy as I've got on line one here,
up here at the top here,
to line two class Enemy object,
but again that's Python 2.
Not a problem with Python 3
which we're using in this course.
Okay, so back to troll,
so our troll class will inherit from enemy
and it'll have to access or have access to the attributes
that we defined in enemy.
The takeout is called damage method for example.
Now we really should write a constructor,
the init method for this troll class,
but let's start by saying what happens if we don't.
Now the first thing that's happening is we've got an error,
indent expected,
and that's because Python expects there to be some code
after the class declaration,
but we don't wanna provide any just yet.
Now fortunately, there's a very useful command
called pass that doesn't do anything
so I can just type that in there.
So pass doesn't do anything at all,
but unlike a comment,
it doesn't get ignored by the compiler.
So by including it in instruction that does nothing,
we've removed the syntax error
and our code will ultimately be able to run.
Now it may seem strange that an instruction to do nothing
is very useful,
but you'll come across pass in all sorts of places.
Now you may wanna catch an error, an exception,
that we've covered in section 13
to prevent the programme crashing,
but don't wanna do anything if the error happens.
For example, if your programme is reading a load of data
that was provided by people completing the survey,
you may have to convert their date of birth
into a valid Python date.
Now some people would rather not give their date of birth,
so that particular field could be blank.
So you could trap the error
when the code tries to convert no input into a date,
but there's no action that needs to be taken,
you just wanna skip that field
and continue passing or continue processing the data.
So that's a good time to use pass
so that you can catch the error
but continue without doing anything.
So you can find more information on pass
in the documentation.
But rather than give you a link this time,
I'm gonna show you one thing that may be confusing
when you search for Python documentation
using a search engine.
So if I open a browser
and do a search for pass in Python,
we've got stack overflow tutorials,
important stack flow, et cetera,
but I suggest always starting with links
to the Python documentation.
But with that said, you'll often find references
when you're searching for general Python information
to links that are Python 2.7,
as is the case in this fourth link here,
and obviously we want the Python 3 documentation.
Now the Python 2 documentation tends to be returned
because of the way the document is organised
so click the link anyway
and ignore the fact that it's for Python 2.
Then not surprisingly,
we get the documentation coming up for Python 2,
2.7 in this case,
but as you can see up in the top left is a dropdown
that lets you choose which version of Python
you're interested in.
So you can choose 3.5 from there
and I recommend you do that
to make sure the information you're getting
is for the right version.
So don't rule out those links
because they mention the earlier version of Python.
Once you get to the docs.python.org site
like where we are now,
you can still choose the version of Python
that you're interested in.
Now Python 3.6 haven't been released
at the time of recording this video,
but what it is you'll be able to get the documentation
for that version from here as well.
The same for Python 3.7 which is still in development.
Okay, back to our main programme,
so I'm gonna go back to main
and what we need to do now is import enemy and troll
without having to qualify them with a module name
so that we don't have to write enemy.troll
whenever we wanna create a new troll instance.
So I can put from enemy import Enemy
and we can just put a comma
Troll
and we're getting that warning because it's unused
but that we're going to change shortly.
Now we don't really wanna use the enemy class anymore,
but before I delete it,
I just wanted to show you how to import several classes
from the same module.
All right, so let's go down here on line 15
and we'll put ugly_troll is equal to Troll
then we gotta do print Ugly troll replacement field
.format ugly_troll.
Okay, we run that
and we can see down at the bottom,
the ugly troll printout
or the ugly troll information is being displayed,
but it's not too good at the moment though.
The name is still enemy as you can see
in the output down at the bottom
and the troll has got no hit points
so it's probably not gonna be
a very challenging enemy to fight.
Now we didn't add an init method
so creating a troll like this
uses the default values for the enemy class.
Now the enemy class init method takes three arguments
so we can create another troll
and pass some values to the constructor.
All right, so let's remove the code that created our enemy
so we're just working with trolls now.
So I'm gonna delete all this right up to there
because we don't need the enemy anymore
and then we'll add another troll as well
so we'll put another_troll is equal to Troll Ug, 18, 1
and we'll do a printout print another_troll
replacement field so no output .format and another_troll.
So this time I've created another troll with the name Ug
that takes or has 18 hit points.
All right, so let's create another troll, Ug's brother,
he's called Urg so we'll call it brother equals Troll,
we'll call him Urg and this guy's a bit of a brute
even by troll standards
and he can take 23 hit points and damage
so let's set that to 23 and print brother.
Now if you're used to overloaded constructors
in languages such as Java,
then you'd probably be quite happy
with what's going on here,
even if you can't quite work out how Python is doing it.
But if you've never used another language,
then this might be a bit confusing what I've just done.
So when you overload a method
in other programming languages,
you provide a method with exactly the same name
but taking different arguments.
So the ugly troll constructor on line three
doesn't take any arguments
and another_troll constructor on line six
takes or gets three arguments
and his brother Urg on line nine
and he has two arguments.
Now in Java, you'd need to write three constructors,
one for each case.
However, Python doesn't have the concept
of overloaded methods.
Now if you try,
the last method that you defined in the code
will be the only one that exists.
Now if you haven't used another object oriented language,
then don't worry about that last bit,
overloaded methods and so forth,
because Python doesn't have them
and I'm gonna be explaining how all this is working
in a minute.
But for those who have come from other languages
and thinking this looks like method overloading,
it actually isn't,
but it is how you achieve the same thing in Python.
All we've done here is use optional name to parameters
in the enemy class init method.
And it's really now different from using the print method
to print things out because on line 10,
we print brother
and that's the only argument we provided to the function.
Printout does take other arguments
so you could specify that there's no end of line character
for example.
So I'm gonna come along here.
Actually, let's do it on line seven, so another_troll,
and you save this before encoding
and equals and two double quotes,
an empty string in other words,
so when we do that,
we find the another_troll Urg and his brother argument
and his brother Urg are now printed on the same line
because we've removed the end of line
or replaced that with an empty string.
So this is not the best example
because we have to specify the name end.
That's because the print function
can take any number of strings to print
so just adding another one
to the list of arguments wouldn't work.
But for methods that have a fixed number of arguments,
you can provide them without using their names
as long as you keep them in the same position
that they were specified originally.
So when we don't specify any arguments on line three,
the default values that we specified
in enemy's init method are used.
And you can see we've got name equals enemy,
hit points equal zero, lives equals one.
So obviously the default values
are the ones that are after the equal sign on each.
We're going back here now to main.
On line six, all the values were specified.
And then on line nine,
only the two arguments were specified.
So name in this case on line nine gets the value of Urg
and hit points gets the value of 23
then the lives were defaulted to one
because of the way we have defined this
as the default value for the lives attribute.
So once again,
if you are used to languages such as Java or C++,
you can't actually overload functions and methods in Python,
but you can generally get the same effect
by using named parameters with default values.
All right, so I'm gonna stop the video here.
In the next video,
we're going to look at making our troll class
a little bit more useful but at the moment,
we could do exactly the same thing
by using the enemy class rather than a troll.
So in other words,
we could come back here and change that to enemy.
And if you run that,
we get exactly the same result.
So although troll is a subclass of enemy,
at the moment it's not a very useful one.
Now in the next video, we'll make some changes
and see the advantages of creating classes
that inherit from another class.
But just before I do that,
I'm gonna remove this and equals part on line seven.
Okay, so I'll see you in the next video.