ok so moving on in the last video you can see what we've got up to we've got the
interface working you can see below and we are getting closer to
what we're trying to achieve here we still got
some issues we've got to fix this left
hand border up so we can move things over
because obviously its too far to the
left so we will do that shortly but we also need
to add the ok and cancel button so lets do that next
and we want to align those to the right
edge so that they appear close to each other so we
get back to the code to do that we're
going to have these buttons so...
.....
...we are going to add that
but we're going to add a command to quit
as well I'll show you how to do that I have simple command you can
actually call that as well so....
...and extra points if you can remember how to go about doing that we did something
similar earlier in the code and it's using
command so.....
...so we need to specify the command so....basically if the
cancel button is clicked it is going to close it down ok so we specify those
we now need to add them to the grid so....
......
.......
...so thay you can see the OK button
is going to the east going right and
the cancel button is going west to
the left so therefore their aligned close next to each other
basically so the edges appeared
close to each other and you can probably
guess this mainWindow.quit it actually
closes down so its equivalent of us
clicking on
the close button in a window so it does it
automatically if the cancel button is
pressed two things to say about that
though
first things we should really probably
use destroy instead of quit although
quits gonna work destroys actually
kinder sounds weird destroyed sounds worst
that quit because it just stops the
main loop and deletes the widget and all
child widgets that's what destroyed does but quit method also stops the TCL
interpreter so you may have problems if
you're on your program in idle for
example because idle itself is
written into TKinter so it's probably a
good idea to use destroy but having said that quit will work so lets run it and cancel an
interesting enough canceled doesn't work now this is a very common mistake to make when
dealing with widget callback functions and this is why we are going to be
labeling the point slightly the correct
way to assign the function to the
command properties is to just use the
function name in this case mainWindow.quit
and if we come back and have a look at the code notice
how I put the brackets on the end and
if your using any other programming
language it probably very familiar with
that but when we use parentheses after
the function name were actually calling
the function and the result of the
functions assigned to the command
property now the quit method returns none
so the result is that clicking the
command or sorry the cancel button does
nothing because main Windows mainly
hasn't been started at a point when
quit is executed the loop is not terminated so
the incorrect assignment doesn't cause
problems but it also doesn't work either
so we can try we can change that leave it as it is leave that brackets as it is
but change it to destroy......
it would help if I type it correctly...now run that
now we get an error you see we haven't even been
able to run the program and the error is
can't invoke button command application has been destroyed so the value know is still being assigned
to the command property but the
destroy method deletes the mainWindow widget
and all the widgets placed inside so in actual fact the cancel button
itself is destroyed by the line of
code when the command properties being
sent and your error message states the application has been destroyed so what we need to do is correct the
assignment and the program will run fine so close it down
the main thing is again for these types
of things we don't specify the parentheses
because we don't want the function to
run we are assigning the function to be
called when the buttons is click so that's
why there's no parentheses there and
early on in the code we had command
use on line 33 notice I didn't have
parentheses after that either
so no we've done that we should be able to run
this and haven't got a crash which is good and
there's our demo we should be able to click canceled and
you can see that it's exited and we're
back at the IntelliJ with program close which is good so in the
previous video I've talked about rbValue.get we tried a few different values just to
see how the value change depending on what
radio button was clicked but also we're
changing the value set on line 43 so come
back and have a look
sorry line 42 so once it should check the file name it to should check path so if I run it again to
refresh what where up to so we got file name paths so the
currently the values is set to 2 so its going
to be defined as path so we will
leave it as that but we can change it as
the default if you wanna have that as a default and that's effectively what we've
done their on line 42 set it up so that
the first time we run this every
time we run the program that's going to be the default options if you wanted the first one to be the
default option just change it to one run
the program again
now we got the default being the file name now there's one other improvement we can make everything is about to close the
edges as I mentioned at the start of the
video so we should really add a bit of
padding so I'm going to add some code here at the top right up here
lets add it strait after the geometry to
do some padding to the left hand side
so you've seen padx before so I'm
going to be something similar.....
.....try running that
and see what it looks and we now got that padding to the
left hand side so that's everything not flush
against side now so it's much better for
us but the one thing about this layout I'll bring up the
other ones so you can see what we're
comparing it against one thing about
this layout is that we haven't looked at in
detail at the moment and it deserves to be
looked at is the weight property of the
rows and columns so how do we
arrive at the weight values and
that's the values we've used here in line
17 through 26 so what exactly are these values
doing and what do they mean well the
weight property probably doesn't do what may at first appear to do and we actually got an admission to make those
values were largely just made up in
fact there's a whole range of weights
we could have used to get pretty much
exactly the same appearance as the
values we've use so let's have a
look at how weight does behave and why
its not necessary to produce exact values
for it so one nice thing about the
IntelliJ product is that you can run a
Python program without terminating a
previous execution so we are going to use that
to make changes to the code and the compare
the results with the previous execution
just to see what effect the changes have
had to that program
and by dragging the GUI screens next to each other above and
below we can compare the precise
placement of the widgets after each change and so
let's do that now so stop the program
and run again propbably don't need to do that but will run it again so we got one copy running
that's is going to be our test version do
that first and then let's go back and
change all the weights on lines 17 through
26 change them all to 1 and run the program again......
...and run again oops typo and run it again....and now we've got
two versions running and lets have look at what's
changed
firstly we have a look at what's
horizontals so just look at the
horizontal alignments of the 2 you can see that
that setting all the column weights to 1
really has made very little difference
in the horizontal placement of the widgets
so you have might expected columns in the weight of 3 to be 3 times wider than column 0 and 1 which only
had a weight of one but obviously this
is not the case and the width of the first
two columns has grown really only
slightly you can their is a slightly wider their
now than it was in the top example which
was our first version before we made the
changes so the width and the columns and
heights of the rows are determined by
the sizes of the widgets placed in them
and the weight properties used when the
window is resized so column with the
weight of three will widen 3 times more
faster than a column with a weight of one when the
window size increases so just trying to
keep the windows overlay what we are going to do
is just resize and start on that we're
going to make it roughly twice the
size so start with the top one
roughly twice the size it doesn't have to be precies but we'll do the
same thing to this one what I'm going to do is
just set it there and expand so its roughly
the same size and move this down a little bit so
we got space here so the list box now in
the second wind where all the weights are equal
is now wider than the original window
with a weight of 3 the last three columns grew
faster than the first 2 which meant their wasn't really as much room for list box
to get wider as the windows were re-sized know
all the columns have the same weight the
list box can grow at the same rate as
all the others so the list boxes now
wider than what it was originally so gonna
set them back to roughly the size they
were.....
....so you can see how the row heights actually behave because the noticeable
difference in the sizing between the
results label and the entry box for
example like this code here this is significantly different here so with original weight of 10 for row 1 row
2 containing the results doesn't re-size very quickly compared to row
one but when all weights are equal its height
increases at the same rate now because
we've align the label with the top of the
cell and the entry box at the bottom the
greater row height now becomes apparent as
you can see on the right hand side so
when placing to widgets in the same
cell it's generally a good idea to give
the row or column a low weighting and
that's to prevent unsightly behavior
like this which is not a good look
when the window is started now if the
widgets are stacked above each other
like here set the weight low
and in if they are next to each other use the low column weight another tip is that there's very
little value in row 0 it's really just a
title for the window so give that row a
low weight compared to the rows that
actually have content and you can
see this bit by re sizing each window vertically which I'm gonna do now just do
that and just compare our results so......
.....you can see now that I've done that I
resize them vertically that row 0 occupies far more
space than its contents warrant in the
second example because we really wanted
to stay at the top because it doesn't
really need that extra space in face start looking and that's meant to
be a title so with the layout like this one when
re-sizing vertically there's really only
one widget that benefits from growing
and that's the listbox that's why it had a
greater weight originally so the values
I guess weren't entirely made up but
when re-sizing horizontally the list box can still
benefit for it for some extra space but maybe
so could the results box over here as
well so that could be an indication that
we shouldn't have put it in the same column
possibly as the radio buttons so tied
to the list box is the scroll bar but there is a problem with that when we re-size horizontally
so gonna close both of these now
so if we go through and undo those changes I'm
gonna close down the run window and control
z on the computer under to undo the
changes or in my case its MAC I'm
doing command z I'm just going back change all the
code so we got it back to what it was
before does changes so if we run the
program again now let's try shrinking
the window horizontally and watch what
happens to the scroll bar
...see it doesn't take long for the scroll bar to actually disappear obviously their are other issues on the
screen as well but the scroll bars is very
quick to disappear when we do that so at
this point people who haven't got a mouse wheel obviously I got one so I can scroll it
up but if someone doesn't have one the only way they going to be able to
scroll at this point is to use the arrows which I'm using up and down now and
clearly that is not an option for everyone we don't want to force people to have to use only one
way to scroll the values from our
list box and even if it doesn't vanish so open
up a little bit so the case it hasn't
vanish as you can see very quickly its
actually getting really really thin and its
really not usable so remember that
if a column grows more quickly when the
windows made wider its also going to
shrink more quickly when the window becomes narrower so what to do is to protect the scroll bar
column by giving it a much lower weight
than all the other columns for that
reason so it doesn't make much sense
for scroll bar to get wide anyways so a low
weight relative to the other columns
solves both issues here so
its also a good reason to place scroll bars in their own
columns or rows for a
horizontal scroll bar so looking at the ok button
its roughly half the width
of the cancel button and as you make the window narrower
it starts to disappear you can see that pretty
quickly its disappearing there so its columns should
probably have roughly half the weight of
column 4 also because the radio buttons
at the top are not expanded to the
width of the cell unless they susceptible
to changes caused by re-sizing so you can
see they are pretty consistent there so
that's good in that we can allow our column to
shrink faster
well although most of the documentation
mentions the importance and weight when
resizing we haven't come across any that
mentions that affects of weight are
generally more important when shrinking
window than when expanding it so what we
gonna do is just close this off so let's make a few changes to our column configurations we are gonna change the
weighting so the first one is weight equals a 100.....
.....so if we do that it should
behave in a more user-friendly fashion
and hopefully because of what I've discussed
you will understand why its gonna behave that so lets just check that it is going to do that so bring this over again so
now if we try and make it smaller
notice the scroll bar is a little bit better now, now we
can't get it perfect because it's
physically too small to fit the buttons
we can't really do much about it but you can see this scroll bar is a lot better than what it was and we've
got a better result than what we have in the past and likewise
expanding
not perfect but you can see we're getting there so by
starting with a sketch and drawing
a grid on it becomes quite easy to place
widgets where you want them and if I run
this again.....and obviously we talked about
this a few times but we had these
original sketches and obviously this was done in a Linux
but you could have sketch this out here but this is the part where talking about drawing
grids on them as well to figure out
where you can put your items by doing
that it comes quite easy to place widgets
where you want them now of course a GUI
builder such as the ones included in Microsoft Visual Studio or Delphi might make life a lot easier by language to be drag and drop but they
are really a convenience rather than as
necessity so GUI builders
are available for Python but as we haven't use them we can't give any recommendations
frankly I think you get a lot better
mileage by learning to do this manually
you can see that if do that sketch at
the start and you understanding how the grid
layout works the grid geometry manager and do
some testing as we have shown
you how to do throughout the videos you can
pretty well build any interface and you don't
really need to use a graphical builder as such certainly a
personal choice but we certainly would
prefer to be building them manually
as we've done here because it really helps
strengthen your understanding of Python so just wrapping this up in this example we saw
how to position widgets on the screen
obviously you can see our final example
down here of the code we also seen a few of
the widgets is available in tk we attached
that scroll bar to another widget and
connected them together to get the normal
behavior expected of a scrolling widget and
obviously we saw how to populate a list box
and spinner controls and we've been be
able to get the results from a group of
radio buttons so obviously there would be a
lot more that our UI needs to do in order
to be useful such as responding to
clicks on the buttons other than the
cancel which of course we added the code to do and
other things like to determine which item
from the list box was selected so all of that
requires a user functions but we'll be
talking about functions a few videos on
from now in the next we're going to be
doing a challenge so we're gonna come up
and give you a challenge to aid
through understanding of tkinter
so we will see you in that next video