So in the last few videos, we looked at timing code snippets using the timeit module. Now interpreting the results
reliably isn't easy.
And we've tried to point out some of the pitfalls you may encounter.
Now we also saw how to enable garbage collection, if that's likely to be an important factor in your
timings.
Now it is important to pay a lot of attention to what you're timing, and to the conditions under which
the code's running. Now, our example in the previous video didn't come up with any conclusive results,
and that's mainly because printing all the output is seriously affecting the results.
So in this video, we're going to start by modifying our code, so that all three of our code snippets do exactly
the same thing. And we'll also defer the printing until after the lists have been created, so that the
printing doesn't interfere with the results.
Now when changing code that's appearing in strings, or that appears in strings, as we've got here,
it's a good idea to convert it back to code first.
So that way, we can run the changed code to make sure there's no errors, before attempting to time
them.
So what I'm going to do is delete the quotes, and then take the opportunity to show you the other way
to pass your code to the timeit function, by enclosing it as a function.
So let's go ahead and make some changes here.
So I'm going to go back,
starting at the top of our code. Well actually, we're not making any changes to the location, so we'll leave that.
So basically starting here on line 20, we're going to delete these three lines,
and I'm going to make that, type in def nested_loop() colon.
We're going to indent all this for code, our for loop rather. I'm going to tab that.  Leave those two prints
there for now, and we're going to delete this other code, right down to the next for loop. And we're going to
add a function name there, so def loop_comp() colon. We're going to indent the code, tab it over.
And we're going to delete the next batch of code, and make a bit of space here.
def nested_comp() colon. Indent that
code as well. Then we're gonna delete this last one here.
Now the IDE is complaining because there should be two blank lines, before and after function definitions, sso
I'm going to fix that before continuing.
OK, now we still got all sorts of errors and that's because now, our dictionaries aren't defined.
So the easiest way to fix that is to duplicate the string, then remove the quotes from the copy.
I want to go ahead and do that. So we're going to start on copying line five, and finish on the exits
down here. And we'll paste that down here.
Ok, and one more line there to keep IntelliJ happy.
Alright.
So at this point we should be able to run the program.
Everything works fine.
So let's confirm that is the case, though.
Ok, so you can see we're able to run it - no problems there, that's working.
But note here, I'm not sure whether you noticed when I was changing that - up here now, what we're doing
with these lines, 59 through 61, we're basically, passing a reference to the functions rather
than a string containing the code snippets. Because of course we removed the strings and replaced them
with functions.
Now I kept the function names the same as the string variable names, to avoid editing those lines,
just in case you're wondering how come it's still working.
Now that's how you can time functions using timeit, rather than wrapping things up in strings.
But be aware that it will only work with functions that don't take any arguments.
If you need to pass arguments to your function, then you can't pass the function directly to the
timeit function.
Now there is a way around that using decorators, and we'll cover that later.
But now though, it's time to make some changes so that all three functions create the same list,
and also don't do any printing.
So let's go and start creating that code.
So go back to the first one first -
first function, the nested loop.
So go ahead and make some changes.
So I'm going to start by typing result=[], so creating an empty list. Then we've got our test
here under if the test for locations, so under that, what we want to do is append that one level back.
We want to append back after the for loop, so result here,
result.append parenthesis, exits_to_destination_1. Then what we're going
to do is delete these two printouts. And finally what we want to do, is return result.
So that's the nested loop changes.
So for the loop comp we also want to make a change to that. So I'll just add the second line there to keep IntelliJ
happy.
So we're also going to create an empty list at the start. So result equals left and right square
brackets, to create an empty list. And after the exits_to_destination_2,
we want to type result dot append, in parentheses it's going to be exits_to_destination_2.
We're going to remove the two print statements.
Then we're going to do a return after the loop,
so return result, making sure we've got 2 lines there, between the function names, function definitions. And
then the third one, what we're going to do,
well we really only need to delete these three lines here, because it's just printing things out, and we
want to just return exits_to_destination_3.
So what we should also do, is print out the results to confirm that the three functions are doing exactly
the same things.
Let's do that as well.
So we do that on line 58. I'll type print parentheses nested_loop and print parentheses
loop_comp,
two lines there, to keep things happy, keep IntelliJ happy, print parentheses nested_comp.
Ok. Alright, so if we now run, we should get identical output. You can see that that seems to be,
to me, that's identical.
So the output's identical in all three cases, and we're getting our timings below that as well.
So all three,
confirming now that all three functions are doing the same thing.
And notice also now that the results of the timings have got much smaller values.
That's because we're no longer timing all that printing.
And I think you saw in the last video that the timings were, I think, round about point
four, or something along those lines. So it's seems to be much more efficient than what it was.
So in this particular case, all we can really say, with any certainty, is it's not really a huge difference
between the three codes snippets. So Loop and comp, you can see in my case, seems to be marginally slower.
Well in this case, the nested comp is actually slower when I ran it, but when I run it again, we find that
nested comp and loop and comp are still pretty similar, pretty even between all three, as you can see
there. And I'll just run it a few more times.
So perhaps loop and comp might be marginally slower than the other two. Nested loop is actually the slowest
of the three there. Run it again.
Loop and comp was generally the fastest there. So it does really depend on your computer.
And keep in mind that the differences here are being measured in milliseconds, over 10,000 runs of each
snippet.
So unless performance is absolutely critical, there doesn't seem to be much to choose between the three blocks
of code, as far as performance is concerned. And that shouldn't really be too surprising, because we haven't
done anything silly, and each of the snippets is as efficient as it can be,
for what it's doing.
So all three blocks of code are pretty much doing the same thing.
It now comes back to the question that I posed, quite a few videos ago and now, "has performance suffered when
using generators rather than list comprehensions?".
Now we can change the last function, and see what values we get.
What I'm going to do is just that. So I'm going to close down the Run window.
Let's take a copy of this function,
and we'll call this one nested_gen.
Of course, to do that we need to change our square brackets to parentheses,
the start and end, like so.
And what we want to do after, to test this, is add the new function in a call to timeit.
So let's do that.
So I'll just duplicate that line, result_4
This is going to be nested_gen this time.
Then we'll also print out the results, so result_4, and of course Nested gen.
That's what it is -
a generator.
So now, let's try running this and see what results we get.
And you can see there that that's a huge difference, compared to the other three. The nested_gen function
looks to be over 10 times faster.
So I'm gonna run it again -
significantly faster, and consistently faster, as you can see there.
And once again that's not really surprising.
The generator isn't spending time building up the lists - it's just going to return each one when we iterate
over it.
So before you rush off and decide that you'll use generator expressions for everything,
it is important to realize that you don't get something for nothing.
So creating the generator is a lot faster than using loops or list comprehensions to build up the lists,
but we'll pay for it when we come to iterate over the generator.
Now we can check that, by adding a loop to each of our functions.
Now we're not going to do anything inside the loop.
We've just seen how something like printing can make the results unreliable.
What we want to test here, is the comparative timings,
when we loop over the list that we've created. So I'm going to add the same loop to each of our functions
to achieve that. So going back up to our first function.
Alright, so I'm going to start by, after the append, I'm going to put the same code in all three. So I'll type it once and
I'll paste it in the others. So print the result before returning.
I'm just going to do for x in result
colon pass. And obviously that's not being used, but we're aware of that. So I want to copy those three
lines. I'll copy the blank as well.
And by the way, pass is actually needed here, so that the for loop is syntactically correct.
So I'm going to come down here, and paste the same code at the right indentation level, there.
Right.
And then for the third one
Add it, obviously, before the return. W'ell add it there. This one is slightly different, because we need to go
through the exits_to_destination_3, because we haven't got a
local list variable, result, defined there.
And then lastly, let's do the same for our generator.
That's going to be for x in exits_to_destination_3.
Now we've talked about the pass statement before.
It doesn't do anything, but we need it to make our loops valid, or to make the for loops valid there.
So now if we run it again ...
this time you can see we're getting a different result.
You can see that we're getting some consistency with all four functions now - around about the same
timing.
The difference really isn't huge, but there is a slight performance penalty to be paid for the saving
in memory that we get.
So in general, you should probably find that the generator would be slightly slower,
and again the results may be getting skewed a little bit on my computer.
Now there's often a trade off between speed and memory use, and we have to decide which is more important.
Now with massive lists, the performance penalty's probably worth paying, so that our code doesn't crash
for a lack of memory.
Alright, so at this point we've seen a couple of ways to use timeit to investigate the performance
of different code snippets, so it's time for challenge. What I'm going to do here is paste in a
challenge file. I'm going to create a new file here, New > File, Python File and I'm going to call this one
timeitchallenge.
I'm going to paste in some code.
I'm going to close down the Run window.
So that's the challenge.
You can see there, I'll just read it out briefly, that in the section on Functions,
we looked at two different ways to calculate the factorial of a number.
Now we used an iterative approach, and we also used a recursive function. This challenge is to use
the timeit module to see which performs better. And I've actually included the two functions below.
And just as a hint here,  change the number of iterations to 1000 or 10000. The default of one million will actually
take a long time to run.
So that's the code, so you can go ahead and actually perform that challenge.
I'm going to end the video here, and we'll go over the solution in the next video.
And also I'm going to show you how to use the repeat function, instead of timeit, in that video.
So I'll see you in the next video.
Good luck with the challenge.