alright so let's have a look in more
detail now the stack trace has been
printed out here now because of the way
that the stack trace is generated it may
be interspersed with the program's
output if i run the program a few times
you can probably see or you will see we
don't always get the exact same contents
well technically the content will be
identical each time but the stack trace
and the output can get mixed up and when
it is mixed up we can't rely on what's
been printed first we can say every time
is that 4 ducks fly before we get an
error to show you what I mean lets run
this a few times so you can see that
the stack trace is different there
we've got dispersed in a different
position than it was previously run it
again we three at the top
three lines of output and again we're
getting different results pretty much
every time we run it so we can't rely on
what's been printed first all we can really
say every time is that the four ducks
fly before we get an error and that's
true even if the trace starts to print
before we see the fourth duck take to
the air so reading from the bottom first
and ignoring any text that doesn't
appear mostly in red
we've got an attribute error because the
penguin has no attribute called fly
right here down the bottom up until that
the error as you can see here occurred on
line 55 the migrate method and that's
when it tried to called duck.fly so
that's useful because it tells us where
the error happened
however we know there's not a problem
with that particular line of code
because we've seen 4 ducks already
start flying
so this is where the stack trace is
useful now we've got code that works as
long as its operating on the correct type
of object to find out what's really
caused the error we have to keep reading
up the call stack so next we can see the
migrate method was called on line 22
duck.migrate as you can see here
line 22 and in module and that means the
main program when it called the flock .
migrate method now sometimes that's all
you need
so if migrate accepted arguments that
it would probably indicate a problem
with one of the parameters
but here though it's not quite
that simple because we set up the flock
earlier in the code but there are now
enough clues to let us know that
somehow the flocks got a penguin it now
the important thing is that the cause
of the error in this case isn't in ducks
.py it's in a migration .py
module now we've only got two modules here
but we could have a coordinator program
that calls another program to select
different species of ducks that in turn
calls our migrate module that uses
the classes from ducks.py and
things can get quite complex but with a
stack trace like this it's much easier
to find the root cause of errors and
crashes alright so let's go see what
we can do about this exception now in
fact we've already done the first thing
we could do we have done nothing so we
didn't handle the exception in the
migrate method so the exception
propagated up the call stack to wherever
called migrate and that was our main
program and because that didn't handle
the exception
it got propagated up the python run time
the Python runtime prints out this useful
stacked trace and then terminates the
program so if an exception isn't handled
it will get passed up the call stack
until either something handles it or it
reaches the python runtime now having
a program crashed like this isn't good
but that doesn't mean that migrate
method should handle the error it's so
often better to leave errors for
something further up the call chain to
deal with so that's one option now is
there anything useful that the migrate
method could do in this case if
there is we should actually do it but if
there isn't then we should let the
exception propagate to allow code
that's in a better position to deal with
the situation handle it now I don't know
much about ducks and i'm pretty sure
that once you've caused the flock of
ducks to take flight
there's no way to get them back on the
ground now humane way that is but we can
make sure that all the ducks that are
capable of flying managed to migrate so
to do that I'm going to start by
catching the exception in the migrate
method let's have a look at doing that
i'm looking at our migrate method here
so after the four we're going to....
...
so this time you can see that all seven
ducks manage to take off poor Percy is left
on the ground but at least the rest of
the flock are away but unfortunately the
main programs now and none the wiser as
far as our migration program is
concerned we've got eight birds in the
air so we didn't take any action in the
exception handler so the exception was
effectively just ignored so what we can
do now that all the ducks safely flying
is to raise the error that we've got
when Percy attempted to fly now if we
attempt to do that within the for loop the
loop will terminate when we raise an
exception so raising it in the exception
handler will leave us no better off than
before and to show you what i mean i'm
going to change this Pass will print a
message here one duck down they're and
put raise run that again we're back to
the same scenario where we were before
or be that we've got an extra message
here informing us that the percy
didn't make it but importantly with now
unfortunately only got four ducks in
flight now you can log the values of
local variables for example before
raising the exception again some of the
words are here and let the caller
deal with it so to raise the exception
that you just caught you just used the
raise statement that has been typed in and
actually preserves the stack trace so
that all the useful information is still
available for debugging and again if you
run that again you can see that's the
case so we still got our information
and pir stack trace which we can see
propagating up the call stack much as
the case was before
so basically all the useful information
still available for debugging npw as O have
said many times before everything in
python is an object exceptions are no
exception
so we can obtain a reference to the
exception that's just been raised and we
do that with a slightly different form
of the except Clause sp come back to
our ducks.py to our migrated method
and we do instead of typing accept
attribute error at the end of that we do
....so when used like this a
reference to the exception is stored in
a variable for us to do something with
now one useful thing we could do is
store the exception then raise it once
all the Ducks are off the ground so to
show you what I mean will delete the
raise line which always commented out and
we'll put..
...
you can see we've got problem here local variable problem
might be referenced before assignment so
to fix that we should really assign
value to this outside of the for loop so
problem equals and we'll start with none
that then remove that error
so let's now run this to see what
happens
you can see this time we've actually got
all seven ducks in the air one duck down
for penguins didn't work and then we've
got the error at the end so in other
words that the seven ducks that can fly
do so and our migration programs
notified of the problem once they are all
of the ground now you probably won't do
that very often but it can be useful and
it also shows another way to use raise
which is to specify the exception that
you want to raise so looking at the stack
trace now we still got all the useful
information that we had before the
original problem was on line 57 ducks.py
i can click that link to have a look
at it
that's the duck .fly called their we got
another entry this time and clicking
that takes us to the line where the
exception was raised
this one here in line 63 and just move
this down a little bit line 63 is we've
raised the exception clicking on the
first link takes us to well the actual
line where we call the migrate method
so the stack trace is slightly different
but it still contains all the
information you had before so
let's end the video here in the next
video we're going to talk about creating
your own exceptions see you in the next
video