so in the previous we talked
about the While loop and we had a very simple
game that we modified to use a random now the problems we had with that
code of course was that were only able
to have two guess’ in the code and
the consequently it made the game very frustrating because unless you fluked it
in which I tried three times and was
unable to do that, you wouldn’t be able to solve it
so you won’t be able to win the game
so the challenge I got the same code I pasted in a new Python file called
challenge, and your challenge is to
modify the program below and to use a
while loop to allow as many guesses as necessary
so you see obviously in the current code
at the moment with only have two guess’ and that's it but
your gonna change all so the program
now should let the player know where to guess
higher or lower and should put a message
whether the guess is correct and the correct guess will terminate the program, now as an optional extra
allow the player to quit by entering the number 0 before they guess
so time to pause the video go away and see if you can figure this out, and of course were
you want to create a while loop statement to do that
and when you're ready to come back and
see the solution come back and will go through that
so pause the video now, so hopefully you managed to get a
solution to that and to get it working
so lets go through our proposed solution
now to see whether we can figure it out
so what we need to do is we need to put
a while loop in here we need to get rid of all
these extra bits of code that we no
longer need so were gonna leave the first part which
is correct
which is generating the random number and printing it out on the screen and what we're
going to do now is instead of putting guess = int(input) input what we need to do is
initialized that to 0 because if you recall in our
discussions with a while loop we need to
pre-initialized that variable as we done in the for loop, a for loop doesn't need to but a while it
does, so its going to be
that can be initialised basically to any number, it has to be outside of valid
range again, if we got it in the valid
range as you saw when I created in the
previous video then the while would not
be started for the first time so making
it zero when its going to be OK
and because the reason we know that it's not
a valid number is of course on line 15 we
are getting a random number which starts on the
low range as one and in the highest ranges
which is tent and therefore we know that we get a
number of 21 and 10 so guess has to be an invalid
number, so to fix this now we need to change that to while loop so we
gonna
and we are gonna put, and so again because guess is 0 this code will work on the first time we run it and
will prompt for input which is correct
and then we still need to put some tests in here
to check whether it's less than or greater than or put an else in there if you got it the first time, so were going to delete that, and get rid of this “you got it right
the first time” so we’ve now gotta to check if guess is less than
the answer in other words I’ve typed in
a number that is lower than the answers, so its gonna
say please guess higher, otherwise have typed in a
number that's higher than the actual answer so the else comes in and says we need to guess lower, we need to take
this next line actually out because we don't wanna input the
code again what we really want to do is
wanna put an else there, and I should
have change this code here to be an elif
now the final else we longer need, so you can see now we are left with a while loop that start making sure
that guess is not equal to answer as soon as
guess equals the loop is effectively going to end
and so what happens is we do is guess = inputs so we are
getting the integer from the keyboard
if the typed number is less than ours were gonna print a message please guess higher, else if guess is
greater than answer, then we print the
message please guess lower than else if it
was not less and greater then in it means the we got it right, so print will done you guess it, and obviously if the
code gets down to hear that's not
true it's gonna look back again until guess
as equal to answer
essentially as long as the guess doesn't
equal to answer the loop’s continues to
request a new guess and checking the
answer and you can see now that the if
statements are obviously a lot easier
because of taking something out we just
checking for less then greater than we can let the player know to guess higher or lower or print when they get it right, so lets just run
that and make sure that it does work, please guess a number between 1 and 10
will try 5, please guess lower so 3 and that confused me for a moment because of course we're running the wrong
program so I need to close that, we are
running the while program we created in
the previous video, I need to right
click and run this first, click challenge
will try again, 5 again please guess higher, try 7 days, please guess higher will try 8 well
done you guess it, we got the number 8, and will just try again so lets try the number 9, guess lower, 1,5,6,7, well done you guessed it, we will try again
10 please guess lower, 5 higher, 7, 8, 9, well done you guessed it, is clearly working now so lets also do the
optional challenge and of course the
optional extra of this challenge is for 0 to
break out of the loop and it's quite
simple to do after the guess where we are
entering the number or getting the
number from the keyboard we put
that should be equal to 0, two == and now if we run that, lets make sure that working, so if we put a 0, and there we go exits the loop, and just to make the app
more interesting so if we close this down let's
make the highest number a 1000 now
what you should be able to do, is you have
to guess the correct number within 10
guesses, if looked at what I was doing
initially probably got an idea what I
was doing especially from the
previous video and little bit in this
video but there is a way of doing this so you can within 10 guesses no matter what the
number is the, whatever the number ranges you should be
able to determine that within 10 guesses
So I’m going to leave that Im not going to show you how to do that, see if you can figure
that out but you will find out how and
why later in the course so that's it
that's this video finished now and will
see you in the next one