Alright, so I stopped the last video with a challenge. That was to work out which of our two factorial functions
performed better.
Now, both functions take an argument. That means that we can't pass them directly to the timeit function.
Now we'll see a way around that,
when we've looked at decorators.
For now though, we have to test calling the functions.
So let's actually make sure they work first, by calling each one.
So we'll add these four lines to the end of the program, remembering that we need to add two
blank lines after the function definitions.
So I'm going to start with x equals fact(
130)  print(x). Then we're going to do y equals factorial(130)  print(y).
OK so we'll run that. You can see that each one there has produced the same result, as we would expect it to have
done.
So that's fine.
Just fix up that little warning there.
So it's those function calls, on lines 30 and 32, that we want to test.
Now there's a few ways to do this.
Remember that we need to make sure, or make the functions available to timeit
by using the setup argument. And if you're using Python 3.5 or above, you may have used globals
instead.
So either way is fine.
So one easy way, is to move the function calls to just after each function, then wrap the whole lot up
in a string.
So what I can do is just come back here, to the x = fact(130) and I can print that and or add that, rather,
on line 21. And I can come back up here and put fact_test equals three double quotes
backslash, and take those last three double quotes, and paste them under the x = fact
line - this line here, line number 22.
And then for the next one, we can take the y = factorial line. Add that, with a space, and come back
and define the second string,
factorial_test is equal to three double quotes
and a backslash. Take the last three double quotes, and paste them under the y = factorial line, like
so. Let's remove these other lines.
The prints, we don't need at the moment. And what we can now do is call the timeit function with each string.
So we can start by print parentheses, and it's going to be timeit
dot timeit parentheses and that's going to be fact_test,
comma and we'll do number equals 10000.
That's the first one.
And then we'll just duplicate that line and for the second test,
it's going to be factorial_test,
factorial_test.
Now obviously, there was a few ways to do this,
as I said. Let's now run the program
and you can see there in the second test, the recursive function takes over twice as long to run,
and depending on how many times you run it, maybe even more than that. Over double, there.
So there's a few ways to do this, as I said, but if you managed to time the functions correctly, then well done!
Now I'd probably have done this a little bit differently.
Now we've covered everything we need to use this next approach, but putting it all together may not have
been obvious.
Now the setup string can be an import, and we can import our own module, as long as we make sure the
timeit code isn't executed.
Now to see what I mean, I'm going to undo all these changes, going all the way back to having just these function
definitions.
I'm going to close this down, and I'm just going to undo everything.
I'll just add the last blank line at the end there.
So our module can actually be imported, but we have to make sure that any code we add isn't executed.
Remember that we do this by checking the value of underscore underscore name_ underscore underscore
So I can put some extra code down here, on line 30, and I can type if __name__
equals "__main__"
colon.
Then we can do print parentheses
timeit dot
timeit and double quotes x equals fact(130) in double
quotes as you can see there, comma setup equals double quotes from space
__main__ import fact
comma
then number equals 10000.
That's the first line. And I can ducplicate that line, and we'll change the second one to factorial(130)
setup is from __main__ import, and this time it's import factorial.
So the code's only going to be executed if our program's run as a script.
So in other words, it won't be executed when the module is imported.
So if you run the program now
you can see we're still getting the output there.
So it's probably not obvious that you can import from main as we have done here, from __main__
So that's equivalent of from, we could have done timeitchallenge import fact. That would also work, but the advantage
of using the __main__ is that it will still work even if we rename the file.
I'll just undo those changes, and put it back to main.
So this approach needed fewer changes to our code.
It gives similar capabilities to using globals, and also works on Python 3.4 and earlier.
Now if you read the documentation for timeit - we'll get back to our Web site -
you'll actually see this being used right at the bottom of the page.
It has setup equals __main__ import test.
Alright so that's the end of the challenge.
But I also promised you, in the last video, to show you how to use repeat instead of timeit.
Now it's very similar, but it runs the test several times, and returns a list of all the individual timings.
So let's go back and have a look at that.
Alright, so I've undone that change there, so we're looking back at main again now.
So I'm going to then change our code to use timeit.
Instead of timeit.timeit, it's timeit.repeat.
We can use that for both calls, and run that.
You can see we get two lists printed out there.
Each one contains the timeit results for three runs.
And that's because they repeat, or repeat defaults to repeating the test three times.
But you can also override that and change that if you want.
So I can come down here and put repeat=6, for argument's sake, repeat equals six. And the same for the next one, equals six.
And run that again.
And you can see we've got our two lists this time, with the timeit results for six results
in each list.
Now this is one reason for the warning about not performing statistical analysis on the results, by the
way. When you've got a set of values in a list,
it's very easy to calculate things like the average.
So let's go ahead and change the code a little bit more.
We're going to assign the lists of variables instead of just printing them, and have a look at doing that.
So instead of print, we're going to put list1 equals, get rid of the initial parentheses and the ending
one. Then list 2 equals - the same thing about removing the parentheses,
and then we're going to do print(sum(list1)) and print(sum(list2)).
So the sum function calculates the sum of the values in a list.
Let's try running that. OK so you can see that it works nicely. In this case, you can see that the
sum function calculates the sum of the values in the list, and you could get the arithmetic mean by dividing
by the number of items in the list.
But note also there's a statistics module, in the standard library for Python 3, and we can actually import
that to analyze the results further.
Let's have a go at doing that.
So we're going to come back up to the top of the code, and put another line, line 12; from statistics
import mean comma stdev - standard deviation.
And I can come down here, to our output, and we can do something like, change this first one to mean, list1 and we'll also
do a comma
stdev(list1).
We can do the same for list2.
So mean(list2), stdev(list2).
Alright, we'll run this to check it works.
And you can see now that we're getting the mean and standard deviation for each list.
Now if you're not into statistics, then you probably wouldn't have dreamt of doing it that way anyway.
But if you are into statistics, that note in the documentation is for you. Statistical analysis like
this is only useful if you're able to account for all the variables, and there's so many other factors
causing variations in the timings on a multi-tasking operating system, that the mean and standard deviation
are effectively meaningless.
So use common sense instead.
But that was a good excuse to show you sum of the statistics functions, anyway. Now you can find
out more information on the statistics functions that are available, and how to use them, in the documentation
that Python have put together - the Python crowd. and I'll put the link there for you to check out some time, at your leisure.
Alright, so we've covered a few different ways to use timeit module in these last few videos.
Now I haven't yet looked at the Timer class, but using it's no harder than using the timeit and repeat helper
functions.
The tricky bit is the setup and globals arguments, and you should now be confident in setting up the environment
correctly, so that you can run your tests. In the next video,
what we're going to do is go back to comprehensions, and look at some of the alternative functions that
Python provides.
So I'll see you in the next video.