So in the last few videos,
I've digressed to look at exceptions
and exception handling in Python,
but now it's time to get back to databases.
Now what we're going to do is have a look at
rolling back transactions in situations
where it's important that all transactions are successful.
Now if you recall,
we discussed one example of that earlier
and that was transferring money between bank accounts.
In that scenario,
we really don't wanna end up in a situation
where one account is debited
without the corresponding amount also being stored
in the other account.
So what we're going to do is use a simple account class,
basically very similar to what we did in an earlier video,
to see how to ensure that both transactions occur
or neither of them do.
Now in the process,
we're also gonna look at a neat way
to do the contents of our database from IntelliJ.
So what I've done is I've created
a new IntelliJ Python project calling it rolling back
and I've created a new Python file called rollback.py
and we're just gonna quickly type in the account class
that we're gonna be working with.
So it's gonna be class Account(object):
and we're gonna start by defining the init method
and that's going to have also a name: str
and also an opening balance
which is a float the default value 0.0
and we're going to assign the parameter
so self.name = name,
self._balance = opening_balance
and then we'll just print something to the console
Account created for two curly braces dot and a space
and it's gonna be .format
and then we do self.name
and end equals two single quotes
then self.show_balance
which we obviously need to write.
All right, next we're going to start off with our
or start with the deposit method so def deposit
self is automatic
and then amount which is gonna be a float.
We can also add an annotation here for the return type
which we've talked about
to be a float.
Then the code is going to be if amount &gt; 0.0
then we're going to do self._balance += amount
and then we're gonna print a message as well
two curly braces deposited.format(amount)
and then in either case
we're gonna return self._balance
and that's our deposit method.
Now the withdraw method,
def withdraw
it's gonna have a self obviously
and then it's going to be amount: float
and another annotation for this for the return type
which is going to be a float
and then the code is going to be
if 0 &lt; amount &lt;= to self._balance
and we wanna do self._balance -= amount
then print something to the console
so print two curly braces withdrawn.format(amount)
return amount
else:
we're going to print a message basically saying
the amount must be greater than zero
no more than your account balance
so the amount must be greater than zero
and no more than your account balance
return 0.0
and lastly we want to define the show balance method
that we're calling upon line seven up here
so we need to define that show_balance
and the code for that is going to be
print Balance on account
curly braces, left to right curly braces,
is and another set of curly braces left to right
.format(self.name, self._balance)
okay so there's our account class.
As I mentioned,
I've added annotations for the return values,
but I also added annotations,
you probably noticed as I was typing it,
for the parameters as well.
And where this differs,
this class differs from our earlier attempt
is both the deposit and withdraw methods
now also return a value but other than that,
it's very basic.
It's pretty much the same code that we've seen previously.
Now just to test this out,
let's write a bit of code to do just that.
So if __name__ is equal to and in quotes __main__
now we're gonna put john = Account("John")
and john.deposit(10.10)
and john.deposit another 10 cents
john.deposit another 10 cents
john.deposit 30 more cents
and then john.withdraw(0)
and john.show_balance.
So before I run this programme,
we're gonna be depositing a total of $10
and that actually should have been a withdrawal.
So we're depositing a total of $10.30,
$10.10 plus another 20
then we're withdrawing 30 cents or pennies
or whatever you like to call it.
So if we run this,
and I'm just putting this down the bottom,
well what's going on here?
So we got the account must be greater than zero
no more than your account balance
so it seemingly has worked,
but at the moment the balance on account John is $9.999999
so obviously that really should have been,
the balance remaining should have been $10.
So we're using floating point numbers here
and in just about every computer language,
these floating point numbers are subject to rounding errors
when converting between binary and decimal.
Now integer values can be converted
between any two number systems with complete accuracy,
but as soon as you introduce fractions,
you'll often get rounding errors.
Now you're probably familiar with pi
and the fact that it can't be represented
exactly in decimal.
Now other fractions such as 1/3
also can't be represented accurately in decimal
so it comes out as 0.3333 recurring.
Now when 1/10 or 0.1 in decimal is represented in binary,
that also has the same issue with recurring,
that also recurs.
So in other words,
we lose some accuracy every time we use 0.1
in our example on screen
and 0.3 also recurs in binary as would 0.4,
0.5 is 1/2 which can be represented exactly in binary.
Now Richard Pryor's character in the film Superman 3
takes advantage of this to make a small fortune
by creaming up the small fractions of a cent
for millions of transactions but in the real world,
our answer here of 9.99 is obviously not satisfactory.
So what can we actually do about this to solve the problem?
Well, one solution is to use the decimal class
that comes with Python.
Now I'm gonna not cover that right now.
If there's sufficient demand,
then it could be a good topic for a future video.
But what I will do is show an equivalent version
of this programme on the screen for a few seconds
just so you can get an idea for how it's used.
So I'm gonna create a new Python file called rollback2
and paste the code in there just so you've got it
and you can also refer to that
by downloading the source code for this video.
So I'm gonna create a new file rollback2
and I'll just grab that and paste that in.
Okay so there's the code there.
So essentially the main programme still uses float values,
but the accounts class converts them to decimal objects
and you can see that here on line nine,
line 14 and also on line 21 down here.
Now you can work entirely in decimal values,
but the class is a bit cumbersome to use
so personally I like this approach of allowing
clients of the class to work in floats
and then converting them for storage and arithmetic.
All right so I will close that file now
but again as I mentioned,
it's in the source code for this video
so you can refer to that at your leisure.
Let's go back to rollback.py that we were working on.
So the other thing we can do
is work entirely with integer values.
Now as I've said,
integers can be stored exactly in binary
so we won't get any rounding errors
if we perform all our arithmetic on ints.
So when we need to display values,
we divide by 100 so that the programme shows dollars and cents
or pounds and pennies or whatever currency units
that you're actually dealing with.
And if the programme receives input,
we need to multiply by 100 to convert to an integer.
So basically we're working in cents or pennies
rather than dollars or pounds.
So what we need to do now
is make some changes to our source code
to replace that with integers.
We're gonna start up here on line three.
We're going to put int = 0
no decimal anymore so just int = 0
and for the deposit method, amount is going to be an int.
We're also going to still return a float though.
And for printing out,
we're gonna use some formatting for printing out now.
So within the curly braces,
we're gonna put :.2f two decimal points
and we're gonna put amount format is going to be
amount / 100.
For the withdrawal method, we need to convert that.
The input's gonna be an int.
We're still gonna return a float.
In terms of formatting,
exactly the same as we've done for the deposit method,
:.2f within the curly braces
and formatting it's gonna be amount / 100
and then I'm also gonna return amount / 100
and of course we also need to return self._balance / 100
to convert that back to a float as well.
And show balance, we need to make a change to that,
so the second set of curly braces in the print line
is gonna have the same formatting :.2f
and the balance we're gonna do the same thing there
self._balance / 100
and in terms of the deposit function,
we're not going to use decimal points anymore
so we're using whole numbers, integers,
so it's gonna be 10.10,
this is gonna be 10, 10, 30.
So basically I changed all the float parameters to int
and divided the values by 100
before returning or printing them.
And you saw me specify
the format of :.2f in the replacement fields
so that the amounts printing
is floating them with two decimal places.
So if we run this now,
you could see we're now getting the correct formatting
for all our numbers
and also the balance returned now
is as we would expect it to be 10.00.
All right, so I'm gonna finish the video here now.
In the next video,
let's start storing these account details in a database.
See you in the next video.