In programming languages such as C or
Java, for loops work differently.
In those languages, you provide a starting value
and an ending value, and increment a
variable each time around the loop.
Python's different approach to for loops
makes them incredibly powerful but also
very flexible. We can get the same effect
as C for loops, by iterating over a range
of values. So let's take a look at that.
What I'm going to do is create a new file
here. We're gonna call this one ranges.py.
Now be careful here with what I've just
done. You can get problems if you'd
called the file range without an s,
because its name will conflict with
pythons range class. That's why I called
this one ranges.py. Alright so let's
have a go at printing out the values
from 1 to 20. We'll use a range object
and give it the starting and ending
values; for i in range parentheses
1 comma 20, and the closing parentheses
colon. Next line, print parentheses double
quotes i is now. Then within the double
quotes, left and right curly braces
closing double quote dot format
parentheses i in the parentheses and the
two closing right parentheses. We'll talk
more about naming variables in a later
video. Up till now, we've just been using
simple words that describe the values
we've been dealing with. Normally, you
should avoid using single character
names for variables, as they don't give
any indication of what the variable is
for. Loop control variables, however, are
one of the few places where names like
i or j are acceptable. i is taken to be short
for index, and the convention is that it
is an acceptable name in a for loop, as
we're using here. Now when we run the
program, which I'll do now, you can see the
output on the screen and you can see
that it almost works. The range was
actually outputted from 1 to 19.
So in other words, 20 isn't included here
and you can see clearly that we use the
numbers 1 to 20 on line 1. So do you
remember how our strings slices
returned the characters up to, but not
including, the end number? Well ranges
work in the same way. The last value specified
is not included. range produces a range
of numbers from the starting value, up to
but not including the end number, or the
end value. To include the value 20 in our
loop, therefore, we need to change the stop
value to 21. So I'm gonna go ahead and do that,
and this time when I run the program we
should see the values from 1 to 20.
You can see there that we've now got the
correct output. So experiment with
different values in the range to
understand what it's doing. For example,
you could try the following:
I'll change 1 to 21 to 10
to 16, and that would give us the
numbers in the range of 10 through 15,
and you can see that is the case with the
output at the bottom of the screen.
When you're happy with that, I'll
see you in the next video.