Alright so how did you get on with the
challenge from the last video.
The first part of the challenge was to slice the
string to produce the letters q, p and o.
So let's have a go at doing that. So I'm
going to type, on line 7, print
parentheses letters square brackets 16:13:-1
So we're standing at position 16.
We're extending backwards, up to, but not
including the character at position 13.
So let's run that, and there's the
letters q, p and o. So next we want a
slice to produce the letters edbca.
The easiest way to include the beginning
is to type print parentheses letters[4::-1]. So if we
run that,
and there's the letters edcba.
Finally, we wanted the last eight
characters in reverse order. So we'll be
using a negative step value, which means
the start will default to the end of the
string and can therefore be omitted.
So to type that, I'm going to do a print
parentheses letters square brackets
:-9:-1
Alright so running that, and there's the last 8 letters, zyxwvuts.
Now there are other solutions you could have
used, especially when returning items
from the beginning and end of the
sequence. Using default values for the
start and stop is recommended, when
trying to return a certain number of
characters from the beginning or end of
a sequence. If you managed to produce the
correct strings with your slices, well done.
Alright, so I'll finish talking
about slices for now, by looking at some
common idioms that Python programmers use and recognize.
In the last video,  I mentioned that a slice of ::-1  is a Python idiom. When you see
that, you'll recognize it as reversing the sequence.
Let's see some more idioms. The first is to return the last n items in a
sequence. So let's say we wanted the last
four characters from letters. So I'm
going to come down, and on line 15 I'm
going to type print parentheses letters
[-4:]
If I run that you should get the last
four letters, wxyz. Whenever you see a
slice with a negative start value and
defaults for the stop and step, that just
returns the end of the sequence.
Our common use of that is to get the last
item by specifying -1 for the start
value. So let's have a go doing that. So I'm
going to type print parentheses then
letters[-1:]
Run that, we get the last item, in this case, the z.
Now you can also use a slice to get
the first character, very similar. We just
type print(letters[1:]
Run that, and I actually did that the wrong
way, because that obviously gave us
everything but the first, starting at sequence position 1. It should have been [:1],
which is what I meant to type. Running
that, we now get the letter a, which is
the first item in the sequence, the first
character. Now that last one is useful
because it doesn't give an error if the
sequence is empty. It may though, be more
natural to get the item at index
position 0, and that works with a string.
So we could also do it as print(letters[0]),
and that's the same, gives us the same
result. That works, but what would happen
if our string was empty? So I'm going to
go up and delete the letters, or the
characters rather, on line 1.
So I'll make that an empty string.
Run the program, and we now get an error, and the
error is: string index out of range.
You can't access the first item of a sequence that doesn't
any items. So looking at the code, the
slice on line 17 produces an empty
string, instead of crashing with an index
error, and just to confirm, if I run it again,
the error's actually talking, or is showing on line 18, as you can see there.
So I had no problems with executing
line 17. So the idiom on line 17 is
useful for getting the first item in a
sequence, without your code crashing.
If the sequence is empty, you'll get an
empty sequence back, and that's often
what you'd want to happen. Alright so
that's the end of slices, for now.
In the next video, we'll look at string
operators. See you in the next video.