So this video we're gonna start storing
our camp details in a database.
What we're gonna do is go to the top
of this RollingBack.py folder that we created.
We're gonna start off by importing SQLite3, import sqlite3
and then we're going to continue on
and we're going to start putting in some commands
to actually create the table and the two tables we want
which we're going to talk about shortly.
Which will be the accounts and the transactions tables.
We're going to start with db = sqlite3.connect
and we're going to go with "accounts.sqlite"
is the name of the database
and we're going to be putting two statements here.
So db.execute first one "CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS"
we talked about this before and it's gonna be
accounts name TEXT PRIMARY KEY NOT NULL
and balance which will be an INTEGER NOT NULL
so that's our accounts table.
We also want transactions table.
Again we're doing this for this account class
that we created so db.execute this time it's going to be
CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS and transactions
this one's gonna be time
which is going to be TIMESTAMP NOT NULL,
account TEXT NOT NULL
trying to be consistent here with the case.
Leaving all the SQL statements in upper case
and the name of the columns in our tables
all the table names in lowercase.
Next one's gonna be amount which is gonna be
INTEGER NOT NULL it's getting a bit long
so let's just continue on like that.
And I'm gonna finish this off with PRIMARY KEY
is gonna be time, account
alright so that should be that.
Alright and two blank lines so that IntelliJ is happy.
Now there is a reason up here on line three
why I've given the database file a SQLite extension.
So make sure you do that too, even if you're using
an operating system that doesn't rely on file extensions
to determine the top of the file and we'll see why shortly.
Now both tables are pretty straight forward.
The accounts table just stores the name of the account
and the account balance.
Although in a real application you'll probably
store other information for example, an overdraft limit,
the date the account was created and so on and so forth.
Now the transactions table
stores the time of the transaction,
the account that the transaction relates to,
as well as the amount.
We're gonna store deposits as positive
and withdrawals as negative.
Now the PRIMARY KEY for the transactions table
this part down here, is defined a bit differently
to how we've done it before and that's because we need
what's called a composite key.
Now it's quite possible for many transactions
to happen at the same time and obviously
one account will have many transactions.
So it's the combination of time and account
that will uniquely identify a particular transaction
in our database.
Now perhaps a more usual way would be to add an ID column
but we've already done that and I haven't shown you
how to define composite keys, so that's why
I've done it this way here.
Even if you don't create a composite PRIMARY KEY
composite keys can be very useful.
Remember that you can have other keys
in addition to the PRIMARY KEY.
If you want to create additional keys
you kind of just drop the PRIMARY from PRIMARY KEY.
Instead you use the word UNIQUE.
Now if there's a transactions table storing
all the transactions on the account you might be wondering
why the balance is stored in the accounts table.
You can see this up here.
Strictly speaking that's not necessary
and in fact is breaking normalisation.
The balance can be calculated by summing
all the amounts in the transactions table.
Over time though, there will be a lot of transactions
and calculating the balance each time will be expensive.
You'll find examples like this in real world databases
where the theoretical rules of database normalisation
are broken for performance reasons.
Provided everything works correctly
there should be no disparity between the balance stored
in the accounts table and when calculated
by summing all the transactions.
A real financial application may run a job
during quiet times to compare the two values
and make sure in fact they do agree.
So moving on, we're actually storing the time
as a TIMESTAMP property, this one here on line five.
If you check the SQLite documentation
you might be wondering where I got TIMESTAMP from
and that's because SQLite only has five tops
for its columns and just to confirm that
if I just open link and I open a browser
and you can see those five main types
NULL, INTEGER, REAL, TEXT, and BLOB.
Now they're storage classes rather than data types.
Apart from INTEGER PRIMARY KEY fields
you can store any kind of value in any type of column.
So INTEGER PRIMARY KEY columns are handled differently
and in fact can only hold INTEGER values.
Now the system is very flexible though
and the Python SQLite3 library includes support
for datetime values.
So it performs conversion automatically
to and from datetime values.
But we do have to tell it to do that
and we will see how to do that shortly.
Now I'm gonna go back and refer to the Python documentation
when we come to read our TIMESTAMP values back in.
Notice I mentioned in the earlier section of this course
when we looked at the date and time modules
we'll be storing UTC times.
Unless if you have a very specific reason
for doing otherwise, always store times in UTC
and you can refer back to that earlier section
to find out why.
Now you should be happy with storing text
and numbers in a SQLite database
so I've added this TIMESTAMP field
to demonstrate how to cope with dates.
It's really no harder than storing text and numbers
you just need to know how to do it.
We go back to our code.
Looking at these warnings over here,
no data sources are configured to run this SQL.
So we're going to ignore those warnings for now.
In fact we're going to get a few more as we progress.
But we will look at them a little bit later
and see how to get rid of them.
They're actually nothing to do with the Python code per se
they're actually cause by IntelliJ being unable
to verify things like the table and column names.
Now that we've got the tables created,
I'm gonna make a change to the account classes init method
so that it retrieves the account details from the database
or saves them if the account doesn't exist.
Quick looking down here, in our init method, line 11.
We're going to start with getting our cursors
going to type cursor is equal to db.execute and the SQL's
gonna be SELECT name, balance FROM accounts WHERE
and (name = ?) for prepared statement,
then we're gonna put (name,) wrap parentheses
as you can see there to end the line.
Then we're gonna do row = cursor.fetchone()
meaning a single record.
Then we're going to type if row:
and we're gonna change this a little bit,
we're gonna put self.name, self.balance is = row
then we're going to put print("Retrieved record for
and set up a replacement filed with
left and right curly braces . ". format(self.name),
and end='')
I guess I could have copied some of
this other source code here
in fact let's try and do that for
some of this other code.
else so if you weren't able to retrieve a record
from the database presumably it doesn't exist
so we're gonna change this self.name = name
and self.balance will actually in fact
equal the opening balance.
Then we need to add some code here, so that's going to be
some SQL code to save this cursor.execute
INSERT INTO accounts VALUES watching the extra spaces
then two question marks there
and then we want (name, opening_balance)
then we'll do a cursor.connection.commit()
to immediately save that.
We're gonna leave that message there,
print("Account created for that's gonna be exactly the same
as what it was before so we're going to leave
the self.show_balance on the next line
so that's gonna be executed whether we receive the data
from the table, if it was already in existence.
That would be if the row was found here
on line 15 or if didn't exist when we're creating it
as per new here, either way we're gonna show
the balance once we're done.
Basically, again what we're doing here is running
a simple SELECT query to retrieve the row
where the name matches the one passed in
when creating the account instance.
So using this name here you actually do a query
and we're using that there as you can see
they're setting it up to replace the argument there
with the name that's been passed to the init method.
So the cursors fetch one method will return either tuple
containing the values from all the database columns
otherwise it will return none if no record was found.
You've seen conditions like this with this if row before.
The condition will be true if row
isn't either zero or an empty string,
list, set, dictionary, or none.
So I guess we could have written this instead
as if row is not None: would be and alternative way
to do that, in fact the effect would be the same
and with that said you'll often see the shorthand way
of writing it when you read other programmers code.
In other words, either way is actually okay.
Based on this query, if we get a record back
from the database we unpack the tuple
you can see on the next line here on line 16
to set the values for the account name and balance.
Now if a matching row isn't found in the database
the else clause is triggered and down here
we're actually saving the name and account balance
then we insert a new row.
Because we're doing an INSERT we have to commit the change
by calling the commit method on the cursors connexion.
I think it's time now to run this.
So let's just run this and see
whether it actually works or not.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We've actually got a error here.
And the problem's actually up here
you see that I've got a left parentheses
in the SQL statement but I'm not ending
the right parentheses and in fact here you can see
that IntelliJ is helpfully telling us
that there's a problem there.
So I'm going to change that and put the right parentheses
to fix that and just check the next one
I think I've got the right parentheses there OK.
So that's looks ok let' just try running it again.
Alright so this time we can now see the normal text here
that the account got created for John.
Balance on account John is zero.
And we've got these deposits
that are going through and withdrawals.
At this stage, we haven't actually updated
the balance value in the database row for John's account.
So that's something that we're
going to need to do shortly in those methods.
Firstly though I want to create a few more accounts
and then close the database when we're done.
So let's just go ahead and do that down here.
We'll just add a couple more,
terry = Account("Terry")
and graham = Account("Graham")
and we'll also specify an initial balance there, 9000.
And eric = Account("Eric") and also I pass
a value there 7,000 and we'll do a db.close()
So let's run this.
This time we can see that it's retrieved the record for John
balance on account John is zero
so we can see that our row got retrieved successfully.
It's actually retrieved the data, even though
we're not yet updating the balance with the amount
you can see that it has retrieved it successfully
so that's off to a good start.
But you can also see here looking down
that the account has been created
for Terry, Graham and Eric as well
you can see there's a balance there which is correct
because in Terry's case we didn't pass an opening balance
so it defaulted to zero, but in the case of Graham and Eric
we've actually got 90 and 70,
remembering that we're storing these as integers
so it's divided by a hundred to get the actual value.
Alright so I'm going to stop the video here.
In the next one, we're going to look at a way
to view these records from within IntelliJ
and we'll also take care of these warnings that I showed you
that IntelliJ's is giving us.
So see you in the next video.