In this video, we'll look at three
operators that apply to strings. In fact,
they apply to any sequence type.
Alright, so back to the code. I'm going to create a new Python
file called sequence operators.
So we've already seen the plus operator used for
strings to concatenate them. So let's just
type in a few strings, so I'm gonna start
with typing string1 equals "he's ", with a single quote there, but the
string in double quotes, string2 equals
"probably ", in double quotes, with a space
after the y, string3 equals "pining ",
with a space at the end of the letter g,
string4 is equal to "for the " space, and
double quote there, and then string5 equals double
quotes "fjords", and then I'm going to print
on line 7, string1 + string 2 + string3,
whoops I put a space there, string3
+ string4 + string5.
But the plus isn't necessary when concatenating string literals, though, in Python,
so we could also do print, so on line 9, double quotes he's space, then another space outside the
double quotes, probably, space there,
another closing off double quote,
another set of double quotes but after a space there to separate it, pining space,
whoops,
space outside of the double quote
for the  and space space and Fjord's, not sure if I pronounced that correctly.
Alright,
so that'll print the same thing and
if we run this, we should see both
outputting the identical output, and
obviously I made a typo.
Run it again
and we've got the identical output in both
cases. So I mentioned this second way,
because it's how Python works, not
because we think you'd ever want to do
something like that.
I'm sure you'd agree that the first
example on line 7 is a bit easier to
read. Now with that said, strings can also
be multiplied, which is a bit weird if you're coming from another programming language.
I can come down on line 11, I can
type print parentheses Hello in double
quotes with a space before the closing
double quote.Then I'm going to put * 5.
Now you can't actually perform arithmetic
multiplication on strings, of course.
Instead what happens is, the star or
multiplication operator repeats the
sequence a certain number of times; 5 in
this case.
So if we run the code
you can see we've got the word Hello printed, or outputted, five times.
Now lists and tuples can also
be multiplied, as we'll see when we look
at those sequence types later in the
course.
You can't concatenate or multiply a
range though, and that's not a problem
because you probably wouldn't want to do
that anyway. Now once again, operator
precedence applies, so if I type some
other code here,
if I type print parentheses double quotes Hello, space before the closing double quote,
multiplied by 5 plus 4. So this example wouldn't
print Hello nine times, and again, we're
talking about operator precedence there.
So if we run this program, we'll see that
we'll get an error, and the reason we're
getting an error is because Hello, in
double quotes, x 5 evaluates to a string,
and then there's an attempt to then add
the numeric number 4 to it and it fails
for that reason. So what we can do is, I'm
going to show you two things here, and
they actually do different things.
So firstly, I'm going to change line 13 to put five + four in
parentheses, but then also I can type on
line 14, print parentheses double quotes
Hello space again and multiplied by 5,
plus and 4 in double quotes.
Now because of the parentheses, line 13
evaluates 5 + 4 to get 9, so it should
then repeat the string 9 times. Line 14
should repeat the string 5 times
and then append the string 4 to it, so let's
just run that and confirm that's how it
works, and can see that works, as I
mentioned. Alright, so there's also an
operator to check if one string is a
sub-string of another. To do that,
we actually check if one thing is in
another. So let's start by typing some code.
On line 16 I'm going to type, today
equals Friday, and that's in double quotes
because it's a string.
Okay, next I'm going
to type print parentheses double quotes,
day in today,
and put a comment here for each, which
should be True, print fri in today, and
obviously the first part's in double
quotes, as you can see there. That should
also be True; third example, print
parentheses and we'll put t h u r in
today, which should obviously be False,
and lastly we do a print parentheses parrot in double quotes in double quotes fjord.
That should also be False,
and I'll just clean up
these a little bit.
So here, the in operator evaluates to True if the first
thing exists in the second,
and false otherwise. We'll be using that a lot when we look at conditions and for loops,
and you'll get plenty of practice using it
and see loads of real examples.
So I'm not going to discuss it any further now,
but we'll just run that to confirm we're
getting the results that we think we
should. You can see we get True, True,
False, False, which goes in line with the
code from 17 to 20, and getting the expected values.
Alright so let's end the video here
and in the next one, we're going to look
at the various ways we can format
strings, and some of the string methods
that allow us to manipulate them.
See you in the next video.