So string replacement fields can also
contain formatting, to display values
with a specific number of decimal places,
for example.
So let's create a new Python file. I'm going to call it formatting,
and I'm going to use a for loop to
generate some output.
We'll be looking at for loops in the next section, so don't worry about what's happening.
Concentrate on the print lines that I'm going to type in this code, to see
the effect of the formatting in the
replacement fields. So we're going to
start by printing the values from 1 to 12, with the values of their squares and cubes.
So on line 1 I'm going to type
for i in range(1, 13):
and put a colon to the right of the
right parenthesis. So on line 2 I'm
going to press ENTER here. You need to
make sure there's 4 spaces before print,
which I'm about to type, on line 2. I'm
going to type print parentheses,
and in double quotes I'm going to type number, or the abbreviation No, period. Then I'm
going to put replacement field 0, which
is our left and right curly braces with a
0 in the middle, squared is, and replacement field 1, and cubed is, replacement field 2.
Then I'm going to type dot
format parentheses i, i. I'm going to use
the exponent operator, which is 2
multiplication signs, 2 then i, exponent
operator again, 3, which is to the
power. It's basically raising one number
to the power of another in Python.
Alright so if we run this now,
and you can see we've got the values of the
number, the value squared, and the value
cubed, for each of those numbers. And in
case it's not obvious now, you can
provide any expressions inside the
format parentheses. They don't have to be
variables or literal numbers. On line 2,
we've got i exponent operator 2 to get
the number squared, and i exponent
operator 3 to get the number cubed.
And the exponent operator, is how you can raise one
number to the power of another in Python. So that's the power to operator as well.
Alright so that works, but as
you can see, the numbers aren't - or the
values rather - aren't lined up. So we can
fix that in the output, or we'll fix the
output by applying some formatting. So
firstly, I'm going to specify a field width
for each of the replacement fields. So
all the values for i are a maximum of
two digits, because we're, obviously, only counting
from 1 to 12 here. So we can use a
field width of 2 for the first
replacement field.
I'm going to use a field width of 4
for the other two fields. So to actually
specify width, we come back up to our
line 2, and we add the width by putting a
colon and then the number that we need.
So for the first replacement field
zero,  I'm going to put :2 there, for a
width of 2, and for the other two
replacement fields I'm going to put :4 and :4 again. So if we run the program now,
it's now easier to understand, because the
formatting makes it easier to see at a
glance, what the values are. Alright so that
looks tidier. The values are now
lining up nicely.
So on line 2, we're using 0:2 in
our left and right curly braces for the
first replacement field.
2 is the field width, as I mentioned,
and it's separated from the index with a colon.
Now everything in that first
column prints in a width of two
characters. So think of it as
reserving two spaces on the screen,
so that the one digit values still line up
with the two digit ones, and you can see
they're happening there in the output.
Now our squares also line up, in a field
width of four characters. Maybe a width
of three would look better there; have
a got at changing that yourself, and see
what it looks like. Pause the video
and I'll make the change when you come back.
Okay, so if we only want to use three
spaces for the square values, the change is
obviously easy enough. We come back up to
replacement field 1, change the 4 to
a 3, and if we run it again,
well that looks tidier still now, as
you can see. There's now only one space
between is and the value on the last
three rows. We can also align the values
in their field width. To left align the
values we place a &lt; symbol after
the colon. So what I'm going to do is,
just to make this easier to see, I'm going
to firstly add a blank line. Then I'm
going to take a copy of the line - of the
two lines there. We'll just run it again
so the original code's there as well. So I'm going to paste that in as it was before.
So this time what I'm going to do, again we're
trying to left align the values,
so we'll leave replacement field 0 as it
is, the first one. For the second one
we're going to put, before the three, I'm
going to put the less than sign there,
and for replacement field 2, we're going
to put a less than there as well.
So if we run this,
and the values are now left
aligned, and if it's not immediately
clear to you what's going on there,
scroll up the output to compare the
two blocks. But if we have a look at the
formatting here, notice how it's now left
aligned. If we go back up to the top, you
can see clearly that was right aligned.
So the alignment symbols are quite
visual. The less than, left aligns,
the greater than will right align, and a caret
symbol, well that centers within the
field width. So let's center the last
column to see what that looks like.
So instead of using the less than there, I'm
going to change that by using the caret
symbol instead. And if you run this code
again,
you can see the values are now clearly centered, compared to the
first output,
which was right justified on the right hand side
and this is
obviously for the cubed values.
Now keep in mind that we don't get half
spacing in a terminal, so the result
isn't as accurate as centering values in
a GUI program, but it's available if you want it.
So for floating-point numbers
you can specify a precision - the number
of digits after the decimal point. For
our precision, we specify the precision
after a decimal point, following the width.
So let's have a go at doing that, so I'm going to type some more code in.
So I'm going to put an empty line in there,
and the line after, well
actually line 11, I'm going to type print
parentheses Pi is approximately,
we're going to put replacement field 0:12,
which is the precision for a floating-point number, then dot format
parentheses 22 divided by 7, and 2 right parentheses
to close it off. And let's take a copy of
that line, we're going to make some
modifications. So I need another 5 lines.
I'm going to paste that 5 times.
Alright, so on line 12 what we're going to
do, is we're going to put an f after the 12.
Next line, we going to put 12.50f, line 14
we're going to put 0:52.50f,
and the next, I'm going to put 62.50f, and
the last line, I'm going to put 72.50f.
So the first line of output, well
actually, I'll run it first and then we'll talk about it.
So the first line of output, and that's produced from the code on line 12.
I'm going to see if I can get that on the
screen at the same time, on line 11 rather,
well that's the general format,
and that defaults to printing 15 decimals.
When we specify a
floating-point value using the f on line 12,
we get the default of 6 digits after
the decimal point.
Now on lines 13 through 16, we're still
specifying a floating-point format,
but we also add a precision of 50 and that
gives 50 points after the decimal point.
The third line of output corresponds to
line 13. If you think it doesn't look
right that's because Python won't
truncate a number. We can't put a value
that's got 50 decimals in a field width
of 12. Python decides that precision is
more important than field width, and
ignores the value 12 that we've
specified for the width, and that's the
code on line 13.
Now the next three lines after that,
print the same value but in different
field widths. When we specify width
greater than 50, you can see that the
effect becomes clear. Now the maximum
precision of a Python floating-point
number is between 51 and 53 digits.
There's not much point specifying a
precision greater than that. Now this
will be easier to see if I left align,
that last line, so I'm going to do that,
and then copy it and increase the
precision just to show you what I mean.
I'm going do that, copy that last line 16.
I'm going to change the 72.50f to 72.54f,
but we're also going to use the
left align, so you can see the value
left aligned, and we'll put that
to the left of the 72 after the colon. We run the
program now,
and what I should do is,
actually, left align the previous line
as well just so you can see the differences.
So we'll do that again as
well on line 16, we'll run that again,
and you can see we only get one extra digit
in the output. We can see that there's
four digits here but the remaining
digits are just padded with zeros,
so there's no actual value there. Alright
so I'll finish this video now by
mentioning that the field number in
replacement fields is optional.
If they're not specified, then Python takes
the value from the format method in order.
So to see what I mean, I'm gonna
take a copy of the code again,
this code up here on line six. I'll take a copy of
that again.
I'm gonna paste it down here on line 19,
and I'm going to actually remove
everything. So we're just going to put
just a left and right curly brace only,
for the three replacement fields,
and actually, what I'll do on the third
replacement field, I'll just put a
colon 4 there, so we can see that we're still
specifying a width.
If we run this,
we can see that the third field shows that you can still use a colon to control the layout,
even if you haven't specified a
field number. All the values in the final
column of output are printing in a field
with the 4. Now if you don't provide
field numbers, you can't use a value more
than once, nor can you change the order
in which values are used. Now our earlier
example, with the number of days in the month,
wouldn't have actually worked without
field numbers.
Alright, so experiment with different
values for the field widths and precision's,
to see how it affects your output,
and I'll see you in the next video.