in the previous video we have a look at
polymorphism and we saw how different
objects can inherit similar behavior
from a common base class so although ints
floats and lists are different types
they can all be printed
that's because they will provide a
string or STR method if a type doesn't
provide a specific implementation of str
string method it ends up
getting inherited from the base object
class so python isn't really interested
in what type something it focus
instead on how things behave so again if
it quacks like a duck it's a duck when
we finish the last video by giving our
penguin class the same methods as the
duck class so that penguin would behave
the same as a duck so inheritance isn't
the only way to implement polymorphism a
class can behave in the same way as
another class as long as it's got the
necessary methods and data attributes so
relating this back to our enemy objects
we can say that a troll is an enemy and a
vampire is an enemy so inheritance
results in a is a relationship and
similarly a penguin is a duck at least
as far as that test_duck
functions concerned so in this video
we're going to start having a look at
two other object orientated terms
composition and aggregation now
composition and aggregation are used when
you have a has a relationship rather
than a is a relationship so if we go
have a bird's wings we wouldn't say that
a duck is a wing would say that duck has
a wing now if you're unsure about
whether you should use inheritance or
not then those two ways of looking at
the relationship will normally make it
obvious whether inheritance is
appropriate or not what I'm going to do is
going back over here now to our duck
.py again I'm just going to comment
at this code at the bottom for new so
what I'll do is I'll comment the
test duck altogether and we'll just
like Donald in will just comment out
percy for now and I'll just delete the call
to test _ ducks so we are just left
now with defining donal alright so
let's add a wing class to the start of a
main file and we are going to give duck
class wings so at the top
here.....
...
....
ok the couple of extra lines to keep intellij
...
happy now this is simplified
slightly so whether wing is capable of
lifting an object such as a duck depends
on things like the weight of the object
the surface area and shape of the wing
and its speed through the air and we
could apply Newton's law and put in the
correct formula to decide if our wings
capable of flying when it's attached to
various birds but I've taken a much
simple approach for this example if the
ratio of the wings thrust to the weight
of the bird is greater than one we're
going to say that the wing can fly if
it's equal to 1
the bird has to flap hard to get off the
ground and if it's less than 1 then the
wing won't lift the bird
ok now we get to see composition in
action I'm going to go through all the
code once we've seen it working since it
makes more sense once you see what does
so go back to the duck method and need to
add a constructor....
...
....
...so let's just run this we get the
result we this is fun so and again we
this is fun is coming from self .
ratio being greater than one there so what
if we actually done here
well in the init method for duck class
on line 17 we create a new
wing object and assign it to the _
wing attribute of the duck class now
any duck objects we create will have
their own wing object and can use the
attributes of a wing including this case
the fly method now when a class
contains another object like this
that's called composition now we could
add a leg class and a beak and build a
complete duck out of component parts
the duck would then be composed of
other classes and would have few or no
attributes of its own that weren't provided
by the composing classes now that's
probably a bit extreme for a duck but
could make perfect sense if we were for
example representing an HTML document so
let's actually do that instead seeing
composition being used in a more
realistic situation is a good way to get
a feel for how powerful a technique can
be so let's create a new python file
new python and will call this one
....now I'm not going
to actually explain html here
most people already know the basics of
HTML even if you haven't created any web
pages using it a HTML document is
basically a structured document that
uses tags to enclose text the browser
uses those tags to work on how to display
the text let's just have a quick look at
the structure of HTML document open a
browser and do a search here for HTML
document structure the first results
telling us what it is without us having
to follow the link and probably the
better one here definition is
this one here the global structure of
HTML document i could click on that
and look and these three lines here
probably sum it up pretty well there's
three parts that a HTML document must
have a line containing HTML version
information that's called the document
type definition or DTD a header section and
a document body and we've got an example
on the screen here so at this point what we
can do is we can say that a html
document has a DTD and it has a header
and it has a body when you've got has a
relationships like this that's an
indication that we could consider we
should consider using composition when
creating a class
ok so the basic building block of HTML
is the tag
let's go back to code and start creating
a tag
class.....
....
...
we also want to create the string....
....
...
ok now if you're not familiar with HTML
tags they have a name which is enclosed
in angle brackets the tag is close by
using a similar tag but with a slash
before the name that's what we're trying
to do the definitions on line 4 and 5
if you go back to our browser again
in the structure here and you can see
the definition their now the DTD looks
quite complicated but it always takes
one of the few forms so when
getting a webpage you just copy and
paste it the rest of the documents in
close as you can see there in HTML
starting tag up here and ends with the
closing HTML tag down here notice how its
got a / in front of it for the closing
one and obviously we can see that on how it
works in the example here now the tag
names aren't case sensitive so i'm going to
be using lower case for no other reason
that I prefer typing it in lowercase now
within the HTML tag their is a head tag as you
can see here followed by body tag down
here the contents of the head tag up
here include a title and the bodies
contents here a single paragraph would
start with that p with the less than
greater than sign so the P tag in other
words strictly speaking looking at this
code there should be a closing P
tags in other words a less than sign / p
greater than sign closing tag but the
HTML specification isn't very
restrictive so you'll often find that
tags aren't closed xml on the other hand is
stricter and all tags there must be
closed so as this example is at the
moment you couldn't use an xml parser to
read this html code it will
actually fail because there's no
closing P tag here
alright so that's the sort of thing our
classes are looking to create or going
to create let's go back to intelliJ
now the tag class constructor
initializes the init method up here
on line three accept a name for the tag
and its contents it then uses string
formatting to create the start and end tags
and stores the contents in the self dot
contents data attribute now the string
method the STR method will return the
complete string for the tag so that's
the opening tag followed by the contents
and finishing with the closing tag and
as i mentioned i'm also giving the
class a display method just prints the
instance out as we saw earlier the print
function we use the result of the string
method to do that
alright so next we need a doc type class
so let's go ahead and create that it's
gonna be class....
....
...
alright so doc type inherits from tagged and
uses the super method to initialize
itself with the DTD that we saw on the
webpage now doctype doesn't have any
contents and there's also no closing tag
so we are setting that the closing tag
the end tag on line 19 to an empty string
but hang on though I've just extended
the tag class doesn't that mean we're
using inheritance here rather than
composition
yes we are now the two approaches are
exclusive and you can create a class
hierarchy using inheritance and then use
those classes in a composition
relationship to build up another class
when using composition you have to have
some classes to compose a class out of
so our HTML document class will be
composed of a DTD the header and a body
at the moment we're creating those
classes
we're going to come to composition when
we create the HTML . class in a minute
for now though let's just finish off
this video by creating the head and body
classes and turns out the head is going
to be very simple class to create we're
going to go ahead and do that it'll be....
....
...
....so just going to be there
the head opening and closing tags with
no content that's what we've actually
done there in the head class if we want
this to be complete we should actually
add similar code to what I'm going to
write in the body class but I don't want
to get distracted by those sorts of
things that go into the header so to
keep things simple our header is going to be
empty for now although I can sense the
a challenge is coming up
ok let's finish off now and create
the body class and end
the video move on to the next
one so class body tag....
....
...
alright so let's add method to add the
tag we're going to put....
....
...
alright let's just discuss this briefly
before we end the video so once again for
the body class were inheriting from the
tag class but we initialize the
contents to an empty string when calling
the super method because we don't what
the contents to be created just yet and
that's because we're going to store all
the contents and list as you can probably
ascertain in the attribute self dot
_body_ contents so we
initialize that to an empty list in the
constructor can see them doing that on line
32 now the add _ tag methods
used to add the content to our body and
we give it a name of a tag and the
contents and it creates a new tag
instance and appends that to the body
contents list i'm going to move swiftly
on here but you may already spotted this
is an example of composition absolutely
it is and I will come back and talk
about that more in the next video i want
to show you the use of composition in
the document first because that's a much
clearer example so moving on in the
display method as you can see there on
line 38 overrides the method from the
tag superclass so it builds up the
contents attribute by iterating over our
body contents list and adding each tag
to the contents and once thats done it
then uses the superclass display method
to display the body tag with the full
contents
now if you were going to fully implement
the header then we could give our head
class the same ability to add tags and
build up its contents in fact we might
create a special kind of tag class that
can contain other tags and have both
head and body inherit from that but we
are trying to keep things simple here
alright so I'm going to finish the video
here now in the next video
now that we've got all the classes that
we need to make up our HTML document we
can create the actual document class so
let's work on that in the next video