now towards the end of the last video I
mentioned that if we were going to fully
implement the header then we could get
our head class the same ability to add
tags and build up its contents and in
fact we might create a special kind of
tag class that can contain other tags
and then have both head and body inherit
from that but we are keeping things
simple here and at this point we've now
got all the classes that make up our
HTML document and we can create the
document class let's go ahead and do
that in the bottom
ok so....
....
...
...this init method
defines three data attributes to hold
the doctype head and body of a HTML
document now in all three cases a new
object of the appropriate classes
created as you can see and each attribute
is assigned a reference to the new
object so our HTML dot class is made up
of instances of the three other classes
so you could say that it's composed of
the three other classes and that's
composition now this example is pretty
uncomplicated because the HTML. class
is entirely composed of other classes it
doesn't have any data attributes of its
own
now that doesn't have to be the case so
I don't want to give the impression that
composition means creating a class and
entirely out of other classes
the important thing is that our HTML
. class contains other classes and
can make use of the attributes that
those classes provide alright i'll
carry on with the code
so we can see this program working and
how it produces a html doc so we
want to add a method....
...
....
...we need to
add content to our document and HTML
content consists of various tags so what
given the html. class and add tag or
add_tagged method to allow
tags to be added to the document this
method just delegates the job of adding
a tag to its instance of the body class
the body class takes care of
implementing the process of adding a new
tag to its contents the HTML . class
just passes on the name of the tag and
the contents as you can see on line 53
now we could have called this method
anything add_content for
example but by giving it the same name
as the class that will actually be doing
the work for us our body class in this
case we can pass the HTML document
object to any function that adds tags
now the other thing we want to do with
html objects is display so i'm
going to add a display method....
....
...
so once again this method delegates most
of the work to the classes that contains
so the DTD is displayed by calling the
doc type instances display method now after
the DTD everything else is enclosed in
the HTML opening and closing tags on line
57 and 60 now we could have created a
class to handle that but that's really
going to be too far
there's only one html tag in a
document and hard coding like this is a
much simpler solution now the display
the remaining content is also delegated
to the appropriate classes so apart from
including the opening and closing HTML
tag our documents display method
doesn't have a lot to do
once again we could have called this
method anything but by calling it
display it matches the corresponding
method in the classes its composed of
by calling the method display it can then
be used by any function that displays
tag objects in fact the method it has are
exactly the same as the method in the
body class so our HTML dot class is now
displaying polymorphic behavior it is a
html doc but it can also be used
in place of a body object it can even be
used in place of any of our tag
subclasses when pass to functions that
just need to display method so we've
implemented polymorphism without using
inheritance we've used composition
instead now the program itself does use
inheritance all our other classes
inherit from tagged but the HTML doc type
isn't a subclass of tag it provides the
same methods as their tags but does so
by defining methods with the same name
and then delegating the implementation
of those methods to the classes that is
composed of alright so let's see this
running to make sure that this theory
that we've been talking about does work
in practice so we're going to add a
method down here....
....
...
...creating a new
HTML object and then were assigning the
reference to it to a very variable
called my_page so next we
use this add_tag method to add a
heading and a subheading now the add_tag
method remember just
delegate to the body classes add
underscore tag method so these elements
will really be added to the body section
so effectively we're building up the
document by calling the add_tag
method to add the content that we want
when we done the last line we're calling
the display method to display the
finished document
alright so let's just run the program
need to put a colon in that line
correct on line are 63 and run this
now
and we got an error over here and we can see
that the typo looks to me that I've use
start _ capital T so just click on
that to go to the link that's the
problem you can see added a capital T
i'll make the lowercase T because
obviously the the attributes
should be or have rather a lowercase T
in its name
let's just try running it again and this
time we seem to fix it which is much
better
alright so you can see now if
you familiar with HTML that this is now
perfectly formed HTML code
now it's not as readable as it would be
if a human it type it manually but line
breaks are ignored in HTML documents
there only added to make it easy for
humans to read if you're not familiar
with HTML the real test will be if it
displays correctly in a browser so let's
actually make a change so that we could
write the document out to a file instead
of just printing it now the only changes
we need to make are to the three display
methods i'm going to start with the base
class the tag classes go back up and
look at that
so the display method here on the line
11 we want to change that what we're
going to do is add another parameter here
so after the display itself...
....
ok so we've added a named parameter called
file that matches the file parameter of
the print function so we need to
do the same in the body class down here
under display in the body class on line
38....
...
....
alright so we added a filename parameter
as you can see there to this method as
well and then provide the default value
of none so if a file isn't specified the
class will be printed to the screen
effectively alright so now the
display method of the html. class
ok so down here in the display method
we put....
....
...
....so now that we've done that we can
now send the output to a file if we want
to using the technique we saw back in
Section 10 when we're writing to files
so let's end this video here now in the
next video we'll come back and test
this will talk a little bit more about
composition and then we'll move on to a
challenge see you in the next video