In this video, we're going to follow on
from writing our data to the history table
and look at how we can get it back out again.
Now you ought to be wondering
why I've bothered creating this video,
after all we can just run a simple select query, can't we?
Well let's actually see whether that's true.
So what I'm going to do is start off by creating
a new path and file.
And we'll call this one check db.
And let's actually just try getting some data from the
transactions or rather the history table.
So import, sqlite3.
Then we're gonna do db equals sqlite3 dot connect
and counts dot sqlite.
And we'll just extract the data or retrieve the data
for row in db dot execute, and was select star
from history, and we'll print out the condensed print row.
And then would do a db dot close once that's been done.
Alright, so that looks relatively painless.
To look what happens when we run this,
and I put a colon on the end there.
And you can see we get a tuple printed for each row
in the history table.
Now everything looks fine at a cursory glance
until we look closely.
We can see that the tuple consists of two strings
and an end.
So our time stamp fuel is being retrieved as a string,
and that's not what we want.
Now, if we have a date time value,
we can convert it to a local time for example,
and let's have a go at that.
Commit that out for now, the print.
And we can do something like print,
another replacement field backslash t to add a tab,
another replacement field dot, and then you can do format
local and it's called time,
and type local and just put time.
And I need to actually define local time.
So local underscore time is equal to row zero.
And we use the talk function in the last section
to see what type our penguins were.
So, let me actually run this.
You really can see
that the local underscore time variable
is definitely a string type.
Now we could convert these string types into
date time values by importing the date time module
and using the STRP time method.
You find everything you need
to do that in the documentation.
So do feel free to try it out.
So it's the STRP time method from the date time module.
Now there is one gotcha though,
which I'm going to mention a bit later,
but as long as you use the Python documentation
and not the sqlite date time docs,
you actually won't have any problems.
But we're not actually going to do that here,
because there is another way that I wanted to show you.
Now we've used the python sqlite3 time stamp
contalk for our times, and this relies on the fact
that the sqlite3 library can examine custom data types
for a column and respond to types that it knows about.
Now, it's possible to define and register
your own data types if you want to,
but the date and time stamp types have already been
registered for us.
What we do have to do is tell sqlite3 to respond to them,
and we do that by passing PARSE underscore DECYLTYPES
when we create the connexion.
So let's actually look at how we would do that.
So we go to our line, that is connecting up here, line four.
And what we have to do now is we pass the parameters,
that's going to be, detect underscore types is equal to
sqlite3 dot, then we do PARSE,
underscore DECLTYPES,
like so.
And if we run this again now that we've done that,
you can see that this time we've got a different result.
And you can see quite clearly near the type
coming back is date time dot date time instead of string.
So that's pretty cool.
So Python is performing automatic conversion
when we write the data, and up here
so setting the detect underscore types argument
to sqlite3 dot PARSE underscore DECLTYPES
as we've done here, causes it to perform a conversion
when reading the data back as well.
Now if you want to read the details of how this all works,
let's check out the python sqlite3 documentation.
It is a page specifically for that.
So, there's quite a bit there,
and the relevant bit is in section 12.6.6.2.
Using adapters to store additional Python types
in Sqlite databases.
So basically describing adapters and converters.
So it's definitely also worth searching that page for
PARSE underscore DECYLTYPES.
I'm going to search for PARSE underscore DECYL.
You can see that there is some more information
in there as well as to what that is and how to use it.
Now you don't actually need to know all the ins and outs
of how this is implemented.
All we have to do is add that argument
when calling the connect method,
and then any timestamp fields
will be handled by the library.
So that's again this line here, on line four.
Now this doesn't handle timezone aware dates though,
and I'm going to quickly demonstrate that.
So back in rollback dot pi,
I'm going to change the current time method now.
Let me close this down.
So with this current time method here on line 14.
Let's change that, instead of returning as date time
we'll just current that out for now.
We're actually going to instead,
type local underscore time is equal to
pytz dot utc dot localise.
I'm probably just going to copy that,
so date time dot date time dot utc now,
and if you return local time dot as timezone.
So we're converting it into a timezone,
and then I go back into my database.
And for the history table, we'll just double click that
and we'll just delete any records that are in there.
Until they get recreated.
You're going to delete them and commit the change,
and now we got a commitment button not refresh.
Okay, so that's been committed,
and I'll just close that now.
And if you run this again, and open the database again.
Probably should have left that open.
You can see now in my case it's added the timezone
plus 10 colon 30 which is the current timezone
for Adelaide, Australia.
And if you run this on your computer you will get
whatever your local timezone is.
But, with that said, if I go back to check bd dot pi
and run that again,
and those have the results that we're getting back here
do not include the timezones,
and in other words there is no offset appearing.
And these values aren't timezone aware.
So strange as that may seem there's actually no easy
and reliable way to correctly PARSE those values
into aware date time values
using the standard Python libraries.
Now this is something you really need to do, if it is,
storing and retrieving times with timezone information.
There are actually different libraries that can help.
Now I'm going to link to a couple
in the resources section.
So be sure to check those out and I'll just load up one
just to give you an idea what they look like.
In the browser.
So there's one library.
It says extension to the standard Python datetime module
and it provides powerful extensions to the datetime module
available in the Python standard library.
There is also a couple more, so I'll put links
to this one and the other two
in the resources section of this video.
Alright, so back to the code.
So I'm going to change back to rollback dot pi
to how it was before.
So what I'm going to do is just commit those two lines out
in case you want to test that for yourself with the code,
and I'll just put the original return statement back in
that didn't use a timezone.
Alright and then I go back
to the history table again to refresh it,
and I'm just going to delete the entries again.
Okay, on the programme again.
We got our entries back and there is no timezone,
and obviously we'll get the same result now with checkdb.
Alright, so I'm now going to look at two different ways
to display our timestamps
in local time rather than utc times.
Now the first method is just to convert
the utc times into aware times, then localise them.
And we saw the code to do that a minute ago
when I changed rollback dot pi.
So I'm going to butterfly checkdb dot pi here now
to show the times as local times alongside the utc times.
So we're going to make a change to this checkdb,
and we're going to start by putting utc
underscore time is equal to row zero.
Then we want to local underscore time is equal to pytz
and actually what we need to do is import the library
so let's stop and do that.
Import pytz.
Then pytz now on line nine
dot utc dot localise
and it's going to be utc underscore time
then dot as timezone.
And I'll take those two lines there and we can
terms for printing it out now.
We're just going to print out instead of local time,
we're going to do utc underscore time
as the first bit of output
and the second type of output
is no longer going to be the type,
it's just going to be local time.
Like so.
Alright, now that I run this,
we can see now that we get the dates in my local time.
You can see that it's showing 8:56am.
Which is correct
and if I look at that now
it's actually a couple minutes past.
So it's 8:58am,
and the reason a couple minutes past of course
this was saved about a minute and a half ago in the video
when I reran rollback dot pi.
You can now see the utc times and the same times
in my local timezone with an offset of 10:30.
Which is correct for this part of Australia in summertime.
Now that's one way of doing it.
But there is another way to do this as well,
so lets explore that alternative way
of doing things in the next video.