so just as a recap from the previous
video when we run this we do get an error
and looking at the error we can see objects has no attribute power and the
error is on line 45 which you can
see on the screen
and the reason for that is the Hamilton
instance doesn't have a power
attribute because we haven't created one by
assigning a value to it like we did for
the Kenwood instance on line 43 and this is
the dynamic nature of Python that
allows this kind of behaviour and you can
easily end up with instances that are
created from the same class
template but which ultimately have
different attributes and it can be
useful feature but can also cause
problems if you make a typing error when
trying to assign a value to an existing
data attribute for argument sake so it's
worth paying careful attention to the
IntelliJ tool tips that will appear after
you type a do and to make sure that
you're assigning it to attribute that you really expecting it to be so
going back to the analogy of a class
definition being like house plan that
can be used to create houses in the real
world theirs nothing to stop an extension
being added to a house out after its built and
that's pretty much what is happening
here now of course subclassing which is
where a new class is created from an
existing one may be preferable to adding
attributes to instances and will be
looking at sub classes a little later
there are ways to prevent this kind of
behaviour and you can create classes in
such a way that additional
attributes can't be added to instances
forcing classes to be sub class extra
functionality is required but Python allow you to take either approach in now their is one aspect of
classes that I want to mention before we
start practicing all this by creating
some more useful classes now I introduced
to small talk term instance variable in
the previous video and that's because it
includes the words variable whereas data
attribute does not and this is important
because methods are also attributes of
classes and you find the term attribute used to
refer to both in the documentation
so the terms data attribute and method are
used to distinguish between the two
types of attribute now the other aspect that I want to mention is that classes also
have attributes and once again the
Smalltalk term instance variable is
useful because it contains the word
instance now the data attributes in the
kettle example as such as make and price have both been attributes of the instances and each
instance has its own values for them so its
also possible for the class to have
attributes which is shared by all the
instances so to stick with the analogy
of a house plan each house that we built from the
plan will have different attributes such
as its address however all the houses will share some attributes such as the type of
house now all house are built from a plan for a four-bedroom lodge would be four
bedroom lodges so our kettle class is modelling electric kettles so we can
introduce a class attribute called power source
that all instances will share
so lets go ahead and do that so we are gonna go back up to
the top of the definition for the kettle
class and on line 32 I'm going to add....so
that's a class attribute that we've added called power source
so now we've done that we can demonstrate that all instances share a single version of this class attribute so we are gonna add the following
at the end of the file but first I'm going to comment out line 47 to remove that error so we
can try doing...
...
.....now if you run that...you could see that all three have got
electricity as the power source so the two
instances kenwood and hamilton plus the class
itself kettle have got this power source class
attribute so think of that if you know
Java or C++ this is very similar to
static fields in those languages similar
but not exactly the same but although its a
useful comparison if you are used to
those other languages don't take this to
literally it is useful to examine the
namespaces of the three objects to
verify that the two instances are
sharing the same attribute which only
exists in the class and we can access the
namespace via the dic attribute so lets go ahead and do that so...
....
....and
I'm going to change or run it first move this as a
bit more space I'm gonna move to bottom we can see
its a little bit better and looking at that
output down the bottom of the screen the
kettle class namespace contains quite a
lot of items and we can see power
source showing their and we can see some of the other functions we
can see an init function and we
should be able to see our switch on
method if we scroll over and their is the switch on
kettle.switch_on so that's their and the 2
instances below that you can see that
they've got far less in their namespace and in fact theirs only
the instance variables make price and on
and you see Kenwood has got the extra power
attribute that's the second from
bottom one that we added earlier in this
code but other than that
their the same so what happens is that
when we try to access the power_source
attribute for the instances Python checks
to see if the power source exists in the
instance name space if it doesn't which
is the case here it then checks the class
for the instance and finds power source
in the kettle class and that's why the
reason it printed out because basically
it got it from the class attribute so if
you close it down if you go ahead and make a
change with the power source if we do something like this
so....
....
so if we run this again you can see what happens there is that atomic we are switching to atomic power and the three
printouts are now all the same again as well and only updated the class attribute
but it has changed the other two instances one automatically which is more or less sort of proof that the
instances for Hamilton and kenwood are
looking at the class attribute at that
point and this is probably not
surprising if Python is your first
experience of object oriented
programming and will probably make
perfect sense after our discussion of global
variables and functions that we've talk
about previously so as long as we only access the class
data attribute via the class rather than via
instance then when we want to assign a new value to it this works as expected so all 3 objects are still sharing their
common power source in this scenario and
show the same value in this case atomic
but that's not true if you try and
change this in different ways so if we
come down to say the kenwood instance below their will do....
...
...so if we run that now...you can see in the bottom here we've got atomic for the class attribute we change kenwood to gas and that is showing
as gas and Hamilton still showing
atomic
and the class attribute is still showing
as atomic so this is probably not that
surprising if Python is your first experience
of object-oriented programming and would
probably make perfect sense after our
discussion in previous videos about
global variables and functions remember
that as soon as we try to assign a value
to a global variable
Python created a new local variable that
shattered the global one so a
similar thing is actually happening in
this scenario when we added the code to
switch the Kenwood power source to gas the code on line 53 so although kenwood
is now running on gas hamilton's is still
running on atomic power which is one of
the ways that class attributes differ
from Java static fields and examining
the source if we run this again and
look at the namespaces notice now that Kenwood second to
bottom one has now got its own data attribute
called power_source that
shadows the class attribute so this is
definitely something to watch out for as
it's quite easy to make the mistake of
assigning a new value to a class attribute
via an instance variable and Java will give you a warning if you try to access
as a static field via an instance variable
but you won't get any such warnings in
Python so that's the basic of classes
and their is a quite a bit of jargon and new concepts that we've thrown in
there and it may not make complete sense
at the moment but don't worry because I'm
gonna be using a lot of examples in the
next set of videos that will consolidate
what's been covered so far a simple kettle class doesn't really do very much
but as we create more class and using them to
encapsulate data and functionality it'll
start making a lot more sense now
also we've introduced other object-oriented
concepts such as inheritance and
composition so that we can build more
complicated class structures and the
other thing I do is also introduce other
object-oriented concepts such as
inheritance and composition so that we
can build more complicated class
structures so we'll start off slow in
the next few videos will look at some
more examples of using classes see you
in the next video