I finished the last video by saying that
strings are immutable,
whereas lists are mutable. When an object
is described as immutable, that means it
can't be changed.
The following immutable types are built
into Python: int, float, bool - which is True
or False, a subclass of int, string or str,
which is a string, tuple, frozenset and
bytes. So it should be obvious that an
int like 5 can't be changed. 5 is always
5. You can add another value to it - for
example, we can add 1 to 5 and we get a
new number 6: However, we can't change 5.
The same's true of floats. 3.14159 will
always be 3.14159. Once again, we can
perform arithmetic with a float, and get
a new float value, but we can't change
the value of 3.14159. So stay with me on
this, because there might be an obvious
question that you're asking.
I'll explain that next, but at the moment,
trust me that these values are immutable.
bool values are also immutable, and so are strings.
The question you're asking is
probably becoming disbelief now.
So let's type in some code now, that proves this.
So I'm going to create a new Python file
here, called immutable, for these examples.
So let's start by typing result equals
True - True with a capital T,
another_result is equal to result,
print on the next line, left parenthesis id
left parenthesis result then two right
parantheses. Then on line 4, print left
parenthesis id, a left parenthesis
another_result and we've
got our two right parentheses to end
the line. Alright, so here, we've got two
variables; result and another_result. They're both bound to the value
True. On lines three and four, are
printed out the ID of those variables.
Now it's worth checking the documentation for the ID function, so I'll just briefly do that.
So as you can see there, id
returns the identity of an object.
Now the documentation doesn't state that
it should be the object's address, just
that it must be "guaranteed to be unique
and constant for this object during its
lifetime". The CPython implementation does
return the object's memory address, but
not all Pythons will do that. The ID for
an object may be different each time you
run the program, but while your program
is running, the object will have the same id.
Of course, if python has to destroy the
object and re-create it, then it's ID will
also change. So that gives us a good way
to tell if an object is changed, or if
python has to create a new object.
Let's go back to our code. Let's run it. We can
see here that both variables have the
same ID. They're both bound to the same
value - True - so that makes sense that it
should have the same ID. Remember that
we're printing the ID of True here.
The variables - result and another_result - are just names that we've bound
to that value. Alright, so if bool
values could be changed, then changing
the values should mean that the ID
doesn't change. So let's see if that's
the case, so I'm going to add some new
code down here, line 6, result equals
False with a capital F. Then we're going
to print left parenthesis id left
parenthesis result, then two right
parentheses to end the line. Let's run
that code, and you can see here, we've got
a different ID for a result with the
code that we've just added. Because bools
are immutable, we weren't able to change
the value of True. What Python's done
instead, is rebound result to a new value - False.
When we were looking at the slides,
when I said that bools were immutable,
you may have been thinking, but hang on -
I can assign a new value to a boolean
variable. Now that would be true in other
languages. In C or Java, for example,
you can assign new values to boolean
variables. In Python, though, that's not
the case.
Instead, we've attached the name result,
to a new value. So let's comment out all
that code, and here's another example here.
I'm going to type result equals double
quotes Correct with a capital C, and
that's in double quotes, as I mentioned,
and then on line 10, I'm going to type
another_result is equal to result,
and I probably could have pasted
those lines before I commented it out but
I'll just type it again: print and left
parentheses, id left parenthesis
result, and the same thing, this time for
another_result. So I'm printing
the ID for both variables, again, as we
did earlier. Alright, so let's run the program,
and you can see here that the
variables, again, have the same id.
Alright, so moving on, let's attempt to
mutate result. Now we can use augmented
assignment to concatenate more
characters to the end. Let's have a go at
doing that: result plus equals double
quotes ish. I'll print the id again.
So if we could mutate the string, then the
value that result is bound to would
change. The ID should remain the same if
that happened. Let's run the program and
see what happens - and it's not. As you can
see there, result now has a different id.
Now just in case you're not convinced,
I'm going to print the id for
another_result as well, so let's do
that. I'll just take a copy of that from
line 12 and paste it in. Run that. So
notice that the id of result has
changed, but another_result
still has the same id that it had to
start with. Because strings are immutable,
Python couldn't change the string
correct. What it did instead was create a
new string, and bind the name result to
this new string. Now don't worry if
you're still a bit confused about this -
it will make sense once you've seen the
same thing with a mutable object,
and we'll look at doing that in the next video.