So, in the previous video we started
with an introduction to lists, and
we went through various scenarios to
sort of see how we could manipulate some
basic lists and indeed actually
talked about what lists were.
So, as it turned out we went through
three ways to create a list,
the first was enclosing the item in square
brackets by concatenating existing lists,
adding two together, and also by
using a function that returns a list,
which I used in this example, sorted.
We can also use the list type constructor,
which is like a list in brackets,
with brackets.
And constructors will make more
sense when I've introduced classes,
which will be in a later
section of this course.
But for now, just think of the list
constructor as just another function that
you can actually call.
So, if you use list with no parameters
it just creates an empty list.
So, I'm going to delete this code and
we're going to start
with a clear slate here.
Like so.
So, using a list as I said with no
parameters, it just creates an empty list.
So we can type, and that ends up being
exactly the same as the first option here.
So, I've got list_1 = [],
which is an empty list,
but I can also do this, list_2 = list[].
And in both cases,
what they do is they create an empty list.
So basically,
they're both identical as you can see.
And just to confirm that,
we can actually print this out.
I can type print, list1.format.
This data's called 1, and
print list 2.format, this data's got 2.
And I can put if list_1 =,
this data's called 2.
Print the list are equal,
we can actually run this.
We can see that both are empty lists,
list 1 and list 2 are both empty.
So, you can see there and we get
confirmation by doing the comparison
the double equals sign to compare them,
and
they are both considered equal by Python.
Now ,I don't think we've actually
mentioned this before, but
actual, when you call a function
such as print or sorted.
So, function in this example being print.
You can see this stuff in the middle here.
They're actually called parameters or
arguments.
So, the parameter in our last
print function code was the string
the lists are equal.
So, this is actually a parameter.
That's a parameter that we're passing
to the function called print.
But later in the course, we'll start
actually creating our own functions, and
we'll actually cover parameters and
arguments then in more detail.
But strictly speaking,
the lists are not equal is an argument.
But the two terms, argument and
parameters are often used interchangeably.
So, the list constructor, and
again the constructor is using the list
with the brackets, can be called
with no parameters as we've done.
We can also call it with
a single iterable parameter.
So, in Python an iterable is just
an object that is capable of
returning its members one at a time.
So, all the sequence types built into
Python are actually iterable, and
we can actually pass a string to the list,
so we could do something like this.
print(list("The lists are equal."))
like so, we can run that.
And you can see what's happened
there is automatically,
Python has actually created a list from
what we sent to one character at a time.
So each item, each letter, of this string,
has been added individually,
as a separate option in that actual list.
And that's what the constructor's
actually doing.
It's actually doing that for us, and
I'm recalling that list function.
So, creating a list whose members
are each of the characters in the string
that we passed to the list.
And this was the lists are equal,
is what we actually passed to it.
So it can actually be very useful to
do that, if you wanna assign a list to
another variable, and
have them then reference different lists.
So, a normal assortment works as in other
languages, and it can actually confuse
newcomers to programmers, as I'm gonna
show in the following example, so,
I'm gonna type in some code here,
comment this out.
We can put even = [2, 4, 6, 8].
Then, we type another, even = even.
Then we can type another,
even.sort(reverse=True),
note the capital T for True.
We can do print(even), so
if we actually run this,
you can see what's
actually happened there.
We've actually got it printing out even,
even though,
we're actually updating another variable.
So, we've created another_even
variable and assigned it to even.
Then, we actually updated
the values of even using sort.
And we actually used the reverse
equal true parameter to actually
return the results sort of last to first,
instead of first to last.
But the important thing here was that,
even though we haven't actually updated
even directly we've used
another variable called even.
Because we've updated that variable
it actually updated the variable
even as well.
So, in other words both variables even and
another even
refer actually to the exact same list so
that and that's why when we used the sort,
both [INAUDIBLE] were actually sorted
as you can see, because we're actually
printing out the first list, which we
didn't actually directly use the .sort on.
And just to confirm that what we can
actually do, after the assignment we can
confirm that they're the same by
typing print, another_even is even.
And that should actually return true.
So if we actually run that,
it actually returns true,
which actually says from Python's
perspective these two are the same thing.
They're actually pointing
to the same list.
But if we actually create a new list for
another even variable,
and pass in the parameter of even,
we can get that not to be the case.
So we can actually type list here,
the function list,
well the constructor list, we're passing
even, that current list to that, and
list is going to return,
in fact, a new list.
So, when we do this print down here,
we should find that that comes up and
says false.
But we still will end up
getting the same results,
because we're still ultimately
sending the same information.
So, if we actually run this,
you can see that's now false.
And that's because they're
no longer the same list.
We had a list that was created for even.
And then we used the list constructor,
passing the even list.
And the list constructor
actually returns us a new list.
So, consequently,
there's two separate lists now.
The even variable has got its own list.
And the other _even variable has
also got its own list, as well.
Just to confirm, we can actually do
another test there and print another.
Instead of putting is we can put
equals equals then actually run that.
That's gonna tell us to say
at this point now it's true,
because that's saying whether the contents
are equal, not whether they're
actually pointing to different variables
in memory if that makes sense,
in different lists essentially.
So, it's important to know, The difference
there between the double equal.
So, we're actually comparing it to see
whether what's in the lists are the same
as supposed is.
We're saying is this the same list
that's actually in memory somewhere.
So, that's gonna return false,
cause it's separate now.
And again, equals is the contents
of the lists the same.
That's gonna return true.
Now, if you really wanted a new
version of even, the first variable,
we could have actually done something
like this, where instead of putting list,
we could have actually done
something like sorted, even,
reverse equals true,
true, we could run that.
And that's now false, because we
sorted it into a different order.
So, sorter does return a new list, but
now it's sorting it in a different order.
And just to confirm,
I set that to be is and run it.
It's still set to false,
because they're actually pointing
to different lists still.
And setting that to equals we
correctly get false as well,
and that's because the sorted
function returns a separate list.
So moving on.
So earlier, we concatenated or
appended our even and odd list.
That's actually in a previous video.
And we actually produced
a new list called numbers,
that included all
the items from both lists.
I'm gonna put some more
code on the screen.
And see, if you can actually
guess what this will do.
So, I'm gonna comment that out and
put the even in there.
And we're gonna put an odd equals 1,
3, 5, 7, 9 and
this is from the previous video when we're
dealing with adding these things together.
What do you think is gonna happen if I put
numbers equals even, odd and print it out?
So, can you guess what's
that gonna actually produce?
Let's run that and see.
Now, it actually returns
a list containing two lists.
So, you can see,
sort of lists within a list.
That's the list number one, which is
based on the contents of even, and
the second one is based on the contents
of odd, and now are both appended into in
one master list, and just to confirm that,
instead of actually printing that out,
let's actually change that and actually
add some code here and put a for loop.
So, for numbers_set in numbers.
Print.
Number set.
And it actually should have been number
set just to be technically correct.
Like so.
And then, we'll put for,
noting the indent level for
value in number_set.print(value).
So, in the outer loop number_set
iterates through the members of numbers,
so it's assigned each of
the two lists in turn.
And within the inner loop itself the value
iterates through the members of those
sets, so it's assigned each of
the even numbers first time around
then each of the odd ones
in the second time around.
So if we actually run that,
we can actually see we can
go right through the list.
We can go through and
print out the number set first.
This is the initial print.
And then, the second follow-up is
going through each of those numbers
within that list and printing them out.
It does that for both lists
because we've got an initial for
loop, the outside one, which actually
goes through all the contents.
So, we're actually gonna
end this video here.
In the next video I'm gonna go through and
just show you a few more examples of using
lists the way we've been using them.
And we'll actually then introduce you
to a mini challenge to finish that off.
So, I'll see you in the next video.