let's start talking now about the Python
Standard Library now this standard
library that ships with Python
provides a wide range of modules that we
can use so it includes everything built
into the language that we can use
without explicitly importing anything
plus whole lot of other useful modules
such as shelve and random which of course
we've used in the course previously now
I did say without explicitly importing
anything because the core built in modules
are imported for us automatically
so I'm gonna create a new file this is the
same project from the previous video so I'm gonna create a new Python
file and will call this one example so when
useful command that's gonna let us see
is dir command or dir function and thoes that uses will note that this is not
related to the dir command you can use
from a command prompt to print out a
list of directories so to see what is
imported for us automatically we can
print the output from dir so we could do
something like....
to call the dir method run that and right
click Tim and click run example I remember this time
and you can see when I've done that
we got a whole heap of information
as you can see there, now we're gonna be
covering this in a lot more detail later
but it's worth noting that anything
whose name starts with an underscore
here is something that we shouldn't be
changing without good reason so if the
name starts with two underscores like
these two and then not intend to be
changed at all so in fact
there's no such thing as private
variables in Python and everything is
available everywhere but the convention
is to use underscores to intention so starting a name
with an underscore indicates that it's
private to its module but it's up to you
as the programmer to inspect that convention
because Python itself doesn't prevent you
from changing and that's done by design
but getting back to the dir as you can see on the screen
here now we are not going to look at most of the entries as they are
to do with the internal running
of Python but a good one here is this
first one underscore underscore builtins
underscore underscore this is the module containing
the Python built-in identifiers and there is
actually a list that I'm going to put on the
screen and I'll share this link in the
Resources section and will just open a
browser and go that URL now that's a decent list of all
the built-in functions from or based on
that module the built-in
modules but with that said that's one way of
doing it but we can
also use the command to find out a bit more as well
so come here on the next line ill put..
...and if we run that that gives us a whole heap of
stuff and obviously you want to scroll that
but this is Python so we can easily
display that of course in a more readable
format as we've done this before so
let's just comment that line out and use our
handy for so.....so run again and I need a colon there so run again and now we got a decent list here so we got
a whole heap of errors at the top but also just scrolling
down the list you will see there is the false one
there is none we seen that before and true down here as well that just 3 and....
if you go a bit further you can see the dir hex input
and bin up here
slice and so on so essentially you should be able to
recognize quite a few of these other
entries and even things like list is
there on the screen
map open print etc of course that's more
interesting than actually useful but if
we import shelve we can have a look at
what that provide so lets close this down
so just delete the codes here and start again so
what we can do is import shelve and
have a look at what it actually provides so...
....and run that and you can see
we got a whole heap of bits and pieces there
relating to shelve and the first list
shows you shelve on the list because we imported
it that's now coming up in our list when
we print dir and printing dir on the shelve as you see on the
third line there has shown the objects and
methods available from the shelve module
of course we've used the open function
before to open a shelve and this returns
a shelve object so you may notice that
close doesn't appear in the list and I'll just run it again
so looking at the list when we use open there is the
open method in the end and when we do
that it returns a shelve object one of these
but you will notice that close doesn't
appear in the list and that's because
it's a method of the shelve
class we're not interested in the
underscore method so we can filter out to see what
a shelve object provides just to show you how that works so we can do something like, will leave the shelve import there and will put...
and I will put a test here to ignore underscore so..so let us run that and you can see now
that apart from pop and popitem we've
seen all these other methods either when
looking at shelve or when discussing
dictionaries and in face Intellij provides
a similar list plus a lot more in order
of completion we type the full stuff after shelve
so if we type something here going back
to the code so if we type....you can see there is
a big list of things that IntelliJ
will bring up automatically
IntelliJ is quite smart that way that it
can present all this information to us as well
now some of the standard modules are
written in C these are generally the
ones that provide access to system
functionality such as File I/O but many of
them are actually written in Python
and we can examine the source code from
IntelliJ holding down the Ctrl
key and clicking on the module name shelve
in this case so we can come over here
and we can I believe its control
on a PC but on a MAC it is command click on
a command hold command down and click on
shelve that's gonna give us access to the
source code for the shelve.py and
you can just scrolling down there is some actual code
that is part and parcel of Python
so until we have covered functions and classes the code you can see on the screen
probably looks a bit horrible to you so we are gonna leave it there and have a look at some of the
standards library code later in the course
so on the next few videos we are gonna look at
some of the modules that come with Python but
will finish this video by saying how the
help function can be useful to work out how to use some of the
various modules
so let us just close this file off we only got shelve imported so what I'm gonna do is delete that and on
line 3 I'm gonna type....
if I run that you can see that actually
gives us quite a bit of information
about , quite a detailed amount of
information about shelve how to use it
description of what it is the various
parameters interfaces and so on and also a link to the
documentation
so you can see here there is a link we can get and from
their we can click on that goes straight
to documentation in a browser so copy that
go back to the browser and press enter
generally following the link is better
because you get the object or output rather
you got this way of looking at the data or coming
back to a browser and seeing it in that format
to me I would prefer to use this format the
browser I think it's a lot easier to
read but it's personal preference and
you got the ability to choose either way
when you actually choosing a
documentation and we do suggest that you
do take some time in read this
documentation you don't need to know
or understand it word for word but it can
be a good way to help solidify your
understanding of how some of the
internals work within Python it is really really
handy and you can also request help on
individual functions so for
example we could change that to import
random and here we could type...
.....and we can get some help just on that again it is quite
short but it does give you the
information relating to the parameters and so forth for that particular function
so I'm gonna end this video here in the next one
we're going to continue our discussions
of modules and imports