ok so moving on with our blackjack
program now just before we continue their is a
few items of housekeeping that
I want to go through firstly when we actually run
the app I've mentioned before that it wasn't
sort of looking the best so if I have
look and run it you can see that there's a lot of
white space and obviously as we start
using it it gets better and the cards get
dealt
and its starting to take up some space so
probably the easiest thing to fix right
now is just a change this backgrounds so what
I'm going to do is change the background
so its green so that's number one
go ahead and do and where I would do that
would be just under the two lines that
set the window title and the geometry
now here I'm gonna type....
...and if we run that we've got a green window that's going to look
a little bit better once we've got some cards in there so that's number one that has made our application
look a bit nicer and bearing in mind that we haven't
got an text showing here but that will be becoming
but the other issue that I want to fix
is this code on line 8 its really in the
wrong position that's should really be the
last line of codes so I'm going to actually
move that down delete that line and
then put it down right below all the
other definitions I'm going to put it
down here and will be actually dealing
with talking about this a little bit
later we're going to talk about an idea of a main function to put the code
that's not directly in functions but we will
be doing that a little bit later and lastly
on line 35 you may recall that I
talked in the previous video about making sure
when we're actually grabbing cards the
that we don't pop the cards of the end of the list
and that's what I did so next_car = deck.pop on line 35 is doing just that
so we don't want to grab a card from the
bottom of the deck
we want to grab a card from the top of
the deck obviously so that's a mistake on
my behalf that should actually be a 0 their 0 meabs to pop it basically to grab the
card that's sitting from the top of the
deck that's obviously the card that we
actually want to grab ok so now that we've
done that we've finish off that bit of
housekeeping the next thing we really
need to do is calculate the players
score and displayed in the frame that
is in that little bit at the top of the screen
that I pointed before now I want to
demonstrate the other reason why IntelliJ
gives warnings about local variables
shadowing those from the main program
of course we talked about shadowing in
previous videos and so the first attempt
at running this function isn't going to
be the final one so although I'll be
replacing this first line of code the
technique used is sometimes necessary so
it's really important to understand it
and the reason for these warnings so in
terms of the players scored the
sensible place to calculate the total is
just after each card has been dealt so what
I'm gonna do is modify the deal_player
function this is one
starting on the on line 46
so the face value of a card can be
obtained from the tuple returned by the
deal_card function so that
can be used to update the players total
now the code also has to deal with the
two values that an ace can represent so
in blackjack that's not actually too
difficult luckily because no matter
how many aces a player has only one of
them at most can have the value 11
of course a player will be bust because the
maximum score is 21 so the technique
used here is to give the first ace the value 11 and add any subsequent ones the value of 1 now if
the player goes bust by holding at least
one ace ten is subtracted from the
total and a check for being bust is
perform again so that way it will actually
give the player the option to treat an ace
as one instead of 11 so in order to do
all this we actually really need two
more variables one to store the players
total and another two to tract whether
or not the player holds an ace that has
the value 11 so let's go ahead and add
those so come down here first
just after the player_score_label I'm
gonna add a line of code they're and I'm going to put...
and also gonna set another variable.....
...now I'm not sure if I've used this term before but
variables that are defined in the main
part of the program rather than in a
function are called global variables and
variables that only exist inside a function
are called local variables and I know we
talked about that before so in this case
where I've actually added these two
global variables on line 72 and
73 by putting them here outside of the
function we're making them global
variables so ok now that I've actually got those 2
variables set up we can go back to our deal_player function and start
using it so I'm gonna start typing some code in so deal_player I'm gonna start by putting....
.....
...we are actually obtaining the result from the
deal card function and need to do a bit of
checking here so....
....
...so by default and ace has got a value 1
and what we're saying here is if an ace
was drawn from the card from the deck and the player hasn't
already got an ace in their hand then we are
going to assign 11 to this particular
card so next we are gonna put...
......
...and we need to make a change here this deal card we need to also
make sure that we can return the face
value of the cards so we need to specify
position 0 element 0 so basically we
are determining if its the right value and then
were actually assigning the score so player score += card_value and will do a test here will
put..... because we are gonna treat the
ace as one if the total score is over 21
so put....
....
......
...so the only information
we get we can get on the outcome of the
game is if the player goes bust and that's
because the deal were not get any more
cards until the players finished their go so
we can set the result to the dealer
winning if the player goes bust but any
other outcomes will have to wait until a
dealer is getting cards now before going any
further I'm going to run the program and you can
see that sort of behaves but there is a
subtle bugs ok so just have a look at this running
now so if I click on player notice that the
score is being updated but if I click it
again and noticed it's only storing the last value
so its not actually calculating the total and reasons
for that its going to be probably be pretty obvious if
we actually closet this and have a look that's
because on line 47 we used a local
variable and overrode
the global variable and set it to a value of
0 so consequently the player_score is only going to ever
be the total of the last card that was
actually drawn now just before we go
ahead and actually removed that and fix that error if we
just have a look at the error shadow name
players score from out of scope the shadowing of
player score is one of them the other is
that why don't we get the same warning about
player ace because both variables
are defined in the main program but
IntelliJ is really only warning about
one of them in the deal player
functions so why is that the case so lets
actually do a bit of a mini challenge for you
is looking at this method is
there a difference in the way that
player_score and player_ace
are used in this function and that might
lead to why IntelliJ is only warning about
player_score so stop the video now
and see if you can figure out the difference between
player_score and also player_ace
and also how they are used in this process
and if you think you got it come back and we'll continue
on
ok so hopefully managed to figure it out
and the answer is that the value of
player_ace is used in the comparisons
on line 49 and 53 its being used but the
difference between that and the player_score variables is that the
function doesn't attempt to assign a new
value to player_ace but player_score
is assigning new values so its first
set on line 47 to 0 and then the card value is added
to it also on line 51 and then of course
ten is subtracted from it if an ace is held on
line 54 and its because of this difference
in the way that they used that Python
treats the variables differently inside each function so IntelliJ is just
reporting here it's Python is that actually
making the rules so we can confirm that
there is a difference by using command
click so I click on player_score and if we click it to
see player_ace goes back to our definition
on line 83 that's control-click if
you're on PC or Linux machine and go
back to our function again so player_score
on the other hand If I clicked that
somewhere other than the definition its
staying in the method itself so try again their but player_ace if I click that that
goes down to where it was define on line 83 so that's just a quick way to determine
local or global variable putting that function back again so when you use the
name of a global variable in a function
Python assumes that you want to use the
global variable and will happily let you until you try to change its value
that's the key point there so soon as
you assign a new value to a global
variable within a function Python then
creates a local variable with the same
name and your cpde no longer refers to
the global variable so once you
understand behavior it actually does
make sense and it actually saves you
from introducing hard to spot bugs but
it can be an unexpected behavior until you
do understand that and we can see that
in action in our deal_player
function their now so at the moment we've used the
variable name player_score
and assigned new values to it
as a result Python's created a new
local variable called player_score
and IntelliJ's complaining
by giving us a warning that its shadows
the global variable so it is important
to pay attention to those warnings as
they are the only clue that we really not
in fact changing the global variable
player_score also inside the
deal_player function we use
the variable name player_ace but we haven't
assigned in new values to it so as a
result Python let's us refer to the global
variable and consequently there's no
warning bells from IntelliJ about
shadowing because we in fact not doing that
because we are not saving values and essentially not creating a
local variable so I'm gonna end this video here
now in the next video will continue our
discussion about this and then move on
and get this deal_player
function working correctly in calculating
the score for the entire hand the players
got rather than just last card so I'll see you in the next
video