At the end of the last video, we'd got our
nospam program to
print out the items in each meal.
Each one was printed out on a separate line, though,
which may not be what you want.
That's easy to fix - the print function has
some extra arguments that we can use.
Let's see what the documentation has to say.
I'm going to go to the built-in functions page, for Python
Now we've seen this table of built-in functions
before, and it's something you'll want to
come back to often.
We're interested in print at the moment, so
click print to see what else it can do.
That takes us to the function signature for
the print function.
The first parameter explains that print will
print objects to the file text stream.
That strange default for file - sys.stdout
- just means the console.
So that's where our output's been appearing.
stdout is short for Standard Output.
Each of the objects that we provide will be
printed, separated by whatever character we
provide for the sep keyword argument.
Remembering that the default for sep is a space.
After all the objects have been printed, end
is printed.
end defaults to a newline, and you've seen
that we got a new line, after each call to
print in our code, previously.
Alright, in the next video we'll swing back to IntelliJ, back to our code, and see some of this in action.
See you in the next video.