To see some more of the things we can do
with print, what I'll do is create a
new Python file called moreprint.py.
The first thing we're going to do, is
print several things out at once.
We'll start by typing name equals
double quotes Tim, line two, age equals 10,
then on line four I'm going to type
print parentheses, and then within the
parentheses, name comma age comma Python in
double quotes and then 2020.
So we've got two variables, and on line
four we pass both of them, with a string
literal and an int, to print. And when I
run this program now, you can see we get
each object printed out. The function
definition had a single parameter, called
*objects. Now the asterisk is
often said as star, so we'd actually say
star objects. That means that we can
provide several values, and that's what
we've done here, on line four. Now I wouldn't
normally use this, when displaying output
to a user of the program. That's because
you don't have all the formatting
options that replacement fields provide.
For printing diagnostic information,
it is a very quick way to print out the
values of several variables. But the main
reason I've done it here, is to show you
that a function can take several values,
when that argument is star something, and in
this case, it was star objects.
The sep parameter is a keyword argument we
talked about in the previous video. If we
want to provide a value for sep, we have
to specify its name. Now that's why
they're also called named arguments. So
let's have a go at doing that.
So I'm going to duplicate line four and
on line 5 now, I'm going to type a comma
after the 2020, and put sep equals, and
in double quotes I'm
going to put a comma and a space. Its usual not to
put spaces either side of the equal sign,
when passing a keyword argument by the way.
Okay, so we've set sep to a comma,
followed by space. Let's run the program
to see the diffearence. Now as you can see,
in the second line of output, each value
is separated from the next one with a
comma and a space. This can be useful when
writing data to a text file, and we'll be
seeing that in a later section.
The separator's only used when you print
several things at once, as we've done here.
If you only print a single value -
and that includes an f-string or a
string produced using .format(), then
the separator won't be printed. The other
keyword argument that we saw in the
documentation, was end. Now end is very
useful in loops, so to see this I'm going
to go back to our challenge code,
in  nospam.py. So I'll run this first,
and as you can see, each of the items is
printed on a new line. Now, it would
be tidier to have the items for each
meal appearing on one line. Now we can do
that by changing the value of end. So to
do that I'm going to make a change to
line 22, and before the right parenthesis
I'm going to type comma end equals, and
in double quotes, I'm just going to put a space.
Setting end to a space, tells print
to print a space after printing, instead
of a newline. Let's run the program now,
to see what effect that's had to the output.
You can see, we've now got the items
on a single line. Now the print on line
23 is needed, otherwise all the meals
would be on the same line. So I'm going
to comment line 23 out, and rerun it, just
to confirm what happens. You can see the
items are now all on one line which
is, obviously, not what we want. So I'll
undo that and run it again.
Alright. Now we can't use sep here,
because we've only passed one object to
print - you can see that on line 22.
Remember that the separator's only used
between the values we print, when we pass
more than one value to the print
function. However, we can still get a
comma between the meal items, by putting
a comma in the string that we used for
end, so let's do that. end is now a
comma followed by a space, as you can see there.
Let's run the program to make sure
the output is what we expect.
That's not bad, but did you expect that extra comma
at the end of each line? It's not
actually easy to remove that, with this
code. In fact, the most pythonic way to
get that output without a trailing comma,
is to use a generator expression.
So what I'm going to do is take a copy
of this file - nospam.py. We're going to call
this one, nospam_gen, so we
don't mess up our original code.
So we can replace the loop on the lines 19 to
23, with this generator code that I'm
about to paste in. Alright so there's the
code. Let's run this,
and this time we get the items without
the trailing comma on the ends of the
lines. So that's pretty cool, and as you
can see, that's only three lines of code.
Alright, so I'm not going to discuss that
code on line 20, yet. What I will do in
the next few lectures, is talk about
some more methods that strings have.
We'll also see what join on line 20, is doing.
See you in the next video.