In an earlier video on if statements,
we created a very simple guessing game.
The player had to guess a number
between 1 and 10. We want to open up
that guessinggame.py file and work
on that in this video. Now what I'm
going to do is delete the commented out
code at the end, because we no longer
need that. Alright so there's our code at
the moment. Now as it stands there's a
number of problems with this game.
One problem is that it only allows two
guesses. If we wanted to allow more than
two guesses, we'd have to nest more and
more if tests every time the player
guessed incorrectly. The other problem is
that five is always the correct number,
which makes the game a bit boring,
and not that it was terribly engaging to
begin with. Now the first problem can be
solved using a while loop, which is what
you'll be doing in the challenge coming
up next. Before we do that, though, let's
digress slightly and address the second
problem, so that we can produce a more
interesting game. To fix the problem of
the correct number always being five, we
need to get the computer to generate a
random number in the chosen range - that's
one to ten in the example - but we can
extend that. Python has a lot of features
built in such as the ability to do
arithmetic, lists, ranges and tuples and
more. There's enough built in, in fact, for
us to be able to write a random number
generator if we wanted to do that.
The good news is though, however, one has been
written for us and comes included
with Python in a module called random.
We'll be looking at creating modules and
packages much later in the course, but
for now what we're going to do is use
the one, the random generator, that comes
with Python. Because it's in an external
module, we need to import it into our
program to use it, using an import
statement. When you want to use objects
from the Python standard library you
import them, usually at the start of your
program. Importing a module allows you to
use all the objects from that module in
your own code. So we want to use the rand
int function from the random module, so
we can start by importing random. We're
going to do that right up on line one, by
typing import random. Now that we've
imported the module we can use its rand
int function on line three. So let's
change the five, the literal value
five to random dot randint parentheses
1 comma 10. I've used random.randint
on line 3 because the randint function
is in the random module. We imported
random on line 1 at the start of the
program and we can now use the functions
it contains by using what's called dot
notation. We separate the module name
from the function name with a period or
dot, which is why it's called dot
notation. We're using dot notation to
tell Python that the randint function
is found in the random module.
The randint function produces a random
number within the range we specify.
We've passed the values 1 to 10 to the
function, which means we'll get a random
number from 1 to 10 inclusive. So we've
used the value 10 in two places in our code.
If we wanted to increase the range
of numbers that the player has to guess,
we'd have to make a change in both of
these places. That's a good way to
introduce bugs in your code, so if we
changed the value on line 3 but forgot to
change the message on line 5, the program
wouldn't behave as the player would
expect it to. We can make the code more
robust by using a variable to store the
upper value, so let's have a go at doing
that. So on line 3 I'm going to type
highest is equal to 10.
Then on line four I'm going to change the
literal value 10 to highest, like so, and
then what we're going to do is change
our message here, delete 10 and put
left and right curly braces instead,
and after the double quote put .format and
in parentheses, highest. Now we can increase
the range if we wanted to by making a
single change on line three and a change
would be reflected in both places.
Alright so let's run the program and see
if we can guess the number. So I'm going
to guess five the first time, and if
that's too low I'm going to guess eight,
otherwise I'm going to guess three,
unless five happens to be correct of
course. So let's try five and I got it first
time, amazing! It is actually quite hard
to test this program properly, unless
we're really lucky. We can't test that it
prints the right message when we guess
correctly, but of course I got it correctly
the first time, so let's try running it again.
I'll try five again, Please get higher.
This time I'm going to guess 8, as I
mentioned I would do, and it was too low,
and well done I guessed it. Well I'm having
an amazing amount of lucky here because this
is entirely random.
We'll try one more time.
We'll try five again and that's just,
again, amazing. Three times out of three.
Please guess higher. We'll try eight
again. This time finally, we've got it wrong.
Sorry you have not guessed
correctly and I'll try one more time just to
see if we can get the opposite to happen,
five again, Please guess lower this time.
I'm going to try three, Well done, you
guessed it. Again I'm having an amazing run
of luck here. One more time - I can't believe
I've got this right so many times but we'll try
one more time, Please guess higher.
I'll try eight and we'll leave it at
that. So we didn't get to see us not
guessing it correctly by guessing a lower
one, but that's fine.
That really alludes to the fact that it
is quite hard to test the program
properly, because even if it does print
the message we can't tell if it should
because we've got no idea of what the
correct answer is. So to get around that
while testing, what we can do is print
the value of answer out. So for testing
purposes, it just makes it easier for us
to know rather than just guessing, so
what I'm going to do is add the code
on line five. I'm going to do print answer,
and that's gonna be the answer
from the, so that's basically the number
that's been randomly generated. I'm also
going to put a comment here, hash TODO
remove after testing. Obviously you wouldn't
want to leave this in, in a real
game, because of course what would happen
would be the player would know the
number to guess each time. Now you might be
wondering what happened with that TODO.
Two things; firstly, it changed to blue
when I typed TODO, but secondly, IntelliJ
treats comments that start with TODO in
a special way. It highlights them in blue
with my color scheme and also keeps
track of them. Down at the bottom of the screen
we've got a TODO tab. I'm gonna come
down here and click on that. If we open that
up we can see that it'll give us a list
of all the TODOs, in this case, just in
the one file we've got, and it actually
tells us there that on line five, we've
got print answer and it shows us the
TODO that I've actually entered. So you
can basically expand the sections and
double click on a particular entry to go
straight to that line in your code, so
for example, if I was down there, double
click it, my cursor moves back up the
line five - very useful if you happen to
be in another file at the time. So in
general, TODOs are a great way to keep
track of things so that you don't forget
about changes you intended to make. Note
that this is a feature of IntelliJ, the
IDE. It's not a Python feature. Python
just treats that comment like any other.
Alright, so at this point now, the program
should be easy to test, even though I had
a good run of luck last time. I'll just
close down the TODO tab. Let's run it again,
and what I can do is check what happens
if I get the correct result first time,
and on my second guess. So the first time,
we know that the value is one there.
So we enter 1, we got it first time so
we know that that's working. We'll
try it again,
this time I'll enter a number that I
know is too high,
8, Please guess lower. Well I could
guess 5, guessing the number correctly
on the second time, Well done you've guessed
it. And obviously, now that you know the
number, you could go through all the different
scenarios of testing, to make sure you
fully test all program flow conditions.
So at this point, you'll probably find
the program a bit frustrating. With ten
numbers to choose from we'd probably
need a minimum of four guesses, to be
sure of getting the number if you didn't
know the answer in advance, and that
sounds like a good challenge to try.
So the challenge is to modify the
program to use a while loop, to allow the
player to keep guessing. The program
should let the player know whether to
guess higher or lower, and should print a
message when the guess is correct.
Now it already does that, but I suggest
you don't worry about printing a
different message, if they get the
correct answer on their first guess.
We'll look at counting the number of
guesses later. A correct guess will
terminate the program. Now as an
optional extra, allow the player to quit
by entering 0 for their guess. So these
challenges are intended to give you a
chance to practice what you've learned.
Don't think of them as tests. There's no
pass or fail as such. If you have a go but
don't manage to solve the entire
challenge, or even part of it, that's fine.
Generally, most people, even if they don't
successfully complete it, will learn
something from the experience, so it's
well worth giving it a go. The bottom
line is, you'll learn a lot more by
trying before you watch my solution
coming up in the next video, than you
would if I just presented you with the
working code. So have a go and see how
you go with it, and we'll go over that
solution together in the next video.