All right, so as I mentioned
towards the end of the last video,
there's a slight problem with this code
and I'm gonna get you to look at a challenge
of fixing that shortly,
but before we do that, let's see what the actual problem is.
So what happens if the calling code specifies
a key word argument that our function is already using?
So in our code, we need to suppress the end of line
character when we call the built in print function.
So we're parsing, as you can see here,
the end equals on line four with the little space there
and I'm going to actually show you,
I'm gonna change the calling code on line seven
to put to also specify the end argument,
which would be something that ordinarily
would be a perfectly valid thing to do.
So if I change that and put end=
single quotes, a new line character.
So if we actually run this now.
So what's happening here is you can see
there's an error is that kwargs contains the end argument.
You can see that I'm calling that there.
You can see that's showing in the printout of kwargs
that we're doing on line two in the console output.
But then we're also providing a value for it
here on line four.
You can't actually specify the same key word twice,
and that's the problem.
The specific error, got multiple valleys
for key word argument end.
And consequently we're getting a crash for that.
Alright, so there's two ways to deal with this
and I'm gonna show both in your solution to the challenge.
Okay, but onto your challenge.
You need to look at and fix the print_backwards function
so that it correctly handles the case when the calling code
also specifies the end keyword argument.
And just as a tip here, you may want to remove
the file=backwards from the call to print_backwards,
just so you don't have to keep opening the file
to check the results.
Instead, getting the output on the screen.
So that's your challenge, see how you go with it.
Pause the video and I'll see you when you get back.
Okay, so how did you get on?
Hopefully you managed to solve that.
And as I mentioned, there's actually two solutions to this,
or two ways to deal with it, and I'm gonna show you both.
Both of the solutions rely on making sure
that we don't parse the end key word argument in kwargs.
One approach is to actually include end
in our parameter list.
If we come up here and after the *args
and before the **kwargs,
we can actually put end= and then our space
in single quotes and then a comma and a space
and then our **kwargs.
Just like with *args, **kwargs will actually scoop up
any remaining key word arguments
that we don't specify in our function definition.
So that's the reason that I'm putting the end=
a bit prior to that.
Now, there is a slight difference though.
*args deals with positional arguments.
If they don't have names,
so they just appear in order in the function call.
But **kwargs uses the parameter names,
so it doesn't care what order we specify them in
when calling the function.
It just scoops up any that our function hasn't declared
and puts them into kwargs.
So before running the programme,
I'm gonna remove the file=backwards argument
just so we can see the results on screen.
So we'll try running that now.
Alright, so that's the first option.
That works fine, as you can see there.
There's now no errors showing.
The other approach though is to remove any
end key word argument from the kwargs dictionary
before parsing it on to the built in print function.
I'm gonna leave that first statement definition
commented out for reference.
So I'll take a copy of that, paste it.
And I'll comment out the first one.
So I'm gonna change this,
and we're gonna come down here to,
after we do the print of kwargs,
we're going to do kwr, so kwargs, dot pop,
single quotes, end, comma, space, none with a capital N.
So kwargs is just a dictionary,
so we're free to manipulate its contents
just like any other dictionary.
I've used the dictionary pop method here.
Now, if we click on pop and have a look at that,
you can see that it removes
the specified key from the dictionary.
And we're providing the default value of none
to prevent an error if end isn't already in the dictionary.
Now, we could use other methods for removing the key,
such as the del command,
but just remember that the end argument may not exist,
so your code has to check it before removing it
or catch the key error exception.
Alright, so we'll go back and check this code.
And run.
We can see that it too is also working just fine.
Alright, so if you use one of those approaches
to solving the challenge, then well done.
And if you found another approach that also works,
please let us know.
That'd be very interesting.
Alright, so that challenge was intended to show you
how you can manipulate kwargs,
either by providing the key word in your own definition
or explicitly removing it from the dictionary.
Now, our print_backwards function at the moment
doesn't really behave like the built in print function.
We've got working code, but it doesn't behave
in the way that the calling code would expect.
So to see what I mean there,
let's press another string immediately
after the print_backwards call.
We'll just do a print, another string.
And if we actually run that,
you can see we've got another string
sort of showing on the same line,
right at the end of our backward string
instead of on a new line.
We're effectively using the end argument as a separator.
Because we're using multiple calls to the built in
print function inside our loop,
we have to use end to prevent each word
appearing on a new line.
Now if we specify sep when calling
our print_backwards function, it actually won't do anything.
So let's compare our code to the built in one,
when a separator's used in the function call.
I'm gonna add this code outside the file loop
and print a blank line first to separate the output.
So let's have a go at doing that down here.
So we're gonna do print to move to a new line
before we start and then print,
and I might take a copy of this again,
just to save us typing it.
We're gonna leave the end in there like so,
but then we're also gonna introduce the sep,
so sep= and we're going to use a pipe character,
and then we're going to come up here
and do an equivalent thing,
but I'm going to just call the print function.
So print in this case, exactly the same as the call
on the line below to print_backwards,
but we're just calling the print function instead.
And let's just try running it now.
So you can see in the version, the print version,
we've got the pipe character working quite nicely.
It's between each word, but on our version,
the version that's calling the print_backwards function,
the separator, the pipe character, isn't working.
We've still got the space only working.
So the point I wanna make here is that
kwargs is very useful, but you also have to be careful
that you don't subvert the meaning of the arguments
that you're parsing on.
Now we could fix this by joining the reverse
words up into a string and using a single call
to built in print function.
In fact, that's probably the way I'd recommend it.
The code would end up being a lot cleaner
and more obvious with what's going on.
But this video is about using args and kwargs,
so I'm going to manipulate the key word arguments instead.
You may find yourself having to do this
when subclassing another class,
so it's also useful to see how to do it.
But what we're going to do is use any sep argument
that the calling code provides instead of hard coding end
to be a space, which it's currently doing on line six.
So you can see it's hard coding the end there.
And once we've done that, we'll add a final print call
using whatever end value has been provided.
Now I'm gonna copy the print_backwards function
and comment out the original so the code is still available
in the resources section of this video.
So let me do that.
Copy that and then we'll comment that out
and then come down here and we'll paste it in again
and then we'll make the changes to that.
And two lines there to keep the editor happy.
Alright, so firstly, what we're going to do
is delete these two lines here,
the print kwargs and the kwargs.pop
and then we wanna add something.
After here, we're going to then add end_character
is equal to kwargs.pop end, then the slash N,
single quotes, and then set_character
is equal to kwargs.pop, and that's sep,
and then a space in single quotes.
And then we're gonna come down to our call to print here.
We're gonna change end= and single quote and space
that was in there, we're gonna change
that instead to sep_character.
They're still needing **kwargs on the end of that,
and then on the line after that
we're going to do a print.
That's going to be after the (mumbling) is finished,
so print, end= end_character.
Alright, so let's just try running that.
You can see now it's actually looking a lot better.
It's now behaving almost the same as
the built in print function.
And it also works if we suppress the end of line character.
Let's have a go at doing that just to see if it works.
So first thing we're going to do here in this first print
is we're going to change the end=
and we're gonna remove the new line
so it's just two single quotes.
And we're also gonna do that on the regular or the,
call to our method as well,
so both the print and the call to our method.
And actually what we'll do is we'll also change
the separator this time to a /n for new line, **/n
and we'll do the same for the function call
to print_backwards, so separator= /n **/n.
And then just to make it clear,
we'll add a bit of text to separate it, so print= times 10.
Right, so we're on that.
So now the first word of our backward string starts
on the same line as the last word on the print function.
I've got the equals printout showing as the,
well, after rather, the last backwards word.
Looking at that, this is the code here
that I'm talking about or the output.
So the first word of our backwards string
starts on the same line as the last word
from the print function.
That's the point really there.
But then the line of equals
does appear after our last backwards word,
so print is correctly honouring the end of line characters
but our print character, our print_backwards function
doesn't cope when the end of line
is suppressed, in this case.
So as you can see, if you change the meaning
of a key word argument, things can get a bit tricky.
Now I probably wouldn't code this function
using repeated calls to print.
It's easier to join the backwards words
using the join method that we've used before,
then just call print once to print out the final string.
But I can't leave you with an always working function
so I'm gonna fix this one before ending the video.
What we need to do though is handle
the last word that we print a bit differently,
so in fact it goes to a new line.
The last word should be printed using
the specified end argument rather than a separator.
Now that's actually easier to do in Python.
We just alter the range so that it reads the word backwards
but stops before it prints the last one,
which in this case is the first one
because we're going backwards.
Then we print the first word in args separately
using the end value that the calling code specified.
So let's have a look and see how to do that.
Back to our definition here.
The first that we've gotta do is change this
full word in args.
At the moment we've got ::-1.
What we're gonna do, as I mentioned there,
about changing the range, so we're gonna change
that to, I'd be :0:-1.
And then we're going to leave this coding as is on line 13.
And then we're gonna come down here to the end here,
print, and we're going to actually change that,
so that we're gonna do a print.
We'll actually comment that out, (mumbling)
what it was before we're making this change.
We're gonna do a print, args, zero,
in square brackets, then another left square bracket, ::-1
and then right square bracket, comma, end=
and it's end_character then **kwargs.
What we're doing here is effectively, we're uh,
then print the first word separately.
And by the way, as a result of that, that means...
I'm gonna take a bit of a comment here,
make it clear what we're doing,
and here what we were doing on course was change the range.
So those comments are meant to be read altogether.
So I've changed the range,
and print the first word separately
which means we don't need this line,
so that's why I've commented that out.
Alright, so let's try running that.
And the other thing I should have done previously
was also remove this so I'm going to do that now.
We'll run this again.
That's actually what I was trying to do,
because obviously we changed our functionality
so we weren't using end anymore and I've removed that now
and this is what was actually meant to happen.
You can now see the equals sign is peering on the same line
as our hollow going backwards (mumbling).
So I used zero as the stock value in the code on line 12,
as you can see here.
Remember that the slides will extend up to
but not including the stock value
so therefore the first word isn't included.
I'm gonna leave you to rerun the previous tests
to confirm that our function now behaves
the same as the built in print
with different values for end and sep.
So we can create new functions that are called
in exactly the same way as an existing function
but then change the way that the original function works.
And we do this by retrieving the arguments
using args, or using *args, I should say, and **kwargs
to provide a version of the function of different behaviour.
We can do the same thing with classes to create a subclass
that adds additional functionality to the bass class
and we'll be doing that actually in the next video.
I used the print function here
because it's a visual function,
so it's easier to see what's going on.
The aim was to show you how to use and manipulate
the kwargs dictionary and how it's important
to retain the expected behaviour of the original function.
Now I've said a few times that if the aim
was to create a version of print that prints backwards,
then I wouldn't be doing it this way.
I'm gonna finish the video by showing you
the code I would write if the aim had been
just to print backwards.
Let me go ahead now and add that
just to show you how that would work.
And it would be def backwards_print *args comma and **kwargs
sep_character equals kwargs.pop sep
and then the space in single quotes,
then we'll do print, sep_character.join word
and in square brackets, ::-1 for word in args
and then left square bracket, ::-1
then a right square bracket, a right parenthesis,
comma, **kwargs and then a final right parenthesis.
Now backwards_print, as you can see here,
joins the reversed words using the join method.
So this would be the way that I would normally do it
and it actually uses something called a list comprehension
which we haven't looked at yet
but we'll be looking at those later in the course.
So again, if the aim was to create a version of print
that prints backwards, I wouldn't have done it
the way that I've shown you earlier in the video.
We've done it that way just to really explore
what kwargs is and args and how to use them.
Anyway, I'll leave it there
and we'll see you in the next video.