Let's have a look at some examples,
to understand how tuples work. So I'm
going to go back to tuples_intro.py from the last video,
and we're going to delete the old code.
Alright, so I pasted the code in there to
save some time. Pause the video, then come
back when you've caught up with the
typing. Alright, so run the program,
which I'll do now. We should see the
Metallica tuple printed out, and you
can see that on the screen down there.
So it's a tuple containing three items;
We've got an album, Ride the Lightning,
the artist, Metallica, and the year that
it was released, 1984. Tuples are a
sequence type, which means we could use
indexing, to access the individual items in
the tuple. Let's have a go doing that. So
below line 7, I'm going to type print
metallica, then in square brackets, 0. I'm
going to do the same for the next two lines.
I'm going to change the index
number to one and two; 1, 2, like so.
So the item in index position zero is the
album name, and let's actually run this, so we
can actually see all of them. So again,
the item at index position zero is the
album name. We can see that printed on
the second line of the output.
Next we have the artist on the third line
then the year on the last line of the output.
Indexing a tuple works the same
as indexing a string or a list.
You provide the index position in square
brackets. Now that's caused some
confusion in the past. Even though tuples
are created using parentheses, you still
use square brackets to index them, and
you can see that, if I close down the run
window now, on lines 8 through 10. When
you're indexing something, use square
brackets. That's the same whether the
thing you're indexing is a list, a string or a tuple.
Unlike a list, a tuple is immutable.
If you attempt to change an item in a
tuple, you'll get an error.
So let's actually check that. On line 12
I'm going to type metallica square
brackets 0, is equal to Master of Puppets.
Now before I run the program, notice that my IDE's
highlighted that line.
If we hover over it, you'll see a message
that says here, something similar along
the lines of Tuples don't support item
assignment. Now not all IDE's will do this,
but most modern ones will. Now when we run
the program, you can see that we've got
an error there; Tuple object does not
support item assignment.
Python provides ways to create sequences of a different type.
You may have checked out the
list and tuple functions, at the built-in
functions table in the documentation, so
let's have a look at that.
So we can see the two functions list and tuple there.
I'll just move this up the screen a little bit so we can see it.
Now the documentation may be confusing
because these aren't really functions.
They're really Python's equivalent
of a class constructor. Don't worry about that
because it will make sense in the
Object-Oriented Programming section of
this course. For now, though, you can
pretend that they are functions. The
documentation has included them
in a table of built-in functions, so that's not
unreasonable to pretend that they are.
So the list function returns a list, using
the values in the iterable that's passed
to it. So let's go back to our code, and
what I'm going to do is delete that line
that gave us the error. Instead what
we're going to do, is type metallica2
is equal to list metallica. We're going to print metallica2.
The list function returns a list using the
values in the iterable that's passed to it.
As I mentioned, if we run the program,
you can see that we've now got a list
containing the same items as our
tuple. The last line of the output is the
same as the first, except it uses square
brackets, which indicates a list.
Because we've got a list, we can now
change the title of the album.
So let's have a go at doing that. So metallica2
then left square bracket 0 equals,
in double quotes, Master of Puppets. Then
we'll print Metallica 2 again.
So we'll run this, and there shouldn't really be any surprises there.
We've covered changing values in
lists earlier. So looking at the last line
of the output, we've got an album called
Master of Puppets by Metallica,
released in 1984. So when might a tuple be more appropriate?
At this point, I'd like to
thank one of the students on this course,
Toni Peralta, for pointing out that the data
is now incorrect. The Master of Puppets
album was released in 1986, not 1984.
The original video did mention that tuples
help protect the integrity of your data,
but didn't link back to this example, so
thanks for that Toni.
You'll see some other examples of tuples
being used, when we read data from a
database in section 13. It's important
that the data in memory, matches the data
in the database, and using an immutable
tuple can guard against unintended changes.
We'll look at another reason, for
favoring a tuple, in the next video.