Alright, so we're on the way
to create a scrollable list box
that can populate itself from our database.
Now, we got the scrollable bit working in the previous video
so the next step now is to look at getting
the data into the lists.
Now, we're gonna be creating another subclass soon
but first though, let's see what we have to do
to populate the list boxes
and allow clicking on an item in one list
to cause another list to update.
Now, the artist list is the simplest
because that doesn't really update
when something else is clicked,
so we just execute a query
and then insert the query result into the list box.
So, to do that let's go to the artist list box
and the configuration code here,
below that artist list dot config line
and on there we're gonna type in four,
artist in, conn dot execute
and the SQL query in double quotes will be
select, space, artists dot name,
from artists, order by,
artists dot name,
colon and then we're gonna do
artist list dot insert
and it's gonna be TK inter dot END
in upper case, comma, space,
then artist zero in left square brackets
and right parentheses.
So, let's actually try that.
We'll try running this to see what happens.
And we can see that very nicely.
Let's move this out of the way
so that we can see the code.
We got the artists showing in the first list box,
in the artist list box on the screen.
So, that's pretty cool
and obviously, I'm scrolling through that
and that's working quite nicely.
So, the next step that is to respond
to one of these artists being clicked.
At the moment that we can click it but nothing's happening.
So, let's close that down.
So, what do we need to do to get that to work?
Well, we've seen how to cause a function
to be executed when a button's clicked
way back in the black jack game in section 11.
Now, list boxes actually don't have
an explicit command property,
but they do have a number of events
that we can bind functions to.
Now, the one that we want is here is a virtual event
called list box select,
which the list box receives when an item's selected.
And the good news is that we can bind our own function
or method to that virtual event,
so our function's called when the even happens.
So, let's have a look at adding that.
So, we're gonna add that below the SQL code
and that's gonna be artist list
dot bind
then parentheses, single quote,
and I want two less than signs,
then list box selects
and then we have two greater thans signs
and then a single quote,
comma, space,
get_albums,
then right parentheses.
And obviously, we're getting an error there
because we need to write that.
But what we're actually doing here
is that whenever an item's selected in the artist list,
we going to get our get_albums method to be called.
So, for that reason we better go ahead
and actually write that method.
Now, I'm gonna add it after the class definition,
leaving the usual two lines before it.
So, let's go up and do that.
So, we're actually gonna add it right up here.
Okay, on line 26
and we're gonna start with def, space, get_albums
and event in parentheses, colon,
and then we're gonna do lb equals event dot widget,
index equals lb dot cur selection,
parentheses and then in square brackets, zero.
Then we want artist_name is equal to lb dot
get index,
then a comma.
And now what we need to do is,
so we wanna get the artist ID from the database row,
So, we do artist_ID is equal to
conn dot execute
and double quotes within parentheses
is gonna be select artists dot _ID
from artists where,
and I'm not mentioning the spaces,
but you'll know by now with SQL that we need to have spaces
at the appropriate places there,
where artists dot name equals question mark.
So, we're using a placeholder there.
Comma after the double quote,
artist_name,
right parentheses
dot fetch one.
On the next line we're gonna type
list equals and two square brackets,
then four, row in, conn dot execute,
then the SQL we wanna write for this one
in double quotes is gonna be
select albums dot name
from albums
where albums dot artist
equals placeholder
or question mark and you wanna order by
the albums dot name.
Albums dot name.
Then double quote, comma, space,
then artist_ID,
then colon, then a list dot append.
In parentheses we wanna do row and square brackets and zero.
And finally, after that has finished,
we gonna type album LV dot set
and in parentheses, tuple, a list.
Alright, so when a bound function's called,
it gets passed as single argument,
this event here that you can see we've defined on line 26.
So, we can use that to then retrieve a reference
to the widget that triggered the effect.
We're doing that you can see here on line 27.
Now, a list box has got a cur selection method
that returns a tuple,
containing the positions
of all the selector items in the list
and we're calling that on line 28.
Now, you've probably used list boxes
in your operating system's GUI
and know that you can use the control key
or command on a Mac to select several items in the list.
Now, we're actually only going to be allowing
a single item to be selected
and we're gonna be coming back to that
when we produce our class.
But that's where we're only allowing
a single item to be selected,
we'd actually just hard coding that fact
for this value in square brackets here with zero
from the return tuple.
Now, once we know the position of the selected item,
we can then use the get method
to get that from the list box's list.
So, at that point we know the artist name
that was selected
but unfortunately, the TK list box
doesn't provide any way to associate an ID
with the strings that it displays.
So consequently, we have to query the database
to retrieve the artist ID
and you can see that we're doing that here on line 32.
Now, we're using a local database,
so that's not really a problem here.
But if we were retrieving data
perhaps from a remote database,
then you might wanna reduce the number of network calls
that you may have to make to fetch data.
In that case, we could add a list to our subclass list box.
We'd then store the database IDs in the list
in the same position as the names in the list box.
Now, that's not particularly difficult
but you do have to be careful to keep the list in sync
if rows can be inserted into and deleted from the database.
So, a better option though in that case,
might be to use the new TTK tree view widget
and that'll let you store the IDs in a column
alongside the names.
But in this case, we're using a local database,
so we just gonna run a query as you can see here on line 32,
to return the ID for the specified artist,
and it's obviously in the artist_ID variable.
And now I've done something slightly sneaky
when assigning the artist name to the artist_name variable.
So, we're gonna use artist_name as a parameter
to the query and we have to pass a tuple
rather than a single value.
I'm talking about this code here on line 29.
So, artist_name is actually a tuple
and we don't have to worry about using it
when executing the query.
The fetch one method that we're using on line 32
on the cursor that comes back from conn dot execute,
well, that returns a tuple,
so the variable artist_ID will already be suitable
for passing on to the next query.
So, once we've got the artist ID,
we then use that to query the album's table.
You can see that code on line 34
and from there, we're getting a list of the albums.
Now, the remaining code after that
should hopefully, be pretty straight forward for you.
We're just appending the names to a list here on line 35
and remember that the list box wants a tuple
in the list variable,
so we convert a list from a list to a tuple
here on line 36,
before setting it as the value for album LV.
Alright, so at this point, with the code we've got,
this should hopefully work,
so let's actually run it and see what happens.
Alright, so there's our list of artists.
So, we can click a couple there,
like 1,000 Maniacs
and you can see Albums got updated here.
B.B. King, Black Crows.
Let's try one that's got a lot.
I think Blue Oyster Cult.
You can see that's got multiple albums there,
so that's worked quite nicely.
Bruce Springsteen
and you got a single one.
We can try another one from Aerosmith.
I know he's got quite a few.
So, that's working nicely as well.
Alright, but what I'm gonna do is finish the video here.
In the next video we're gonna continue on
and we're going to get the songs working as well.
So, we're gonna be able to click on an album
and retrieve a list of songs.
So, I'll see you in the next video.