Alright so we had a warning at the end
of the last video and I just wanted to
check whether you could pick that up. You can
see there, it really gave it away when
I hovered over it: Name guesses can be not
defined, and of course if you look at the
code, guess equals 1 should have been
guesses equals 1. And of course when I
do that, it disappears. Alright so
there's that. Alright, so we've written
the code to get the computer to guess
a number we think of. Let's now see if
it works. So we're gonna run the code, and
we're thinking of a number between 1 and
1000. The number I'm gonna be thinking of
is 837, so I'm gonna press ENTER to start.
The computers guess is 500. Now should it guess
higher or lower, enter h or l or c if my
guess was correct. Now what I'm gonna do
there firstly, just add a space there,
then what we're gonna do is just re-run
this. I'm gonna stop it and run it again, because
that's going to annoy me very quickly.
Press ENTER there. Alright so that's
better. 837 was the number we're guessing.
We can see here, the computer's guessed 500.
Should I guess, the computer's asking,
should I guess higher or lower.
Well obviously, it needs to be higher so I'm
going to enter h there. This time the
computer's guessed 750. It's still too low
because their number's 857, h again in
that case. Computers guess is 875. It
needs to guess lower so we need an l there.
Computers guess is 812 now, or 812
is obviously too low because their
number's 837. So I need to tell it to guess
higher. 843, getting closer now to 837,
so it's actually too high. So we need to go
lower. Next guess, you can see there is
827, which needs to be higher, so I'm
gonna press h there for higher. 835 now -
it's getting close but still a bit too low.
We tell it to go higher again. My guess is 839.
l for low because it's still too high -
our number's 837.
This time you can see he's guessed it,
837. So I'm gonna type c there,
then it's correct,
and after all that time I've been
wondering, well why have we got to guess
in 837 guesses. What have we done wrong
there? Well the simple thing is that
we've actually printed out
the wrong message. If we go down and
have a look, we're printing out guess
which is the last guess, and not guesses.
So I'm going to fix that, and we'll run
it again and this time I'm going to run it
in fast motion, just so we go through it
quickly to confirm that it works then.
Okay, so you can see the computer's now
guessed 837 again, c if we're correct.
This time we've got it in nine guesses, so we've got the
correct output now that I've fixed those
two bugs. Now it can take less than that,
depending on the number you thought of,
but it won't ever need any more than ten
guesses. So try with a few more numbers to
make sure the program seems to work okay.
So this is actually quite a hard program
to test. A simple typing error could
result in the program never guessing
correctly, and we may not detect that
unless we chose a number that causes a
problem. Now before I would be
completely happy with this code,
I'd probably test it for all possible numbers
- so I'd think of each number from 1
to 1,000 in turn. So the next 35 hours of
video would be me pressing h and l,
over and over again. Of course not - that's
not a very good use of our time,
especially when we have computers to
perform repetitive tasks for us.
So later in the course, we'll get the
computer to test this code for us. But we
need to understand about functions first,
so we'll leave it till later. Now one thing
you might want to do, is run the program
in the debugger. I won't do that, but go
ahead and do that if you want - it's a
great way to learn. The reason I'm not
going to do it here is because there's
only two values that we're interested
in, when stepping through the code. The
loop already pauses each time around,
because it waits for our input. Printing
out the values of low and high is much
easier than using the debugger, in this
case. So I'm going to do that at the
start of the loop. So just, I'm going to
close the run pane and go back to
the start of the loop, under the while
statement there. Line nine, what  I'm going to
do is print parenthesis double quotes
backslash t, which is a tab character,
Guessing in the range of, left and right
curly braces, to, and left and right curly
braces again, double quotes dot format,
and in parentheses low comma high,
then we've got our two right parentheses
there. So I've included a tab character,
that's that backslash t at the start of
the output. Indenting the output makes
it easier to pick out the computers guesses,
from the diagnostic information that
we're printing. So let's run the program
again now, and this time we're going to
be using 987 as the number to guess. So I'm gonna
press ENTER to start there.
Alright, so you can see the range is
there, guessing in the range of 1 to 1000.
1987 is higher, so I'm going to press h
there, and you can see it's now guessing in the range of
501 to 1000. The next guess is 750. 1987
is higher, so the next guess, higher again. 875,
well it still needs to be higher. 938, and
number's 987, so it still needs to be
higher. 969, higher. 985 - we're getting
much closer now, but higher. At this point
now, the computer's guessed 993. That's
higher than 987 so we go lower.
The next guess you can see is 989 and we're
guessing in the range of 986 to 992.
So scan through the output at this
stage. I'm just going to scroll up a little bit,
and you can see all the hi-low ranges
and see how they've changed each time. So
we need to go lower now because our
number is 987, so I'm going to type l
there for lower, and you can see that
the next guess is now the correct value.
So printing out information such as the
low and high values can be a great way
to help understand what code's doing.
It's often quicker than using the debugger,
and something you might want to try
first, but with that said of course, the
debugger is always available if you want
to check things more closely. Alright, so I'm
going to enter c there to say that the computer
was correct, and you got it in nine guesses, as
you can see there. I'm just going to fix
this run pane and then close it, and
we'll end the video here.
In the next video I want to talk about something
called an Augmented assignment. Now this
may be a suggestion that you see on line
27. I'm on Windows and it doesn't pop up
for me, but you might be, if you're on a
Mac or on a Linux machine, you might be
seeing a suggestion that the assignment
can be replaced with an Augmented
assignment. And the suggestions do vary
and it may or may not appear. The bottom
line is we're going to talk about that,
and find out what that's all about
in the next video.