Alright, so continuing on with our project.
We're almost done at this point,
but what if our data listBox isn't linked to another one?
So we're going to need some way
of linking two listBoxes together
and this on_select method you can see here on line 59.
Well, that should only try to requery
another listBox if there actually is one.
Now in a minute, what we're going to do
is add another couple of fields to the class
to handle the link.
We're gonna finish off this method first, though.
We're gonna get it to check
that there is a link to this box
before trying to requery one, so let's do that.
We're going to put if self.
so that's linked, and it's called box:
we're gonna add that field shortly as I said,
and then we're going to indent everything else.
I'm gonna remove this extra commented out code now,
which we no longer need.
I'm also going to indent this code.
And I'll just put another tab or space in there
because IntelliJ was complaining
that the hash was too close to the code,
you need to put at least two spaces
when you're actually adding a comment.
So I've got rid of that warning.
The other thing we're going to do here
is change this albumList.requery,
let's change that self.linked_box is what it should be.
So that's self.linked_box.requery link id,
so we haven't got the aristList hard coded anymore.
So before we can see the new class working
we need to add a way to link
one data listBox to another.
Now, not all listBoxes will be linked.
Our songs list doesn't cause another box to be updated
and we may want to use a single data listBox
to display a database table
without linking it to anything else.
So rather than insisting that another data listBox
is provided in the class init method,
we're going to add a link method
that can be used if required.
Now we're going to use the link method
by passing it a widget that we wanna link to
and a database column that forms that link,
and that means we're going to need
another couple of data attributes in our class.
Let's go back up to the top and add those data attributes,
and we're going to put them just after
the super call here in line 30.
So first one, self. and it's going to be linked_box,
we set that to none initially,
and likewise for self.link_field
we're going to set that to none,
so that's our two attributes.
And again, we're defaulting to none
so that there's no link to start with.
Now, if we need to link two listBoxes
then we're going to call that link method,
so let's add that method,
and I'm gonna add that just after the clear method here,
so it's gonna be def link,
we've got self as an argument,
, widget , link_field:
and we're gonna put self.linked_box = widget
and then we're gonna do widget.link_field
gonna set that to link_field,
so we're basically saving the value
that was passed in the argument.
So at this point whenever we want
to link two listBoxes together,
we can call this new link method of the master listBox,
then we're passing in a reference
to the data listBox that we wanna link to
as well as the name of the column
in the linked data listBoxes table.
I'm gonna go through what this method's doing again
once we've seen it working
and can refer to the actual widgets.
So that's fixed some of the warnings,
if we have a look at our own query method,
that's looking a lot better now,
we fixed some of those warnings,
but we've still got one more error to fix,
so we come over here and have a look
in our right margin and click on that,
and you can see I've got a problem on line 115,
and you can see with the code there
that that's where we downed the listBox select event
to the get_albums function.
Now we've moved that function
into the class and renamed it,
which is why we're now, of course, getting that error.
Now there's no reason why we have to perform
the bind in the main programme.
Our data listBox class knows
that it's got a nonselect method,
so we can bind to the method itself.
So I'm gonna cut that line of code out,
and I'm going to paste it to the data listBox init method,
so I'm gonna go right up to the top,
the init method up here,
and I'm going to paste it after our data attributes
before the sql select statement,
paste it in there like that.
Now we're no longer binding to the get_albums function
so we have to change that in our on_select method,
and we also wanna use self, though,
instead of referring to the artistList widget,
so I'm gonna change that to
remove the artistList call there, that should be self.bind.
The listBox select is still correct,
but instead of the get_albums function
it's going to be self, or method I should say,
it's going to be self.on_select,
and be careful when you're making that change
because you can see here that IntelliJ tried to be helpful
and added the parenthesis after the on_select.
We actually don't want that, we wanna remove that,
and again, the reason we're moving it is
that if we left it with the parenthesis
then that would result in binding
to the result of calling the method
and our method returns none in this case,
which, by the way, is the default
for all functions and methods
if you don't explicitly return anything,
and we wanna bind to the method,
not to the value that calling it returns,
so watch out for that.
I'm saying, I know we've talked about that in the past,
but it's a very easy mistake to make,
especially with IntelliJ's, you know,
quote unquote helpfulness here.
Alright, so I fixed that,
now I'm going to delete one of those lines
to keep IntelliJ happy.
Okay, so once our main code's created the albumList
we can actually link it to the artistList,
so let's go ahead and do that.
We're gonna go down here
and the moment we've got this albumList.bind
to get_songs, so I'm actually gonna comment that out.
What we're going to do instead
is do an artistList.link
and it's going to be to albumList,
and then the field artist.
Moving down we can do the same
to link the songList to the albumList,
so let's go ahead and do that.
Then we'll do, this case albumList.link
and that's going to be to songList in this case
and then album, that's the column name, or the field.
Alright, so let's run the programme.
It should allow the album and songLists to be updated
when items are selected in the list that they're linked to,
so we'll actually run that and see.
Go ahead and have a look at the code,
and we can select, should be able to select an artist,
we can see that's updating okay,
and if I come over and click on an album
we actually get a crash,
so it's almost working.
So selecting the artists you saw worked fine
and the correct albums are displayed,
but soon as I actually selected an album
we actually had a crash.
And if you come down here and look at the error,
and I'll just close that down for now,
and the error's saying here
that there's no such column artists.
Well the songs table doesn't actually have
an artists column, so we shouldn't be referring
to the artists column in the songs table,
so obviously at this point something's not right.
So if you click on this link to here in the error trace,
that actually takes us to the line where the problem is.
Well, that's actually the line
that's actually executing the sql,
but if you look above on line 56
that's actually where the problem is.
So I've still got the artists column hard coded
as you can see here, into the sql where clause,
and what we should be doing is using the link field,
the one that was set when we call the link method,
so let's go ahead and change that.
So I'm going to delete the artist in the double quotes
and we're going to replace that with self.link_field
so we get the right column for the right table.
But that raises another question, now,
and that question is, what happens
if we don't have a link field,
because the listBox hasn't been linked to another one?
Well in that cause, calling requery
should populate the list with all the rows
so we wanna execute the code
in the else block in that scenario.
So we can fix this by adding a test for the link_field
as well as the link_value.
So if we go ahead and do that,
so I've got if link_value here on line 55,
if we do or add the words "and" and self.link_field
we're now only gonna execute that
if there is a link that has been established
between the two listBoxes.
Otherwise the else code is gonna be executed,
and reflectively going to get the entire contents
of the table added to the listBox
and that's actually what we want in this scenario.
Alright, so we're going to also make a change down here
after the call to self.clear,
then we're actually through and adding the code there
so you can see that adds the entries to the listBox.
What we need to do also is down here
put in some code if self.linked_box
then we wanna do self.linked_box.clear.
Now the reason we're doing that,
that's to clear out the data in any linked data listBox
so that way when we select a new artist
the songs for the previous album aren't still displayed,
and that's the reason, by the way,
that we added a clear method in the first place
rather than just deleting the list items earlier.
So we need a method on the linked listBox
to tell it to delete its contents.
Alright, so let's actually try running this again,
and hopefully things will actually work properly now.
Alright, so if I select an artist,
okay, so we've got an error there,
let's just have a look.
Can't convert DataListBox object to string implicitly,
okay just click on that,
and I've made a typo here,
I've actually typed in self.linked_box,
but it actually should be link_field,
because the field is ultimately gonna be
the column name for the database
that we're trying to add,
so that's just a typo, so I'll fix that.
Link_field, that should fix that up,
so let's just try running that again.
Let's see how we go this time.
Alright so, we'll try running it again,
this time we haven't got an error there, that's good,
so we've got artists showing,
albums you saw was updating automatically,
so each time we're clicking we're getting
the list of albums, so that's good,
and multiple albums are being shown.
Now if we click on an album
we're correctly getting the list of songs,
and that's updating as well.
So that's good, everything's now working great,
and you can see that as I was selecting items
in any one odd data listBox,
the corresponding data is displayed
in the linked data listBox,
and I think at this point that's pretty impressive.
So we've taken the basic tkinter listbox
and now created our own scrollable version of it,
and with that extended that further
to produce a data listBox that can
load its own data from a database table
as well as triggering loading in another data listBox.
So the code in the main programme becomes a lot cleaner
and easier to instal as a result of this,
but with that said we've still got a bit
of tidying up to do there in the code
before I end this video,
and I'm just gonna close this down.
Now to start with, we don't need
this get_songs function anymore
'cause that's now all handled by our data listBox class,
and we also don't need to connect to the database
right at the start of the programme.
Now, we did that originally because our functions
were using the global database connexion,
but now that we're passing the connexion
to our data listBox objects
that code can come down to the main programme.
We should also add a condition
so that the main code isn't executed
when the module's imported by another programme,
and that'll then let other programmes
use our scroll box and data listBox classes.
Let's go ahead and do that,
so I'm actually going to delete the get_songs function
because that's existed in quite a few
other versions of the video prior to this,
or videos prior to this, so we don't need to preserve that,
and clean up some of this.
Let's also add that code there
to make sure that the main code
isn't executed when the module's imported.
So if __name__ is equal to '__main__' :
and from there we want to indent the code
but we gotta start by moving this connexion,
I'll comment that out and we'll delete this,
clear up some spaces there,
then I'm gonna come down and put that code in here,
and then we're going to indent this other code,
then go right down to the bottom
and indent all of that, like so.
Now we also were loading data
into the albums and songLists when the programme starts,
and if you recall we did that when testing earlier
but we can now go ahead and delete those lines now.
So in terms of that code you've got
this requery here, firstly for albums,
so let's, I'll just comment that out.
You could just as easily delete that if you prefer.
We've also got another one in the songs,
the songlist.requery, which we no longer need
to have that code there anymore.
But of course we do wanna leave
the original artists in there,
so that all the artists are initially loaded,
so that's good, that's now fixed.
And down here for the main loop
we can also get rid of the testList
and the albumLV.set tuple,
you don't actually want that to be populated either,
so let's actually get rid of that as well,
comment that out.
Which really only leaves the code for the main loop
in printing, the fact that we're closing
the database connexion and then the connection.close,
so let's just run this to make sure that it still works.
So I've now only got the artists populated initially.
We can click on a particular artist.
By the way, we can click on songs as well,
and because that's not associated with any other listBox
we're not getting any errors,
and that's working as well as we think it should be working,
and we're still getting our other selects working correctly
and the various data listBoxes being updated on the screen.
So that's actually it, that's our data ListBox finished.
I think you'd agree that the main program's now
a lot tidier than what it was,
and we haven't got any code copied and pasted,
more to the point.
We've also now got two completely reusable classes
that we can import into other projects
whenever we need a scrolling listBox
or one that can display data from a database table.
Now, there is a bug in the data listBox class, though.
Let's see if you can figure out
and try and spot what that is.
In the next video I'm gonna show you what the bug is
and then set you a challenge to fix that bug,
so I will see you in the next video.