Alright, so how did you get on? Did you spot
the places in escapechar.py
where the code doesn't conform to the style
guide? Well, the three problems are with
the names of our variables. Now, if we go and
scroll up and look on line one up here,
I used camel case for the name split
String.That's the convention in Java, for
example, but we should avoid doing that
in Python.
It's called camel case, by the way,
because the large capital letters
resemble the humps of a camel. Camel case
reflects the shape of the word, when you
include capitals in it.
Alright so that's the first one.
The next is tabbedString on line 4, and the
third one is anotherString down
on line 14. Now those three variables
appear on six lines of the code; lines 1
&amp; 2, again on lines 4 &amp; 5, and lines 14
and 19. Now it wouldn't be too hard to
change them in this short program, but in
a larger program they could be appearing
all over the place.
If you forgot to change one of them, or
made a typing error, you'd cause an error
in the code. And that's not good, and it's why
you shouldn't refactor code just to
conform to a style guide. But I'm gonna
break that rule here, because I want to
show you how your IDE can make that a
lot easier and safer. What we're going to
do is refactor the code, to make it
comply with PEP 8. Refactoring code means
changing its structure, without changing
its behavior.
Refactoring might change how the code
does things, but it doesn't change what it does.
Alright, so in IntelliJ and PyCharm, I
can right click on splitString and I'm
going to do that on line one. So from the
context menu that appears, I'm going to
choose Refactor, then Rename. As you can
see, that popped up a dialog where we can
change the name of the variable. I'm
gonna change it to conform to the
guidelines; split_string,
instead of a capital S like we had.
Click on the Refactor button, and all
occurrences of splitString are renamed.
We can see, in this case, it's been changed on
lines 1 &amp; 2. I'm going to do the same for
tabbedString on line 4. That should be
tabbed_string.
Then we're gonna do the same again for
anotherString, right click, Refactor,
Rename, and that, of course, should be
another_split_string
I say, of course, but you get
the jist there. Okay, so there's the 3
things changed, and you can see that both
lines 14 and line 19 are changed there.
Now most modern IDEs have a feature that
allows you to rename things in your code,
and that's much safer than doing it
manually. As I said, if you miss one or
make a typing error, you'll break
the code. Make sure you test your code
after refactoring it. Run the program to
make sure it still works.
Alright so the code in this course
will follow the PEP 8 guidelines, most of
the time. I'm re-recording the videos
for this course, and some of the earlier
examples were written a long time ago.
You might find that some of them don't
follow PEP 8.
You'll also find code in the Python
libraries, and elsewhere, that doesn't
follow those guidelines either. The code
that you write should follow the
guidelines, and I'll refer you back to
them, as we cover various new Python
features. Now there's one more thing that
I want to cover, and we'll look at that
in the next video.