Alright, so let's talk about nested data structures in more detail.
We've had a think about how we're going
to represent the songs in our list of albums.
Now at the moment, we've defined
albums as a list on line 1 of this file -
tuples_intro.py.
Inside the list, we've got five tuples.
I'm going to take this slow,
because nested data structures is
something that new programmers often
find confusing, but they're really quite
straightforward, once you get the hang of
them. But at first, they can seem very
complicated. So let's start by adding
some songs to each of the tuples in the
list. So we're going to create a new Python
file here, called nested_data.
So we recommend that you type in all the
code in this course. Typing the code
really helps you get used to the syntax,
and if you make errors, then fixing them
is great practice. But typing data's
just boring, so what I'm gonna do here is
paste in the data. You can get what I've
pasted it, in in the resources section for
this video. So copy the contents to your
clipboard and paste them in.
Alright, so that's what I've pasted in. You can
see that we've got a list here,
containing four tuples, just as we had
before. Each tuple now contains four
items. So we've got the album title,
artist and year - you see an example of
that on line two - and that's just like
it was before, but now we've also got
a list in each tuple. You can see the
first list, starting on line three,
extending down to line nine. Now, we can
use a for loop to print out the items in
each tuple, and it's going to be very
similar to our previous for loop.
We'll just add an extra variable for the
songs. So let's go down to the bottom of the
source code and add that. So I'm going to
type for name comma artist comma year
comma songs in albums : I'm just going
to print them out, so print
parentheses, and in double quotes Album : left and
right curly brace comma, and we're
going to do the same for the other three.
So we've got Artist :
left and right curly braces comma Year :
left and right curly braces comma
and finally Songs : left and right
curly braces closing double quote.
On the next line I'm going to type
dot format, and in parentheses name comma
artists comma year comma songs.
Let's run the program and then check the
output carefully there. Now the first
three items in each album are simple
variables, the title artist and year. The
fourth item is a list, and we can see
that there on screen, if I scroll over
a little bit, we can see the various
songs there. Now that's at index position
3, and we get the list of songs for any
album by indexing into an album's lists.
Now as I said I'm going to take this
slowly. We can do things a lot more
concisely than I'm about to do, but it's
easier to understand if I break it down
first. So I'm going to start by getting a
reference to the budgie album - that's
this third album starting on line 23. So
in the code I'm going to actually type
we'll separate the outputs so I'm just going to do
a print in parentheses on line 45, on line
47 I'm going to type album equals albums and square
brackets and two within the square
brackets then we'll print album on the
next line. Run this, and we can see the
entry there for Budgie's Night Flight
album. Now we can also index into the
album tuple, to get the songs. The list
of songs is at index position 3. Then
come down here and type songs equals
album 3 in square brackets print
songs in parentheses. Now run this
and you can see we've now got just the
list of songs there, on screen. Now we're
not done yet. We can get any particular
song by indexing into the list of songs.
So let's have a go at doing that. Down
here on line 53 I'm going to type song
equals songs and one in square brackets
print, in parentheses song. Run this
and we can see that song is a tuple.
It's track number two, and the item is
Keeping a Rendezvous. Now if we just want
the title, we can index into the tuple
to get the item at position one. Let's
have a go at doing that. So I'm going to
type print in parentheses song and one
in square bracket, or brackets rather,
and then I'm going to do that and run it.
And you can see we get the song title
Keeping a Rendezvous in the output.
There's nothing very complicated about
this, it's just indexing. If the item we
get is another list or tuple, we can
index into that. If that's also a list or
a tuple then we can index again.
Experiment with different albums and
songs, and use the correct index numbers
to refer to them in the albums list.
Now as an example, looking at this code
again, change the indices so that the
last line of output is Mayhem, from the
Imelda May album. In the next video
we'll see how we can do this more
concisely. See you in the next video