Now that I've installed the IDE and the
python plug in if you
installed IntelliJ IDEA rather than
PyCharm we need to make sure that it can
find Python. Now the steps are almost the
same for IntelliJ IDE as they are for
PyCharm and the chances are that it's
sorted itself out but just in case it
hasn't I'm going to go through the steps
to configure the Python SDK, so from
IntelliJ IDEA first if you're using that
come down and click on configure and
select project defaults and select a
project structure on the left hand side
here you want to click on SDKs this is
where we set up the Python SDK then in
pycharm, I'm just going to start that up,
the process is a little bit different
it's a lot different
basically come down here to configure,
let me select settings over here on the
left hand side we choose project
interpreter and we click on this little
cog to the right of the project
interpreter field and then we click on
add and that keeps us this screen here
where we can add the Python interpreter
if we go back to IntelliJ we can do the
similar we'll get to the same screen in
IntelliJ by clicking on the plus and
because we're in IntelliJ we've got a
choice of multiple languages I'm going
to select a Python SDK so that's
basically now the same screen that we
saw in Pycharm, now you see that its
popped up here is talking about a
virtual environment virtually env
I'm not going to discuss these virtual
environments just yet we're gonna be
looking at them later in the course what
they are though is briefly a way of
keeping your Python environment separate
so that things you can store for one
project don't affect other projects you
may be working on. So we will be looking
at those from the command line, so I
won't be discussing these specific
IntelliJ or pycharm options because
obviously this is a Python course and
not an IntelliJ or pycharm course but
once you've explained about virtually
env, these are these virtual
environments these options will make
more sense, for now though making sure
you've got the virtual env environment
search option selected in the left pane
the new environment set up selected and
again you'll do this for both IntelliJ
and for PyCharm, you're gonna click on
both these boxes inherit global site
packages and make available to all
projects, now the location here should be
your home directory and if you only have
a plan to use one version of Python and
you can leave that location unchanged
otherwise, you want to add a slash
forward slash Python in the version that
you're actually installing, now in my
case you can see the base interpreters
3.5 but you may have 3.6 or
even 3.7 or if you're
running an older version of Ubuntu is
3.4, any of those will be
fine and will work just fine with this
course, I've selected Python 3.5 to match
my base interpreter and in late 2018
Linux distros will probably start using
Python 3.7 so don't be too perturbed
with the number slightly different long
as long as it's version 3 points
something you'd probably be good you'll
be good to go and three point four would
probably be the worst would be the
lowest version that would be acceptable
here, that's also fine and if for some
reason there's no base interpreter
selected you come everybody click on the
ellipsis button and you can navigate or
browse to the folder to where path is in
store to your particular Linux
installation but in my case everything
is good to go here and what I'm
going to do is click on ok, again you'll
get a similar thing with PyCharm if you
do this you can see that it's loaded up
and once you've done that, you close it
off by clicking on ok, at that point
you've got an installation set up and
ready to go. Now I want to show you a
worrying error message that came up on
Ubuntu 18.04 so if you get
something like this showing up it looks
horrible but don't worry if you see this
dialog because it is ok and you can
recover from that, now I didn't get
that error but what I can do is put my
installation that I've just completed
into the same state and I can do that by
going back in into intelliJ configure
project defaults project structure and
what I can do is again simulate that
error by clicking on the installation in
my case part of python 3.5 and clicking
on the minus button to remove it,
so effectively if you did get that error
and only if you got that error this is how you
know actually overcome that, so you click
on plus again and do a similar thing for
pycharm, click on Python SDK which you
wouldn't need to do that for pycharm
because it selects it automatically,
the difference though is this time again if
you have recovered from this error you
click on an existing environment you
click on make available for all projects,
you click on the ellipses and you'd
never get to the folder that was that
was where the virtual environment was
set up and if you recall it was home
parallels in my case there's a folder
called vemv, go into the Python
3.5 which was the folder that I called
it and into the bin folder the subfolder
again and you need to select your
various of python, in my case it was
Python 3.5, he'd select whichever version
was appropriate and then click on ok
then we click on ok again and that would
fix and recover you from that actual
error and again you had only fourth
perform those steps of deleting and re
adding if you got that error if you
didn't get the error which I didn't get
that first time, then now you wouldn't
have to do that well let's swing over
now to pycharm and see what that looks
like with the installation completed so
looking at Pycharm you have something
probably similar to this you'll have a
project interpreter now selected and you
click on ok and you see that it updates
the part will be updating the Python
interpreter the first time you do that
give it a moment to complete let me go
back into it again just have a look
configuring settings and you'd have
something like that once it's all fully
configured and working properly.
Alright I'm just going to okay that so
this point now we go back to IntelliJ
and click on ok to that we've now got
the installation complete there's one
other thing that I want you to check
just to make sure that so we've got show
line numbers enabled in the setup now
this this step is the same for both IDEs
like you can't configure choose settings
we want to come down here expand editor
and expand general they're going to
click on appearance we just want to make
sure here that the show line numbers
option is checked
if it isn't make sure you do check it click
ok and that's because it's very handy to
see the line numbers in your code
especially when you get errors and the
error message talks about say line six
for example but you can see the
installation automatically had that show
line numbers option enabled and I didn't
need to do anything but just check it if
it's not already enabled. Alright I'm
going to close that, at this point now
we've finished the configuration for
IntelliJ IDEA and for PyCharm and we're
ready to start programming. So in section 5,
we'll write our first program I'll see
you in next section.