So I continue on with that discussion
of dictionaries in Python,
that we've worked on in
the last two videos.
Again, just recapping what we
did in these last few lines.
We had fruit and it's called keys.
So we got a view object.
When we use the dot keys,
that's what we get.
We get a special type, sort of like
a list, but it's a view object.
We then printed that out so you can
see it on the screen Then we add it
a new item to the dictionary and when
we print it out that fruit case again,
even though we haven't directly updated
that variable, it was updated by Python.
So it happened behind the scenes.
You can see the tomato was
added in the second example.
That again is the only way that
view objects can be updated.
Sort of indirectly with the dictionary
that's happening behind the scenes.
So we can't add items, and
using delete we get an error here.
What we can do is we can
convert them to lists.
So we can convert them to lists, and
you saw us using the list method.
The list function I should say there list.
And we were quite able to
actually convert that to list and
then use the sort function to sort them.
But before we leave our fruit and move on
there's one more view we should look at
and that's the items method which returns
a dict_items object, which
is another dynamic view object that
consists of key and value tuples as well.
So to do that We'll get rid of this code.
Cut that out.
Let's close out the run window for now.
And we'll put the print in.
Print fruit.
We can do printfruit.items.
Oops, semicolon there, wrong language.
[LAUGH] Run that, and
you can see we've got a different output.
It looks very similar if you
recall our videos on tuples.
And as it turns out, we can produce
a tuple from it using our tuple function.
So we could do f_tuple equals tuple, they
give us a built in function, fruit.items,
and print f_tuple, like so.
We can run that, and I forgot to put some
brackets in there, cuz it's a method call.
Run that And on the last line now
you can see we have a regular tuple.
And of course, from that point
on we can then use tuple, or
in the case the variable tuple just
like we used tuples in any early videos.
For example,
we could do something like for snack N
quatupple item common description,
equals snack print item
plus is past description.
And we can run that, and
you can see we've got our items there.
What was the key from the dictionary, and
also the value from the dictionary
because we've created a topple.
We've then got them in our
description variables.
Now this wouldn't be Python if it
wasn't possible to go the other way.
In other words to create a dictionary
from topples of key values pairs, and
the dict constructor
allows us to do just that.
So I walk down here On this
line we could type print.
Then use the built-in dict function and
pass a tuple to it,
the tuple that we've created.
If you run that As you can see that there,
that's now just our regular dictionary,
probably not terribly exciting to you
because all we've really done is got
the original directory back
that we had that we created.
On line one.
But what it does do is demonstrate how
a dictionary can be created from a tuple
which is extremely useful.
There is a lot of interaction between
dictionaries, tuples and lists.
And later in the course we'll
summarize everything we've
done with these data structures.
And what we'll also do is include a list
of all the methods that apply to each one.
And now moving onto something
that's completely different,
I'll just close down that one window.
Now rather than try to cover
everything at once, and
have it all become terribly overwhelming,
what we've been doing is we've been
introducing methods and functions as
it becomes appropriate to use them.
So now's a good time to introduce another
of the string methods Which is joined.
By now you should be used to the idea
of mutable and immutable objects.
If you remember strings are immutable.
As a result this means that it's
not at all efficient to concatenate
strings in a loop.
Anytime you concatenate a string to an
existing string, the new string has to be
created and if that's done in a loop
it becomes expensive and slow.
So you really do want to avoid that.
The string join method is
there to actually help you.
It actually takes a sequence and
produces a string from it.
So the items in the new
string are separated by
the stream that join was called upon.
So as said a lot of these things are
probably easier to demonstrate rather then
for me to explain it any further.
So I'm gonna create a new file now
to leave the [INAUDIBLE] as it was.
New Python file.
And we'll just call this one join for
want of a better word.
So let's create a list first.
And myList = ["a","b","c","d"].
newString = "",
just an empty string for now.
And we're going to go through,
iterate through my list.
We'll see in my list newString += c + ",
" like so, and
then we'll print(newString).
So I consider this first example, and
I will just make sure I'm running
this right one, running join.
ABCD so
you can see has appeared on the screen.
So as I mentioned this is not
a good way of producing code.
So, a couple of problems here,
leaving aside the fact firstly there's
a comma on the end of our output.
It's also inefficient because every
time through the loop it's creating
a new copy of new string because again the
strings that we're using are immutable.
Now augmented assignment will help We did
say that talked about that earlier in this
course it does try to update
the variable in place where possible but
this is not one of those times where its
possible so in other words because strings
are unbeatable augmented a summit isn't
gonna help you so what you'd want
to do in this scenario is you want to use
join to fix this problem and the way we
would use that Instead of putting
plus equals we will delete that out.
We put newString = ", ".join(myList).
And we run that.
Notice we haven't got
the trailing comma now.
So is much more efficient.
It also solves the problem of
the trailing comme, as you can see there.
And it's really much more Pythonic in that
it's working in a way that Python would
intend to work for something like this.
So the way this particular method works
is it creates a new string by taking each
item in a sequence which is a list as
you can see that are created on line 1.
And separates the item with a string
comma that join is actually invoked on.
So we can use any sequence tied
by some parameter to join.
So for example instead of a list
we can pass another string.
So I'm just gonna place some code in here.
You see what I mean.
So let's change that to letters.
And instead of my list, make that letters.
Of course, you can see See the letters
there is now a string instead of a list.
If we run that then we get
the same output as you can see.
The same processing, I've since gone
from a to Zed because the input was
a string in this case
containing the letters a to z.
The other thing to remember is that the
string we called joined method on can be
quite complex as well.
If I for example,
come back here or close the again.
Numbers, let's try instead of
just putting a comma, we'll put
And then .join numbers.
Run that, you see one Mississippi,
two Mississippi, three Mississippi.
And so I probably to fix the Spacing,
then again you can say 1 Mississippi,
2 Mississippi, 3 Mississippi, and so on.
Again in case you're wondering why,
separating numbers with the word
Mississippi is a very rough way to count
seconds, if you don't
have a stopwatch handy.
And you could also use 2000
in place of Mississippi.
But anyway I'm getting off track there.
You might have guessed that we're about to
concatenate the keys of a dictionary to
give us a stream and you'd be right.
So let's get to doing that because of
course this is all about dictionaries.
What we're gonna do is we're going to use
dictionaries to store locations in a very
basic adventure game.
We'll also store the available exits in
another dictionary and we're gonna link
the two together so that players can
move from one location to another.
So I'm just gonna bring a little
image up on the screen now so
you can see what I'm talking about.
You can see there that there
is five locations a road,
a hill, a building,
a valley, and a forest.
The roads are not all straight and
you can see this.
That going north from the hill takes you
to the forest entering from the west.
So you can go west from the forest
to get back to the hill.
What we are going to do What we can do is
we can represent the map as a dictionary.
And although we could use the short
names of the location as the key,
what we're gonna do is use numbers instead
cuz that's easy to read initially.
And if you want to replace one
with rho etc., a simple search and
replace will do that once
everything's working.
So what I'm going to do now is just copy
and paste that code for that dictionary.
I'm just going to replace
the code we worked on here.
So I'm gonna paste it in there like so,
and you can see we've got the 5 locations
and the keys you can see for each
value in the dictionary is the number,
and then it's obviously the description,
which is the, and
the other one, the other part is
the value as well for the dictionary.
So you've got the key and the value for
each and the 5 locations on
the screen as you can see there.
Incidentally, I think that's a lot easier
to do when you're adding dictionary
entries like this, creating a dictionary,
it is better to separate them.
So I put a comma and separate them on
a separate them on a separate line.
It's just easier to read and sort of
avoids your dictionaries becoming a little
bit too messy as can happen if you've got
them all sort of linked up on a line.
You can see I did it in there
as well with the fruit.
So what we now need to do,
we've got our basic locations,
we need to represent the available
exits from each location.
Comparing to mine again is four plus one
exits, north, south, east, and west,
plus quit to exit the game.
So quit's going to available everywhere,
otherwise the available
exits will match the map.
So again, looking at the map again
What we;re trying to do now is
basically duplicating this set of
options which direction is valid.
A set, but
also enabling a quit to actually enable
you to quit the game at any point.
From the road for example,
we can go in all four directions, but
if we go east to the building.
The only exit from there is
gonna be ways back to road.
So one way we can represent
this would be a dictionary with
the directions being the key and
the values being the location that we
end up at if we go in that direction.
So from one,
remember in our key one is the road,
if you go west from there,
we'll end up at two, which is the hill.
And if you go east We get to three,
the building.
So when we get to a new location,
we should print out the description.
And that's gonna be easy to
do because each direction
gives us the key of the destination in the
locations directory, if that makes sense.
So what I'm gonna do is paste this in now.
Our next dictionary is going to be exits,
like so.
And you can see now that we're
using a key for the direction And
the value is of a key from the locations.
And again, the reason we're doing that
is so that we can ultimately print out
the location when we move,
where we've moved to in other words.
So again, bringing the image
back up on the screen again.
So if we start off on the road, we get
the available exits by looking at index 1.
So I'm just going to
just put that over there.
Again the exits is represented
as a list of dictionary objects.
This contains one dictionary for
each location.
Notice this is a list
of dictionary objects.
Important distinction to locations
which is just a dictionary.
And we're doing it this way ultimately
because we can index the list.
We know that element zero is
always going to be the same.
We know that element.
One's always going to be the same and
so on and so fourth unlike a dictionary.
And the method we come up here isn't
necessarily the best way to represent
the exists.
For example, we could use a dictionary
with the key being the location number and
the exists perhaps the List of tuples or
another dictionary.
But it's probably easy to start this way,
and sort of progress to that ladder.
So again, if we start off on the right,
we can get the available width just by
looking at index one in
the list to get the dictionary.
So again, we start here.
One, come over here to
element one on the list.
And, that's the valid entries,
or the valid directions and
also the quick to exit for
that particular location.
So, standing on the road, going west would
go to two, location two which is the hill.
East would go to three.
Which is a Building.
North will go to five
which is the Forest and
south would go t four which is a Valley.
And again, we have the Q coming
out to quit out which is going to
basically quit the game.
Similarly from the Hill, we get the
dictionary in position two on the list.
You can see position two has
been defined there on line 10.
The only way we can go from the hill,
we can go north to go to 5,
which of course is the forest.
There's no other exit, other than quit,
so we can't get back to the road from
the hill,
that's the way we've designed the game.
You can see that by the arrows telling
you whether it's multi-directional or
single directional.
So now that we've done that,
a simple loop should allow us
to allow the player to keep entering
directions until it's [INAUDIBLE].
And each time around the loop,
we'll display descriptions of the local in
the available exits,
just to make it look good.
So let's try that.
So I'm gonna type [INAUDIBLE]
equals one,
while true, and continue until,
basically till Our quitters are selected
available exits equals nothing for now.
For direction in exits location
we're starting off at location one.
Again we're starting off
starting on the road, number one,
that's why I like lock equals one.
So retrieving the dictionary from
our list as you can see there for
that particular direction,
we're getting the directions and
available booting up our list then,
available exits.
Plus equals direction.
Like so.
And then we're going to print locations
and loc is equal to zero.
Oops.
Don't need a bracket there.
Then I'm going to type direction
equals input available.
[INAUDIBLE]
plus available exits Or upper.
[NOISE]
Just going to do an empty print.
If direction in exits.
[NOISE]
Fixes in such a way,
and lock equals exists so in other
words if it's a valid location and
we're gonna sign that direction.
Else, print,
You cannot go in that direction.
The program's gonna keep looping until
the player goes to location zero.
At that point the programs gonna
break out as you can see there
on line 24 when the game ends.
So when a direction is chosen we check
that the k exists in the appropriate
dictionary from our list of exits.
And you can see we were doing that.
If direction in exits location or
lock, I should say the lock variable.
And then we use the key to retrieve the
next location if it does actually exist.
The exits lock and direction.
Again we are using that as
an index into the exits list
to retrieve the dictionary containing
the available exits of that location.
So when we get to equals one location,
one gives the description,
you are standing at the end of the rope,
you cross groups, small brick building and
we can actually run that.
So I can see [INAUDIBLE] standing
at the end of a rope before a small
brick building.
It shows us we can go east,
south, north, quit or west.
I can just type quit.
You're sitting at a computer,
learning [INAUDIBLE] I should say,
then it's exited the game as you can see.
If we run that again This time off
we go south we're gonna valley
just to confirm that it's
south toward valley, so
we shouldn't have to go back towards
north so we shouldn't have to go west.
At the top of a hill we go back
to west was the hill again and
we shouldn't now be able to go back to the
valley because the way the program's been
designed, we should only be able to go
to the forest now which would be north.
North and quit, north, you're at a forest.
But the forest and from there we should
be able to go back to the road or
back to the hill so
it should either be a south or west.
South or west as you can see there and
so on and so forth.
We can quit out of that.
So I'm gonna close that run window,
and again,
booting up the list in booting
up a list of compatible exits,
we're iterating through the keys
of the dictionary to do that.
But wait a minute,
didn't we just say earlier in this video
That can cannonading strings
in a loop wasn't a good idea.
Without the moment it's probably
not a problem because let's face it
there's a maximum five
keys in the dictionary.
When this game becomes the most popular
multiplayer game on the internet and
we've got thousands of people
playing it in real time, that
performance hit will become significant
and things will slow probably to a call.
So we can actually replace line 17
through 19 literally with one line.
Let's go and do that,
we'll put available x is equals dot join,
exits lock dot
keys which you can see is far more
efficient has less lines of code to type.
And are not going to be slowed down by
that problem we would have trying to
strings.
And we eventually have a huge, really
fast application and popular application.
And you can see it should still work.
We still get the same results.
Here we can go North.
The forest of [INAUDIBLE] he's sitting
in front of a computer so that's good.
Of course the other thing we managed
to do by doing that approach was we got
rid of the trailing comma,
which is good as well.
You might be wondering, we use direction,
why didn't we use the word exit.
Probably make more sense to say
the x at the exit variable there,
because that's really what it is.
We're trying to find the exit
to the current location.
The reason is x is the key within python,
quite a dramatic one as well.
Of course, [INAUDIBLE] quit immediately.
So that's why we use direction instead.
And incidentally this is a good
example of when you would check for
the existence of a key rather than
using get with the default value.
If we'd use get here, you remember we
talked about this in the previous video,
and wether we had a specific
default value, or
we just relied on it returning none.
Then what we have to do is we still have
to check through a ten valley before
we can use the key and
direction to retrieve the next location.
In this case, it makes far more sense to
just use the key using in before using it.
Remember the course that the players
could top anything, not just a letter for
the valuable exits.
Now, the only other comments to make are
that we're displaying the available exists
in an input statement.
And we used upper on the input string, so
that the player could type in upper or
lowercase.
This is the line here on line 24.upper.
There's a slight problem
with this program, though.
Not with the code, but
for us as programmers when we come to add
new locations, and we're using a list
to store the and relying on
the order of the items in the list.
Now that's fine as far as Python goes,
because lists are ordered, When we start
adding 50 or 60 locations and we don't
necessarily add them in numerical order,
we're gonna have to camp down the lines
of code to make sure new entries
are in the correct position
when we build the list.
Now, that will rapidly get tedious.
And as well as that's gonna be a really
excellent source of potential errors.
So it would be much better
if we use the location's key
Also access its exits dictionary.
Now there's another minor problem in
that some players might type west.
They'll put capital W and
a lower case E-S-T instead of just W.
In upper or lowercase.
Now that doesn't matter in this case.
But really what we should do is
allow them to top the full direction
as well as things like go west.
Now we could achieve this by
creating a dictionary containing all
the words players may use as keys with
the values perhaps being the word or
letter that we could understand.
Now that seems like a good idea for
a challenge, so
we're gonna do that challenge and
talk about a challenge to try and
solve that problem in the next video.
And just one other little thing
I type exists instead of exits.
I fixed that up.
And probably what we should do here
also is we should add a space like so.
And that's so when we run this,
there's a space there between
the end of the Available exits, and
where the user can actually start typing.
So anyway,
I'm gonna end this video here now.
In the next video we're gonna tackle
those issues I've talked about
in the form of a challenge.
So I hope to see you in that next video.