In this video we're gonna go ahead and
download and install IntelliJ IDEA which
is the editor or the integrated
development environment or IDE that
we're going to be using in this course
for our path and programs. Now there are
other IDEs available for python
programming and if you're happy with the
IDE that you're using that's fine,
there's no need to install another one
we had to pick one for this course but
you can take this course with any IDE
that supports Python. In this particular
video is for the Mac platform, if you're
running on Windows or you're running on
Linux, there are separate videos for both
those operating systems in this course,
so refer to those videos that's
appropriate but if you're on a Mac
you're in the right place,
so let's get started. So JetBrains makes
two IDEs that are suitable for python
programming that's IntelliJ IDEA and
pycharm, so let's go to JetBrains.com
jetbrains being the people who have
created these products and have a look
at their website,
don't forget they want to click on tools
and the two products here that will
actually work for this course are
IntelliJ IDEA as well as PyCharm. Now for
Python programming effectively they're
identical they're gonna look identical
I'm going to be using IntelliJ IDEA
and download and install that but if you
want to use PyCharm instead everything
will look almost exactly the same in the
videos. Pycharm got the advantage that
you don't have to install a python
plugin it's basically a version of
IntelliJ IDEA that only does Python the
idea of IntelliJ IDEA is that you can
install it for a whole range of
languages so if you plan to program in
other languages and that's an example
the Learn Programming Academy has got
to Java master class that uses IntelliJ
IDEA, in that situation IntelliJ IDEA may
be more suitable and for that reason we
suggested you actually go ahead and
install IntelliJ IDE but hover over
whichever one you want to see here and
then click on download. Now the IDEs
come in two flavors we've got the
professional Edition Pycharm we've
also got a Community Edition and an
IntelliJ IDEA has got an Ultimate
Edition in a community edition. Now
the ultimate or professional editions
they are the paid versions you can use
them as an honor trial basis for 30 days
but after that you have to purchase a
license to continue using them the
community editions on the other hand are
free for personal use now the community
editions have some features missing but
generally they're not things you need to
worry about while learning part them and
there's a feature metrics on the page
generally that you can actually have a
look and see what the differences are so
we go back to tools we go back to
IntelliJ IDEA and we can scroll down and
have a look here we can actually see
down the bottom this feature matrix
which gives us a bit of an overview of
the different versions and what's
included, so you can see that the
Community Edition hasn't got all the
features that the Ultimate Edition has
but again the things that are missing
out things that you generally need to
worry about while in python, if all of this doesn't
mean much at the moment, don't worry too
much about it just install a community
edition you can always change in more life
then, I'm going to select download under
the Community Edition download and
install that one that should start off
automatically in the moment and I'm just
going to save that and just while that's
downloading, I'm going to mention again
that you don't have to install this IDE
if you've already got one that
you're happy with and that supports
Python, you can quite happily use that
for this course and because I've created
courses for a number of languages I
picked an IDE that supports them all in
IntelliJ IDEA. Now I'm going to be
showing you ways that IntelliJ can help
you to find bugs in your code and some
other features that modern ideas usually
have to make programming easier and
other ideas have similar features and
once you know that something is possible
you can Google how to do the same thing
in any other ID that you've chosen or
happened to be using, the other thing I
want to mention is for the ultimate
edition of IntelliJ IDEA, I can also
extend the trial period if you wish so
if you're considering purchasing it and
you'd like more time to evaluate the
Ultimate Edition you can check out our
later lecture. Now I'll show you how to
get a special key that you need to paste
into the Ultimate Edition to get the
extra 90 days trial so gives you a total
of 120 days to try it out if you do want
to try those extra features or as I said
another alternative is just to use the
Community Edition and again that's the
one that I'm downloading here in this
video. Alright, so I'll just give it a
moment to finish now, it's just about
finished you can see it downloading in
the left hand corner and then we're
going to continue on and continue on
with the installation. Alright so you
can see there that's finished now, so I'm
just going to click it to start the dmg
file so you just want to double click it
depending where you've installed it to
to start up and the process like it is
for most Mac installations is
pretty straightforward we're just going
to drag that over into the Applications
folder give them a moment to copy C
copying in the top right hand corner there.
Okay, so that's finished the next thing
I'm going to do is just close it down
and I'm going to go and run IntelliJ I'm
gonna go to my applications
I'm gonna run IntelliJ IntelliJ ideas
see e which cities for Community Edition
and you get this a verification thing
popping up I give that a moment to verify
okay eventually we get to this point
here you click on open
so usually yeah once you've done that
you'll see this option pop up and it's
coming up telling us that we've got the
option to import some settings now this
would be useful if you're running
IntelliJ or you've installed a previous
version and you want to retain the
settings that you've configured
previously in this case it hasn't found
any other configurations because I
haven't turned toward IntelliJ on this
computer before so I'm going to leave
the default selected which is doing an
import settings and click ok
otherwise again if there was a location
that you did have the files or
installation you could select that
installation by using the ellipsis
button over here and import those
settings, but in my case I'm just going
to leave the default option do not
import settings and click OK
now the other thing that may pop up here
is you may get a privacy policy popping
up asking you to accept that if that's
the case you need to scroll down to the
bottom for the accept button to be
enabled. Now the screens actually new and
I believe it relates to the privacy
legislation enforce outside or inside
the Europe you know they're one that's
taking effect as of the 25th of May 2018
it probably won't show up or shouldn't
show up if you outside of that but I
didn't write that when I was installing
the the Linux version of IntelliJ that
it did pop up for me even though I'm not
in Europe, so if it does pop up bottom
line is just scroll down to the bottom
and click on accept but don't be too
concerned if you don't see the privacy
policy so after that we'll see a
configuration section and we just need
to set some settings and tell IntelliJ
which options to use so firstly we've
got the screen here for theme you can
see you've got a choice of using a dark
background or the dark Euler famous I
call it or a white background the light
theme which is the IntelliJ theme these
select each one you want to work is
knowing that you can always change it
later so what I'm going to do is click
on the light theme, click on next to go
to the next part of the configuration
here we've got an option to define our
keys and what I would generally
recommend you do is just leave the
default option I've never used IDE on
the left hand side and leave that as a
default option and click on next
we've then got an option to create a launcher
so that we can open IntelliJ IDEA from
the command line but I'm not going to
specify or set that up because I
generally just like to start GUI and
actually select the projects and create
them from the GUI so for that reason was
kind of skip down and click on next now
there's a series of plugins you can see
on the screen here you can choose all
sorts of things and going up nuts if you
wanted to but what I'd do suggest you do
at this point is just leave them as is
for now and you can always come back
later and go into the plugin settings
within the configuration if you decide
you want to install other plugins later
and one other thing to note is if you're
running or installing the ultimate
edition of IntelliJ IDEA you'll have a
lot more options to install plug-ins for
that in my case I'm just going to click
on next here without changing anything
we get to this next screen same deal
here we can change or install those
things but but we're not going to be
using those in this particular course, so
I'm going to skip per these as well you
can click on start using IntelliJ IDEA
okay so you can say that IntelliJ IDEA
has now started, we're now successfully
installed IntelliJ IDEA what we need to
do is install the Python plugin and
that's a plugin that's been developed by
IntelliJ, so that it supports Python
within IntelliJ IDEA and if you decided
to install PyCharm instead of IntelliJ
IDEA you can skip this step do make sure
though that you watch the next video
where we configure Python and change
some other useful settings but get me
back to IntelliJ IDEA the Python plug-in
gives IntelliJ IDEA the same
capabilities as pycharm for Python
programming so to get access to that I'm
just going to come over here and click
on configure and select plugins and I'm
going to come up here and type Python
you can see you've only got the one
option showing up there but I can come
down here click on install JetBrains
plugins anyway that gives us three
options but I'm going to choose the one
down the bottom nobody know that's the
one from jetbrains
that's the official path and plug-in and
then click on install so you can see
that's downloading a plug-in give that a
moment you'll notice this button down
here changed and still got the option to
restart IntelliJ IDEA whenever you
install a plug-in IntelliJ IDEA wants
you to restart the application so I'm
going to click on restart then I'm going
to click on ok this restart option comes
up and I'm going to click on restart
which is going to restart and then
activate the python plug-in within
IntelliJ IDEA we'll just give that a
moment to start you can see that
sometimes IntelliJ has a bit of
difficulty restarting it does
occasionally do that I'm just going to
close that down again then I'm just
going to start IntelliJ again and
hopefully it'll restart correctly this time.
Okay so I can see it's restarting
this time so you may or may not get that
a problem when you're actually going
through the installation process.
Okay, so you see now that IntelliJ IDEA
has restarted we've got the Python
plug-in installed and so I'm going to
stop the video here but in the next one
we want to make sure that the Python
plug-in is configured correctly but we
also want to change some settings just
to make it a bit easier to use you know
the steps in the next video will be the
same for IntelliJ IDEA and pycharm so be
sure to watch it even if you installed
PyCharm instead of IntelliJ IDEA, so I'll
see you in the next video.