so as I mentioned at the end of the
previous video theirs a fundamental problem
with the code for the account class that
we've created and although fixing it is
easy there's more than one way to do so
so I'm gonna cover that later but so I
will let you see if you can spot the problem until we
get to that part
of this course so now that we have a program
that is using the class to maintain an
account balance it's easy to see
hopefully easy to see how the class
encapsulates the balance attributes and the methods
to manipulate it without any client of
the class having to worry about the
details now a client is anything
that uses a particular class or this
class so clients don't have to worry about the
implementation details they just need to
call the deposit method to put more money
in and the withdrawal method to take
money out so one advantage provided
by encapsulation is that we can change
the way that the methods are implemented
as long as we don't change their
signature in a way that is it that is
incompatible with the current signature
so if we do that any client code will
continue to work now if you remember back
from the lectures on functions that a
signature is the definition of the name
and parameters of a function as well as
any return value and applies to methods as well so to demonstrate that what I'll do is I'll keep the bank
orders as happy by including a transaction
log to track the details of all deposits
and withdrawals now will start by just
tracking deposits because the same code
will ultimately be used for withdrawals
and you know rather than duplicating the
code I'll use that as an opportunity to
introduce class methods
and first I'll add a list to the classes
data attributes and modify the deposit
method to add the transaction details to
the list the details to be log will be
using the date and time of the
transaction also the amount so we'll need
to import the date time module and remember from the videos in section eleven that
to we really should install local time
so we'll also used to pytz module so
that we can log our location and where UTC
time so lets go ahead and start the changes and
the first we need to do is import those
modules  so....and remember if you having
problems with pytz getting that to work we did
install that in a previous sections so go
back and check that out
as its not installed usually by default
with the Python installation alright so what we're
going to do is we need to add the list to
the class attributes so that we can store
the log and we'll do that in our
init method so we'll come down here to the init
and....
....and what we need to do is in
the deposit method we need to add the
call that is going to append the amount
of the deposit with the UTC time so
we'll do that by typing...
...
....
....and attribute called transaction list has been created in
the init method and that sent to an empty
list initially and in the deposit method
we then appended the transaction details
to the list which is the date and the
amount in this case now I'll come back to how the dates is calculated in a
minute because their have been a quite a few video since the ones on dates and times in Python
and I have chose to store the details as a tuple containing the date time and the amount
so I'll add the method to print out the
transaction log after the show balance
method so let's go ahead and do that so...
...
....
.....and that should be it
so before I make any changes to the main
program down here lets just run it to make
sure that it still works even though I've
made changes to the implementation of course
of the deposit method by adding the call
to add the transaction log so if I just run that so it still works but the
class now has got additional
functionality the ability to display a
transaction list so any existing code
doesn't break as a result of the changes
we made to the deposit method bit if we want
to we can also print out the transaction
list by adding that to our main so we can
come down here after the withdrawal....
...and if we run that
....you can see $1000 deposited on the date of the transaction in
UTC time and in the local time which is
works out to 8:32 in the morning Australian
time so before I move on you might be wondering
about the for loop in line 30 or on line 30
where the code iterates through the
transaction list so we created the
transaction list to contain tuples and in
the videos on tuples I showed you that you can assign a value to several variables in a
single assignment statement by using a
tuple and that's all it's really
happening in the for loop instead of just assigning a value to a single variable for
each value in the list
Python unpacks the tuple and assigns the
value to both data and amount at the same
time
ok so our class now logs deposits and I
could do the same thing in the
withdrawal method to log withdrawals as
well and to do that that would involve
duplicating the code that creates a date
and time with time zone information so its
probably better to create a function to
do that instead now I could do that by
adding another method to the class but
the method wouldn't be acting on any
data attributes and there's no point
including it in the namespace of every
single instance when a function in the
would do the job just fine so
it's a good place to introduce static
methods which is the same term used in
Java and C++ so what i'll do is i'll
start by creating it as a method which I
put right at the start of the class
so we are going
put it above the init so....
....
...
.....so two things firstly
you notice I've use a underscore at the start when defining
the method and also we've got a warning so IntelliJ has detected that the
self parameter isn't use and suggest
that the method
can be implemented as a static method
instead...so detecting
a method which may safely be made static so you can just
repeat what I said it's detected that the
self parameter isn't being used in the
method that was created and its
suggesting that this method can be
implemented as static method instead a
static method is shared by all instances
of the class in the same way that the
power_source class
attribute of our kettle class was shared
by all instances so making the method
static is pretty simple we just remove the
self parameter and put an annotation
before the method definition so if I
removed self after we delete that parameter we
also have to put annotation so above the method we put...
...and notice how the warnings disappeared
and if we hold the Ctrl key down or command
on a Mac and hover over the annotation
you can see that it's coming up and showing its a class and as I said everything in
Python is an object so if we now click while
holding down control or command on this
annotation you see definitions showing
up here in the built ins module that useful
to remember again that everything is an
object but unless your experience in object
oriented programming I wouldn't worry
too much about this implementation
details just yet so the current time method
uses the date time class or the date time
module to get the current date and time
in UTC format and then uses the pytz
module to localize it so that it stores time zone information for the current location
and then on line 10 it returns the localize UTC date time so we looked at pytz and
time zones in section eleven and here I'm
just making sure that I store UTC time
but have the ability to also display the
times in the local time that the
transaction happen and I've also
named the current underscore time method
with the leading underscore to indicate
to anyone using this class that this
method isn't really part of the normal
usage of the class now this conventional
the convention is that names starting
with an underscore are non-public
even though if you remember theirs nothing
in Python that enforces this so the account
class is concerned with managing bank
accounts not with dates and times so
although clients can call the current
underscore time method if they want to
the underscore makes it clear that this
method isn't intended to be used outside
of the class now if someone who does use
the current time method from outside our
account class they run the risk that we may
remove it in later version or change
it to remove to return something
completely different in the future
starting the name again with an
underscore is the Python way of
informing them of this they used the
method at their own risk
ok so now we've implemented this static
method we can go back to our deposit
method and used that static method
instead of performing the conversion in
places as we currently got on line 22 so
come down and make a change to that so let's
make the change here
delete all this code now in the transaction_list.append
then brackets that will only be a matter of now
adding an extra set of brackets and
....
...so that's all we need to do now so its
now calling the static method that we
defined on line 8 returning or adding the
returned date and then also as it was
doing before appending the amount and we
can go back to our withdrawal method and
in the code that's confirmed that
we're able to do the withdraw after we deducted
the amount we put....
....
...so if we run this to confirm its running you can see now we've got our code working
quite nicely we got our deposit and
withdrawal by showing nicely in it's
formatted as it should be and obviously
we could do a bit of work if we wanted to
do to fix these dates up but we will leave them for now
so the point here is that despite the
additional functionality that the class
now has the program still runs fine
without any modification to the main
part in other words we didn't modify
anything here in the code from line
46 onwards that's still as it was before
and its still working despite us making
these changes in the various class
methods and looking at lines
22 and 28 you notice
that when we are calling our static method were
using the class name then the name of the
method so we're not using self in other
words again that's because the current
time method is a static or class method now you
can call class method on an instance as I
said some in other words I can change that and
just make this say here....and that's will
work just as well as but theirs no advantage to
doing so and in actual fact
performance slightly suffers because
Python will first attempt to find the
method in the instances namespace and
when it fails it then checks the class name space so if you know you got a static methods best to leave it
there just a to say that little bit of
time and to make it clear also in the
code that it is a static method so some
ways needed to tell the difference
between deposits and withdrawals and
negating the amount is a quick way to do
this you could as an alternative
add a transaction type item to the tuple if you wanted a tuple
if you wanted to do that so I'm going to end the video
here and then the next video we're
going to talk a little bit more about
the transactions and start a mini
challenge so see you in the next video