So we're not gonna start
talking about reading and
writing binary files in Python.
Now, there's two main reasons why
we would wanna deal with that,
why we would wanna deal with binary files.
So either we're processing binary data
Such as for an example, an image file.
And all we might want to store
the variables in our program so
that we can load them back in later.
Now the good thing is that
the basic principles of reading and
writing text files can be applied
here in principle in both cases.
So what we'll do is we'll start
writing some binary data,
and then we'll read it back in again.
Now creating a binary file is just
as easy as writing a text file
What we do is we just specify
the mode as b for binary.
Thing to keep in mind is that strings and
integers cannot be directly
written to a binary file.
They need to be converted to
a format called Bytes first.
And Python provides a number of ways to do
this and the most obvious being the method
I'm about to show you which is
using the Bytes build-in function.
And then the two underscore Bytes method
integer objects which does just that.
So, lets start out now by writing the
numbers from zero to sixteen to a binary
fall and then ringing them back in again.
So, you're going to start talking with,
we're going to be using with
like we did with text bowls.
Open and we'll call the fall binary.
And we're going to put B for
binary and W for wright.
Notice that if we don't put the b there
it's going to assume to be a text file.
So we need to put the b as well as
the w for write mode and binary files.
We'll call that sb number score file.
Then we'll put
firing range 17 because you want
the numbers from 0 to 16 to be processed.
Be put [INAUDIBLE]
and
then we wanna put bin_file.right bytes.
And bytes is the in built
function that comes with Python.
Then we'll just put I, so what we're
doing is we're converting the number I
to a byte format, and
then writing that to our binary file.
And that should be like so.
And then to read it, we come back here and
we type with open("binary",
'br') as bin_file.
Actually we should make that
dip into the first one.
Binfile we'll call it on this time.
Binfile print b.
So there's our basic code, so
if we now run that And you can see
the output on the screen there.
So opening a binary file
in order to write it,
it's very similar in the examples we used
for writing to a text file as I mentioned.
We just specify b, which you
can't see on the screen here now.
Oh, actually you could see that.
So that is b in front of the mode.
So it's gonna be bw for
writing binary, br for reading.
And you didn't see this before previously,
but
when we're writing,
we now use the bin_file identifier.
And we use a .write method that's part of
that to write our bytes out in that order.
So that's a little bit different
to what you've seen before.
And of course, the other clear thing there
is the bytes method there on line three,
we have to use that built in bytes
method data in this case an integer to
a bytes object which can be written
to the binary file effectively.
So that method on line three,
the bytes method returns a bytes object.
And that's an immutable version of a byte
array, which we'll be looking at later.
And essentially it's just a sequence
of integers in the range 0 to 255,
in other words, a sequence of bytes.
And you can see that in the example that
I've actually shown when we actually were
in the airport,
right when we'd written the program.
Now the bites function itself doesn't
quite behave as we might have expected.
And we'll discuss line
three in a bit more detail
after we talk a bit more about the file
that was created here to the right.
So your binary file should be saved in
the same directory as your Python program.
In my case, now it's going to be there
in my python program slash binary.
So what I should be able to do is I
should be able right click my file,
click on reveal and
find to go to that folder directly.
And you can see there is
the binary file at the top here,
and we can also come back here, and
the binary file should be there now.
We can double click that
IntelliJ will come up and say,
do you wanna register a new file type, cuz
it doesn't recognize this type of file.
Clearly we're getting different results,
I'm not gonna actually open that now.
But clearly the point is that it's not
a text file anymore, and it can't be read
read a normal text file, because we're
using a different process to write these.
The very nature of binary files is often
they're using non-text characters So
again we can go back and have a look,
and try to open this file.
And you see the mechas number that is
not displaying anything there at all.
As far as its concerned it doesn't exist,
so that's not good.
So let's go back to IntelliJ and
we'll double click it again.
And this time we'll just get it to use
the text file just to see what happens,
see what will come back.
In this case you can see,
again, it wasn't very helpful.
Basically displays a non-text
character as a square.
And we can't really do much,
we can't go over.
But essentially that's because the format
of the file isn't at all that you can
normally read from in the tradition
sense that as a text file is.
And just to confirm this is the actual
output on the right hand side here.
This is the data that got written so
you can see it's in a weird format,
the slash means it's a.
Character code so if you look carefully
you can see that we're fusing slash x for
number zero, number one, number two,
number three, 4-5-6-7-8.
And then we're getting into
hex as you can see there.
We count through eventually to ten
which is hex for the number 16.
Other thing to point in mind is
the slash t there for tap And
that's because the number code for
a byte 09 or
character 09 is actually known as a 10.
And for
10 that's also known as a recoratoon.
When you want character
to be more precise,
in case you are wondering what
they are and d is also missing.
It's in fact replaced by \r And
that's because a return character,
which has got the value thrown in.
So, what's happening is there's
been some sort of conversion here.
Intelligent knows that some of these
are common codes that are used and
its actually showing what
the representation of those are when
we're outputting this set list.
Now, if we actually did this, if we
actually output this on a Linux console
X07 is a bell character, so,
not sure whether that will work on a Mac.
But we can go to the folder,
I'm just going to my terminal.
And if I go cd
~/Documents/Programs/PythonPrograms/Bin-
ary, I'm going to go into that folder,
and if I try and
do a cat which is the equivalent of
Of typing the file contents out.
[SOUND] Did it again.
[SOUND] Did you hear that beep?
That's the beep for the character 7,
XI7, which is a beep character.
So you'll find that you'll get a beep
if you run this under Linux as well, or
if you try and type this.
And I think you may get
that on Windows as well.
So if you go to that folder and
type in the commands type and
then space and then name in this case
binary you'll probably get the same thing.
You'll get some sort of beep for
the character because it's the character
would actually beep in Windows as well.
So getting back to line three in our code.
I'll close down the binary fold out now.
And closing the run window now.
Now getting back to line three,
did you notice that we actually passed
the list to the bytes function?
And the reason that we passed the list,
that we didn't just pass i without a list
or not in a list It's because
bite works a little strangely.
So if you pass an integer to it,
it creates a bite sequence with
that many bites all set to zero.
Which is not what we wanted here.
So by enclosing I in square brackets,
we're parsing a list with
the single item I, which
the bite function then correctly converted
to a single binary file in the airport.
If we fail to convert the single
number to a bite we'll get an error.
I can see that by changing line three And
temporarily removing that code to
convert it to a byte and also the list.
And we try and
create it like that and run it.
We get an error,
bytes-like object is required, not 'int'.
So we do need to do that
conversion before we try and
save it as a byte in binary
format to a binary file.
Now we'll have a quick look now on how we
can write numerical values greater than
255 to a binary file.
But first one question you might be asking
now is if we have to pass a sequence type
like list to the bytes method, and I'll
just un do that so we can see it again.
So if you need to pass
a list as you saw there and
we generated the sequence
from the range function.
The previous line.
Whether we bother iterating through it
to create a single item for each value.
Now the answer is that we
shouldn't have done that but
really what we wanted to do was just
to demonstrate what was happening.
In practice you wouldn't create some
code exactly like we've done here.
You'd actually write the program in one
less line by just adding the range to
the bytes function.
So in other words you
do something like this.
You get rid of the for
link altogether, and
instead of putting bytes and
putting a list there,
we put (bytes(range(17))), Like so,
and if we run that You can see
we've got exactly the same result
in terms of output with this line of code.
Now it'd be more useful with binary
files to store the of our own numerical
in a binary file, and we can do that.
And it turns the itself's got a 2_bytes
method that it allows it to do that.
So this next example,
what I'm going to do is
Write the value out of four variables and
allows to read those values back in again.
Going to close this and
I'm just going to that code out.
And I'm going to we're going
to set the values first.
A equals 65534 and
that's equivalent to FFFE and A equals 65.
535.
That's equivalent to FF FF.
C equals 65536.
That's equivalent to 00010000 And
finally D equals 2998302,
that's equivalent to O2, so
2DCO1E, so that's our four variables,
and I'm just giving you the hex
equivalence there to the right hand side,
And this the code so we can put right,
so I can put width, open two.
And b w because we want to
write a binary file format.
S bin file.
I'm going to put bin
underscore file dot right.
A dot two underscore bye method
we converted the integer
Automatically two bytes and then we're
gonna pass an extra parameter here,
we're gonna put the length, and
we're gonna put the bar [INAUDIBLE] and
we'll talk about that shortly.
I'm gonna set that to big.
List D we'll set that to X to just be
a little bit different because there's
a reason for that shortly.
We'll just do the same for the other two.
In fact on three variables.
The next one is going to be two bytes
again, so that's going to be B.
We're basing that on the fact that
this representation over here,
so for A and B we only needed
two bytes to store the value.
But the next one, because we've
clocked over the 65 power 53 mark,
we need to use four bytes.
So I'm going to set that to four.
Four and the last one which will be X that
also needs four bytes as you can see,
so I'm going to change that to four.
And I'm going to do something extra,
and then we'll discuss it.
So I'm going to set that to write another
variable out, X again, this time I'm going
to leave it on four, but I'm going
to change this to little like so.
So first of all, run it.
And whoops, I made a typo there,
so that should've been a, b, c.
And I'll run it again.
[LAUGH] I having a hard
time typing at the moment.
little, that's meant to be,
so I will try that again.
Third time lucky, run it.
And we've got no output, which means that,
well no errors, which is a good start,
and we haven't got any
output in our program.
So it's surprising that we have
anything showing on the screen.
So for these two parameters and
it's called bye method the first one
is the number of bytes we want and
the second is whether to return the result
as big indian or little indian.
Now the number of bytes
is straight forward.
Cuz if you remember from the earlier
lecture on binary the largest number
we can store in two bytes or
16 bits in other words was 65535.
As soon as we get to a higher number
we need to go to more bytes to store
those numbers.
And it's in this case.
Case for c, we need at least 3
bytes to represent that variable.
But it's usual when you're writing binary
to use an even number of bytes, and so
that's why we've converted
it up to 4 in that case.
Now ending this are rows, this is that And
here the second parameter so
this indian row where computer
manufacturers had to make a decision
about how to store numbers
in their computers memory.
So what happens is stores
the most significant byte first
with the remaining bytes of
the number following in order,
the same way you'd write
it in other words.
But little indian is the reverse
of this in other words it shows
the least significant
byte being stored first.
Now the initial choice
was largely arbitrary.
Whilst for example, IBM choosing
big endian for their mainframes.
This is years ago.
And Intel, Intel CPUs and Intel the
manufacturer are using little endian for
their early microprocessors.
So once the choice has been made,
it continues to be used and
maintain backwards compatibility.
Now we've chosen in this example
Beaconed in for all but the last right.
And as you can see there by passing
big for the first four calls
we used big [INAUDIBLE] and the landing
difference is the fifth one, but
we've written a value of x again, and
we've actually used little indian form.
Comment for that time.
What we're gonna do is have a quick look
at reading the numbers back into our
program, before we move on to more
pythonic ways of storing number variable
to a binary file.
So that's the write.
Let's write some code now that's
going to read those values back.
So I'm gonna put with open, binary2.
We're gonna do a br mode
to read at this time.
And we're gonna call it binFile.
Let's use a different name.
We don't really have to, but I will.
And what we'll do is, we'll assign
some new variables, e, f, g, h, i.
Five variables for
the five that are now in that file.
So we can put e = int dot
from underscore bots and
it's the opposite to two underscore bots
from is converting it from the file.
We are going to put bin underscore file,
or bin file.
Just to show you that we
can't do it that way,
we are going to use Use the same
identifier so we'll call that file.
Because there isn't a reason now
that we're finished with the first
that we can't reuse that.
So equals it dot front byte bin file and
then you need to pass the number of bytes,
in this case two.
Two and then the format whether it's big
or little, we're going to put b like so.
So that's creating a variable called and
we'll do the same for F, g, h, i.
So it's f, g, h, i.
And of course, that represents,
or relates to e is variable a,
f is b, g is c, h is x but
with big-endian format,
and i is that same variable x
again in little-endian format.
So for the last one,
we've purposely left it as big again.
So we're reading them all
back in big format again.
The other thing I need to do is
change the last three there to make
sure we're storing the correct number of,
or reading the correct number of bytes.
And relates completely to the number that
we used when we created the binary, So
if we run that again now, actually
what I'll obviously need to do first,
is preprint it.
Print a, you can sort of see the result
and confirm they're actually the same,
and we'll just change all those now.
So F G H I.
So now if we run that And
I missed a method didn't I?
I should have put .read because
I specified the name of
the file identifier but
I didn't put .read so
we need to actually call the method
.read To do the opposite of .write and
to read the data from, of course,
the binary file that we've created.
Okay, so we have a .read for all of those.
Now, try again, run it again.
And this time we've got some results.
And you can see that the first
four examples that have come back.
This is E, F, G and H.
You can see they should represent,
well they do represent the exact numbers
that we originally saved them in.
But the fifth one is what we
want you to have a look at.
Notice how that number is now
completely different to the X value or
2998302 that's on line 11.
And what's happened there is,
I'll just close this down so
you can see it a bit easier.
We used big format again here, so
we saved it in little Indian format and
we tried to read it back
again in big Indian format.
So in other words the bytes are in the
reverse order because they were written
Initially in little indian
format on line 18 and
we're trying to read them back
in big indian format in line 29.
This demonstrates that's very
important to understand the structure
of the binary data in a file if you're
going to attempt to read it successfully.
Now, again it's one making point here
that this is pretty low level stuff
They can come out of this knowing that it
is possible, but it's a bit fiddly if all
you want to do is store your programs
data and read it back in again.
But luckily,
with that said Python provides a couple of
other methods with dealing with this data.
And to make things easier for
you to do something along these lines.
So we'll move on now and
look at pickle and
shelf, which are two ways of working
with binary data in the next video