We've seen how our program's going to
work in the last video. Now let's write
the code. I'm going to create a new
Python file here. I'm going to call it jukebox_menu.
We're going to need our
albums list, and the obvious thing to do,
is to copy and paste it into this file.
One problem with doing that, is that we
have to then modify the data in two
places, if we want to add new albums.
Python lets us import things from other
Python files, which can be a great way to
share data between different programs.
And it's also a great way to share code
between different programs, and we've already
seen that, when we imported the random
module for our high-low game. We're going
to be looking at importing in more
detail, later in the course. To import the
data, we need to use the import command.
There's several ways to import things. I'm
going to use one of those ways here now.
I'm going to start typing from space nes -
notice that IntelliJ has provided
auto-completion for the file name. I called
my file, if you recall, nested_data.py,
and IntelliJ is offering that as a suggestion.
Pressing the tab key, as I do now, selects nested
data which saves typing, and also
avoids typing the name in incorrectly.
Alright, so we want to import albums for
nested_data, so we need to
type import here. So space import -
I'm going to type a there. Once again, IntelliJ is
offering suggestions here, for things
beginning with a in the nested_data file.
You could use the cursor keys
to move up and down the list, then press
tab to choose the relevant options. I'm
going to select albums and press tab.
So make sure you do choose albums, which I
did - that second option in the list.
If you just import album without the s,
you'll get an error later. Alright, so
that'll include the definition of our
albums list, into our jukebox_menu
program. The list is defined in nested_data, but we've
now made it available in this program as
well. And that's pretty cool,
but it isn't quite as straightforward as
I've just made it look.
And as I said, we'll look into this in detail, later.
For now, though, I wanted to show you
something strange that happens and one
way to fix it. So we're gonna go ahead
and run this jukebox_menu program.
Now make sure you're
executing the right file because this is
going to look very strange.
So right-click, as I usually do, in the
editor pane, and select jukebox_menu,
which I'm doing now, and make sure you're
running that from the context menu,
and we get a load of output, as you can see
here, even though there's no code in our
program yet. When you import another file,
Python executes all the code in that file.
Now that can be very useful, but it
isn't what we want to happen here.
Now we're gonna see another way to deal
with this. When we start writing code
that's intended to be shared, we'll write
it slightly differently.
For now though, if you want to share data
between different programs, then make
sure your file contains only the data
definitions - don't include any code in
the data file. So I'm gonna close down this
run window. And in fact, what I'll do is,
I'll just change this for now by
clicking on the cog, go back to View Mode
and doc, so it's back to how it was before.
I'm gonna close that down now, and what
we want to do, we want to open up nested_data,
so do that from a project pane,
or because it's on screen,
I'm gonna click it on here. And we're going
to delete everything, other than the
definition, at the top of the file - so
everything, basically up to and including,
line 40. So you can see there, we've only
now got our album's definition. So
basically, nested_data only includes
our albums list and no other
code. We can import albums into as many
other programs as we want, without
getting a load of code executed, as we saw.
Let's check this by switching back to jukebox menu, or _menu, up here,
and let's run it again. This time we don't
get that unwanted output. In fact, we
don't get any output, and that's because
we haven't written any code yet. Your IDE
may also be giving you a warning on line one,
that you've got an unused import
statement, and you can see that I've got
that warning here. That's fine - the warning
will go away when we start using it.
Alright, so I'm gonna print albums,
just so you can see that it's available.
So let's go ahead and do that: line three,
print parentheses albums.
You can see that warning's now disappeared. Run the program - you can see that we've got
our albums lists printed out. Alright, so
this is one way to share objects between
different Python programs. On line
one, we import albums from nested_data.
The syntax is the other way around -
we've got from nested_data import albums,
but it's still easy to understand what that means.
Now that we've got our data available
in our jukebox_menu program,
we can use it to produce the menus. We'll
write that code in the next video.