For the next part of the challenge, we
need to display the options again, if the
user enters an invalid choice. The
obvious way to do that is to copy the
print lines, from lines 1 to 7, and paste
them into an else block. So let's have a
go at doing that. I'm gonna add an else block
here, and paste in those choices.
Then I'll make sure they're obviously
indented to the right level, as well. Okay
So that should work. Let's run the
program and make sure that the valid
options still work, and then try an
invalid choice. Alright, so I'm going to
use 3 to go swimming, 4 to have dinner
- that's working. Let's try an invalid
choice, 8 - that's obviously invalid - and we're
now getting the menu displaying again
which is good. I'll enter zero, to make sure
that still works, to quit the program.
Alright so that works, but obviously it's
a little bit untidy. Obviously up here,
in the options on lines 1 to 7 but also
then on lines 17 through 23. It would be a
lot neater to only print the menu in one
place. A function might be the most
appropriate way to do that, but we
haven't covered functions in the course
yet. So this is the bit that requires
some thought, and it's why we made this
part of the challenge,
optional - thinking like a programmer.
One thing you'll find, when you learn to
program, is that the way you think
changes. It happens slowly, over time, as
you work with more and more code.
You'll automatically start looking at things in
different ways, and considering different
options to solve a given problem.
So back to our code. In this example, what
would happen if we requested the input
at the end of the loop, instead of at the
beginning, where it currently is on line
10. Well the first thing that will
happen is, we'll get an error.
So let's actually see that. So I'm going
to take line 10. I'm going to cut
that and move that down, here, to line 23.
Actually, what I'll do is, I'll put a space there, and then
I'll come up here and remove the blank line on line 10.
Now be careful with the indentation when you
move line ten, as I've just done.
It should have the same indentation as it
had before, and be at the same level as
the if, elif and else, which you can see
that it is here. Now I won't run the
program because my IDE's showing a problem
with line 10, and if I hover over the
choice variable there, Name choice can
be not defined. If your IDE doesn't highlight
problems before you run, then run the
program to actually see the error.
Alright, so we need to define choice
before the loop starts. So I'm going to come
down here, basically, above the while, and
start there. So choice equals - now we need
to bind it to some value but what value
should we use here? We know that it
mustn't be 0 because that would cause
the loop to break straight away. We also
don't want to use one of the valid
options 1 through 5. So we can initialize
it to almost anything else, apart from
the strings 1 to 5 and 0. So what I'm
going to do is bind it to the string
value - or the minus sign. So that makes
sure that the variable exists and has a
value but it doesn't have a value that
we're likely to use in our menu. The
error has obviously disappeared now,
on line 11. Let's run the program and see
what happens. So you can see, immediately,
what's happened there, is we're now getting
the menu printing out twice. So now that
we're seeing that, we don't need lines 1 to
7 anymore, so I'm actually going to
remove those, delete them. I'm gonna delete the
blank ones as well. I'm going to rerun this
again, and we've seen this popup before,
The program is already running. We don't want to
be typing into the old version, so I'm
going to choose stop and Rerun, to run the
latest code instead. That's looking
better now, the menu's only printing
once and we're inside the loop, waiting
for input. Let's try some options here,
so option one, Learn Python - You chose 1.
Let's check the other options - 2, 3, 4, 5.
We'll choose an invalid option. It should
hopefully display the menu again, and it
does do that, only 0 to quit. So don't
worry if you struggled with this part of
the challenge. As you read and write more
code, you'll start to consider different
ways of doing the same thing. As long as
you take the time to understand how your
code's working - and you can use the
debugger to help here - you'll start to
look at problems in different ways. Try
different ways to solve a problem and
experiment by changing code, to
understand what effect each line has.
Alright, so the final video coming up in
this section will be very short.
I'm going to use a condition on line 2,
instead of while true.
See you in the next video.