Alright, let's talk more about using if, elif
and else in the debugger.
At the moment, our program only allows one guess as its answer. Now we're going to change that in an
upcoming video,
but first, let's run it in the debugger
just to confirm what's happening. We're
gonna set a breakpoint over here, on line 6.
I'm going to right click and choose
Debug guessinggame. Now if you're using a
different IDE, just start your debugger
in the usual way. Alright, so at the moment,
you can see down the bottom of the screen,
our program's waiting for our input.
So I'm going to click into here and enter
the answer 3, and that's obviously less than
our answer 5. Now when I press enter, the
debugger stops on line 6. That's going to
test 'if guess is less than the answer',
which of course it is. We can see the
values of guess and answer in the
variables pane. Now IntelliJ also shows
the values in the code pane. We can see
answer 5 at the end of line 1, but also,
we can see 3 as the guess entered at the
end of line 4. So work out in your mind
which line's going to be executed next,
before using the step-over button. So I'm
going to come over and do that. As
expected, we get to line 7. Stepping over again,
the program's executed, and did
you note that the little console
tab has got the little yellow circle and
a down arrow, indicating there was some
output. You might have seen that flashing,
so we click onto that. We can see we've
now got some output below where we entered 3,
"Please guess higher", and the program's
terminated.
So basically, Python won't test the code
in an elif or an else when the if
condition is true. And obviously, in this
case, guess < answer was True. It printed
"Please guess higher" and the program terminated.
Alright, so now we're about
to test the condition guess is greater
than answer, which will be true. So
let's rerun,
or re-debug I should say, by clicking on debug. I'm going to enter 8 as my guess.
We've stopped on line 6 again and
this time the condition is going to be
false because 8 is obviously not less than 5.
So I'm going to step over.
Next we're about to test the condition guess
greater than answer, which will be true.
So I'm going to step over again, stepping
over one more time. You can see the flashing
little down arrow in the console tab at
the top there. Click on that and we can
see the output "Please guess lower".
Alright, so let's run the program one
more time, in the debugger this time.
We're going to enter the guess as 5.
Alright, so now that we've entered 5,
so the condition on line 6 will be
false, and so will the condition on line
8. Those lines will still get
executed. Python has to evaluate the
conditions to know what the results will be.
It's the code in the blocks after the if
and elif that will get skipped. So let's
use step over, to see the first
condition getting evaluated, and then
we'll click step over again to evaluate
line 8. Execution has jumped to
line 11. Note that the else isn't
evaluated. There's no condition to evaluate.
else blocks will be executed if nothing
else evaluated to true. The rules I
mentioned a couple of videos ago are simple.
So an if-statement begins with the
keyword if, followed by condition. The if
condition will always be evaluated.
Next ,you can have one or more elif
blocks. You don't have to include elif
and we will be seeing code that doesn't,
but if you have any elif lines, then they
come after the if. elif also has to come
before else, if there is an else.
And finally, you may have an else block.
You don't have to use else, but if you do,
it must come after the if, and it must
also come after any elifs, if there are any.
Alright so we're back in the code
here and I'm going to click on step over
one more time. Program's ended, click on the console tab and you can see "You've got it first time"
is outputted to the screen.
Alright, in the next video we're going to
improve the program slightly. It's still
not going to be very exciting. We've got
a few more things to learn first but we
have to learn to walk before we can run.
See you in the next video.