In this video we need to check whether
Python is set up and configured for your
Linux installation. Now I'm running
Ubuntu 18.0 4.1, but the concept should
be generally applicable to other Linux
distros. So let's open a terminal window first,
and first command I'm going to type
is pythons space - - version.
Now if you actually get a version return, and version of Python 3 point X is showing
other than command not found, which is
showing for me, then you don't need to do
anything else and you can probably finish
off the video. But in my case you can see
that I've got an error and a suggestion
on how to go about installing Python.
So what I'm going to do now is just confirm
that Python 3 also isn't available, so I
can do that by typing Python 3 space - -
version, and in my case you can see that
I have got Python 3.6.5 installed by default on Ubuntu.
Now this is a brand new installation. I
haven't done any configuration, or any
patching or anything like that. So
basically, that's probably enough for you
if you're running ubuntu, and you won't
need to actually do anything else.
If you do want to install the latest python
version, version 3.7.3,
you can do so, but frankly there's
no real need to do it because there's
not significant changes that have been
made, and you'll find that over time,
this installation Ubuntu will actually update the Python version anyway.
But one thing you'll need to check though,
is we use a program, and that's PIP.
We use a command line program called PIP, and we need to check whether that exists on this installation
so I'm going to type pip. You can see
I've got an error there. Again, if you had
a version come back and it did actually
report something, then chances are,
that'll be all you'll need. But you can also
type pip3.  Let's do that just to make sure.
That's not working either, as
you can see there. So if either of those
commands returned PIP with a 3 point X version, then you wouldn't need
to do anything else, but as you can see
with a brand new installation of Ubuntu,
that didn't work for me, so therefore I
need to install at least PIP 3.
So to do that I'm going to type sudo apt
a p t space install space python3 - pip.
We're going to type password, my password,
accept yes there, and that's going to
download it and install PIP, or PIP 3 in this case.
Once that's finished we'll just check the version number to
confirm we've got pip version 3, and
that's all we need to do before we move
onto the next video.
Alright so that's finished so I can
type pip3 space - - version. We've now
got a command being returned for us.
We've got, in this case, pip9 being
returned, so that's telling us that
everything's good to go, and the
3 point X that I was referring to,
by the way, over to the right hand
side, notice it says Python 3.6.
So basically, we know that we've got a
version of PIP for Python three-point-something,
3.6 in this particular case, because we
wouldn't want to be using PIP 2 with a
Python 3 installation. But basically, at this
point of time we've got both Python 3,
in our case it was, I think, 3.6.5.
I'll just check that again,
python space - - version, python3 that should have been.
And python3 space - - version,
we've got Python 3.6.7  installed, and we've also got
PIP version 9.0.1, which is for Python 3.6 installed.
So we're actually good to go at this point.  So let's end the video here,
and in the next video we'll start going through and installing IntelliJ IDEA,
which is the IDE we're going to be using, to write Python programs in this course.
So see you in the next video.