In the last video, we saw how to use the os.walk generator to work with files and directories
on the local file system.
In this video we're going to use the os.walk in generators of our own, to give a lot of flexibility
in working with files. I'm gonna start out by creating a new file.
So I'm going to do that; new Python file.
I'm going to call this one filesearch.py.
Alright, so let's go ahead and enter the following generator, so start with import os. Then we're going to do import
fnmatch, and we want to start with a function, so
Def find underscore albums
parentheses root comma space then artist underscore name, close parentheses and a colon.
Then we're going to put for path comma space directories comma space files in os.walk, root
in parentheses and then a colon. Then we're gonna do for artist in directories colon, then we're gonna put subdir is
equal to os.path.join parentheses path comma space artists, sorry artist, because we've
defined artist on 1ine 7.
And then we're going to do for space album underscore path comma space albums comma space underscore
space in os.walk, subdir in parentheses colon. Then we're going to put
for space album in albums colon. Then we're going to type in yield space
os.path.join.
Then it's going to be album underscore path comma space album, end of parentheses, then comma space album.
OK.
So this generator's similar to the earlier ones. So it uses
os.walk, as you can see there, to walk through the directories. For each one,
it joins a path to the directory name, then walks that tree to pick up the albums. Now at the outer level,
we're not actually interested in the list of files that's returned -
this one here,
line 9 - and that's why I've used the underscore as the name. As I mentioned earlier,
that's a Python convention to show that you're not using a value, but have to specify a value when doing
things like unpacking a tuple or dealing with values returned by a function call.
Now for this example, we return a tuple containing the album name and the path to its songs. Just like the
os.path.split function was used to split a path up,
we use os.path.join to recreate the path to the album directories. So let's add a
simple loop to check that it works.
Then we're going to actually start doing something interesting with it.
So I'm going to type here,
album_list is equal to find_albums,
music in double quotes, and obviously, this is in parentheses and that's the path. And
then the artist we're going to search for is Aerosmith, so capital E, capital A rather, e r o s m i t h, close
parentheses. Then we're gonna type for space
a in album_list colon, print a in parentheses.
So if we run this program now, go back
up to the top. So that's nothing we haven't seen before.
We've got a series of tuples containing the path to the directory, as well as the album name. But where
it gets really interesting is when we start matching file names. So you may have wondered why we got
an unused import at the start of the file,
and I'll just close this run window down.
If you didn't, you should certainly have wondered why we're passing the name of the band Aerosmith, as an
argument to find_albums, when in fact we're not using it.
So the file name match module, fnmatch, well that's used to match files whose names follow some
sort of pattern.
So our find_albums generator might be more useful if it just returned the albums for a single
artist, and with a quick change we can get it to do just that.
So we can come up here, under the, well actually on line 7.
We've got for artist in directories. We could change that to put for artist in. Then we could type fnmatch dot
filter, then directories will still be in parentheses.
Then we add a comma, then a space, then the artist_name, close parentheses and leave the colon there.
So instead of just looping through all the directories, we can actually filter them first.
So in this case, we'll now get only those albums from directories that exactly match the artist_name that
was passed to this function.
So if we actually run this. Let's check that it works, and obviously, I can't spell because that should have been filter, filter.
That's better.
I wasn't really paying attention to the warning there.
If we run this again now, you can see in this case, we'll just let it run til it finishes,
but at this time, it's not just outputting everything. We've only got some output based on Aerosmith.
So the generator returns a tuple, and you can see the program's exited there.
So the generator retains a tuple containing the path to the directory, and the name of the directory.
So depending on what you want to do with the results, you could just return the album name for argument's
sake.
So in this case, I want to demonstrate how using generators can be a great way to simplify code.
So as an example,
I think it would be more useful to have a way to get the list of songs on the albums.
So let's add the find_songs generator after find_albums, and need to make sure
we leave two blank lines between them as well.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we're going to type def space find_songs, and the parameter's going to be albums parentheses
colon.
I'm going to type for space album in albums colon, then on the next line for space song space n space os
dot list
dir, parentheses album, then left and right square bracket and a zero.
This is because we want the path, not the name of the album.
So let's put a colon there, and just put a comment there to that effect.
And then after that, we're going to yield song. OK,
and then we do album_list equals find_albums, music Aerosmith as it was before.
But this time we know the directory and we aren't expecting any subdirectories, so there's no need in
that case, to walk the entire directory structure, and we can use the os.listdir instead
of os.walk and that's why I've done that on line 16.
So this should be more efficient but it actually may not be. I'm gonna come back to that point shortly.
But first let's make use of find_songs to get the song list of all Aerosmith albums.
So I'm going to do that on the next line:
song_list is equal to find_songs, album_list. And I'm going to comment out
this loop,
because
we've seen that before, to save a bit of time, and we're going to put for s in song_list colon print,
s in parentheses.
So if we actually run this now, you can see here that we've got all the information we actually need.
The interesting thing here is that we've removed the generator of the data from the code that makes
use of the data. Now we could do that with ordinary functions,
but then we'd be returning lists and they could actually get huge, and they'd also stay in memory until we explicitly
cleared them, which is just something else to forget to do.
So when using this approach, we can create a list of songs for any artist in just four lines of code,
with very little overhead.
So we're basically chaining generators together by passing one generator on, as the argument to the next.
So I'm just closing this again.
So basically, on line 15 here,
when we loop through all those albums, the generator returns the details for each item as we request
them.
So at no time does a complete list of the albums exist in memory, and the same is true of all the songs.
We get
each one as it's needed and the program doesn't create a list of songs as such.
Well I guess that's not strictly true, because the os.walk function does return lists in its tuple. If that's
likely to be a problem,
os.walk may not be suitable for your particular application.
We'll be looking at scandir in a later video, and that can be useful if you want to avoid generating
the lists that os.walk creates. So creating and destroying a lot of lists will affect performance.
So Python has to take care of reclaiming the memory for the previous album song list,
.
each time we process a new album. So with thousands of albums, that memory management is going to have an
effect on performance.
Alright, so using generators like this could be very useful for things like interrogating log files
on a server. So there could be thousands of logs, and patch logs for example, can be really huge.
By using a generator to return the full path and name of each file, then another one to check for a file,
or check
a file for a particular matching string, is a very memory efficient way to look for particular errors, or
requests say, from a certain IP address or whatever you want it to find from the logs.
So generators are really one of those features that make Python an excellent choice for working with
huge data sets.
Once you get the hang of them they're actually quite simple but yet very powerful.
Now there's more you can do with generators since Python 3.5.
It's also possible to set a value into a generator using a slightly different form of yield but that's
enough to be getting on with for now.
So I'm going to finish this video now with a quick comment about the fnmatch module's filter method.
Now I can take wildcards, so it can process all the artists whose names start with black, by adding an
asterix.
Let's go ahead and do that.
For example line 20 here, where we've got Aerosmith, if we change that to capital B L A C K and put an * there,
after that, if we actually run this
you can see we can see different output that we got last time.
We get all the songs for the Black Crowes black case black hole Arkansas or Black River Project.
Black Sabbath and black beards Tea-Party.
So that's pretty cool and makes it easy to find all .log files
In the example I mentioned just now.
Searching log files.
There is one thing to be aware of though.
The future is sort of case sensitive.
Now that sounds a little bit vague its because the behavior depends on the underlying file system.
Now Linux file system is a case sensitive so it's not surprising that if it matches all saké sensitive
on Linux but Windows NTFS isn't case sensitive.
So if I change black to lower case.
In other words it closes down.
Change it to a lower case pay for black.
The program will still return the same results on Windows as long as I'm using an NTFS drive of course
so that is a hard drive that's been formatted with NTFS.
Now if you connect remotely to a Linux drive then the behaviour would be different.
So I actually run this, in my case because I'm on a Mac.
This results in no output.
But that example examples a change with the lower case b would still work in Windows.
Now I haven't mentioned the Mac yet and I should point out that I haven't changed the behavior of my
next file system.
So you might expect that the program to work for me is well after all the Mac file system HFS isn't
case sensitive by default.
It is however case preserving.
So there's a subtle difference between case sensitive and case preserving.
So if you wrote a Python program that will run on different operating systems you need to be really
aware of that.
So with HFS or HFS
Plus, you can't create files with the same name using different case but you can refer to a file
using its name and either uppercase or lowercase.
When Python reads the file it returns the name in the original case that it was created with.
So that's why black in lowercase isn't matching our directories.
Even though HFS isn't case sensitive.
And again HSF and HSF+ are file systems on a Mac. Now you shouldn't need to do this for the
next challenge.
But if you want to cater for matching black regardless of case, then what you could do is use a generator
expression to convert the directory names to uppercase. Generator expressions will make much more sense
when we've covered list comprehensions.
So really don't worry too much about his next bit of code.
I'm just including it here to show you one way of dealing with this, rather than leaving you hanging. Please
don't ask questions about this generator expression at this point.
And that's because it's going to be explained in detail in a later video.
So let's actually have a look at that.
So what I'm going to do first is comment out of the existing.
If you matched up filter. So for what you that what I would do is actually duplicate that line and coming up
in the first one you want to make a change it is going to be for artists.
If you matched futa.
But here is where it changes and I'm just going to delete that and just top it again.
So I went to see teleprinter CS D.
Oppa then left to rot parentheses for d in.
Single parentheses Raupp prophecies that is Colma spice capsule's score 9 and another wrong parentheses
and then a colon.
I am actually adding another line here after the method declaration.
The function declaration at the top the caps is called 9 is equal to artist.
Don't name drop us and then let the parentheses to be honest on the score top line.
If I run this
you can say where are getting a working again on my map but tonight this still doesn't work on case
sensitive file systems such as Linux uses the case sensitive file systems it's probably best to use
regular expressions.
However a slightly more complicated generator expression will actually do the job but isn't a sufficient
as using future.
So let's have a look at that so I'm going to close this down and I'm going to come into that second
line again.
Let's talk an example which is going to be for us in in parentheses.
T for t in directories.
If it didn't match dot if it match in parentheses data Anapa comma caps underscore 9 and to what parentheses
and then a colon.
So that's more complex but that should actually work.
So just checked and it still works on a Mac.
And you find this will also work on Linux and obviously it's going to work on Windows anyway because
it's a case insensitive so they generate expressions in case you're wondering will make a lot more sense
a bit later in the course.
Right so let's end the video here in the next video I'm going to start you off with a challenge.
Then look at another way for extracting the information we want without relying on having such a neatly
organized directory structure.
After all who has a music collection is organized I feel they had drives.
See you in the next video.