ok so let's continue on now with our
discussion about time and date time and
just to confirm that the actual program we
used this reaction game again is very
simple it uses the random module to
generate a random number of seconds from
one to six then it slept for that amount
of time and it woke up and of course you
have to press enter as soon as you got the prompt
to stop and it measure your time now I did allude to the
last video that there are problems with this program
so first one was of course as you saw me
in the last video do I manage to cheat by pressing enter twice to start with and as a result
it came up with a really really fast time
of .000 of a second which would
ordinarily be impossible for a human more
or less now other problem was that
if your playing around the time the
daylight saving start or ends then
the display time could indicate that it could taken
over an hour to press enter in spring or the
end time could be displayed as an hour
before the start time in autumn so that's
obviously not a problem as well and the
other issues of course the system clock
itself could be changed while waiting
for the player to press enter so many
computers now keep their clocks
synchronized with the time server on the
local network or the Internet and as
the computer's clock drifts its
automatically reset so it is
basically completely on track and showing
the right time or keeping the correct
time and in actual fact the
documentation for the time functions does
mention this so when the function
normally returns non decreasing values
it can return lower value than a
previous call if system clock has been set back
between the two calls
and that's this little bit here now the thing is Python now provides three more
functions that we could use instead of
the time function now if you want to
measure elapsed time as we did in our
code so these three functions we are
about to talk about were introduced in
Python 3.3 and we are going to have a look at
each one of these in turn by changing the
import on line 2 so go back and do that well I
said line 2 I'm talking about line 12 I should say so from time import as my_timer
so we're going to do now is change time to
perf_counter and you can see
the advantage of setting this up
as we've done because we still got the my_timer
functions showing down here so we do not have change any other code other than
the single import now what this does is
this gives an accurate measure of the elapsed
time but the value returned doesn't
represent an actual time so although we can
calculate the difference between the two
times it returns when we try to convert them
to local time the result printed out isn't going to be the current time so we can run that
to see
ok go on here and press enter start now the perf_counter is
the most precise clock and where
it really shines and its very useful is for
bench marking in code as in one example now
it's used by the trace and time modules that we can be looking at later
to get an idea of the performance of
functions that we wrote the next one is
the monotonic function and this behaves very
similarly and in fact it can be very
difficult to see any differences between
monotonic and perf_counter so perf_counter can
have a higher resolution on some systems so
it makes sense to use that
rather than monotonic but will change line 12
again now anyway to see how monotonic or
how the monotonic function works so change perf_counter to....
..and we can run that....ok you can see that its work like the previous example we are getting very similar results now if
a clock interesting enough is described
as monotonic what that means is that the
time can't go backwards and it's always
rules out any adjustment as a
result of daylight saving but also means that
adjustments to the computer's clock will
also not affect the times returned
by a monotonic clock now these three
functions the original one we use
the time but also perf_counter and
monotonic have allowed us to calculate
the actual elapsed time so the fourth
function we gonna look at it now is called
process_time now
process_time is not really
appropriate for this little game and
that's because it returns the time that
the CPU spends executing the current
process rather than the actual elapsed
time but we just going to give it a test anyways so you
can see the results so change it to process...so run that
so you can see the reported reaction time is much smaller
than previously and the reason that it's
only the amount of time spent on the
actual CPU is being recorded
not the elapsed time so we're process_time is useful is for things
like profiling code and in actual fact
it's use by the Python profile module a
module which we will also be looking at
later in the course ok so lets
close it down now to summarize here if
you want to measure actual elapse
time then use the perf_counter
function that's really the best way or
the best function if you wanna know how
much time the CPU is spent on a
particular task then used process_time now to deal with real times
rather than just measuring
durations use the time function and
that just leaves the monotonic function
at the moment it doesn't seem to be any
compelling reason to use that against
one of the other options on literally
any operating system so despite its
name is not the only monotonic clock
available in Python because both perf_counter and process_time are also
monotonic if you want more information
on these functions the reasons why they are
implemented and discussed in pep 0418 and that's available
online and I'm going copy and open it up we are going to go back to the browser and pep by the way stands for Python
enhancement proposal and its proposals
such as this one that resulted in the
language involving so you can see
the original proposal was created on 26
March 2012 to add monotonic time
performance counter and process time
functions now the things is if your reading them
you'll find that they are really quite
technical reading the pep for a
particular language feature can be
really useful if you're struggling to
work out something about the
documentation something out from the
documentation because you can gain really useful insight
into why the feature was provided and
why it was implemented in a particular
way ok so it's time for a challenge so
let's go back and do that i'm gonna
create a new Python file for this
and I'm just gonna call it challenge
and paste in the challenge ok so your
challenge to write a small program to
display information on the 4 clocks
whose functions we just looked at
and of course they are time perf_counter
monotonic and process_time and
use a documentation for the get_clock_info function
to work it how to call it for each of the
clocks so go away and do that now and when
you're ready to come back and see the
solution start the video again and I'll go through that with you then
so pause the video now...
ok so how did you get on hopefully you
manage to solve it and did you look up
the documentation for get_clock_info so let's have a look at the
documentation first will go back to the browser
and go back to the documentation that
we first opened in the previous
video and it is on that page so if we go away
now and have a look for get_clock_info
...we can see it on the screen there
and that gives us the information we
need to be able to call the various
methods so going back and typing
that code so we need to import our module
first...so let's now go ahead
and do the first one the regular one time and we can do that with filing and what we can is just
put an indication in the print as to which one we are calling and add a few tabs the
to tab it nicely the first one is time...we saw
that on the web page and the parameters is time
and we can do something similar for the other 3 and I'm just going to do that 1 2 3 and the second we are going to call is perf_counter
...because it's a longer word we're just gonna have one
tab for that... is going
to be the parameter or the argument
next one is monotonic... and that is also a longer word so it only needs the 1 tab and the argument is....and last one is process_time...
..that also needs the 1 tab...that should be monotonic but it not really matters because it is just a print out but  we will actually run that now actually we have to right click
it because we opened a new file run challenge and there is the 4 examples their now looking at the examples
and you notice the first one time
adjustables is true that means that the
clock can be adjusted with daylight
saving etc so it's not therefore
surprising that monotonic and adjustable
are mutually exclusive so in the case of perf_counter monotonic and process_time
we mentioned that they
are all monotonic so
therefore the adjustable is set to false
because the time cannot be changed and I
just made a typo their so I should fix that up that should have been tab \t it does not matter too much but will run
that in any way now the other thing
to note is that the get_clock_info
function also returns the
resolution of the clock and also the
underlying routine that's used to
implement it so on Linux you get something
completely different
you find that both perf_counter
and monotonic are implemented
in the same way and have the same
resolution in Windows 10 you get a
different result you find that you
should find perf_counter has much
higher resolution than monotonic and you
can see here on the Mac we've got the
perf_counter and monotonic both use
mach_absolute_time and time uses
get time of day the implementation and
process_time uses another one
as well which is get rusage so there you go
that is our discussion or our challenge completed
now for time so in the next video
what we're going to do now is expand
upon and start looking more
at dates and date time rather that times we are just pretty well focused on the last two
videos so I'll see you in the next video