So in this video we're gonna
continue on talking about ranges.
And just at the end of the previous
video we started talking about
equality with ranges.
And just to run this example again.
So you can see that,
I'll just make it more space here.
That my range which was set here, you can
see under decimals which is the range
3:40:3 and using a range actually topping
it out actually returned the same result.
So we actually returned true,
in other words,
saying both ranges were the same
effectively, or equal in other words.
What would actually happen,
do you think, if we actually typed this?
Print range 052 equal to range 062.
So, what do you think
that's going to print?
True or false?
Let's just run that.
If there the numbers are different,
we're actually gonna get true.
So why you might be asking, is that equal
when clearly they numbers are different?
Well it's all got to do with
the same sequence of values.
So it's regardless of how the values were
specified, it's what the end result is.
So in other words,
it's what the range actually returns
that is important here to test equality.
Obviously, it was quite easy on
line three, testing equality,
because they're identical.
But on line four, of course, we've got
one which has got 052 as the range,
and the second one is 062.
Can easily see what's going on here
by actually printing out a list.
So if we do a print, list, range, 052, and
then we do the same thing for 062.
It'll actually become clear why that is
actually equal when you think maybe at
first glance it shouldn't be.
And you can see that because
we're stepping by two,
the actual sequence that ended up
being generated was 024 in both cases.
And, that's actually what the test for
equality is.
So, it was actually testing what
the result of the range is,
not the actual numbers that were
typed in to come up with the range.
So, it's very important distinction there.
And just in relation to slicing again,
we did start doing that.
So a slice connects to the step value
of a slice could also be negative.
So it can go r equals range, 0 comma 100,
print r, and we're gonna do for i in r,
colon, colon, minus 2, print i.
And if you run that,
you can say basically we're stepping back,
going backwards to start two at a time.
Starting from the hundred and
basically going down to one.
Which of course is identical to typing for
i in range.
99, 0, -2,
print i, and fix the typo.
So you can see those two commands
were basically identical.
Okay we see that they're both the same,
and
we can actually confirm
that by just doing a print.
Separate them and you can see we got one
counting down to one and standing for
99 and the second one is 99 counting
down to one so that's actually working.
And do another space there, and
take careful note of this line.
To print(range(0,
100)[::-2] ==
is equal to range 99, 0, -2.
And if you run that, we should get true.
And you can see we
actually get true there.
So that's correct.
But if we actually do this for
i in range, 0, 100,
-2, print i.
We gonna run that.
We actually get nothing.
We only get the true which
is from this line here.
We don't actually get
any output from that.
The reason is because in
the negative slice example,
a negative step causes
a slice to be reversed.
Now, the same effect is obtained by
specifying a negative step in the range,
and you can see whether we've done that.
But the start and
end values must also be reversed,
otherwise the reading,
the way it's coming across,
is that it starts at 0 and moves in
steps of minus 2, until you hit 100.
So you can see what the problem is there
and that's never gonna obviously work if
it's moving back from zero,
which is why we didn't get any output.
But the slice, in contrast to that,
is returning items from a sequence and
that as we saw if a negative index
is specified then you start counting
from the end of the sequence.
So it's -1 being the last item,
-2 second to last, etc.
So, a range with a negative step can
be very useful for counting a for
loop backwards, but a negative
slice is also extremely useful, and
I'm gonna show you why.
So, we're gonna first
comment out this code.
And let's try an example.
So, I would type backstring.
So, what I will do, for reasons that will
come up is I am going to paste this in.
I will paste that in, backstring.
Then I will actually type, print
backstring colon, colon, negative one.
We'll actually run that,
Python is a very powerful language.
So you can see what it's
actually done there.
It's basically a simple way to
process the range in reverse order,
as you can see in that example where the
words were deliberately typed in reverse.
It was that one line,
we managed to get it to actually appear
as Python is a very powerful language.
So applying a slice to a negative step
to an existing range is also,
is a very simple way to process
that range in reverse order.
And as another example, r = range(0,
10), for i in r[::-1],
print(i), and we can do that.
And we get a similar result.
We get it reverse, so we get the results
of the range respectively reversed
from 9 to 0, in the same way that
when we actually printed the string,
we actually got the results
backward as well.
So that's actually it, so
it's now time for a challenge.
So, the challenge is gonna be
a little bit different this time.
It's gonna get you to,
well I'm gonna type in what to do, but
it's more a bit of experimentation
required on your behalf.
So basically I want you to experiment.
With different ranges,
and slices to get a feel for how they work.
So basically the challenge is not so
much a challenge, it's more a way,
it's more of a request to actually get you
to experiment with different ranges and
slices.
The idea is to get a feel for
how they're gonna work.
So remember that you can actually print
the range as well as iterating through it
to print the values.
And also you can actually check
that also checks that you,
the range is actually what you expected.
Because as you can see in some
circumstances, as I've shown in this
video, ranges don't always come
back as you would think they would.
And you might also want to include
things like I've shown there,
o = range(0, 100, 4),
printing out for contents of o, and
actually using the slice with the colon
colon 5 I have there on line 8,
printing out the values of p, and
using a for i in p and printing out i.
And basically see if you can work out
what this code is going to do and
what's gonna be printed before
you actually run the program.
Now if you're unsure what's gonna happen,
you can actually use for
loop to print out the values of o to see
why p actually returns what it does.
We're gonna actually run this, and
then I'll leave this with you
to actually experiment with.
This is one of those things, range is
where it becomes a lot more familiar and
makes more sense once you've actually
spent some time testing it and
going through it.
So, let's just run this result or
run this little program.
And there's the results that
it printed out, which may or
may not be what you thought it would be.
All right, so I'm going to actually
leave this video here now,
leave it to do some experimentation.
In the next video, we're gonna talk about
tuples or tuples, depending on how you
pronounce it, which is something that is
a very, very useful concept in Python.