So continuing on with Dictionaries,
I mentioned in a previous video
after the challenge, there was
a couple of more things to cover.
Before I start that, I just wanted to let
you know that I've changed to a different
theme for my videos.
You can see the background.
We're now using darcula,
and the reason for
that is you've probably noticed
in the last few videos,
whenever a dialogue box Pops up,
the buttons look out of place.
Because what I've done is I've
increased the font size so
that you can see these videos easier.
But there seems to be a bug,
at the moment, in the white background.
A standard thing that comes with IntelliJ.
And if I change to this thing,
that problem goes away.
So we'll see how we go with this color.
Hopefully it's still good.
And give me some feedback,
if you wouldn't mind, please, and
let me know if you're still
being able to see this video.
And still not very clear on your screen
but certainly good to work with.
I think I mentioned earlier in the course
when we're installing intellij that I
actually prefer this for
my everyday development.
Okay moving on we're going to look at two
more dictionary methods that can be really
useful in your everyday path in
programming First one is the update method
and that allows you to combine
two dictionaries together.
So that's really useful.
And the second one is the copy
method which is used to
create a copy of a dictionary.
And I've created a new file
I've called fruit.pie and
I've just pasted in our fruit.
from the original dictionary
videos that we did bout that.
So I've posted those back in again.
And we're gonna do,
what we're gonna do now is we're
gonna store some veggies as well.
So we're gonna put print fruit.
Then we're gonna do veg for
veggies equals, let's add some vegetables.
Cabbage, everyone's favorite.
Especially children,
every child is maybe not every
childs favorite
sprouts, lovely.
That's debatable I think.
And spinach,
which is something I actually do like.
Can I have some more fruit please,
which would be a typical
response from people to spinach.
Okay, so we've added three
entries in our dictionary and
we're just going to
print that out as well.
We can run that.
So at the moment Oops, I need to
cancel out of that, so disconnect.
That does come up and you're wondering
what's going on, it's because challenge is
selected, which was the last path and file
that was run in this project, so I can
right-click the current source file run
fruit, and that will then work and then
subsequently I can come in here and select
fruit or just make sure that's selected.
But okay, in this example you
can see that we've successfully
created two dictionaries and
they're separate as you can see.
One's got fruit and
other has got vegetables.
So that's working fine.
But we can actually
combine those together.
Using the update method, and when we do
that we pass the other one as a parameter.
So we can do something like
this veg.update(fruit) and
that's adding the fruit
dictionary to the veg dictionary.
So we then print that out and run that You
can see now on that third line of output,
you've got all the entries, and you can
see there we've also got sprouts there.
Cabbage there, etcetera.
So we've got both of them combined.
So that's a really handy command
if you've got two dictionaries and
you just want to combine them together.
There of course is nothing
stopping us from also doing this.
We could have done fruit.update And
that is added to the fruit dictionary so
I obviously left this example line 13 add
the veg dictionary to fruit, I am going to
take that again and the entry on line 15,
of course that is adding
the fruit dictionary To veg.
Now, the method returns none.
And if you remember from our
discussions of the list sort method,
a new list isn't returned when you call
sort, and with dictionary update method,
a new dictionary is not returned either.
So, the reason that we've talked about
this and mentioned this a few times
is primarily for people who are used
to other programming languages and
may expect a new object to be returned.
But just to confirm that,
if I do something like this,
Print is what I'll do,
I'll do at the end here, and then here.
I can do, print (fruit.update (veg)),
then I can do print(fruit).
So we actually run that You see
the first line we got none.
And the second line you can see
we've clearly got fruit and
some vegetables in there.
So, very important to remember
it doesn't return anything.
You know if you wanted to create a new
dictionary that contained all the items
say from fruit and veg, but you didn't
wanna modify the original dictionaries.
Then instead of using update it's a better
option to use the copy method instead.
So we could do something like this,
we could put,
nice and nasty equals fruit dot copy.
And we could do nice and nasty dot update.
(veg) print (nice and
nasty) and
just comment some of these lines out, so
if you run that now, you can see that
clearly there we've done the .copy and
then the.update and so that last line you
can see were really got 'sprouts' in there
And fruit, so we've got fruit and
vegetables, so
let's combine them again, creating
a new dictionary called nice and nasty.
And fruit and veg, both of those
dictionaries weren't modified at all, and
so, as confirmation, nice and
nasty, that dictionary now
contains all the items from both.
And just to confirm that,
you can do print veg dot fruit.
And run that.
And that should confirm.
You have vegetables on
the second to last line there.
And it's only vegetables and
then the last line you can see
scrolling over, that's all fruit.
There's no vegetables.
So that's a good way if you wanna copy.
One example,
one that's gonna be extremely useful.
What we're gonna do is make some
improvements to the user interface of our
adventure game.
So I'm gonna go back to the challenge,
and I'm going to copy all of this.
We're just gonna create a new folder just
to preserve that source code if you need
to go back to New > Python,
we'll just call this one game.
I'm gonna paste that code in again,
that was the last code from the challenge
That we did in the last video.
So I think that's something
that would be extremely useful.
We've gotta change the user
interface of this adventure game.
And wouldn't it be useful if players
could enter the name of the location
rather than a direction?
So I'm still allowing them to go there if
there's an exit from the current location.
In other words, an account temper
of the map, but for example,
it would allow them to type hill from the
road instead of west to get to the hill.
So the easiest way to implement the change
with the current count we've got
is to extend the vocabulary dictionary
to include the location names.
So what we're gonna do is extend that.
So we're still gonna leave
in our other directions.
But if we then go back in there and
put in So road 1
and what's this going to be called now?
Hill 2 building
3 valley It's gonna be four and
forest.
Five.
But the thing is we can't use
a direction as the value.
Although Talking road from
the forest moved south
talking road from the building moved west,
and
from the valley north so one solution that
keeps maintenance of the exits dictionary
simple is to use the location number
of street, then For the valley.
Then we have destination of
one of the exits dictionary.
We just had another entry one, one so
we can maintain the exits without
checking the map each time.
And again, that's easy to see and
to not actually describe.
So let's go ahead and update that now.
So what we need to do.
It's for each location we need to
put in the corresponding number.
So for number 2 here we've got west 2.
What we then need to do is put 2:2.
East will be 3:3,
North is going to be 5: five and south.
You guessed it 4:4 then we don't
need to do anything with qui,
so we'll leave that as it is.
So likewise for location two,
we need to also put in a five here.
So five is the key and
five is the location.
The third one, for west we're going
to put 1, 1 for the location.
And for location 4 we're gonna do
the same, we're gonna put 1, column 1.
And the second one after west
we're gonna put 2 column 2,
we're gonna leave quid in there.
And on the last line,
we need to put "2": 2.
"2" being the key, 2 being the location.
And cuz we're going south,
we also need to add a "1": 1, as well.
So essentially,
the corresponding direction, we've
also added that number into it as well, so
that it matches up WIth our vocabulary.
So, if you go ahead now and
run this, and I'm gonna change this,
we need to right-click first,
actually, and click run game.
I think we still should be able
to type in so south, north,
so we should always be
able to type in valley.
That takes us to a valley.
And road,
to take us back to where we were before,
and we can still get--could still So
that's pretty neat.
So providing there's an exit tour,
we're able to type in the destination name
to get there from our current location.
Now there is actually
an issue with this though.
So the list of available
exits from a location,
As you know is built up from the keys of
the exits dictionary for that location.
So now that we've added the extra
entries to the dictionary,
we end up with a load of numbers
in the value of x's list.
And just to run that again, 4352, etc.
You can see these extra numbers
that are being added there.
Now we do have a problem with this,
though.
The list of available x's from a location
As you can see it's built up from
the keys of the exits dictionary.
So we're using this to go through, we're
cycling through the line 42, the keys
dictionary or the exits dictionary and
building up a list of available exits.
So consequently of course when we run it,
which you saw when I run it previously
We've got now all these numbers and
they're 4, 3, 2,
5 as well as valid directions.
Now that's actually a problem,
it doesn't look good.
So what we really need to do is store the
nine destinations in a separate dictionary
then combine then at the point
when we check the players input.
And what we actually wanna do here,
I'll just connect that.
Cuz you really wanna undo those
changes that we've made and
create a combined directory.
So am gonna undo this.
The easiest way for me to fix this,
is to go back and just copy and
paste from our old challenge.
So am gonna copy the old exits And
I'll paste that in.
Go back to our game.
Pi file, paste that in.
So we're left now with our original exits.
So what we want to do is add
a new dictionary called name dex,
that contains those numbers
that we've just removed.
So, name x's equals 1.
2 colon 2.
3 colon three.
Five: five and
four colon four.
So that's our first dictionary for
the location one.
Location two, we only had the one,
and that was to location five.
Location three, we only had one again.
1, 4, we had a couple.
We 1, 1 and also 2, 2.
And lastly, location five Also had 2 so
2:2 1:1 like so, so that's our NamedExits,
so what we wanna do then is create a
combined directory Copy of the location's
exit dictionary and updating it to
include the appropriate named exits.
But there's no point doing all that
work if the player's charging to quit.
So what we're going to do is add
an else clause to the check for
location zero and
prepare our combined dictionary there.
So down here if loc equals zero, break.
And I'm going to add an else.
If it's not location zero, which means
we're still moving to another room.
And we're gonna type
allExits=exits(loc).copy,
so I'm grabbing a copy
of that dictionary and
allExits.update(namedExits[loc]), so
we're grabbing a copy of all the exits
That count in the exits
directory from here.
And then what we're doing, and that's for
that particular location, and then so
we've created a copy of that.
It's on line 55.
And then line 56 what we're
doing is we're updating it.
So we're grabbing a copy of
the appropriate entries from the name
dictionary for that location, and adding
to the new dictionary, which is all x's,
which we've created.
So consequently, now, instead of here on
line 68, checking for the x's location,
at the x's current location,
we can change that and test for all x's.
So we're just checking to see
whether our direction's in allExits.
And of course, allExits contains both
the directions, north, south, east,
west, but also the other locations,
the actual numbers, as well.
And of course allExits again, we confirmed
now is the west, north, east, west, etc.
But also the named exits
as in the numbers as well,
allowing us to use that vocabulary for
that purpose.
And the other thing to note is of course
we don't need to change anything here.
So line 48, the available exits is
now going to correctly look at just
the location, the exits for that
particular location, and it's not going to
include any of those numbers that
we saw when we previously ran it.
So now if we run this, You'll notice
now that the numbers have gone.
We should be able to just
use our normal items.
So what I'll do is we'll quit out of
that again and we'll run it again.
Just to the same as what
we've been doing before.
So south, north, road,
should be at the top road.
Nothing will happen cuz we're already
there, but we can type, valley.
And we got an error there.
So it's probably a good time
to actually debug this.
That's line 69 that's failing.
And I suspect what I've done is I've coded
something incorrectly, one of the keys.
And what I failed to do,
if we look at it, actually line 69,
probably should have looked
at the error straightaway.
If you look at that carefully,
lines 68 and 69,
you can probably see what I've done.
So we're looking in our
dictionary all exits
then trying to retrieve
a location from the exits.
So consequently, the code's gonna
work fine if we use west, north,
east, south etc using
those sorta locations.
But soon as we start typing in
the number it's gonna exit,
it's going to crash rather
Because it doesn't exist.
So what I should have done
there was make that all exits.
And that should fix it, so we should
be able to run that again now, and
still we have to go south, north, but
now we should be able to go valley,
and go back to road.
And if we just type road again we should
get an error because we can't go in
that direction.
So as you can see, update and copy,
really two very useful commands.
So we've covered quite a lot of important
concepts in the discussion overall,
of dictionaries.
And it's gone over, now, quite a few
videos, including the way that we've
related different data structures
by using the location,
the loc variable to access entries in
both the locations and exits structures.
And this is only one was to represent
allocations and keep that in mind.
So our net could be modeled in very
different ways so keep that in mind and
we could have used lists instead
of dictionaries for example.
Now dictionaries have the advantage that
insertion and deletion are extremely fast.
And that's of little relevance here,
because we're not using those operations
but access by key is also extremely fast,
which will be very useful for
a game like this.
So I'm gonna finish the video here now.
In the next video we're going
to go through another challenge.
We're going to challenge around
a standing of dictionaries.
So see you in the next video.