Alright, so let's look at appending items to a list. For this example, we'll allow
customers to choose which parts they
need when buying a computer. I'll keep it
simple to start with - we'll just offer
five items for sale. Now we saw how
to write a simple menu, in the challenge
at the end of the last section.
This program will start off very similar
to that. So let's start by creating a new
Python file. I'm going to call it buy
underscore computer.py.
Alright, so first we need to initialize a couple of
variables. We need a variable to store
the customers choice, as well as an empty
list to add items to. So on line one,
current_choice = double
quotes, with a dash character or minus
character in there. We talked about the
reasons for using that in the last section.
Line two, computer underscore parts
equals, and just left and right square
braces, and a comment there, create an empty list.
Again, that's going to be list to
store the items. Alright, so the code to
display the menu is the same as we've
used before. It's just the description of
the items that have changed. So I'm going to start on line four - I'm typing while current
underscore choice is not equal to, in
single quotes, 0 colon. Then on the next line,
if current underscore choice is in and
in double quotes, 1 2 3 4 5 colon print
parentheses double quotes, adding
left and right curly braces double quotes,
dot format, and in parentheses, current
underscore choice and two right to
parentheses to finish the line. Press
enter there, and backspace. We're gonna start on
line 8, then else : then we're going to
print out our menu option, so print
parentheses, Please add options from the list below,
and double quote and right parenthesis.
Next line, print parentheses double
quotes 1 : computer, double quotes and
right parenthesis. Next line, print
parentheses 2, and double quotes 2, rather,
monitor. That's the next item there.
Moving on to the next line, print
parentheses double quotes 3 : keyboard,
and our double quotes and right parenthesis.
Next line, print parentheses 4 double
quotes, in 4 rather, or four in double
quotes, mouse, and double quotes and
parenthesis. Next line, print 5 in
parentheses, sorry in double quotes,
which is also in parentheses, mouse mat.
There's our 5 options, and the only other
one we want after entering the double
quote and right parenthesis is our
option to exit, print. That's on the next
line, parentheses double quotes 0 colon
to finish. Double quote and right
parenthesis, and then we're going to go
down to line 17 at the same level as the
if and the else, current underscore
choice is equal to input, left and right
parentheses. When you're starting out
learning to program, it's a good idea to
run your code often. That way you can
spot errors and fix them, without having
hundreds of lines of code to work
through. I'm going to run the program
that we've got so far, to make sure it
works as we expect. Let's run it. You can
see there we've got a menu, so that's a
good start. Let's just start by trying to add
a few options. We're going to start by adding a
monitor, option 2, and we got the
message there, Adding 2 printed.
Try adding 4 now, for mouse, Adding 4. So
mouse also works. Now you should test all
the valid options to make sure you get
the appropriate message printed. I won't
go through all of them in the video.
Pause the video and check the other
options yourself. Now we should also test
what happens when we enter something invalid,
so I'm gonna try entering 8 here,
which obviously, isn't an option there.
The menu doesn't have an option 8 so
nothing's added. Our code displays the
menu again, so that's also working fine.
We'll try 0 now to finish, and the
programs exited.
Alright, so far so good. The next step
is to add the items to the list. At the
moment, our computer_parts list -
that's the one we've defined up here on
line two, is empty.
We've used square brackets with nothing
between them on line two, and that
creates an empty list, as the comment
said. Inside the if block, we can append
new items to the list. So let's go ahead
and do that. We're going to add it under
the print statement on line six. so I'm
going to type if, and indent it at the
same level, current_choice is
equal to 1, and 1 in single quotes -
two equal signs there - colon. Then we're
going to do computer_ parts
dot append, and in parentheses,
computer in double quotes. So the code
here, if the customer chooses option 1,
we add a computer to the list. We do that
by calling the list's append method. The
argument is the thing we want to append,
a computer in this case. That's the text
in double quotes on line eight. Alright,
so the other items are more of the same.
I'm going to paste the code in here to
save a bit of time. Alright, so there's
the code that I've pasted in there now.
Alright, so pause the video while you
enter the remaining code and come back
when you're ready to continue. Okay, so
those blocks of code use the append
method to add the items to the list. So
there's a few things wrong with this code.
We have to duplicate the five
strings, for one thing. The string
computer, on line eight, also appears in
the code on line 20. Let's take the
opportunity to fix this up as well. I'm
going to remove that extra line there.
So you can see the duplication there, again, computer line eight, as well as on line 19 now.
Adding a new option also
involves a lot of work. We've had to
change the code in three places. But
let's make sure it works before we start
improving the code. To make sure it's
working, we need to print out the
computer_parts list that we're
appending to. So let's do that right at
the end of the program. So I'm going to
do that right down here, on line 28,
indented to the left so it's executed
when the program finishes, print
parentheses computer_parts, and closing right parenthesis there.
And again, make sure that line
isn't indented. Basically, we want the
list to be printed out when the loop
exits, as I mentioned. So let's run that.
Let's choose some items now, to add to
our list. We'll start with option 1, computer.
Let's do another one,
option 4, which is the mouse.
Let's exit by selecting zero. As you can see
we've got a list there containing a
computer and a mouse. So that code's
working fine, but it isn't very clean, though.
There's a lot of duplication, and
making changes to the menu is a lot
harder than it should be. Improving the
program is a good way to see some of the
other things we can do with lists, and
we'll make a start on that in the next
video. But I'm going to finish this video
first with a mini challenge:
Change the program to have another
option, option 6, for a HDMI cable.
So remember that you'll need to make a
change in three places. Have a go,
test your code thoroughly and I'll go over my
solution to that in the next video.