Alright, so let's revise our guessing
game. specifically, what we're going to do
is give our players another guess, and
we'll do that by requesting input again.
So at the moment, we've got the code on
line 6, which tests whether the guess is
less than answer then we print a message, "Please guess higher". We're going to add
some code down here on line 8, and
we're going to type guess equals
int parenthesis input left and right
parenthesis and then a closing
right parenthesis. Now it's important
that this line is indented at the same
level as line 7, and in my case, you
can see that it is. Both lines are part
of the same code block and are indented
to the same level. Alright, so at this
point we've got a second guess from the
player. The next step is to see if that
guess was correct or not. So we're going
to add some code on line 9 now:
if guess is equal to answer, so two equal
signs there, :
then on the next line, print parenthesis
double quotes Well done, you guessed it.
And obviously, we've going a closing
double quote and right parenthesis there.
So we're comparing guess to answer, to see
if they got the correct answer. So note
that we have to use two equal symbols
here, one on line 8 and one on line 9.
A single equal is used when
binding a variable to a value, or when
assigning a value to a variable, if you
prefer to think of it that way.
Now when testing for equality, we use two
equal signs. Okay, so that's all we need
to do. We've used an if statement to
check if they got the right answer.
I'll leave the code like that because I want
to make it clear that you don't have to
have elif and else in your if statements.
The code would benefit from an else
clause, but we'll come back to that. Al
right, so that's the second guess when
the first guess was lower than the answer.
We'll do the same thing if it was higher.
So I'm going to come down, specifically,
for the code here, and on line 13,
type the same code in. I could copy and paste it.
I'll type it in again, guess equals int
left parenthesis input, left and right
parentheses and then closing parenthesis.
If, on the next line, guess is equal to, so
two equal signs, answer : press ENTER,
print parentheses double quotes, Well
done, you guessed it.
Alright, so we've done the same, when
testing whether the guess is greater
than the answer as well. And again, very
important that you've got the correct
indentation there, and that the code's
indented nicely under the print
statement on line 12, which we've
done.
So our if and elif blocks each contain,
now, another if block. Specifically,
that's the blocks on lines 9 to 10, and
also on lines
14 to 15. The two if
statements are indented one level, at the
same level as the other lines in the same block, as you can see. Lines 10 and 15,
they're indented another level
because they're in another block.
Those lines will only be executed when the condition guess is equal to answer,  is true.
Alright, so let's see if this works. I'm just going to run this as opposed to debugging.
I'm gonna start by
entering 9 as the first guess,
Please guess lower - you can see on the
screen. Now there's quite a few tests to do
here, to check every possible path
through the code. So let's guess
correctly this time. I'm going to enter
5 as the second guess.
We get the message, Well done, you guessed it, printed by line 15. So if you're not sure why the
message came from line 15 rather than
line 10, then run the program in the
debugger to check that. I'm going to run
the program again, this time I'm gonna enter 1.
So you can see we've got the
message telling us to guess higher,
so I'm going to enter 5 - Well done, you guessed
it, on the screen, and this output came
from line 10. And again, if you're not
sure why that's the case, make sure you
run the code through the debugger, step
through the code, and you'll see that
that's the case. Alright, the code's
working when we guess correctly the
second time, but what happens if we get
the second guess wrong. Well let's test that.
So I'm going to enter 1 again, and now
I'm going to enter 9,
and as you see, that's not really very helpful. The program's terminated without telling us what happened.
I wanted to show that you
don't have to use elif and else clauses,
but we really should use else here, to
print out a message when the second
guess is wrong.
So let's actually add the code. so I'm
going to come up to do that on,
after line 10. So I'm going to come down here.
I'm gonna press backspace so that my else is
on the same level as the if, else : enter
print on the next line, parentheses,
Sorry, you have not guessed correctly.
And we want to do the same thing when the
guess is too low, and that's down here on
line 18, which it will be when I type it.
I'm back spacing again to make sure the
else is at the same indentation level as
the if, else, print parentheses double quotes.
And of course, that should be "You
have not guessed correctly", not "You have guessed correctly"
because of course that
means the else is executed if the guess
has not been entered correctly. Same down here, so "Sorry, you have not guessed correctly".
Okay, we got it right in the end. Alright,
so again I mentioned it but pay careful
attention here to the indentation. The if
and else keywords have to be indented to
the same level. This now makes it very
easy to see which else or elif goes with
which if. The indentation is essential
for Python to understand what we want it
to do, but the added benefit is that it
also makes the code easier for us to read.
Alright, so we're going to run the
program again now.
I'm just going to do the same thing. In my case, I'm going to enter 1 as the first guess,
9 as the second one, and this time we've got a message, Sorry, you have not guessed correctly.
So run the program yourself
and experiment with different values
for your guesses. The answer's always 5,
which is a bit boring, but has the
advantage to make it easier to test the
program, in other words, you know which
messages to expect. Alright, so in the
next video we'll look at more of the conditional operators.
See you in the next video.