so we are gonna look on a way of updating
values stored in a shelve and also
take a look at a common way to increase
performance and also discussing go
through problems that often surprise
people new to the shelve module so what
we're going to do is create a new Python file
and we are gonna store something slightly more
complex other than simple strings
and use shelve to store recipe ingredients as a
list so go ahead and create a new Python
file for this will call this recipes and
start typing so I'm gonna import shelve again....
and type in some so...
and..and one more....ok I'm gonna type with...so we are gonna save it
to a shelve called recipes and as recipes...and we should be able to do recipes...
...so the list of ingredients are
simple and I've done this to cut down on the
amount of typing that has to be done
not because I can't cook anything more
complicated although my partner would
probably think that is true so after
creating a list what we do is we open the
shelve and we say for the meals to it you can see that on lines 10 through 13
so this point now I can run this
so right click it to run it for the
first time and you can see over here we got
our database recipes.db our shelve created
successfully
once we've done that I can close
the run window in comment out
some of the code because we don't need those anymore because we
got our data written and likewise I'm going to comment these out because
they've now been written to the shelve
and we don't need to write to them again
and you can see the list itself was
pretty simple we can come back and actually add recipes
so recipes...
...then will just do a for....
....and to look up at our shelve the value for that is passing our snack key and we should be able to run this
and you can see that we were able to get the other values
that were previously stored as well as the
soup entry that was stored from line 14
and outputted fine on the screen again everything
is working as expected
so continuing on what we do now is to look
at what happens when we modify one of
the list so adding butter to the
bacon lettuce and tomato sandwich is
probably good idea and we also add some
tomato to the the pasta
dish so to do that what we do is
actually what I'll do also is I'll comment out this soup because we
written that to the database but in terms of  pending items
you type....
...and we can do....
...so we are adding tomato to our pasta and butter to our blt...
...so looking at that you think that would be all
you need to do so we got the code in there
you can see we are adding a .append
it would seemingly be the case
that adding butter to BLT this is how
we go about it and we can run this program to see
what happens but we look at the screen
we can see what's happening is that it's
not updated the pasta still has only got
pasta and cheese and the BLT still only got
bacon lettuce tomato and bread so there are 2
items were dependent
the problem here is the shelve has no way
to know that these lists are changed so
what's actually happened is that we've
appended items to a copy of the list read
into memory but we haven't provided any
trigger for the shelve to write data
back out again and this is very
confusing when you first starting with shelve
the reason that it works this way is to
keep the disk access to an
absolute minimum
so that values aren't continually written to
disk but it does have this unfortunate
side effect that when accessing the same
keys value after a change causes it to
be read from the shelve and that's the
unchanged value is returned
rather than the value that you
think it would be in this case by our tomato
from our two list there is two ways to solve
this so we're going to do is look at
both and discuss the
implications of each approach so first
we can append to a copy of the list or
do whatever immutable objects being used
for the value and assign the copy back
with the same key exactly as we did when we
change lime to be great with tequila which we did in
the previous video so we'll do that with
a bit of code to show what I mean, so will comment that out
and how we would do it would put temp...
....so we are retrieving our existing BLT
the items in that list and we are gonna go temp....and then we do recipes....
....and like wise for the paste...
....and then we do.....so you can see what we are doing there is creating the list
from the recipes shelve grabbing the BLT in this
case where appending the entry
we want to append butter in this case and then using still
updating the effectively in the shelve for
BLT to be whatever the contents of the
list is the temp_list is and we are doing
exactly the same to pasta on lines 22 to 24 so
if we run this we can now see that
BLT has got butter and our pasta has got
court tomato as well just as
confirmation of that we should then be able to
comment out the scope because we have updated it
I'll comment that out and if we run this again now you can
see we got the values
butter and tomato still proving that the data has been written out to the shelve because we didn't
to do any update this time when we run the
code again so the advantage of this
approach is that you gain the benefit of
working with objects in memory with all
the performance benefits that that
provides because obviously a lot faster than if
you continue reading and writing to disk but
the disadvantage is that you gotta make
sure that your reassign any mutable
objects that have changed back to their
keys in the shelves, as we did on this
now commented out code on line 19 to 25
so there's another way of doing it and
the other approach involves opening
the shelve with writeback set to true.
so to see this working what we gonna do
is add some croutons to our soup after turning
writeback on for the shelf, on line 9.
so we are gonna come down here and put recipes....but we also come up here, to our with, where
its got recipes for shelve name....again don't worry about the red their
which is meant to indicate a valid
part of the statement but for some reason its coming out
in red and we just run that to confirm that
it does work you can see that our soup has now got
croutons. And again, just to be sure, comment that code out,
run it again, and again you see that our soup here has got
croutons in it. So when you actually use writeback
Python caches the object in memory and doesn't
actually update the shelve
file itself until you either close the shelve
or use to sync method. If there's been a lot of
changes, closing a shelve can take a while
because all have to be written to disk at once.
So this gives the advantage, as you saw,
of sort of slightly simpler code because we didn't need
to do all this code on 19
to 26 because it was handled
automatically. But the price of this, the
disadvantage in other words, is heavy memory
usage. and possibly much more heavier
usage, depending
on how many changes and the amount of data you're working with.
And there's also, I mentioned, the sync method and that the writeback way of
doing things doesn't actually update the shelve file
until you close the shelve or used the sync method
there's a potential problem with
using that sync method that can catch people
out so sync itself causes all entries in
the cache to be written to disk but it also
clears the cache as well so sync
is called automatically when the shelve is
closed but you can also use it anywhere
anytime you want to force the data
files to be updated. Now so far, we've
appended to our lists by retrieving them from the
shelve by key. As a general rule, that's the best way to
do things; however there could be a
situation where you may want to update
list immediately after adding to the
shelve. What we do is we'll add sync again, then
we'll appended a drop of cream to the list.
But we're gonna call the sync method
after adding the soup, which probably
think at first time you think is a reasonable
thing to do and we're doing
that so it's immediately saved to disk
so the code is going to look something similar to
this so we got our recipes I'm going to uncomment
that again, actually what I'll do is I'll leave that commented out and put...
recipes...so of course thats now
essentially with wrtieback = true enabled is going to overwrite our previous
entries for soups so in other words it's
going to delete out the croutons and we are going to be left with the initial
settings on line 6 so we are going to do that
so if we do a recipes.sync you would think that's the way of doing it
and I should be able to do soup....and of we run that soup no cream their, run again, no cream their
and obviously take this code out still no cream on the soup so the reason for that
is that these soup list object is
stored in the cache and the sync causes
the cache to be cleared so soup.append on
line 29 and ill just uncomment those out
so the souped.append cream on line 29 does
add cream to the list but there's no
corresponding list object in the cache
anymore because we called recipes.sync
on line 28 so when we loop
through the shelves putting the lists were
actually retrieving the lists from disk
again so in other words the soup list that
retrieved is not the same one
that we've just added cream too that's
because the sync is effectively in the wrong
place so to be very careful if you
decide to take this approach to call the
sync method probably better advice is to not update
objects in this manner
use the method that we previously
previously showed here something along those
lines that's a better better method of
ensuring its going to be updated so far we look at
how to use the shelve module and how it
behaves very much like a persistent
dictionary so we summarize the features of
shelve and have a look at the
when it will be appropriate to use it before getting
into the challenge now that we've mentioned
that the keys must be strings but the
values can be just about any Python
objects and can be really literally
just as complex as you need so dictionaries
containing lists for example can be use as
values in the shelves the value are pickled
before being stored in the underlying
data base fields so the same for pickle
applies to shelve values because of that now this makes shelves really
convenient and simple way to store
programs data unless you have persistent
storage yet continue to use the usual
Python syntax without having to learn SQL
which is Structured Query Language a way
to access data bases so you don't really need
to use the use that SQL to
interrogate database here rather use the usual
Python syntax in the last few video
however with that said the shelve
module does have some drawbacks and I
mean it's not suitable for some applications
so as a few examples for example
because values are pickled before being
stored and are unpickled by the value when it went
back if your values are really complex
this pickling and unpickling may impose significant overhead and
affect performance so in other words
slow down your application and the
we mentioned that different systems may use
different underlying database technology
for storing the shelve so that data is
platform agnostic so if an application
is likely to be moved to a new system
and must take its data starting with it then
shelves aren't probably the best solution because
they may or may not work properly or at
all in that environment or system and of
course this also leads to another
potential issue and that's data from
untrusted sources so deploying an
application that uses shelves for
essentially Data necessary for the
program to run as such as the location of the maps from our adventure
game would be deploying the shelve files
with the program as well as the previous
issue that the shelves may not be usable
in some systems if the application is
deployed over the internet and of course
is that real possibility that the files
can be tampered with and that would ultimately
expose potentially user's to security
threats
also concurrent access can also be a
problem with shelves although concurrent
read accesses are safe if a program is
writing to the shelve and no other
programs should have it open or attempt to
open it so the bottom line here is although shelves are very useful in the right
place it may be preferable to store data
in a database rather than using shelves
now we are gonna be covering data bases later
in the course and you'll be able to
choose which persistent mechanism
that best suit your needs after seeing how database work
worked as well so that's it
for this section on shelve I hope you have got
a lot out of it and in the next video
we got a challenge for you to practice using
shelves see you in that video