Alerts! (signal horn blows)
Strong alerts are needed for many interfaces. And in the past, messages were just done using native JavaScript
alerts, and you and I know how frustrating and ugly they are.
And one of the problems is, is that the native alert JavaScript function
is a system object, and that just means we can't manipulate how it looks, um, it's literally coming
straight from the browser.
So in order to manipulate alerts, how they look and feel, we have to design our own CSS on the back
of it.
So I'm going to show you a few examples now of some alerts.
Let's have a look.
So here we go.
I've got a plain HTML page just called "alert" up and going.
So let's start now by producing an HTML page.
I can call this "Alert Example".
And you can create this alert in many ways. You can create buttons, you can do inputs, you can do
images, etc.
I'm just going to do an input here.
Make it a button, but you can do it in many ways.
So let's just make it a button. And let's do an "onclick" and let's fire a function that we can call whatever
we want.
Let's just call it show_alert.
And let's make the value of this input
I don't know
"Click me to execute a JavaScript alert."
Now, the one thing left to do, is for us to define this show_alert function, and that is JavaScript.
Remember, JavaScript has to be inserted between script tags.
Let's execute.
So let's put this online.
There's our button that we created. And if I click on it, what do you expect to happen?
"YAY, this worked!". How easy is that? You've just seen how I've created a button, with a click event, and then
this alert here, is JavaScript.
Let's get into some more examples.