Welcome to yet another kind of call it a Sydney bonus section slash teaser.
So let me be clear right from the get go.
This is not about JavaScript.
It's completely beyond the scope of this course, but it is super useful to know as a programmer, as
a developer, because let's be honest, every single site that you visit, every single site that you'll
create will result in a request being made to a server and server, then has to deal with that request.
Send back a response of data to browser, then has to deal with and data and displayed on a screen.
So understanding this entire process is very, very important.
If you want to take your coding to the next level, which is why I just thought, you know what you've
been, you've been through such a long way.
You've soldiered on, you've got to the end.
And I just wanted to give you a bit of a high level understanding on the critical rendering path.
What?
That's right.
The critical rendering path.
Remember that it is very, very important.
And the critical rendering path just refers to the entire process I just discussed from the time your
browser sends a request to the time it has to receive that response from the server.
And then it has to figure out where everything goes on the page.
It has to put it into machine code to bots.
All of this happens very quickly, and you want to optimize this process so the user can see the content
on his or her screen immediately.
So that's a point with the critical rendering path.
But there's a lot to it because the browser has to construct the and document object model that has
to also construct its on.
And of course, through this whole process, it has to build the brain to treat, but then has to figure
out the layout.
And then finally, it has to actually paint the pixels on the screen.
I know you're probably thinking, I've got no idea what you're talking about, but and that's okay.
Just sit back in these pictures.
You don't even have the code with me.
Grab a coffee, goes through it and enjoy it.
Just view this as a real bonus.
I was actually in two minds whether to put them on him, but I did.
And because this course is about JavaScript, I have included videos that promote JavaScript relevant.
And again, I've only given you a quick snippet of these things.
We know we can't sit in hours and hours going through the critical rendering because one, this isn't
what the course is about and to you may not even be interested in learning about it.
But for me, it's incredibly fun and I would enjoy the session.
So, you know, don't give up.
Keep going.