Oh,
fancy seeing you here!
I guess you want to find out about variables.
Well, using and storing data is the backbone of writing code.
And if JavaScript couldn't do it, it would be a pretty useless language.
So lucky for us, it can do it, and it does it very well.
I'm excited about the section.
It's all going to be about variables. And sometimes you want your variables to change.
Sometimes you want to explicitly state that you want a variable to never change. And you've already seen
us use variables.
I've been using the "let" word often in these lectures,
(music starts)
so hopefully some of it's familiar, but enough
said.
Let's learn about variables.