Working with dates can be rather complicated.
And trust me, developers have felt the pain.
And before we get further, I just want to say that in this section, we are going to be ignoring third
party libraries like Moment.js that help us when working with dates.
And the reason is, I want you to understand JavaScript.
This course isn't about third party packages, and in any event, it'll help you understand dates at
its core.
So when you're working with third party libraries (later), it'll help you in any event.
Let's get into it.
A date in JavaScript is an object.
Remember how we had the two data-types in JavaScript? We had primitive, which is just another word for
simple like strings and numbers.
And then we had an object.
We had a complex data type.
Well, that fits into this bucket, and date represents a moment in time.
So even though it's named date, we do use it to handle time. And to instantiate, to access this object
called date,
we have to call it by using the "new" keyword and we go "new Date()".
And we normally put this into a variable.
And this creates a date object that points to the current moment in time.
And just in case you were wondering, for computers, the beginning of time is 1st of January 1970 and
all dates are expressed in milliseconds since this time.
But hang on ...
(record scratch)
Whaaaaat?
Why is the 1st of January 1970 the beginning of time?
Well, let me first point out the JavaScript is not the only language with this nuance.
Java, Python and a plethora of others also start their time on the 1st of January 1970.
When you start Googling these things, you're going to see some people say that that's the birthday
of Unix.
That's simply not true.
Why do we know it's not true?
Because there were operating systems before 1970.
In fact, in the 1960s, we already had rough versions of it.
So the reason that it's 1970 is that it was just a ... thumb
suck from the engineers designing the operating
system. They needed a start date of time and they just decided what better date than the New Year's
Day of 1970.
Something else that's very interesting is on a 32 bit system,
numbers can be represented from (swoosh) all the way to (swoosh).
These are large numbers. What it means is that our time span is limited.
What do I mean by that? Well, the negative numbers goes back in time.
Call it pre-history.
The positive numbers go forward in time.
Call it the future.
Based on these numbers,
pre-history dates all the way back to 1901.
What about the future?
Well, it only goes to 2038.
Oh, no.
Does this mean the world's going to come to an end in 2038?
I hope not.
But it is known as the year 2038 problem.
So how do we fix this?
Well, computers are already coming up with 64 bit operating systems, and that just means we're going
to be able to push out that future date.
So I don't think it's too much of a concern.
I just thought it's a bit of interesting knowledge for you.
Let's continue.