Yet another section and you can see I'm wearing a jacket.
Why it has been raining all day, so I'm just a bit cold, so apologize if it makes me look a bit aggressive.
But anyway, that's not the subject of this section.
You get us to this keyword is massively important to understand why.
Well, let me give you this example.
Say I make the statement to you.
I have a dog named Wolf and I have a cat named meal.
And it is so sweet, but the other one is terrible.
What is it and what is the other one referring to?
Am I referring to the dog or the kettle, the kettle, the dog?
And it's just a very simple example, but you can really see how important it is when you execute program
functions and often in programming, you need this keyword.
You want to understand the context environment in which your code is being run and you want to make
sure that it's referencing the right thing.
Anyway, I guess it's not making that much sense at the moment, but I promise you, at the end of the
section, you're going to be like, This is so easy.
It's beginning.