Oh, man, I've got such a nice cup of coffee right now.
That is beautiful.
And in Africa, we've got these little, I don't know, I mean, we call them "rusks".
It's like bread.
It's like dry bread, and you dip it in your coffee.
It is just phenomenal.
This is like a treat.
So I'm just stopping now quickly.
Let me finish this and then let's get started.
(music plays)
All right, Done!
Well done for getting this far in the course.
Seriously.
Keep going.
You're going to be learning a lot as we go along.
And now we're getting into the section of syntax. And you just need to sit back, relax and enjoy it.
But, you know, one of the serious things in learning syntax and all that is, data types in JavaScript.
And data types are very important because you've got to think now, take a step back and just think about
a website.
When you go and visit a website,
all it is, is it's a whole lot of data.
Yes, we put CSS in there, we put images in it to make it look pretty.
But think about it from a computer's point of view, it's just data.
Sometimes there are images, sometimes there are words on the screen, sometimes there are numbers on the screen and why
it's important to learn about data types, is you as a programmer,
you and I, we need to know how to deal with these different data types.
We need to know what we can do with different data types.
We need to know what functions we can apply to them.
And that's what this section is pretty much about, so we're going to be doing a lot of coding.
We're going to be learning about semicolons, white spaces, return statements, but we're going to
spend a large portion on the different types of data types. In particular,
we're going to be talking a lot about strings, numbers,
we're going to be talking about
null, we're gonna talk about undefined. We're going to be getting into a lot of this stuff and it's exciting.
So enjoy.
(music starts)
Sit back.
Go get a coffee. Get pumped up.
And let's start.
(music continues to play in background)