I guess there's no better place to start than with the browser, and as I'm sure you know, a browser
is just a program used to display files and navigate the web.
We know that I use Chrome all the time on my iPhone, I use Safari.
These are browsers, and the browser's main functionality is to present a resource that we choose.
And it does this by requesting it from the server and displaying it in the browser window.
And if why this process has to be done super duper quick, because yes, you and I are very impatient
when it comes to Googling.
When it comes to loading web pages on the web and how fast is fast, what are we going to get into that
later?
But for now, just know that Google researchers have suggested that page load times of less than 100
milliseconds.
Not that we can achieve this.
I'm just saying, if we can, that gives us the illusion of instantaneous website responses because
our visual sensory memory process inside our brain works in bursts of one hundred milliseconds.
Anyway, that's just a bit of a fly.
So we know that Brazil's main functionality is to present a resource that we choose to us.
But what resources am I talking about?
All but the most obvious one is HTML.
Every website that you load has to begin with this fall, but they also are the resources we may want
to load, like images, PDFs, ex email Jason.
Seizes JavaScript and so on and so forth.
But that's all well and good, so we know that we need to get a resource.
The next question is, will we test the browser, find this resource?
Where does it go?
And the answer to this is that the location of the resource specified by the You or I, the Uniform
Resource Identifier.
OK.
Already, you just want to see an example.
Well, let's just come up with a fictitious website.
My site dot com.
And once you enter this, you are all that you seeing on the screen into your dress line.
The browser will break this down into three distinct parts.
Can you guess what parts they are?
Well, you can kind of even guess intuitively what would be the first one will be HTP, and this is
the protocol.
This is the set of rules that govern how browsers speak to servers.
We're going to get into the soon, so that's the first aspect it breaks down into.
Secondly, it breaks down your server's name.
This is the site you want to go visit and in order for your browser to actually connect to the web server.
In this case, my site dot com to retrieve the information we requested.
It has to communicate with a name server that translates the server name into an IP address, and the
IP address is literally that.
It's an address.
It's a place where your browser can go and fetch that file from your web browsers, then able to connect
to the web server at the resolved IP address, usually on Port 80.
So that's the second item.
We've got a protocol.
We've got the server name.
And lastly, we've got the actual resource we want to collect.
So once your browser is connected to the web server using the HTTP protocol, in this example, the
browser will then read the hypertext markup language that index dot HMO file.
And this is the authoring language used to create documents on the worldwide web.
And then, of course, what happens next?
The daughters display to you on the screen.
So they have it a very, very high level view of the process your browser goes through in order to server
file to your web page.