Let's start coding.
So let's open up Google Chrome.
Okay, its opened up. Right click and go "Inspect".
And then click on this Console button here.
And there you have it.
This, ladies and gentlemen, is the Console.
And don't worry about the Elements, Sources, Networks, etc etc.
For now, we just want to start playing around with the Console.
So what is the Console?
Let's start playing. You know, like I said, this is where we write JavaScript code.
Let's start typing something.
So let's write "dog".
Man, what does this mean? Uncaught ReferenceError: dog is not defined?
Well, of course "dog" isn't defined.
We haven't told the computer what "dog" is, so that kind of makes sense.
What about some random text?
Same thing.
"alskdjfklasjf" is not defined, either.
Makes sense, right?
So it's not scary.
You can click this little button here to clear the console to get rid of everything you've typed.
Let's try something else.
What about one plus five?
See if that works.
Push "enter" or "return" on your keyboard. And yep, there you go. It evaluates an expression.
How was that done?
Well, the awesome thing is, that is JavaScript running on your browser. It literally knows what a one
is, what that little plus sign means,
and that five. And some clever programmers have written a program in the browser that interprets that into
machine code that displays the result for you.
And this is what the Console is. The fact that we could write one plus five, and then it printed back
a result,
six,
that is what the Console does.
All it is, is it's an awesome way for us to see immediate results.
Let's jump into something quickly before we continue.
All right.
A quick, quick break.
We know a Console is a place where we can write and run JavaScript code.
Let me just break it down a little bit more for you.
The Console serves two main purposes.
The one is diagnostic
information - it gives you information about your code, it helps you fix bugs and helps you change elements
on a page.
That's what I mean by diagnostic info.
The second function that console provides us is awesome, guys, and that is to write JavaScript.
And you've just seen some of the code that we've written. And I mentioned this in the last lecture,
I mentioned that the Console gives us the ability to read, evaluate, print and loop.
I just want to dive a little bit more into what I mean by read and evaluate, because it's really important
to understand how the Console works and how JavaScript works.
In the programming world, there are few little terminologies that help us along the way.
And one of these is what's known as an Expression.
What's an Expression? Well, think about when we type "1 + 1" into the Console, or we type "dog", we're
telling the computer what we want it to do, or what we want it to evaluate, that is called an Expression.
And the process that the computer takes to transform that Expression into response,
that whole process is called an evaluation. And the last part of it is that when the process of
evaluation is done
you're left with a value.
In the case of "one plus one", we're left with a value of "two".
Taking a step back, I want you to start thinking when we type this code, think about that. Expression
results in the computer evaluating that expression, which results in a value. Cool,
That's it.
Let's move on.