Allright, we're going to get more and more complicated as we go on.
So say now we want to click a button, shown an alert, and when you click okay on that alert, text is replaced
on the screen with something.
How would we do that?
Let's go.
Let's create an HTML document.
And again, let's create a button
with an "onclick" event.
Let's just call this one alert ... alertMe.
alertMe is not defined. Again, we've got to write JavaScript.
JavaScript has to be inserted within script tags.
We need to now define the alertMe function.
Don't worry about the syntax around functions, we're gonna learn about that shortly.
You'll see how it all fits in, and how to write a function.
Now, after you click OK on this alert, what do you want executed beneath it?
Remember with JavaScript, or actually it's the browser, the parser, it starts from the top
to the bottom.
So once this alert is done, it's going to execute what's beneath it. And say we want on the screen,
This text was
replaced with JavaScript.
This text was placed here with JavaScript.
Let's try and run this code.
I would expect to see an alert.
Well, I'd expect to see a button. When we click the button
we should see an alert.
And after the alert, we should see text put onto the screen because we've used document, and remember document
is a global object.
It's almost, but it's not quite the king,
remember Window is the king, but under Window
you've got this big object
called "document", and this document is your web page and all we're saying, is we accessing a method called
write(), which literally just puts text on that page.
It's as simple as that.
Let's see what this looks like.
There's our button "click me please".
When I click it, there's an alert.
And what happens when I click OK?
The text was replaced. How awesome is that?
Let's move on.