All right, let's get into some examples.
Let me show you how dates work.
So now the first thing is let's create a new object that instantiate or calls the JavaScript date object,
and I'm going to make comments here so you can follow along.
So here we're going to create a variable with
the current time. So let's just say, let "now" equal
new Date().
What I'm going to do quickly, is I'm just going to start Quokka, so we don't have to console this to
a browser. And now let's just see what "now" is.
So there you go.
How cool is this?
We have eight pieces of information here.
And remember, I said that time starts from 1st of January 1970, and that any time now is just how
many milliseconds have passed since then.
What do I mean by that?
Let me show you.
Let's get the current timestamp.
Let's console.log our time, which is "now".
There's an inbuilt method, remember how we were saying that these JavaScript date objects come with
a whole lot of inbuilt methods?
Well, one of them is getTime().
There you go, there you have it.
That's how many milliseconds have passed since  1970.
But hang on.
Before we go further, there's just one thing which you may have noticed ... this "new" keyword.
Did you notice that new keyword?
Well, when you use the new keyword in JavaScript,
you're creating a new object.
And yes, initially it's just going to be a blank object.
But that object
will inherit its prototype from somewhere else.
We're going to get onto prototypes later, so don't stress too much yet.
All that "new" keyword means is that it's creating a new object and that the "this" keyword points to that newly
created object.
Well, what if we didn't use the new keyword?
Good question.
If you don't use a new keyword, you'll be fooled because the date that you create without the new keyword
would just be a string.
What I mean by that is you wont' have access to any properties or methods.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's now delete all this.
And let's create a date, one with no new keyword and the other one the proper way with the new keyword.
So let date1 equal Date() with no new keyword, and let date2 equal new Date().
Let's see what they look like.
And like I said, they're going to look the same.
date1 and date2.
You can tell they look exactly the same, but we know they are not the same.
And how do we test this?
Remember the typeof
method.
So we can just go console
dot log,
typeof(date1).
It's a string.
And if we copy this down and try it on date2, it's an object.
And this is the point I'm trying to make. When you're working with dates,
make sure you remember the new keyword.
Why is it important?
Well, if you're wanting to access properties or methods, you won't be able to.
It's just a string.
Let's have a look.
I'll show you what I mean.
Remember how on the previous example, we showed the getTime() method and that produced the number of milliseconds
since 1970.
That was a method that we accessed.
Do you think we can do it here, if it's a string?
Let's see.
And we get an error: date1 getTime is not a function.
So if in doubt, let's just use the "new" keyword when working with dates.
And I just want to give you another quick summary on the new keyword.
All right, very quick recap.
We've seen that
to start working with the date object,
you must use the new keyword.
And this just means a new empty object is created.
And the object will inherit all properties from the Date prototype.
That's why you and I could access the getTime method.
We didn't write that method.
We could just access it straight out of the box
and that is because we used that "new" keyword.
And the last thing that I did mention is that the "this" keyword is bound to this new object that you create.
We're going to have a whole bonus section on this, but just bear in mind, this is what it does.
Let's move on.