Let's get into this.
What is this?
Simply put.
I like to think of this as the object.
It belongs to you.
And what is it?
Well, it's going to sound strange, but it is this it's whatever you're referring to.
I just want to highlight three things before we deep dive into this keyword one.
And this is the most crucial point of them all.
The value of this is usually determined by the execution context and execution.
Context simply means how function has been called.
Point number two.
This may be different and by different, I just mean, it may refer to different things.
Each time a functions call and point number three is don't stress if you don't understand.
Point number one and point number two, it's all going to make sense by the end of the section.
Now, before we dig deeper into this, we need to understand the execution context.
Remember, point one point one was that the value of this is usually determined by what?
By the execution context.
So now we need to understand this execution context in detail.
And trust me, it is so awesome to know this kind of stuff.
And I hope you really enjoy this up and coming lectures.
I've had a lot of fun putting it together.
And if you still confused or if it doesn't make sense, ask questions.
I'm here to help.
I'm sure all the students doing this course are willing to help, but helps everyone.
But enough said, Let's get into it.