The best thing is with these things is to just keep going with examples, because then you start feeling
more intuitive around it and you start becoming more comfortable around this concept of race.
So let's get into it.
Let me give you a practical example.
Let's say we've got a shopping list and we want to enter.
We want to delete things from the array.
We want to access the linked properties.
How would we go about doing all these things that have a lot?
Well, the first thing is, let's create a shopping list.
And you can call it what it what you want.
Let's just call it shopping list.
And this is to necessities.
Look.
Breed.
If we console.log this out.
Let me start Quokka.
There you go.
I'll raise the milk, bread, beer.
What about if we wanted to access properties in our well, we can access those properties with square
brackets.
Any initially?
We wanted to access mock.
Let's console.log shopping list.
Open and close.
Square brackets.
And remember, we've got an exercise in memory, and it's going to be at the starting point, which
is zero.
And that gives us look, if we wanted to excess beer, what would we do?
That's right.
We put two.
That would give us beer and with a raise, we can also override values very easy.
Let's override Belize.
That's our shopping list.
Instead of milk, it's by hook.
Now, if we console.log our array.
It's replaced milk with Coke.
And what about accessing the linked property?
What about if we wanted to add elements into this array if we suddenly remembered, Hey, I also need
to buy toilet paper?
Well, what about if we didn't want to buy beer anymore and wanted to get rid of that?
How would we go about doing that?
Well, let me show you something quickly.
Let me just open the console and look at this any array that we create.
This just creates the number, right?
It can be an injury free console of this art, and we open up this little thing here and we access its
prototype.
The coolest you could what we have access to.
We've got access to the method and the push method and mimic the examples of what those are now.
Let's go back to our I.D. and let's access the linked property.
How do we do this?
Well, you'll see if we go back to the console, you'll see here that we've actually got a Lynx property
automatically on this array.
On any array we create, we've got the property directly.
So if we go back to our I.D., we can access it.
Let's just console console.log shopping list.
In this case, the length of.
Three, we got three items in our air.
It makes sense.
Milk, bread and beer.
Well, in this case, coke, braeden beer.
Let's now add an item to our shopping list.
How do we do this?
Well, arrays have an in-built method called push in JavaScript, and it literally pushes an item onto
the array.
So let's exercise our own shopping list.
It's going to have a push method on it, and you can see my ID already tells me that this happens a
new element to array, and it returns a new length of the array.
So let's push.
Toilet paper.
Until right now, if we console.log this out.
Our shopping list.
And there you have it.
OK, but now say we made a mistake and we've got enough toilet paper, we want that thing out of there.
What do we do now?
Well, that's where my cup comes into it up.
It's remove an item from the array.
Again, that's access our shopping list.
Now we want to pop.
And this permitted waste removes the loss element of the array, which in our case is the toilet paper.
And now, if we console.log our shopping list out.
Toilet paper is nowhere to be seen.
Great.
I hope you having fun.
But there's more to raise than this.
Let's get into it.