Woohoo (party sounds)
You've just written your first JavaScript and we are not gonna stop,
so let's continue.
Let's open up the browser again and let's go to the Console.
Something now I want to introduce you to, is a built in JavaScript function, and that function is very
well known and it's called an alert.
Now, when you tell the computer you want to run an alert, the computer sometimes needs certain
parameters from us in order to understand, or in order to execute fully that function or
code. With an alert, you need to give it text because basically what you're telling the machine is that
you wanted to give the user an alert.
But what do you want to tell the user?
What is the alert all about?
So let's write "alert()", OK, and you'll see also later in this course, we go into functions and functions
have to ... in order to execute a function, you have to enclose it within these parentheses, these brackets.
So let's just alert the user "hello world".
Now, what do you think's going to happen when I push the return key or the enter key on a keyboard?
Yeah, well, yes, it's going to come up with the Alert tab that we all have learned to love to hate.
And there it is, my "hello world", and it comes up with an alert.
But check at this. If I push "Ok"
Check at the return value. Undefined.
What is that undefined?
Well, er, I'm going to share something with you now. It's awesome.
I'm going to drop some knowledge.
Let's check it out.
We ran the alert function and alert function is just one of many JavaScript commands.
So let's write it out on the screen.
And lets dissect it. Let's understand why the return value was undefined, and let's understand
this alert function, JavaScript function, in a bit more detail.
So the alert word we know that's just a special JavaScript function.
And I didn't have to go and write the machine code or tell the computer what to do because JavaScript
as a language has already done it for us.
Now remember, and we spoke about this earlier, every expression, and an alert is just an expression -
you're telling the computer what to do, in this case shown an alert,
it has to return something, and in this case, the alert hasn't returned anything.
And if it returns nothing in JavaScript, that just means undefined.
Simple as that.
And that's why that "undefined" word came up below our function call.
And most people will stop here, but I just want to go into a bit more detail just so you understand what
we're doing here.
In between the brackets, we've written "hello world". In JavaScript, and you're going to hear this in
other programming languages as well,
this is termed a string literal.
I know it's a weird thing to call it, but it is just called a string literal. Well, what is a string literal?
It's just a way of defining a kind of value called a string.
And what string? Well, a string is just text in programming.
I don't know why
we don't just call it text.
You know, why do we call a boat a boat?
I do not know, its just the way it is. And a string literal tells JavaScript that the text is data
and it's not part of the code. Otherwise,
how does JavaScript distinguish between the words we wrote there, the "alert" and "hello world".  Hello world is
not an inbuilt JavaScript function, its just words you and I have created. And putting it in those little
blue speech marks, tells JavaScript
"Hey, this is a string literal."
It's not part of the code, it is just data.
And yep, yeah, the brackets, the parentheses,
we've already said to execute a in JavaScript, you have to enclose it in parentheses.
It's just a rule that we have to remember.
And you can see here we ended the statement with a semicolon. Just like in English, when you have to
end every sentence with a period or a full stop, its
the same as JavaScript.
You have to end every statement with a semicolon.
Now strictly speaking
you don't have to use a semicolon.
It's just good practice to use a semicolon.
That's what I do.