So let's start at the basics.
Programming involves a lot of jargon and terminology, but don't panic
okay,
because once you understand the jargon, you'll find it surprisingly easy.
And what is programming?
Well, I mean, at the end of the day, programming is just a set of instructions that tells the computer
what to do.
And the good news for you and I, is that these instructions are in plain English, and these instructions
are just made up of tiny little commands.
Again, you can call them commands,
you can call them instructions
it doesn't matter.
And we refer to these commands or instructions as the programming syntax.
But I don't wanna
jump ahead.
We're going to get into syntax now and all that kind of stuff.
For now, I just want you to know that these commands are simple. Each command on its own is very simple,
and they're often the same for most different programming languages.
So whether you're programming in Java, C#, etc etc, a lot of them all have these same
little nuances.
So the benefit is, once you learn this, it's going to set you on a path of becoming an excellent programmer
in any language.
Just take a step back.
The important point that I want you to know from this, is that programming is just a set of instructions.
That's it. It's just English.
It's just words.
So when you get frustrated and you will, and when you start pulling your hair out, just step back
and go, You know what?
I've obviously got the wrong words.
I've obviously got the wrong syntax.
I'm putting a full stop where I shouldn't, or putting a colon where it shouldn't be.
And that's all I want you to get from this lecture.
So this lecture is ... programming is just a set of instructions to tell the computer what to do, and those
instructions are written in English.
Let's move on.