Before we move on, just a very quick example, remember how we just said that to invoke a function,
you need to include the double parentheses.
Well, what happens if you don't include the double parentheses?
Let me show you.
So let's define our function called wolf.
And all this does is console logs to the screen.
Now, if we don't include the parentheses.
What's going to happen?
Well, in this instance, it's not going to execute the function.
It will literally return the function itself to you.
So just bear that in mind, if you want to create instances of this function and put it into variables,
make sure you don't put parentheses behind because as soon as you put the parentheses behind it executes
their function shape.
If we go wolf and we put in parentheses, what's going to happen?
Well, it's going to console.log with the screen hope that makes sense.
But there's plenty more to go.
Let's get on with it.