Let's look at variables and how we create them in a bit more detail.
Remember in the previous lecture I said that using variables to store data is done in 3 distinct
steps.
Well, let's discuss those steps quickly.
The first step is you have to declare your variable.
And all that means is that the variable is registered in its corresponding scope.
And the scope of a variable is simply where the variable can be used.
Don't stress about scope yet, we're going to be talking about scope in more detail later.
The next step is initialization.
You've got to initialize that variable.
And this usually occurs at the same time the variables declared.
And all this means is that the variable is assigned in  memory.
It's assigned space by the JavaScript engine.
And when you initialize this variable, it takes a value of undefined.
Remember that undefined,
it's a primitive data type.
It takes that value until you assign a value to it.
And here is a practical example of a undefined variable.
Let's say we just make up a variable called animal, but we don't assign a value, meaning we don't have
an equal sign with
a value.
We just gonna declare a variable, this is what we've just done.
And now we go typeof(animal),
it is undefined.
So we've declared a variable. In the background, the parser has initiated that variable.
It's assigned memory space to the variable.
But at this point in time, it is undefined.
Which brings us to the third step, and that is assigning a value to that variable. And all that, that
means is that you literally put a value into that container.
You tell JavaScript that that variable is to have that value.
We've declared & initialized our variable called animal
in this case, how do we assign it a value?
It's easy.
Let's say our animal,
we just retype it out, because remember, it's been initialized
so there is memory space.
The parser knows that this is a variable, but let's assign it a value of
warthog.
And now, if we go to typeof(animal), we would expect to see ...
A string, which is what we've got. Hope its making sense.
Let's move on.