And I've mentioned that objects are a whole bunch of name value pairs.
I just want to stress this point again and drive it home and name an event and the name in the video
separated by column.
You've got your name on the left colon and your value on the right.
Let me give you an example.
And our member lives at 100 main unit three one on the third floor.
The address is the name and the actual location, the is the venue.
And again, it's separated by column, but we can represent this in another way.
You might want to separate it out.
What I mean?
Let me show you.
Let's take the address.
Let's open up a new object.
And now in the JavaScript engine sees those curly braces.
It's not an operator.
It's going to assume that that is an object.
So the address is going to be the name and the venue is going to be that entire object.
So let's separate it up the street as main.
Again, that's a name and a value.
Now we just put a comma in.
We've got no.
Which is the name.
Colon and then the value, which in this case is 100.
We can keep going on, but now we've got a unit.
This is another point I wanted to stress we can actually have nested objects and name value within an
object.
Yeah, we've got the floor third floor.
And then number three, oh, one again, Unity's name.
And that entire object is the value.
I hope this is starting to make sense.
It's just name value pays.
Let's move on.