We've had a look, an example, but let's dive a bit more into prototypes and what they actually are,
so becomes very intuitive for you.
Prototype is just a reference to another object.
That's all it is.
And remember, JavaScript is a prototype based language, so this means that all JavaScript objects,
inherent properties and methods from a prototype.
What I mean will take dates, take a rate?
What about even a custom object that we create user?
Well, they will inherit from the associated prototypes.
If they have one.
And all those prototypes, in turn, will inherit from the overall arching JavaScript object prototype.
Remember, we've even used that object that enable JavaScript object many times in our examples.
This is still a bit fuzzy.
Well, let me quickly should over to the console, and I'll show you what this prototype looks like.
OK, so remember we see the array inherits from the array prototype, and that in turn inherits from
the overarching object prototype.
That's have a look.
So this just creates a numbers, right?
And it's log up numbers we can see at the moment, it's an entire day, but if we open this up and we
dig deep into JavaScript construct, what do we see?
We'll remember how the Rays have this built in links properties, that's no surprise, but look, it's
got this protein and the school and the school protocol and the school and the school.
And it's inheriting from the array prototype.
And if we open this up, in turn, we get a whole lot of methods that we can access straight out of
the box.
And if we scroll to the bottom, we can see that this array prototype inherits from the object prototype,
which is what that is.
How cool is this?
And this is one our numbers here.
And say we just define it as one to nine hundred and five.
This is why we can access things like sort.
Like, we didn't have to Typekit we can just do it right out of the box.
And that's why it's because we got access to these prototypes, these methods and properties on our
array from somewhere else.
It's cool, right?
What about if creates an object?
So late, Obi Jay Equal.
The object.
And if we console.log out this object, yes, it's an empty object, but if we look at its JavaScript
construct, we can see it's inheriting from the prototype object.
Over starting to make sense, let's move on.