We know what an engine is, what it's meant to do.
So what's the engine that we should be looking at?
Well, you could say that there are 2 major engines that are interesting. And why do I say 2? Well, because they're
both leveraged by NativeScript.
And these two engines are 1) WebKit's JavaScriptCore and 2) Google's V8 Engine.
Now, I don't really want to get into JavaScriptCore because it is an engine that handles code a bit
differently.
The one that I think we must concentrate on is V8 because this is very powerful when it comes to Node
and JavaScript and it is really an awesome engine.
Google built the V8 engine. It's written in C++, and it also compiles and executes JavaScript
source code. And the engine is used inside Google Chrome.
Unlike the rest of the engines, however, V8 is also used for the popular Node.js runtime.
V8 was first designed to increase the performance of JavaScript execution inside the web browsers
and in order to obtain speed, because speed is everything you can agree with me,
V8 translates JavaScript code into more efficient machine code instead of just using a normal interpreter.
It actually compiles the code into machine code at execution by implementing a Just-In-Time compiler
like a lot of modern JavaScript engines do, such as SpiderMonkey or Rhino, which is Mozilla's engine by
the way.
The main difference here, though, is that V8 doesn't produce bytecode or any intermediate code.
It actually translates JavaScript into machine code
directly. And what's really cool about V8 is it can be embedded into any C++ application, and this
makes it incredibly powerful because C++ was designed to talk with your machine and to do server side
tasks.
And as we know, JavaScript came from a beginning
where it was only designed for browsers.
So what this means is you can take your JavaScript, run it through the V8 engine, or your C++ program, and
you can literally convert that into machine code on the fly.
How awesome is that?