We've seen that objects have a special hidden property called prototype.
And again, don't be intimidated by those double square brackets.
All that means is that in the specification, it's a hidden property.
And this prototype is either now or it references another object and this other object is called a prototype.
It's a very quick example.
This just creates a use object.
And we've done this many times before.
This user has a name, age and an online status so we can determine whether he's currently on line or
not.
And when we console this out and we see the JavaScript construct, you'll notice we've been seeing prototype
or underscore school and the school proto underscore underscore.
And that prototype references another prototype object, and that other prototype object is an automatic
object hasn't been set up by you and I.
Let's get set up by the JavaScript engine.
And that's exactly why we have these other methods on our objects when we create them straight out of
the box like to string value off and the others that we've even used throughout our examples.
But let's jump deeper into this rabbit hole.
It's not only one type of prototype in JavaScript, and this causes so much confusion, and it is complicated
because it's weird.
It's just, you know, JavaScript, one of those languages that have kind of evolved over the years.
But through all of this is some weird nuances that pop up, and it can be complicated to understand
unless you just break it down.
And hopefully, after this, you'll understand the differences between the two.
OK, so the two prototypes in JavaScript one is the full word prototype and the other one is prototype
in square brackets or what's known as underscore, underscore Kroto.
And the school and the school is look at this prototype.
This is a spatial object that is created as a property of all functions, and this happens automatically
for all functions.
And this is the same object that is pointed to by and the school and the school project and has gone
to school by that other type of prototype.
Which brings me on to the other type of prototype.
This is a hidden property on every object that is created, and it can be accessed in script, using
and school and the school project and the school and the school.
And I know this can be confusing.
So let's just take a step back and let's create an object literal and let's call it food.
Let's set a property called yummy to it, and that yummy has a value of true.
So these are custom food object with one property.
OK, but this time, let's create a constructor function.
Let's call that carrot, and it just sits this color, which is passed into that function as a property
type and all this function does.
This sits a color Typekit to the newly created object.
So now we've got our custom correct function.
Let's set the prototype on this carrot to food.
What do you think is going to happen now?
We're going to create a new variable.
Let's call it carrot.
And we use the new keyword to execute their constructor function.
We'll remember what happens when we use the new keyword.
Well, firstly, it creates a new empty object.
Then it will go and look at the function carrot.
It will then take any prototype on the correct object and see that as the prototype property of the
newly created object.
Lastly, it then feeds the object into the newly created Keret constructor as this keyword and it returns
whatever the function returns.
It's kind of long story short.
All it does is it sets the proto property of the newly created character to the food object.
So taking a step back, what this means is that prototype is a regular property and.
And a school and a school project and a school and a school is the inheritance of character from food.
So look at this diagram.
Let it sink in and then let me show you one more example before we move on.