Whitespace, what do I mean by whitespace?
Well, I mean, spaces and tabs.
Do you think JavaScript cares about that?
Well, let's have a look.
So let's define a variable called myName, and you can see we've got whitespace before and after the
equals sign.
What about a tab?
Let's try that.
What about a whole new line entirely?
let myName = newline Clyde.
Yes, it looks terrible
but will this work from a JavaScript point of view? And the short answer is ... yes.
Under all three of those scenarios, if you had to console.log myName, you would get the correct result.
You would get a string with an output "Clyde".
So the good news is that JavaScript, like most modern languages, does not care about whitespace.
The interpreter automatically reformats all the whitespace.