So you starting to wrap your head around programming, what it is.
Garbage in, garbage out that it's a set of instructions executed line by line.
And we did mention this thing called "syntax".
Syntax is just another word, or another way to say how we write these instructions to a computer.
You know, I'm speaking English now.
I've got to structure my sentences in a certain way.
We need a full stop at the end of each sentence.
Well, with some programming languages, they want you to put a semicolon at the end of each instruction,
at the end of each command.
It's the same thing right?
So instead of putting a full stop at the end of each sentence, you put a semicolon.
Some programming languages, all uppercase, some languages are all lowercase and yes, some languages
just don't care.
So the question you're probably asking is "Well Clyde, tell me the syntax for JavaScript?"
We're gonna get there.
For now, just understand what syntax is.
And that most languages or most modern languages are trying to move away from very strict syntax.
And where does JavaScript fit into this?
Well, JavaScript cares ... a little. So its very forgiving, but there are some certain rules that you do
need to be familiar of, and we're going to get into those.