So objects are a whole bunch of name and value piece.
We were just discussing a minute ago about what an object is, and we concluded that an object is just
about everything.
So what does this mean?
Let me give you an example before we start coding and you might be thinking, Nah, man, you know,
we went through variables.
Why do we even need objects illustrated by an example?
So has Wally.
We've got his details and remember how he had his details and variables.
Named Ballons favorites logged in all as well.
But what happens when you've got thousands of users on your website?
And if you randomly pick a container from your pantry, how do you know who that belongs to?
And even if we look at the variable name, it could be multiple Walleys on your website.
So how do you know that Dick Cheney is actually the one related to these containers?
Well, this week objects come into it, and what I mean by that is you almost have to ring fence all
these variables.
And put a label on it and say, this is the general look and feel for every person on our website.
Once you've done that, you can assign variables and you can create multiple instances of this person.
So for all one key example here, this is a real person on our site.
You can ringfence him and you can say that he's an instance of a person object.
And in the heading, it sees an object is just a whole bunch of name value pays.
That's all that this means.
So his balance of funds is a name, and the values that he for is he logged on to the site.
It's the name of the variable and then knows the value.
So you can see objects and variables all kind of related.
You can actually say objects are a whole bunch of variables within it.
And how do we create this new Wally object?
Well, if we define the structure being a person object, all we need to use is the new keyword and
we're going to be getting into the new keyword later.
But just understand when you do that, you've literally created a new object, a new instance of that.
And yeah, we've defined it into a variable called Wally.
Don't worry if you don't understand too much or if I'm losing you a little bit, you're going to get
so familiar with this by the end of the section.
Just take a step back, take a deep breath and just remember all an object is this it's a way to store
your daughter.
And because we can still dots an easy way, it makes it easy for us to access their daughter as well.
It's all an object is don't get lost in all the detail.
Let's move on.