In the old school way, how was this problem resolved?
And the answer is drum roll.
And the problem of having to reload pages every time you can't into a speech from a server, the way
that that problem was solved was by technologies allowing web pages to request smaller chunks of data
like HTML, eczema or Jason, or even just plain text, and allowing these browsers to then only display
their text or that resource or their daughter we needed.
And how do we achieve this?
What kind of technologies can we use?
Well, we can use many APIs, such as XML, hp request.
This is the heart of Ajax.
This is where it all began.
We've got new ones such as the fetch API, and these techniques are known as using Ajax.
And can you guess what Ajax stands for?
I'll give you a clue.
That's right, it stands for asynchronous JavaScript and Exmouth.
And as I just mentioned originally, it mainly used the example a sheet of object to request ex email
data, hence the word and Ajax that extends, for example.
But these days, don't stress about eczema because you're more likely to use the same object the eczema
LHP request object or the feature API.
Both of those, we're going to be using him to fetch JSON, not eczema.
Alex emails old school.
But the results are still the same way that we fetch Ajax, H.
Jamaal, Jason or even plain text, and this is why the term Ajax has stuck around.
But if you're anything like me, you probably want to see this visually anime trial.
Let me do my best.
Yeah, you've got your browser and your server, just like we had before.
And in the middle, we've got this technology called Ajax.
And how does this help us?
Well, your browser now sends a request, but it doesn't send it to the server directly.
It sends it via Ajax.
Ajax then sends and http request in the background.
The server does its job, does its business, and then it sends and HTP responds.
And then Ajax provides that data to the browser.
But what is so awesome is that whole process of the HTTP request and the response, you guessed it,
it happens in the background without us having to wait for page reloads.
How awesome that.
But wait, there's more.
To speed things up even further.
Most sites today also store assets and data on your own computer's hard drive on your computer's database.
And how does this work?
Well.
Very simplistically at a high level, what happens is when you request a website for the very first
time, a lot of those assets that are from the server will be stored on your computer in a database,
meaning that next time you visit that same site on subsequent visits, you are able to use local versions
of the data instead of downloading fresh copies all the time.
And it also means that content is only reloaded from the server when they thought on the server has
been updated.
So how does this look?
Well, your browser cannot request data from a database, your computer will then ask, does daughter
need to be updated?
Has Dot have been updated on the server?
If it hasn't, the simple solution is it can just send that data straight back to your browser.
This results in a very fast load paging time.
This is awesome.
This is why many sites you visit.
It's almost instantaneous.
OK, but now say that the data does need to be updated.
What's going to happen next?
Well, the first check your computer has to do is Well, are you online or not?
Let's say you're not online.
Well, in that case, unfortunately, the database is just going to send you the data it has, and you're
still going to be looking at outdated data.
Cool.
I think we've got that under wraps.
What about now if your computer is online, the database is going to send a request to Ajax to this
technology piece sitting in the middle.
Ajax will then send an HTTP request to the server.
The server will do its business.
It's going to send an HTP response when it's ready.
Ajax will store the data in the database, but now it's updated data and that will be sent back to your
browser.
So I know the screen looks a bit funky right now, and there's a lot on there, but I hope you're gaining
an understanding of how this all works at a very high level, at least.
We're going to get into more detail shortly, though, so be with me.