I know approvato and prototype are confused often.
So that's why I wanted to dedicate another example just to help solidify your understanding of these
two concepts.
Let's have a look.
The first thing I want to show you is protein and the school and the school project and the school and
the school.
Let's see how that works.
Let's define the use of our website.
It's just say it's got one property, which is false, and that is, is this person a member or not?
Now, let's create a guest user.
And say the issues user has a name of Wally.
Now what all prototypes we've kind of seen, the prototypes are just referencing another object and
allows one object to use properties and methods define on another object.
That's what it is.
It's almost like delegation.
So let's now take our guest user and set its prototype to the user object.
One way to do that is we can access the global object.
We can use an inbuilt method called prototype of and we want to set the prototype of this user to user.
Now, this means our guest user automatically has access to the member property, and if we consolidate
lock out, we get false, which is what we sit on the main user object.
So this is fine.
This is intuitive and this is what prototypes are all about.
If we console.log guest user out to the screen and we open up its object, we get this photo here,
which is an object and we open it up and then object.
You can see now has a property of no false.
So this protein is actually referencing the exact same object of user.
And in fact, it's not creating a replica of it.
It is literally the same object.
So it just means if I go now and I change user, if I change the user and add a property called age.
It's actually now going to have updated the proto-Earth biggest user ID to prove it.
All we have to do is go to use this user and let's just console.log this protocol up to the screen directly.
There you go.
It's updated, it's Friday, which is now an object consisting of both member and age.
OK, so that's pretty kind of intuitive, right?
What about prototype?
What is that about?
OK, well, let's start having a look.
Let me just clear the console.
This creates an empty function.
This will help illustrate prototypes.
It's a function call.
And this just says empty.
Then on this call function, it's safe to prototype and let's set the prototype.
This is called property of sound.
We can make it whatever we want.
And let's say that sound has a value of through.
OK, this is the first time we've defined our object.
Second step to construct functions is that we have to call it by using the new keyword.
So let's just define my call equals new call.
And then we know that Michael has access to the sound property.
And remember what the new key word does here.
This is why I just want to emphasize it once again, the new keyword creates an empty object.
Just a simple object.
It will then encounter that call function and relook at that call functions prototype and to set the
properties of the newly created object to be that prototype.
Then what I'll do is I'll pass in the newly created object into the call function, and then this keyword
will point to itself the my call object.
That's kind of what happens in the background, and this is the only reason why this prototype property
exists, it exists.
So when we use the new keyword, it's able to sit the proto of the newly created object.
We kind of get us.
Let me prove it to you.
Let's take our Michael and its console look at prior to.
What would you expect to see?
What is its price to remember what we said, it's proto will be the prototype.
We sit on the function call.
And it is it sound from.
But do you think our call is going to have its own prototype?
Let's have a look.
Prototype.
Undefined, it doesn't have a prototype, and this is the point I'm trying to make.
Only functions as prototypes, and it's only there.
So when we use the new keyword, it can set the prototype of that to the prototype of the function and
functions, automatically get prototypes and show you another example.
Let's create a function called bike.
And let's go back to prototype.
There you go.
Its prototype is an object, it does have a prototype, this is the point I'm trying to make.
What about objects?
Objects don't have prototype.
It's only these functions for these scenarios.
Can you give you another example?
Lit.
I'm trying to think of another.
We've used car we used like this used jet.
And let's just say that is an empty object.
Does it have a prototype?
No doesn't have a prototype because it's not a function, but it does have protein.
But ways that project from Limit will first show you that it has a protein protein.
These it's protest, what protest is that?
And we had to come from all defining an object like this is the same as us.
Going legit equals new object.
So what it's doing and we've used the new keyword here.
This is a function.
And remember, the Kroto of G8 is going to be set to the prototype of this global object.
So it's no surprise.
The G8 does have a protocol, and I can prove that it's a global object is what we can do is we can
go.
On so long.
Jade Trotter.
Does it equal the object prototype?
And it's true it does equal now exactly the same thing, it's referencing that prototype of the global
object.
And this means and I know it's going to sound very strange, but this means the actual global object
is a function.
I improve it's a function by executing it.
You got a function.
Amazing.
So to recap and the school and the school proto and the school and the school is available and objects,
and all that's doing is it's referencing the prototype of another object.
It's all under school and the school and the school and the school is in prototype, which we've just
seen.
Well, that is only available on functions, and it only exists because we like using the new hewould
crew.
I hope this is starting to make sense.
But don't worry if it is confusing.
I mean, a lot of people struggle with these concepts in JavaScript.
Let's continue.