We have three broad categories of meetings on arrays.
Let's have a look at an example of each of them.
So as we just did in the lecture, let's look at mutate.
Mrs.
And remember, these methods alter the original array.
So let's create an array, let's just call it members for lack of a better word, and let's has five,
10, 50 in that array.
And let's use the push method.
The push method is a mutating method, and it's push the number 20 on this.
It's console log numbers.
Whoosh.
And it says here in my IDs, really giving me a tootsie that returns the new length of the array and
it's pushed the number 20 onto this.
Now the race is going to have length for so an I console.log up numbers, it's going to have four numbers
now it has affected the actual original rate.
What's another example?
Let's work with colors.
Let's say the original.
Colours of blue and green.
But let's say someone else comes along and wants to create amended colours, but they want to start
off with these colours is like the base point.
So let's say the mandate comes along and they want to use the original as a starting point, but they
want to push another colony red.
Now, when a console.log original artist speak to only see blue and green, then I'm sure as a guest
that's when I log in arts and actually has now read.
So with this mutation, with this push, mean it does affect the original right.
Just be careful with it because you might mess up original data that you weren't intending to do.
Another method is access and methods.
Let's have a look at that now quickly, and you just copy this up here.
It's good, and to top it all again and being lazy and just call this excessive.
An excess of methods, a nice because it allows us not to manipulate the original array, but to create
a copy of the original array and then manipulate that.
It's quite cool to have a look at.
Let's define an array of names and it, said John.
Wally.
And Cindy.
Now, one access and method available to us is known as slice and slice just returns a specified portion
of the array.
Show you what I mean.
No.
So let's just say coffee equals names.
It's our original array.
We want to access a slice method, and you can see my ID is already telling us what the two arguments
are.
The start is the beginning of the specified portion of the range end, which specifies when there needs
to end.
So let's just return, say we want to return just Wally and Cindy.
We didn't want to involve John in all of this.
So here we can start at one.
And end at three.
Now, if we console.log that out, we've got Wally and Cindy uncles.
But I mean, if I console.log up names.
Names has kept its original form of having three people in it.
There's an excessive method.
What about a iterator metered iterator method, as we said, just iterates through an array and allows
you to do things with a certain value each time and iterate through that array.
It's a bit of a mouthful, but again, it's much easier to understand with an example.
So let's give you an example here of an iterator method.
And a very popular one that you are going to be using, and I'll probably even do a whole section on
it, if not a whole section, definitely one or two full on episodes is the map method.
Now there's a lot we can talk about with the map methods.
I'm not going to do it.
I'm just going to show you very briefly how it works and when it's right, admitted meet.
And let's create an array of animals.
And let's just say we've got a dog.
And a cat.
I want to make it too long, and now I just want to create a it's a right, an animal iterator.
Let's just call it animal iterator.
And we can access all our original array, and we're going to use this map method.
OK?
And as you can see in my I.D., this map method calls a callback function on each element of an array
and by element of an array.
We just saying the dog in the cat.
In this case, those are called elements.
So a function is going to be called returning a dog and returning a cat, etc etc.
Don't worry about callback functions yet, we're going to get into these things later.
So the first argument in this map method is the callback function.
You can even see that in my I.D., it's telling.
So let's define callback function that takes the element.
Which in our case, is an animal.
It's a type of animal type.
And they must do something with the animal type.
So in our case, this just console.log.
The statement that's used template literals and it say, I don't know.
And we are dealing with a.
And then you can literally take that animal on.
Who?
And look at what's just happened.
You can see the console says we're dealing with a dog, we're dealing with a cat.
So that's what the map makes.
It does.
It takes each element of your right.
So in the first iteration, on the first loop, it's going to take dog.
It's going to put that dog into that callback function, and it's going to name that it's going to put
that dog into a variable called animal type.
And then we just do whatever we please will it?
In this case, we've just done a simple console log message of that animal type.
But this doesn't affect the original array.
If I type animals, we've still got our dog and cat are nothing to it.
It's just a method that allows us to iterate through an array.
We've gone through a lot.
Well done.
Hope is starting to make sense.
See you soon.