Once we have a date, we have both methods we can use on that date and the methods we return a part
of the date we're interested in, how do we access these methods?
Well, each of these methods will begin with drum roll.
This shoot over to visual studio code and show you a few examples.
So let's have a look at some of these gitte methods.
Gates methods, and I'm going to try to make it a bit practical here because I know these things can
get a bit theoretical.
Let's say we want to create a user's birthday.
And let's say on this website we've designed, when you sign up, you ask for your birthday, your month
and your day, and let's just say this user puts 15th January.
Five.
First thing we need to do to remember is what?
Yes, we need to use the new keyword and let us now establish his birthday into a variable.
So let's say late birthday equals new date.
And remember, one of the ways to create a date was to be very specific.
We could put in the year, the day, the month.
So let's do that, 1985.
Let's say it's January, and remember, January starts at zero.
It's why I keep stressing January, and it's just it's the 15th of the month.
Now we've got the user's birthday and his birthday variable.
I'll prove it to you, we can talk Thursday.
And the it is on the screen, it's you, some get me, it's not, let's say we want to get the day of
the month.
How would we do this?
Well, let's see our result by using console.log.
The first thing we need to do is exercise our variable date variable.
Now we want to use one of these great methods.
And for the day you used date and you can even see here the I.D. Visual Studio code is really giving
me a head that says get dates is the day of the month using local time.
So I can do that, and the 15th, which is 15th of January.
What about if we wanted to get the year?
Let's try this again.
We need the birthday variable and get full, here's the method in 1995, so you can see how easy it
is to use these gifts to access different things.
What about the month gift month?
I'm sure you know how to do this now.
Console.log, we is our birthday variable and we get month.
And its era, which we know is January.
But remember, we don't any of gates.
We've also got six.