We've seen it objects consist of a whole bunch of name value pairs, but what are these names and what
are these values?
Well, again, take a step back and object can only contain two things.
That's it.
So complicated properties and methods.
What do I mean by that?
Well, let's just take the simple HTML button.
What are the properties of their button properties or things like width and height?
What are methods?
I like to think of methods as doing words, so for example, when we're talking about a button, it
could be on click events or even on your keyboards when you click enter or even when you take your mouse
and you hover over that HMO button, those events or methods attached to the object.
Cool.
So we've seen objects consists of properties and methods.
What do we mean?
Let's start typing code.
And it say we have a bike.
One of the ways to create an object is to you've got to sneeze coming.
This for men, one will know.
I'm done.
Hey, sorry.
So let's create an object.
And this is object back.
Think about an object as a big container.
And it said to make about bike is Yamaha.
Hello is blue.
It's got wheels, the two of them.
So we've done properties now, but remember, objects consists of properties and methods.
Method is more for doing words, something that happens.
So this defining method, let's call it sound and oldest method does is it creates sound.
Let's say we just console.log.
There you have it, an object consists of properties, the property has the mate, the colour, the
wheels and methods.
Yeah, we've just created a sound method.
But how do we exercise these properties and methods?
What do we do to extract it?
Let's have a look.