Working with daughter is extremely important when it comes to programming, and a lot of the things
we've been doing at the moment have been us storing data and we've be putting it into objects.
We've been defining variables, we've been creating arrays.
But what about accessing those values?
You know, you can think if you have an application with thousands of users, they're giving you daughter.
But at some point you are going to want to extract their data and display it, to use it, to perform
calculations on it.
And this is way looping becomes vital.
And here we are talking about looping through objects, but just bear in mind.
An array is actually an object as well.
You can loop through objects and you can loop through arrays.
But once you have an array of vanilla array and by vanilla just means you've got a whole string of values.
Once you've got to that point, it becomes very easy to loop through it.
So that's why I wanted to start with objects, a more complicated object that you've defined, how do
we loop through that?
And you'll often find yourselves in a situation where you want to loop through your object.
And the only way to do so before is six was with a four inch loop.
And I'll show you an example of a in new shortly, but let me just say this a better way and then better
ways to convert your object into an array.
And then you can just loop over there because looping over an array is very easy now.
So how can we convert our object into an array?
Well, there are three very popular methods object keys, object values and object entries.
Object or keys creates an array that contains only the property names, a.k.a. the keys of the object.
Object values.
You probably guessed it already.
That creates an array that contains the value of each property within the object.
An object entries just gives you an array, but not this time.
You've got both the key and the value that always creates an array of arrays.
But I'll show you what this means shortly.
OK, so let's take a step back.
We start off with a complicated object.
We then convert that object into an array and we can use one of these three methods that we've just
discussed to do that.
And now we can loop through this array as if it were a normal vanilla array.
And we do this with the.
Full of loot, the full of loop is awesome, and it's a much easier way to loop through elements of
an array.
Let me give you an example and just quickly show you how this full of loop works.
It say we define a whole lot of fruit trees and it is an array.
It's a banana and a manga simple.
So what does a full of loop do?
Well, it's loops through each key.
And what I mean by key here, you key in this case in that array is banana.
On the second iteration, that key is going to be Manga.
For Const. Key, it's going to take the key of the array, but now without us doing anything else on
this for of loop, how does it know to use the fruit keys array?
Well, this way the second argument comes in you have to tell this array Hey, find each key of the
fruit keys array.
Then you open up this full of loop with the curly braces and we can do whatever we want with that key
because we know on each loop that key is going to be in the first instance banana and on the second
instance, mango.
So in this instance, a simple console, low key, we'll just console.log Banana on the first iteration
and then on the second iteration root console Mango.
Let's have a look at some more examples now.