Before we go further, you need to understand that JavaScript is a scripting language, and what I mean
by this is that JavaScript cannot run on its own.
In fact, the browser is responsible for running JavaScript code. And we alluded to this earlier and I
have mentioned it before,
that JavaScript is an interpreted language, which means that it's run on the browser. It's run on the
computer's machine on the fly.
So when a user requests an html page with JavaScript in it, the script is sent to the browser.
It is then up to the browser to execute that (JavaScript) code.
And of course, we know the main advantages of JavaScript is that all modern web browsers support JavaScript.
So you don't have to worry about whether your site visitor uses Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox,
Safari, JavaScript will be supported.
And the good news is that JavaScript also runs on any operating system, including Windows, Linux,
Mac, and we are going to be talking about engines, JavaScript engines, these things that run JavaScript
code in the browser.
But you know, engines can be complicated, but the basics of engines are easy.
But anyway, I don't want to get into much detail now on engines.
I just wanted you to understand JavaScript is a scripting language and it cannot be run on its own.
It has to be run by an engine on the browser.