When we program, we are giving the computer instructions to process one line at a time in the order
that we give the computer those instructions. And just so you're aware, there is an old phrase in this
industry, in many industries actually, called GIGO.
But basically, it stands for "Garbage In, Garbage Out". And in programming languages, we write these
instructions by writing what are called "statements", and these statements are kind of like sentences
in English. And you can imagine if I go "didly didly dillydoo click uh oheeeh",
That means nothing, and it's the same as programming languages.
The computer is going to process
what you give it. If you give it junk, it's just going to throw it back at you.
But at the end of the day, I just wanted you to be familiar with this terminology.