The console object gives you access to the browser's Console, we've just seen that, and it allows us
developers to log certain results and alerts and warnings to the screen.
But what is the console?
How did we have that method available to us?
Well, you need to understand the Window object.
That's where it came from.
And the console is part of the Window object.
What's the Window object?
Well, the Window object is supplied by what's known as the Browser Object Model,
or you can say BOM for short - the Browser Object Model.
And the BOM allows JavaScript to talk to the browser about things other than the content of the page.
So yes, JavaScript can interact directly with what the user is looking at on the web page,
but there's also other information that the browser's Window gives us.
What other information?
Well things like navigator, screen, location history, etc.
The Window object is the root element of the whole website.
Think about the king sitting on his throne and all his peasants and subjects beneath him.
The king, in this case, is the Window object that defines everything that you and I can do on a web
page, more than just manipulate its content.
And I know it's difficult to actually picture
so let me let me try and just draw a picture for you.
I hope it helps.
Let's picture the whole universe of the browser and the web page and everything, the little tabs and
everything, in this blue box.
And at the very top of this box, you've got the Window.
And that's the entire browser.
That's what I'm trying to say - that it defines the whole universe. And this Window provides two broad categories
of functionality to us. It provides us with the document.
And by document, I mean, it's the website
we're actually looking at. Titles on the screen, buttons we can click on, etc.
The other thing it gives us, though, is things like I mentioned, the navigator, location, screen,
the history, etc.
And I hope this sinks in because this is an awesome aspect of JavaScript in the console and how things
fit in with each other that most people don't understand.
And I'm sharing some awesome knowledge here - things that taken me a long time to learn.
So I hope you appreciate it. Anyway,
moving on, moving on.
So we know what the Window object is, and each browser tab has its own Window object.
So when you've got two different tabs open in your browser, they can't share each other's objects.
The one has a Window object and the other one has an entirely different Window object.
The other thing worth mentioning here is that there are no standards for the Browser Object Model. You know,
like for JavaScript, we've got the standard ECMAScript.
Well, there are no standards for the BOM, and the whole HTML document
you know, where we type our HTML code, headers, bodies, paragraphs, etc
That is a property of the Window object.
Remember, because the Window object is king. And a very useful Window object is ... and you guessed it, the
Window's console.
And you can access the objects of a Window (object) by using the dots.
So "window.console" would be how to access the console object.
But remember, we didn't type "window.".
We just typed console.
And that's true for Windows objects.
You don't have to write window dot. So it's exactly the same if we just wrote the word console.