Consider this a bonus lecture, because we're going to go on a bit of a tangent, but I think it's very
important to understand and is a very good example of what we've been talking about.
So taking a step back, we've seen that for many years, different browsers have only followed a small
parts of the specifications set by the W3C.
And this meant that browsers had different rules in some browsers, followed certain HTML and CSS code,
and others didn't.
So that's the first problem.
The second problem is we've also got other standards like Ignace script and all all the script.
And of course, the problem again, is twofold.
One, certain browsers don't follow all of ActionScript recommendations and to the script gets updated.
Same as with the W3C specifications.
So over time, new functions and new methods get created.
So what does this mean?
Well, this means all the browsers don't understand the code of the new rules.
Makes sense, right?
And this is why we mentioned polyphenols in the previous lecture.
So what is a polyphenol will at its very core?
It's very simple.
The polyphenols just a piece of code that provides a fallback.
If certain features don't exist within that browser's engine.
In JavaScript, Landis will be in that browser's JavaScript engine, but it doesn't have to be JavaScript.
And this is important.
Many people think of poly falls just for JavaScript, but you also get policies for HTML and CSS code,
which will also get into tiny bit more later.
But we are going to focus on this JavaScript piece because this is what's interesting and this is what's
more complicated when it comes to death.
Now, police also usually follow a pattern, and the pattern starts with a simple question Does the
feature exist within the browser?
And if the answer's yes, well, then we don't need a poly for.
We can just resort to the browser's engine to handle that certain HTML, CSS or JavaScript.
It gets more interesting.
Of course, if the feature doesn't exist within the browser and this is where we have to use a poly
for.
Keeping track of the ever evolving age, HTML five inches is three support in today's way, browsers
can be an overwhelming task and it can be pretty daunting.
Sure, we can all use awesome CSS animations to create some whiz bang effects, but should we?
And which browsers support that certain feature?
And what do we do about all the browsers that don't understand that code?
And of course, this is where Polly Falls come into the picture and the website, and this is just one
of many HTML5, please.
It's useful for finding policies that do a particular job, as Jamal sliced these up as a whole list
of HTML5 elements and SEISS three rules with an overview of browser support and any poly falls for each
elements listed.
Before we move on, I just want to say we did mention Babel as an example of a for not Babel was more
targeted at JavaScript.
To remind you, ActionScript version six was a major update of JavaScript.
They brought new features and lots of some tactical additions, but iOS six was later renamed to iOS
12 15.
And this was just done to reflect the changes in the release cycle.
So when we use Babel, if you want to support Internet Explorer, for example, or you'd like to use
the latest ActionScript features in a browser that doesn't support it yet, then we use Babel, who
I know we're going through a lot, but nothing is better than with an example.
So why don't we build our own file?
Then that'll help you understand how these things work.
And today, let's implement our own poly file for the arrays for each method.
This was introduced in JavaScript one point six or eight script for sedition.
In reality, for each is a very well supported feature today, but I've chosen it more for the fact
that it's fairly simple to reconstruct, and I can walk you through building this party for step by
step.
But I should note at this point that this implementation is by no means going to be fully fledged comprehensive
one that's just going to be a way for you to really solidify understanding of what a Polyvore is.
So if you really wanted to get into the nitty gritty of certain polyphenols for certain functions,
I recommend visiting Mozilla Documentation Network.
Or indeed, I'll put a link at the end of this lecture.
OK, so we've just said we're going to be building our own for each poly full and remember what the
first step was?
What is the first question a polypill has to ask in order for it to be implemented?
That's right.
Does the browser support that feature?
So the first step is let's check to see with for each method is natively supported by our browser.
Let's go have a look.