We know we have to insert JavaScript between the script tag and recall, I mentioned that there are two broad
categories of how you can actually execute your JavaScript.
The one is called inline - and that just means you don't have an external file,
you write your JavaScript within the index.html file.
Well, what I mean by inline, what do I mean by that?
Well, let's have a look. Let's say you've got an
HTML document.
Listen, for the sake of simplicity, I'm just going to ignore the opening HTML tags, the header tags
and the body tags.
So let's just get to the meat of HTML.
Say you've got a paragraph called Hello Wally.
And you want to write JavaScript in your HTML.
All you need to do is have your script tags, and let's write a simple JavaScript alert.
This is an alert from JavaScript.
We close the script tag.
That means the end of your JavaScript, and then you can continue writing your normal HTML.
This is inline JavaScript.
That's all it is.
It is literally that simple.
Now, in this case, what do you think would happen?
Because remember, the browser engine
it interprets your code from top to bottom.
So intuitively, you might think you should see on your browser window
Hello, Wally.
And then an alert comes up and then you'll see Hello again, Wally.
Well, you'll get an unexpected result here because the alert is not triggered by any JavaScript event.
So that alert function will fire as soon as the DOM is loaded.
And don't worry about what the DOM is, I'm going to get into this later.
Just think about the DOM as your actual document, your whole web page and all the HTML tags that go
along with it.
That's the one category of how you can execute JavaScript on your page.
What's the second category?
The second category is external JavaScript. And it's all exactly the same, but the only one difference
is you include a source attribute. That source attribute just tells the browser engine where to find
that external file.
And then what's interesting is that external file will have to then write that alert.
Hope it's making sense, but we're going to see a lot more in depth details coming up.