No decision on dates.
I want to just go through some practical examples and some real life things you might encounter, and
you're not going to understand all the pieces, how they fit in, how we extract variables from the
use and all that.
Again, worry about that later.
For now, just understand what it is we're doing and I want you to cut along with me.
So I want to show you three quick examples.
One is, and we've already seen part of it.
It uses birthday.
I want us to display a message to the user only if it's his birthday, you know, it's his birthday.
If you want to that you want to put the guy up a little bit, he said.
How would you do that?
The second thing I want to go through with you is what if we want to use UTC time?
So it's just the world standard in calculating time and clocks in managing that whole process.
What about if you didn't want to use the uses local machines time?
Thirdly, what if you wanted to reformat dates?
Let's look at some of these examples.
Well, let's start with what you want to display iMessage with the users first.
How do we do that?
Was a few things I think we would need.
We would need the current date, the current month.
In the current day, it would need to compare that to the user's birthday day and birthday month.
And if those two are the same, we want to show the message if they're not the same.
We do nothing.
Let's clear this up, and hopefully it makes more sense.
So, yeah, you can see we've got a blank sheet that's not coding.
School this birthday example, the very first thing you need to assume you've got is the birthday details
of the user.
And like before, let's create a variable.
How do we do the dates again?
It's right.
We're got to use the new keyword, the date and yeah, we said we want it to be 1985.
January, which starts at zero in on the 15th.
So that's the USA's birthday.
Now, let's extract the uses month and the use of Birthdays Day.
It's extracts.
Birthday month.
And.
Birthday day, you can use whatever words you want.
I know I'm not the best at using words, so even if you cut in along with me, you can call your variables
more intuitive names.
I'm just going to call mine, use a birthday month.
And we've got the birthday variable.
And remember those date methods?
It months.
This will return.
We'll turn the month of the user's birthday, which is zero, and we can test it by logging it out onto
a log.
And there it is, Sarah.
So we've got the month.
Let's not get the day, use a birthday day.
Let's access again.
Birthday variable.
Dictator, remember, turns the day.
Will return date, thank.
Of birthday.
Which is 15.
And I can prove it to you by logging it out.
And it is 15, so now we've got the user's details.
But now let's get the current date.
And it's cool that now equals new date.
Let's extract the current month and the current date.
Current.
Length equals now eight months.
And to get the day current day.
Excess that now variable, which is stored, which has thawed the now date, and we want to get the
day.
So now we've got the current month, the current day, all we need to do is display a message of those
to match to the user's birthday.
How do we do that?
Well, in JavaScript, you've got an if statement and it's very intuitive.
We're going to get into the latest.
I'm not going to get into it now, but you'll see even the syntax like it makes sense.
So now let's start the section where we display usage.
If the current month.
And De equals the users.
So let's start an if.
And this is built in JavaScript, so we don't have to code all the intricacies behind this statement.
We have to open parentheses and all we have to define the condition, the condition is we want the dates
to match.
So the current month.
We want to make that equal to what?
Well, this right to the user's birthday month.
And we have to use the ampersand here.
What else do we want?
We want the current day to be equal to the user's birthday.
I'm sorry, I put there should be once.
And if this is true, this is what the if statement will do to commerce and we've been through coercion
occurs this whole statement, and if it's true, it will execute the code in the following block.
That is the case we want to console.
Happy.
Are you amped?
You are all.
Happy birthday.
But if it's not true, if it's not the USA's birthday, we want to do nothing.
And for the sake of completeness, let's just say console.log, let's do nothing.
It's not.
The USA's birthday.
Who?
OK, so we've been through this whole example, and you can see how it's starting to make seems like
it's going to hopefully get a lot more practical and real for you.
So let's see what's happened here.
The birthday of the user is 1985 that we don't care about.
So we want to know what is his actual birthday, and all we need for that is his month and his day of
birth.
The month is January and the day is 50.
What is the current month now?
We'll show you until log current month.
Current month now.
Is April.
That's why the number three is coming up in the current day.
It's the 14th of April.
So what this means is that when we're looking at that, if Block and the JavaScript engine coerces or
ceases or executes or evaluates that statement, current month equals user's birthday month and current
day equals birthday day, that's good cause to false.
So then all statements are going to be executed, which is why we see that what does get cancelled is
let's do nothing.
It's not the user's birthday.
It makes sense.
But now let's change the user's birthday to match the current month in current day.
Just to illustrate that when it is equal, the console log should be the birthday log.
Let's say it's birthday's April.
On the 14th.
Happy birthday in Chicago.
And we get its happy, happy all you and your old happy birthday.
So there you go.
I hope this is getting more intuitive.
Hope you have a lot of fun.
This is the first one.
The second thing I wanted to show you is the UTC time zone.
What about if we wanted a more accurate way to measure time across all our users across different continents?
Initially, this.
So it's insidious.
So now let's see another get me that we can use to solve their problem.
So remember, get methods of based on users local machine machines time.
To be more accurate.
You may.
One to.
Use UGC to how do we do this?
Well, let me give you an example here.
It's say now.
Is the time now?
And we want to access the hours, my hours now it's 11 o'clock here, live in City.
It's just print time.
Normally.
Console.log now, and I'll get ours.
And you can see it's 11 o'clock in.
But what about if I went to the UTC time?
Let's use UGC to.
Well, it's very simple, because we instantiated the date object by using the new keyword we've got
in methods and properties straight out of the box and instead of using gate hours, we can use get UTC
all.
So this ex is unavailable and get UTC.
Alice.
There you go.
It's nine o'clock UTC time.
There was the second example, the third example was what about if I wanted to reformat dates to show
the user what he said on his machine?
Pretty cool.
So let's get rid of this.
If you want more example, how do we go about reformatting dates?
The internationalization API is very well supported across browsers, and it's not only limited to dates.
This APIs awesome.
We can also modify numbers and strings and currencies.
Let me show you an example.
So again, let's create a variable called now, let's make that equal to 1st of January 2020.
Now, if I console.log the state out the format, it's going to be standard, it's going to be what
the code with the JavaScript engine gives me.
Which is this I don't want this to say, I want it formatted to whatever settings I've got on my computer.
Well, we can do that.
Just say now this is the new date we now need to access the internationalization API.
That's a mouthful.
We do that by the keyword.
I intel.
And what do we went into effect?
I remember I said we can do currencies, no strings, what we want to do the date.
So we want to access the tape date, time format method.
And a method on that object is the format method.
And what do we want to format our date, which is now?
And that's it, that's done.
Let me console.log new date that you got.
So instead of showing that big, long string, I just get twenty twenty first first.
How awesome this.
Okay, so I hope you've had fun in this nation was a bit of a bonus section.
They've got a lot more to cover.
Get em, get a coffee and let's move on.