OK, so she was met at random, is this just create a new file very quickly?
I know this is a long letter, so I won't be I won't be long.
We'll just call it M.J. Is this just close everything else?
Just explain the general concept of what was done.
I want to start quicker.
And now let me show you what it is we did.
Firstly, what does Method Random do?
It's inbuilt into JavaScript, so we have access to this object automatically.
Let's just say lit.
No equal method random.
And later console mode, this number.
There you go.
And every time we say the fall, we get a new random number.
But you'll notice that these numbers are between zero and one.
So when we have our array in this, just let's just say lit array equals one, three and five.
To access these, we have to either use zero, one or two.
For example, if I wanted a console log out the first element in inside the brackets, the square brackets,
I have to have whole integers.
In this case, I'd have to have zero.
One or two?
And that retrieves the value out of that array.
So you agree with me already with conscious use?
No, because no, and I'm keep saving now, so you can see it's always between zero and one.
So that's precisely why we multiplied the myth Dr random by number and what number should we multiply
by?
Well, we had four quotes, so we multiplied it by four.
We console log.
The rate of length.
Yeah, we've got three, but to keep it similar to the previous example, I'll show you, let's just
put one more now we've got four.
So we multiply this by four, but instead of actually writing the number four, we just said, Okay,
well, let's just multiply it by its length.
Now we know that the largest number this can be is four in the smallest number.
This can be zero.
You with me so far?
Great.
But now can you see how these produce such random numbers?
If we tried to go array and we tried to access a number like this won't be able to doesn't exist, it
has to be a whole number.
And that's why we use method or flaw in the method.
Floor always returns the largest integer less than or equal to a certain number.
So, for example, on the screen at the moment, we see numbers two point nine four zero using --
floor just return to its assigned to make sense.
So all we did was we included a -- don't flow function in front of a whole description here.
And there you go.
So now the no variable always be between zero and three.
How awesome is this?
That's exactly what we did, which allowed us to access all the elements in there.
I hope it's making sense.
Let's move on.