Looping through data to extract it, it's so important when it comes to programming, and I want to
really I want to stress this, so I'm going to show you two examples the one I'm just going to loop
through arrays show you the different methods.
And then as we've discussed in the lecture, I want to actually create an object with with properties
named Ellipse, and I want to look through that.
So without further ado, let's get into it.
I'm going to start cutting a bit more complicated functions and calls and loops because we've come a
long way.
And I think you're getting really familiar with the traditional easy objects, arrays and all of that.
So let's create a function.
Let's say we've got a whole list of members on our site and we want to loop through each member and
give them a welcome message.
How do we do that?
Well, firstly, let's create a function and we're going to get into functions in a completely whole
new section.
So don't worry about syntax yet.
Just understand the concept.
Let's define a function called high, and it said it function takes in the person's name.
In all this function, does it returns our welcome message?
Welcome, and we using template literals here and we just going to cancel out their name.
So next.
Let's find our members.
And let's say we've got a whole member list.
And we're just starting out, so we've only got two members, Tom and Jerry.
But then let's say we get new users if, say, we get new users.
John?
And Wally.
So member lists its push.
John?
And as to the sad and push Wally.
Now, our member lists should contain four members.
And it does.
And we wanted to greet all members.
How we go about doing this?
We'll remember how I keep stressing these never one right way to do something, and there's lots of
ways to loop through this array.
Just look at the traditional old school ways first.
So the traditional for loop and something worth remembering is that every four loop has curly braces
at the end, and it's kind of like whatever we want to do and code goes in between these curly braces.
What differs is what's in the parentheses here.
So for the traditional so let's start off here with traditional.
Old School for Loop.
We have to define a variable and that variable iterates by one each time the loop completes.
So we can call this anything, but traditionally people like to call it I.
So we say it, I equal zero.
So I'm going to start at zero.
And then the second parameter in this for loop sees under what condition will the loop continue to loop?
Because eventually the loop is going to have to stop.
Otherwise, it's going to be an infinite loop.
So let's say here, we only want this to iterate how many times.
That's right.
Only four times because they are full members, right?
So we need I to be less than.
The member must link.
And in the third parameter is what happens to AI after the first iteration.
And we want AI to increase by one.
So when we start I0 does the first leap.
When it finishes, that is going to be increased by one and then this condition is going to be tested.
I hope it makes sense.
And now I wanted to find a greeting, a particularly greeting for each member, let's say late greeting
equals.
This is where we want to return the high function and remember the high function.
One of its input parameters was the name of the individual.
What is the name of this individual on the first loop?
Well, it's going to be our members list and remember to access properties and array.
We can use the square brackets and here I zero on the first iteration, I'll be zero network, two in
the name Tom.
And then all we wanting to do is console.log pretty.
So there you have it.
Welcome, Tom.
Welcome, Jerry.
Welcome, John.
Welcome.
How cool is that?
I hope you understand what it is.
We did, but again, this is an old school for loop.
I'll show you a better way to do it.
But before I show you the best way to do it, you me show you another old school where it's called the
four in loop.
This is also old school way the for in loop.
Again, we had the fall, and then we've got these curly brackets, and now all we have to do is we
have tickets for concert name in the list.
So what this and is doing is on every loop, it's going to get each element in our right.
We've called out element name because we know their names Tom, Jerry, John, Wally.
So it's going to grab that name in our object members, in our right.
And then traditionally, what this does is that this actually accesses all the prototype's properties
as well, so it can get very cumbersome and sometimes it accesses things it shouldn't.
And for this reason, you often include an if statement within this fall in Newark, and you just have
to say if member list.
And there's a built in property called his own property, and all we've got to say is if this certain
array has its own property and that is outside of any prototypes.
Then.
We want to execute this code.
So now we've passed this if statement, we in the bloc, what do we right?
Well, the same thing.
We want our greeting to execute that high function, and we're going to be passing in each name of the
member.
So the member list and yeah, we haven't called it, I like we did above in that old school followed.
Yeah, we've defined each iteration.
We're going to have the name, it's going to be called name.
So we pass and then.
Now we've got our greeting and all we want to do is console log.
This greeting.
And Bob's your uncle.
There we go.
Welcome, Tom.
Welcome, Jerry.
Welcome John, welcome Wally.
But you can see these methods all that cumbersome.
You know, you really got to think about it.
You've got to do a lot of typing.
Let me show you the full of loop, which is awesome.
Full of loot.
OK, so let's do a full of loop.
My I.D. again helps me with this concert iterator of object.
So, yeah, we've got my name and our object is member list.
And you'll see how much easier this is, this is going to loop through each name.
Each element of our array of our object.
All we need to do now is the trees get our greeting, which is executing the high function and we've
already got our name.
And then we can console log our greeting.
Can you see how much easier and simple the for of loop is?
It's great.
But I want to show you one more example now because yeah, we've been dealing with a simple array.
I want to now deal with the more complicated object.
So let me stop this video because it's getting a bit long, and in the next video, we're going to be
dealing with the object.
And then we're going to iterate Susette object.
See you soon.