So we've seen the Window object rules everything.
Well, let's see some of the properties that we can access on this Window object.
So let's open up the console as usual, and I'm just going to make this a bit smaller so you can see
what's going on.
Now, if I drag this console, right, narrower and wider, you'll notice there are some numbers on the screen.
And that's showing you the width in pixels, and height in pixels, of what the web page is, the website.
And we can access these properties directly, which is an awesome thing.
So the first thing I want to show you here is, innerWidth and outerWidth - that's an interesting one.
innerWidth, and
outer
width.
How awesome is that.
So this will show you the width inner and the width outer.  What do I mean by that? Well, have a look at this image quickly.
(swoosh sound)
So the red is the innerWidth and the purple is the outerWidth. The outerWidth includes those scroll bars
and all of that.
And, back to our example, you've also got innerHeight and outerHeight, so lets try those.
window.innerHeight window.outerHeight.
OK.
And this is what I mean
(swoosh sound)
innerHeight, outerHeight.
You've also got the screen, the screen object that's available via the Window object.
If that kind of makes sense. So within the Window, you can access the screen.
And that gives you access to another whole lot of other properties like left, and top, and all these things.
So let's go screen.top, that's 39px. That's this little gap here.
Yeah.
What about screen.left?
screen.left.
That's this bigger area here. And here's a screen to explain what I mean.
(swoosh sound)
And what about the entire width of the screen and the entire height of your computer or laptop screen?
Well, I'm going to introduce you to something else now quickly, and that's "document".
Remember how we had console.log, and it just logs it (text) to your console?
We've also got document. And you can write to your document. And remember what the document was?
That was your actual HTML page.
So let's go document dot
write,
open parentheses because this is a JavaScript function,
and now let's write "window.screen.width".
And there you go.
That's the the width of my screen. And we can do the same with height.
So now a quick protip, is if you push the Up Arrow, it goes to your last
written statement, so I don't have to write out the whole thing again.
And now let's write out height.
There you go.
How awesome is that?
So those are some useful commands with the Window object and the screen object, but why would that
be useful?
Think about if you want to perfectly align a modal that pops up on a user's screen regardless of the
device they're using.
Well you can use some of this and just mathematically always pick the center.
So that's one example I can think of a lot. A lot of this is fun.
You can explore and try your hands a few different things.
OK, so what other examples
can I give you?  Um, window
open is a good one.
window.open literally opens up a new window.
There's also one (a method) where we can move it around.
I'll show you.
Maybe that is quite a cool example. So let's go
let's creates a new variable, and just call it myWindow. We   can call whatever we like.
And let's go now window.open. And you're allowed to pass a few parameters to the window.
The first one is a URL
in this case, we want it just to be no URL.
The second one (argument), is features. We want zero features. But now let's say we wanted a small window.
So we want to do a width of 200 and a height of, let's say, 100.
If I push "enter" what's going to happen?
It's going to open a new window, how cool is that?
Now, let's say I want to move that window around, how would I do that?
Well, we've got this variable called myWindow, which is why I did it in a variable and we're going
to get into variables in a lot more detail later.
So let's go myWindow, because that's what we called it, and lets type moveTo.
And let's just pick a random number. And now watch what happens when I push enter, or return.
Whoa, where did it go?
Yep, there it is, so it moved the screen.
So these are just some fun things you can play around with on the Window objects.
You know what else is really cool?
You can also navigate history.
So say we were on this page, and now I went to apple,
or lets say we were at google.
Now, let's say we navigated to apple.
OK. What we can do is access the window object.
And within that, there is history, the history object.
And we can go back and Bob's Your Uncle, we're back at, um, google.
There's also location, you can see the current web page URL.
So if we go window and we access its location object, and access href.
There we go. It tells you the page we're currently on. So you can see there is really awesome stuff
going on.
Yeah.
And I implore you, I encourage you to go and explore, feel free to Google some of the stuff and just
get familiar with the window object.
It's awesome.
Enjoy.