Whew!
So, okay, we've come quite a way.
And I know I'm going a bit slowly and I apologize to some of you.
But trust me, you need to get these basics down before you can really master the language.
But it's time to take a step back and just remember what programming is. It's very simple.
It's just a set of instructions that we give a computer to execute line by line. And these instructions
are just a sequence of small commands that we give the computer
one at a time, line after line.
It could be 2 instructions, it can be 2,000 instructions, it can be 2,000,000 instructions.
And there are rules and syntax about how we write these instructions which we're going to get into. But before
we can run, we need to walk.
And unfortunately, you have to learn this stuff and trust me, once you learn these basics, you're
going to be well on your way to programming every single day because it's so much fun.
So let's move on.