Remember earlier we said that the prototype either has to be now or an object.
And you've heard me countless times saying that in JavaScript, pretty much everything is an object
and everything inherits from another object.
Well, let me explain, and I think this will drive the point home.
Let's start off with the number seven.
What's its prototype going to be?
Will its prototype property is going to be the No.
Prototype, and that's why we can access methods like is in our in is finite and a whole plethora of
other methods.
It's because when we declare that variable, it's inheriting a whole lot of properties and methods from
the number prototype.
For now, let's look at the number prototype.
What's its product going to be?
It's proto is going to be the object prototype, and that's why we've got other methods and properties
like to string and value of.
And this is almost the overriding arching object prototype that is accessible from all other objects
in JavaScript.
But now what about this question?
What is the photo of object prototype?
And you guessed it, it's null.
It stops.
It's empty and that makes sense, right?
And that's what I mean when I see prototypes either have to be an object or now.
OK, that was a number seven.
Let's now look at an array.
Let's say we have an array of one, three and five.
What is its pronto going to point to?
It's right.
It's going to point to the array prototype.
And that's why we have methods such as push, pop and other methods because it's all attached into that
prototype.
And what about the array prototype?
What is its product going to be?
Correct.
It's going to be the object prototype.
And let's look at a function.
We define function.
Cordelia, what's its product going to be?
Yep, it's going to be a function prototype.
And again, we've got methods such as bind, cool to string and a whole bunch of others, and it's proto
is going to be the object prototype.
So take a step back, look at this image and let it sink in.
And I hope it's now starting to become more intuitive and to make sense and to prove a point, to prove
that eventually you get to know at the very top by starting at the bottom.
Let's look at an array and let's head to the console.