Heeey, you might be sitting there (scary music starts) and you might be thinking now "JavaScript is scary"
(quick change to happy music)
but I'm here to tell you,
she ain't scary!
Stick with me, and you going to think this thing is a breeze.
What's interesting with JavaScript is it's a safe language.
It doesn't provide low level access to memory or your CPU because it was initially created for browsers
which don't require that.
So the capabilities generally depend on the environment that you run JavaScript on. And,
when we typically think about JavaScript, especially when you starting out at the stage, you thinking
about it from a client user point of view, from a browser  point of view, and there JavaScript cannot
read files or write to them on your computer.
JavaScript in the browser can do everything, but only related to web page manipulation, interaction
with the user and the web server. For instance, in-browser JavaScript is capable of adding new
HTML to page, changing the existing content, modifying styles, reacting to user actions, doing things
on certain mouse clicks and pointer movements and key presses.
Simple right? It cannot execute though any other programs.
It cannot establish a connection to another computer, of course, except to download a new HTML page
or send mail.
And what's very cool about this language on the front end,
is that you cannot influence anything that's not contained by the browser.
So you might be thinking, well, why is this the case, why
why is JavaScript limited like this on the frontend?
Well, JavaScript abilities are limited in the browser for the user's safety - for yours and my safety.
The aim is to prevent a very nasty web page from accessing private information or harming your data.
And that's good.