You've got to wonder, don't you how does the machine know where to look for all the variables and functions
declared in our code?
And this is what I want to speak about now.
We were looking at the execution context.
We were understanding about the stick and that the execution contexts are placed at the top of the stack
and new execution contexts are created each time a function is called.
But we didn't look deeper into the execution context itself.
So we understand the high level artworks, but the execution context is created in two phases.
One is the creation phase and two is the execution phase.
The execution phase is when all the assignments of those variables are done and the code is finally
executed.
So that is pretty straightforward.
I want us to concentrate on this creation phase.
The creation process has two distinct items.
It has a lexical environment and a variable environment.
Let's first look at the lexical environment.
And before we actually go into detail here, I just want to zip across the coding ed and show you what
I mean by lexical environment.
At least when you learning the theory look kind of help you understand what it is we're talking about.
Have a look.
I really don't want you to freak out about these fancy words.
Lexical environment.
Who cares about that?
Just take a step back or a lexical environment is the scope.
It's another word scope, and you create a scope by the curly brackets.
Let me just shoot over to the code and get it to committee and show you what I mean.
But please, I just I just want to stress that don't be intimidated by all of us.
Take a step back.
Understand what it is we're doing, and it will make complicit.
Let me show you quickly.
So as I was saying, curly brackets define a scope.
So there we go on our screen, we've defined a scope.
You may even zoom in a bit more.
And what's really cool about JavaScript is we can create as many scopes as we want.
For example, we can do this now we've created two scopes to lexical environments.
And we can keep going on more and more and more and more to our heart's content.
But remember the some of these examples of De.
I mean, let's just delete this.
It's getting a bit ridiculous.
And let's console log a variable called X if we haven't yet defined.
Now let's create a scope.
And what about even another scope, and let's define a variable x equal dog.
What do you think's going to happen when we execute this now?
With all the things we've learned with looking at the political environments, remember how we had the
two environments within each context, we had the lexical and we had the variable and the lexical defined
the late in the contest variables.
What do you think will happen here?
Well, from what we've seen, we know that late doesn't get initialized until it's encountered in fancy
programming talk.
This just means it's not going to be hoisted to the top.
I'd expect to see an area.
It's just thought, okay.
And then we go we get an error.
X is not defined.
And what about if we use VAR?
Well, as we're going to be see for sits in an environment called a variable environment, and this
gets assigned a value of undefined Ford's initials.
So if we go for, you'd expect not to see an era.
In fact, I'd expect to see undefined.
And that's what we see, we see undefined.
So you get this, you starting to understand what a lexical environment means.
So let's delete this.
It's God of war and this make this list again.
And then what about if we now define another lexical environment?
So the cool thing with lit is that anything below it, any lexical environment created after it will
be valid could.
So if we go console log X where your dog makes sense, right?
It's all I want to show you.
Let's get back to the lecture.
OK, cool, we back.
So we onto the creation phase of an execution context.
And we know that this involves the creation of a lexical environment and the lexical environment holds
identifier variable mappings.
What I mean by identifier?
Well, that is just the name of the variable of function and the variable within the identifier.
Variable mappings refers to the actual object of value itself.
You'll understand what this means for each lexical environment has three components.
It has the environment to record.
It references the outer environment and it has this binding and it binds this.
Well, let's look at each one of those very quickly.
The environment record is just the place with a variable, and function declarations are stored inside
the lexical environment.
It's not much else to it.
It's quite simple and straightforward.
Now, when we look at the reference to the art environment, that just means that it has access to its
outer lexical environment.
And that means that the JavaScript engine can look for variables inside the Alta environment if they
are not found in the current lexical environment.
And we've also got the this finding in this component.
The value of this is determined or set in the global execution context.
The value of this refers to the global object.
We've seen this in browsers.
That global object is the window object.
And what about in a function execution context?
What happens with the value of this?
What is that?
Well, that depends on how the functions called if it's called by an object referenced in the value
of this asset to that object.
Otherwise, the value of this is going to be the global object or even undefined.
If we're using strict mode.
And finally, we have the variable environment.
It's actually just a copy of the lexical environment and in all practicality.
There is no real difference between the two except when working with with the statements, because when
you work with with statements, it actually modifies the lexical environment, not the variable environment.
But, you know, I don't want to be going into the with statements.
Nine Many developers actually argue you should avoid the word statement altogether for performance reasons,
says such just treat the two as pretty much the same thing.
And although they are pretty much the same thing in iOS six.
One difference between the lexical environment and variable environment component is that in the former
in the lexical environment, we store function declarations and the lit and contact variables, while
in the variable environment we only store the variable VAR.
But again, going forward with coding, you and I should not be using VAR, we should be using latent
content.
But for the sake of understanding it, I am going to throw in a few balls in the upcoming examples.