JS inline.
I know you might be getting sick of this for now, but I just want to drive the point home, I want
you to intuitively understand how JavaScript is included in your code, and we know that inline JavaScript
just means that your JavaScript code is been included (or written) directly in your HTML.
So let's set up a basic structure of an HTML website, a web page.
We know we've got to start with "DOCTYPE".
We've got those header tags.
We've got the body tags.
Let's say we want to write "Hello World".
And, you know, in the head tags, you got a few bits and bobs.
You've often you've got a stylesheet that it (the HTML) references from an external file.
I don't know, say we want to make the paragraph text red.
How do we include inline JavaScript?
The one place you can put it, and you can probably see by the gap in the code there, is within the head
section.
You can literally put your JavaScrip there. That is valid JavaScript code. But that's not the
only place you can put your JavaScript code, lets have another look.
So we set up the basic structure once again.
You write your "Hello World" and within your head tags you've got all the bits and bobs, plus you have your
CSS.
But now we can choose to put our script tag within the body tags.
And again, it's valid JavaScript code.
The point I'm trying to make, is you can choose where to put your JavaScript code.
And there are benefits and pros of putting it in the heads and in the bodies, but I don't get into that
now.
We're going to get into that later in the course.
I just wanted you to get the concept that you can choose as a program where you put that script tag.
Cool.
OK.
Let's go.
Let's let's see how this all fits together.
Let's see how it works.
What I'm going to go through now is I'm just going to show you a very simple example of how we write
JavaScript inline.
So you can see I've got a very simple template of an HTML page.
How do we include JavaScript?
Well, let's include it in two places.
We actually don't need this link ref.
We're not styling the page.
So let's now put it in between these head tags.
Let's run JavaScript.
We've already seen JavaScript has to be inserted between script tags.
And let's issue an alert, "JavaScript
being run in an IDE
inline".
Let's now put it in the body section.
What do we need?
Correct.
We need script tags.
Opening and closing script tags, and what should we do this time?
Well, we know console log. So let's just console.log
JavaScript,
"This JavaScript.
has been executed
after the alert,
also INLINE".
Before I show you what this looks like in the browser, just understand that when the browser
parses this document, this html page, it that starts at the top, and it goes to the bottom. So this script
will hit first, which is in the head tag.
And because there's no JavaScript event that fires this alert, like "click" or something like that,
when the browser starts rendering this page, it's going to execute that JavaScript straightaway.
So we would expect, I hope you agree,
we would expect to see an alert.
When that alert is finished, we should be able to open the console and see our console message here, if all works well.
Let's have a look.
So here's the Go Live that I was telling you about. Let's
execute this in the browser. And boom, there's the alert:
"JavaScript is being run in an IDE inline"
That's what we wrote, When you click OK,
we're going to see nothing,
and that's expected because, well, we defined nothing in our HTML.
But if we inspect our page,
and we click on our Console tab.
There we go.
"This JavaScript has been executed after the alert, also inline." How cool is that?