There are turn key word is important to understand.
But why?
Let's have a look.
It creates a function.
It just adds a and b my image credit function.
We need the function keyword.
Now we need to name it.
Let's just call it ED.
Let's add two numbers A and B that will pass into the function.
And look at this.
I'm going to return.
JavaScript understands what this means, and I'm going to explain shortly what it means.
And we can return a plus B.
And if we execute this function.
It's not quicker.
And it's aired five and 10.
And it's console this large console log.
We got it comes up with an onslaught of 15, as we would expect, but what does this return keyword
actually mean?
Let's have a look.
The return keyword simply ends execution and you guessed it, returns a value.
What about if there is no return value?
In that instance, undefined is returned, not now undefined.
And something else to bear in mind is that the return statement is affected by automatic semicolon insertion.
What I mean?
Well, let's take our function example.
We had returns FSP if we had to write return and on a new line, we wrote A-plus B, what's going to
happen?
Will the pasta is going to interpret that as return semicolon and then a plus B semicolon?
And the important point to realize with this is that the eight plus B in this instance will be unreachable.
So how can we return something that's spread across multiple lines?
Well, in that case, you just need to close it in parentheses.
That would work.
Let's have a look at another example quickly.
Alright, so a few more examples on the return keyword.
Remember how we said that when you use the return keyword, it stops the execution of the function?
What does it mean?
Well, that firstly means if we've got other variables we define, Yalitza equals 10, D equals 20 and
we console.log C plus D.
You can really see my I.D. is kind of great off these statements.
And the reason it's great, these answers that these are not going to be executed if we add five and
10 again, it still shows us fifteen.
If we wanted to see both, we would have to then reposition these above the return statement.
Only now does it console.log C plus D and return 15.
And you must always just be careful with the return keyword because if you don't have it, it can cause
weird things.
What I mean?
Well, let's go to plonker.
Remember Palanca?
We haven't used it for a while.
Just on the homepage, and I'm just clicking this new button here, and we can just default to standard
empty HTML, CSS and JavaScript file.
And what's nice about Palanca is on the left.
You can kind of see your project file layout.
You can kind of see your setup, you've got your index file.
And if we click on our index file, you can see it references to JavaScript file within the Lib folder.
So it's just a nice overview for you.
It's nice to see how everything fits in.
But now what I want to do is I want to create in the index file.
This just creates a paragraph with I-D demo.
It's all I'm wanting to do.
And in our JavaScript file, which we know is already referenced in our index file, so we know this
is going to be executed, this define a function.
Called Taste and taste, we're going to pass in a variable name and argument.
Remember how we saw this example earlier?
And yeah, all I want to do is on a right into that paragraph.
Hello.
Name.
It's all we want to do.
So now we've defined our function.
All we need to do now.
Access that paragraph tag and insert this text into it.
So how do we access a pair of tech?
Remember, we start off with the document because that's the overarching application.
We access an inbuilt method on that element by ID. And then we can write whatever we want and signed
it.
So yeah, we're going to start with document.
It element by ID. In this case, the I.D. we said, was demo.
And in there, we want to right within its inner turmoil.
We want to execute this function and let's say the users wisely.
Now all we need to do is preview this.
You can see.
Tanker that was inserted in the index, eight-month-old and they we got undefined.
It's another reason why if you don't have the return key keyword, remember what I said?
It returns undefined.
I've just proven it to you and this is weird.
You think, why is it not returning?
Hello, Wally.
And the reason is, as you guessed, that you need the return.
Key would say, if we now return hello name and it refreshes.
We should get help, Wally.
And we do.
There you go.
And one more example let's just open up Chrome's console.
And he has another example is create a function, let's call a function test for lack of a better word,
and let's just define a dog, and let's say his name is doggy.
OK.
Now, if I run this function, what do you expect to be returned?
Well, we haven't included the return keyword, so yes, I'd expect undefined to be thrown.
And that's exactly what happens.
So what about if we create another function?
Let's just call it Test two.
I know I'm not being very creative here.
The names and it's early dog to equal wolf.
Wolf.
Now, instead of closing and ending the function, let's put in the return keyword and what do we want
returned?
Well, let's just say we want the dog to return the dog to which is its name.
So when I run taste two, what do you think should happen now?
It's right, we should see were fourth Test to.
Woof, woof.
So these were just three quick examples of how the returned keyword can affect the outcome of your function
execution to the speed in a mind.
It's quite an important point to note.
Let's move on.