Great, we've seen a diagram of the whole tree structure of prototypes, and at the very top was no,
let me just prove it to you.
This creates an array, so relate a equal and in theory.
How can I prove that this inherits from the right prototype?
Well, it's just got a dot.
It's protein.
Should be equal to the array.
Which is built in JavaScript, and that should be equal to the right prototype.
I'd expect this to be true.
But see?
A wholesome set.
It is true.
But what about the array prototype?
I would expect that to be the.
That's right, the global object prototype.
So if we go a and we access the prototype, we know that's already now the ray prototype.
So they lose contact now, the photo of the array prototype.
So we go we access the proton again.
But now, bear in mind, this is the photo of the array prototype.
What would you expect to happen now?
Well, I'd expect us to be the object prototype, which if I consolidate of looks like exactly what
it is and I can prove it to you, we can call it up again.
So that should be equal to the object prototype.
I would expect this to be true, and it is true.
I'm luckier.
Cool.
Now remember how we say that ends it now because the object prototype its product is now well.
Improve that, so it's take the array, its excess, its protein, which we know is the array prototype,
then we're going to we're going to reference its protein, which is their race protein, which is the
object prototype who gets confusing.
And lastly, we want to excise the promoter of that object prototype.
Which we would expect to be No.
And it is.
So there you have it.
We've just proven that we starting with an array that we've created at the very top it's proto references
array prototype, which is why we've got push, pump, slice.
All these other methods attached to it that day references the object prototype and the object prototype
is the king.
There is no higher project, which is why when you access a prototype that you get no hope, it's making
sense.
Well done for getting through this bonus section, but let's continue with the course.