(music)
That's not a bad connection.
That's just how amplified I am, and how much I'm enjoying this course.
Before we move on from constants, I just want to show you one more example.
And here I want to use what's known as the try and catch block.
All it is, is that the try block of code allows you to try an expression and if it throws any errors
that's where the catch block comes in, and in the code defined within that block will be executed.
Let me give you an example, and going through this example, I hope you get a bit of feel for the const
keyword.
So let's define a number.
Let's make the number equal ten.
You know what I haven't done, I haven't stuck with best practice.
And that is, to have caps for your constants. So, let a NUMBER equal 10. Let's define a try block.
And again, I've got Quokka.
That's why we're seeing these errors displayed real time.
Let's try number equals
five.
And remember, with constants, we are unable to re-assign variables, which we've tried to do here.
So I'd expect the "catch" block to be executed.
And one thing with the catch block is that when an error is thrown through the try method, it passes
on a variable with the error in it.
So let's just call it error, and let's console.log error.
Is not giving us any errors! Of course, and this is another lesson that I've unintentionally was not
meant to give,
variables are case sensitive, so the constant NUMBER is different to this "number" in here, which is
why I've got to go caps and I would expect now an error.
And that's exactly what we have: TypeError: Assignment to constant variable.
We're not allowed to do that.
I hope you've learnt something. Don't stop.
(music)