The most popular data type in JavaScript is arguably a String.
So let me just show you a practical example of how we can work with this specific data type in JavaScript.
We've already seen lots of it because we used alerts, console logs,
we've done count methods,
we've done a lot. And all of those (methods) take Strings.
They take text.
Here's another example.
Here's an HTML file.
Let's just insert a button.
I dunno, called "click me", and I'm not going to worry about CSS right now making it look pretty,
I just want to illustrate JavaScript.
So here we got a button.
We click it, nothing happens.
What if we want an alert, and we pass a string data type into that alert
once you click the button? Well, it's very easy.
All you need to do is add what's called a click event listener on this button.
So that's onClick.
And we want to fire a function, let's call it
alert, alertMe() function.
All this is saying is that we've added an event onto the button called "onClick". When you click it,
it's going to fire this function called alertMe(). What do you think's going to happen?
Well, nothing because we haven't defined what this alertMe() function is, and that is where JavaScript
comes in.
If we're now in JavaScript (tab), we can go,
function alertMe(),
and we can say, let's give an alert.
This is a string data type in JavaScript.
There you go.
Now it works.
This is a string data type in JavaScript.
Button works.
How cool is that?
Just bear in mind here, because we're using JSBin, it automatically makes the link between HTML and
JavaScript.
In practice, you would have to include a script tag say here,
and you'd have to have the source attribute, etc etc.
We just haven't done that because we are working on an online console.
Hope it helps.