Whew, okay, remember in the previous lecture, I mentioned that when the browser parses your HTML, it
goes from the top to the bottom.
Well, I just want to tell you why that's important.
And and when you start writing JavaScript, you need to think about this.
Here's the body tag.
Let's just say we've got a paragraph.
And in the paragraph, we want to replace this text with JavaScript.
So, say we've got this text and we want to replace it with JavaScript.
And remember, it parses from top to bottom.
So what about if we try and replace this paragraph before the browser has have rendered the paragraph?
Surely that won't work.
Well, let's see.
Let's put JavaScript at the top.
And again, don't worry about syntax for the moment, I just want you to understand the concept of what
we're trying to learn.
Let's just define ... all we have to do now in JavaScript is we have to somehow identify that paragraph tag, so
let's do that.
Okay, we have to, this actually returns a collection, so we just want to access the first element of the
collection, which is the element itself.
And let's now go and replace the innerHTML with this:
"This is new text replaced by JavaScript".
Should we try and run this?
Let's give it a go.
Let's see what happens.
So again, let's click on Go Live.
What do you expect to see?
Something didn't work, because look, we want to replace this text with JavaScript, and obviously
it hasn't happened.
Let's inspect the Console and we've worked with the console already, and this is why it's awesome.
Have a look here when you encounter errors like this -Uncaught TypeError, cannot set property 'innerHTML'
of undefined. And it even tells you where in you code
this has happened. If you click on that,
It says, this is undefined, "para". We've defined "para" as getting the tag name paragraph.
So let's switch back to our IDE.
So what's happened, is the browser has encountered this tag, getElementsByTagName("p"), and
has tried to find it, but it hasn't got there yet.
So this is undefined when it happens.
And how I can prove it to you, is let's just move the script tag to the bottom.
All we've done is we've moved the script tag below the paragraph tag. And what happens now, do you
think, if I go back to the browser?
"This is new text replaced by JavaScript".
How cool is that!
I hope you understand now the importance of where you place JavaScript does matter in your HTML.