OK, so let's start by showing you what the for each method does.
Let's open up Chrome again.
And you can see we've even got our previous example still on the screen.
I'm going to be cutting this in real time with you and to prove that you need just medication us off
just second.
Second, just give me a second.
And there we go.
All right.
So here I am with you.
I'm coding in real time, and I just want to show you what the for each method is meant to do.
And I want to give you an example.
It isn't so easy.
You know, I can just use an array and we just loop through the rain console, load those items, but
always try.
And I mean, I think you get the point now, especially with this course that you understand at a high
level of JavaScript is so let's let's create two arrays and we take all the elements in the one array
and we pushed them into the second array yeasted, something a bit more different.
So the first step is let's create another file.
Another snippet.
And it's just cool that for each.
Now, the first thing I want to do is create an array.
Let's just call it array one.
And let's just have this full of food, let's just say milk.
And he.
And I don't know, shouldn't.
It create an array to and at this stage, it's just an empty array.
The next step is, you guessed it, let's create a for each loop.
Let's do it.
So let's access array one.
And on this array, one, we should have access to the for each method natively because we know that
every era on our Brasa has a prototype and their prototype has the for each method.
And remember what the for each method took, what was the argument rigged to provide innocent?
That's right.
The callback function so has provided a callback function.
The callback function took two arguments, well, actually two three, remember, but the third one
I just want to ignore for our purposes, it takes two.
And the first argument is the actual item in the array.
And for argument's sake, let's you and I just call that item.
We can call whatever we want.
And the second item we passed in this function is the index.
And again, for simplicity, let's just call it index.
Now what this allows us to do is that this for each method is going to iterate over one and each time
it iterate over the array one, it's going to take each item in that array and it's going to throw us
back an item in an index.
What do we want to do with that?
Will it push the item into the new array array two?
So let's access Array two.
Let's push each item into this array and others push me.
That is very similar to the four each in that it's on the array prototype, meaning we have access to
it natively straight out of the box.
We're going to use template literals here.
And we're going to access the item.
We should say has been added.
As no.
And they will also access the index, and then the last thing I want to do is I want to show you what
this array looks like.
So let's run this function by pushing control.
Enter.
And there we go.
We can see what the result is on the screen.
Milk has been added as nO0 and he's been enters number one and should have been added as number two.
And of course, we can even improve on this code.
We know that the new and improved way of doing things is the error syntax.
You can get rid of the keyword function.
And we can put arrows and ticks over here and we can run it again.
Sorry, we have to refresh to refresh our code, let's clear the console and let's run it.
Here we go.
We had exactly the same result, but now we're using the new and improved aero syntax.
Before we move on is one more thing I need to mention with this for each method, and that is what is
this referring to?
Well, one way of testing what this refers to is let's just console.log it out, console.log this.
And again, just to refresh, it's clear the console and its right.
What this tells us is that the this keyword is currently referring to the window object.
And this makes sense, and we're going to get into this in more detail later.
So I don't want to hop on why this happens now.
I'm going to be talking about that.
So just hang on for that.
But with this, for each method, it actually takes two arguments.
The first argument was the callback function, which we've done, but the second argument over here.
It's also interesting that lets us define what we want this to point to.
So for example, if we wanted this 2.0 array one, we could just pass array one into the second argument.
OK, let's refresh, let's clear this console in this run, this again.
We still referring to the winter object, this is a nuance of error syntax if we fall back to old function
keyword.
And we get rid of the error.
And now we do exactly the same thing.
We run this again.
The we got we get this referring to the actual array.
Okay, so just bear that in mind with the error syntax, it really does handle the word this differently.
But as the for each method is just shown, it two arguments.
First argument is the core function.
The second argument is what you want this to refer to.
But if you are using that, you have to fall back to the old way of writing a function.
Q I know that's a lot, but you doing so on this continue and get into writing our very own poly.