Remember how we said the Window object gives you access to a whole lot of other functionality other
than the content of the web page.
One of those is what's known as the Navigator. And I just want to say that as you start exploring these
things, just understand that some things might be deprecated. And by deprecated
it's a very much the programming term, and it just means that it's no longer supported.
So you're may get some weird results, sometimes.
And an example of that is navigator.appCodeName.
That will always give you Mozilla, even if you're not using Mozilla.
This is a weird kind of thing that happens.
Another example is navigator.name.
And it just always gives you Netscape.
So you might be asking, "why is it still around if it's deprecated?"
Well, according to the HTML Living Standard (or HTML5), these values must be retained, and the only reason they're
still around is for backwards compatibility.
What I mean by that, or um, think about an app that was built with these functions in the past, and now
suddenly, if they removed it, those apps would break.
So their removal could break an app that depends on them
in other words. And as you know, as with other web standards, we pretty much always in a bit of a transitional
phase.
So until that happens, just be just be careful.
There's all I'm trying to say.