For example, number one, this just make it the most simple.
It's creates an empty object.
Remember how to define an object literal?
Leonid is an opening and closing curly it.
It's all we've done, and that is literally now an object, if I console.log that out, we get an empty
object, which is what the blue?
OK?
What about creating an object with one property?
So let's create this object.
One property?
The dog equal.
Opening and closing curly brackets defines an object.
It say it has a name, and it said the name is.
Wolfie.
So now we've defined an object and object with one property, and removal of properties are just key
value pairs.
Yeah, the keys name and the venue is Wolfie.
Console.log, they wrote.
We get our object.
But let me emphasize something here.
You do have to specify the key and a value in order for this to work.
Otherwise, you will be thrown in error and we give you an example.
So you have to specify both key and value.
So yeah, if I go a late animal.
Equals type, and I just leave it.
I get an error as this type is not defined, so I have to assign it value.
So let me say mammal now I don't get any errors in even making it more simple than that.
And also, if I go late animal to.
And I go just type.
The same thing happens as this type is not defined.
So you see, I have to specify both in order for this code to be valid.
Let's just delete these quickly.
What about methods using object neutral syntax?
Let's just create an object with one method.
And let's just call it welcome it, say you want to give a welcome message to a user welcome message
open and close curly brackets defines an object.
JavaScript knows this is now an object.
Now it's the teacher method and it's cool.
The method.
Say hi.
And this method will be a function, and method just means a function, by the way a function is outside
of an object and a method is inside of an object, that the same thing.
And let's say we have to take it to this function as an argument, and we're going to be getting into
functions in one of the upcoming sections.
So don't panic if you don't know what I mean.
And it's just console.
Log the text up to the screen and to make it more clear, just one comments.
So you understand what we're doing.
This is an object with one method.
Now this access this method, welcome message.
Dutch remember, that's how we access methods and properties, say, hi, what we've called it, and
it needs to be passed a stream.
So let's say hello.
And there you have it, console.log hello to the screen.
Okay, but up until now, we've just been dealing with properties or we've just been dealing with methods.
What about if we combine properties and methods?
No problem.
So this object with properties and methods, so let's define a person object and this person has a first
name.
This person has a property called age.
And it's say there's a message method.
And let's say this method just console logs.
This first name so that we collide is.
This age is old.
So there you have it.
We have a person object with properties and those properties of key value pays.
And we've also included a message method that's trying to access that person message.
We execute.
And as soon as we do, that executes the function.
I hope you're starting to get a bit more comfortable with objects and how we create them in JavaScript.
But don't get too complacent yet because this was only one way to create an object.
Now let's discuss another.