We've learned about objects, we've learned about arrays, but this lecture is going to be epic.
But let me start off by saying that all JavaScript engines use the concepts discussed in this lecture
as a way to optimize code.
And as you can see from the hitting, this shapes the different engines cool shape different things.
So when you start doing this, you may come across different terminology.
Some people refer to these as hidden classes, but this is confusing because we've got JavaScript classes,
V8 cores in maps.
But this is also confusing because remember, we use that map iteration.
Others called him types JavaScript core causing structures.
But Spider monkey calls in shapes and just to avoid confusion with other terminology.
I've decided to call them shapes as well.
But anyway, I digress.
We now know how objects are defined in JavaScript.
We've been working with him.
But in this lecture, I want to dive deeper.
I want to discuss how JavaScript engines work with objects looking at what we've done so far with objects.
You've probably already guessed that existing properties is by far the most common task.
What do I mean?
Well, when we have an object, let's just define the user object of the first name and last name.
It's going to be very common for us to query those values.
For example, use a dot first name.
We asking the engine to go and fetch us the first name of this user.
And because of this, it's crucial for JavaScript to make this process as quick as possible.
OK, OK.
You get it.
So what is the shape?
Well, let me say this.
It's common to have multiple objects with the same property names or keys.
For example, let's create a dog and snake object.
For example, let's say we had a dog object, and it's got to these two names type and age.
Now we create a snake object.
And it's also got type an age.
It's intuitive that these two have the same shape.
Those objects have the same keys, and it's only mean machines.
Shapes are just objects that have the same look and feel.
But let's dig deeper to understand what JavaScript does with objects.
So let's create an object with properties X and Y equal value of 10 and 20 when we create these objects.
We know that JavaScript object model is implemented.
Remember, we looked at the JavaScript object model, and all I mean by this is that each object uses
the dictionary data structure we discussed earlier.
It contains the keys as strings.
The keys here are X and Y, and those keys point to their respective property attributes.
Now, when we access the Property X on that object, i.e. we actually type into our code object X or
in the case of all, use object, we type use a dot name.
What's going to happen?
Will the JavaScript engines going to look in the JS object for the key for that X?
And then it's going to load the corresponding property attributes, and then it finally, once it's
done it, it's going to return the value.
You see the very day in square brackets, it's going to return that in the case of X, it's going to
return 10, but these property attributes.
Well, they stored in memory.
Let me ask you another question.
Should we stole these property attributes as part of their JS object?
Before you answer that, let me just say what if we end up creating thousands of objects that have a
similar structure, i.e. that have the same shape?
I'd argued with Wasteful to store the full dictionary, which contains property names and associated
attributes on each face object.
Why?
Because this is going to result in a whole bunch of duplication and unnecessary memory usage.
Of course, we know it wouldn't be efficient to go and duplicate these property attributes for every
single object that has the same shape.
So then what does the JavaScript engine do?
Well, it stores a shape of the object, and it does the separately to the actual object itself.
In this shape, restore all property names and attributes, except for the values, instead of storing
the value property, the shape has to store the offset value that references the JS object so that the
engine knows where to find the value.
And this means that every JavaScript object that has the same shape will point to exactly this one instance.
This one shape instance.
No duplication and no memory leakage.
And because each JavaScript object is unique, you know each item is going to have different values.
That just means that that object only has to store their unique values.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's get our object with X and Y.
Now, instead of that object storing the keys, it's only going to have its values because those values
are unique to it, so it's only going to store the values 10 and 20.
And that object is going to be pointing to a shape.
And its shape is what's going to be storing the keys and the associated offsets.
Does it make sense?
So we know when you're looking at the shape, the X points to property attributes with an offset of
zero.
And that's why the JavaScript engine is going to know that X has a value of ten.
Why are you confused yet?
Good.
It's part of the journey.
Perhaps this example even be more clear once you have multiple objects.
So let me show you that now we had an object o'bagy that just had X and Y.
Now let's create OBJ one and object two.
So we've got two objects now, the two different values.
And this is probably going to make sense to you now because now we've got two objects and they're both
utterly unique values, but they both point to the same shape because they both have the same shape.
How awesome is us?
And you can already see now that instead of storing that information in both objects as property attributes
is only stored in one shape.
Just remember, even if you're getting confused, not just remember this, no matter how many objects
are hundreds, thousands, millions or billions.
As long as they have the same shape, we only have to tool the shape and property information once.
But so far, we've only seen examples where you have an object in a predefined structure.
We've never had to add properties to it, which of course, begs the question what happens when we add
properties to an object that has already been created?
What happens to the shape?
This is we transition chains and trees come into the picture.
This creates a user object.
And initially, let's just sit it out, so it's empty, it's got no properties.
What is its shape?
Well, its shape is also in.
So at this point in time, the user object is pointing to an empty shape.
Simple, right?
But now let's add a property code name to this object with a value, John.
As soon as you do this, a new shape is going to be created.
The JavaScript engine now transitions to this new shape that contains the property name.
The user object has a value of John as its first offset.
At this point in time, it's actually the only offset.
But let's keep going.
Let's now at a property called Age to the use object and give it a value of 38, you guessed it, another
shape is created.
The JavaScript engine again transitions to this new shape that now contains both name and age.
The property attributes attached to that age.
It tells us that the value for age can be found at the offset one position of our user object, which
makes sense.
And just as a side note, and if why the order in which properties are added to the object does impact
the result in shape, for example, we defined name and then age.
But that's going to result in a different shape than if we had first assigned age 38 and then named
John.
Makes sense.
It's just going to shuffle around all shapes.
In fact, another way to represent this image that you're currently looking at is the following.
As you can see, we don't need to store the full table of property attributes for each shape.
Instead, if we shape only needs to know about the new property it introduces.
For example, in this case, we don't have to sold information about name in the lost shape because
it can be found earlier in the chain.
And to make this work, every shape links back to its previous shape, and this is why it's called a
transition chain.
It's like a chain.
It's like one big chain with a lot of links and all these shapes have links to each other going back.
Now, in our case, what if we want to access the name properly and our use object, which we know is
John, when we write user name, the JavaScript engine is going to look up the property name by first
approaching the age shape.
Why?
Because that's the further down on the chain.
It's not going to find it there, so the engine is going to keep having to walk up the transition chain
until it finds the shape that introduced the name property.
Makes sense.
Okay, now we're almost done, but I want to get a little bit more complicated.
What happens if you have two objects that offers empty and then you place different properties on each
of them?
Well, remember how I said transmission chains and transmission trees?
This is where the trees come into it, because in this case, we're going to have to branch out instead
of having a transmission chain.
We're going to have to have a transmission tree.
Let me show you what I mean.
Let's create a user one object.
First, it's empty, and then we place a property name onto it.
We're going to end up with a JS object called use, the one that contains a single value in this case,
John.
And it's also going to result in how many shapes.
In two ships, that's right, the empty shape and the shape with only a property called name.
Okay, and let's create user to.
Use it to is also going to start with an empty object.
But then let's add a different property called age.
What is the result of all this?
Well, we're going to have two objects, but they're going to be three shapes.
There's going to be two shape chains, one related to user one and another related to user two.
But let me ask you this now, does this mean there's always going to be an anti shape associated with
every object?
No, not at all.
Let me show you another example.
Have a look at.
Let's say we create user one starts off as empty and he's got a name of John.
We know in this instance we can have a giant object with barely John that points to an empty ship that
then transitions to a new shape with the property name of name.
We know this, but let's say we create a second user, but this time we immediately create a property
called name to it.
In this case, we've created an object that immediately has the name property, and this means the JavaScript
engine is not had to start from an empty object and transition to a new one.
It's immediately just gone to the end result, and I'm going to make a very good point here.
This is why object literals can be very good, because this optimization that we've just seen, it shortens
the transmission chain and makes it more efficient to construct objects from liberals who know I want
to get just a little bit more complicated.
Just be with me.
Hold on.
Tight.
Don't stop now.
You're almost done.
This is very useful information.
Very interesting.
Let's create a use object with three properties now name, age and bold.
Let's just say it is ball.
The motto is we learned before fall.
This creates an object with how many shapes.
With four shapes in memory, that's right.
And now to access the property name on that object, the JavaScript engine needs to follow the linked
list.
It's going to have to start with the shape at the very bottom, and it is going to have to work its
way up to the shape that introduced name, which is way at the top.
And as I'm sure you've already case, this is going to be the only scheme if we do this more often,
especially when the objects have a lot of properties.
So to speed up searching for properties, the JavaScript engine adds a shape stable door to structure,
and the shape table is a dictionary mapping property keys to the respective shapes that introduced the
given property.
Here is the shape table and what it looks like.
In effect, it's another kind of dictionary that shortens this whole process.
For example, you can see on the screen at the shaped table will tell the JavaScript engine way to find
these property values in which shape to find these property values.
So when we search for the name, it still starts in the shape, in the later shape.
But the later shape points to shake table and the the JavaScript engine knows to look in which shape
to find that name property.
It's making sense, right?
What cannot believe it?
Are you serious?
Now we've got another shake table.
Oh, I thought the whole reason for shapes was to avoid the old dictionary.
Look up.
Now we've got another one.
I don't think I don't get it.
I guess I'm just going to give up.
No, don't give up.
I know the answer.
And the reason is is that the shake table and these shakes are a means to an end, and that is to enable
in line Kesha's.
Line caches of the true secret behind JavaScript runtime environment makes JavaScript so fast, and
I don't go into too much detail about inline caches because that's a whole topic in and of itself.
But I hope I've given you enough flavor and enough knowledge so you can dig deep into this topic.
This is what interests you, but we're not quite done with this feature because a I want to show you
what a shake table looks like and b I just want to introduce you, but more to the concept of an inline
cache and what it actually means that it's very, very high level.
So just get a coffee.
We've only got one minute left of two minutes left max of this lecture, so hang in there.
Let's get back into.
And I don't want to get into inland caches.
We know that just another whole topic in and of itself that just had a very high level.
This is how I like to think of it, say we create a functional taste that takes in the use user object
and we just console log the user's name out when you execute the function for the first time.
The in-line cache will look up the property name and find that value is stored at offset zero.
Right, because we know the user, one object has the name John.
In this case, it offsets zero when you execute that function.
It's going to find that offset, and the in-line cache will memorize the shape and the offset at which
that property was bombed.
So when you look at the JS function taste, it's going to store that offset zero in that function call.
And what this means is that if the JavaScript engine sees objects with the shape that the inline cache
recorded before it no longer needs to reach out to the property information at all.
Instead, the expense of property information lookup can be skipped entirely.
And this is significantly faster than looking up the property each time.
Let me show you what I mean, so see how we set up the test function.
We've called it on user one and the in-line cache is stored offset zero in the function itself.
Now, when we call it on, use it, too.
What do you think's going to happen?
Well, in this case, the airline cash is going to recognize that it's got the same shape, and instead
of having to look up the property attributes and go to the shade, tables etc etc, it knows it's etc.,
So all it does is it takes it in line cash of zero and it returns eventually from that object.
Cool, right.
But anyway, that's a very high level of inline caches.
You don't have to really understand it too much in depth now, but if you do want to dig deeper, I
hope I've given you enough of a flavor.
Well, this has been a long lecture, so thanks for being with me.
Well done.
If you've got this fall, I just want to recap quickly.
We've learnt how JavaScript engines store objects and arrays and how shapes and inline caches help to
optimize operations on these objects.
And based on this knowledge.
What can we take away from it?
Well, if there's one thing we can take away from this, that's practical.
We must just initialize our objects in the same way so they don't end up having different shapes.
For example, if you want to create a user object, don't create one with a property and name another
one with its name.
Another one of first name.
Another one was first and then a capital in your name.
That's all going to have different shapes, and it's going to make things more complicated and slow
the background.
Rather be consistent in how you initialize your objects.
Cool.
I hope this has been very informative to you.
I had a lot of fun putting it together.
Was quite a complicated topic, and not many people know about it.
So, yeah, enjoy it.
And let's move on.
Let's get into some more JavaScript season.