Let's now understand how to eliminate unnecessary JavaScript from affecting the critical rendering path.
Remember what our goal is?
Our goal is to deliver above the fold content as quickly as possible to the user.
Just remember that that's our goal.
So if we only need JavaScript further down our page below the fold below what the user can see, then
we don't want those resources taking up critical rendering path performance space.
Do we know?
Unlike CCS, the browser doesn't need to download and pass all JavaScript resources to render the page,
so it's not technically a required step, although most modern web sites do actually require JavaScript
for above the fold experience.
But when your browser hits a script tag, the page rendering process is paused and it's paused until
after the JavaScript is executed.
And the reason the page rendering is paused is because JavaScript has the power to manipulate the Dom
and the CSS.
We've been through this.
We know this, but let's look at this visually.
We know that your browser starts passing your HMO and what happens when it hits a script.
That's right, the parser has to go and fetch that JavaScript file.
It then has to also execute a JavaScript file, and during that whole process, the parser is paused.
We've seen it and only after execution of JavaScript, as does your HMO parser continue.
And once that is finished, the Dom Content Loaded event occurs.
OK, so what are we going to be doing now?
Well, we're going to be looking at ways of how to improve our critical rendering path performance,
and when we look at these ways, you need to try and think, Well, what is we optimizing?
So let's think about what all we can optimize.
Well, there's many different metrics we can look at, but the one that I think we should look at when
testing these different methods is the first meaningful paint that is the first thing that we want our
use to see when they land on the page and kind of be what we consider the first meanings of paint.
So it's almost like we want that to happen as quickly as possible.
So let's go through these different methods.
It's code up examples.
And then while we're doing it, let's keep track of the time that it's taken for us to reach these critical
rendering path milestones, for example, the face paint.
I'll also include the dome concentrated event because this is interesting.
And then let's also put the load of it in there so we can kind of just copy times, process different
methods.
And I just want to say, you know, there is not one solution that's all you know.
And a lot of people just want a quick fix.
If there was a quick fix would be brilliant because in one way it can just be applied to everything.
But it's just like if someone comes to you and says was, you know, can you build a beautiful website?
It's always relative.
There's always different aspects to it.
We've seen you have a shopping website, you can have an automobile website, you have a booking system.
You know, you can have a chat room, and just my answer is to that person will depends on kind of what
side you want.
And it's the same here without optimizing our code.
It depends what you want.
You could do depends how big your jobs with files are, how many scripts you have, how many images,
resources, etc., etc. So we just going to go to a very simple example, but it'll get you thinking
about the process and how it works.
So I hope you enjoy it.
Well, let's get into our first one.
As you know.