We're getting very familiar now with creating objects via the literal syntax.
And like I mentioned, it's the most easy way to create objects in JavaScript.
But the second type is known as an object constructor.
And this is an alternative way to create an object.
But don't worry, the constructor means making or constructing something.
So don't get intimidated by the word constructor function because all it is is that it's a normal function
that just creates an object.
I don't know why we have to have all this jargon.
I guess it does just simplify things.
Instead of calling it a function that creates an object, you just call it a constructor function.
OK, so how does this work?
Well, in order to use the object construction, you have to go through two steps.
One, you have to define your object.
Kind of make sense.
You have to define what it is you wanting to create.
And then two, you've got to actually construct it.
You've got to call it.
And you do this with the new keyword.
Let's have a look at a quick example.