Now, before we move on, we're just going to have a quick look at the types of functions.
Remember what objects?
There were different ways to create an objects with little rules.
We had constructors, we had to create method.
We had the class.
Well, the same with functions.
We've got different ways to create a function.
But what's nicer is that here it's a bit more simple because there are only two ways to define a function
in JavaScript.
We've got a declaration and we have an expression.
The declaration we've been seeing often through our examples is when we have the function key word,
then we have the name of our function.
He had to say, Hi, we've got the parentheses, we pass in the parameter and then we've got the curly
braces where we actually define our function here.
We just defining high name by using template literals.
So that's a function declaration.
Well, how would we write the same function?
But using a function expression?
Well, yeah, you can see how some ladies we just define a variable called say hi and we assign that
the function.
You can see in both instances we have to use the function keyword.
These these arrows and text, which we're going to get on to.
But before we get onto that, you can see the traditional way to create both functions meant that we
had to use the function keyword.
So let's just dive into these in a bit more detail.
We've got a function declaration on the left and we've got a function expression on the right and the
meaning of both.
These functions are exactly the same.
And by that, I just mean that both create a function and they stole that function in a variable.
Yeah, we've called the variable so high.
So then you're probably asking, well, then why have one method over the other?
And the answer is there's a more subtle difference, and that difference is the timing of when the function
is created.
And a function can be created immediately or later, and with a function declaration, it's created
immediately and with a functional expression.
It's only created when it's called.
And I'm going to show you examples of what this means in the next election, so don't worry if you don't
fully understand what this means now.
But just had a very, very high level.
It just means with the function declaration, you can actually call the function even though you've
defined it later on in your code.
OK, but now let's look at function, expressions and a little bit more detail.
The first thing you'll notice is that you can store the function in a variable.
We've called it say hi.
And the other thing to bear in mind is that with function expressions, do you notice how we don't give
the actual function a name?
Look at the function declaration when we say function, and we followed it by the function name called
say hi.
Yeah, we just define a function well in programming jargon that's just known as an anonymous function.
It's just a function without a name.
We kind of have given it a name because we put it in a variable.
But we haven't directly given the function a name like we have with a function declaration.
And one of the other massive advantages with a function expression is an iffy and again, Duncan intimidated
by these weird words.
All that means is that when you want to use a function, once you often do it via a method called ifie,
immediately invoked function expression.
That's what it stands for, and I don't want to be getting into immediately invoked function expressions
right now.
But if you're anything like me, you're going to want to be curious as to what this actually means for
the sake of scratching that itch.
Let me just give you a quick example say we have a paragraph element with an idea of taste in our HTML,
and all we want to do is we want JavaScript to run code that places a string called a yay in that paragraph.
How do we go about doing that?
Well, of course, we first need to start off with a script tech.
Then let's define a function expression.
We are not doing a declaration here.
We're doing a function expression.
We're going to access JavaScript Document Object, which is your overall web page.
And then on that document, we automatically get access to a gate element by ID method.
The ID we want to get is taste and then we want to changes in the HTML to yeah.
So there you go.
There's our function expression.
We closed the script tag and we done.
But the problem with this is we haven't called this function heavy.
We've now just defined a function expression.
So with an immediately invoked function expression, we want to tell the engine to run this immediately
automatically.
How we go about doing that will all you have to do is you have to close your code in parentheses and
then you go, you've told JavaScript this is an iffy and to execute a function, remember what we had
to do?
That's right.
We had to follow that function by parentheses, and it's the same thing with an iffy.
So you follow the function with parentheses and Bob's your uncle.
You've just created your first self invoking function.
So let me show you a few examples now practical examples of the differences between an expression and
a function declaration.