Before we move on to other code, I want to jump back to the console object that we were dealing with
previously because it really is something that you will encounter all the time in JavaScript.
So I want you to really have a solid understanding of what it is.
We know that the console object is primarily used to log text and other data to the screen.
Okay, we've seen some of that, and many properties on the console object.
And the most popular we've been through is logging stuff to the screen.
And remember, to execute a function, you have to use parentheses, so that's why we always go
console.log(), and within the parentheses we included a string literal.
But console.log is not the only method available to us.
There are four categories of output you can generate in JavaScript.
It's console.log(), console.info(), console.warn() and console.error().
So, let's quickly go over some of these so that we can get some flavor as to the differences between them.
So let's get into some more awesome console methods that you may find useful.
So let's type here console
console.log().
We've already seen dog, let's say "log dog"
just because it rhymes.
Another pro tip is if you don't wanna execute this code but you want to keep writing JavaScript, you can push shift
enter, okay. It goes to the next line.
Now, let's try our hand at info.
Let's say info info.
That's now do
warn.
And the last one is ... error.
And, you can tell they all work exactly the same way - you just pass one argument to all of these,
one or more,
we've just passed one argument, which means that we can just pass one string of text into each one and
then they will both,
they will all print to the screen, but in different ways, which is what you'll see now.
Here you go.
Now you might be thinking, "well what is the visual difference in representation between console.log
and console.info?"
You can see that warning and error clearly have different visual references, which is useful for you and I because
in different parts of your code, you might want to have different kinds of warnings, which is why that's
awesome, but there's not really any difference between those two.
And yes, you are right, there isn't a difference between those two in the console. But you don't
only use error messages in the console.
You can also use error messages with Node and you can use it with ESLint.
As all ESLint is,
by  the way, is it's a program that checks your code.
So what I'm trying to get at is within those pieces of software, it will come up with different colors
or it can come up as different colors.
So you may want to use it in those scenarios, but for our purposes, it doesn't matter.
And 99% of the time you're probably going to use console.log anyway.