I want to drive home the importance of the order of your JavaScript code, and the impact it can have
on your website.
So let's have a look.
Let's say, in the body tag
we've got a paragraph.
"We want this text to
display
after the script."
Well, lets just say "We want this text to display" and to identify this paragraph,
let's just have an ID of, I don't know,
"order matters".
So now we've got this paragraph, and we want this text to display on the page. But let's say we've
got a script tag within the head section, and we did this in a previous lecture,
I just want to go into a bit more detail now.
Date() is a JavaScript inbuilt function. Again, we're going to get into more detail later,
don't worry too much yet. Just know that it returns a date.
And if you don't want the actual date and text displayed, you can just display a number by including the +
sign.
So let's console.log
"script
started at", and lets display the time.
OK, and now I also want to console.log this paragraph element.
So let's go to console.log
"element",
and let's get it. So doc ... you have to start with the document because it is everything on your page.
There's a JavaScript method called getElementById.
And we want to get the element with ID, "order-matters".
Let's just put hyphen in here, order-matters.
And now I want to show you something.
Let's create a delay.
And we're going to get into this while-loop later, this while function.
So let's say while, and let's do a new Date,
is less than
t1 plus 5000,
then do nothing.
And then finally, I want to console.log
"script has finished running at"
and then let's do a new Date.
Ah actually, I think I made a mistake here.
We shouldn't have brackets.
That should work.
Allright.
So before we execute this, understand what we're trying to do. We're defining a time, now, then we console
log that time just so that we all know what it is.
Then we're trying to console.log this paragraph element before. Remember
your browser interprets code from top to bottom.
So by the time it hits this, this isn't going to have been rendered by the browser yet
so we can expect some sort of error. But we're going to console.log an element and it's going to be that paragraph.
Then after that, I want to wait five seconds and then I want to console.log again,
the new time.
Then we're going to display the paragraph text on the browser.
Let's see what happens.
I'm going to click "Save Now".
And I'm going to refresh.
And look what happens.
One, two, three, four, five and then the text is displayed.
Did you see that?
And look at the element that we consolled.
It's null. And we would expect it to be null.
Remember, we hadn't encountered that paragraph tag before we included JavaScript.
This is a really cool concept to grasp, understanding how JavaScript is executed in the browser.
Let me just quickly show you why this happened.
Let's take a look.