As mentioned, first pot building our poly for is going to have to be to determine whether that callback
function is that is the function.
So let's get into that start building up.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a new file and I'm just going to call that.
Polyvore and what we want this qualified to do is we want it to be on the prototype of every era, so
we've got to access the right object in JavaScript.
On its prototype, we wanted to define a new function called for each.
Now in this instance, you and I know that our browser need to be, but because I'm doing it this way,
I'm actually going to be overriding the normal functionality for each.
So in effect, we're going to be creating a brand new poly for branding function.
We know that this for each is a method.
And this means it takes two arguments.
The first argument is a callback function in our case, let's just call a callback.
We can call it whatever we want.
And remember, the second argument was, look, we wanted to define this as this is cool.
This this argument will argue this.
And there you have it, this is how we started building our plentiful.
Now the first thing we want to do is we want to check whether the Caldbeck.
Is a function.
And we do this by using Java scripts in both method called Time Off.
It's an operator.
So what we want to do is we want to test if.
Type of the callback.
If that is not a function.
Then what do we want to happen?
Well, we want to stop our code because it has to be a function.
So what we want to do is we want to throw a new type era.
And what we want to do is we want to throw back that call back and we want to say is not a function,
just so the user has some feedback about what it is they did wrong.
And we know it's this doesn't throw type error, the Knockaert can continue, we can continue our code
here.
So there you have it, let's test whether this code works or whether we've done anything wrong.
First thing I can actually spot you haven't even tasted it yet is I should have actually had two equal
songs here.
Some actually wanting it to be of the same time as function.
Let's see if this works, let's hear our console and let's run.
Of course, they haven't actually executed the function for each function.
So what I must do here is let's define a new era lit array equals smoke.
Honey.
And sugar.
And now let's excuse off for each mate that we've just bolt.
For each.
And let's just execute it, let's not pass in a function, what do you think will happen?
Well, let's try and run it.
I'm court type error undefined is not a function, this is exactly the era that we've thrown yet.
That's why we actually throw an error.
I mean, even if you put in something that's not a function like an unknown, let's do console log a,
for example, let's run that.
So we've actually defined already.
Let's refresh the console and run it if we go console.log is not a function.
So this just shows you why we actually throw an ear off because we're getting feedback to the user saying,
Hey, guys, you have to actually pass a function in the for each method.
So let's do this.
Let me show you is what does it mean?
Alright, well, let's throw function.
So let's pass it a function.
There you go.
In this instance, the function is completely empty.
So let's refresh the page here the console.
It's run this function and there you go.
We haven't had an error and we can even test our code by saying call.
If an error hasn't been thrown, let's just go console log.
Yay.
We can continue.
So there you go.
Let's see if this works.
It's run our function and you can see log to the screen as, yay, we can continue.
And this proves that our callback is actually a function.
Awesome, right?
So this is the first part to building our own full.
You can see we're not done by any means because we haven't even got into what the callback function
should do.
And that is it right through our array and then allow us to manipulate and work with the item and the
index.
Let's see how to do that shortly.