All right, so the question we had in the last picture was, how do we solve this problem?
How do we stop JavaScript from blocking the rendering process?
Well, there are a few ways.
Let's start at the most simple and obvious.
If you've ever taken a we've designed one or one course, this is going to be very familiar to you.
We just placed links to external scripts at the bottom of our atrium health body, and placing links
at the bottom of your page is very similar, if not identical to what you would get.
If you actually listened for the DOM Content loaded event and only ran your JavaScript, then I'll show
you more.
What I mean later, while placing JavaScript resources at the bottom of the HMO remains a standard based
practice.
This method by itself can be suboptimal for eliminating render blocking scripts from the critical path.
Why is this?
Remember what it is we try and do here.
We try to display content above the fold as quickly as possible.
So when the user lands on your website, he sees Boom exactly what you want him to see and everything
below the fold below the screen.
It can kind of happen in the background without the user even knowing before he scrolls down on the
page, whether with his finger on a phone or scroll ball at the mouse, right?
That's what we're trying to achieve.
But placing our JavaScript at the bottom of our file still means that we have to wait for that to be
executed before the final render can occur, you know, and sometimes you want that.
Sometimes you want to pause the rendering process for very critical JavaScript resources and in that
case, continue to put your JavaScript files at the bottom.
It is good in that instance, but sometimes for non-critical resources that can wait.
Why not delay the execution so immediately, the user can see that rendered content on the screen and
in the background before you even scrolls.
You can then continue to build your site.
Cool.
Hope it's making sense.
It's enough.
So, like I said, every step of the way, I want us to start assessing performance at three major milestones
in the critical rendering path process one.
I want to assess where the dumb content loaded event fires to.
I want us to look at where the first meaningful paint occurs and three, I want us to look at the unknown
of it, which is when all the resources have been faced and executed and done and fired.
Now you remember in one of our previous examples, we had this quote in the background.
I don't want to recode everything.
Just to recap, it's very, very simple age html file here.
We've just got hit a thanks.
Then we've got our script tanks and we've got our first in line scripts and console.log in line one,
we then have an external script.
To remind you, let's just look at that is we just change the H to Taylor style to red.
That's what we do.
And then we console.log external one to the screen.
So they our external one script.
We've got another in-line script, and then we've got a full scrub tank again referencing an external
file, and this external file just changes the H.
Three tank and we change its color to blue and within just console.log to the screen, external to simple
nothing.
We I mean, we've been through this example.
We know what it's all about, and then we've got our final in line script, which just console logs
in line three simple.
So this is our default approach where we place our JavaScript at the bottom of the page, and let's
just now get those Tom of of--it's.
Do you remember how to do it?
Mulaney pulls a video, think love.
I hope you gave it a good guy that it's it together, so let's.
Fire up our site.
Now we go make sense.
The first thing I can see is that our external files have worked correctly and if we go back to our
code.
What would we expect to see in the console?
Well, the first thing is that we know that the JavaScript execution happens synchronously, so when
the browser hits the first script tag, everything else falls in line.
One should be console.log to the screen at then hits our external one, the JS file.
And then at pause, everything below it, and it will console.log external one to the screen possible,
then hit the next crop tank, which is just console logging in line two.
It'll then hit the external to the JS file.
And finally, the possible hit the lost script tank, which just console logs in line three to the screen.
So expect the solution to be what that's right in line one external one in line to external two and
inline three.
So if we go here and we inspect our document.
And we go to the console.
In line, one external one in line to external two and in line three.
So this is all making sense now to get those time metrics.
Let's go to the Performance tab and let's start profiling this process.
So let's do that.
And there we go.
What I want to do now is I want to go on to the event log.
And what's really cause we've got this full term, so we don't have to go and scroll down everywhere,
we can just go cool, what is the dumb content loaded event?
And we can see that happens at one hundred and sixty seven milliseconds.
Have you got that one hundred and sixty seven point nine milliseconds?
That's how long it took to fire the dumb Clinton loaded event.
Remember that?
No.
Now, the meaningful paint will again.
It's really handy because we can just like paint on the screen.
How long did that take?
Well, if you click on this paint activity, you can see in the right hand side of the page that it
actually gives you a display of what that paint did.
Well, I'm actually in the way, so let me just remove myself quickly.
OK, maybe you can see that better now that the right part of the screen and zoom in a little bit.
Can you see it?
So there's not the paint we want because no color has been changed.
It hasn't.
What about the next one?
The next one is only executed the very first external one JavaScript file, so it's still not quite
what we want.
If we go on to the last point, we can see that that's exactly what we want the user to see.
We wanted to see the black header one tank.
We want to hit it to to be changed to red and hit a three tablet.
So how long did that take?
Two hundred point four milliseconds OK.
Remember that number?
And lastly, I want us to look at the load of it, and you just zoom out changing and you can see if
we look at our main tab, you can kind of see the load event happened at roughly just the full 300 milliseconds
because there are a lot of load events that happen.
Bear in mind that this isn't the final load when we fail to for this, the loss of event loads that
are happening, like when the jobs report gets executed, when your pulse is finished, all that kind
of stuff.
So the one that we are interested in is this event out here, 281 point four milliseconds, you mean
just a up, so you can see here.
Can you see it there?
You mean just do this and then make the smaller lift us up and then you can see it.
There you go.
There's the event load at two hundred and eighty one point four milliseconds if you got that cool.