The cool thing with the console object is that we don't only have console.log available to us.
We also have other methods.
What are some of these other methods?
Well, let's have a look.
It's exciting stuff.
One of them that I want to show you now is called
console.assert(). And assert is just a method on the console that takes two parameters.
Okay, you've got to feed the function two things.
The one is just a boolean expression, and by boolean I just mean true or false.
And then you have to feed, um, the second parameter you have to feed it
is what happens when that assertion fails.
It gives us some sort of an alert.
Let me give you a practical example.
Let's say you're developing a site and you only want people above the age of 50 to enter the site.
Why?
I don't know.
So let's say you got a gentleman and his age, let age equals 35.
And let's say he wants to come onto your site.
Well let's say, in your code, that you want an alert or you want to alert the user that he's not allowed onto
your site. We can go console
console.assert().
Remember the first parameters is a boolean. And what do you want to happen?
You want the age to be greater than 50, remember?
And your second
Parameter is what you want to happen, or what you want to say to the user when this fails.
In this case, if it fails, he's going to be below 50
so you want to say "Access denied.
You're too ...
You are too young
to enter here."
What do you think's going to happen when I push return?
You guessed it, it comes up with an assertion, and it gives you the error message.
How cool is that?
Another cool method is the count method on console. What's the count method?
Well, let me show you. It'll be easier that way.
console.count takes one argument, and that is the label that you want to give it, and it tells
you how many times something has been done.
So let's say you got a button and you want to know how many times the users clicked on the button.
All the count, well the console.count, method does, is that it keeps track as to how many times an action has been called. Simple,
right?
Let's see it in action.