Before we can actually appreciate the full power of JavaScript and how the computer actually reads the
language and converts it into machine code, I just thought, you know, you need to understand what
a processes is. And it's quite funny because
I mean, I spent a lot of my time starting out coding for probably two to three years, and I don't even really,
truly understand what a processor was.
So I'm just going to give you a quick overview.
OK, what is a processor?
Again, you just need to realize that programming is not difficult.
There are just lots of little pieces.
A processor is just one of those little pieces. And a processor is just a small chip, okay.
It's like a machine that resides in computers and other devices,
your cellphones, radios etc and its basic job is just to receive input and provide output.
OK.
In other words, let me rephrase it another way. I'll say that its a tiny machine that works in tandem with
electrical inputs. AHHHH but you probably just want to see one, right? Because you don't fully understand
it and you're sick of all this jargon.
OK, well, here's what it looks like.
(swoosh sound)
Cool.
Just a small chip. Okay, so you could say that the processor is the brains of a computer. It performs
arithmetical, logical input / output operations of the whole computer system.
And we give this processor instructions, right?
Because the processor to work needs instructions.
But unfortunately, and this is what sucks with processors and sucks with machine languages, is that
not all processors are the same and not all speak the same language. Which means, we really don't want
to be diving into writing at a processor level, right, at a low level.
Which brings me onto our next topic.