So humans aren't very good at working with binary numbers used in machine code
right?
I mean, come on, who wants to go and write programming languages in 1's and 0's.
So that kind of make sense. And then we take a step back and we go, cool
okay, so all these programming languages are really just a compromise.
They really are just trying to bridge the gap between us as humans, right, trying to just create something
legible so we can understand it, versus what a computer needs in order to function, which is zeros and
ones.
And some languages are closer to this machine code than others.
And these languages are kind of akin to what's known in the industry as an assembly language. And an
assembly language is known as a low level language.
Why is it called low?
Well, because you can kind of think about it that it's as low as, you know, to the process as possible,
other than literally writing zeros and ones.
And yes, yes.
You know the question you might be asking now is
"why don't we all just write assembly languages,
right?"
It's executed much quicker by the computer, and this is because the computer can directly understand
assembly language and no transponder or translation of the program is required.
And you also use efficient use of some primary memory.
So, yeah, lets just all learn assembly language.
My only hesitation, and it's a very massive hesitation, is that assembly languages are difficult.
OK, it's very machine dependent.
Machine language differs from one computer to another.
It's difficult to program, it's difficult to modify, and it's very error prone.
So for me, in this day and age, I don't think there's a real need to learn an assembly language.
I think, you know, you get such good programming languages, JavaScript being no exception at all.
It allows you to actually write code
you understand, others understand
but that is equally powerful as any other assembly language out there.