Great, we know what a fool each does.
Now what I want you to do is assume our browser has no idea what a fool is, say that it's not natively
supported by our browser, so therefore we want to build a poly full on our array prototype.
The first step is going to be actually writing at the beginning of our code, and it was going to look
something like this.
And let me just point out it is on the prototype of our array object.
Then we want to define the for each method we can call it whatever we want, but for our purposes,
I want us to call it for each and we putting it on the prototype of the JavaScript array global object.
We know for each is a method.
That's why we've got the function keyword and that for each method takes two arguments.
The first argument it takes is a callback.
And remember that callback that takes three arguments, it takes the item, the index and the right.
I don't often use the right.
That's why we were only concentrating on the item and the index, but it does actually take three arguments.
And the first thing that we need to test for in our poly form in our custom code is that callback has
to be a function.
It has to be a function that takes these items as its inputs.
So let's switch over to the console and let's start writing our first bit of code.