Okidoki, let's see "console.count" in action.
So let's go to the most simple case, console.count.
And this is the fun thing with JavaScript, you can just start typing and go for it.
You won't break anything.
console.count().
How many times do you think it's going to show?
Of course, three.
So let's click enter and let's see.
Default text because we haven't provided any parameters and it's showed you how many times it's been
called - three times.
What's a more practical example, well, let's say you got some function call, okay, and this is a
"for-loop", so don't worry yet, we're going to get into this later as well,
let's just say I, we're going to call this thing 5 times.
And then we call console.count() and we can pass in a parameter, you can write anything in here and
lets say, "I have been called".
If I push enter now, what do you think's going to happen?
Yeah, it's going to be called 5 times, and it uses the text that you've put in here to cool call it up.
So that's console.count.
OK, what's another important console method you need to be aware of?
Oh, and I almost forgot about this
it's console.dir(). You have console.log()
but console.dir(), and I know it's going to sound weird, it prints the JavaScript representation
of the object to the console, whereas console.log(), on the other hand, prints the HTML representation
of that object.
What do I mean?
Well, you can see on the current screen, we've got Google open.
If I console.log the document, and remember what the document was? That's right, the document is the
page itself.
So if I go console.log() and I log the document
what's going to happen?
Well, what's cool is it gives me the actual document and you can see when I hover over it
this Chrome console highlights the area, the relevant area. I can open it up.
I've got the heading, I've got the body.
I can look at the whole HTML structure here.
But say I don't want that. Say I want to know what methods and objects are available on this from
a JavaScript point of view.
Well, console.log doesn't cut it, and that's where you type console.dir().
And I can do the same thing.
Let's look at that.
Looks the same.
Look what happens when I open it. How cool is this?
You can see all the methods
and properties available from a JavaScript point of view on all of this. You've got click events you can
add to it, which we're going to get into later, keydowns & all of that kind of stuff.
So that's another important thing you need to be aware of with console. It's a nice little tip that, um, not many people know of.
Alright, what else is there?
What else is there?
Oh yes, there's table which is quite cool - console.table().
Let's give you an example quickly.
console.table().
If I just execute table, nothing's going to happen because the table needs a list.
If you think about a visual representation of the table, well, you need data.
So in JavaScript, what we refer to as giving data is it's called an Array.
It's called an Array of data. And you enclose an Array in square brackets.
I'll show you what I mean.
So console.table(), open square bracket and let's go 1,
3, should we do one more? Let's do one more. 4.
Close square bracket. Execute. And how cool is that. It literally shows you a table.
You can even be more practical with it, say we want to display an object.
What do I mean by that?
Well, don't worry too much about the code.
Just understand the concept of what we're trying to do here.
So let's say we we we want a dog name.
Okay, the first name is Paw.
And I don't know,
the second name , the surname is Patrol.
So now we've got the dogName (object).
What about if we want that displayed?
Well, OK, first question is you're probably saying, well, let's just console.log() it.
Let's console.log dogName and that's cool.
You can see it displays it as an object to us, but the other way is that table method.
So let's go dogName.
How cool is that?
It lays it out for you, with the name and the property.
Name and the value, sorry, the name and the value. So that's console.table(). Another one we can look
at,
let's just clear this console,
another one we can look at is console.group().
And what happens is sometimes, you can already see how fill the screen is getting,
you get too many logs, and you want to group a specific category of logs together so you don't have
them all over the place.
How do we do that?
Well, that's from console.group().
Let me show you an example.
So say we want a group dogs.
Think about the "group" as the group heading,
so we want to call it "Dogs" and within there we want to console.log(),
I don't know,
an Irish Wolfhound.
OK.
And we want to console.log a Sausage Dog.
If I push return now, can you see how awesome that is, it has literally grouped them. And you can collapse it.
So if I open it, I can see my Irish Wolfhound and Sausage Dog.
And did you notice how when I clicked enter it (the console) automatically expanded it?
Well, we can stop that. If we do what we did before but you go groupCollapsed(), and now we hit enter
it literally collapses it
by default, it doesn't open it
by default.
What about if I put lists within lists?
Well, the awesome thing is with groups, you can do that.
You can make a list within a list.
Let's see how that's done.
OK, so let's say we want a list of animals and within the animals, we've got cats and dogs.
So we go console.groupCollapsed, and
let's call the main group "Animals", animals.
Now, we want dogs.
So let's do dogs, console.log
Let's do ... uh, sorry,
group()
Let's have a heading called "Dogs".
And then we want to do the same.
We want to console.log() Irish Wolfhound.
And we want to console.log() a
Sausage Dog.
Now, let's say we want to end that group -  console.groupEnd().
And now we want cats.
So let's go "Cats".
And what's a cat? Si, simese, Siamese.
And it's ... oh where did it go?
Ooo, don't know where it went, but its back.
And let's do one more console.log(), what's another cat?
Rag Doll, No, Rag, Ragdoll, I think that's one.
Okay.
And then we can do a console.groupEnd.
Now what's going to happen when I execute this? Check this.
Hey, where did it go?
GroupCollapsed, animals, group dogs, group end,
Why hasn't this worked?
Oh, now its worked.
Okay, don't know what happened there. But there is your group of animals, which is at the very top level.
If you
open that up, you got dogs and cats. So that's console.group().
One more I want to show you this console.time().
It's similar to the group method in that you need like an opening and closing call in order for
the browser to know when it starts and finishes.
So it just helps you measure time.
So say you've got a function and you want to optimize your website to go super quick.
You want to know how long it takes for it to do a certain event, you can use console.time().
Let me give you an example.
Let's say console.time(),
it's a math timer, for example.
All right.
And let's say we want a console.log()
some random number times another really big number.
OK.
And we want to measure how long that took. So we go console.timeEnd
end.
And here, bear in mind, just just better this in mind,
the description has to match the start description, because you think you might have multiple times going
on, so you want to make sure that this heading matches, that heading. And let's push return.
Bob's Your Uncle.
That is how long it took.
That's the result, sorry. This this it's a massive number. But this here is the result of your timer
call.
That's how long it took. It took 0.34 milliseconds to complete. At this point you're head is probably exploding.
And that's good, because what you've learnt is that the console object is powerful. You've got group methods
on it, you've got time methods on it,
You've got assertions, you have warnings, info etc
There's a lot you can do on just the console object, and not many people know that. So it's gonna
put you ahead.
But for you and I, by far the most important is console.log, and we're going to see that a
lot.
So let's continue with the course.