Yes, so you've heard that floating point numbers can do weird things.
Let me show you an example that'll just blow your mind.
And before I do, I just want to clarify that this problem is not only JavaScript related, it's actually
going to happen in any programming language that uses floating point numbers.
But now let me show you this quick example.
Here I'm using CodePen.
And I can just double click here because we're not using HTML and CSS, I just want to show you a JavaScript
example.
And let's define a variable "a" that is equal to 0.1 + 0.2.
It couldn't be simpler, right?
What do you think the answer should be?
Well, we know the answer should be 0.3.
But what happens when I console.log this variable a? Let's look at what it produces.
It's almost 0.3, but it's not quite. There is this random digit 4 on the end.
That is crazy.
Let me quickly zip across and show you why this happens.