Great, we're getting into it, but now you're probably wondering what is the difference between an
object constructor versus an object literal?
We know that an object constructor has to start with the finding object and we do this with the function
keyword and then an object literal just needs the opening closing curly brackets.
Both methods above creates a JavaScript variable called person.
The main difference, though, is what you can do with that variable with a constructor function.
You can create multiple instances with the new keyword, but with the literal notation, you only get
a single object.
Now this is just theory enough of it now.
Let's go code.
I'll show you what I mean.