In order to understand why 0.1 + 0.2 does not equal 0.3 (exactly), you need to understand
numbers.
And let's start with numbers that you and I understand and we've been brought up with, and that is
in the Base 10.
And all this means is that there are 10 symbols that represent all quantities. And we know this, we've got
10 fingers and this is probably why we've, we've done it this way.
So let's look at our 10 digits, our 10 symbols from zero to nine.
When we say zero, we just mean there's nothing. When we move one placement to the right,
we know that that is 1.
In this case, we have one warthog.
If we move one to the right, we know that represents two warthogs and so forth and so on.
When we get to five, we know it's five warthogs.
When we get to nine,
we know there are nine warthogs.
But what do we do now?
We've run out of digits.
Well, now we just repeat the process, but we separate out the 10s versus the single digits.
So we've got a one.
We've gone through the iteration one whole time. And now we start at zero again.
And that gives us our solution of 10 warthogs, represented by the symbol 1 and a 0.
You and I know it as ten.
And you can represent this in an entirely different way.
Let's take the number 32 for an example.
We know in base 10, we've got symbols that represent each digit.
And as I mentioned before, once you go through one iteration, you move along. So the three we can put
in the "ten's" bracket and the two we can put in the "singles" bracket.
And because we're working with Base 10, you can represent this as 10 to the power of (one times three) and
10 to the power of (zero times two)
To quick side note, anything to the power of zero is equal to one, not zero.
So this is known as the long format, but you're probably thinking "computers don't work in Base 10
format, we know computers only work in binary."
So let's take our 10 digits, our symbols, and let's break it down just to 2, because this is all
the computer works in, a zero and one.
And now let's start the process again.
How do we represent nothing?
Will this the same as our Base 10 - its just zero.
How do we represent one warthog?
Well, that's also the same.
It's just the number one.
But now what do we do?
Because now we've run out of digits, we've run out of symbols.
Well, we do the same process.
We start a new iteration. So to get to 2 warthogs, it is represented by the numbers 1 and 0.
What about three warthogs?
Well, let's keep going along - a one and a one. Can you see now we've run out of digits again?
No problem.
We start a new iteration - one zero zero would give us four warthogs, and you can literally keep going with
this process to get to higher and higher numbers.
So to recap, in binary zero is represented by zero,
and a one is represented by one. But two is already represented by one and a zero, because we need to scale
up just like in decimals
we did that after the number 9.
And if we continue, three in binary is 11, four is 100, and five is represented by 101,
and so on.
And this brings us all the way back to our (original) question - why does 0.1 + 0.2 not equal
0.3 in binary?
This isn't just a JavaScript problem.
This happens in other languages as well.
To find out why,
Let's just recap a little bit.
Remember how we said the ECMAScript standard only recognizes one number type in JavaScript, and that
is the double-precision, 64 bit binary format?
What does this all mean in this context?
Well, let's take another step back. In maths, 0.1 is a rational number. And all I mean by a rational
number is that it's the result of a ratio between two numbers, a one and a 10.
We have no issue with this because maths is typically Base 10.
So going one divided by 10 is doable in maths, and we know that is represented by 0.1. And we
can easily calculate numbers like 0.2, which is also two divided by 10.
But what happens with irrational numbers? Irrational numbers on numbers that can't be written with
a finite series of digits.
We cannot measure one third, for example, in Base 10.
What is one third?
Well, it's point three, three, three, three, three, and it just continues on forever.
And think about that - we actually cannot represent this number in Base 10.
Weird right?
But now remember how I said ECMAScript only recognizes one number, the double-precision 64 bit binary
value? Well, when you break that down
it uses different amounts of bits to store different pieces of information.
Remember in the previous lecture, we saw how you had the "significand", you had the "mantissa", the "exponential"
and the "base"?
Well, to cut a long story short, the reddish bits you see on the screen is what stores your actual
number. And it uses 52
bits to store that number. And in Base 10, we just took one and divided it by our base, which is 10.
But with computers, we only have Base 2.
So the first iteration we can do is only divided by two. And with 64-bit
this means we can only keep halving 53 times. And to represent this in a way that I think will make the
penny drop,
and you go, "Oh, I get it". Imagine
we had this pizza and we could only halve this pizza 53 times.
This is binary, and this is the smallest amount of a sliver we can actually get in binary.
It's the highest level of precision.
Now, once you've halved this 53 times, that slither is going to be tiny, right?
But let me ask you this.
Can you take a certain amount of those slithers, and add them up to get one tenth
exactly?
How about one fifth?
The answer is ... you cannot do it.
It won't give you the exact right answer.
Let's look at the number 0.1.
If you added up all those pizza slithers, immediately less than 0.1 is the number zero point zero
nine nine nine nine nine nine nine nine ...
... one six seven three three two, etc etc.
That's what you see on the screen.
And if you added one more slither (of pizza), you're going to get a number that's slightly more than 0.1.
And the difference between these two numbers is literally the smallest slice that you have to decide
whether to include, which introduces an upward bias or exclude which introduces a downward bias.
The JavaScript parser will prefer the higher number as it's closer to 0.1.
And this process is exactly the same for 0.2.
And what does this mean for us?
Well, it means the result is an approximation of 0.1 and 0.2, and both of them are scaled
upwards.
And this is why
0.1 + 0.2 is slightly higher than what we would expect.
And do you know what's interesting? If you didn't take the higher number of both of those, if the parser
didn't do that and you took the lower of the two, you would actually get a much closer number to the
true answer, which is point two
nine nine nine nine nine nine nine ...
... seven, seven, six nine, etc etc.
But the parser doesn't
that way, the interpreter does scale them both up, and that's why we get point three zero zero zero zero ...
four.
I hope this makes sense. For me
this was really a "Aha" moment when I came across it.
I think it's interesting, and I hope it helps you understand numbers in JavaScript in more detail.
This is really awesome.
Awesome stuff.
Let's keep going.