Before we move on from the console, there's just one brief thing I just want to go over and that's something
called "substitutions". And given its name, you can kind of guess that it's replacing something with something
else because you substitute one thing for something else.
In this case, in JavaScript, we denote this with the percentage sign.
In other words, you're replacing a percentage sign with something else.
For example, in JavaScript, a %s means you're going to be replacing that with a string.
So, for example, with console.log("Hi %s"), the second parameter is what's replaced with that
%s.
So in this case, it's going to display with "Hi there", and the "s" keyword is not the only thing available.
You've also got d, c and o, which replaces different things,
integers, CSS and objects in this case.
Let me show you a quick example, and then we can move on.
Cool.
So let's look at an example quickly.
Let's say we want to type "33 green apples", and we want to put these in a variable.
So we'll create here a variable, and we'll get into variables later,
and how much did we say? 33 apples, so let's say var number equals 33.
And let's say
the color is green.
OK, so we have two variables. We've got number and  color. And we want to display "33 green applies".
How would we do that?
Well, let's use substitutions ... console.log()
it's an integer which is d.
Second thing we want to display is a string, so whats that, that is an "s".
Is that right?
Let's see if that works! Invalid or unexpected token.
What did I do wrong here?
Oh, I forgot
to close that off.
ummmmm, no man, silly, silly, silly.
I put the percentage afterwards, it should be before. This is where not having a text editor is excruciating.
But there you go. So I've replaced the %d's with the number and the %s with the color, and
we get "33 green applies".
The reason why this isn't so important now is because ES6 has (introduced) "template literals", and these can
be a substitution to this approach.
Because this can be quite cumbersome.
Do you want me to show you what I mean?
Allright.
Well, we've already defined number and color.
So let's, let's use the latest syntax, and you'll see how much more easy it is.
You go console.log() and you use back ticks `` now with the new ES6 syntax.
And it's that little button above your "tab" key
or to the left of the number 1 key, but depending ...
(swoosh sound)
It's this little thing. You can see what it looks like.
Okay, you put two of them instead of quotation marks, and inside I can write,
oh, and then whenever you want to put in a variable, you've got to use a dollar sign and open curly
brackets.
OK, so here it's the number,
it's the color.
apples.
And if I execute that, we get exactly the same thing.
The preferred approach is the second approach, which is why I don't really want to harp on too much
about substitutions.
Cool.
Let's go.
Let's move on.