This might be a little bit advanced, but I believe, I believe you guys can do it.
It's interesting in the sense that we're going to be using a debugger tool in Chrome to ascertain whether
our variables are local or globally scoped.
How cool is this?
So let's quickly create something that we can test our variables in.
Well, let's start with an HTML document, a standard template. And let's start writing our JavaScript.
Remember, JavaScript has to be inserted within script tags.
And now let's define a variable called age, let's make that equal 3.
And we know this is a string (OOOPS).
And we know this is a number. And we would expect this to be a global variable.
So let's say
a global variable with type
number.
Now, let's create a function.
And let's just call it scope() for lack of a better word.
And let's create another variable now.
But let's make this a string and say it's "young".
And take a step back, what scope do you think this would have?
Hope you said local.
Local
variable with type
string.
And now I'm going to get more complicated.
Let's create
a block.
And let's create yet another variable. For the age this time, let's call it "old".
And in isolation
what would this IF block be? What scope would that be?
Yes, it would be a local scope, it would be a local block scope to be specific.
This should be a local block
scope variable with type String.
And to test it, we can console log age over here. Outside this IF statement, outside that block, we can
console.log age.
And outside everything
we can console.log age.
And remember, to execute a function we have to call its name, which we've called scope, with brackets.
Now you might be sitting there wondering, how do we know whether our variables are locally or globally
scoped? And if it's even locally scoped, how do we know whether its function scoped or block scoped?
Well, one way is to just use theory, sit down and figure it out.
But the other ways to use Google DevTools.
But before we get into DevTools, I just want you and I to think about each one individually.
The first age on the screen,
that I'd expect to be global.
We've defined that age outside everything.
Then we get to the function.
So when we define new age equals "young", I would expect that to only be available in function.
And then when we nest another block within that function, that age equals "old".
I would expect that to be only locally available within that block.
Does it kind of make sense?
So how do we see this in DevTools?
Well, there is another keyword in JavaScript, and that is "debugger". When you put that in your code and the
interpreter comes across it, it literally pauses the execution of JavaScript and it defines the variables
for you.
Let's see it in action.
So where do we want to put these?
Well, let's say on the first age.
On the global level, we want the debugger to stop execution.
We wanna see what that age is.
Then we get into the function. We defined
age equals "young".
Let's see at this point
what scope that age has. And then when we get into the second nested block, let's do the same thing.
All we've gotta do now is start the server, and we should be able to see the results in the browser.
And we've got a blank screen, and you'd expect a blank screen because we haven't defined any HTML. So, it makes
sense.
What we interested in now, though, is the JavaScript and those variables.
And this time, we're not going to be looking at the Console tab.
We're going to be looking at the Sources tab.
So, let's go into Sources. And as soon as we refresh,
let me just make this a bit wider,
as soon as we refresh, I would expect that debugger to kick in. Let's refresh the page.
And there, we've hit our first debugger.
And at this point, we've defined age within the script, which is global and you can see on the right
that's exactly what's happened.
It's got a "Scope" tab, and we can see the scope of our variables.
And remember how I said the interpreter executes code from top to bottom?
Well, this means that it's going to skip over this function for now because we haven't executed the
function.
This is only defining the function and it should hit this console.log age expression.
Let's see if that happens.
And it does. It hits the console.log age expression.
And at this point in time, what is age?
That's right.
It's the global age, it's the number 3.
So when we step over this and it executes and we just tab over to our Console tab, there's the number
3.
But let's go back to our Sources tab.
Let's continue. Now,
it's hit this scope function and it's going to execute the function.
So let's execute the function.
So here, it's hit age equals "young".
But look what it's done within the Scope tab, it's actually created a local variable.
And at this point, the variable is still undefined.
Remember, you need to declare a variable.
Then it gets initialized.
And this is what it's done here, its initialized,
but it hasn't yet been assigned a value - that comes in the next step.
Step down.
We stop at our debugger. Now it's assigned a value to the variable, and that is "young".
Let's continue, let's go into this IF block. I would expect the debugger to stop now at the age again.
That's exactly what it's done.
I hope you're starting to feel how cool this is. This is awesome, and you're probably actually understanding
this.
Very few people do. So well done. So now we've hit this IF block.
We've got the next "age", which we've defined as "old". Again,
it's been initialized, but not yet assigned a value.
But now it's been assigned.
Age is the value "old".
Now, when we hit this console.log age, we are still within this block.
So at this point in time in our code, we have access to the block variable, the local variable and
the global variable. How cool is that?
So, let's keep going down.
When we hit this console.log age, it's gonna console.log "old"
I would expect, because we're within this block.
So we step over that, let's head over to our Console, and there's "old". So it's working.
We go to our Sources tab.
Now we're hitting console log age.
But at this point in our code, look what's happened.
Our scope block doesn't have a block variable anymore.
It only has local and global.
And at the moment, we're in the local scope because that's at the top.
So our age is defined as "young".
SJOE, this blows my mind.
Cool
let's continue, so let me step over this.
I would expect "young" to have been consoled.
That's exactly what's happened.
So I hope this was a nice little bonus for you.
(music starts)
I hope this sets you on the path to using the debugger tools to understand globally, locally function
scoped and block scoped variables.
(music continues)