This section on functions would not be complete if we didn't discuss aero functions, air functions
or just a concise way, a quick way to define function expressions.
And it's one of the most practical changes introduced by year six or year 2015.
And the way I like to see it is that it introduces two major benefits benefit number one, which is
the most intuitive and obvious one.
It's just shorter to right.
It takes us less time, and it's easier.
Let's take our say hi function expression.
We know how that's written.
We've seen this before, so you can see with error syntax, we're taking double parentheses and we put
all the arguments in there.
We used the arrow syntax and then we define our code in the curly braces.
So it's very similar to the old way.
It's just a little bit quicker.
But depending on what we want to do with our code, we can even simplify it further.
For example, if you have no parameters meaning we not wanting to pass in variables or arguments, then
you can do this.
Let me show you an example.
If you don't have parameters creating function expressions, why the error syntax is super simple.
Let's have a look.
Let's define a variable called say hi.
And now ordinarily we would have to now include the keyword function.
Yeah, wouldn't we?
But not with error syntax.
That's what's so cool.
We can just have opening closing brackets.
We now have to include the Arrow syntax.
And then we have opening and closing curly brackets once again.
And this is just going to console.log.
Heidi?
And now what have I done wrong here?
For the record's console.log, say hi.
There you go.
And if I execute, say hi.
It console lungs, Heidi.
No problem with that.
But we don't even have to have the opening closing brackets do.
We could just have to underscore it's another example.
So let's go, let me say by equal and yeah, you just have to underscore.
Can't be much simpler than that, cannot have the errors and text the opening and closing curly brackets.
And yeah, we're just going to console.log.
Finally.
And that's said, if we execute dysfunction expression, we get by body.
Or if you have one parameter in the opening brackets or even optional, you don't even have to have
opening brackets.
Did me show you another example?
Okey, dokey, what about if you only have one parameter?
Well, it's very simple, it's define a variable again called say hi, remember or narrowly now we would
need the function keyword, but because we're using error syntax, we're replacing, that was the error.
So what do we do?
Well, when you've got one parameter, you don't even need opening and closing parentheses.
You can just write the argument and use the error syntax.
And again, opening closing curly brackets.
And then now or we want to dos console.log and we'll use template literals.
Hi.
Name.
There you go.
We've literally done it, we've replaced the whole complicated and cumbersome way of function expressions
into one line, and we can console.log this out.
To see if it works.
And this is undefined, oh, we forgot to pass in a name we passed in the name of Wally and says, Hi,
Wally.
So we know that works.
And the most simple way we can do that is if we are only returning an expression, we don't even have
to have the curly braces.
Let's have a look at a quick example of what that looks like who.
And now if you are returning an expression only, you don't even need curly brackets.
How insane is that?
Let me give you another example.
So let's say we have a function expression and we have a we're going to put that into variable could
end.
Now, ordinarily would need to put function, we don't have to put function because we're using arrows
and text say we've got two arguments.
Number one and number two and all we wanting to do now is we wanting to return the addition of these
two.
So you and I both know ordinarily we would put it in curly brackets and we can.
But the point is with arrows and decks, we can do away with that because now we're just returning an
expression.
We are returning number one plus.
I'm too, and I mean, that is just so elegant, isn't it?
It's beautiful, it's like art.
And if we execute this function and we pass in one and two, we get back three.
There you go.
There you have it.
The arrow index is much, much easier to use.
OK, so those are some some tactical differences with the arrows and text, but now something a bit
more meaningful benefit number two.
There's no binding of this keyword.
This is so crucial the error of function does not bind this.
And of course, this is theory.
Let me show you exactly what this means.