I want us to look at instantiation versus the singleton approach and a bit more detail and in a way
that you can understand.
We've already seen one of the main differences is that with a constructor function, you can instantiate
as many objects as you like and each object will be independent.
It'll be a brand new object.
However, with object literal syntax when you go and create an object, it always references the same
original object.
And this is known in the programming industry and you can google it.
Singleton.
Object literal syntax, you're literally creating a singleton.
All it means is that an object can only be instantiated once and that any references to that object
in the future, even if anyone still refers to the same object.
Let me show you what I mean.
So here we're going to be creating a constructor versus literal.
And let's first look at a constructive function.
OK, cool.
Let's get into it.
Let's create a person object.
And let's assume we want to give certain default values to this person object.
For example, let's say that we want the membership status to be false.
And then only once the user goes through the whole signup process does it actually become true.
It's also give it a default name, and let's even put an a in the image show you what I mean.
So let's created by the constructor function and remember what the two steps are.
What's the first step?
It's right, the first step is to define our object using the function keyword.
The second step is to call that object.
So let's do the first step and that is to define object.
Let's just call our object person.
Let's say this membership status is false.
And we'll say this name is just give a default name of only.
And now let's just put in a message as well to make it more interesting, and let's call this method
talk.
And in this method, let's just console log and we'll use template literals.
We've been through this before, we know what these are and we'll just say.
The.
Membership status.
Of.
This person's name is.
This membership status.
So there we have it.
We have a constructive function object all set up, ready to go.
You remember what the second step was?
How do we how do we access this?
How do we create a new object?
That's right.
We instantiated.
You need to instantiate the object before you can use it.
And let's say a user comes in our sorts and for lack of a better word, let's just call in person one
because new.
Person, and now it's cool as we have access to all these objects, we've seen this before in our example
says I just console one person one and we access the top method.
We go console logs.
The membership status of Wally is false and this is straight out of the box as what's really cool about
constructor functions.
But let me show you the difference is now, because that's what this list is all about.
Let's say a second person comes along.
Lake Person two equals new person, and let's say this person two goes through the registration process
and he changes his name.
And his name isn't Wally.
It's John.
When you get rid of this.
Each person will be, and this is the crux of it, unique.
So if we go person one to talk.
We've got a membership status of what is false.
But now, if we got person to dot org, what do you expect would happen?
That's right.
The membership status of John was false, and now we've literally created two different objects that
are independent from each other.
I can even go and person two and I can go person two memberships that are say they go through the whole
membership, they pay their membership fees and now their membership status is true.
You've got two distinct objects.
How causes?
And now you're probably wondering, okay, cool constructor functions, you've got it like it's making
sense, but how as object literal syntax work?
Well, initially, let me show you what I mean by the fact that object literal syntax creates a singleton
campus.
Let's create now.
Latrell Centex approach.
And let's start defining our object.
We've got a person we've got.
Membership status.
And we're going to set that to false as the initial value.
We've got a name which we're going to say to Wally is the initial value and we've got our talk function.
We'll talk method, and all that does is console looks.
The membership status of.
This name is.
This.
Their mission status.
So there you have it.
These are object literal object that we've just created, but how is this different to the first?
I'm interested.
Well, let's comment all of this out, so we don't get confused.
It's just common.
Everything else the and start looking at this house is different.
Well, the first difference is that we can use this object straight off the bat.
We don't have to instantiate it first.
Let me show you what I mean.
So this person, we can access a talk method directly.
We don't have to go person.
One equals new person with the object, literal syntax.
We can use it straight away.
And what I mean by this is a singleton.
Let me show you.
Say we wanted to create Tom that uses this object.
Construct how we do it.
Well, you can't just call person the same way we did with the constructor function.
We can't just say it tongue equals new person.
It's going to throw an era.
And you know, we see a person is not a constructor.
It's literally told us we are doing it.
But what about just saying, well, if Tom equals?
Person.
OK, so it looks like we can do that.
That's console.log, Tom.
And it has accessed all those properties and methods.
Cool.
It's all good, but let's try to change Tom's name.
Let's say Tom, his name.
And you guessed, this is Tom.
And now let's create a second person, second person comes along.
Sydney.
And Cindy says, OK, who?
Cindy's name is Cindy.
What do you think's going to happen, not when we access the top method on top men and talk method on
Cindy?
Well, let me first do the talk meter on Cindy.
It's more intuitive talk.
You need just console.log this oxygen infused Vega.
So Cindy says the membership status of Cindy is false.
It makes sense.
What about if I access the talk methadone, Tom?
Tom, talk, I know it seems the membership status of Cindy is false, says still referring to Cindy.
And this is the point I'm trying to make with object.
Literal syntax is that it's always working with the original object.
So any change you do here will affect that original object.
Let me just drive this point home by giving you one more quick.
A quick example with the literal notation you are always dealing with the same object.
Ding.
Ding, ding.
Singleton.
It creates an original object.
With name, virginal, simple.
Now, let's create a clone and then just equals the original object.
And this clone, we want to give a name of Clone.
So all we've done now is we've taken the original object.
We've created a new variable.
You mean, just comment all these aren't.
So we don't get confused.
Original.
There you go.
So all we trying to do here just take a step back as we've created an original object called original
and we've given in the name of original reasoning to find a new variable that is that object.
So you'd almost think intuitively what should happen is you've created a brand new object in memory
space that references a brand new object.
Then on that brand new object that we think has been created, we give it a new name of time.
So now you think that the two objects in memory one with the name turn one with the name original but
with object literal syntax?
This is a point that doesn't happen this way.
It references the same object.
So if I want to access the original object and console it and look at that, its name has now been changed
to Clone who this has been very importantly, to fight few tickets and very few people understand the
differences between the two.
It's continue because I do want to show you one more example.