Whew.
Okay, so let's take another step back.
Okay.
Unwind. Clear your mind.
Let's just see what we've learnt.
So we've learned that machine code can only speak zeros and ones, right, which is at the processor
level.
And there are all those horrible languages that we don't want to touch.
Then a little bit higher than that, you've got, you know, still low level languages.
Examples are C, C++ and they just require deeper knowledge of how hardware and underlying CPU's actually
work.
They're more difficult to write from that point of view.
And then you've got high level languages, which are very practical and very powerful.
And that's where JavaScript fits in.