Let's now quickly discuss Numbers in JavaScript.
Number is part of the window object.
Let me prove it to you. If we console.dir(), and remember
in a previous lecture when we were really getting into consoles, we saw what "dir" was. It was just
a way for you to console the JavaScript notation or value. In here,
we're going to pass in
Number.
And if I open up this Number, you can see that there are lots of methods and properties attached to it, and
this wasn't me.
This is native to JavaScript.
This is awesome.
This is what we have right out of the box.
Let me show you this example. Let's define "a" as 13, but let's say 13 is, we've put it in inverted commas,
so it's a string.
I'll prove it to you. If we're go typeof(a),
it's a string.
But what happens if we use the
Number method? Well, we can go
Let's go let b equals Number,
and we also pass it a 13 string,
what do you think is going to happen now?
Well, what does Number method does is it converts strings into numbers, if it's possible.
So if I go typeof(b),
I'll be a number.
How cool is that?
So you'll find that during your JavaScript career, you're going to be using Number now and again, because
you're going to want to make sure that whatever value you pass to a function is actually a number.
And what happens if we pass a random string, like dog?
I'd expect some sort of error to occur - that can't be a number.
So let's go
Number(dog).
(wrong buzzer sound)
Ah, that makes sense. NaN - not a number.
We're going to get into NaN a bit later. I want to show you a few examples now first.
So let's head over to JSBin.
And remember, I said that JavaScript only has one type of number and that is a floating point number?
Well, what do I mean by that? Well have a look here.
Let's let a equal 10, and b equal 10.00.
And this is a cool little tip here. I've defined two variables on the same line without using the "let"
keyword twice. Just a bit of a pro-tip there.
document.write(), so we can see it on the screen.
All I want to show you now is, is a equal to b? And from a JavaScript point of view, there is no difference
between 10 and 10.0000.
They are the same thing.
We can also use the exponential function for large numbers.
Say you're lazy and you wanted to write the number.
I don't know
3000.
What you could do is instead of writing three zero zero zero, you could write three, e,
three.
Simple. And we can document.write that,
and there's your 3000.
What else can we do in JavaScript?
We can add numbers together.
Lemme give you another example. Let's that say apples equals 10, and let pears
aqual to five, you can literally add "apples + pears", and the answer should be 15, as we would expect.
Alright.
And then the last thing worth mentioning is infinity. Remember if I go back to this console here, Google
Chrome, and we console this number,
and open it up,
we've got POSITIVE_INFINITY, and
NEGATIVE_INFINITY.
And intuitively, infinity is what, is what you would expect.
It is just an incredibly large number.
So let me give you an example now.
And let's say we've define a bigNumber variable.
By the way, that's a very big number.
And what I'm going to show you now is, let's say, if bigNumber equals
Infinity,
then I want to document.write()
"Let's just say this is Infinity."
And there you go.
I've just proven that in JavaScript, a really large number is going to be treated as the Infinity data-type.
And as you would expect, one plus Infinity will be Infinity and one divided by Infinity is going to
be, zero.
Let me show you.
One plus
Infinity.
It's just Infinity. And,
one divided by Infinity,
is zero.
I hope this is starting to feel more intuitive to you. I hope you're not being intimidated by it, it's just a
number and this is how we work with numbers in JavaScript.
Let's move on.