So you want.
He was.
You are down all that, sit back and enjoy the spoils of what you just learned, it has been incredibly,
creatively awesome to be with you.
Thank you for supporting me.
Thank you for getting this far.
I know it has been.
It's been tough and I hope you enjoy this teaser.
There's a lot we haven't covered in the critical rendering path, but like I mentioned, it's beyond
the scope of this course.
I just wanted to get a very high level overview of how the browser works.
Kind of.
We are experts in what is age it's all about and then how JavaScript specifically fixed the critical
rendering path in some things we can do to improve it.
Now we didn't discuss the future or we didn't discuss preload and custom motivations.
And the reason for this mentioning is just beyond the scope of this course.
But if you are interested in learning more, do the course.
If you're not, that's perfectly fine as well.
You've done incredibly well to get this call.
Thank you again for supporting me, man.
I'm excited to do another course.
I'll let you know in another courses that keep going and good luck in your career.
I'll see you soon.