Let's finish for the final part of our plentiful and that is to fix this, this issue.
So to make things easier, let me just delete previous console log.
And I just want to show you if we console.log this to the screen.
What would you expect to happen, what do you think is going to be shown on the console?
Well, let's have a look.
Let's run the function.
And then you go to the window object.
Why is this?
And what's even more weird?
This just kills console again.
What's even more weird is we put a break here and we start executing this.
Let's run the function and look at these local variables again.
OK.
The scope.
I'm going to step through our code.
We get to the array.
Now we get to the for each function, so it's going to hop into our custom check, it's going to check
whether the callbacks, not a function, it's going to pass that.
And this is what's interesting, right?
That this I hover over that when I use this keyword within the call, it refers to the right.
But when we get outside, when we get to this console log, it actually refers to the window object.
If I continue to execute this.
We going we stepping through now at this console.log.
We outside the side of the for each function, and now we're now hover over that.
You can see that this face to the window object.
How weird is this doesn't make sense unless you know JavaScript because it does make sense, and I'll
show you why in a second.
But before I show you and get into the nitty gritty of it, just take a step back and look at the different
ways we've just executed functions when we executed for each.
We did that as a method.
We executed it as a method.
That's when we actually execute the function, a callback function, look how we do it.
It's right, it's a regular function.
We're not accessing a method before we call it, we just executing that function.
And it may seem on the surface that that's a very subtle difference, but it turns out the subtle difference
causes profound effects.
But they may show you why.
Let me just jump to the other screen quickly and show you why this happens.
Oh, I feel your pain.
I know it can be difficult to get you hit around this and what?
It should refer to different areas of your code.
But this is just a very quick, high level overview of this and why it's doing what it's doing.
This is taken an example, and this creates an array with three values in it.
Don't cat and mouse.
And let's just say not our code yet one that we've been working with with our coliform.
And you'll notice when we go and execute that for each method.
As I just said previously, that function is being called as a method.
So we know this in this instance, the confusing, but we all know that this will refer to the array
in this instance.
But when we get our callback function, this is where things get very interesting because JavaScript
handles this very specifically when it comes to calling functions and how they're called.
When we pass a function to the for each method of the array, the value of this is the global object
window.
In other words, IT function will be a method of the object window.
And this is just the way that JavaScript works.
When you have a function that's not being called as a method, then by default, that function is actually
a method of the window object or whatever the global object is, depending on your JavaScript environment.
For example, if you're running a node, the global object isn't the window object.
It's called ironically global.
So we can say that it's kind of like the full each callback method is calling window, not callback.
And that's why when you use this, it's referring to whatever call that callback.
In this case, the window, the window object who accessed this at a very high level.
What's going on in the background?
But the question you probably asking now is, OK, cool, I understand.
But how do we fix the problem?
How do we define what this should refer to?
What about if I wanted this to avert my array, not the window object?
And as it turns out, it's a very simple solution to that.
Let's check it out.