It's clear that with the object literal syntax, you don't have access to a constructor.
Remember, with the constructor function, we could actually pass through parameters into their constructor
and set up an object the way we want to.
So if you want to show you what that means, let's have a look, let's say.
With A.
Constructor function, we can.
Construct our object.
With parameters, we asked.
Into it.
Let me give you an example that say, we've got an object, and let's just call it website Euro.
And we pass in our bureau of the website.
We say this euro equals the euro, we've passed into it, and let's say we want to create a method,
we want to show the euro.
And all it does is it just console logs this year are all very simple.
Nothing.
Nothing too complicated.
Now we've defined our object, what's the second step when using the constructor function?
It's right.
We need to call it with the new keyword.
So let's define a variable, and it's cool that my website and it's just say that's a new website and
it's passing the URL and say, this is my website dot com.
And we've done we've literally constructed this whole function.
We've got a method that can now call this new website, and the constructor function allows us to pass
variables as well.
If we go to my website.
And we go show you all this should console.
This is my website dot com to the screen.
Let need just start quicker.
And there you have it now with an object literal.
We don't have this amount of flexibility.
So what people tend to do to work around it is that you have to blend in it to function and you don't
have to call it in it, but it's just convention in the programming JavaScript.
Let me show you what I mean.
So how would we create this?
Well, maybe you can even give it a bit of a think before I show you the answer.
But how would you create the same set up with an object?
Literal syntax way?
You got to be a bit creative because you're going to have to create a function that you can call and
passing the perimeter three to one.
Let me show you.
Let's look at this now.
So with a object literal, you are unable to have a.
I'm struck.
Which means you are unable.
To initialize.
Your.
Object.
Unless and this is important, unless you add your own innate function.
And this is what I'm going to go through now.
So how do we do this?
Well, let's start creating this object.
So lit websites.
Equals it's created in it function.
This function takes a parameter, and you guessed it, takes a URL, and then all we wanted to do is
we wanted to set this objects euro to the URL.
Halston's seems weird.
But this is a way to get around the whole constructor, passing in variables and initializing your object
when you created.
Remember, with object controls, we've got a separate each key value pair with a comment.
And the second property we want on this is actually a method.
We want the same method as last time show you are on.
And that is just a function where we console log.
This year on.
So there you have it.
We've just created an object with a built in a day function.
And this is getting quite complicated, so don't worry if you're not fully understanding it, but you
will, you'll get it.
So now how do we use this now?
Well, we can access that in its function so we can go website and we can access the init function and
have our own our custom your old dot com.
So now we've run that function.
We sit this euro equal to our customers.
So when we admitted.
Show your.
It's done our own custom URL gets console.log to the screen.
But you can see it's not as intuitive using the constructor function, which is why you must use the
constructor function.
If you're going to be passing in a lot of parameters and you've got a lot of built in methods and complicated
things within your object.
It's better to use that constructor function, but if you want to create a simple object, the few property
developers that is perfectly fine to use object literal syntax you must just use whatever you want to
use is what I'm getting.
It doesn't matter.
Remember, there's no one right way to do something.
I hope this has been informative, but now we still have two other ways we can create an object in the
sky.
A look at them now.