We need to get our source code converted into machine code somehow before it can run.
And there're two main ways of doing this - what's called compiling the source code and what's called interpreting
the source code, and most languages you'll deal with will naturally fall into one or the other.
But I think it's worth knowing the difference because you are going to be encountering these terms a
lot in your programming career.
With a compiled language, what happens is you write your source code and then you have a program called
a compiler that will go through that source code and create a separate file that contains the machine
code.
The end result is sometimes referred to as an "executable file" because we can directly execute it.
The user can directly run the file and you as a programmer, you get to keep your source code (secret) and the
user never sees it.
Clyde, what are some examples? Well okay, programs, you know, or languages such as C++ or Java,
they need to be compiled before they run.
All that means is that the source code has to pass through a compiler, which is translated into byte code
that the machine can understand and then execute.
And when a program is compiled, it's often compiled for a specific platform.
For example, an IBM platform which will only work for IBM computers and no other platform, so it won't
work on Apple computers.
So what's interesting is that most high level languages today includes their own compilers, or they
have toolkits available that can be used to compile the program.
If you want another example, I mean, a good example of a compiler that uses Java is Eclipse.
And an example of a compiler used with C and C++ is the GCC command.
Depending on how big the program is, it should take a few seconds or minutes to compile. If no errors are
encountered while being compiled, then an executable file is (finally) created.