Who I guess what I just did this morning, my very first time I did a yoga session and I'm shattered.
We did this thing called angles cold and the bird of paradise pose through my mind.
So anyway, I'm in a lot of pain right now, but that should not stop us learning about JavaScript.
And very specifically, I want us to learn about this method called to lower case.
It sounds simple, but I just want you to understand exactly how it works, because it's a very, very
useful method provided to us straight out of the box by JavaScript.
Now, although it doesn't take any arguments, it is a super practical method.
Why?
Well, in many cases you want your takes or you want your strings to be case insensitive, a.k.a. you
don't want capital to think whatever it is you're doing.
For example, if you've got a list and a user types in a certain word, sometimes you want to see or
you want to compare whether that word is in the list and you don't want capital to ruin your formulas
in that case.
Why not just convert everything to lowercase?
And in order to do that, we use the two lowercase method.
So without further ado, let's jump into the presentation quickly, and let's start talking about the
two lowercase method.
Enjoy.
So what exactly is this two lowercase method?
Well, very simplistically, all it does, and it's very intuitive.
It converts your text all into lowercase.
In other words, the two lowercase method returns the calling string, the string you've called it on.
It converts it strings value all into lowercase, and I could just stop here.
But I want you to know just a little bit more about this two lowercase method.
Firstly, it is a JavaScript function is provided to us by the JavaScript language.
Second, D does not take any arguments, but don't let that fool you.
It's still a very powerful method.
And what I really want you to understand here and I want to pause on this point, is that the two lowercase
method does not alter the original string.
Instead, it generates a new modified string.
Yes, with all lowercase letters.
Then we hop over to the console and show you what I mean by this.
OK, so we know that the lowercase method does not affect the original string.
I just want to prove it to you now.
How am I going to do that?
Well, let's create a string, and let's just call it sentence original.
And it's just say we make that equal to crazy frogs or just, well, you know, crazy.
How's it?
And then let's create a new sentence.
OK, so let's call it sentence lower.
And here I want us to access our original sentence.
And this is what I want us to do next.
I want us to access the two lower case method.
And what's really awesome is that because we have a string and this sentence original is Typekit string,
we automatically have access to JavaScript to lower case made it onto.
We access that we existed with the dot notation.
And of course, we can just start typing to lowercase and our I.D. already picks up this method so I
can just click tab open and close parentheses to execute that method.
And we are done and dusted.
Now I can open up a browser and we can console.log things to the screen, but I want to use something
called quokka.
If we go to my Extensions tab here and I just start typing Quokka.
You can see I've installed Quokka in my I.D..
It's really, really useful, so highly recommend it.
And all we need to do to run Quokka is we literally call up the search box here.
Push control, shift p on my keyboard.
And I want to start quokka on the current file.
It's just an extra plug in and that allows us to execute JavaScript in real time in this file.
It's all it does.
So here we go, and all I want to do is I want to log out the sentence original.
And you can see the blue ticks there.
That's what's being consoled.
Let's see what's being returned to us by JavaScript.
And this is quokka working.
It just allows us to see our effects in real time.
Very useful.
Now what do you think is going to happen when we return sentence lower?
Well, I'm sure you've probably already guessed us all that's going to happen as we get exactly the
same thing, but all in lower case.
That's what I've managed to prove to you.
Is that our sentence?
Original.
That original sentence that we wrote together is unchanged.
This two lower case means it does not alter that original string.
OK.
Kind of making sense.
I'm sorry.
Let's continue.
OK, also, we've seen that it doesn't alter the original string.
In fact, it generates a new one.
But at this point in time, you still may be scratching your head.
You may be going cool and know it's provided by JavaScript.
But we exactly.
Does it come from?
And the answer to this is Drumroll, please.
That comes from the string object and JavaScript.
And just remember that the string object is a global object for all strings.
Again, let me hop over to the console and just show you where we can find it.
Let's pick up exactly where we left off.
Remember, we wrote the sentence, we converted it to lowercase.
Now I just want to prove to you that it has to be on a string.
So one way to do it is we use the type of operator that's console.log.
And let's go type of.
And we want to look at what our original.
Time is, and we can see what's returned to us by JavaScript is a string type, so we know our sentence
original variable is a string and that is why we could execute this two lowercase method.
But you probably wondering where is this exact method from and how do you see it?
Well, it is very, very simple.
Let's just go and open up a browser.
So I'm just going to right click on my Chrome new incognito.
And let's go to the console cooking.
That's opened up the console museum, and so you can see what's going on, and it's very simple.
All I want to do is I want a console, dirt and dirt.
By the way, is the front to console log.
It gives us whatever we want to do out, but in JSON like format, in a tree like format.
And of course, what I want to do is I want to get JavaScript string object because remember, we know
our original sentence is a string.
So we know of type string.
And if we open up string again, it's not much on here.
We've got links, we've got name.
But what we want to look at is this prototype because it inherits a lot of methods and properties and
because it's a string, its prototype as a string.
Here we get lots of methods and properties from the string type.
And if we scroll down, we should find two lowercase.
And there it is, yes, and here we go, we've literally famished, you know, exactly where it comes
from.
Hope is making sense.
We're not quite done.
So let's jump back into the ledger.
We've seen that it comes from the string object, and I guess it's quite intuitive.
It only works with strings if you try pulse in other data types such as null, undefined or even a number,
the JavaScript parser will throw you in error.
In fact, you'll get a type error.
So just make sure you take the type before passing it into this function.
Otherwise, your app will crash.
What am I talking about?
Well, let me jump over to the console once again, and let's start coding together just to see this
in action.
One last thing before we finish this off, remember we saying that it can only be used on a string type,
so let's scroll up.
We've actually just finished off, be picking up exactly where we left off.
It's clear the console.
So what does this mean?
Well, this means if we have a number, let's just say eighty font and we try and access to lower case.
What do you think is going to happen?
Well, we get a syntax error, invalid or unexpected token.
We can't call the two lowercase method on a number.
Makes sense.
What about kind of an array?
So say we've got a meringue just with one night a minute called.
And we try access to lowercase.
Is it going to work?
No, we get a type error.
We cannot call this function on that.
What about undefined?
Well, if we try and access again, two lowercase.
On undefined, again, it's not going to work.
And what about now, if we try now?
Do you think that'll work?
You know, so this is the point I'm trying to make.
We can only access the two lowercase method on strings.
I hope you're having fun and I'll be learning a lot.
So this is just a little bit more detail on two lowercase method that you might have not known previously.
Keep going, stay motivated, and I'll see you in the next lecture.