Who we have come a long way.
Alright, the fourth way to create an object is with forces, specifically the East 2015 class syntax.
Other programming languages, for example, Java, Python, they use classes to define objects, and
people were battling to understand Java scripts, prototype or inheritance.
Again, we're going to have a whole bonus section on project talks and how that all works.
But it is confusing, especially if you have come from another language that uses class syntax.
So to solve this problem in 2015, ActionScript or year six introduced classes and under the hood,
and I want to stress this JavaScript is still the same.
This class that has been introduced is just syntactic sugar.
It's kind of a sugar coating, but it doesn't change JavaScript in any way.
JavaScript still uses prototypes.
It just now rips it within the class keywords, so people coming from other languages are not that intimidated
by it.
Let me show you how classes work.