Before we get into coercion, I just want to explain Operators to you. In particular I wanna be discussing
unary
vs binary operators.
And I wanna draw your attention to the plus "+" sign, the "+" unary operator. When that's placed in
front of a value,
it (the JS parser) tries to convert that value, whatever it is, into a number.
So you can understand if that value is already a number,
it's going to do nothing, but if it's not a number, it's going to try and convert that value into
a number.
And that really is the only difference between a unary operator and a binary operator.
Let me show you exactly what I mean.
I'm just going to be using Visual Studio Code here, similar to what I did last time.
With Quokka. Okay.
So let's start.
Let's go a = 1.
And if I console.log(+a), it's just going to return 1.
What about if we go "let b = -1"?
And I console.log(+b)? Again, it's just negative one. And all this means is that really we don't
really need the unary operator here at all.
We could get rid of it, and it would just be the same thing.
There is no difference.
But remember what I said, if it's placed in front of a value that's not a number, it will
convert that to a number.
So let me give you an example.
let c = true.
And we're going to get into coercion soon,
just understand that intuitively, you'd think true is 1 and false is 0.
So we console.log, and if we console.log(c), we get true, which is what you see.
But if we put the plus + unary operator in front of "c", it will coerce that to a number, which is 1.
And we can do the same thing,
another example is a string.
Lets define an empty string and let's
console.log(+d).
And because it's an empty string, it coerces it to 0.
And if you're really sharp, you would have picked up that this unary operator is exactly the same as Number. Remember,
JavaScript also gave us the Number function.
Let's say e = false
and we console.log(e).
It'll just give us false.
You know that.
But what about if I go Number.
It'll give us zero. And that is exactly the same as if I didn't do that,
and I just put the "+" here.
So actually, the + unary operator just gives us a bit of a shortcut, which is awesome.
And let me show you why practically it's cool.
Let's say we've got 10 apples, but we put it in a string.
And let's say we've got 5 pears in a string, and you wanted to add these together.
Apples, plus
pears.
Now, the normal binary operator "+" will try and concatenate these two things, it will combine these
two things as strings.
So you've got here, an answer that looks to be 105, but it's actually not 105,
it's a 10 and a 5 that have just been placed together because JavaScript thinks they are strings - its text.
So to get around that, we just need to place the unary operator in front of the apples and in front of
the pears.
And JavaScript knows now to interpret those as numbers.
It's coerced them into numbers.
And if you didn't want to do this way, and you wanted to do it the long way,
you'd have to literally write Number, open bracket,
pears.
And you'd have to do the same with apples.
Number.
It's just a lot longer.
So, using the plus "+"  unary operator saves us time.
Let's get onto ... coercion.