So what exactly is this of Ray from method all about?
Well, very intuitively and very basically all it does is it creates an array from an array like object
on its object, but I'm not going to get into that now.
Similarly, just like the two lowercase method, the array from Method is a pure JavaScript function.
In fact, it was introduced as part of iOS six.
Yes, six, by the way, was just a major overhaul and upgrade to iOS five.
And you're probably not scratching your head, but you may have already forgotten where does it come
from?
And we just saw it comes from the array object itself.
But these are all things that you already know.
So how does it work?
Well, it's very easy to access this method.
We start off by accessing JavaScript array objects within access.
The from method and the from method takes an argument and its argument is an array like object.
But before we talk more about what it does, it's hop over to the coding editor and let's start seeing
how it works in action before we start getting into more detail on the array from method.
I just want you to understand how it works.
So remember what I said?
It has to be an array like object on editable object in order for us to use this array from method.
So how does it work?
Well, let's define an array like object.
And let's just be very, very simple here, let's just say what, so we know it's a string in this case.
How does the erase from look like?
Well, firstly, I just want to say I have a quicker open, OK, just allows us to run JavaScript real
time in our text editor so we don't have to keep jumping to the browser.
It's just a lot quicker to kind of write up your code.
It's very handy.
Anyway, how does it work?
Well, let's console.log something, and let's access JavaScript array object on there.
We know there's a method called from.
And we wanted to pass in our array like.
And as you can see, it takes our array like object outputs and is converted into an array, which is
really, really awesome.
And you can see our array just consists of each letter in that string.
It's all.
It's done.
It's all back to the lecture.
Cause they're making sense, we looked at a very simple example, but just bear in mind that what does
this array like object mean?
It just means that the object needs to have a length property and indexed elements.
What do I mean by this?
Well, let's hop over to the console again and this just look at exactly what I'm talking about.
All right.
So we've looked at this example here, but how and why does it work?
Remember, the array from Method will not work on everything.
In fact, as the description kind of season as we've spoken about, it only works on array like objects.
And what that means is that the object needs to have a length property and therefore index elements.
What do I mean?
Well, it's got a console, so let me right click on Google Chrome here.
New incognito mode.
And did you go to a console?
So kind of making sense, can you see that?
And remember what we said, let's just define dog or array like object as what?
And we know that the array from is it works on this, we just saw an example of that.
But why?
Well, to show you, let's console out this array like object and I want to look at its protein.
And if we learned this out, we know it is off Typekit Street, and if we open up the string method,
what's awesome is that we've got this Lynx property.
That's what I mean by an array like object.
It has to have this link properly in order for the array from makes it to work.
So there you go.
Hope it's making sense.
Let's jump back into the picture.
Alright.
I hope it's time to kind of make more sense to you.
And remember what I said earlier that it does take more than one argument.
Actually, it can take up to three arguments, can take a map and it can take what you want this to
refer to.
Bear in mind, these arguments are optional.
We don't have to put them into this function at all.
And a lot of people actually combine the this optional argument into that map function itself.
So oftentimes you'll just see two arguments in the array from method.
Anyway, I don't want to go into too much detail about this.
I can quickly show you what the map is all about.
So let's hop over to the text editor again, and let's have a look at how that would work.
Last but not least, let's see how the second argument today array from function works.
What is it all about?
Well, let's delete everything we had on our screen previously, and let's define an array is just say
that our air has a dog.
And you guessed it a cat.
Very simple.
Now what I want to do is I want to define a hand of function.
I want to take everything inside the Syrian.
I want to log something out of the screen.
So let's use JavaScript function keyword.
It's cool that handler, we can call it whatever we want.
The handler is going to take an animal in each case, and all I want to do is I just want to return
a statement and I'm going to be using template literals here.
And all I'm going to say is I'm going to say a.
Animal.
Went walking, walking.
So there you go.
That's nothing too profound.
It is a very, very simple function.
Now, what do I want to do?
Well, let's console.log.
Let's assess the array, the from method we know we want to access this array type.
And as you can see, if we just keep it with one argument literally does not make sense for us to do
so because it is an array already.
So there is no point of creating an array from an array.
It's the second argument that map and I want us to understand.
And the second argument is what we've defined as this hand function.
And then we go, What's returned to us on the screen is a dog walking and a cat went walking.
This is a new arena.
It's created a brand new array, and it's taken each item in the original array posted through our map
function and it's returned to us.
A new array is that kind of makes sense, and that's what it's all about.
Hope you're having fun, and I think by now you kind of have a good, intuitive feel for how this works.
So well done.
I'm very, very impressed.
Here we go.
I hope it's starting to make a bit more sense.
And don't worry, you know, as you come across these in your coding career, you'll start using it
more and more, and it will become a lot more intuitive.
I just wanted you to know about the ray from method because it is and it can be extremely handy.
Which brings me on to the next topic, and that is why do I need to know about the array from me said,
why did I even discuss it in this course?
Well, sometimes we want to work with methods that are only available from the array object.
For example, the for each method is only available on the right object.
And in order to access that method, we sometimes have to convert what we working with in our code into
an array.
Does that kind of make sense?
And over and above this, the array from method is extremely useful.
It allows you to do lots of other things like cloning arrays, removing duplicates, even filling an
array, etc., etc. There are a lot of things you can do, and most definitely, you're going to be
using this when working with Dom collections.
And it brings me back to the first point.
Sometimes we want to use methods that are only available on the array object.
So when you're working with a DOM collection, for example, in H2 multiplication, sometimes we need
to convert that into an array object in order to access methods we want.
So I guess what I'm trying to say is that it comes in handy when you encounter and work with array like
objects.
Hope that is providing a little bit more clarity on what this method does.
Don't worry, we're only just getting into it.
So don't panic if you don't fully understand it yet, it'll come through time.
Hope you enjoyed the school so far.
Hope you stay motivated and I'll see you in the next lecture.