And now, I want to just mention coercion.
A very important topic in JavaScript.
What do I mean by coercion? Well, sometimes in JavaScript, what it does, is it's smart and it thinks on our
behalf and it says cool
I'm sure you meant this,
therefore, let me just fix it for you and then continue the flow of the code aka everything doesn't blow
up.
Let me show you what I mean.
A is 10, let b equal 5,
but look what we've done.
Can you see what we've done?
We put the 5 within quotation marks, which means JavaScript is going to treat that as a string.
That's a string
we've just defined there.
So what do you think's going to happen when we add
the two  (a & b) together?
Look what JavaScript has done.
It's concatenated, meaning it's combined the 10 and then its slotted the 5 behind it.
So you think that's a 105, but it's not really a 105, is it?
It should be 15.
But we've accidentally put that as the string.
Now, most other languages would have thrown errors here. They would have said you cannot add "a" and "b". But
JavaScript hasn't done that.
It's actually coerced the two together and put them together.
That's a cool thing about JavaScript, but it also means you need to watch out. What's another example?
Well here, here's a fun one.
We wanna write to the screen.
What do you think is going to happen when you go "5 < 4 < 3"?
What do you think that's going to display?
Intuitively, I would have thought that would have been false. JavaScript
displays that is true, and let's understand why.
This is where coercion comes into it and operator precedence. So JavaScript within in these brackets
here, operates from left to right.
So first it's going to evaluate "5 < 4" And what is 5 < 4?
What is that going to evaluate to? Well, 5 < 4 is going to evaluate to false.
So this is going to evaluate to false.
And is false
less than 3?
And this is where coercion comes into play because in JavaScript
true is a 1 and false is a 0.
So is 0 less than 3. The answer is yes.
So it's coerced false into a number 0 and it's given you a result.
So there you have it.
You're starting to understand coercion now as well.
You're understanding that JavaScript executes from left to right.
I really am getting through this fast, guys, but I spent years learning all this, so I really, really
hope this puts you on a path to success.
Let's continue.