Who we are getting there?
Let's go.
I want to show you now an example of a class object, but before I do, I want to use a constructor
function and I know I've been doing that a lot, but I just want to have a very simple one, just so
you can compare the differences between the two.
This is all about classes, and let's do example one where we use.
A constructor function.
And remember, the first step to reconstruct the function is to define the object.
And this just to a person.
Which gets passed in a name, and we seek the new objects name to the name that we passed in the person's
name will be the name we passed in.
But now let's say on this object, this constructor function, we want to include a greeting method
that can greet the use of by the name.
Now, one of the problems we saw when we saw in the previous lecture is that if we use the constructor
function and put the method inside its body, inside its block like this, if we go this in the school
of greeting equals function, blah blah blah.
If we put it in there, we saw that every time you create a new instance of this, this greeting method
is being stored in that new variable.
And that's just a memory leak.
It's just a waste of space slows your system down.
So what we saw was we can access the person and on the prototype, we can include a method called greeting.
And let's do this not.
And all those greeting was to just console log.
The snake.
And what's the second step with a constructor function?
That's right, we need to instantiate, we need to call the object.
So let's go, let's use it equals new person.
And let's say his name is Wally.
And because we've set the greeting method on the prototype, we can access the star Ricky right now.
For example, user beating and IT console logs, Wally.
This is intuitive and you understand us.
So now that creates the same object with the class syntax.
Now, before actually going to class syntax, can you see my I.D. has already put three dots below that
P Alema function constructor?
Can you see that?
And if a hover over it?
It sees this constructor function may be converted to a class declaration.
So it's actually saying to me, Hey, we can convert our constructor function into a more up to date
class and text way of declaring this object.
But anyway, I'll leave that day for now so you can compare the differences.
You'll see how similar they are.
So with the constructor function, the first step was to try to find your object, and we used that
by using the function keyword or with the clause syntax.
We don't use a function.
Key word we user what keyword drum roll do we use?
The class keyword.
So class person.
And then we follow it by opening, closing curly braces so you can see we've just created a class object.
But now the only difference is is it with a constructive function?
We POSTECH name variable within it was a class object.
We have to define a constructor function and it's simple and it's intuitive.
You call it the constructor and the construct is going to take in a name.
Variable and we going to set the new variables name to the name, we pass into this constructor function.
Whoo!
So there you have it.
It's the first part that we've replicated on that constructor function.
And you can see how some lengths and text it is always done, though different times that we've defined
a constructor method within this class, within this object.
The other thing now that we want to do is one edit creating method.
Remember?
Well, when we use the constructor function, we had to explicitly put it onto the prototype of it.
It was a class.
Any method you actually declare in it is automatically put on the prototype.
So it actually helps us automatically allocate methods in the most optimal way.
You don't need commas or anything to separate.
These are.
You can just keep going.
Yeah, we're going to define a greeting function.
And all we want to do is console log.
The name, right?
And there you have it, we've created a class that results in the same object.
And what we just did above with a constructor function.
Let me comment this out and then I'll show you I just don't want conflicting variable names.
And let's look at an example.
And what's awesome about this is that we still have to go through the same processes with a class than
we did with the constructor function, remember step one was to define your object.
We've done that now.
What stick to?
That's right, we've got a call object, so let user equal new person, and now we're going to put it
in the name Wally.
And it's very similar to what we've been seeing previously.
Now the screeching method, if we go use a greeting.
It console logs Wally to the screen.
How cool is this, but we're not quite done.
I just want to show you three things very quickly.
You know how I keep telling you how the class syntax is so similar to a construction function?
Well, a constructor function is a function, so you expect this class that we created to also be a
function.
Right?
Let me prove it to you.
So let me say here in JavaScript.
A class is a kind of function.
And it puts the methods.
We create here into the prototype.
Property.
Improve this to you.
It's console log the type of.
Person.
And there you have it.
It is a function.
But what function is it?
I would expect it to be the construct function.
Remember, for the constructor function, we if you console.log the function out, it would actually
throw you back the constructor function.
So I'd expect the same here and I can prove that to you as well.
So let's console.log the person.
Class Person, which we just created, and we know that's a function, and it's tasters are saying,
is that equal to?
The person.
The prototype and the constructor on that prototype.
And the result is true.
So you can see that these things are just exactly the same.
And the final thing I want to prove to you is that can you see my second statement on it says using
the class puts the methods we create into the prototype property.
So how many methods should we have on the prototype property of this person plus?
Well, would expect to one called constructor and one called greeting.
And the cool thing with JavaScript is you've got in-built methods on that global object that allow us
to access and taste what properties we have.
So it's console.log, let's access the global object.
And this is a property or a method called gate property names.
That's what we want.
We want to see all our property names on our person object.
But the prototype of it?
And you can see they we've got to construct and greedy who this is cool.
This is really getting advanced.
Hope you starting to get a feel for these things.
I mean, just take a step back.
We've done a lot.
We've created objects by the literal syntax, construct the functions, object of create.
And now we've just done it via the class method.
And don't worry if you've been a bit confused with this loss section, now we're going to get into prototypes
in the next section.
I'm going have a whole bonus of it, but just take a step back and realize, like there's so many different
ways in JavaScript to create objects and we can play around with these things all day long.
But the truth is, you must just get comfortable with what you enjoy the most.
And in some situations, you're going to prefer one over the other.
So let's continue.
Let's let's have fun.
Go get a coffee, go get a coke.
Whatever pumps you up.
Maybe not a whiskey you need.
You need a good mind for these things.
And let's let's continue.
I'll see you in the next lecture.