OK, so here we are, and I want us to start coding together, but I want us to go step by step slowly,
slowly catch a monkey.
The first thing we mentioned is that this index of existence on two data types in JavaScript and the
first item type we are looking at is the array semi.
Prove it to you before we go further in our coding when a console log all its just console dir.
The array object if we openness and we look at its prototype.
There is an index of method.
Here we go.
Can you see it?
So now I've just proven to you that it does exist on the array, the global array object in JavaScript.
That's where it comes from.
All right.
Now let's go to our coding editor.
I've just got a blank JS file open here and I'm running Qualcomm quick is very useful, by the way.
There is a useful I keep saying it, but it is very good.
OK, the first thing I want to kind of get across to use one is an array.
Well, firstly, let's create an array and we use it by the square brackets here.
And I just want to say I am the first element.
And the second element and you guessed it, I am the third element, see how we go.
We've created an array, we've used those square brackets.
And how do we access arrays will first thing I want to mention is that JavaScript arrays Osiris created
what I mean by that.
I just mean that the first element of an array is always indexed at zero.
And the lost element can always be found at the index that's equal to the value of the Erase Links property
minus one.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's console log our array and remember how I said that it's zero indexed.
So to access the first item in the array, we Typekit zero.
I'm the first element, and of course, we can do that for the next item, right?
We can go zero, one and two.
I'm the first on the second on the third element.
That makes sense.
And the other thing I want to mention is that every Ray has a length property, so if we console.log
out our array and we access this property called links, we know that our array has three items.
So a very handy tip when it comes to coding.
And I'm even going to comment here.
We can always access.
The last item.
In an array like this, and this is very, very useful, so please remember this before I type out the
solution, just think about what it is we've just done.
We know the raised length is three, and if you look at that console just above, we know we've assessed
the lost item by using array and the index two.
Because remember, JavaScript arrays are always indexed at zero.
So we know the lost item in the array is that array length, which is three minus one, which gets us
to two.
So all I'm trying to say is to access the lost item and array, all we have to do is access our array.
And now if you don't know what the link is, it's very handy to access the link property, which in
this case is undefined because there is no fourth item in the array.
So you always minus one.
Does that make sense?
I hope so.
And I hope you sign to get a more intuitive feel about how arrays work.
The other thing I want to mention.
Let's just delete this man.
I hate deleting stuff sometimes.
Have you spent so long to try and get a point across and then I just delete it?
It's a bit sad, man up, dude.
All right.
But anyway, let's create a new right one, two and three.
The other thing I want to just mention with arrays that are quite peculiar is that you cannot use the
dot notation to access items.
This is an important point.
So for example, if we console.log our array and we try and get the first item, it's not going to let
us do it.
We actually get a syntax error.
So just bear that in mind.
And it's not, you know, there's nothing special about this.
In fact, JavaScript properties that begin with a digit can never be referenced.
The documentation must voice assistant using bracket notation.
It's just a nuance of JavaScript.
Don't worry.
OK, but you are probably wondering why I don't want to learn about arrays.
We are on the topic of index of and you are 100 percent correct.
I just wanted to kind of get you familiar with arrays before we jump into it.
OK.
The point I want to make with index of is that it returns the first index at which a given element can
be found in the array.
If it doesn't exist in the array, negative one is returned.
What do I mean?
Will lead us to find an array called animals, and it's got a warthog.
It's got a giraffe.
And it says, got a buffalo and it say it's got a lion.
How does it work?
Well, let's look, it's console.log so we can actually see the result of what we're producing.
The first thing in order to access our index is to access an array and array.
We're going to access is our animals.
All right.
We want to now access the index of method, which is inbuilt into all arrays.
And let's search for target.
What would you expect to see?
We is warthog located.
That's right, it's located at index zero.
Remember, JavaScript arrays are always indexed at base zero.
So if we try and find talk.
We can see returned to us is zero.
That makes a lot of sense.
And I'm just going to duplicate this code.
Let's now search for Buffalo.
What do you think the index number there to be?
That's right.
I would expect no to see if that's right.
You know, what I want to do is let search for dog.
What do you think's going to happen with dog?
Well, as I mentioned, if it's not found negative, one is returned to us.
Who does that make sense?
So just remember, negative one means it's not harmful.
And the last thing I want to mention just before we move on is that the index of method compares elements
in your way using strict equality.
In other words, using the same method used by the triple equals sign.
Just remember that.
Cool.
Okay, Clyde, this is all well and good, but we are only using one argument in this index other way.
I want to use both, and I want to understand it in more detail.
Well, it is good to hear my fellow student list delete all these consoles.
Let's now look for this warthog animal, but let's tell our index of that.
We only want to start in the second item in our array, a.k.a. from index one onwards.
What do you think will happen then?
So let's go to our second argument in this method, and it's said we wanted to start from the second
item in their aim.
Well, of course, it doesn't exist because we know we look looking from giraffe onwards and there is
no warthog, the.
Let's look at another example that's now look at Buffalo.
And install our index automated to search from, say, the third item in the.
Number two, and in this case, it does return our index number.
So it's very, very cool and we know it does exist.
This is kind of holistic.
An argument works that kind of making sense.
I hope so.
We worked a lot of the raise, but now I want to jump back to the later and I want us to look at the
second data type where we can start using this index of method.