Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I'm getting confused.
Let's just take a step back.
So the process of converting your source code to machine code has to happen, somehow.
And it's just a question of how much of this happens on your machine when you're coding versus how much
of it happens on the other uses machine, and that determines whether it's compiled versus interpreted.
For example, C, C++, Objective-C,
these are all typically found as compiled languages, so you need a compiler installed. And the compiler
can be downloaded for free, but they're often built into IDEs.
The good news and I've mentioned this before, is that JavaScript is an interpreted language. But now
you are well on your way to understanding different types of languages.
How JavaScript fits in.
Why JavaScript is such a powerful language in terms of how its converted into machine code.
And with that said, let's move on.