Now, are we going to be getting into a race shortly and on the topic of objects?
I just want to take a step back and dive a bit deeper into how engines view objects.
It's important because at a very high level, all JavaScript engines work the same way.
There's a Porsche that goes through your code and then there's an interpreter and a compiler that optimizes
that code into machine go.
But now I want to just discuss the JavaScript object.
It's interesting, and we're going to be looking at a few different implementations of this in the upcoming
lectures.
So this is cool more just a very quick intro into the JavaScript object model.
And when I think this button, we're going to dive into the later.
As I mentioned, this is just a quick introduction to the JavaScript object model, and what I mean
is that how does the engine set up an axis object properties?
Because once you start becoming an awesome programmer, you're going to want to understand the intricacies
of objects, how the engine accesses these, you can encounter bugs and now you'll know how to fix them.
So these are good things to know anyway.
The starting point is to know that the script specification essentially defines all objects as dictionaries.
What I mean by that is that you've got keys on each object, and those keys are meant to what's known
as the JavaScript engine is property attributes.
And of course, the easiest thing to do is to start with an example, let's creates an object by the
object literal syntax.
And it just has two properties on it X and Y.
And remember what I said?
The script speak defines as dictionaries, and it maps keys to property attributes.
Will the keys in this instance are X and Y?
It's the name of the property.
Those are the keys and those keys, or each reference to property attributes, and those property attributes
have certain values attached to them.
One is the value of the actual name of the property.
In this case, X has a value of 10.
Y has a value of 20.
These three other properties attached to this rewritable enumerable and configurable.
What do they mean?
We'll just very briefly rewritable just determines whether the property can be reassigned.
Enumerable determines whether the property can be seen in a full in loop.
And as you can see from its variable, this innumerable property is set to true.
And this is because every new property is innumerable by default.
There's an exception to this, but we'll discuss that later.
For now, just know that Enumerable is set to true by default.
And the lost property is configurable, and that determines whether the property can be deleted.
And don't get weirded out by these double brackets, the double square brackets is just how to speak
that it must script specification shows properties that aren't directly exposed by JavaScript.
So you're probably thinking, well, if they're not exposed by JavaScript, can we ever see them?
And the answer is yes, you can.
You can access them with the object.
Get own property descriptor method.
Let me quickly show you how you access these.
OK.
Very quickly, let me show you how we can access these property attributes.
And all right, all configurable in the venue.
Remember how I said we can access these don't get into mid-table the square brackets.
Using the same example we didn't lecture now, let's just define an object, and let's just say existing
instead of having line just have, it's just easier for us if we console.log this object out and we
open it up here.
And you look at its prototype and you look at the constructor.
If you scroll down, you can see that gate owned property descriptor.
There is this method available to all objects we create in JavaScript.
Awesome, right.
So let's use it.
So let's access the global JavaScript object, and then we want to get Owen property descriptor.
Now we've got to define the object, which is o'bagy, and we've got to define the variable that we
want.
And that is.
If we console.log that out, there you go.
You've got your value rightful and usable and configurable.