So now let's talk about Amazon GuardDuty.
Duty GuardDuty helps you do intelligent threat discovery
to protect your AWS accounts.
How does it do it?
Well, it has machine learning algorithm,
performs anomaly detection,
and uses third-party data to find these threats.
So to enable it, it's just one click.
Then you have a 30-day trial.
You don't need to install any software.
So GuardDuty is going to look at a lot of input data,
such as your CloudTrail Event Logs to look
for unusual API calls or unauthorized deployments.
It's going to look
at your management events and your data events.
So for example, on the management side,
the create VPC subnet event and so on,
whereas on the S3 data events, for example,
get object, list objects, delete objects, and so on.
And then for VPC Flow Logs, it's going to look
at unusual internet traffic,
it's going to look at unusual IP addresses.
DNS logs to look at EC2 instances sending encoded data
within DNS queries, which would mean they're compromised
and Kubernetes Audit Logs to find suspicious activities
on your EKS, your Kubernetes cluster compromises.
So we can also set up EventBridge rules
to be notified automatically in case you have findings.
And then these rules can target
whatever EventBridge can target,
such as AWS Lambda, or SNS topics.
Also, this can come up in the exam,
GuardDuty is a very good tool to protect you
against cryptocurrency attacks
because there is a dedicated finding for it.
So it knows how to analyze all these input data
and find that there is a cryptocurrency attack.
So to summarize, we have input data,
such as VPC Flow Logs, CloudTrail logs, DNS Logs
and the EKS Audit Logs that will go
into GuardDuty and will generate findings automatically.
These findings can trigger automatically EventBridge events,
which, thanks to rules, can end up in Lambda and SNS.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.