So congratulations on finishing this course.
I'm super happy for you.
I'm so glad you went all the way through with it.
I hope that you will pass the exam without a hitch,
but again, I'm pretty sure that if you follow this course
with attention,
and you will practice with the practice exams,
you should be good to go.
If you haven't done so yet, I would love a review from you.
They help future students find the course,
and they'll help me get popular
in this topic and help people.
If you passed, I would love to know that you passed as well.
So post it in the Q&amp;A to help motivate other students,
share your tips, or post it on LinkedIn and tag me,
and I'll do my best to say congratulations to you.
Overall, I hope that you learned
how to use AWS security in-depth
and that you will be a tremendous Security Specialist.
It is really a fascinating topic,
and something that can really differentiate you
in the job market on AWS.
Okay, that's it from me.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next course.