So let's have a look
at IAM Roles for Services.
So we know that some services will need
to perform actions on our behalf,
and so therefore we must assign permissions to AWS services,
and we are using for this IAM roles.
So we know this for a fact.
Whenever we have an EC2 instance that wants
to access the APIs of AWS, we must assign it an IAM role
and then it will be able to access
and allocate the DynamoDB table and so on.
So I'm not telling you anything new here, I hope,
so the common roles will be EC2 instance roles,
Lambda function roles, roles for CloudFormation
but really I think pretty much every AWS service
at some point requires to have a role being created.
The other thing you should know about role
is how to pass a role to AWS services.
So you can grant a user to pass an IAM role to a service
and that's maybe something that you do not know.
So with this permission, you can ensure
that only the approved users can configure an AWS service
with an IAM role that grants permissions.
So for this, for the user to be able
to pass a role to a service
you have the IAM action, API call called iam:PassRole.
And this can be assigned, for example, to a user.
And in this example we have the GetRole
and the PassRole assigned to a very specific role.
So we have resource and then we have a star.
So we match all roles that have the prefix EC2 roles for.
And so that means that this user will be only
able to PassRole that starts with EC2 roles for.
And so we have effectively restricted which roles
a user can pass to EC2 instances.
So PassRole is not an API call on its own
so you will not have any CloudTrail logs
generated out of it.
But instead you can review the CloudTrail log
for the API call that actually created
or modified the resource receiving the target IAM role.
So if you create an EC2 instance
and you assign it an IAM role
then this is where you will find who assigned
which IAM role to that EC2 instance.
Alright, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.