So let's talk about AWS Glue Security.
So you have encryption at rest using KMS
for all your Glue concepts,
such as databases, table, Job Bookmarks,
and you get encryption in transit using TLS.
Now, to get access to Glue for the security,
either you define IAM policies,
and you attach them to users, group roles, or services,
and they can access Glue resources.
That's one way of doing it.
The other way is to use resource-based policies.
This is when you attach a resource
such as, very similar to an S3 bucket policy.
You attach it to a Glue data catalog
and that grants access to IAM identities,
which is very helpful in the case of cross-account access.
The next thing we have
is a centralized data catalog for Glue.
So how does that work?
Well, we will have cross-account concerns
because we want to centralize everything in Glue.
So we'll have a producer account,
and we'll have a consumer account,
and the producer account
will have the Glue data catalog connected to an S3 bucket,
and say the consumer account
wants to be able to query this S3 bucket through Athena,
and then it wants to reference the table
from the Glue data catalog.
So how does that work?
Well, we create a Glue data catalog policy,
and in this policy,
we allow a principal from another account.
So this account 444, 555 and so on,
to get access to the catalog, the database,
and the table of our own accounts.
And this is the data catalog policy
and it's a resource policy.
And this will allow the other accounts,
if they have the proper IAM policies, of course,
to query the data of our Glue data catalog.
So the S3 bucket policy also must have security in place.
So because the S3 bucket policy
is going to be queried by Athena,
you need to have also an allow statement
to allow Athena or the other accounts
to do a get object or list object on our buckets
and our buckets' objects.
So hopefully that makes sense.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.