So now let's talk about
Amazon WorkSpaces security.
The first one is the IP Access Control Group.
They're very similar to security groups
but they are for WorkSpaces.
So you list the IP addresses or the CIDR address ranges
that users are authorized to connect from
and then they will be accessing WorkSpaces.
If the users are accessing WorkSpaces
through a VPN or a NAT
then you need to make sure that the IP Access Control Group
authorize the public IP of your VPN or your NAT.
So if you have a corporate data center,
a user has a public IP from the CIDR that's owned
by the data center
and then we have WorkSpaces with an IP Access Control Group.
We'll just authorize the CIDR of our data center
and we're good to go.
We also have access control options and trusted devices.
So we manage which client devices can access WorkSpaces
and we can use WorkSpaces certificates based authentication
to limit access to only trusted devices
using digital certificates
and this works for Windows, MacOS and Android clients.
So we have our user and we are issued a certificate
by our administrator,
and then we are going to authenticate with WorkSpaces
using that certificate which prevents malicious users
from accessing our WorkSpaces directory.
That's it for WorkSpaces security.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.