So now let's talk about
the EC2 serial console feature.
So the serial console is a very special kind
of terminal capability into your EC2 instances,
because it allows you to troubleshoot the boot,
troubleshoot the network configuration,
and analyze reboot issues.
So it has a very specific use case, and the idea is,
that we access the EC2 instance over its own serial port.
So, a serial port is what you would have,
if you wanted to hook up a monitor,
or a keyboard, directly into the EC2 instance.
So, that looks just like this.
Obviously this, no one goes
into the data centers of AWS and actually plugs it
into the serial console, the serial port.
But this is the kind of thing you need to think about.
So, it does not require any network capability,
because you access the instance through the serial port.
So, it only works with the specific kind of EC2 instances.
They're the Nitro-based EC2 instances.
And for this to work, you're going to log into
your EC2 instance, with a user and a password.
So, you need to set a user and a password
before you can use the serial console.
Okay, next, because there is only one serial console part,
you can only have one active session per EC2 instance.
That may be an oversimplification,
but you get the idea, and the serial console,
because it has very strong and powerful capabilities,
is disabled, by default, in your accounts,
but you can enable it,
by going into the accounts EC2 settings.
So, this was a short explanation
about the EC2 serial console.
And just remember, it is meant to analyze boot issues,
network configuration issues, and reboot issues,
because if you reboot your EC2 instance,
you will still have that, quote-unquote,
term terminal console opened,
which allows you to troubleshoot this kind of issues.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.