So let's go through some very tricky examples
of how we can access services of AWS through VPC endpoints.
The first one is CodeDeploy.
So CodeDeploy is a way to deploy new application versions
onto your EC2 instances, for example
and EC2 instances that are going to
run the CodeDeploy agents.
And the CodeDeploy agent is going to be making API calls
to the CodeDeploy service.
Now obviously if your EC2 instance is in a private subnet
then this agent must have networking capability
to the CodeDeploy service.
Now, it turns out that they are two kinds
of VPC interface and points that are required.
The first one is an interface endpoint
directly into the CodeDeploy service itself.
This is for all CodeDeploy API operations.
The second VPC interface endpoint is going to be required
for EC2 types of deployments
is the one code CodeDeploy commands secure
which is going to allow to have CodeDeploy agent operations
because CodeDeploy is going to be sending some
commands directly to the agents on the EC2 instance.
And so as you can see,
two VPC endpoints may be required for CodeDeploy.
So just to give you some comparison,
if you're deploying on EC2 instances,
you must have access to both VPC interface endpoint.
One for the CodeDeploy API operations
and the second one for the ones related to the agents.
But if you're using CodeDeploy to deploy EC2 or Lambda
you only need access to the CodeDeploy APIs themselves
not this second VPC interface endpoint
that is only reserved for EC2 instances.
The next service that you may have questions on
is Secrets Manager.
So with Secrets Manager, say we have a Lambda function
and it wants to access privately the secrets
of Secrets Manager, for example, to get a database password.
If your Lambda function is deployed in a private subnet
you must also deploy a VPC interface endpoint
of Secrets Manager in this private subnet.
This will allow the Lambda function to
get the database password
through the VPC endpoint onto Secrets Manager
and then to privately connect, for example
to a private RDS database instance.
If you didn't want to use a VPC interface endpoint,
you will need to set up
net gateways and internet gateways
to access from Lambda the Secrets Manager Service
and that may be more complicated.
So with this setup,
everything goes privately and works really well.
Another service is the SSM Session Manager.
So with the SSM service, we can connect
to EC2 instances using Session Manager
and these EC2 instances
they may reside in private subnets without internet access.
So again, how do we do this?
Well, first of all, we need multiple
VPC interface endpoints.
The first one is the SSM service itself.
So this service must allow the inbound 443 ports
on the security group to allow secure connections.
The second one is the SSM Session Manager
VPC interface endpoints, called SSM Messages.
And again,
it must allow the port 443 for inbound connections.
Therefore, because your EC2 instances is going to access
both these VPC interface endpoints,
you must allow at least the port 443
outbound on your security group of your EC2 instance
so that all these things can communicate together.
Then if you are using, for example
KMS encryption for your data
then you must also have a KMS VPC interface endpoint.
And if you are deciding to send your logs
into CloudWatch Logs,
you must have a VPC interface endpoint for CloudWatch Logs.
Finally, if you do decide to also send the logs to Amazon S3
then you can use a VPC gateway endpoint.
So as you can see, a lot of things are happening
and if you do choose to use an S3 Gateway endpoint
you must up the root tables.
But from an SSM perspective,
the access required for session manager
is going to be around the SSM service itself
and the SSM session manager VPC interface endpoints
called SSM Messages.
Next for Patch Manager, something similar.
So we need to have access to the SSM service itself
with its own VPC interface endpoint.
And then there will be one called the SSM Commands VPC
interface endpoint, called EC2 messages
which is going to allow the SSM service to send commands
into our EC2 instance.
So the network security is similar as before
and again to get dispatches now,
you must also get them from Amazon S3
and so therefore we'll need a VPC gateway endpoint
for Amazon S3 and adding these group tables, of course
when you have a VPC gateway endpoint.
And finally,
because the VPC endpoint must access your patches
you must authorize through this VPC endpoint policy.
Several buckets,
the first one is the patch baseline snapshot
for your specified region.
The second one is the AWS SSM for your specified region
or any other S3 buckets required by SSM.
And finally, if you wanted to send the logs
of the patch manager utility to CloudWatch Logs
you must have your own VPC interface endpoint as well.
Next, you should know how VPC endpoints work
for the API gateway.
So if you define a private REST API in API Gateway
you can only access it using the VPC interface endpoint.
There's no way around it.
So that means that in this diagram,
what's missing is the VPC interface endpoint
for the Execute API endpoint.
So once we have this in place, then the EC2 instance
can access our private API.
Of course, for it to work
we must have the correct VPC endpoint policies
and they must use together with
the API gateway resource policies.
So that means that using a resource policy,
you can actually restrict access to your private API
from a specific VPC or VPC endpoints.
So this is the kind of API resource policy you can have
in which your saying,
"Hey, I will allow anyone to execute this API
but you cannot invoke it if you don't come from
the specified VPC, thanks to this condition".
Alright, that's it.
You've seen several examples,
a bit redundant but hopefully you get the points
and you understand the whole complexity
and power of VPC interface endpoints.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.