So now let's talk
how we can revoke IAM role's temporary credentials.
So when you have a session with IAM, for example,
a long session of 12 hours,
in case the credentials are exposed,
they can be used for the duration of the session.
So that means that if you leak them,
then someone can use them, and this is bad.
So what we want to do is that if they're exposed,
we want to immediately revoke all permissions
to the IAM role's credentials before a certain time.
And we can do this with the console
and in the backend what's going to happen
is that AWS is going to attach a new inline IAM policy
onto the IAM role that is going to deny everything
if the token is too old
which will force users to reauthenticate.
So this is where the DateLessThan
is going to be used as a condition.
So this policy is going to be attached to your IAM role
is gonna say deny everything
if the token issue time is less than right now.
And what's going to happen out of it is that your users
that had a token issued before right now
will not be able to do any actions on AWS
because you have now an explicit deny.
So it doesn't affect any user who assumed the IAM role
after you revoke the sessions
because, well,
the token issue time is going to be greater than,
so this deny section will never come into place.
So you don't need to delete this policy called
AWSRevokeOlderSessions Policy.
You can leave it forever and you're fine.
So in case you have, as I said, a leaked credential,
and you want to revoke these temporary credentials
because an attacker had access to them,
then you're going to, as an administrator,
attach this AWSRevokeOlderSessions Policy
and then automatically,
the attacker will not have access anymore.
It will not be able to use the credentials that have leaked.
So that's it.
That's the one time
where you can use the token issue time condition in AWS.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.