So on the left-hand side,
I can go into Patch Manager
to automate patching of my instances, okay.
So I will click on "Patch now."
And this is to apply a patch to my instances.
So we can have a scan, or a scan and install.
And do we want to reboot
if we want to patch our instances?
And then what instance do we want to patch?
So we can patch all instances
or we can patch only some specific targets
based on tags, resource groups,
or specify the instances manually, okay?
Then patching log storage can be done
and can be placed within an S3 bucket of your choice.
And then you can use Lifecycle hooks
if you want at certain points during the patching
to perform some complex patching scenarios.
So this is one way of doing things, okay.
But you can also view the predefined patch baseline.
And this is all the baseline that you have for different OS.
For example, the Red Hat patch baseline,
the centOS Patch Baseline, the Windows and so on.
And whether or not they're default baseline.
So some are yes and some are no.
I don't want to go too deep into it
because I don't want to overwhelm you with details,
but just so you have a quick overview
of how Patch Manager work.
So these are all the patches distributed
for Windows and for Amazon Linux 2
and their release date,
whether or not security,
and the level and whether critical and so on.
So whenever you create your patch group,
then it will appear here
and it will be associated with a specific patch baseline.
And you can look at reporting
to see if an instance is compliant or not
with its patches.
And finally, if you want to have a look
at maintenance windows,
they're right here on the left hand side.
So under maintenance windows,
we can create a maintenance window to run our patches.
So I'll call this one Demo Maintenance Window,
and then we allow unregistered targets
to be under this window.
Where do we want,
how far, how often do we want to run this window?
So it could be a Cron schedule, a rate,
or a Cron Rate expression.
So we can say daily,
you start every day at zero three, so 3:00 AM.
And it's going to be a two-hour maintenance window, okay.
And stop initiating task while zero hour
before the window closed.
But you can say one hour if you wanted to.
We can say start time and end time if you wanted to,
the schedule.
And then we can create this maintenance window, okay.
And within this window,
what we can do is that we can register specific tasks
that will be run.
And one of this tasks, for example, is, could be
a run command.
So I'll call it Patch
and the document to apply itself
is going to be AWS-RunPatch.
And we have the Run Patch baseline right here
in documents that we can register within our targets.
And we can select unregistered targets,
for example, these three, to apply this.
And obviously, thanks to the maintenance windows,
we can specify concurrency and the error thresholds.
Hopefully this works,
obviously one target at a time and zero for errors,
and that should do the trick.
So let's see if I can just go ahead
and click on register run command.
Here we go.
So now that means that within my maintenance window,
this run patch baseline will be run,
and it will happen only during this window.
So this is just a way to do things.
I'm not going to go ahead with this maintenance window,
but I want to show you a high level of how patch manager
and the maintenance windows were working.
And to clean that up,
you can delete this maintenance window
and you'll be good to go.
So that's it.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.