So just a short lecture on CloudShell
so you know one caveat for the exam.
So CloudShell is a way for you to get a terminal
from within the AWS console, which is very handy.
So CloudShell is a browser-based shell
to manage your AWS resources
and you can run CLI commands, it's pre-configured,
and you can run scripts without leaving your browser.
It comes pre-installed with common libraries
and common CLI tools such as the AWS CLI, the ECS CLI,
the SAM CLI, and SDKs for Python and Node.js.
It has Bash, PowerShell, zsh, et cetera, et cetera.
It comes with preconfigured AWS credentials,
which are inherited from the logged in user.
So as soon as you go into CloudShell,
you'll have the same permissions
and you have persistent storage,
up to one gigabyte per region,
and it runs on Amazon Linux 2.
So you may say, cool, that's perfect.
From CloudShell, I can 100% SSH into my EC2 instance.
Well, you cannot.
You cannot access resources in a VPC from CloudShell.
So EC2, RDS are not accessible from CloudShell
and that's what I wanted you to remember.
Okay, CloudShell is great
for doing API calls using the AWS CLI
but you cannot access resources within the VPC.
For this, you would need to have something
actually within your VPC,
such as an EC2 instance, and then you would use something
like EC2 Instance Connect.
Okay, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.