So now let's talk about IoT Core Security.
So say you have IoT Core and an IoT Thing.
The IoT Thing is going to connect using the MQTT protocol
to your core control plane
and it will pass in a client's ID.
Now out of it we will have an IoT certificate,
we'll have a thing name
so we can identify which IoT device it is
and we can attach an IoT Core Policy that looks like this.
And the core policy may allow our thing name to connect.
So here we have to match everything together using variables
and I'll talk about it right now.
So first, the IoT Core Policy.
So it's a JSON documents
and this allows you to control access
to the IoT Core control plane.
So this is for your IoT Core message broker
to receive and send MQTT messages and so on.
And you attach it to the IoT certificates
or according to identity of your IoT Thing.
So the IoT Thing will have a certificates
and then it will have a core policy
attached to the certificates.
So thanks to this the certificate
we get authentication of the IoT Thing
and the core policy defines authorization of the IoT Thing.
And we can for example,
say that we want to access,
to allow our IoT Thing to access all MQTT topics
or restrict access to a single topic.
So once the IoT Thing is identified
with IoT Core using the IoT Certificate
and has authorization using the IoT Core policy,
we can define it in a scalable way
by using the IoT Thing policy variable.
And that can come up in the exam.
So the idea is that in your policy,
and you can look at the bottom right of this slide,
in this policy, you can include the thing name
to have conditional policy variables.
And this allows you to have permissions
based on the IoT Thing properties
such as its name, its type
and some attribute value.
And then at runtime is going to be replaced
by when the IoT Thing connects to the AWS IoT Service.
This seems complicated, but the idea is
if a Thing connects to the IoT Core
using a Core policy and IoT Thing policy variables,
you can control what this thing has access to,
based on its name or its type and so on.
So hopefully that makes sense.
This can come up in one question at the exam.
It's a very easy one,
once you know this.
So hopefully you like this lecture
and I will see you in the next lecture.