So just something
that can come up in the exam.
It's around attribute-based access control,
so ABAC with KMS.
So with this, you control access to your KMS keys,
not based on IAM policies and so on,
but based on tags and aliases.
So how does that work?
Well, a user will have an IAM policy, but we say
that we can access any key for decrypt, encrypt and so on
as long as the resource tag on that key is environment prod,
meaning we have access to all the prod keys.
And in this KMS key,
we'll just have a tag environment equals prod.
And this way our user will have allowed access
into this KMS key.
This is one way to have security
at scale and one example that can come up in the exam.
So this was a very short lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.