So now, let's talk
about the AWS abuse reports.
So, if you suspect that some AWS resources are used
for abusive or illegal purposes,
then you can create an abuse report.
So, they could be for anything such
as spam, port scanning, DDoS attacks, intrusion attempts,
hosting prohibited content, or distributing malware.
In that case, you just contact the AWS Trust and Safety Team
with all the details and they will take care of it.
So, for example, you notice that a hacker,
as part of an account, is sending you spam emails
and you detect it's coming
from AWS because the IP range belongs to AWS,
therefore, you can create an abuse report with the Trust
and Safety Team, and then they will notify the accounts.
So, if you're in the case of receiving an email
from the Trust and Safety Team saying
that some resources are used for illegal activities,
then you must respond to the email
and explain how you are preventing this kind of activity
and if you don't respond within 24 hours,
then AWS might suspend your AWS account.
Alright, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.