So let's talk about security groups,
outbound rules for a second.
By default the outbound rules allow anywhere with this CIDR,
but we can remove and just allow specific prefixes.
So here is an example of an outbound rule,
and as you can see, it authorizes the port 443
of a destination to be Amazon S3 in the US East 1.
So it looks like from this we have used a prefix destination
so that the only amount authorized is to S3.
And so as such, we can introduce the concept
of managed prefix lists.
So it's one or more CIDR blocks and it makes it easier
for you to configure your security groups
and your route tables.
So in your account, for example,
you can define your custom prefix list.
For example, this CIDR 1, CIDR 2, and CIDR 3.
You can share them to another account
such as in the security group, inbound rules.
You can actually reference the prefix list
that you've defined in Account A.
So these customer manage prefix lists are a set
of CIDR that you define and that you manage yourself,
and they can be shared with other accounts
or within your organization.
This allows you, for example, that if the Account A
wants to modify the prefix list once,
it will be applied to many security groups at once.
The other option is to use the AWS managed prefix list.
So it's a set of CIDR for AWS services,
but you can't create, modify, share, or delete them.
You can only use them.
And some of the services that may be important
that you can already reference using this managed
prefix list are Amazon S3, Amazon CloudFront,
DynamoDB, and Ground Station, and they may be others,
but those are the most important.
All right, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.