So here is a quick lecture
on EC2 Image Builder troubleshooting.
So in case you have a EC2 Image Builder
but then you get Access Denied Status 403 on an S3 bucket,
then the reasons may be that the Instance Profile attached
to your EC2 Image Builder doesn't have
the required permission or that it's missing the permissions
to actually perform logging into Amazon S3.
So the resolution of this
is to make sure you have the proper IAM role
and you have some managed policies
that you can come up within IAM,
such as the Amazon SSM Manage Instance Core,
the EC2 Instance Profile for Image Builder,
and the one that's the EC2 instance profile
for Image Builder with ECR Container Builds
in case you decide to create containers.
Then you can also make sure
that you can add a policy to your Instance Profile Role
that grants put object permissions to write
to your S3 bucket because this is where all the logs
are going to be included and that's necessary
for EC2 Image Builder to work properly.
Okay, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.