So now let's talk about CloudHSM.
And the best way to start is to talk about KMS.
So when we have KMS,
AWS manages the software for encryption
and the encryption keys.
But with CloudHSM,
AWS will only provision us
the encryption hardware.
It's going to be dedicated hardware
and HSM stands for Hardware Security Module,
hence the name CloudHSM.
And your responsibility is going to manage
your own encryption keys entirely, not AWS.
The idea is that you are entirely responsible
for the security, the maintenance,
and the backup of these encryption keys, not AWS.
So the HSM device is going to be tamper resistant.
It has some kind of compliance.
And so that means that
if anyone onsite at AWS tries to
open up your HSM device,
there's going to be a flip
and it's going to be seen.
So it supports both symmetric
and asymmetric encryption
which is really helpful if you want to do something
called TLS or SSL uploading
and there's no feature available.
For you to use CloudHSM,
you need to use the CloudHSM client software.
It's not something that is done through API calls.
And you have some integration with CloudHSM,
for example, with Redshift,
that supports CloudHSM
for database encryption and key management.
So in case you want to use SSE-C
type of encryption for your S3 objects,
which is when you provide your own
encryption key to S3
and then there will be server side encryption happening.
Then a good way to generate that encryption key
would be to use CloudHSM.
It's a very common pattern.
Okay, so let's have a look at a diagram.
AWS will manage the hardware for us,
but then we will be provided
with a cloud HSM device,
and it's dedicated to us,
and then that's all AWS does for us.
So if we lose the encryption keys,
if we lose anything,
AWS cannot recover the device for us.
It's really our own responsibility
so use with caution.
And to manage these keys and everything,
you need to have a CloudHSM clients,
which will access your CloudHSM device,
and you manage your keys.
They will have encrypted connection
between your CloudHSM clients,
and your CloudHSM device of course,
to encrypt and share a secure information.
But it's your responsibility to manage everything
within your device.
AWS cannot help you once it has provided you
with the hardware you need
in terms of IAM permissions.
Therefore, the only thing AWS can do
in terms of IAM,
is helping you create,
describe, and delete your CloudHSM cluster.
But anything within your CloudHSM cluster,
it's your own responsibility.
So using the CloudHSM software,
you can manage the keys.
That means create, read, update, delete keys,
and also manage the users
that have access to these keys.
It's very similar to say a database
where AWS will give you the database itself
and you have to manage the users within it.
It's not exactly the case,
not exactly similar as CloudHSM
but you get the idea.
You have to manage all the security
within your device and AWS can not help you with that.
Okay, another very important thing
is to set up CloudHSM with high availability.
And for this, you need to create a CloudHSM cluster
that will be spread across multiple AZ.
It's going to be great to enhance
one more time the availability,
but also the durability of your data.
So we have this very classic architecture
where we have two AZ,
two CloudHSM devices
that are going to be paired up in a cluster,
and your CloudHSM clients.
And the idea here is that if we lose one AZ,
while we still have access to the second AZ,
and our data is safe,
highly available and durable.
But important to see it once,
to know that it's possible to do it.
Going into the exam it can be very handy.
So for CloudHSM, you have a single tenant device
whereas for KMS, it's multi-tenant.
For standard, it's level three.
On CloudHSM level two,
for FIPS on KMS.
In terms of the master keys,
you have different kinds.
On KMS, you have the AWS Owned Keys,
the AWS Managed Keys
as well as the customer managed KMS Keys.
Whereas on CloudHSM, you just have one thing.
It's customer managed CMK.
Now for the key type,
while you have similar ones,
you have symmetric, asymmetric, digital signing,
and CloudHSM gives you also hashing.
For key accessibility,
KMS keys are scoped per region,
although you can do KMS key replication
and CloudHSM while they're deployed
and managed in specific VPC.
And you can be shared across different VPC
by using VPC peering for example.
CloudHSM has cryptographic acceleration
for SSL and TLS and Oracle TDE.
In terms of access and authorization,
KMS is using IAM,
whereas CloudHSM is using their own users,
and you have to manage your own permissions
from within the CloudHSM device itself.
For high availability,
while this is embedded in the KMS service,
but for CloudHSM, you need to have multiple HSM device
over different availability zones.
For other capability,
you have CloudTrail and CloudWatch,
but on top of it,
CloudHSM has multifactor application supports.
And finally, there's a feature for KMS.
Whereas there's no feature for CloudHSM.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.