So now is the time to sign up
for your certification.
And for this you go to this website,
aws.training/certification
and then you click on sign in.
You have to create an account
for Amazon or sending user accounts
but as you mentioned, it's not for AWS
it is an Amazon account, so make sure you have one
but you can just create one, it's fairly easy.
After you sign in, you're redirected to the screen
and then to get your certification
you click on go to your accounts.
Okay, so I am now on the training and certification homepage
and I want to register for an exam.
So you click here to register for an exam
and you'll have access to the exam list
as well as a schedule option.
Now just so you know, in the next video I go
over the benefits tab, so watch the next video as well
before you schedule your exam
because I show you how to get 50% discount
on your next exam.
This is a benefit you get
once you successfully complete an AWS certification.
So back in here into registering your exam.
So we can schedule any of these exams.
For example, I can select developer associates.
I will schedule it with Pearson VUE
which is the only option now online.
And then I have two options.
So we have either the option to select a home office
or to select a testing center.
So let's have a look.
So here we can, for example, take it at a test center
in which case you need to bring your photo ID
and you have like some expectations
regarding your personal items.
And then in that case,
well you need to select the language you want
and then you will find a map with the locations
that you may want to select.
So here we accept the terms
and we can select some testing centers right here
for example, here in Portugal.
But that's one option.
The other option is to do it online.
So let's go back to exam registration,
and then I'm going to schedule one,
this one for example, online.
So let's do it.
I will do it online at my home or office.
And you have a few things to do.
So you need to run a system test
and I strongly, strongly encourage you to do this
to make sure your system is fine
because I've been into cases where my computer was not fine,
so it's something for you to do for sure.
Then there is some guidelines where your testing space.
You need your photo ID
and it's recommended to arrive 30 minutes early
to make sure you are set up just fine.
So once we click on online,
we can choose a language we want,
so English for me is fine.
We take all the conditions to accept the terms of service
and then click on agree.
Then we select the language again,
so English for the proctor,
your time zone if you wanted to.
Finally you can find a date
and a time, so I can choose for example
tomorrow at this time, perfect, book this appointment.
And next I'm ready to just pay for my exam
and proceed to checkout.
Also, before you book your exam
please, if you are a non-English speaker,
you can request an exam accommodation that I show you
in the next lectures
on how to get 30 minutes extra for your exam.
Finally, once your exam is actually scheduled,
the day of the exam itself,
you click on manage Pearson VUE exam
and this is actually going to take you
into the Pearson VUE system,
and from there you will be able, in here,
to see the scheduled exam.
You can click on it and access your exam from there.
Alright, that's it.
I wish you the best of luck for your exam
and I will see you in the next lecture.