So, now let's talk
about IAM condition operators.
They're the operators that allow you
to construct a condition,
and we've seen StringEquals or StringNotEquals
which is a case sensitive way of doing exact matching.
In this example, we compare the principle tag
of type job category to the value IAM user admin.
We have StringLike and StringNotLike,
and this is very similar to StringEquals,
but now we allow partial matching using
the star or a question mark.
So, for example, in here we look at whether
or not the S3 prefix of the object
is corresponding to home/*/data.
So, star can be replaced by anything we want.
This is extremely helpful,
for example, when you compare ARNs
and you want to remove the account iID
so you just put a star instead,
and you've seen this,
you must have seen this quite a lot
in your experience.
Then, we have DateEquals,
DateLessThan, DateGreaterThan.
So for example, you can compare the token issued time
of your credentials to a specific timestamp,
and we'll see a use case of this in some future lectures.
Then, we have ArnLike and ArnNotLike.
So, this is very similar to StringLike and StringNotLike,
but this is used specifically
for ARNs because it just works better.
So, anytime you must compare ARNs with partial matching
then use ArnLike and ArnNotLike.
We have Bool to check for the value of a boolean.
So, here we have Bool awsSecureTransport, false.
So, we wanna know at runtime
if secure transport is false
this is how you read it,
and so when secure transport is false,
that means that you don't use HTTPS.
This is something you'll see
when we deal with S3 bucket policies, for example.
We have IpAddress and NotIpAddress.
So, this is a CIDR format,
and here we are going to have a look whether or not,
for example, the source IP of the API call
corresponds to the CIDR on the right hand side.
So, this is going to resolve to the IP address
that the request originates from.
and it's only works for public IPs,
it does not apply to request made through VPC endpoints,
but we'll see the type of conditions we can have
for VPC endpoints to compare on private IP addresses.
So, that's it.
There was just a short intro around IAM conditions.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.