So, now let's talk about
the Secrets Manager service.
So, as we can see,
it's to easily rotate, manage, and retrieve secrets
throughout their life cycle.
So, it's similar to the SSM parameter store
because you can store secret things,
but it's going to be different from it
because while you have rotation, management,
and tight integrations with databases
such as MySQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon Aurora,
and RDS and so on.
So, the pricing is you have a 30-day free trial available,
and then you're going to pay $0.40 per secret, per month,
and then $0.05 per 10,000 API calls.
So, if you again expect to remain within the free tier,
just create a secret and then delete it.
So, let's go ahead and store a new secret,
and we can choose a secret type.
Now, over time,
it's very possible that this gets increased
in terms of the capability of integrations,
but we have Amazon RDS, we have Amazon DocumentDB,
Amazon Redshift, other databases, or other type of secrets.
So, if you are on Amazon RDS, as you can see,
it prompts you for username and password and so on.
And if you go for example,
for other type of secrets,
here we can store anything we want.
So for example, I can say MySecretKey,
and then MyVerySecretValue,
and this would be a secret stored in here.
And another one could be, for example, API_KEY,
and then would be as well like a secret API key,
so you would enter some text in here.
So you can enter it through this UI,
or you can go in plain text and you have adjacent document
that you can edit it.
To edit the key values,
this is just a different way of specifying your secrets.
So, this will be kept secret so that only person
with the correct IAM permissions can access these secrets.
Then we specify an encryption key.
So, we have the default one,
but you can use your own KMS key if you wanted to.
I click on next.
Then we need to name our secret.
So prod/my-secret for example,
and a description but I don't need it.
Resource permission,
so do we want to have a policy
that restricts who can access the secret?
And it could be across AWS accounts
thanks to this resource policy right here,
and you would've have it adjacent form.
So, it's similar to an S3 bucket policy.
And then you have the option
to replicate the secret across regions.
And this is good if you want to have multi-region setups
which as multi-region apps or multi-region databases.
And here we can say,
"Okay, I want to replicate this
into us-west-2 using this encryption key right here
and also into AP Southeast-1 and so on.
So, I'm not gonna do this,
but this would be how you would replicate your secrets.
So, then I click on Next.
Then you want to automatically rotate our secrets,
yes or no.
And when do we want to rotate it,
and if we do enable rotation,
then we need to specify a rotation function.
This is a Lambda function
that will be performing this rotation.
So for now, disable it.
And then we have a look.
So, we have a secret right here.
It's replicated into us-west-2.
And here's some code if we wanted to invoke
and get that secrets from our clients.
So, I'm not gonna go ahead with creating this,
but as you can see, this would store a secret
and then use this code
to retrieve in your code the correct secrets.
So, we'll cancel this.
Another kind of secret you can have
is a credential for an Amazon RDS database.
So, you would create a username and a password
and then you would specify a database.
And the cool thing about it
is that thanks to the integration
between RDS and Secrets Manager,
then this username and this password
would be used to be able to login into the database.
And if you wanted to rotate it,
then automatically the database also gets updated.
So, here you would enter it.
Then you would configure the secrets
as well if you wanted to have for example
some kind of multi-region replication.
Rotation as well if you wanted to review it and you're done.
So, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.