So you need to be able to troubleshoot issues
with the Unified CloudWatch Agent.
So, in case the agents fails to start, it may be an issue
with the configuration file, in which case,
you should go into this file logs
at this place on your EC2 instance,
which is going to give you some configuration validation,
and information.
If you cannot find the metrics collected
by the CloudWatch Agent, of course,
check whether or not you are in the correct namespace.
The default for the CloudWatch Agent is CWAgent.
And then you check the configuration of the Agent itself,
it's a JSON document,
and this is the kind of configuration it has.
So you can check the region, you can check the debug mode,
and you can check as well the run as user,
because if these things go wrong,
then the CloudWatch Agent may not work.
On top of it, if the CloudWatch Agent
is not publishing log events,
then look at the CloudWatch Agent version,
test connectivity from the Agent into
the Logs endpoint of AWS.
So that includes checking your Security Group rules,
and your network ACLs.
Please review your account, region,
and log group configuration.
Check your IAM permissions, of course,
because you may need to have a Custom Policy
if you're missing it,
or you can just use Managed Policies as well
if you want to use a shortcut.
And verify that the system time on the instance
is correctly configured, and in sync.
Again, there's a debug file for the CloudWatch Agent Logs
that you can find on your EC2 instance
to give you more information.
Alright, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.