So let's have a look
at some advanced concepts around Secrets Manager.
First one, we can use KMS to encrypt
and decrypt every version of every secret value.
And so each secret is going to be encrypted
thanks to envelope encryption,
with a unique data key.
So Secret Manager internally
is going to use the generate data key API call
to get a data key
and is going to encrypt, for example, a secret value,
a database password,
and then you're going to get the encrypted value
and that's how it works
in the reverse mechanism for decryption.
So we have the option to set our own KMS key for this,
or to use the AWS managed key
called AWS/Secret Manager.
It only works with symmetric KMS keys
and all the encryption process will happen
within the service.
You don't have to do it on your own.
To access a secret,
very similar to SSM Biometric Store.
You must have access, of course,
to the secret in Secret Manager,
but also have access
to the underlying KMS key to be able to encrypt
or decrypt that secret.
Next thing is around secrets rotation for Secrets Manager.
So this is around the idea that you want to automatically
and periodically update a secret.
So for some databases you have automated password rotation
for example, RDS, Redshift, Document DB or other databases.
What's going to happen is that Secrets Manager,
if this is enabled,
every 30 day is going to invoke a Lambda function
that you create yourself
or that is provided by the service
when there isn't already
in existing integration such as RDS.
And this Lambda function is going to change the password
of your Amazon RDS database
and therefore it's also going to store the final value
in Secrets Manager.
So no matter what the secret you have,
Secrets Manager will use a Lambda function
to rotate the secrets.
And if you do happen to enable Secret Rotation,
the Secret is going to be rotated immediately.
Now, in the use case of you're using a Lambda function
to rotate an Amazon RDS database,
you must make sure
that this Lambda function has access
to both the Secrets Manager Service
and your database.
So let's assume that our Amazon RDS database
is deployed within a VPC.
Then we must, of course, deploy our Lambda function
within the same VPC,
then is going to be able to access Amazon RDS privately,
but also we need to make sure
we have a VPC endpoint to access back Secrets Manager
or a NAT Gateway in place,
again, to get network connectivity into Secrets Manager.
We also have the possibility from Lambda function
to pull secrets at runtime from Secrets Manager.
For example, say we want to connect to an RDS database
and the password of this RDS database
is within Secrets Manager.
We want to inject the secret as an environment variable.
So for this, we're going to reference
the secret from Lambda,
which, when the Lambda function boots up,
is going to fetch that secret
and then access the RDS database.
Thanks to that, of course, password value.
So for this to happen
your Lambda function
must be configured to access the secrets in Secrets Manager
and must have the proper IAM policy.
There is also a very similar mechanism
where we integrate ECS with Secrets Manager.
So let's talk about the exact same problem.
We want to access RDS database at runtime
and so we, at boot,
are going to pull the secret out of Secrets Manager,
is going to be injected as an environment variable,
and then we can access RDS.
And this can happen
only if we have the proper IAM policy in place
and we've configured our ECS task properly
with an IAM role.
Alright, next we have resource policies
for Secrets Managers.
So it is possible for you to define access to a secret
thanks to a resource policy,
the same way we have bucket policies for S3 buckets.
So let's say we have a secret
and we attach this resource policy to the secret,
where we're saying is that this secret
can be accessed by the user Mary,
and that's good enough.
Mary does not need to have its own IAM permissions
to access the secrets.
So the use case is
to grant access to a single secret
for multiple users
managing this from a secret perspective.
And forcing provisions,
for example, we can add an explicit deny
to a secret for whatever use case you have,
or sharing a secret between AWS accounts.
Okay, that's it for Secrets Manager.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.