Just a short lecture
around CloudFront's geo restriction.
So you can restrict who can access your distribution
based on the country where they try
to access the distribution from.
So you can set up an allow list to define
a list of approved countries or you can set up a block list
to set up a list of banned countries.
Now, the country is determined
by using a third party geo-IP database
to match the IP of the user to the country it belongs to.
So the use case for using geo restriction
would be copyright laws to control access to content.
So if we have a look in the geographic restriction
in CloudFront, you can edit them
and you can set up an allow list or a block list,
and then say for example that only people from United States
and then India are allowed in my distribution,
and else not, and then you save the changes.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.