So now let's talk about Object Encryption
in Amazon S3.
So you can encrypt objects in S3 buckets
using one of the following four methods.
The first one is Server-Side Encryption, SSE.
and you have multiple flavors of it.
So you have SSE-S3, which is Server-Side Encryption
with Amazon S3-managed keys,
and that is enabled by default for your buckets
and your objects.
Then we have SSE-KMS where we encrypt this time
with a KMS key to manage the encryption key.
Then we have SSE-C to use Customer-Provided key.
So this time we provide the own encryption key
and don't worry, we'll see all of these in great detail
in the next slide.
So this is just an overview.
And then we have Client-Side Encryption
when we want to encrypt everything Client-Side
and then upload it to Amazon S3.
So at the exam it's important to understand
which ones are for which situation.
So let's do a deep dive into all of those
and understand the specificities of them.
So the first one is Amazon S3 for SSE-S3 Encryption.
So in this case, the encryption is using a key
that's handled, managed and owned by AWS.
You never have access to this key.
The object is going to be Encrypted Server-Side by AWS
and the security type of the encryption is a AES-256.
Therefore, you must set the header to
x-amz-server-side encryption AES256
to request Amazon S3 to encrypt the object for you
using the SSE-S3 mechanism.
Now SSE-S3 is enabled by default for new buckets
and new objects.
So how does that work with have Amazon S3 and our user?
The user you, you're going to upload the file
with the correct header
and then it will be an object under Amazon S3.
Amazon S3 will pair it with the S3 Owned key,
okay, because we're using the SSE-S3 mechanism.
And then we'll perform encryption
by mixing the key and the object
and that will be what will be stored on your S3 buckets.
So that's for the simpler one, SSE-S3.
Then we have SSE-KMS.
So this time, instead of relying on the key
that is owned by AWS MD S3 service,
you want to manage your own keys yourself
using the KMS service
the Key Management Service.
So the advantages using KMS
is that you have user control over this key.
So you can create keys yourself within KMS
and you can edit the key usage using CloudTrail.
So anytime someone uses a key in KMS
this is going to be logged in a service
that logs everything that happens in AWS called CloudTrail.
So for this, we must have a header called
the x-amz-server-side-encryption:awskms.
and then the object will be encrypted server-side.
So anything SSE of course is server-side.
So how does that work?
Well, again, we upload the object
this time with a different header,
and in the header we actually specify the KMS key
we want to use.
Then the object is appearing in Amazon S3
and this time the KMS key that's going to be used
is coming out of the AWS KMS.
So these two things together are going to be blended
and then you're gonna get encryption
and that's the file is going to end up in the S3 buckets.
So now to read that file from the S3 bucket
not only do you need access to the object itself,
but also, to the underlying KMS key that was used
to encrypt this object.
So this is another level of security.
So SSE-KMS has some limitations,
because while now that you upload and download files
from Amazon S3, you need to leverage a KMS key.
And the KMS key has its own APIs,
for example, generate data key.
And when you decrypt you're going to use the Decrypt API.
And so therefore, you're going to do API calls
into the KMS service,
and each of these API calls
is going to count towards the KMS quotas
of API calls per second.
So based on the region you have
between 5,000 and 30,000 requests per second,
although they can be increased
using the Service Quotas Console.
And so, if you have a very, very high throughput S3 bucket
and everything is encrypted using KMS keys
you may go into a thread link kind of use case.
So this is something the exam may test you on.
Next we have the SSE-C type of encryption.
So this time the keys are managed outside of AWS,
but it still service that encryption,
because we send the key to AWS.
But Amazon S3 will never store
the encryption key you provide.
After they're used, they're being discarded.
So in that case,
because we transmit a key into Amazon S3
we must use HTTPS and we must pass the key
as part of HTTP headers for every request being made.
So how does that work?
The user is going to upload a file as well as the key,
but the user manages the key outside of AWS
and then Amazon S3 will use the client's provided key
and the object to perform some encryption
and then put the file as encrypted into an S3 bucket.
And of course, to read that file, the user must again
provide the key that was used to encrypt that file.
Finally, we have the Client-Side Encryption.
So this is easier to implement
if we leverage some client library
such as the Client-Side Encryption Library.
And the idea with Client-Side Encryption
is that the clients must encrypt data themselves
before sending data to Amazon S3.
And also, you can retrieve the data from Amazon S3
and then the decryption of the data
happens on the client outside of Amazon S3.
Therefore, the client fully manages the keys
and the encryption cycle.
So how does that work?
We have a file and we have a client's key
that's outside of AWS.
The client itself is going to provide
and perform the encryption.
So now we have an encrypted file.
And that file as is can be sent into Amazon S3 for upload.
So we've seen all the levels of encryption of objects,
but now let's talk about encryption in transit.
So encryption in transit or in flight
is also called SSL or TLS.
And basically, your Amazon S3 bucket has two endpoints.
The HTTP endpoint that is not encrypted
and the HTTPS endpoint that has encryption in flight.
So anytime you visit a website
and you see that green lock or a lock
usually that means it's using encryption in flight
meaning the connection between you and the target server
is secure and fully encrypted.
And therefore, when you're using Amazon S3
it's fully recommended to use HTTPS
to have secure transmission of data, of course.
And if you use the SSE-C type of mechanism
you must use the HTTPS protocol.
Now this is not something to worry about in real-life,
because well, most clients would use
the HTTPS endpoint by default.
So that's it for encryption.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.