So I know you've just seen
S3 encryption in detail.
I'm just going to give you a summary
with one bit of information you need to know.
So we've seen SSE-S3 is to encrypt S3 objects
using keys handled and managed by AWS.
We've seen SSE-KMS where we use KMS
to manage encryption keys.
So the benefits that the key usage appears in CloudTrail.
But the thing I haven't told you
in the previous lecture that I'm telling you right now
is that the objects, even if you make them public,
they can never be read by anonymous users
because they do not have access to the underlying KMS keys.
Whereas an objects encrypted with SSE-S3 made public
can be accessed by anonymous user.
So also, when you do s3:PutObject,
you need to make sure you have
the kms:GenerateDataKey permission
because well, you need to generate a data key
to encrypt a large file in Amazon S3.
When you use SSE-C,
this is when you want to manage your own encryption keys
for server-side encryption.
Then we have the option of client-side encryption.
And finally, if you use Glacier,
all data is going to be encrypted with AES-256
and the key will be under AWS control.
All right, that's it for this summary lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.