Hi, and welcome to this lecture
on VPC Endpoint Strategies for Amazon S3.
So we know that we can access Amazon S3
directly through a VPC Gateway Endpoint.
So this doesn't have any costs
and it can only be accessed by resources
within the VPC where it's created.
So we have VPC Gateway Endpoint for Amazon s3
and then we enable DNS support.
We update the root tables and we keep on using
the public DNS of Amazon S3.
And what's going to happen is that the traffic
is gonna go through this VPC gateway endpoints.
We also need to make sure that the security group
attached to the EC2 instance has Outbound rules
that allows traffic that go directly into Amazon S3.
So when we have all these things together, it's working.
Just remember that Gateway Endpoints can only be accessed
by resources within your VPC but not elsewhere,
so Direct Connect does not work,
side to side VPN does not work,
and so on VPC peering does not work,
only stuff within your VPC.
Next we have the VPC Interface Endpoint for Amazon S3.
So let's take an example of a VPC
with several availability zones.
We have DNS support enabled and DNS hostnames enabled.
We have private subnets across these two AZs.
So with the VPC interface endpoint we're going to get
Elastic Network interfaces deployed in our subnets
and then the security groups can be attached
to these ENIs for network security.
So then what we're going to do
is that we're going to have EC2 instances
and with the appropriate network security
we're gonna be able to access Amazon S3 privately
through the VPC interface endpoints.
The advantage of using an interface endpoint
is that we can get access directly from on-premises
through a site to site VPN or Direct Connect.
This costs about 1 cents per hour per AZ, so it's not free
and it's works similarly, once you have enabled the DNS
in your settings in your VPC,
then any public DNS of Amazon S3
will be resolved to the private interface endpoint
and you'll be good.
Okay, finally, you need to know
there's like something called private DNS name,
which works for most VPC endpoints,
but for the VPC interface endpoint for Amazon S3
there is no such thing as private DNS name.
The only thing you can use is the public DNS name
of Amazon s3, but the traffic will still resolve
to the VPC interface endpoint within your VPC.
So if we try to summarize what we have
in a single VPC architecture, we may have EC2 instances
accessing directly Amazon S3
for a gateway endpoint for free.
Or if you choose to create an interface endpoint
we have a private link into Amazon S3
and the use case would be to use
either direct connect or site to site VPN
to connect to Amazon S3 through this interface endpoint.
If you have a multi VPC centralized architecture
where you want all your network traffic
to go through one Central VPC,
then an architecture you can have is EC2 instances
that connect through Gateway Endpoint to Amazon S3
in their respective VPC because that's free
and you can do it.
And then interface endpoints can be very helpful.
For example, if you wanted to centralize traffic
through this central VPC,
so instead of going through Gateway Endpoint,
you could go through a transit gateway
into the interface endpoint.
And this works as well for the on-premises traffic
such as Direct Connect and site to side VPN.
So at the exam, you will have indicators
whether or not you should use Gateway or interface
and it's up to you to choose the right one of course
but you have enough information now
to really understand the differences.
Also, we have VPC endpoint restrictions.
So we have a couple ones.
We have SourceVPC, and SourceVPCE.
So here with SourceVPC we can restrict access
to a specific VPC.
For example, in here I restrict access to my bucket
if it doesn't come through a specified source VPC.
Now this condition can only work if you have a VPC endpoint.
So that means that on top of going through the VPC endpoint
you can restrict the VPC it's coming from.
If you wanted to restrict access to specific VPC endpoints
what you can do is have a source VPCE condition,
E for endpoints, and then you specify the VPC endpoints ID.
Once you have this as well
so you can restrict by SourceIP.
Just remember, the AWS SourceIP condition
is for public IP addresses,
whereas the VPC SourceIP is for private IP addresses
and it is only valid when you start using VPC endpoints.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.