So just a short lecture
on this feature in CloudWatch called Contributor Insights.
So this allows you to analyze log data,
and then you create time series
that will display contributor data.
And what is contributor data?
Well, this is the use case to find the top talkers,
for example, on your network and to understand who is what
and what is impacting system performance.
So for example, if you have network data
and logs on CloudWatch Logs,
then this allows you to find the bad host,
to identify the heaviest network users,
or to find the URLs that generate the most errors.
So this is about ranking and doing some computation.
This works for any AWS-generated logs,
so it could be your VPC flow logs,
your DNS logs, and whatever.
And you can use the built-in rules created by AWS
or you can build your own rules.
So let me give you a concrete example
for you to understand this feature.
So let's say we have our VPC flow logs,
then we are going to export them
and stream them into CloudWatch logs,
and then we're going to use
the CloudWatch Contributor Insights
to figure out the top 10 IP addresses
on my network, because that may indicate
that some EC2 instances are not behaving correctly
or that we're being under attack.
So hopefully, you understand the value of this feature.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.