So now let's talk about a cool new settings
for your S3 Buckets using it with SSE-KMS encryption.
And this is a new setting
which will allow you to decrease and wait for it.
The number of API calls made to KMS from Amazon S3
when you use the SSE-KMS type of encryption by 99%.
Which will reduce the cost of your overall KMS encryption
used by Amazon S3 by also 99%.
And how does this work?
Well, this leverages data key
and more importantly,
this thing called an S3 bucket key.
So how does that work?
Well, a customer master key and KMS
is going to be used to generate
a data key for your Amazon S3 Bucket once in a while
and this key will rotates.
But, once in a while and this key's called
an Amazon S3 Bucket key.
And this key is what's going to be used to encrypt objects
in your Amazon S3 Buckets with KMS encryption.
So this extra bucket key is going to generate
a lot of data keys using envelope encryption
which is going to go into encrypting your S3 Buckets.
But by adding an S3 Bucket key
and not using KMS directly
to generate these data keys,
we are reducing the number
of API calls we are making into KMS.
And therefore, we are reducing our costs by a lot.
And so this is an optimization
of using SSE-KMS to decrease the number
of KMS API calls in order,
for example, not to have a high bill
or not to go over the limits of encryption
within your Amazon S3 Buckets
but without compromising on security.
The result of that is that you will see
less CloudTrail events regarding KMS in CloudTrail.
And also, you will have
a way way lower costs as I said in KMS.
So that's it for this lecture.
A very good setting to know,
especially if you use SSE-KMS at Scale
were very high for both.
Now let me show you where you can find
that setting in the S3 Console.
So let's go into the S3 Console
and I'm going to create a new buckets.
So I'm going to create a buckets
and I'll call it,
(keyboard typing)
Demo S3 Buckets key.
Okay?
Then we'll block, public settings.
We'll disable, versioning.
We'll enable, encryption.
And it's going to be SSE-KMS,
and it's going to be managed key.
(mouse clicking)
And we are going to enable, bucket keys.
So by default, it is enabled now,
but we could disable it
if we wanted to get every single upload to talk to KMS.
But, if you want to enable it
we'll just click on enable.
And this will use the bucket key to decrease the cost
and the number of calls made to KMS
without losing any security.
So fairly easy,
then we create the buckets
and we're good to go.
And we're now using the bucket key
for encryption into our S3 Buckets.
So that's it, I will see you in the next lecture.