Next we have WAF, the Web Application Firewall
which allows you to protect your web applications
from common web exploits at the Layer 7.
So, this is the HTTP Layer.
You can deploy it on the Application Load Balancer
to get localized rules.
You can deploy it on the API Gateway
to get rules running at the regional or edge level.
You can deploy on CloudFront
and these rules are going to be running globally
on all edge locations where CloudFront is.
And this can be used for example,
if you wanted to have a Web Application Firewall
for your Cloud Load Balancer,
your EC2 instances, custom origins or S3 websites.
You would have CloudFront
and then deploy WAF on CloudFront.
You can also deploy it on AppSync
and this is going to allow you to protect
your GraphQL APIs directly.
So, remember that WAF is not used for DDoS protection.
For this we have Shield.
WAF is used for Layer 7 type of exploits.
So, for this you're going to define Web ACL.
So, the Web Access Control List.
And the rules can include IP addresses filtering,
HTTP headers, HTTP body, URL strings.
You can have common attacks protections
such as SQL injection or Cross-site Scripting, XSS.
You can have size constraints to say,
"Hey any request bigger than 20 megabytes at once."
You can have Geo match to block or allow a specific country.
And you can have rate-based rules.
So, to count occurrences of events
and say, "Hey if this happened
more than five times per second,
this looks fishy, block it."
And the rule actions can be
allow or block as we know
to allow or to block traffic.
They could be Count.
And that's an interesting one.
This is to see if a rule would be in effect or not.
So, this allows you to detect false positives ahead of time.
So, you would just count occurrences
and analyze the result of a account operation
but the traffic is still allowed through.
So, you do Count before Block or CAPTCHA
if you wanted to protect some traffic
with a CAPTCHA to make sure
that there is some some client side verification
before it gets to you.
So, something super important
for you to know is that WAF has Managed Rules.
You need to know it for the exam.
So, there are over 190 Managed Rules
and I'll give you some of the most important.
They are ready to use Managed Rules
that will be from AWS or the Marketplace Sellers
and they allow you to just power up WAF very quickly.
So, you get Baseline Rule Groups
which is general protection from common threats.
And this include the Managed Rules Common Rule Sets,
the Managed Rules Admin Protection Rule Set and so on.
So, they're just baseline for common protection.
Then you have Use-case Specific Rule Groups
and they give you protection for many use-cases
such as the SQL Rule Sets, the Windows Rule Sets,
the PHP Rule Sets, the WordPress Rule Sets
to protect these kind of applications.
Then you get IP Reputation Rule Group.
And this is to block request based on the source IP.
So for example, you have a malicious IP
and there is this very important rule called
the Managed Rules Amazon IP Reputation List.
Which is a list of all the IPs
that are trusted by AWS and those are not trusted by AWS.
And this can help you block spammers very quickly.
You can also get anonymous IP List as a rule and so on.
And finally there's Bot Control Managed Rule Group
to block and manage request from bots.
So this includes, for example,
the AWS Manage Rule Bots Control Rule Set.
So, as you can see we have four kinds
of Managed Rule buckets Baseline,
Use-case Specific, IP Reputation and Bot Control.
And the thing that can come up in the exam
is one of these including the Amazon IP Reputation List.
Okay, so what about logging for WAF?
This is also something that can come up in the exam.
So, well WAF can send logs to Amazon CloudWatch Log Groups
and you get a debit of five megabytes per second maximum.
You can also send it to Amazon S3 bucket
and the logs will be sent every five minutes.
Or if you want to have more control,
well you can send it directly from WAF
to Kinesis Data Firehose
in which case you are only limited by the Firehose quotas.
Well, while would you do this, well, for example,
if you have very high traffic
very high logging capacity requirements
then using KDF could be a very good thing.
And then from Kinesis Firehose
you can send it to any destination supported by Kinesis
such as Amazon S3, Redshift, OpenSearch, and so on.
So, using WAF there is a solution architecture
you need to know which is to enhance
CloudFront Origin Security.
So, let's say we have CloudFront
in front of an Application Load Balancer
talking to EC2 instances
and we want to make sure that only the traffic coming
from Amazon CloudFront is allowed
into the Application Load Balancer and not,
for example, site traffic if we were to have the URL
of the Application Load Balancer.
So, how would we do this?
Well, using WAF we can already set up some Web ACLs
on the CloudFront level.
This is not going to help us
with the Application Load Balancer
but at least we control some level
of security on the client.
Okay, next, what's going to happen is that
on the Amazon CloudFront you can create what's
called a custom HTTP Header
and you have it, for example,
set to X-Origin Verify and then a secret string.
And so this will be added to every request
that goes through Amazon CloudFront.
The result of which is that we can also set up WAF
on the Application Load Balancer
and we create a Filtering Rule that says that
any traffic that has this header, the X-Origin Verify,
and the value will be allowed
and anything else will be rejected.
So, that means that someone, a user,
trying to access directly the ALB,
of course they don't know about the fact
you're using custom HTTP Headers
because they're heading from the user.
Therefore, they cannot access your ALB
because they will be blocked by WAF directly.
On top of it,
you can set up auto-rotation of this HTTP Header
to have maximum security.
So, using Secrets Manager, we can have a secret
that is automatically rotated
using a Lambda Function,
and the Lambda Function will update once in a while
the custom HTTP Header Value
with a new value in CloudFront,
and of course update the Filtering Rule in AWS WAF.
So, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.