Okay, Another short lecture
around how to encrypt many objects at a time
in the S3 bucket.
To do so, we must use the S3 Batch service,
which allows you to do bulk operations on existing objects
such as encryption or de-encryption.
And then we need to use also S3 inventory.
This is going to give us a list
of all the objects and their metadata,
and then we can find
whether or not objects are encrypted properly.
And then we have S3 Select or Athena
to filter or list only these un-encrypted objects.
So to combine it all together,
using S3 Inventory we get an object list
that we can filter using S3 Select.
Then we have the list of all the unencrypted objects.
We use S3 Batch then to reference a KMS key ID,
and then we're going to process all the objects
and encrypt them.
Super simple, but you need to make sure
that the S3 Batch operation has access
to the S3 bucket and the KMS key.
So that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.