Okay, so let's do a short intro
to Amazon ECR.
So Amazon ECR stands
for Elastic Container Registry,
and it's used to store
and manage Docker images on AWS.
So so far, we've been using online repository
such as Docker hub
but we can also store our own images
on Amazon ECR.
And actually you have two options for ECR.
We can store images privately,
just for your account
or your own accounts
with an s
or you can use a public repository and publish
to the Amazon ECR public gallery.
Now ECR is fully integrated
with Amazon ECS,
which is great.
And your images
are behind the scenes stored
by Amazon S3.
So your ECR repository
may contain different Docker images
and then your ECS cluster.
And for example,
an EC2 instance
on your ECS cluster may want
to pull these images.
So to do so
while we're going
to sign an IAM role
to our EC2 instance
and this IAM role will allow our instance
to pull Docker images.
So of course, all access
to ECR is protected by IAM.
That includes that if you have a permission error
on ECR have a look
at your policies
and then your
containers are going
to be started
on your EC2 instance
after they are pulled
by your EC2 instance.
And this is how ECS
and ECR ECR work together.
Now, Amazon ECR is great
because on top
of being a repository,
it, supports image vulnerability
scanning, versioning, image tags,
and image lifecycle.
So overall, anytime you see
storing Docker images think ECR
and that should be it
for you at the exam.
All right.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you
in the next lecture.