So now let's discuss Trusted Advisor.
So Trusted Advisor is a service that just runs out of the
bucks. You don't need to install anything,
and it gives you a high level AWS account assessments.
So it will just run a bunch of checks
and tell you if the checks are passing or not passing.
And here's an example of the checks does, for example,
Amazon EBS public snapshots, zero found,
okay good. The check is passing and so on.
So it's going to analyze your accounts and provide
recommendations on five categories.
And you need to remember these five categories so please
learn them. We have cost optimization performance, security,
fault tolerance and service limits.
Remember these five categories because the exam
will ask you,
"Hey, what are two of the Trusted Advisor categories?"
So remember these five so that you can identify the ones
that are going to be correct in the question.
The second thing that the exam will ask you on for
Trusted Advisor is around the support plans.
So we have by default seven core checks available to us
if we are on the basic and developer support plan. So again,
something to remember seven core checks on the basic
and developer support plan.
And you need to remember them what these core checks are,
because again, the exam will ask you,
"Hey, what are some of the core checks of Trusted Advisor?"
So we have seven, we have S3 bucket permissions,
making sure bucket is not public. Security group,
making sure that some ports are not unrestricted,
such as SSH.
IAM Use so making sure that we have at least one,
IAM user in our accounts. MFA on root accounts
so making sure that we have enabled
multifactor authentication
for the root accounts,
ensuring we don't have any EBS
public snapshots, ensuring we do not have any RDS
public snapshots.
And finally looking at service limits in AWS.
These are the seven core checks. Please remember them.
And the fact that it is for the basic
and developers support plan.
The other thing you need to know about Trusted Advisor is
around the full checks.
So this is available for your business
and enterprise support plan.
Yet nother thing to remember.
And is going to give you access to
all the checks in the five categories I showed you before
you can set CloudWatch alarms
when reaching these limits and you have very important
as well from an exam perspective,
you get programmatic access using the AWS support API.
You do not have access to the API if you are on the basic
and developer support plan. Okay?
So let's have a look at Trusted Advisor now in the console.
So let me go into the Trusted Advisor service.
Here we go. So currently there's zero actions,
zero investigations and zero excluded items,
and you can refresh all checks
if you want to have a run of all the checks
of Trusted Advisor.
And as we can see, there's a recommended action.
It says you need to upgrade your support plan to get access
to all Trusted Advisor checks.
Because right now I am just on the basic support plan.
So let's go into cost optimization. As you can see,
we have none because we don't have the support plan needed
for that. Same for performance, same for security.
I'm sorry, same for fault tolerance.
And for security, we have access to six checks.
So we have EBS public snapshots, RDS public snapshots,
IAM Use, S3 bucket permissions,
MFA on root accounts and security groups
specific ports unrestricted.
So this is six free core checks available to me.
And then on service limits,
we have access to a bunch of service limits in here to check
for example, whether or not we're using the limits
of EC2 on-demand instances and so on.
And for tolerance as well
we don't have access with the checks.
So what I want you to see
is that if you go to cost optimization,
we can have a look at, for example,
this is a low utilization. Amazon is two instances check,
but we don't have access to this check unless we upgrade our
support plan. Okay?
So you've seen everything you need to see
from the exam perspective.
It's not very interesting to look at Trusted Advisor on
the core checks when nothing's running on my accounts,
obviously. But I find it very, very good, for example,
to have a check for EBS public snapshots
or RDS public snapshots,
because this could be a data leak or your Amazon S3 bucket
permissions that are too open to the public. Okay?
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and it will see you in the next lecture.