Okay, so let's talk
about SSL encryption for your Elastic Load Balancer.
So this is our classic architecture,
and the idea is that you could have termination
at the ELB level
by having an SSL or TLS certificate loaded onto it.
In which case, while our users will access our ELB
using an encrypted connection
for example, HTTPS, but there is going to be a termination
because then the ELB will just send HTTP traffic
over your prior VPC into your EC2 instances.
So you would load an SSL or TLS certificate
on the ELB and to manage these certificates,
you need to use ACM, which is AWS Certificate Manager.
You can upload your own certificates as well onto ACM
and then have them used by the ELB.
For your HTTPS listener,
you must specify a default certificate
and you can have as well an optional list of certificates
if you wanted to support multiple domains.
And as we'll see,
there's something called Server Name Indication, SNI,
to allow clients to specify the domain
the hostname they're gonna trying to reach
and therefore your ELB will be able to send back
the correct certificates.
You can also specify an SSL Security Policy
for compliance features, compatibility, or security
as we'll see in the very next slides.
So now let's talk about SNI or Server Name Indication.
The idea is that SNI will solve the problem
of loading multiple SSL certificates
onto one single web server
that will be serving multiple websites and domains.
So we have our ALB and say, we have two target groups.
One is www.mycorp.com, which has EC2 instances.
And the other target group will be serving demo.example.com
with other sets of EC2 instances.
The idea is that on our ALB
we're going to have routing based on hostname.
And so therefore the hostname when indicated
will be served by the right target group.
Now, we're also going to load a lot of certificates
on the ALB.
So we're going to load demo.example.com,
but also www.mycorp.com as well as maybe other ones
and a default SSL Certificates.
What's going to happen
is that a client when it connects to your ALB,
will indicate the server name, the hostname.
So I would like to connect to www.mycorp.com
and thanks to the SNI feature,
the ALB will know which SSL certificate
to use to establish the connection with the clients
and make sure it is correctly encrypted.
So SNI is quote in quote, a newer protocol
and requires the client to indicate the hostname
of the target it tries to connect to
during the initial SSL handshake.
And therefore,
the server will find the correct certificates.
This only works therefore for the newer generations types
of load balancer, such as the Application Load Balancer
and the Network Load Balancer.
Now, these SSL certificates can be loaded onto the CLB.
So the CLB supports only one SSL certificate.
And if you wanted to support multiple hostnames
through your CLB, you would need to use SAN.
So Subject Alternate Name on your SSL certificates.
But the idea is that anytime you will need
to add or remove a domain name,
you will need to edit the SSL certificate with new SANs.
And so therefore it is a complicated process
because you will need to reissue
and reassign these certificates over time.
Therefore, sometimes the best option is to use multiple CLBs
for multiple hostnames with multiple SSL certificates.
But if you can transition away
from the CLB and use the ALB instead,
because the ALB has the Server Name Indication feature
that we just saw that will simplify your life.
So talking about the ALB,
it supports multiple HTTPS listeners
and multiple SSL certificates.
And then in order to make it work
with multiple hostnames,
then we're going to use this Server Name Indication feature,
the SNI feature we just saw.
The NLB is similar.
It supports multiple listeners
with multiple SSL certificates.
And we're also going to use SNI
to serve the correct SSL certificates.
Now, finally, it is possible for you
to set up a security policy
for your HTTPS or your SSL listener.
So security policy is a combination
of SSL protocols, SSL ciphers
and Server Order Preference option
that's going to be supported during the SSL negotiation.
That is when your client is connecting
to your server and establishing a secure connection.
So you can use some predefined security policies
for example, the ELBSecurityPolicy-2016-08
and then apply it to your load balancer.
So if you consider the Application Load Balancer
and the Network Load Balancer,
then in case of frontend connections,
so connections from the client to your load balancer,
then you can use a predefined security policy.
And for backend connections,
then you must use the ELBSecurityPolicy-2016-08.
It's going to be always used.
So what can we set for predefined security policy?
We have different ones.
We have the default I just showed you.
But also you can use the ELBSecurityPolicy-TLS policies.
So in this case, you must meet compliance
and security standards that require
to only use certain TLS protocol version.
That may be something internally within your company.
And also if you wanted
to sometimes support older versions
of SSL and TLS for your legacy clients and application.
The other kind of policies you may want
to use is the ELBSecurityPolicy-FS.
And this is when you require Forward Secrecy.
So the idea is that with this,
you're going to get additional safeguards
against the eavesdropping of encrypted data
by using during the negotiation,
a unique, random session key
and that can come up in the exam.
So anytime you see,
how do we use a unique random session key for your ALB,
think of a Forward Secrecy policy for your load balancer.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.