So here is a specific lecture
for TLS and your network balancer.
So if you want to have a TLS listener,
you can use it on your NLB.
So it will use the server certificate
to terminate the TLS traffic
and then it will decrypt the front end connections
and then they will send it to the targets unencrypted.
If you wanna create a TLS listener,
you must create a certificate in ACM
and then you attach it on your NLB.
And even if you have TLS termination
on your NLB, with client IP preservation setting enabled,
the target instances, we'll still see the source IP address
and port as if it comes from your clients.
So the diagram is like this.
The client, for example, talks to the TLS listener
on port 443 of your network load balancer,
which has TLS termination enabled
because it has a certificate.
What's going to happen is that the EC2 instances
in your target group
are going to see HTTP unencrypted traffic
from your network load balancer, and the source IP of that
if client IP preservation is enabled
is going to be the IP of your client.
Now, with this kind of mechanism,
because the traffic is terminated
at the NLB level from an encryption perspective,
then these networks do not support TLS renegotiation,
or mutual TLS authentication, mTLS
because it has to be done directly by the client
with the EC2 instances and not by the NLB.
So how do we do this?
Well, the option to do this kind
of end-to-end encryption is to use a TCP listener,
so not an encrypted one
but you define it on port 443, even though it's just TCP.
And what's going to happen is that all this TCP traffic
is going to be passed encrypted to the target
without the NLB decrypting it or terminating it.
So we don't use a TLS listener, and it is the responsibility
of the target group to actually decrypt the traffic.
So how does that work?
The clients sends encrypted traffic through your NLB
but we have a TCP listener this time.
Then the same traffic is going to be passed
in encrypted to your EC2 instances,
which are the one that will be performing TLS termination.
And when you have the setting, you support mutual TLS
because well, the NLB will pass the traffic as is
and then the mutual TLS authentication
can be implemented directly
on your EC2 instances as targets.
So something to know that once you see it in the exam,
it would make sense.
So I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.