Okay, so now let's discuss Identity Federation in AWS.
So, the idea is that you want to give users
that sit outside of AWS,
permissions to access your AWS resources in your accounts.
And the idea is that because the users already exist
within your corporate directory,
then you don't want to create specific IAM users for them,
because you'd like to do user management outside of AWS,
so this is why we need Identity Federation.
So these cases, is for example,
your corporation has its own identity system,
for example Active Directory,
or you have a web and mobile application
that needs to access AWS resources
and so, this is where we need Identity Federation.
So at its core, here it looks like so,
the user wants to access AWS
and we have an Identity Provider.
First,
and this will not be represented on any following graphs,
but just on this one,
obviously you need to set up a trust relationship
between AWS and the Identity Provider,
to tell AWS that it's fine to get an identity
from this one provider.
Then the user will perform a login
onto this Identity Provider,
will receive back credentials for AWS
and will access AWS using these temporary credentials.
So, Identity Federation can have multiple flavors,
it could be SAML 2.0,
a Custom Identity Broker,
Web Identity Federation with or without Amazon Cognito,
and then, the more recent Single Sign-On (SSO) service.
So, I'm going to discuss the first three,
Single Sign-On will have its own lecture
and this is the more recent generation
of Identity Federation,
but still from an exam perspective,
you need to know about, all of them.
So, let's go ahead with SAML 2.0 Federation.
So, Sam 2.0 stands for Security Assertion Markup language
and it's an open standard by many Identity Providers,
such as ADFS.
It supports integration
with Microsoft Active Directory, which is nice,
or any SAML 2.0 compatible IdP,
which is Identity Provider with AWS.
Using this, we can access the Console,
the CLI or any API using temporary credentials,
so we don't need to create IAM Users
for each of the employees in your ADFS
and you need, for example of course, to set up a trust
between IAM and your SAML 2.0 Identity Provider, both ways.
So under the hood, we'll use an API
called AssumeRoleWithSAML comes from the STS service
and they will give us temporary credentials
using SAML Assertion.
So as I said,
SAML 2.0 is the old way
and now the newer Amazon Single Sign-On service
is a new manage in super way to get this working,
but still,
we have to learn about SAML 2.0 Federation in here.
So, the best way to understand this is,
to go through a diagram.
So, we have our corporation where our Identity Provider sits
and AWS and our user wants to access an S3 bucket.
Now, inside of our corporation
we have a Portal or Identity Provider
and the user will make an authentication request to the IdP.
The IdP will verify the request through an Identity Store,
for example, LDAP-based,
and then it will return SAML Assertion,
if the login is successful.
So, this SAML Assertion is a proof that the user,
is who they claim to be
and therefore with this SAML Assertion,
the user can call the STS service
with AssumeRoleWithSAML API
and STS will verify the assertion, make sure that yes,
it is the one that is trusted and then say,
okay, here are some Temporary Security Credentials for you.
And the user will be able to access the AWS APIs,
using that mechanism.
It is very similar if the user wants to access
the console of AWS,
so very similar setup,
so, we still have the IdP and the LDAP Identity based Store.
We have the authentication loop, as I said from before,
but this time we post to AWS Sign-in,
in this endpoint with slash SAML.
And what this will return is that,
it will return a security credentials
through the STS service
and this will return a special URL,
the signin URL for the AWS console
and this URL will be used by the user,
to be redirected into the AWS Management Console
and from there on, everything is good.
So these two flows are very similar
because they use the same semi 2.0 Federation.
Now, if we have ADFS, it's something you may have,
well, it is the exact same mechanism as before,
the only difference is that on the left hand side,
we have the Microsoft Active Directory Federation services
on the top left,
and then on the bottom right, where the user sits,
is Active Directory itself.
Okay. So this is for you to understand,
what is the difference between the IdP, so ADFS
and the directory itself, which is Active Directory.
Okay.
More complicated and definitely older is that,
if your Identity Provider is not compatible with SAML 2.0,
then you need to use a Custom Identity Broker.
So, let's say we want to access AWS services
and the Management Console
and we have our corporation Identity Provider,
we'll have a Custom Identity Broker.
Now, the user will login to the Identity Broker,
which will verify the login itself,
but then, the Identity Broker,
will be the one to authenticate and request
temporary credentials from AWS,
so this time, there is no AWS API that can be used,
so therefore the Custom Identity Broker has admin power
and can request temporary credentials,
directly from the STS service,
which will be returning these credentials themselves.
Now, that means that the Identity Broker is responsible
and must determine the appropriate IAM role for that user,
so it pushes the management of the users
into the Identity Broker itself.
Then the only way for it to work is,
to use the AssumeRole or GetFederation Token API from STS,
directly from the Custom Identity Broker.
So, once the security credentials are retrieved,
then they're passed on to the user
and the user can access the APIs AWS
or be redirected through the Management Console.
So again, these are the old ways of doing things,
SSO will come up later in this course.
Now, with Web Identity Federation,
we have two flavors,
we have without Cognito and with Cognito.
So, without Cognito is not recommended by AWS anymore,
it is recommended to use Cognito instead,
but still you need to know about it.
So, what is web identity Federation?
So, this time we have an untrusted environment,
so before it was our corporation, so we knew the clients
but in this case it is cloud
and we want to access services from our client directly,
but we are going to authenticate
with a third party Identity Provider,
it could be Amazon Google, Facebook
or any OpenID Connect Compatible IdP.
So, this obviously will be set up with AWS,
as a trust mechanism
and so the flow is that,
the client will login into the IdP, the third party IdP
and then the Web Identity Token
is going to be shared back with the clients.
The client will use a special STS API
called the AssumeRoleWithWebIdentity API
and then by trading that token,
it will receive a Temporary Security Credentials for AWS.
These credentials will be used to access
AWS resources directly.
So, this is the old way without Cognito.
With Cognito it's a little bit more secure and more simple.
So, it's preferred over Web Identity Federation
because here in Cognito, we can create IAM Roles
with the least privileged needed
and then we just need to build the trust
between the OIDC IdP and AWS.
So now, we have the Cognito service,
the client still authenticates to a party Identity Provider,
gets a token back,
but then the token is exchanged with Amazon Cognito,
which will return a Cognito token.
That Cognito token can be exchanged with STS
to receive a Temporary Security Credential for AWS.
And then the client will be able to access
the AWS resources directly.
So, why should we use this mechanism with Cognito?
Well, Cognito will support anonymous users,
which is a plus.
It will support MFA and it will have data synchronization.
So in that instance, Amazon Cognito operates,
at what's called,
a token vending machine,
because it exchanges token for credentials.
Okay.
So when we have Web Identity Federation,
can we restrict IAM policy?
The answer is yes,
you can use an IM policy variable.
And so, here is an example of a policy
that allows the user to only list a bucket with a prefix
as the user ID
and also to get update
and put objects with that specific prefix.
So, the idea is that,
when you have a Web Identity Federation,
you can use some special variables,
for example, cognito-identity.amazonaws.com:sub
or amazon.com:user_id and so on,
to restrict your IAM policies with conditions
and make sure that the users
really have the restrictions they need.
Okay.
So that's it for Identity Federation,
these are the old ways,
obviously, except what me using Cognito
and we'll see SSO in the future lecture.
So, hope you like this
and I would strongly suggest to revisit this lecture,
one more time before exam and it should all make sense
and I will see you in the next lecture.