Let's talk about Route 53 DNSSEC.
But before I introduce a solution,
let me expose in a simplified version the problem.
So we have DNS poisoning or spoofing.
It's a type of attack.
So for example say we have our web server,
it's hosting the website we want, for example.com.
And it is at a specific IP 9.10.11.12.
So the web browser of a client
is going to ask the local DNS server for example.com.
Then the local DNS server needs to actually
get the record for it.
So it's going to figure out
that Route 53 has, on its DNS, the solution
for where example.com is located.
So it's going to ask, for example.com
and Route 53 is going to return
well, it's the IP 9.10.11.12.
Okay. Fair enough.
But then a hacker through some process
manages to inject the value example.com equals
21.22.23.24 in our local DNS server.
And this is because, to very much simplify it,
the DNS works on the UDP protocol
which makes it somewhat easy to hack
and also when we don't have a DNSSEC
there is no cryptographic DNS verification process.
So therefore our local DNS server has been spoofed
and now is going to return to our web browser, the wrong IP.
So 21.22.23.24.
And therefore the web browser
is going to think it accesses the correct server
but actually it accesses a malicious website
at a different IP.
So that's call DNS poisoning and spoofing
and DNSSEC actually is going to help mitigate that issue.
So DNSSEC is for DNS Security Extension
and it's a protocol that helps you secure DNS traffic
to verify the DNS data integrity as well at its origin.
It only works when the hosted zones are public,
so for public domain names.
So Route 53 is going to support DNSSEC
both for domain registration and signing of the DNS records.
So the DNSSEC signing is the ability to validate
that a DNS response actually came from Route 53
and has not been tempered with.
So no record has been injected.
And how does it work?
Well, Route 53 is going to sign each record
in the hosted zone using a private key.
And then the clients can verify with a public key
that the signature is correct.
So the client needs to have some sort of logic
to understand the DNSSEC process.
So we have two keys happening within the DNSSEC process.
And the first one is managed by you
and you must remember it.
It is the key signing key, the KSK,
and it's based on an asymmetric CMK that you create in KMS.
So this key is managed by you
and then you have another one managed by AWS
which is call the ZSK, the zone signing key.
And you must know which one is yours.
So the one we manage is the KSK.
The ZSK is managed by Route 53 directly.
So when you enable Route 53
there's going to be some DNS signing in DNSSEC
and so therefore
you can verify cryptographically your records.
And there's also a second measure of security
which is that the TTL becomes at most one week
for all records in the hosted zone.
And if you have a TTL of less than one week,
then they're not affected, of course.
So the exam may ask you,
"How do you enable DNSSEC on a hosted zone?"
So first one you need to prepare for DNSSEC signing
that needs make sure that the zone availability
is working good.
That means that the DNS is responding correctly.
And this is done through customer feedback.
Then you lower the TTL for all your records to, for example,
one hour and you lower the TTL of the SOA to,
the SOA minimum, sorry, to five minutes.
So this is to prepare for DNSSEC signing.
Then you are going to enable DNSSEC signing
on your hosted zone
and you're going to create a key signing key, a KSK.
So to enable DNSSEC you can use the console or the CLI.
And then Route 53 is going to create a KSK for us
and we link it to a customer managed CMK from KMS.
So once this is done, we have enabled DNSSEC signing
but that's not all.
You need to establish a chain of trust.
And I will show you in the next slide
what that means, visually.
So chain of trust means that the hosted zone,
where we enable DNSSEC,
is going to tell the parent hosted zone to trust it.
And this is done by creating
a delegation signer, DS, record in the parent zone.
So it's very important.
The parent zone must have a record to trust the child zone.
So the DS record contains a hash of the public key
that's used to sign DNS records
and that's how the trust is established.
So your registrar that needs to trust your child zone
could be, for example, Route 53,
or it could be a third party registrar.
So once we've done that, we are signing all the records
using the key from step two.
And from step three, the parent hosted zone
knows to trust that signing key
thanks to the delegation signer, DS, record
that we insert in the parent zone.
And then finally, a very good to have in this setup
is to monitor for errors using CloudWatch Alarms
so you can create CloudWatch Alarms
for two specific type of metrics
and they can come in the exam.
We have the DNSSEC internal failure
and the DNSSEC key signing key needing action.
Okay, so all these things allow you to enable DNSSEC.
To remember them, okay:
step one, step two, three, and four.
And what is a chain of trust just to understand?
So in a DNS way, when we, for example,
query for a specific record,
we're first going to go to the root DNS server
which is going to point to the TLD DNS server's .com.
Then the registrar,
for example, for example.com on Route 53,
then the hosted zone, which contains the records.
And maybe if we have a second hosted zone in there
that is a sub.example.com,
then we may have children of children of hosted zones.
So the chain of trust can only work
if all of these DNS servers along the way
are DNSSEC aware.
So what's happening is that the root DNS server
is going to have a trust on the TLD DNS server.
And then the TLD DNS server is going to trust the registrar.
And then we set up DNSSEC on the hosted zone
and we insert a DS record
so that the registrar trusts the hosted zone.
And then if we have a sub hosted zone,
we insert, again in the parent hosted zone,
we insert a DNS DS record to trust the sub hosted zone
and so on.
And so that means that your client
when it does its queries,
is going to query every DNS server all at once.
And then all along the way, thanks to this chain of trust,
we can verify each DNS response and we can make sure,
and this is of course some logic implemented
in the libraries you're already using,
we can verify that all these units responses
have been encrypted correctly and signed correctly,
thanks to the associated public key.
And this is how DNSSEC works.
So that was a pretty long lecture
but hopefully now you understand how this works.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.