So let's talk about
a few security concerns with ECR.
So the first one is that you can have integration
between KMS and ECR
by encrypting your ECR repositories at rest,
using your KMS keys,
so your images will be encrypted
and they are encrypted using
the envelope encryption technique
thanks to your data encryption key.
And you can only enable the encryption
at the repository recreation.
So in case you want to encrypt an unencrypted repo,
you have to create a new repo that is encrypted
and then migrate over the images.
ECR, the way it works to encrypt these images,
will use a KMS grant on your behalf to interact with KMS.
And so this grant again
make sure you have the DescribeKey,
Decrypt, GeneratedKey and RetiredGrant permissions.
This is when you delete the repo.
So this should make sense by now.
What is new to you, for example,
is the fact that you can only enable the KMS encryption
at the repository creation time.
What about cross account access for your ECR repo?
So let's say we have a container image in an account
and another account wants to access it.
While you may have guessed it,
the one way to do it
is to use a repository policy
which is a resource policy
and this will allow the target account
to issue commands against our repo.
So the way it works is that when you do a login
from account B to get a Docker login,
please make sure to reference the first account
as the URL to authenticate.
You're going to get an authentication token out of it
and then you can just simply push the image
with the correct name to push
into the target ECR repository.
Same for pulling images.
So fairly simple.
The whole magic happens with a repository policy.
So some troubleshooting around ECR.
If you have a 403 forbidden error
or No basic Auth Credentials error.
And even if you've successfully gotten
a Docker login with ECR get login password,
you may have this error.
So the reason that could be the source of the issue
is that you have authenticated
to a different AWS region
and so the Docker login does not work across region.
You need to get a new one for it,
or this Docker login was successfully issued,
but then you don't have the necessary IAM permissions
to push or pull,
or we have an authentication token
and it has expired because it's only valid for 12 hours.
All right.
That's it for ECR.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.