One thing that I think is really cool and worth doing is that if you're not a native English speaker
like me I'm French then you can request a special exam accommodation that will allow you to get an extra
30 minutes on your end of a certification exams.
So I'm going to click on request accommodation and for the request type I can say what I want and what
I want is ESL plus 30 minutes this is available only to non native English speakers.
While taking an exam in English.
Okay.
And you only need to apply once and it will apply for all future exam registrations.
So we have ESL plus 30 minutes.
This is great.
And then I click on Create and here we go.
I have requested my extra 30 minutes for my exams so it will go ahead and be approved directly.
So here we go.
And it doesn't expire.
And so this is only for future exams so if you have somehow booked an exam before applying for this
exam accommodation please make sure to cancel your request this is free and then rebook your exam afterwards
and this will get applied the 30 minutes extra to your exam as well.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
Hope you liked it.
And good luck for your exam.
I will see you in the next lecture.