Okay, so now let's talk about AWS KMS
which is a Key Management Service.
So anytime you hear encryption in AWS
you have to think about KMS, obviously,
and it's a way to easily control access to our data
and AWS will manage the encryption keys for us.
It's fully integrated with IAM for authorization
and has seamless integrations into all the air services
pretty much so, EBS, S3, Redshift, RDS, SSM
et cetera, et cetera.
We can use the CLI or the SDK to interact with KMS.
So in KMS you have two types of key,
you have the symmetric keys and the asymmetric keys.
So the symmetric keys were the first offering of KMS,
it's a single encryption key that will be used
to encrypt and decrypt information.
And then all the services that are integrated
with AWS KMS use symmetric KMS keys.
It's necessary if you wanna do envelope encryption
and you never actually get access
to the KMS key itself or unencrypted,
you must just send data into KMS
with a KMS API call to use it.
Now the asymmetry key are new
and they can allow you to have two kind of public keys,
it's a key pair, so it's a public key and a private key.
The public key will be used to encrypt
and the private key will be used to decrypt.
Now, this is very helpful when you want to have
encrypt, decrypt or sign and verify operations
and you can download the public key,
that means that you can encrypt stuff
from anywhere with a public key,
and you can send the public key to people
that you don't trust in untrusted environments.
But once the data is encrypted with the public key,
only the private key has the power
to decrypt your information.
You still cannot use the private key unencrypted though,
you have to use the KMS API calls.
So the use case for an asymmetric key
is to have encryptions outside of AWS by users
who cannot directly call the KMS API for whatever reason.
Now, you have different types of KMS keys.
The first type is a Customer Managed Key,
and this is a key you create directly in KMS.
So you can create, manage, and use them,
you can enable, disable them,
you can enable a rotation policy
to rotate the key every year
while the old key is still preserved, of course.
And you can add a key policy,
which is a resource policy for KMS keys,
and you can audit the key usage in CloudTrail.
This is the kind of keys you will leverage
for envelope encryption,
so these are the kind of keys that you manage yourself,
therefore, they're called Customer Managed Keys.
But a second kind of key is the AWS Managed Keys.
So these ones are used exclusively by AWS services
such as AWS/S3, AWS/EBS and so on.
And this is what you see in the UI
when you use the AWS Managed Keys.
So they are managed by AWS
and they're automatically rotated every year.
You can view the key policy and you can audit in CloudTrail
but you cannot leverage them
for your own encryption operations.
And finally, you have AWS Owned Keys,
and these are created and managed by AWS,
used by some services to protect your resources
and they can be used across multiple others accounts,
but they're not in your accounts
they're used by AWS internally
and you cannot view, use, track or audit these keys.
But AWS tells you that these keys actually exist.
Okay, so now if we want to have a summary
of the different types of KMS keys
for the Customer Managed Keys
you can manage metadata,
you can view metadata and you can manage it
and you can also use for your accounts
and you can have an automatic rotation every one year.
The AWS Managed Key can be used in your accounts, okay?
But you cannot manage them
and they're required to be rotated every one year,
this is automatic.
And then the Owned keys, you just know they exist
but you cannot use them or see them.
Okay.
Now, how do you create a KMS key?
So you have what's called a Key Material Origin
and it cannot be changed after creation
so you have to define it at creation time.
So you have the KMS, which is the AWS KMS key material
which is, that means that you are going to have
KMS automatically create, generate, and manage the key
in its own Key Store to see what happens
when you go into KMS and start to create a key.
But you have a second option called, External,
in that case, while you import
the key material directly into the KMS key
and you are responsible for securing
and managing this key material outside of AWS, okay?
So, maybe you just wanna create it outside
and then import it into this KMS
and then be done and delete it on your end.
Or you just wanna keep a copy in KMS
and therefore you're responsible obviously
for the copy outside of KMS.
Now, the last option is to use a Custom Key Store
called AWS_CLOUDHSM
and this allows you to create the key material
directly within your HSM cluster
and manage the key material there.
So let's consider how it works
when you have a Custom Key Store,
which is backed by CloudHSM.
So you create your CloudHSM cluster as a Custom Key Store
and there is a direct integration with KMS.
That means that when KMS creates key
while the key materials are going to be stored
in your HSM cluster that you own and manage,
that means that the keys live within your HSM cluster,
they are only managed by KMS and used by KMS,
and all the cryptographic operations
will be directly performed in the HSMs, okay?
So this is the architecture.
You have your CloudHSM cluster with two AZs
and it is directly connected to KMS.
So once you have at least two HSMs for high availability
then you can integrate with KMS,
and then the users can still use the KMS API
to view, create a manage keys
but behind the scenes, you know for sure that KMS
will be using your CloudHSM cluster
for all the cryptographic operations
and for storing and retrieving these keys.
So why do we do this?
Well, the use cases is that you need to have
direct control over the HSMs for higher security
or for security requirements at least.
And then the KMS keys,
partly maybe they want to be in a dedicated HSM
or maybe you need to have a regulatory requirement
to have FIPS 140-2 Level 3 level of security,
because KMS was only validated at Level 2.
Now, if you choose to have an external KMS key source
then you can bring your own key
using your own key material,
and you are going to be responsible
for the keys materials security,
availability and durability outside of AWS.
So it must be a 256-bits symmetric key,
so you cannot import asymmetric material for now
and it cannot be used with Custom Key Store,
it has to be used on its own.
For this, if you want to have KMS Key Rotation,
of course, because the key source is external
then you have to rotate it on your own
so automate rotation is not supported.
So, how does that work?
Well, the user will create a KMS key in KMS
and say that it's a symmetric type of key
and that the source is external.
Now, the key envelope is created
but the key material is not.
So then you download the public key and an import token,
and you're going to use the public key with your internal,
okay, your externally generated key material
to create an encryption thanks to the public key.
Now, this public key,
this private key that has been encrypted
can be sent back to the KMS service
using also the import token,
and then KMS will use some decryption mechanism
to get the key material and store it
in your KMS key in there.
So this is the process to import external keys in KMS.
Okay, lastly,
so you need to know about KMS Multi-Region Keys.
So it's possible for you to create a key,
for example, in US-East-1
and have it replicated across multiple regions.
So they will have the same key material
and actually the same key ID
but they will be in different regions.
So the use cases are amazing because thanks to this
while you have the same key in multiple regions
and that means that you can encrypt in one region
and decrypt in the other regions using the same KMS key ID
so you don't need to reencrypt data
or make cross region API calls.
So they will have the same key ID,
the same key material,
the same automatic rotation, and so on.
But these keys are not global keys, okay?
It's this principle that there is
a primary key in one region and all the others are replicas.
Each key can be managed independently
and although you can only have one primary key at a time
it's possible for you to promote one replica
into their own primary key.
So the use cases for Multi-Region Keys
is going to be disaster recovery,
Global Data Management,
for example, for Dynamic DB Global Tables,
Active-Active Application that span multiple region
or distributing, signing applications and so on.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.