So let's talk about some advanced concepts
on the AWS Security Hub.
So first of all there's cross-Region aggregation
that's possible for the Security Hub.
That means that you can send data
from different Regions in one central Region,
which makes of course security administration a lot easier.
On top of it, on top of cross-Region aggregation,
we also have Organizations integration.
So that means that you can manage all the accounts
of Security Hub into one central accounts.
So automatically,
if new accounts are added into your Organization
Security Hub will detect them and add them.
And you can also have the management account by default
as the Security Hub administrator.
But you can also design one of the member accounts
to be a designated delegated administrator
for Security Hub.
On top of it, you must enable AWS Config no matter what
for Security Hub to work,
because many of the security checks are using AWS Config.
Also, you must make sure that Config
is enabled on on all accounts, okay?
And Security Hub does not manage your Config configuration.
So make sure on your own that Config is enabled
across all your member accounts in your Organizations.
Now, Security Hub has a few security standards
so it will just generate findings
and continuous checks against all these standards.
And for example, from the standard one that comes
with your standard Security Hub
we have the CIS AWS Foundations, PCI DSS,
and the AWS Foundational Security Best Practices.
And you could just enable it in the console,
and it's possible for you to enable
or disable a security standard.
So let's have a look at the integrations with Security Hub.
So of course you need to remember
that GuardDuty generates findings,
and these findings can be sent to Security Hub.
So we just learned about GuardDuty.
We saw some of these findings, for example,
CloudTrail logging disabled, suspicious files,
as I said, brute force.
And these findings are going to be sent automatically
for being dealt with in the Security Hub.
So they're going to be converted to something
called the ASFF format.
The AWS Security Finding Format,
just because this is what the Security Hub
is using overall.
Findings are usually sent within five minutes.
And then if you archive a finding in GuardDuty,
it doesn't mean that it will update the finding
in Security Hub, okay?
So make sure you manage the findings directly
in Security Hub.
Now for services integration.
So not just GuardDuty can send data into the Security Hub,
but a lot of them, so AWS Config, Firewall Manager,
GuardDuty, Health, Access Analyzer for IAM,
Inspector, IoT Device Defender, Macie,
and the SSM Patch Manager, and maybe others
in the future can send findings into the Security Hub.
So it's really why it's called Security Hub.
It's because it aggregates the security finding
across all the different security services of AWS.
And then to deal with these findings
we have a couple of other services that receive them.
So we have the Audit Manager,
we have AWS Chatbot, we have Amazon Detective,
we have Trusted Advisor, and SSM Explorer and OpsCenter.
Next Security Hub can also receive data
from third party integrations
and actually also send data to other partners.
So what is sending findings to Security Hub?
Well, for example, these ones: 3CORESec, Alert Logic, Aqua.
And to just enable these findings in Security Hub,
you go in the console, you find the finding you want,
and you find the partner you want,
and you click on Accept Findings.
And for example, for this one, is going to help you
do intrusion detection systems and network forensics.
You also have other services
that can receive findings from Security Hub.
So we aggregate data in Security Hub
but then we send it to Atlassian, FireEye, or Fortinet
because this is maybe where you manage your findings.
And on top of it, some of these third party integrations
can loop back into Security Hub
and update the findings there so that they are archived.
So for example, Atlassian or ServiceNow.
Now for these findings, so they are always
in the ASFF format, the security finding format of AWS,
and automatically Security Hub
is going to delete and update them.
So if we look at these findings, so we,
this is some of them that were being received in my console,
for example, that I haven't rotated an IAM user access key
in 90 days or that my password policy was not strong enough.
And so therefore I can click on one of these findings
and then I have a workflow and I can say it's new,
I've been notified, it's been suppressed or resolved,
so I can get more information
and I can update my finding over time.
If I don't deal with it, then automatically past 90 days
the findings are going to be deleted.
And in the console you can filter by Region, integration,
security standards, and Insights.
So what is an Insights?
Well, we've seen that they are findings
and they represent individual security issues,
but there are Insights in Security Hub,
and they are a collection of findings
that identifies a security area
that requires an attention and intervention.
For example, if we find that many EC2 instances
are having poor security practices,
this can become an Insights.
So Insights bring findings from across finding providers
and each Insight is therefore defined by group
by statements and optional filters.
So you can define your own Insights.
So you have the built-in managed Insights,
and this is only giving you results
for related product integration or security standards
and you cannot edit or delete them.
This comes as you enable security standards,
but you can define your own custom Insight
to track issues specific to your environment.
For example, if you wanna track critical findings
affecting member accounts.
Security Hub also has some automation possible.
So we can define custom actions,
and thanks to custom actions,
we can actually automate Security Hub
with Amazon EventBridge.
So we create a custom action
and then we send it into EventBridge.
And so this gives you possible response
and remediation possibilities by using Amazon EventBridge.
So you have in EventBridge, you have to define a event type
of type Security Hub findings, custom action.
So it's better to go through an architecture
for you to understand what I mean.
So in this example, we have the Security Hub administrator
in a security account
which could be the delegated administrator.
And then we have our workloads accounts
where we have member for Security Hub.
So for example, say we have Amazon Macie that's enabled
and it's monitoring an S3 bucket for PII data,
and it detects some.
So it's going to create a finding
in the Security Hub and that finding
is going to be aggregated back
into the administrator accounts.
From there, we can trigger a Security Hub custom action,
which is going to pass down that event
into Amazon EventBridge.
From EventBridge, just have a Lambda function,
and that Lambda function can, for example,
remediate either the S3 buckets or the S3 objects
based on the code you want
and on the action you've defined and implemented.
And then resolve the finding itself
in the member Security Hub.
And you're good.
And you have automated the processing
of the findings from Amazon Macie.
Another option, and this is a bit more, you know, general,
is we have again a workload account and a security accounts.
The events are going to be aggregated.
And then we have the detection phase
where we are going to trigger stuff in Security Hub
and custom actions.
The ingestion phase where all these events
are going to flow into Amazon EventBridge,
the remediation phase where, for example,
you have Lambda functions or Step Functions workflow
that can be triggered from Amazon EventBridge.
And then based, for example, on the Step Function,
you can have any kind of way to remediate.
So it could be, for example, using SSM automations,
which at the end of the day will mark the findings
as a result in the Security Hub.
And then you need to log these actions.
So SNS or CloudWatch logs are great locations for that.
So this is just a general architecture,
but remember, detect, ingest, remediate, and log.
All right, that's it for Security Hub.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.