So now let's talk about S3 Event Notifications.
And the idea is that your events
are going to happen in Amazon S3.
What are events?
Well, events are things such as an object is created
or an object is removed or an object is restored,
or there is replication happening.
And you can filter these events.
So you can say I only wanna consider the objects
that end with JPEG.
So the use case for event notification would be for example,
to automatically react to certain events
happening in Amazon S3.
For example, you want to generate thumbnails
of all the images upload to Amazon S3.
Therefore you're going to create your event notification
and then you can send it to a couple of destination.
It could be an SNS topic,
it could be an SQSQ, and a Lambda function.
And don't worry if you don't know this by now.
We will learn about these features in the next lectures.
So you can create as many S3 events as desired
and you can send them to whatever target you want.
So the idea is that these events are typically delivered
within seconds to these destinations
but sometimes it can take a minute or longer.
And those are the main three destinations yet to remember.
But now there is a fourth one, and this is a new feature
of S3 event notifications that has an integration
with Amazon EventBridge.
So your events are going into your Amazon S3 buckets
and all the events end up in Amazon EventBridge,
no matter what.
So all of them, okay?
And then from EventBridge that you don't know yet,
but you can set up rules and from EventBridge you can,
thanks to these rules, send these events
to over 18 different AWS services as destinations.
So it really enhances the capability
of S3 event notification.
And again, we'll see EventBridge later on this course.
But with EventBridge,
you get advanced filtering options
a lot more than what we had from before.
So you can filter by metadata, object size and name.
You can send to multiple destinations at a time.
You can set, for example, to step functions,
you can see data streams or fire hoses,
or you even get the features coming
straight from Amazon EventBridge.
So you can archive events, replay events,
and you get more reliable delivery.
Okay, there's a lot don't know in this lecture
around the new services
but let's just focus on Amazon S3 event notifications.
The idea is that you can react to events
happening in Amazon S3.
Thanks to sending it to SQS, SNS, Lambda
or Amazon EventBridge.
Okay, that's it.
I will see you in the next lecture.