So let's explore
a couple of VPC traffic mirroring architectures.
So in the first case, we can have the traffic distributed
across EC2 instances in an ASG
and that will be the same security appliance.
So we have our VPC with a public subnet, a private subnet,
and then we've created another private subnet
with an autoscaling group of EC2 instances
that are security monitoring appliances.
We put a network level balancer in front of them
so that we can receive any kind of traffic.
And then we're going to enable traffic mirroring
from the EC2 instance in my public subnet
and my private subnet.
And all that traffic is going to flow and scale
because we're using an autoscaling group.
And this is going to go
to the same kind of security appliance.
We have another kind where we want to distribute traffic
to multiple EC2 instances
that have different security appliances.
So in this case,
we have the same EC2 instances we want to monitor
but then we're going to, in a private subnet,
create different kind of EC2 instances
based on their function.
So different partner solutions for security.
In this case, what we need to do
is to do traffic mirroring
into what we call a Cloud Packet Broker.
It's a third party appliance.
And this allows you to actually redirect the correct traffic
to the correct security appliance.
So that's a different architecture model.
Now, if you want to go distributed
you can have two VPCs,
and in each VPC you'll have
a different monitoring appliance.
So in this instance,
the EC2 instance A is monitored by the Appliance 1
and the EC2 instance B is monitored by the Appliance 2.
You can also go into a different kind of setup
where you have one monitoring appliance in one VPC
and then by establishing VPC peering,
you can have instance D and instance E
directly mirror traffic
into the monitoring Appliance number 3.
There's also a way to automate VPC traffic mirroring.
So let's take an example of GuardDuty
and GuardDuty has found an alert
on one of our EC2 instances.
It's going to pass on that finding to Amazon EventBridge,
and from EventBridge,
we're going to invoke a Lambda function.
That Lambda function is going to look
at the payload of the alerts,
and it's going to identify the EC2 instance
and the corresponding ENI attached to that instance
that needs VPC network traffic mirroring.
So that instance is in my VPC,
but first we need to make sure from the Lambda function
that we launch a virtual monitoring appliance
to receive that mirror traffic.
So we launch it
and then we enable VPC traffic mirroring on my EC2 instance
that was detected by GuardDuty.
So automatically the packets of the network
are going to be forwarded,
and then we can send them directly into an S3 bucket
so that the logs could be analyzed later on by Athena.
And all of this is automated,
so hopefully that opens up your mind.
Finally, you can also have an architecture
for VPC traffic mirroring that leverages a transit gateway
between several accounts and several VPCs.
But the idea is that you want to have a centralized VPC
where you'll have
all your security appliances and monitoring.
So in that case,
well, because we have set up a transit gateway,
now any EC2 instance in any VPC
can send their traffic directly
into the network level balancer of the centralized VPC.
And this works great and this scales great,
but you will have higher data transfer cost
because everything goes through a transit gateway.
All right, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.