Now let's talk about the AWS client VPN.
So the idea is that you have your computer
and you want to privately connect into your AWS VPC.
Therefore you will leverage the client VPN
to establish a connection using the open VPN
to your private network in AWS or on premises.
I will show you how in the second.
Why would you want to do so?
Well, for example say you have deployed EC2 instances
in a private VPC and you want to access them
using a private IP.
Well, that's difficult if you don't have a VPN
but if you have a VPN, then it's super easy.
Once the VPN connection is established
you will be able to access your EC2 instances
using their private IP
just as if you were in the VPC network yourself.
So your VPC is right here
and then your client's VPN is installed on your computer.
You will establish the VPN connection over the internet.
So this goes over the public internet, of course.
And then you will be as if you are connected
privately into your VPC.
And if your VPC has established a site to site
VPN connection to your on-premises data center
then your computer will also be able to access,
privately, your servers on your, on premises data center.
And that's pretty magical, but it works.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.