Okay, so very short lecture
on Amazon Detective.
So, when you have all these services
such as GuardDuty, Macie, and Security Hub
that are used to identify potential security issues
or findings, you need to find how these happen
and get to the root cause.
And so, sometimes the deeper analysis to isolate
the root cause can be long and complicated.
It's a complex process to analyze data
from different places and link it together.
It could be quite long
and when you're dealing with security,
you want to get to the root cause as quickly as possible
because there may be a security hole in your architecture.
And so, this is the purpose of Amazon Detective.
The name is quite explicit.
Detective is going to analyze, investigate,
and quickly identify the root cause of security issues
or suspicious activities using machine learning
and graphs in the backend to really allow you
to quickly get down to where the issue is coming from.
And to do so, it's going to automatically collect
and process events from your VPC Flow Logs,
your CloudTrail trails, and GuardDuty
to create this unified view.
And it will, in turn, give you visualizations
with details and context, so you can get to the root cause.
So that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.