So just a short lecture
on the ECS Integration with the SSM Parameter Store
and Secrets Manager
but we've seen this from before so just a reminder.
So ECS can inject sensitive data
for your containers as environment variables
which is very helpful for your secrets
to get them at runtime.
So these secrets can be stored securely
in the SSM Parameter Store or Secrets Manager
and what we do is that we reference sensitive data
in the container definition.
So either you have, for example,
a secret such as the database password in Secrets Manager
and a parameter such as an API key in the Parameter Store,
they can both be referenced
from your ECS container definition
and then your ECS task at boot time
will be pulling these secrets
and inject them as environment variables.
Of course, it must have the correct IAM permissions
to Secrets Manager, to the Parameter Store,
and also to the underlying KMS key
that allowed these secrets to be encrypted.
So then from this we can connect to an RDS database
or access an API with a proper API key.
So that's it.
Something you've seen but one last reminder.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.