So now let's talk about
the evaluation logic of IAM policies.
So here is a simplified version,
and then we'll see the more complicated version.
So by default, all the requests are implicitly denied
except for the root user,
which has full access no matter what.
An explicit allow in an identity-based
or resource-based policy overrides the default in one,
so that means that everything was implicitly denied
but then we have an explicit denied,
so things are going to be accepted.
If there is a permission boundary,
or an Organization SCP, or a session policy,
then an explicit allow is used to limit actions,
so anything that is not explicitly allowed
through a permission boundary, an SCP,
or a session policy is going to be an implicit denied,
and then the final decision will be overridden.
It will be a deny.
Any explicit deny, finally,
in any policy overrides any allows you've ever had.
So bottom line is if you have an organizational SCP,
a permission boundary, or a session policy,
you must see an explicit allow, but it's not enough.
You must also have an explicit allow
in an identity-based or resource-based policy.
That's for the simplified version.
It may take a few times for you to agree with this,
and here is the longer graph.
So you have a look at all these things.
So we start at deny,
and then we evaluate all applicable policies.
Then we look at
if there is an explicit deny amongst all policies.
If yes, the final decision is denied.
There is no way around it.
Then we look at if there is an SCP, and if there's an SCP,
as we said before, there must be an explicit allow.
Good. Then we move on to the next phase.
We looked at resource-based policies.
So if we have a resource-based policy,
we have a look at if there's an allow,
and if there's an allow, it is good enough.
Else, we look into what's next,
and if there is an identity-based policy.
So if there is an identity-based policy, yes,
we look at whether or not there is an allow.
If there's an allow, we look at permission boundaries
to make sure that the boundaries
of your identity-based policies are correct,
and if there is a permission boundary, if it's present,
and there is an allow, we are good. Otherwise, no.
And finally, we look at session policies.
So this is when we have a role session and so on,
so this is the more complicated version,
but the version I just gave you from before should be enough
for you to understand how to evaluate some logic.
So we'll walk through several examples in this course,
so don't worry too much, but you have the basics.
So let's take a look at this policy right here.
We have deny sqs star and allow sqs delete queue.
What can we do?
So can we create a queue?
Well, the answer is no.
We cannot create a queue because we have deny sqs star.
And can we delete a queue?
Well, it's been explicitly allowed, sure,
but it's also been explicitly denied
for the first statement, so we cannot do SQS delete queue.
And finally, can we do ec2:DescribeInstances?
The answer is no, it's not ...
it hasn't been explicitly allowed,
and so therefore it's been implicitly denied.
Okay, when we go cross-account,
it gets a little bit more funky,
so let's take an example of the account A that has Alice
and account B that has an S3 bucket,
and we look at a request from account A to account B.
So the requester in account A must have
an identity-based policy that allows the action
on the S3 buckets,
and then in the bucket in account B,
you must have a resource policy that is going to
allow the requester in account A to access the resource.
So this is different from being in the same accounts
because when you're in the same accounts,
you look at the combination
of the identity-based policy and the resource policy,
and you look for one allow in between them two,
but when you have two accounts, you look at
whether or not do both accounts allow the request.
That's why I was saying it's a bit more funky
with cross-account access.
So if you have a look of the simple use-case
of an IAM policy and a resource policy in the same account,
if we have an MT IAM user IAM policy
but then the S3 bucket policy,
the resource policy actually explicitly allows this A,
this user through its arn to access the bucket,
then this is allowed.
Remember, this is not allowed cross-account,
but in the same account,
it is going to be allowed.
If we take a look at a more complicated use-case
where we have an IAM policy, a VPC endpoint policy,
and a resource policy, what is evaluated?
So we have a look at the instance role.
Here we have s three star,
so we are allowed to do stuff on s3.
Then the VPC endpoint policy does allow us to do
list bucket, get object,
and put object on the bucket itself,
so we've restricted the actions that are being made
on the bucket.
And finally, the bucket policy is saying,
you cannot access me unless you come from
the specific VPC endpoints.
So as a whole,
the ec2:instance will be allowed to do list bucket,
get object, and put object on the VPC endpoint
and only through VPC endpoint
because if the ec2:instance tries to access
the S3 bucket directly,
as you can see on the right hand side,
the policy is saying deny,
and so we have an explicit deny,
and because of the condition,
if we try to access it without the VPC endpoint,
the condition is going to trigger,
and so we'll get an explicit deny.
So with this setup, we have effectively forced
the ec2:instance to access the S3 bucket
through the VPC endpoint, and the VPC endpoint itself
must trigger ... restricted the type of actions
that the ec2:instance could do on our S3 bucket.
Hopefully all of that makes sense for you now.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.