So now let's talk about OpenSearch security.
We have two deployment modes
and the first one is public access,
so this makes your OpenSearch cluster accessible
from the internet with a public endpoint.
So that means you can restrict access
to OpenSearch using access policies
identity-based policies, and IP-based policies.
So this is a kind of diagram of the authorization flow.
So the client will send a public request
with HTTP basic credentials.
They will check whether or not
we require IAM signing of these credentials.
Then the signing, the credentials themselves
are going to be verified whether or not they're valid.
And then if true, then the fine-grained access control
will see if the user is allowed
to perform the action or not.
And then OpenSearch will actually return full
or partial data.
So what you have to remember out of public access
is that if you want to restrict by IP, for example,
this is based on public IP, of course.
For VPC access, we need to specify the VPC,
the subnets, security groups, and IAM role
into which we deploy our OpenSearch cluster,
we need to define VPC endpoints, absolutely,
and ENIs will be created.
And because now your OpenSearch cluster is deployed
within your VPC, if you wanted to access it
from within your own machine,
you will need to be connected to the local network of AWS,
so either using a VPN or transit gateway or managed network
or a side-to-side VPN or proxy server, whatever you want,
but you would need to be connected through the VPC.
You can then restrict the VPC access using access policies
and identity-based policies
and as well your security groups.
So the authorization flow is a little bit
more complicated here,
but the client will be using IAM credentials
to connect to OpenSearch,
so whether or not it will connect
to the VPC first and then go through the security group,
so is everything authorized true, true perfect?
Then we'll check whether or not
the IAM credentials are valid
and then whether or not the access policy
allows the client to access our OpenSearch cluster.
Then the fine-grained access control will take action
and then finally, OpenSearch will return
the full or partial data.
So what are these policies that we can create?
Well, we have something called the domain access policy
which we're going to specify only in VPC
which actions the principal can can perform
on the domain sub-resources,
so the indexes or the specific APIs.
For example, this policy grants the IAM user full access
on all the OpenSearch domain sub-resources
because we have action es star for a specific principal
for a user on the domain test domain,
which is our test domain for OpenSearch slash star,
so any resources there.
And this policy right here only allows HTTP GET
and HTTP PUT on the commerce data within the test domain.
So we can go very fine grained
based on the domain access policy
and that's how you manage security in OpenSearch.
All right, that's it, I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.