So you need to know the different types
of authentication you can have with the AWS Client VPN.
So the first one is an active directory
authentication where you as a user will authenticate
against Microsoft Active Directory.
It's user based
and then you can use whatever directory you want
or you can use a manage directory from AWS
such as the AWS Manage Microsoft AD.
Or if you wanted to use an on-premises AD
then you have to use an AD connector.
This supports multifactor authentication.
The second way is to use mutual authentication.
So this is where you have certificates
and the user will use these certificates to
perform the authentication to the client VPN service.
To do so, you must first upload the service certificates
to the certificate manager
and you will have one client certificate
for each user so that you can properly identify them.
The last possibility is to use single sign on.
So this supports IAM Identity Center
which we use as the new name for AWS SSO.
So you will authenticate
against the SAML 2.0 based identity provider
again based on username, password
and then you establish a trust relationship
between AWS and this identity provider.
For the SSO to work
you can only have one identity provider at a time.
So in this example, the client is initiating a connection
to the client VPN endpoint
and we have defined SAML 2.0 idP in IAM
such as the client VPN endpoint is going to
check the configuration of this idP.
Then it's going to return to the client
the idP URL to do a login against.
The client will do a login using the URL that was provided
against the SAML 2.0 identity providers is where
you use your username
and password to get back a SAML token if you're successful.
And then this SAML token is being passed
to the client VPN endpoint
which is going to validate the SAML token
and therefore establish a secure connection
between the clients and the client VPN endpoint.
Alright, that's it.
Just remember these three methods.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.