So let's look at ABAC
or Attributes Based Access Control.
So this is a newer kind of way of doing access in AWS
but it makes a lot of sense.
So let's say you have a lot of users
and a lot of AWS resources.
Where you can do is that you can authorize each user
to access specific resources
but that can become very complicated to manage.
The other option is to use fine word permissions based
on user attributes.
So for example, you say a user belongs to a department,
a user belongs to a specific job,
a user belongs to a specific team.
And then instead of creating IAM roles for every team,
you're going to use attributes based control
to group attributes
and identify which resources a set of user can access.
How do we have these attributes?
Well, by using tags.
And so we are going to tag the users,
and we're going to tag the resources,
and we're going to create an IAM permissions
to see if they match.
So this is very helpful in rapidly growing environment
because you can add resources and tag them
and don't have to edit the IAM policies.
So let's take the example of these two resources
are tagged in red, these are tagged in green,
and then the last ones are tagged in blue.
And then we tag the user in red, in green,
and in blue with the correct IAM policy.
Then we make sure that the user A,
can only access the resources tagged in red.
The user B, tagged in green and the user C, tagged in blue.
And that scales a lot and it's much easier.
So to give you a concrete example
of how tags are used for security,
let's take an example of an EC2 instance.
And this EC2 instance has an owner, user C,
and another tag called Access Project equals Star Projects.
Now we're going to create an IAM policy
and the IAM policy is going to be attached to all the users.
And here we're saying that there is a condition
in this IAM policy for start and stop instances
and we're saying that we want the resource tag
of key owner to be equals to the username of the user
and also want to have the access project tag to be equal
to the same principle tag that has attached
to the user for the key access projects.
So it's a bit more complicated.
We have IAM policy variables in there
but basically what that means is that
if you do attach the same tag,
Access Project equals Star Project to user C,
then automatically it's going to be allowed to access
the EC2 instance because the access projects tag matches
for user C and the EC2 instance.
But then for user A or user B, which have a different tag,
then it doesn't match and the access is denied.
So if you wanna compare ABAC and RBAC,
so role based access control will define fine grain
permissions based on the user role or function.
So you have administrators or DB admins or DevOps.
And you can create different policies
for different job functions.
Disadvantage that when you want to create new resources,
you may have to update your policies.
If you're using attribute based access controls using tags,
then the advantage is that you can scale permissions easily
because you can just create new resources,
tag them appropriately, and you don't need to update
the underlying IAM policy of your users.
And then, the permissions are granted automatically
based on these attributes.
So you require fewer policies,
you don't need to create different policies
for different job functions.
And on top of it, you can get some users attributes directly
from corporate directories.
For example, SAML 2.0 IDP or a Web IDP.
So hopefully you now understand the power
of attribute based access control.
I hope you like this lecture
and I will see you in the next lecture.