Okay, so now let's talk about networking
and Lambda functions.
So by default, your Lambda functions are launched
outside of your own VPC,
so it is in another VPC that AWS owns, okay?
And therefore, it cannot access resources
that belong in your VPC.
So what is the point in your VPC?
It could be your issue to instances,
RDS database, ElastiCache,
or an internal elastic load balancer, these kinds of things.
So by default, you will learn
that Lambda deployments look like this.
You have the cloud, your Lambda function,
it can access any public websites, okay?
We can access external APIs.
And also we can access other services such as DynamoDB.
But if we have our own VPC and our own private subnet
and we have a private RDS within it,
then Lambda cannot access RDS.
So you may ask me the question, what can I do to solve it?
Can I deploy my Lynda in a VPC?
And of course you can.
So for this, you must define your VPC ID, the subnets
and you need to assign a security group
to your Lambda function.
And behind the scenes,
the Lambda function will create an ENI.
So Elastic Network Interface
in the subnets that you have selected
and to create this ENI, your Lambda function needs
a Lambda VPC Access Execution Role.
So back into our private subnet,
we have our RDS security group
around our Amazon RDS database in our VPC.
And this Lambda function,
we want to give it VPC access.
Therefore once we've set it up correctly
it will create an ENI, an elastic network interface,
alongside the Lambda security group
and to access your RDS database,
Your Lambda is going to go through your ENI.
You know, it's invisible, we don't see it,
but this is how it happens behind the scenes.
So it will go through the ENI
into your Amazon RDS database.
And so for this to work, we need to make sure
that the RDS security group does allow network access
from the Lambda security group, just like
for EC2 instances and load down search, for example.
Okay.
So here is a caveat.
What if we deploy a Lambda function in a VBC,
can we access the public internet?
And by default, Lambda function inside
of your VPC does not have access to the internet.
So you may ask me, okay.
I don't want you to deploy my Lambda function
inside of a private subnet.
I want to deploy it in a public subnet
and you told me Stefan,
that public subnets have access to the internet.
So that is true for EC2 instances
but it is not true for Lambda functions.
So deploying a Lambda function
in a public subnet does not give it internet access
or a public IP.
And it's good to know.
So the exam will definitely test you on this.
So what can we do then?
Well, you can deploy your Lambda function
in a private subnet and to give it internet access,
you would use a NAT gateway, or a NAT instance,
just like we saw in the VPC primer.
So we have our Lambda function in our VBC,
we're in the cloud, and it is deployed
in a private subnet, not a public subnet.
So it's in a private subnet and we have access to RDS
but to access an external API,
we need to go through a public subnet with a NAT device.
So a NAT gateway or NAT instance.
The NAT gateway or instance will be talking
to the internet gateway of our VPC
and the internet gateway will give us access
to the external API.
So all of this is configured
through your route tables and your VPC configuration, okay?
Next, what if you want you to access DynamoDB,
well, we can access DynamoDB either
through the public route and through your internet gateway.
So this would work once a NAT is put in place.
Or, if you want to access DynamoDB privately,
you can use VPC endpoints.
And VPC endpoints, if you remember,
they're used to access private AWS services
privately within your cloud
without access to a NAT device or an internet gateway.
So we'd create a VPC endpoint for DynamoDB
as the VPC endpoint gateway,
and Lambda function will be talking
to the end point and accessing privately
your DynamoDB service, which is great.
And so all of that works.
So if you deploy a Lambda function
in a private subnet, note that your CloudWatch Logs work
even if you have no end points or NAT gateway.
CloudWatch Logs is something that functions no matter what.
Okay, so that's it for the theory,
Now let's go into the hands-on.