Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
In the following tutorials we will be implementing
Logistic Regression on Python,
and I can't wait to show you the final result,
to show you how Logistic Regression
manages to separate some categories
and predict binary outcome.
So let's start making the model right now.
The real first step of making a machine learning model
is to pre-process the data
and to do this of course we're gonna use
the data pre-processing template
we've been preparing in Part one.
So we're gonna copy all this
Copy, and paste it here.
So now we just need to change a few things.
First let's import the three essential Libraries.
Here we go.
And then here we need to change the name of the data set.
Here it's of cause Social underscore Network underscore Ads.
And now let's select this line
to have a look at our data set.
So execute, perfect.
Now let's go to Variable Explorer
to have a look at our data set,
by double clicking on it here.
And here's the data set.
Okay so just a quick reminder,
this data set contains information
of users in its Social Network.
So those informations are the User ID, the Gender, the Age
and the Estimated Salary.
And this Social Network has several business clients
which can put their Ads on this Social Network
and one of their clients is a car company,
who has just launched their brand new luxury SUV
for a ridiculous price.
And we're trying to see which of these Users
of the Social Network are going to buy this brand new SUV.
And so the last column here, tells if yes or no
the User bought this SUV.
We are gonna build a model that is going to predict
if a User is going to buy or not the SUV,
based on two variables which are gonna be
the Age and the Estimated Salary.
So our Matrix of Features only going to be these two columns
We wanna find some correlations
between the Age and the Estimated Salary of a User.
And his decision to purchase, yes or no, the SUV.
Okay, so what are the indexes?
This is Index zero, Index one, Index two and Index three.
So here we're gonna put our indexes.
We're gonna put our two Indexes in brackets.
So it's two, comma and three.
So that's the two Indexes of the columns
that we want to include in our Matrix of Features.
Okay, and what about Y?
Let's see Y.
Okay so this was Index two, Index three and Index four.
So here Y is gonna take Index four.
Alright, and now we're ready.
Let's check if everything is okay, let's select this.
Command or Control plus Enter to execute.
And here we go, X and Y appear here, so let's look at them.
X, okay this is clearly the Age here
and the Estimated Salary
for all of our four hundred observations, perfect.
Okay, and Y.
Okay perfect Y is the Purchase column.
Zero means no the User didn't buy the car, and one means yes
Alright now let's split the data set
into the Training set and the Test set.
So which Test side would you like to choose?
We have four hundred observations, so a good Test size
would be to have three hundred observations
in the Training set and a hundred observation
in the Test set, is that cool?
Okay so let's do this, that means we wanna take
all Point twenty five, that is a hundred observations.
Let's select this, Command or Control plus Enter to execute.
Alright, so we have now our X Train, X Test,
Y Train and Y Test,
and you can see that we have three hundred observation
in the Training set, here.
And a hundred observation in the Test set.
Okay great, and now do we need to apply Feature Scaling?
Well yes we're gonna do it
because we want accurate prediction,
we want to predict which Users are going to buy the SUV,
to, you know, target these Users as well as possible.
So I'm gonna remove that multi-line column here.
And I think we're fine.
X Train and X Test are ready to be transformed, to be scaled
so let's select this.
Command or Control plus Enter to execute.
Okay perfect, now let's look at our Training set
and Test set.
So as you can see the X Train is well scaled
and, okay so that's for--, okay
so Y Train wasn't scaled obviously
because this is the category called Dependent variable
and X Test scaled based on the same scale because you know,
we fitted the SCX Standard Scaler Object
to our Matrix of Features X Trend
and we used the same object on X Test.
So this means that it's scaled on the same basis.
Okay, NY (inaudible).
Great so we're ready, we pre-processed our data correctly
and now we are ready to build our Logistic Regression Model.
I can't wait to show you the results.
Your intuition is gonna get even more shaped
by looking at the results
because everything is going to be visual.
I can't wait to se you in the next tutorial to start.
Until then, enjoy mission learning.