Hello and welcome
to the mega case study of this course,
make a hybrid deep learning model.
So, as you understood,
this challenge is about combining two deep learning models
we made in this course.
And you can already see where they are.
It's the artificial neural network
that we made in part one
and the self-organizing map
that we made in part four.
And so, we're gonna start
with the credit card applications dataset
to identify the frauds.
And then the idea is
to make an even more advanced deep learning model
where we can predict the probability
that each customer cheated.
And to do this, we need to go from unsupervised
to supervised deep learning.
So there we are.
This challenge takes two parts.
In the first part,
we'll make the unsupervised deep learning branch
of our hybrid deep learning model.
And in the second part,
we'll make the supervised deep learning branch.
And, in the end,
we'll get this hybrid deep learning model composed
of both unsupervised and supervised deep learning.
So, before we start,
let's set the right folder as working directory.
So we'll go to File explorer
to our Deep Learning A-Z folder.
And as you can see in this folder,
I created a new subfolder called Mega Case Study.
And inside this subfolder,
you have all the material you need
to create this hybrid deep learning model.
So you have the Credit_Card_Applications data set,
that we've just seen with the self-organizing map,
and that contains all the credit card applications
from the different customers of a bank.
And so you will use the self-organizing map exactly
as we did previously, in part four, to identify the fraud.
So, there will be nothing new about that.
But then, the challenge is to use the results
of this self-organizing map
to then combine your unsupervised deep learning model
to a new supervised deep learning model
that will take, as input, the results given
by your self-organizing map.
So that's the challenge.
The challenge is to combine two models.
So let's quickly set this folder as working directory.
And now, you are ready to go, good luck.
And so in the end, what you must obtain is a ranking
of the predicted probabilities that each customer cheated.
So I just wanna warn you,
you will get very small probabilities, but that's normal.
It's because there are few frauds identified
by the SOM, but that doesn't matter.
What's important is
that you get this ranking of probabilities.
So I hope you will enjoy this homework
and keep in mind that the important thing is
to practice, practice, practice, and practice.
That's how you will make the most progress
and that will be the case,
even if you don't succeed the homework.
So good luck and I'll see you in the next two tutorials
to tackle the challenge because we will take it in two part.
In part one,
we will make the unsupervised deep learning branch
that is the self-organizing map.
And then in the second tutorial,
we will take care of part two,
building the supervised deep learning model,
which will be our artificial neural network.
So I can't wait to do this and until then,
enjoy deep learning!