Hello and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
This is an additional tutorial
to talk about the softmax and cross-entropy functions.
It is not 100% necessary in order for you
to go through all of the parts that we've been through
in the main part of this section
where we're talking about the convolutional neural networks
but at the same time I thought it would be
a good addition to your bag of knowledge and skill set
so let's go ahead and dig in to these functions.
So to start of with,
what we have here is the convolutional neural network
that we built in the main part of the section
and then at the end it pops out some probabilities
for 0.95 for a dog and 0.05, or 5%, for a cat,
given that photo on the left has an input.
This is after the train has been conducted.
This is actually, it's running,
and it's classifying a certain image.
And so the question here is,
how come these two values add up to one.
Because as far as we know from everything
that we've learned about our neural networks,
there is nothing to say that these two final neurons
are connected between each other.
So how would they know what the value of the other one is
and how would they know to add their values up to one.
Well, the answer is they wouldn't,
in the classic version of artificial neural network,
and the only way that they do
is because we introduce a special function,
called the softmax function,
in order to help us out of this situation.
So normally, what would happen,
is the dog and the cat neurons would have
any kind of real values.
They don't have to add up to one.
But then, we would apply the softmax function,
which is written up over there at the top,
and that would bring these values
to be between zero and one
and it would make them add up to one.
And to quote Wikipedia, the softmax function,
or the normalized exponential function,
is a generalization of the logistic function
that quote unquote "squashes a K-dimensional vector
"of arbitrary real values to a K-dimensional vector
"of real values in the range of zero
"to one that add up to one."
So basically, it does exactly what we want.
It brings these values to be between zero and one
and makes sure that they add up to one.
And the way it works is that,
the way that this is possible is that,
because at the bottom over here
you can see that there's a summation
so it takes the exponent and puts it in the power of z
and adds it up so z1, z2, across all of your classes,
all of these values,
and so that's your normalization happening right there.
So that's how the softmax function works
and it makes sense to introduce a softmax function
into convolutional neural networks
because how strange would it be
if you had possible classes of a dog and a cat
and for the dog class you had probability of 80%
and for the cat class you had a probability of 45%, right?
It just doesn't make sense like that
and therefore it's much better
when you introduce the softmax function
and that's what you will find happening most of the time
in convolutional neural networks.
Now the other thing is that the softmax function
comes hand-in-hand with something called
the cross-entropy function
and it's a very handy thing for us.
So let's first look at the formula.
This is what the cross-entropy function looks like.
We're actually going to be using a different calculation.
We're going to be using this representation
of the cross-entropy but the results basically the same.
This is just easier to calculate.
I know this might sound very unrelated
to anything right now, just formulas on your screen,
but there'll be some additional recommended reading
at the end of this section
so don't worry if you're not picking up on the math,
if we haven't explained the math right now,
but the point here is that, what is a cross-entropy?
Well, a cross-entropy function,
remember how we previously in artificial neural networks,
we had a function called the mean squared error function
which we used as the cost function
for assessing our network performance
and our goal was to minimize the MSE
in order to optimize our network performance.
Well, that was our cost function there,
and in convolutional neural networks,
we can still use MSE but a better option
in convolutional neural networks,
after you apply the softmax function,
turns out to be the cross-entropy function,
and in convolutional neural networks,
when you apply the cross-entropy function,
it's not called the cost function anymore,
it's called the loss function and they're very similar
and they're just little terminological differences
and a little bit different in what they mean
but for our purposes it's pretty much the same thing
and what happens is the loss function
is again something that we want to minimize
in order to maximize the performance of our network.
So let's have a look at a quick example
on how, of how this function can be applied.
So let's say we've put an image of a dog
into our network.
The predicted value for dog is 0.9
and this is during the training so we know
the label that is a dog.
So the predicted value is 0.9,
the predicted value for cat is 0.1.
Then here we have the label so we know it's a dog
because this is training and one for dog,
zero for cat and so in this case you need
to plug these numbers into your formula
for cross-entropy.
So how you do it is the values on the left
go into the variable q.
The one that is under the logarithm
on the right side and the values from the right
would go into p and so it's important
to remember which one goes where
because if you get them wrong
you don't want to be taking a logarithm
from a zero value or a logarithm from a one
so you just want to make sure you plug them into
the correct places and then you basically add that up.
So that's how the cross-entropy works
and we'll look at a,
actually right now we're just going
to look at a specific step by step example
of applying this function in real life.
And it will kind of make more sense
what cross-entropy is and it will be less,
my goal in this tutorial is to make you more comfortable
with cross-entropy because it can sound very convoluted
and (laughs) no pun intended.
It can, convolutional neural networks,
it can sound very sound complex, right?
Scary. But it's not.
That's the point.
So let's go ahead and apply it so we know it's not scary.
So here's, and also this will explain why we're doing this,
why we're looking into different cross-functions.
So neural network one, neural network two.
Let's say we have two neural networks.
And then we pass an image of a dog
and we know that this is a dog and not a cat.
And then we have another image of a cat
this time an animal and it's a cat and not a dog.
And here we have a weird looking animal
which is in fact a dog and not a cat
if you look very closely.
So we want to see what our neural networks will predict.
The first case, neural network one,
90% dog, 10% cat, correct.
Neural network number two, 60% dog dog, 40% cat.
Still correct.
Worse, but correct.
Second option. First neural network 10% dog, 90% cat.
Correct.
Neural network number two, 30% dog, 70% cat.
Worse, but still correct.
And then finally neural network one,
in image three, neural network one,
40% dog, 60% cat.
Incorrect.
Neural network two, 10% dog, 90% cat.
Incorrect and worse.
So the key here is that even though both networks
got it wrong in the last one,
throughout all three images neural network one
was outperforming neural network two.
So even in the last case, it was very,
it gave dog like a 40% as opposed to neural network two
only gave dog a 10% chance.
So neural network one is outperforming across the board
when compared to neural network two.
And so now we're going to look at the functions,
that can measure performance
that we've kind of talked about already.
So let's put these into a table.
So there's neural network one.
You have the row number, so that's the image number,
and then for image one you have what it predicted,
90% dog, 10% cat, so those are the hat variables,
and then you have the actual values,
so dog, correct, cat, incorrect.
Same thing for image number two
and same thing for image number three.
And same for neural network number two
so dog 60%, cat 40% in first image,
that's what it predicted,
correct answer was dog not cat, and so on.
And so now let's see what errors we can actually get.
So what errors we can calculate
to estimate the performance
and monitor the performance of our networks.
So one type of error is called the classification error
and that is basically just asking,
you did get it right or not.
Regardless of the probabilities,
it's just did you get it right or did you not get it right.
So in both cases, for both neural networks,
each of them, they got one,
or so this is how many they got wrong.
So they got one out of three wrong.
So 33% error rate for neural network one
and 33% error rate for neural network two.
And so basically from this standpoint,
both neural networks perform at the same level,
but we know that's not true.
We know that neural network one is outperforming
neural network two.
That's why classification error is not a good measure,
especially for the purposes of back propagation.
Mean squared error. Different.
And by the way, I did these calculations in Excel.
I just didn't want to bore you with them.
But you can totally just sit down
and do them on a paper or in Excel.
These are very straight forward calculations,
just basically take the sum of squared errors
and then just take the average across your observations,
and that's pretty much it.
So for neural network one, you get 25%.
For neural network two, you get 71% error rate.
So as you can see, this one is more accurate.
It's telling us that neural network one
has a much lower error rate than neural network two.
And then cross-entropy, again, we've seen the formula.
You can also calculate this.
This is actually even easier to calculate
than the mean squared error.
Cross-entropy gives you 38% for neural network one
and 1.06 for neural network two.
So you can see the results are a bit different
when you look at them like that,
when you look at, you know,
the mean squared error and cross-entropy.
The question of why would you use cross-entropy
over mean squared error isn't just about, the kind of like,
the numbers that they sprout.
These calculations were just to show you
that this is all, it's all doable,
you can just do it on a paper.
It's not, these are not very intense mathematics.
These are pretty simple straight-forward things.
But the question of why would you use cross-entropy
over mean squared error is a very good question to ask,
I'm glad you asked it.
The answer to that is there's several advantages
of cross-entropy over mean squared error
which are not obvious.
So I'll mention a couple,
but then I'll let you know where you can find out more.
So one of them is that if for instance your,
at the very start of your back propagation,
your output value is very, very, very, very tiny, very tiny.
So it's much smaller than the actual value that you want.
Then at the very start,
the gradient in your gradient descent
will be very, very low,
and it won't be enough,
it will be very hard for the neural network
to actually start doing something
and start moving around and start adjusting those waves
and start actually moving in the right direction.
Whereas when you use something like the cross-entropy
because it's got that logarithm in it,
it actually helps the network assess
even a small error like that and do something about it.
Here's how to think about it.
So let's say in, again this is a very intuitive approach,
there's gonna be a link to the mathematics
and you can derive these things through the mathematics
in more detail but a very intuitive approach.
Let's say your outcome that you want is one
and right now you are at one millionth of one, right?
0.000001.
And then, next time you improve your outcome
from one millionth to one thousandth
and in terms of, if you calculate the squared error,
you're just subtracting one from the other,
or basically in each case
you're calculating the squared error
and you'll see that the squared error
is when you compare one case versus the other,
it didn't change that much.
You didn't improve your network that much
when you're looking at the mean squared error.
But if you're looking at the cross-entropy,
because you're taking a logarithm,
and then you're comparing the two,
dividing one with the other,
you will see that you have actually improved
your network significantly.
So that jump from one millionth to one thousandth
in mean squared error terms will be very low.
It will be insignificant
and it won't guide your gradient boosting process
or your back propagation in the right direction.
It will guide it in the right direction
but it will be like a very slow guidance,
it won't have enough power,
whereas if you do through cross-entropy,
cross-entropy will understand that,
oh even though these are very small adjustments
that are just, you know,
making a tiny change in absolute terms,
in relative terms, it's a huge improvement,
and we're definitely going in the right direction,
let's keep going that way.
So cross-entropy will help your neural network
get to the right, get to the optimal state.
It's a better way for the neural network
to get to an optimal state.
But bear in mind that this only works
when the cross-entropy is the preferred method
only for classification.
So if you're talking about things like regression,
like which we had in artificial neural networks,
then you would rather go with mean squared error,
whereas cross-entropy is better for classification
and again it has to do with the fact
that we're using softmax function.
So that's a, kind of an intuitive explanation of that.
A good place to learn a bit more about that
if you're really interested in, you know,
why are we using cross-entropy versus mean squared error,
google a video by Geoffrey Hinton
called "The Softmax Output Function."
And he explains it very well, you know,
being the godfather of deep learning,
who can explain it better anyway.
And by the way, any video by Geoffrey Hinton is golden.
He's just got a huge talent for explaining things.
Anyways, so that's softmax versus cross-entropy.
I hope that gives you, kind of like,
an intuitive understanding of what's going on here,
but more importantly,
that you're not put off by the term cross-entropy,
because Hadland will mention in the practical tutorials,
and I wanted to make sure that you're prepared for that,
and it's just another way of calculating your loss function
and another way of optimizing your network
which is specifically tailored to classification problems
and therefore convolutional neural networks
and comes hand-in-hand with the softmax function.
So, additional reading.
If you'd like a light introduction into cross-entropy,
if you're interested in cross-entropy a bit more of course,
a good article to check out is called
"A Friendly Introduction to Cross-Entropy Loss"
by Rob DiPietro, 2016.
Here's the link below.
Very, very nice, very soft, nothing,
no super complex math, good analogies, good examples.
He uses analogies of cars, and you look at cars,
and talks about information and bits restrictions,
and you know, how would you encode this,
how would you encode that.
It's a good article to have a look at
and will give you a good overview of cross-entropy,
like from an introductory standpoint.
If you want to dig into the heavy math,
like what you see here,
then check out an article by, or blog by,
"How to implement a neural network Intermezzo 2"
so intermezzo is like an intermediate thing,
like a, intermittence in, you know,
like when you to a theater and you have like a break
between the first part and the second part,
because he's like going through all these steps
and then he's like, and then he says,
oh I gotta explain this first.
And yeah, so that's why it's called intermezzo,
no other reason (laughs) as far as I understand.
The article's by Peter Roelants, 2016, as well,
so both are quite recent, and yeah,
check out this if you'd like to dig
into the mathematics behind cross-entropy,
behind softmax and cross-entropy in this article actually.
So there we go, that's all there is to these two.
Hopefully I was able to add some additional clarity
and good luck with that.
It's going to be fun and enjoy the practical tutorials.
I'll see you next time.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.