Hello, and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, in the previous tutorial we created our first layers
of our neural network.
This is the input layer and the first hidden layer
and now in this tutorial we're gonna add
the second hidden layer.
All right, so this is going to be a very quick tutorial
because what we'll basically do is just
to copy this line.
All right, copy and paste it here
because we will use of course the same method
which is this add method
and the same parameter inside this method
which is the dense function
with the same parameters except one, which,
as you might've guessed,
is the input_dim parameter.
And why is that?
It's because, as I explained in the previous tutorial,
we need to specify this input_dim parameter
for the first hidden layer
because no layer was created yet and therefore
this hidden layer here didn't know what to expect
as input nodes.
So that's why we had to specify
that it should expect 11 input nodes
and these 11 input nodes are nothing else
than our 11 independent variables.
But here for the second hidden layer,
well it knows what to expect
because the first hidden layer was created
so we don't need to specify any input_dim parameter here
so we can remove it.
All right.
And then what do we have left?
We have our output_dim parameter
and the tip that I gave you in the previous tutorial
to choose the number of nodes in the hidden layer
if we don't wanna be an artist still applies
for this second hidden layer.
So we will keep this average
of the number of nodes in the input layer
and the number of nodes in the output layer.
That is one plus 11 divided by two, that is six.
So we keep six here.
Same we need to initialize the weights
for this second hidden layer
and we will keep this uniform method
that initializes the weights randomly
and makes sure that the weights
are given small numbers close to zero
and eventually, we have this activation parameter
and remember in the previous tutorial I explained
that the activation function is recommended
to be the rectifier function for the hidden layers
and the sigmoid function for the output layer.
So here since we're dealing with the second hidden layer,
we are still choosing to rectify our activation function.
So that's all.
We are ready to add the second hidden layer
so I'm going to select this line and execute.
All right, perfect.
We successfully added the second hidden layer.
So great, that's done and we are ready
to move on to the next step.
And what is the next step gonna be?
Well, as you might've guessed,
since you know we are only adding two hidden layers
in our artificial neural network,
well the next step will be about adding the final layer,
that is, the output layer.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial
and until then, enjoy enjoy deep learning.