Hello, and welcome to this Python tutorial.
Alright, so now time to make the training
of our restricted Boltzmann machine,
and as I told you in the previous tutorial,
the most difficult part is done.
And even if the training is going
to take a couple of lines of code,
well you're gonna see that everything will be very logical
and basically we will only have
to include inside of a for loop, the different functions
that we made in this RBM class.
Because, indeed, this RBM class contains
what is at the heart of the RBM model
and so now we just need to make the training happen
and that's exactly what we're gonna do in this tutorial.
Alright, so let's start.
We have to start by choosing a number of epochs.
So, we're gonna call the variable
for the number of epoch nb_epoch.
Alright?
Equals, and let's choose for now 10 epochs
because we have a few observations.
We have only 943 observations
and besides we only have binary value zero
and one so the convergence will be reached pretty fast.
So nb_epoch will stand,
seems to be a good choice to start with.
Alright so number of epoch equals 10,
then what we need to do is, of course, make the for loop.
We're gonna make a for loop that will go through
the 10 epochs and then each epoch,
all our observations will go into the network
and we will update the weights after the observations
of each batch passed through the network.
And then in the end we'll get our final
visible note with the new ratings for the movies
that were not originally rated.
Alright, so let's make this for loop.
We start with for, then we need to come up
with a variable for epoch and so
we're gonna simply take epoch,
that's the name of the looping variable,
in range and in parentheses,
well let's start at epoch number one
and then nb_epoch plus one.
Alright, so this will go from one to 10
because even if this is equal to 11,
remember that the upper bound of a range is not included
and therefore this will go from one to 10.
Alright and then colon, and let's go inside the for loop.
Alright, so what do we have to do first?
Well, remember that for any deep learning
algorithm that we make, we need a loss function
to measure the error.
To measure the error between
the predictions and the real ratings.
And so you know, in this training
we will compare the predictions
to the ratings we already have,
that is the ratings of the training set.
And so basically we will measure
the difference between the predicted ratings,
that is either zero or one, and the real ratings, zero one.
And we have a couple of options for measuring the loss
we have the RMSE, the Root Mean Square Error,
which is the root of the mean
of the square differences between
the predicted ratings and the real ratings.
So that's the most common loss measuring use
and practice but then we have some other ones
like the simple distance, the absolute distance
that measures, simply, the absolute difference
between the predicted rating and the real rating.
And so in this deep learning course
I want to introduce you to these two measures,
and in fact for this RBM we'll go with
the simple difference in absolute value,
and for the auto-encoders we will use the RMSE.
And so the point is that we need to introduce
a loss variable, and we're gonna call it
train loss, train_loss.
Train, underscore, loss.
And we will initialize it to zero
of course because before we started
training this loss is equal to zero.
And then the slots will increase
when we find some errors between
the predictions and the real ratings.
Then, we're gonna need a counter.
Because what we're gonna do is
we're going to normalize the train loss
and to normalize the train loss
we will simply divide the train loss
by this counter, and I'm gonna call this counter s,
and we initialize it to zero, as well,
but we want it to be afloat and therefore
I'm adding a dot here so that s has a type float.
Alright, so we have our counter which
we will increment after each epoch
and then now time to do the real training.
And the real training happens with
these three functions, sample_h, sample_v, and train.
And so, so far, when we made these functions
it was regarding to one user
and of course the samplings and the contrast
of divergence algorithm have to be done
over all the users, but remember
over all the users in the batch.
So what we'll do first is get these batches of users.
And to do so we need another for loop.
So let's do it, so it's a for loop inside
the first for loop, and so for,
and now since this for loop is about looping
over all the users, I'm introducing the looping
variable id, underscore user, in range.
So, the indexes of the users start at zero
so we start here with zero, comma,
and now according to you what is going
to be the stop index.
That's an important point.
Remember that we wanna take some batches of users,
we don't wanna take each user one by one and then update
the weight, we want to update the weight after
each batch of users going through the network.
And so right now we're not taking each user one by one,
we're taking the batches of the users,
and therefore since the batch size equals 100,
well the first batch is going
to contain all the users from index zero to index 99,
then the second batch size is going
to contain the users from index 100 to index 199
and the third batch size from 200 to 299,
excreta, until the end.
And so the last batch that will go into the network
will be the batch size of the users from index 943,
minus 100, that is 843.
And so the last batch of users will contain
the users from index 843, to, 943.
And therefore the stop of the range for
the users is not nb users but
nb, users, minus, batch, underscore, size.
nb users minus batch size, that is 843.
Okay, but then, it's not all, we need the step
because we don't wanna go from one
to one, we wanna go from one to 100,
and then from 100 to 200, excreta, until the last batch.
And so the step, that's the third argument
we need to input, the step is going to be, not one,
the default step, but 100,
that is the batch size and therefore here as a third
argument we need to input batch, size.
That's how you implement batch learning from scratch.
Everything happens in this loop.
Alright, and now we're ready to go into the loop.
Okay so now as a first step in this new
for loop, what do we have to do?
Well first, we will get separately,
our input and our target.
Our input is the ratings of all the movies
by the specific user we're dealing with right now
in the loop, and the target is going
to be at the beginning the same as the input,
but then since you know the input is gonna go
into the Gibbs chain and will be updated
to get the new ratings in each visible node
then the input is going to change,
but the target will keep its same initial value.
Alright, so let's get first the input,
and so as you understood, as I just said,
the input is the vector that is gonna go
into the Gibbs chain and will be updated at each round trip.
And so actually, we're gonna call, very simply,
this input, vk, because this is this vk that is
going to be the output of Gibbs sampling, you know
after the K steps of the random walk.
But first, at the start this vk is actually
the input batch of observations,
that is the input batch of all the ratings
of the users in the batch.
The ratings that already existed.
And so, this input is going to be the training_set,
then brackets, and since right now we're dealing
with a specific user that has the ID, id user,
well the batch that we want to get is all the users
from id_user, up to id_user, plus, batch_size.
Why's that?
It's because this id_user, colon, id plus batch_size
is the range from the id_user up to the id_user plus 100.
So we're taking all the users from this id_user here,
up to the next 100 users in the training set.
And so that gives us our batch of 100 users.
So perfect, that gives us our input batch vk.
Then later vk will go into the Gibbs chain.
Then let's get our target, the target is the one thing
we don't wanna touch, that is, it's the batch
of original ratings that we don't wanna
touch, and that we want to compare,
in the end, to our predicted ratings.
And we need it because actually we want to measure
the error between the predicted ratings and the real
ratings to get the loss, the train loss.
So, we're gonna call this target v0,
so v0 are our ratings of the movies that were
already rated by the 100 users in this batch.
And so basically, since, you know the target
is the same as the input at the beginning,
well we just need to paste what's above.
At the beginning the input is the same as the target.
But then the input will be updated, as you saw
in the intuition lectures with Kiro.
Okay, and then we have one third thing
to get before we start the real deal.
That is contrastive divergence with Gibbs sampling
it is our initial probabilities.
So according to you it is the initial probabilities,
it is actually p, h, zero, remember ph0 is the probabilities
that the hidden node at the start equal one
given the real ratings.
That is, given the ratings of the movies that
were already rated by the users of our batch.
And so here, in this for loop, I'm going to take as well ph0
and now what do you think I'm going to add?
Well, here we go, that's where we use
our first function of one of these three functions
according to you which one is it going to be?
Well, we wanna get the probabilities
that the hidden node equal one given the visible nodes
at the beginning, and therefore that of course
sample-h, that we want, because sample-h returns
p_h given V, that is here it will return p_h given V, zero
And since this sample_h function also returns
the samples, the Bernoulli samples, well we have
to use a Python trick to only get the first
element of what this function returns,
and the Python trick to do that is to add here
a comma and then an underscore, so that it understands
that we only want to return, you know, the first element
of the function that we're gonna take right now,
that is sample_h.
So right now what we have to add is sample_h,
but since sample-h is a method of our RBM class,
well we need to use a sample-h function
from our rbm object, and therefore we need to take here
our rbm object, and then dot, and then now we can
take our sample, underscore, h, function.
Alright, and then parentheses of course,
and now we have to input one argument
as you can see here which is x.
And remember, x corresponds to the visible node,
because we want to sample the hidden node,
and we do this with the probabilities p_h given
the visible nodes, and so the variable here is
the visible nodes, and so which visible nodes,
well that's the visible nodes at the start, that is, v0.
That is the original ratings of the movies
for all the users of our batch.
Alright, so, v0.
Okay, things are starting to get shape.
Then, next step.
So the next step is, I'm sorry guys, another for loop.
And, according to you what is
this for loop going to be about?
Well there is only one for loop that we can make,
it's of course the for loop for the k steps
of contrastive divergence.
The K steps of contrastive divergence,
that is in this for loop
that we're gonna make the Gibbs chain,
that we're gonna do our k steps of the random walk.
Alright, so let's do this.
Another for loop, so for, then let's call
the looping variable of course, k in range, (10).
Alright, and now, a little exercise,
I would like you to continue here
to implement what is going to be inside this for loop,
that will be excellent practice for you,
and you'll get the solution in the next tutorial.
You have all the tools you need to apply now
the contrastive divergence, so you should totally be able
to do this.
Alright, so good luck, guess what's inside this
for loop, and we'll continue that in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning!