Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, before we take the challenge to improve our
relevance accuracy of 83% that we that we just computed
in the previous tutorial with k-fold cross-validation,
I'd like to cover a very important technique
in deep learning, which is the dropout regularization.
So the dropout is the solution
for overfitting in deep learning.
Overfitting is when your model was trained too much
on the training set, too much that it becomes much less
performance on the test set and we can observe this
when we have a large difference of accuracies
between training set and the test set.
Generally, when overfitting happens, you have a much
higher accuracy on the training set than the test set.
And another way to detect overfitting is when you observe
a high variance when applying k-fold cross-validation
because indeed, when it's overfitted on the training set,
that is when your model learn too much, well sometimes
it will succeed on new observations in one test set,
when the correlations are similar to what the model
learned too much.
And sometimes your model won't succeed on other test sets
because the correlations that it learned too much,
unfortunately don't apply to these test sets.
And therefore, in your vector of accuracies that you obtain
with k-fold cross-validations, you have some high accuracies
and some low accuracies and therefore you have
high variance and that's how you detect overfitting.
So, we definitely didn't get overfitting in the previous
tutorial, because indeed when we look at our
vector of accuracies, we get our 10 accuracies with the
very small variance, that is by the way equal to 0.9%,
so that's a small variance and as you can see
our accuracies are more or less around 83%,
the relevant accuracy that we obtained
with k-fold cross-validation.
But just in case you used the deep learning models
you learned in this course, on your datasets
to accomplish your goals and you observed some
overfitting, or high variance, well I want you to have
the solution to solve this problem.
And this solution is the dropout regularization.
So simply in this tutorial we will implement dropouts.
And so how does it work?
Where do we need to apply dropout to our artificial
neural network and how does it work?
Well dropout works this way.
At each iteration of the training some neurons
of your artificial neural network are randomly disabled
to prevent them from being too dependent on each other
when they learn the correlations and therefore,
by over-writing these neurons the artificial neural
network learns several independent correlations in the data,
because each time there is not the same configuration
of the neurons.
And the fact that we get these independent correlations
of the data, thanks to the fact that the neurons work
more independently, that prevents the neurons from learning
too much and therefore that prevents overfitting.
Okay, so that's how it works and now let's see how
we can implement dropout within this implementation of our
artificial neural network.
Okay so first we need to import a new class besides
the sequential class and the dense class.
This class is the dropout class, very simply.
So we import this class from
keras.layers, same as for dense.
And from this layers module we import dropout.
Alright, so that's dropout.
We can actually try to import it.
Here we go, dropout imported.
And now where exactly in the neural network
are we going to apply dropout?
So as you understood, dropout is applied to the neurons
so that some of them randomly become disabled
at each iteration.
And so basically what we need to do is to apply dropout
to the layers.
It can be to one layer, or it can be to several layers.
So just to show you, I'm going to apply to several layers.
I'm going to apply it to the first hidden layer
and I'm going to apply it to the second hidden layer.
And my advice is that when you have overfitting,
you should apply dropout to all the layers, because that
will give you more chance to reduce overfitting.
Alright so let's apply dropout to the first hidden layer.
So I'm gonna add here with dropout
and we're gonna add a new line
right after we added the hidden layer
with the dense function.
And actually that's very simple, we take our classifier
then dot and then again add because we're actually adding
dropout and then the add function, you probably guess what
we're going to input, well of course we have to input
dropout parentheses and now we have several arguments.
So let's inspect dropout by pressing command of Ctrl I
and let's have a look at the arguments.
Okay so the first argument is P, which is a code between
zero and one, and that's the fraction of the input you need,
you want to drop.
So basically that's the fraction of the neurons
you want to drop, or as I said disable at each iteration.
So let's suppose we have 10 neurons.
Well if we choose P equals 0.1, 10%, then that means
that at each iteration, one neuron will be disabled.
If P equals 0.2, two neurons will be disabled.
And so which value of P should we input?
Well my advice is that when you have overfitting,
that you start trying with P equals 0.1, 10%,
and then if it doesn't solve the problem, if you still
have overfitting, then you try a higher value of P.
And you increment it for example by 0.1.
So you first try with .01 and then if you still have
overfitting, you try with 0.2.
If you still have overfitting you try with 0.3.
And until you manage to reduce overfitting.
Because of course when you reach one all your neurons
will be disabled and then what you'll get is not
overfitting but underfitting because nothing will be learnt.
There will be no neurons to learn anything.
So in general don't try to go over 0.5 because then
you'll get too close to underfitting.
And so what I recommend is to try with 0.1,
then try 0.2, 0.3, 0.4 and that should do it.
So here, just to give you a start, I'm going to input here
P equals 0.1 and that's your first try.
Alright, and that adds dropout to your first hidden layer.
And then very simply, if you want to apply dropout
to your other layers, for example this second hidden layer,
well that's very simple, you just paste that here
and you don't change anything.
That's exactly the same.
You add dropout here to your second hidden layer
and you specify that you want to overwrite,
disable 10% of the neurons in the second hidden layer
at each iteration.
Alright, so now you know what to do in case you have to deal
with overfitting and now we're gonna get to the fun part
which is parameter tuning.
This is going to be the real deal about improving your
model's performance because basically we're going to
tune our model and we're gonna find the best
hyper parameters, like the best of number of epoch,
the best batch size, the best optimizer, so that
we get the best artificial neural network
that will allow us to reach that 86% accuracy
and make our challenge successful.
That's exactly what we're gonna do in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy deep learning.