A simple Linear Regression
is basically this formula,
where Y equals B zero plus B one times X
and you might recognize this formula
from back in high school.
It's just a formula where a trend line
or a slope
sloped line on a X-Y axis.
And let's go through these variables
and coefficients one by one.
So this is the dependent variable.
The dependent variable is something you're trying to explain
For instance how does a person's salary change
with the years of experience that he has,
so in that case Y would be the dependent variable.
Or what grade does a student get depending on how much time
he's put into studying.
In that case Y would be the dependent variable.
So something that you're trying to understand
how it depends on something else.
X is your independent variable.
In this case in the simple Linear Regression
we only have one independent variable,
so we don't even have to call X one we could just call it X.
And this is the variable that is, you're assuming
that it is causing the dependent variable to change
or as we will learn further,
sometimes that independent variable
might not be a direct cause and effect
but still, there might be an implied association
between the two.
And in that case you're trying to figure out
this association
Then B one is coefficient for the independent variable
and it kind of says how the effect or how a change in X one
a unit change in X one and we'll be talking about this a lot
Unit Changes.
A unit change in X one, how that affects a unit change in Y.
So it's kind of, think of it as the translator
or the multiplier, something like that that connects the two
the connector between Y and X one, so you can't just say,
you can't always say X one is directly proportional
there is,
well you can't just say Y, the change in X is always equal
to the chge in Y.
There might be this coefficient of proportion
to which proportion that change is inflated or deflated.
And B zero is a constant so it's a constant term.
And we'll talk about the constant just in a few seconds.
So now let's look at the Simple Linear Regression
because it's the easiest one to discuss,
it's pretty straight forward you can visualize it quite well
So here we've got the Y and X axis.
Let's look at that specific example
where we have Experience and Salary.
So Experience is gonna be our horizontal axis,
Salary is our vertical axis.
And we wanna understand how people's salary
depends on their experience.
Well what we would do in Regression,
is we don't just come up with a theory,
we look at the evidence, we look at the live hard facts.
So here are some observations we've had
So in a certain company,
this is how salaries are distributed among people
who have different levels of experience.
And what a Regression does is,
so that's the formula for Regression,
in our case it will change to Salary equals B zero
plus B one times Experience.
And what that essentially means is just putting a line
through your chart that best fits this data.
And we'll talk about best fitting in the next tutorial
when we're talking about Ordinary Least Squares,
but for now this is a line that best fits this data
and it even looks like it, right.
So I don't--
it's quite hard to draw a line that fits this data better
and the assumption here is it's impossible
this is the best line that approximates this data.
What does that mean?
Well we'll talk about that in the next tutorial once again.
For now let's focus on the coefficients and the constant.
So what does the constant mean here?
Well the constant actually means
the point where the line crosses the vertical axis.
And let's say it's thirty thousand dollars,
what does that mean?
Well it means that when experience is zero,
so when, as you see on the horizontal axis,
when experience is at zero then in the formula on the right
you cans see that the second part; B one times Experience
becomes zero.
So Salary equals B zero.
That means that Salary will equal to thirty thousand dollars
when a person has no experience.
So as soon as somebody is fresh from university
and joins this company, most likely they will have a salary
about thirty thousand dollars.
There will be some Confidence Intervals there
but we won't go into that right now.
Just we can say that according to this model,
that person will be probably getting paid
thirty thousand dollars.
Now what is B one?
B one is the slope of the line and,
so the steeper the line, the more you get,
more money you get per extra year of experience.
Let's look at this in this particular example.
Let's say somebody went from,
I dunno, maybe four to five years of experience, right.
So then to understand how he's salary will increase,
you have to project this onto the line,
then project that onto the salary axis.
And you can see that here, for one year experience
the person will get an extra ten thousand dollars
on top of his salary.
So if the coefficient B one is less,
then the slope will be less
and that means the salary increase will be less
per every year of experience.
If the slope is greater then that means the experience
will yield a more increase in Salary.
And that's pretty much it,
that's how a Simple Linear Regression works.
So the core goal here is that we're not just drawing a line
theoretically that we came up with somehow.
We're actually using observations that we have
to find the best fitting line.
And what a best fitting line is, we'll talk about that
in the next tutorial.