Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, we are ready to start building our
convolutional neural network.
I'm super excited to start, and I hope you are too.
This is going to be quite a long journey.
We're not making the most simple model here,
so we're gonna make it step-by-step.
And the first step is to import all the Keras packages
that we will need to make our CNN model.
So, I've prepared them here;
there are five of them as you can see.
And these are the only packages we'll need to make our
convolutional neural network.
So, let's get these imports done
so that we can mostly focus on the CNN.
So, let's just see what they are.
The first package is Sequential, and we already saw this
package in the previous section when making the ANN.
This Sequential package is the one that we'll use to
initialize our neural network because, remember, there are
two ways of initializing the neural network,
either as a sequence of layers or as a graph.
And since a convolutional neural network is still a
sequence of layers, well, we use the Sequential package
to initialize our neural network.
Alright, then second package, Convolution2D.
So, Convolution2D, as you might have guessed, is the package
that we'll use for the first step of making the CNN,
that is the Convolution Step, in which we add
the convolutional layers.
And, here, since we're working on images and since images
are in two dimensions unlike, for example, videos that are
in three dimensions with the time, well, we use this
Convolution2D package to deal with images.
Then, next package is MaxPooling2D, and, as you might have
guessed as well, this package will be the package that we'll
use to proceed to step two, the Pooling Step,
that will add our pooling layers.
Alright, the next package, Flatten.
So, this is the package that we'll use for step three,
Flattening, in which we convert all the pooled feature maps
that we created through Convolution and MaxPooling into
this large feature vector that is then becoming the input
of our fully connected layers.
And then finally last package, the Dense package, you know
this package, we already used it in the ANN section.
This is the package we use to add the fully connected layers
in a classic artificial neural network.
Alright, so basically each package corresponds to one step
of the construction of the CNN.
Alright, perfect.
So, now let's import the packages.
I'm going to select all these lines here and
press Command and Control + Enter to import the package.
And here we're reminded that we're using the
TensorFlow backend, which I recommend to use since
the computations are gonna be a little faster.
Alright, so that's done for this first step.
Now, let's move on to the second step,
which is to initialize our convolutional neural network.
And, to initialize it, we're gonna use the Sequential
package, and that's what we'll do in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.