Hello, and welcome back
to the course on Deep Learning.
Today we've got a very exciting tutorial ahead.
We're talking about long short-term memory,
or LSTMs for short.
So let's get started.
It's actually gonna be quite a saturated tutorial,
so we've got our own little plan of attack for today.
Today we're gonna first of all look at a bit of history,
so where it came from, what was the main idea behind it,
why people invented it.
Then we're gonna be talking about the LSTM architecture.
That's gonna be the bulk of our tutorial today,
so be prepared for that.
And then we're going to have an example walkthrough.
Hopefully we'll have enough time for that as well.
Alright, so let's get started.
Here we've got a problem which we identified
in the previous tutorials.
We talked about the vanishing gradient problem.
So in short, what happens is
as we propagate the error through the network,
it has to go through the unraveled temporal loop,
and as it does that, it goes through these layers
of neurons which are connected to themselves,
these hidden layers which are connected to themselves,
and they're connected by the means of a weight
called a Wrec or the W recurrent weight,
and because this weight is applied
many, many times on top of itself,
that causes the gradient to decline rapidly,
meaning that the weights of the layers
on the very far left are updated
much slower than the weights of the layers on the far right,
and this creates a domino effect,
because the weights of the far left layers
are very important, because they
dictate the outputs of those layers,
which are the inputs to the far right layers,
and therefore the whole training of the network suffers,
and that is called the problem of the vanishing gradient.
And as a rule of thumb, we can see here that
if Wrec is small, then we have vanishing gradient,
if Wrec is large, then we have exploding gradient.
Now, how do you solve this problem?
We talked about a couple of possible solutions.
We talked about clipping the gradient,
or penalizing the gradient for exploding gradients,
we talked about smartly selecting the weights
or the echo state networks, which we didn't go into detail
on for the vanishing gradient,
and also we talked about the LSTMs
for the vanishing gradient.
Just if you separate yourself from all of this
information on all this theory and knowledge,
how would you solve a problem like this?
What's the easiest and fastest solution to this?
So if we have Wrec is, in simple terms, less than one,
then we have vanishing gradient,
if we have Wrec greater than one,
we've got exploding gradient.
What's the first thing that comes to mind
to solve this problem?
Well, the first thing that comes to mind
is to make Wrec equal one,
and that's exactly what was done in the LSTMs.
This is a very simplified explanation,
and there's definitely more to it than just Wrec equals one,
but in general, that's the idea,
and that's all it took,
and when I saw this for the first time,
I was so excited that the solution is so simple.
It's really a genius solution,
and that completely gets rid of
the vanishing gradient problem.
Who are the people behind this?
Here are two gentlemen.
We've already talked about Sepp Hochreiter,
and the second person is Juergen Schmidhuber
who was his supervisor during Sepp's research or PhD.
So basically they wrote a paper in 1997
about LSTMs and that's when LSTMs
were introduced to the world for the first time.
Very exciting topic.
So let's have a look at what they actually are.
So we've got a recurrent neural network right here.
Unraveled temporal loop.
This is what it looks like if you dig in
inside the recurrent neural network.
And right here I wanted to do a quick shout out to
Christopher Olah.
So here is his blog right here.
Very well-written blog.
Amazing images, as you can see,
and we're going to be using images from this blog
in our explanation here,
so thank you very much to Christopher
for making this publicly available
and allowing the use of his images in other works.
So we'll definitely reference this
at the end of today's tutorial.
Going back to our presentation,
so here we've got the recurrent neural network.
This is what it looks like inside
and this is where the problem lies.
This operation that happens here
is actually a neural network layer operation
as we'll see further down.
But simply put, as you have outputs coming
into your module, into this module,
this operation's applied and then goes into
the next module operation's applied, and so on.
So as you apply this operation,
when you back propagate, it goes through all of this,
and that's where the weights are applied,
that's where the Wrec is sitting.
As that weight is applied, as it's applied, it's applied,
the gradient vanishes, vanishes, and vanishes
and that means that the weights
cannot be updated properly or fast enough
to train the network properly
and so the further away you try to look,
the more problems you have
and the more of the vanishing gradient you have.
This is the standard RNN,
and this is what the LSTM version looks like.
And I know you might be thinking
that whoa, this is super complex.
There's so much going on here.
And indeed, it is a bit more complex
than the standard RNN, but check this out.
This is how LSTMs are normally displayed
in literature and in papers and so on.
So, this is the same thing as you saw before,
but it's just a much more convoluted explanation
or representation, so definitely this option is better
and we're gonna stick with this one.
And more so, it looks difficult now
but the goal is that by the end of this tutorial
you are completely comfortable what's going on here
and I think that's pretty exciting.
Even though this may seem a bit complex now,
towards the end of the tutorial,
hopefully you'll be able to navigate LSTMs quite well.
Before we go deep into what's going on here,
I wanted to highlight the main point.
Remember we said Wrec equals one.
Well that's this line over here,
that pipeline at the top.
As you can see, there's not much going on here.
There's only like two pointwise operations
as we all understand for the down,
and there's no complex neural network layered operations.
They're all brought out to this part.
This is the essence.
If you're going to take away one thing
from today's tutorial, then this is that.
That LSTMs have a memory cell, what's called a memory cell,
I call it memory pipeline,
which just goes through time,
and this is as going through time,
and it can very freely flow through time.
Sometimes it might be removed and erased.
Sometimes things might be added into it,
but that's pretty much it.
Otherwise it flows through times freely
and therefore when you back propagate
through these LSTMs,
you don't have that problem of your vanishing gradient.
That's the essence of LSTMs.
Now let's dig in in a bit more detail.
So we're gonna replace these modules on the left,
on the right with something more simple.
Just gonna replace them with our,
these representations.
So Ct stands for memory.
A memory cell, I guess.
H is your output, so you can see there's your output
going out into the world,
and here you've got your output going into the next module.
Into the next block.
And then here you've got your input, Xt.
So basically this is the output from the previous module,
which also went into the world
but also is coming here.
So there we go.
So in LSTM a module takes in three inputs,
and has two outputs,
so Ct and Ht because these are the same.
The important thing to understand and remember
is that everything here is a vector.
So all of these are, this is not just one neuron,
not just one value.
There are lots and lots and lots of values here
hiding behind this letter, Xt.
And here as well, and here as well.
And everywhere, these are all
layers, so just remember that,
and we're gonna reference them as vectors
because that's pretty much the same thing,
just lots of different values in one vector.
Remember that and that'll make,
it will allow you not to go down the wrong path
in the intuitive understanding of this.
Just remember that these are all vectors.
And let's go through the legend.
We've got vector transfers,
so any line here is a vector being transferred
or kind of moving around in this architecture.
So that's just kind of to reiterate that it is a vector.
Then we've got a concatenation here.
So here you can see that there's two lines
combining into one.
Important to understand that this is done here
just to save space and make it less convoluted
than it possibly could be, but the best way to imagine it
is that these two lines are running in parallel.
You're not actually combining,
concatenation means that you're combing
these two X's on top of each other
but I think it's even easier to understand
if you just think of it as
there are two pipes running here
but they're running parallel to each other,
so you've got one pipe and then it goes here,
and the second pipe goes here.
Then these same pipes go here
and then they attach to that.
Basically you have two pipes running in parallel
feeding into these neural network layer operations.
Then you've got copy.
So where do we have copy?
We have copy here.
The memories go straight ahead
and just copy it over here.
Then this output is copied over here.
Then you've got pointwise operations.
Now we get to the interesting stuff.
You've got a couple of pointwise operations here,
that's five of them, and the first thing
we're going to talk about these ones, the X's.
The X's are valves and they all have names.
This is the forget valve,
the memory valve, and the output valve.
And in literature you will see letters F, V, and O
in the actual formulas representing these valves.
And so a valve looks like this
in plumbing, a valve looks like this
and we're going to kind of think of it that way as well.
So you've got water or basically something flowing through,
and then you can either close it
or you can open it, or you can close it to some extent.
Same thing here.
So you've got the forget valve
is basically controlled by this layer operation,
and we'll talk about that in a second.
And based on the output of that,
based on the decision made here,
this valve is either closed or open,
so if it's open, memory flows through freely.
If it's closed then memory is cut off
and therefore it's not transferred further
and then new memory just will be added here probably,
based on the results here.
Then you've got the memory valve,
which again is controlled by a sigma.
Sigma stands for the sigmoid activation function.
That means that that's the activation function
used in these layer operations.
And as the decision is made here,
this value, which is another layer operation,
which we'll get to in a second,
is either added to the memory
or is somewhat added to the memory,
or is not added to the memory,
depending on the value that is decided in this valve.
And then again another valve controlled by a sigmoid.
As you remember, why we're using sigmoid
is because they are from zero to one,
and therefore zero stands for nothing goes through,
one stands for something goes through,
and then here you've got the valve,
which is the forget valve.
Or not forget valve, this is the output valve.
And we'll get to that in a second.
We're pretty much already going through
the whole network already.
And then we've got the T-shaped
kind of like pipe,
or T-shaped joint,
and I'll show you where that is.
That is over here.
So where you have memory going through
and then you can add additional memories, so if we go back,
you've got memory flowing through this joint,
and maybe some additional memory will be added into it.
Maybe not, depending on the valve.
And that's pretty much it.
You've got the tangent operation here.
That's more mathematical behind it,
why you want to be between minus one and one.
We won't get into details on that
but that's another pointwise operation here you have.
And you've got the neural network layer operations
over here.
That's their representation.
So basically just think of them as
you've got, instead of pointwise,
pointwise is like element by element over vector,
if you wanna multiply a vector by zero,
you multiply every element by zero or by one
or by a certain amount.
Kind of think of it in that way.
It's very simplistic way to think about these
pointwise operations, whereas these ones
are a bit more complex.
You've got a layer coming in
and then you've got a layer coming out.
Because again, everything here is a vector
so you've got a layer of these sigmoids coming out,
controlling the valve for each one of these
elements in the vector of memory.
So it's not just one sigmoid.
There's many different and that's why
you've got a whole layer coming in
and then you've got a layer coming out.
These are layer operations.
So just remember that.
So we're ready to look into this in step by step,
and it's gonna be pretty simple
because we've discussed everything already
in terms of how it works.
We've got a new value coming in.
You've got a value coming from a previous node,
and together they are combined
to decide whether this valve should go ahead
or should be closed or should be open,
or somewhat closed or open.
Then you've got these two again combine together,
or not combine, again, they flow in parallel
and then they combined in here
or in this operation.
And basically, it's not just them combing.
It's like there's lots of layers here,
lots of layers here.
Lots of neurons here, lots of neurons here,
and then all of that is basically in one
layer operation is used to decide
what value we're going to pass through,
and then also if that value is gonna pass through or not,
and to what extent.
Then here we've got the memory flowing through.
We've got the forget valve, if it's closed or open,
we've got memory valve, closed or open,
and we're adding in some memory possibly
if we want to update.
So basically we can let this whole memory flow through,
then keep this one closed, keep this one open,
the memory won't change.
Or we can keep this one closed and keep this one open,
then we can update the memory completely.
And here, finally we've got these two values combined
to decide what part of the memory pipeline
is going to become output of this module.
Is it going to go to fully as the output
or to some extent, and so on.
So again, these decide that.
So that's how it all works.
Pretty straightforward architecture.
Let's have a look at a specific example
to understand this a bit better.
The example we talked about,
I am a boy who likes to learn.
(speaking in foreign language)
In translation to Czech.
If this were girl,
then here would be (speaking in foreign language),
meaning that these two words,
not just this word would change,
but also it would affect these two words.
So different in Czech rather than in English.
So these words are affected by the gender of the subject.
And therefore, in our LSTM we might want
to store the subject, boy in this case, in memory.
So for instance, let's say boy is stored here,
and then is just flowing through freely,
and nothing is changing.
If our new information doesn't tell us
that there's a new subject,
we'd just having boy flowing through freely
and it keeps flowing like that.
If, for instance we have a new subject,
we have girl or we have a name, like Amanda,
or something else and we understand that
we've got a new subject there,
we'll close this valve.
We'll say, destroy the memory that we had,
then open this valve, put in new memory,
and then put the name here, put the subject.
We won't just put in the gender.
We won't just put in like female.
We'll actually put as much information as we can.
For instance, this could be the,
it doesn't have to be like this
but as an example we could put in for instance, girl now
into this pipeline.
And why would we do that?
Well because then from that
we can extract different elements of information.
We can extract that it's female.
We can extract that it's singular.
So not just that it's,
there's additional information in the word girl,
that it's singular.
We can extract more information.
We can extract that the word girl, for instance,
has four letters.
Or that it was capitalized or it wasn't capitalized.
Just as these are all very intuitive examples,
it doesn't have to work this way
but this is how it could work.
So then we have the word girl in here,
and so that's how this valve works, and this valve works.
And so what this valve does is it extracts
certain information from what you have in the memory.
So for instance, if we have now girl in here,
and for the purposes of the next word or next sentence
that's coming up, you might need to know,
like we saw, you need to know the gender.
So then this valve will facilitate the extraction
of the gender, and that will go as an input
into your next module, and it'll help the next module,
like it'll be here, decide how to deal
with the information that's coming its way.
How to put it into the correct form
for the female gender, for example.
So that's how the output valve works
and what it does.
So there we go.
That's how the long short-term memory works
and I hope this was quite an intuitive explanation,
and now you have a bit of a better understanding
what LSTMs are like.
In terms of additional reading,
you could definitely reference the original paper
by our two authors who created LSTMs.
Alternatively if you don't wanna get that deep
into mathematics and into the technical stuff
there's the great blog by Christopher Olah,
which we've already mentioned.
Great explanation of LSTMs.
Highly recommend to check it out.
There is a bit of mathematics, not too heavy.
And there's another blog by Shi Yan.
Understanding LSTM and its diagrams.
Diagrams are a bit more in-depth,
so there's a bit less space saving,
but diagrams might be easier to understand in some cases.
No mathematics whatsoever, just plain intuition.
So also highly recommend this blog, to check it out
if you would like to get
a bit of additional information on LSTMs.
And on that note, I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial
and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy Deep Learning.