Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, this is not exactly a Python tutorial,
because what we'll do in this tutorial
is just to make a classification template.
And we're doing this
because the future classification models
that we're going to build.
Are going to be built much more efficiently
thanks to this template we are making
in this tutorial.
And we will make this template
from our Logistic Regression model
because as you can noticed
in this model that we just built
in this section.
Well, the only time that we code
something about Logistic Regression specifically.
Is just in this section.
Indeed the rest is purely generalized,
for example when we predict the Test set result
we don't use use any class or function specific
to the Logistic Regression.
We used this classifier here,
which is indeed the classifier of Logistic Regression
but what we'll do in the next sections
when we build other classification models.
Will be to only to import a new class
that will be the required class
to build our future classification models.
And then we will call this class here
to create our classifier object
which we will still call classifier.
And then we will use the fit method.
But that's the only part of the whole code
where we talk specifically about the model.
Nowhere else in the code has something specific
to Logistic Regression.
For example, here I don't use anything
about Logistic Regression.
I only use the classifier here
but our future models will be called classifier as well
and same for this last section here.
I don't talk about Logistic Regression
I don't code anything specific
to Logistic Regression,
only this classifier here.
So that's why it's really easy for us
to make a template for the future models
and that's why we will be so efficient
at creating the future classification models.
Thanks to this specific template.
So lets make the template!
We will actually take everything from here
to the bottom,
copy and
paste it here.
And now what we have to do,
is only to remove this part of the code here
because this is specific to the Logistic Regression model.
So we will remove this section
and replace it by a comment
to specify that we need to create
our classifier
right here.
And then you know we can generalize even more
by replacing Logistic Regression in the title
of this section here by the classifier.
Alright, and actually that's all
our template for classification
is ready to build very efficiently
any new classification model.
And you will see that in the next sections,
you will see how we will only have to
create our classifier here and we will be ready
to make the prediction,
visualize the Training set results
and visualize the Test set results.
So, actually speaking about that
lets recap about what this template is doing.
So, in the first section we import the libraries
NumPy, Matplotlib and Pandas.
In the second section we import
the dataset, our Social Network Ads dataset.
Then in the third section we split the datasets
into the Training set and the Test set.
Then in the next section we have this code
to apply Feature Scaling, if we need to.
Then this is the new section that we create
our classifier and then once our classifier is created
we predict the Test set results.
Then we made a Confusion Matrix
and then my favorite part,
we visualized the Training set results
and same as for the Test set results
that we will also visualize.
To make sure that we don't
have any overfilling and that performance of our model
is still good on new observations.
So, here we are!
Ready to build new classification models
very efficiently, I look forward to creating
these new models with you.
And until then, enjoy Machine Learning!