This video is a follow up to the previous video which introduced you to the idea of making an image
out of a matrix.
So this video is for the exercise coming from that video.
The goal is essentially to make a checkerboard map which looks something like this.
So how do you make a checkerboard in Python the way you do that is by implementing this algorithm here.
This formula here.
So we have each element.
So the AIA throw in the JF column of matrix.
I'll call it C for checkerboard equals minus one to the power of I Plus J where i is the row index and
J is the column index.
So that will produce this plot.
And once you successfully get this whole matrix to work you can see if you can figure out how to get
these tick marks to be present without any labels.
So here you see the tick marks are present but there are no text labels associated with them I encourage
you now to pause the video switch to Python and basically get this to work.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I will go about solving this.
Now I didn't actually tell you the size of this matrix but you can guess that it's going to be a square
matrix and let's just start with making it a 10 by 10.
So I'm initializing this matrix called C to be a 10 by 10 matrix of zeros.
And now I'm going to need to implement that formula that I showed in the slides.
So this is actually I think even parameters this.
So let's pick a new variable called N and set n to be equal to 10.
And this is really great because now we can change the size of this matrix just by changing this one
parameter that's called soft coding.
This is called soft coding is generally preferred whenever possible.
OK.
So let's set up a double for loop.
So for i in range 0 to n this is gonna loop over the rows and then we loop over the columns.
And that's also going from 4 J in range 0 to N because this is a square matrix so it's end by n.
Now we need to specify that each element so the I throw in a J if column is equal to minus 1 to the
power of I Plus J.
And now the question is whether this is really the right implementation of this formula.
And the answer is No.
And that's because if you remember pen does the order of operations exponential nation takes precedence
before addition.
So in fact python will associate the AI with the power and not with the J.
Okay so we need to override this order of operations so that can be done by using parentheses and of
course parentheses trumps everything else.
All right.
So maybe this is good.
Maybe this works.
Let's see what this looks like.
Plot I am show and then matrix C
and.
That is a rather disappointing image.
It doesn't really look anything like a checkerboard.
So what is going on here now in this case it's kind of hard to tell just from looking at this image.
So what I'd like to do is print out this matrix C and see what that looks like.
All right.
So this matrix C is all minus ones everywhere it's minus one.
So clearly something went wrong and let's see if we can figure it out.
And actually the problem is also with this order of operations.
So this looks like minus one into your eyes.
This looks like it's a single object.
You know just the number minus one.
However what's really going on under the surface is that there is a minus one times one to the power
of I Plus J and then this exponent is taking precedence over the multiplication.
So really it's just implementing so python is implementing one to this power and then multiplying everything
by minus one.
So the solution is yet again to use parentheses.
That often happens it's often a solution in mathematics and in Python.
When in doubt start using parentheses.
All right.
So let's see what this looks like now.
So this is now pretty curious because the actual Matrix itself looks great.
This is exactly what we want for a checkerboard.
It's an alternating pattern of minus ones and plus ones.
However the Matrix the image of the matrix still doesn't look very good.
Now maybe this is an issue of the color map.
So I'm going to change the color map to be black and white or in particular.
It's actually called grayscale.
So let's set this to be gray.
And now the image looks really great.
This looks like a game of checkers that we could play.
Okay.
And now it's also pretty interesting and easy to change n to see how that affects this plot.
So let's try 20 and wonder what it's going to look like if I do two hundreds Okay so this is pretty
interesting there's a lot of tiny tiny little squares here that are actually getting a little bit alias.
That's why you see this kind of larger repeating pattern in here.
Anyway let's set it back to be 10.
Okay.
And then the other thing that we want to do is get rid of the tick labels without getting rid of the
tick marks themselves.
So I hope you were able to figure out how to do that.
Maybe you had to look it up on the internet but the solution is to use the method tick parameters for
a tick parameters and then I'm going to specify that the label for the left side.
So here is set to false.
And then when I rerun it again you can see that there are no tick labels so the tick marks are still
there but the labels are not there.
So.
And then to get rid of these guys down here that is label bottom and also set that to be false.
All right.
This looks very nice.
And suddenly I feel like playing checkers in this video and the previous video I showed you how to visualize
matrices using Python and in particular the function I am show being able to visualize matrices is super
duper important for making progress as a coder who wants to understand mathematics better.