I am really excited for this video.
I mean, I am excited about all these videos, but this one in particular is going to be great because you
are going to learn about if statements in Python.
If statements are one of the most important control functions in all of programming. So you're going
to learn how to use and how to interpret if statements in Python. And along the way,
you will also see how to use AND and OR, these are called logical operations.
Now you must be thinking that because if statements are so important in programming then they must be
really hard and really confusing.
Well you are wrong.
If statements are actually really really easy because you use if statements all the time in your normal
human language.
So I'm going to first introduce you to if statements in the human language you say something like if
it's raining then I will bring an umbrella or if it's sunny I'll buy an ice cream cone.
Otherwise if neither of these is true then I'll start learning math using python.
All right.
So this is kind of the way you would go through it if you are a human and I assume you're a human.
The formatting is only slightly different in Python so here's how it looks in Python.
We say if raining and raining here or whatever goes in here after the if and before the colon here this
needs to be a boolean.
So this needs to evaluate to True or false.
So if this is true then you run this code.
If this is false if this statement in here is false then python is going to go to the next piece, which
here it says elif but that's... elif stands for
Else if. sunny.
So again this has to be a Boolean true or false.
And if this is true then I run this code.
And if this is false then I run this code.
So this is the full format of an if statement.
So you have if and then a boolean so true or false and if this is true this code gets run and all of
this code gets skipped but if this is false then python will test the next thing here and then the next
thing here.
Now if both of these are false then else gets run, no matter what. You will see in a moment,
when I switched to Python, that if is important that's the necessary part of the if statement, Elif and
else are optional.
You can include them if you want.
They are not necessary.
So this is for a single conditionals so raining has to be true or false.
But what if we wanted to include multiple conditionals? That can be done by basically stacking multiple
logical operators.
So let me show you what that looks like.
So you might have if raining or snowing then that's what these two call it.
That's what this colon indicates here.
Learn Python at home.
So this means that this code gets evaluated if it's raining or if it's snowing. So the or means if this
is true or this is true both of these don't have to be true.
If you want to setup an if conditionals so that both statements must be true for this code to be run
then that looks like this.
You would say if it's sunny and it's warm then learn Python at the beach.
That sounds like a great idea.
Now this code is only run when both of these conditionals are true.
So it has to be sunny and it has to be warm.
OK.
Well, the best way to learn programming is to see lots of examples.
So now I'm going to switch to Python and show you some examples.
All right.
So because the goal here is to learn how to use Python to help you learn math I'm going to start with
a simple math equation.
So let's say if four plus two equals equals six.
Now you will remember from the previous video on equality and inequalities that this double equals sign
is not a variable assignment, so we're not trying to assign six to some variable called four plus
two, which is not even a legal name for a variable. Instead, with the double equals sign we are asking
python a question, and the question is whether what's on the left hand side is equal to what's on the
right hand side.
Now in this case we know the answer is true but let's print out true anyway.
So I'm going to say print true okay.
And now if I run this code by pressing control enter we actually get an error.
Now the error is not with anything that I wrote here and the error is not with anything that I wrote
here.
It's actually something that I left out, which I mentioned in the slides a moment ago. And that is this
colon.
So these two vertical dots here the colon that is really important you need that colon there.
Otherwise your code is not going to run and you can also tell that there was an error because normally
if you've put it in this colon accurately then as soon as you press Enter you can see that python will
automatically put you on the next line four spaces in.
So let's bring this up here like this.
And now this prints out true so if and then a conditional and this conditional is true.
So then all the code after here gets run.
You can put in multiple lines of code.
You can say...
Four plus two and... let me put that in print. Print four plus two.
And this also gets run.
So the question is how does Python know when to stop this if statement?
And the answer has to do with spacing.
So you'll notice that this has four spaces in front of it.
This has four spaces in front of it.
Now if I were to delete all of those spaces.
So this is no longer indented then only this text here is part of the if statement.
And to prove that to you I'm going to change this to five.
So now this is false.
This conditional is false.
So this code is not going to be run.
However this code here print four plus two.
This is not part of the if-statement because it doesn't have the indentation here.
So let's run this and now -- as I predicted -- this statement true does not get printed out, but this does
get printed out. And now I'm going to press a few spaces you can see now that the word print is appearing
in red font.
And that's because Python doesn't like it.
And in fact, if I press control enter you can even see we get an indentation error.
It does not match any indentation level.
So this needs to be zero spaces or four spaces.
Okay.
Now it prints nothing because this conditional is false.
And so neither of these two lines get run.
And now I'm going to say... else I'm going to add an else statement. And what this else statement does is if all
of the previous conditionals are false then whatever comes after
else gets run.
Notice that there isn't another conditional in here.
So this is different from saying elif here we would need to add another conditional so here I could
say elif four plus two equals six. So with if and with elif, you need a conditional and if you don't want
to have a conditional you just want to have some option at the end that will run whenever all the previous
conditionals are false, then you just use else. I'd like to show you another example, this time using
variables and soft coding for printing.
So let's say x 1 equals 3 and let's set x 2 to be equal to 4.
So I want to run some tests I want to say if X 1 is greater than x 2 then it should say something like
print.
And now what I want to do is say three is greater than four.
However this is not really great programming because this is hardcoded.
So right now this part works however if I change this to five then x 2 x 1 actually is greater than
x 2.
However it prints out 3 is greater than 4, which is incorrect.
Okay.
So the way that I'm going to do this is using more flexible printing that I have already introduced
you to. So I'm going say %G is greater than percent G and then here I say percent sign and in parentheses
x 1 comma x 2.
So now we see 5 is greater than 4.
I can set this to be 50 it's gonna say 50 is greater than 4.
And so on.
Now if I set this back to 3 we should get nothing printing out.
So now let's say elif x 2 is actually x 1 is less than X 2 and now I want to say the opposite. I want
to say x 1 is less than x 2.
So actually, you know, because I'm copying and pasting here I think I'll leave it as greater than but now
I'll put x 2 and then x 1 here.
So this is still correct perhaps it's a little bit awkward because we're testing for X one is less than
X 2 but we're printing out x 2 is greater than 3 x 1.
Of course those are equivalent statements.
It just looks a little bit awkward.
And so what else should we include in here?
So if X 1 is not greater than x 2 and if x 1 is not less than X 2 then what could that possibly mean?
Well it would have to mean that x 1 is equal to x 2, so let's also include that.
So let's say else print and then I think I'll copy and paste this as well.
Now you always have to be really really careful when you are copying and pasting code because there's
always going to be something that needs to be changed.
And if you're not careful then you might forget to change something so equal to this.
Okay so now it's always good when you're writing code it's always good to test out all the possibilities.
So let's set these both to be three and we get three is equal to three. So here is your exercise for
this video.
What you want to do is loop over numbers from 0 to 3, call that variable i.
And then inside that loop you have another loop that goes over the numbers 0 through 4 -- and they should
all be integers by the way.
So this should be 0 1 2 3 0 1 2 3 4 and you can call this inner loop variable j.
And then what you want to do is print i to the power of minus J.
But not all the time, not for every iteration this loop. You want to print i to the minus J
Only for iterations in this loop where i is greater than J.
And where J or sorry I is greater than 0 I misspoke. Where I is greater than 0 and where J is greater
than 0. I recommend you to use the display math functions that you've learned about in previous videos
in order to get this really nice formatting in particular with the exponents up here.
So when you successfully complete this exercise you should get an output that looks like this.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video, show off your skills at using for loops and also if statements,
and when you're finished or when you get stuck then come back, unpause the video, and then you can watch
me solve this exercise.
All right.
So let's get started.
First thing we need to do is import the display and math modules.
So perhaps you remember that.
How to set that up.
Or maybe you need to check back with your notes from previous lectures.
So was import from IPython dot display, import display and lowercase and math was an upper case.
That's good.
So now we need to have a loop that's going to go for I in range 0 to 4 and this was one of the funny things
about Python that when you use this range function it's actually going to go from the first number up
to one minus the second number.
So if you want to print out numbers or loop through numbers 0 through 3, which were the instructions,
then you have to type range zero comma four.
So then I type for J in range zero comma five and then what do we want to do here.
So we want to say something like display and then this is going to be basically I raised to the minus
J
power equals whatever this happens to equal.
Okay.
I like to write things out in text like this before writing it properly in either code or in this
case is going to be in some combination of latex and Python code.
Okay.
So now let's...
Now that I've written out the basic idea, I'm going to go back and replace these.
So this is going to be % G to the.
And then this has to be in curly brackets because it's going to be multiple pieces of text so it's not
just the minus sign It's the minus sign percent g
equals another percent G.
Okay.
So now we need percent sign and then parentheses.
So the three replacements for G here are going to be I.
And then J.
And then we have I.
To the power of minus J.
Now if you got a little bit confused on this formatting I bet it was probably with this caret because
in latex, caret indicates the exponent whereas in Python code you have to use a double asterisk.
Okay so let's check if this works.
Huh.
It doesn't work.
We get an error message.
It says zero division zero cannot be raised with negative power.
So essentially what I'm trying to do here is divide zero by zero and you're not allowed to divide by
zero and you're certainly not allowed to take zero divided by zero.
So why do we get this error if it seems like the code is correct?
Now, you might remember from the exercise instructions that actually we needed to do a little bit more
than this.
So there's part of this code that I have left out and that is that we print this statement only when
I is greater than zero.
And when J is greater than zero.
So I'm going to say if I is greater than zero and J is greater than zero and now there's two more things
that I need to do here I need to have a colon at the end here and then I need this line here to be printed
four spaces in so one two three four.
Okay now let's see how this looks.
This is looking much much better.
And this is also pretty interesting to see that for example three to the power of minus four which means
one over three to the power of four is equal to point 0 1 2 3 4 5 7.
That's really unfortunate.
I really would have liked to have a six here but that's just the way it goes. I hope you enjoyed watching
and learning from this video.
I enjoyed making it.
You learned about if statements, you learned about logical operators like AND and OR. As I mentioned
in the beginning of this video if statements are really really important in programming.
If you are not totally comfortable with using statements in python just yet, then don't worry -- you will
get plenty more experience throughout the next videos.