In this video I'm going to talk to you about Tangent lines to a function.
I'll introduce you to the idea and the formula for a tangent line.
And of course you will get to see this in Python and in the exercise you will get to make a beautiful
plot.
And don't worry there's going to be purple in the plot.
So then you know that it's going to be good.
So what is the tangent line.
So here is a function.
This happens to be the function x squared.
And now this orange line here is a tangent line to this function.
So what is a tangent line.
Attention line is a straight line that just barely kisses the function at one single point.
So it touches the function at this one point over here.
So that's a bit of a intuitive and visual definition of a tangent line.
There is a formal definition of mathematical definition and that looks something like this.
So let's say the line T THE TANGENT LINE IS EQUAL TO F prime at A or F prime.
Of course is the derivative of the function and a sub a here which is the same A is here in here.
That is simply the point at which you want to compute the tangent line.
So in this particular example a would be looks like it's around 1.
So f prime at a so you have to compute the derivative of the function and then evaluate the function
at the point A times the quantity X minus X say an X is actually really just this axis here this x axis
here an x ray is is this point here.
So that would be one for this example.
So X minus X A plus the function value at point A.
So what is this function mean.
I think it helps to understand this function and also to remember this function by comparing it to the
formula for computing a line that I showed you in an earlier section of this course.
So that formula is often expressed Y equals M X plus B.
This is often called the slope intercept form of a line.
So let's compare these are t is a line Y is the line now f prime at a.
I'm claiming is basically the same thing as M now m we interpret as the slope of the line and that is
exactly the idea of a derivative.
The derivative is the slope of a function at an infinitesimal at a you know the tiniest tiniest difference
that you can compute.
So f Prime is the same thing as the slope and then we have the variable x and that's essentially what
we have here.
The only thing is that we are shifting X by X at a and the way to think about this shifting procedure
is that this function value this vector value is going to be zero at the point A.
So really all you're doing is taking this same X and you're just shifting it a little bit so that the
point that you are interested in will have a value of zero in this expression here.
Okay.
And then these slope times the Axis vector X that you know that can be any number of lines it can make
an infinite number of lines you need to know how far up the y axis to shift this line here and that
is given by f of a or the function value at point A which is gonna be this red dot here and just by
analogy that's the same exact thing as this which is called an intercept.
So here the interpretation of the intercept is what is the value of y when x equals zero.
And that's exactly the same thing here.
X this whole term is zero when x equals x sub a.
So that means that this whole term is zero.
So this is basically acting as the intercept.
Okay.
So I hope that's sensible that helps connect algebra and basic graphing with calculus and tangent lines.
What I'd like to do now is switch to Python and basically translate this formula into code and reproduce
this graph.
We are going to be using the simple by the.
No that's a mistake.
The gnome pi and map plot lib in this video.
So let's see.
Let's start by creating a symbolic variable X X that symbols X and then I'm going to define the function
and it's to give tive.
So let's see the function f is going to be X squared and then the derivative I'll call it variable D
F that's going to be sin.
Def of X okay.
And then I'm going to get the function and derivative value at our requested point which is you know
I call it x sub a.
So in fact we haven't even defined x of a song call this X a equals 1.
So this is the points I think I'll even make a comment here.
This is the value at which to compute the tangent line.
Okay so then we need the function and derivative value.
So in other words what is the value of f at X A equals 1.
Now obviously we can just compute it just by looking at this.
You know 1 squared equals 1 and the derivative of x squared is 2 x.
So the derivative is gonna be 2.
However obviously we want this code to be able to work for any value that we want to compute the tangent
of.
So I'm going to create this new variable called F a set it equal to F2 subs and now I'm gonna sub for
X X A.
And let's just do some sanity checks make sure that that's one which indeed it is.
And then I will get D F at a and I'll set that equal to that's gonna be now.
Def that sub.
So again we are now substituting for X the value of X A in the simple I object D F and that corresponds
to the derivative of the main function x squared.
All right.
And let's see what that's equal to 2 as predicted.
Very nice.
Okay.
So to compute the tangent line I actually want to convert these simple objects into num pi functions.
So I've told you how to do that several times already.
I'm gonna call this f fun fun is for function of course although I hope you are having a lot of fun
while going through this.
So that's going to be simple lambda phi X F and then usually the way that I've been showing you previously
how to do this is you would say you know F fun and then X X like this however it turns out that if you
don't need to run this function multiple times with different ranges of x you can actually add the input
that you want into the function immediately after writing the function with this syntax.
Okay now of course I haven't yet defined X X so let's see X X is going to be known pi Lynn space and
I think somewhere like minus two to plus two in two hundred steps is pretty good.
So just to show you what this looks like now instead of fun being a function which it will be if I comment
out this second input.
Now this is a lambda fied function but when I include the input into this function immediately after
generating it like this then f fun ends up being the vector and actually we can already see it gets
starts off as being large numbers and then it gets smaller it gets close to zero you can see you know
like this value for example here is nine but then it's times tend to the minus four.
So this is actually extremely close to zero and then the function gets large again.
Okay.
So that seems consistent with what I would expect based on the function x squared.
All right.
And then of course I need D F fun.
And that's going to be basically the same.
I'll do copy paste except this is now going to be def okay.
And now for the real fun.
Well I think the real fun comes from the plotting.
So but this is kind of fun.
We're building up to the fun compute the tangent line so let's see.
I will call this tan line not to be confused with the tan line you get when you're laying on the beach
in the summer.
The tangent line now remember from the formula that was the derivative of a so I call that f prime at
a.
In the slides.
Times X X minus X a plus the value of the function at point A.
So that's this thing all right.
So run all this code just to make sure I haven't made any silly coding errors and I haven't yet.
Who knows what's going to happen in the future.
Let's see.
Now I want to plot something to plot F..
Let's start by plotting the function itself.
So f fun and I will give this a label of F of X and let's already see what this looks like.
Just for a bit of sanity checking.
Okay this looks pretty good.
It looks like the function f of or C F equals X squared.
Now I'm going to plot the tangent line so that's P L ts and now that's x x is still the x axis vector
and then we have tan line and the label here is going to be tangent.
Let's see how this looks all right.
Looking pretty good.
Now I want to plot that red dot on top of the point here where the tangent line intersects and just
kisses the function.
So that is plot that P L T.
So that was point X a an FAA and you have to be mindful here.
This is not DFA so we're not plotting the point at the derivative.
That's actually not the right point.
We want the point at exactly the original function.
All right.
So this looks pretty good.
What I'd like to do now is just spend a moment to make this figure look a little bit better.
So the first thing I'm gonna do is set the axis to be square and then set the limits.
And as I've mentioned before it's nice to set the limits because you know this graph here is dominated
by all this parts of the function here which are not terribly interesting.
The interesting part is happening right around here.
So let's say that this should be certainly don't want it to go all the way down to minus five.
Let's try to how about that.
So minus two to plus two on the x axis minus two two plus two on the y axis loops.
And this is called Axis not limits.
I told you I was gonna make a silly typo.
Okay so this is looking good but still I don't think we need all this room down here.
Why don't we try setting the lower limit for the y axis to be maybe minus point five.
How about that OK.
This is looking better and I would like to add some dotted lines that go across.
Y equals zero and x equals zero.
So we could hard code them but I'm going to read them right off of the axes and partly the main reason
why I'm doing that is just to give you a reminder of this aspect or this approach to graphing lines.
So I'm going to get information about the current axis.
That's what GCA stands for.
Get current axis and then I'm going to say plot from this variable x.
I'm going to get the x limit and that's gonna give me the two coordinates for the X limit.
Now of course it's going to be minus two and plus two but it's useful to see how to soft code this year.
And then on the y axis the line is just going to go from zero to zero.
And that's this line here actually as it turns out this line happens to be the tangent line of this
function at exactly point zero.
So even though this is not by intention this dotted black line is also a tangent line.
Okay.
And then we want a vertical line.
So that's going to be on the x axis.
It goes from zero to zero.
And on the y axis it goes from the lower limit of the y axis to the upper limit of the y axis.
All right.
So that gives us this and let's see what else do we need to add here.
Well we certainly need to activate the legend otherwise all this work that I went through to write out
these labels is for nothing.
I'm going to say that this is looking pretty good.
Of course by now you know enough about map plot lib and Pi Thun plotting to be able to add some extra
things if you like like a Y axis label and x axis label and so on.
But I'm going to call this good for now so that was a pretty fun video.
I told you about the concept the intuition and the formula for computing a tangent line to a function
and how to interpret that formula and connect it to the Y equals M X plus b slope intercept form of
a line.
And what was this about yet another beautiful plot with Python that actually comes from the exercise
in this video.
And that is the next video.
So stay tuned.