In this video I'm going to tell you about the unit circle and how to create the unit circle both in
math and in Python.
And this is also going to give you a bit more practice at plotting in Python.
So here is what the unit circle looks like.
It's well it's just a circle.
It's centered at the origin.
And why is it called the unit.
Well in math the term unit is often used to indicate the number one.
So the number one is the single unit or unitary.
So the unit circle basically just means a circle that is always a length of exactly one away from the
origin.
Now you can see that when you look at these axes here.
So this is one unit away here.
And one unit away here and one unit away here.
So basically every single point in here is one unit away from the origin.
So how do you create this unit circle.
Well one way to create it is through trigonometry and in particular through cosine and sign.
Now I'm going to talk more about trigonometry in a later section of the course.
But for this video suffice it to say that if you use the cosine of X and the sign of X and keep the
X is the same here then that's going to give you some point in this unit circle.
And that point that value of x turns out to be the angle relative to this axis over here.
So essentially the way that we are going to create the unit circle here is by generating numbers that
go from 0 through pi all the way up to 2 pi and then we just put those numbers 0 through 2 pi into the
cosine function into the sine function and plot one against the other.
And that's our unit circle to create this unit circle.
We are going to use the known pi modules.
I will write import num pi as MP.
And because we are going to plot some things we also need to import map plot lib dot pi plot as BLT
which is basically what everyone does.
Okay so let's define our variable x.
So I'm going to use the Linn space function.
We want to go from zero to two pi.
So how do we get pi.
Actually let me pause this for or comment this out for a moment and talk a little bit about pi.
Now I'm not referring to the food pi I'm referring to the number pi and that is this number three point
1 4.
And you know I forget whatever else comes in there definitely it starts with three point 1 4.
So let's just see what happens if we type pi here we get an error.
So the variable in that or this reserved keyword pi does not exist in the base Python workspace.
However none Pi has a reserved variable for pi.
So N.P. dot pi is going to give us pi out to 15 digits or whatever this is.
Okay.
So with that said we want to go from zero to two pi so two times and Pete out Pi.
And how many steps do we want between 0 and 2 pi.
Let's start off with how about six and let's see how that looks.
So now I'm going to generate the plot by entering this variable X into the cosine and sine function.
So let's say peel tee it up plot and P so num pied out cosine of X by the sign of X and let's make this
a black line.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
Well I guess you can kind of see that it wants to be a circle it's a bit more like a Pentagon but maybe
it's kind of approaching a circle.
Maybe we just don't have enough points in here.
Wonder what's gonna happen if I go for about twenty five points.
All right.
Now this is starting to look a little bit better.
It's a bit rounder why do we go up to 100 and see how that looks.
Aha.
This is looking good.
Except this doesn't really look like a circle.
Looks more like an oval.
Looks like an ellipse.
Now the problem is actually not with this formula.
The problem is not with the code.
The problem is that this axis is rectangular.
It's not square.
So you can see that from the zero to the edge of this circle on top is 1.
And then also from here from zero all the way to the left edge it's still a distance of one.
So in fact the axis is stretched the circle or this object.
I should say is still a circle.
So let's make this plot look a little bit nicer.
I'm going to start by setting the access to be square that already looks a lot better and then I'll
put some labels on here some axis labels.
Say plot that X label is cosine of X and people often write costs in short for cosine and then the y
axis label is going to be the sign of x.
All right.
This is looking better.
I'm mostly pretty happy with this except the picture that I showed in the slides had a gray dashed line
along the zeros of the sign axis and the cosine axis.
So it would be nice to put those in here as well.
So I will draw those here.
So peel teed up plot.
So now we want to draw.
Let's start with this zero line here.
So on the x axis it's going to go from a little bit less than minus one to a little bit over 1 So let's
maybe say that on the x axis it's going to go from minus one point one two plus one point one and then
where does this line go on the y axis.
Well it actually doesn't go anywhere on the y axis or the sine axis.
It starts at zero and it ends at zero.
So this is going to be zero comma zero.
All right.
So this is starting to look pretty good except I would want this to be a gray dashed line.
So let's first make it a dash to line.
So I'm using two hyphens here to make this a dash line.
OK so now that's dashed and now I want to set the color to be Grace.
I'm going to write color equals and then in a list I can input three numbers for red green and blue
or RG B.
So how do we get a gray line essentially to get a gray line.
You set the red green and blue color values to all be the same.
So let's go four point eight point eight and point eight.
Okay.
So that looks pretty good now.
So this is the horizontal line for the vertical line.
We want this line of code to be almost exactly the same except now on the x axis.
We go from zero to zero.
And on the y axis we go from minus one to plus 1.
So all I have to do is basically swap these two sets of coordinates.
All right.
So this is looking better except that the line now isn't quite long enough.
We get some whitespace up here.
So what I'm going to do to fix that is forced the axis to be from minus one point one two plus one point
one.
So these are the two axis limits for the x axis and then for the y axis.
Also one point one or minus one point one two one point one.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
There's one more thing I would like to do one more addition I would like to make to this plot before
we get to the exercise for this video and that addition is basically just to draw one line that goes
from the origin to this circles to the edge of the unit circle.
Now you already know how to do that because you already know how to draw lines on these kinds of Cartesian
axes.
So if anything this is really just a review.
So let's do a line so first let's pick an angle and let's say that angle is going to be pi over four.
So now how are we going to make this line.
So I want a line that goes from the origin to pi over four or I should say to the unit circle with an
angle of pi over four.
So it's going to be somewhere around here.
So we need to specify the two x coordinate so the start and stop on the x axis and start and stop on
the y axis.
Now because this line will start at the origin of course it's going to be zero something and then the
y coordinates are also going to be zero something and that something is N.P. that cosine of angle.
And then here for the y axis it's going to be and Pete out sign of angle and let's make this a red line.
So it's nice and visible.
All right.
So this looks pretty nice.
I think the exercise for this video is to basically produce this plot.
So this looks pretty neat I think.
And what's interesting about this plot is that the lines are really close together here.
And as you go around the circle the lines are getting further and further apart from each other.
Now the reason why the lines are compressed over here and they get expanded over here is because the
angles of all of these lines is E to the x.
So we have this natural exponent and then something in the power here.
Now if you're not familiar with E to the X the natural exponent then you can get really excited about
the next video where I'm going to tell you all about the natural exponent and its associated function.
The logarithm but for now all you need to know is that there is the natural exponent.
And if you're not sure how to figure out how to use the natural exponent in Python then that's going
to be a little bit of a challenge for this exercise.
Okay.
So basically you want to come up with angles so points in vector x that go from minus three up to one
point eighty three and you can just basically do with with trial and error how many points you want
between minus three and one point eighty three.
So it's not just the numbers minus three and one point eighty three but linearly spaced numbers in between
these two boundaries and then you come up with some other variable and called that K and set k to be
equal to e to the x and then you plot those as lines like this.
All right.
So good luck.
Pause the video switch to Python see if you can get this beautiful little graph and now I am going to
switch to Python and we can work through this together.
All right so I'm going to start by generating this vector x.
So from the NUM pi module the Lynn space function we want to go from minus three to one point eight
three and I'm pretty sure that I used 50 if I remember correctly.
So 50 steps between minus three and one point eighty three.
And then I can generate K and so the function for the natural exponential is e XP like this.
And then whatever you want to put into the exponent of the natural exponential you do inside the function.
So that looks like this.
Okay.
And then the way that I am going to draw that map is in a for loops let's say for I in K and then we
want to draw a line.
So it's gonna be one plot line one plotting command for each of the elements in K.
So P L teed up plot and now the code in here actually looks pretty similar to this code here.
In fact maybe I'll even copy and paste this code.
I just have to be super careful to change all the variables when appropriate.
Okay.
So we want each of these lines to go from the origin.
So that's 0 0 2 cosine and sine so that part's correct except it's not variable angle.
It's each element in K which is variable ie.
In the for loop here.
So I just have to replace this with I.
And then let's just see how this looks.
Okay so this looks kind of good it's a little bit stretched out.
So I want to change a few things in this plot.
So peel that axis square.
All right.
That's looking better.
Except that means that P L T does show.
So this is looking better except the figure that I showed in the slides didn't have this bounding box
and it didn't have the tick marks that ticks around the x axis and the y axis.
So I'm going to set P.L. t the Axis off and that's going to turn off the axis without changing the plot
lines inside the axis.
Very nice.
So in this video you learned about creating unit circles in Python and I hope that you are now a little
bit more confident than you were before about plotting lines and circles in Python.