In the beginning of this section of the course you learned how to solve for variables in an equation
using sympy.
So for example if you say like two x equals three then you can solve for x.
What you're going to learn in this video is an extension of solving using the same function in this
sympy toolbox so sym dot solve.
But now you are going to learn inequalities instead of equalities.
And I'm also going to show you how to indicate infinity in sympy.
So let's get started.
An inequality is an expression that looks something like this: four x is greater than eight.
And so the question is what range of x will make this expression true?
Now the answer here is fairly easy to compute.
All you have to do is isolate X on the left hand side of this equation, and you can do that by dividing
both sides of this equation by 4.
So that gives you x is greater than 2.
So as long as X is greater than 2 this expression will be correct.
Now we get to an expression like this, and your first thought when you see something like this might
be to expand this multiplication and get X squared plus two X minus three greater than zero.
Now that's not really the wrong way to do it but that's not super helpful.
In fact, it turns out the answer is that there are two ranges of X that will satisfy this equation and
the way to think about that is that you have a multiplication of two terms.
And basically you want the multiplication of these two terms to result in a positive number, so greater
than zero.
Now two terms multiplied together will be positive either when both those terms are positive or when
both of those terms are negative.
So as long as one term is not negative and the other one is positive then this will be the case then
this will be true.
So we can think about this term, if this term,
so if X is greater than one, this will always be positive.
And this of course will be positive.
So that's one of the conditions.
The other condition is that if this term is negative and this term can be negative if X is smaller than
minus 3, to cancel out this plus 3, then of course this term will be negative as well.
And then both of these terms are negative leading us to a positive value, which will definitely be greater
than zero.
So that's the two answers to this solution.
Now what I'm going to do is show you how to implement these in a python so that once you've finished
thinking about this problem and working through the answer in your head you can then switch to Python
and confirm that you have thought of the correct answer.
So for this video we are going to need these sympy toolbox and say import sympy as sym, and we are
also going to need the nice display functions that I always use in almost every video.
So import display and math okay.
And now we need a symbolic variable let's go for X because X is a great letter.
It's possibly one of the greatest letters ever invented.
I happen to be partial to the letter X..
So anyway let's define this expression.
So  four times x is greater than eight.
This was the first expression that we started off with.
Now first, I haven't yet showed you that it's even valid to put a greater than or less than sign in an
expression, in a sympy expression.
So first thing that I do is run this code and then print out this expression just to make sure that
this is really a valid operation, which it is.
And so to get the solution to this we type sym dot solve just like you did before when you were solving
for x for example.
But now we just write the equation in here, or the inequality, and that's going to give us this answer.
Now in the slides I only actually showed you this part.
I said as long as X is greater than 2, it might look initially a little confusing, because here it says 2
is less than X but that's the same thing as X is greater than 2.
This is what I showed on the slides.
Now here this is actually giving us an end just ampersand is for and.
So Python, sympy, is actually telling us that there are two conditions.
So X is greater than two.
And also X is less than what is this thing??
This is like oo-oo or just ooh!? Actually this is the way that Python represents infinity.
It is a double lowercase o so X must be greater than 2 and X must be less than infinity
for this expression to be true. So it might seem a little bit strange that we also get this result less
than infinity.
But that's just how sympy gives the output.
Okay.
So now I can make this look slightly nicer.
I think this already looks pretty decent but I'm going to in case this into latex code so sym dot
latex and then the output of solve and here we get basically the same thing except it looks a little
bit nicer. Now this symbol here is called a wedge symbol and, let me write that out.
So it's called wedge.
And in fact the latex code for that would be wedge like this.
And in this case the wedge operator is used to indicate a conjunction.
So X must be greater than 2 and X must be less than infinity.
So to access the infinity or to represent infinity using symp, you type sympy dot 0 0. So the output
is 0 0 and we can see you know is infinity greater then.
I don't know.
Some really large number.
The answer is true.
And you know we can make that number bigger.
The answer of course is true.
Because infinity is larger than any number.
Okay.
Now I'd like to show you the other expression that I showed in these slides, So that was X minus one
times x plus three.
And then this was greater than zero.
And here we can see, let me get rid of this....
And so here we get part of the same answer that I showed before.
So X is less than minus three or x is greater than one.
And then you also see that there are these conductive operators for x is greater than minus infinity
and x is less than infinity.
But mostly you know you can just kind of try to ignore these things and focus on the answers that involve
real numbers.
So X is less than minus three or x is greater than minus one.
All right.
There's some one more thing that I want to show you in this video which is what happens if you don't
provide enough information for the sympy solver to do its job.
So let's see.
I'm going to create new variables A B and C so symbols symbols A B C.
Now let's make our expression B A times X must be greater than B squared divided by C.
So first thing I like to do when I see a mathematical equation that looks like this or an inequality
that looks like this I like to see it written out in latex just so I can interpret it better.
So X is greater than B squared divided by C and now if we just try to solve it let's say sym dot solve.
Now maybe, you know that you want to solve this in terms of x because perhaps you are thinking that X
is like the unknown variable and ABC are just these sort of arbitrary scales that represent any numbers.
However, python is going to give a really long warning here and the warning message says well it's a
non implemented error and it says the inequality has more than one symbol of interest.
Okay so you're probably thinking that the solution is really straightforward and that is simply to say
comma x.
Now in some sense that is true.
We can say comma X and that's telling Python that the variable in this expression that we want to solve
for is x.
However, in this case that didn't actually do anything but return the exact same equation that we started
with.
And the issue here is that sympy,
it just doesn't have enough information to be able to solve for any particular variable.
There are no constraints on, A for example, and that's because as you can see up here, the solution to
inequalities will depend on what these other numbers are.
So if I would just write this you know
so this answer here, x is less than one, that depends on knowing the sign of this number here minus one.
So if I would replace this with a and b then sympy simply doesn't know enough about the constraints
on these variables A and B in order to come up with a specific enough example. And in fact if I try to
run this, I'm pretty sure we're gonna get an error, we get an error and oh okay.
So that's actually the same error.
But now even if I tell sympy that I am interested in X, it's still not able to come up with a solution
and that's really because we haven't provided enough information; we haven't provided enough constraints
and that is generally the case with sympy: if ever you encounter a situation with sympy, where
the output of some function like solve or some other function is literally just re typing the input
expression, then that generally means that sympy doesn't have enough information.
It's not possible to come up with a solution. So here is the exercise for this video.
Essentially, you have this long inequality here with multiple terms on both sides of the equation and
X also on both sides of the equation.
And what you want to do is implement this expression in sympy, and then use the solve function to
find the bounds on X, or the inequality on X, that would satisfy this expression.
So here I am in Python.
I'm going to work through my solution.
If you haven't already paused the video, obviously
Now is your last moment to do it.
Now it turns out that actually this exercise is not so difficult.
It's mostly just keeping track of all the variables, making sure that you are typing it in correctly.
So this was four minus five times x divided by three is less than... now,
I haven't told you in this particular video How to Solve for an inequality that involves less than or
equal to or greater than or equal to.
But I think you've probably figured it out.
All you have to do is attach an equal sign to it.
So this side was two minus.
And then we had in the numerator that was five times two minus X and then divided by four and actually
I think these outer parentheses are not necessary.
Okay let's see.
So I run this code don't get any errors so I haven't made any typographical mistakes.
And so out of curiosity, before moving to the solution, I want to display what this equation looks like
in nice latex formatting.
OK so here we get three --
Huh... look at this: Already we see some differences between what I wrote down here and what sympy actually
printed out.
So that's pretty interesting.
What I encourage you to do is pause the video, or maybe do this after the video ends and get out a piece
of paper and a pencil and work through this side of the equation and make sure that you see how this
expression can be converted into this expression.
And likewise for this side of the equation and this expression.
All right.
That said now we can compute the solutions so sym dot solve X.
Now in theory you could also say comma X, however because X is the only symbolic variable in this expression
you don't actually need the second input
in this case.
So it turns out even though it's a pretty complicated looking inequality, the solution is fairly straightforward.
It's basically just that x is greater than or equal to twenty two divided by seven and out of curiosity.
I wonder what.
Twenty two divided by 17.
Sorry I said seven up here.
Seventeen.
what this number is.
So as long as X is greater than one point to nine for one then this inequality will remain true. So in
this video I showed you how to solve for inequalities.
And I showed you some potential problems or weird things that can arise when you're trying to use sympy.
I also showed you how to represent infinity using sympy.