This video is basically a continuation of the previous video on creating functions in Python.
So if you're not really comfortable with the basics of creating functions in Python then you might want
to go back and re watch the previous video.
All right.
So here is... this is like a challenge.
This is a big exercise, this whole video.
What you want to do is create a function that will take basically three inputs and these should all
be user defined or user specified inputs. So you want to be able to input three numbers from the user
an x value and a y value.
So basically two numbers here. These have to be integers for now: two integers and a function switch.
So let me show you an example of what this looks like.
So Python should say input x.
And here I picked two. Input y.
And here I picked four and then Python should print out some text that looks like this.
It should say press 1 to compute 2 to the 4 or press 2 to compute 2 divided by 4.
So it's the same two numbers.
And basically we're going to specify a function switch and that's going to call either the power function
to take x to the power of y or the division function and that will compute x divided by Y.
So you can see in this case I selected 2, so then Python printed out 2 divided by 4 equals point 5.
So this is one example.
Here you see another example of this function and using this function.
So in this case I inputted 3 and 5, and then the instructions were to print to press either one or two.
But you know I don't always like listening to the instructions; I want to know what happens outside the
boundaries defined by the instructions.
So I press 3 but then Python gave me back this result that said invalid selection.
So I hope this is enough for you to get started.
The hint is don't try to do this all in one function.
You can actually create three separate functions in order to get this to work.
All right.
So what I encourage you to do now is pause the video, work your way through, make sure you can implement
these functions and get output that would look something like this or something like this.
And when you're ready to come back, then come back to the video and I'm now going to switch to Python
and show you how I solved this problem. Before getting into my solution.
I should say a few words about solving problems in Python or more generally using code.
There are often multiple ways to correctly solve a problem using Python or matlab or C or any other
computer language.
So if your solution looks different from my solution that's totally fine.
It's a good idea for you to pay attention to what I'm doing and maybe you can learn from how my solution
differs from your solution.
But as long as you get the right answer, the way that you got to that right answer really doesn't matter.
Okay so what I'm going to do is in this cell create the functions.
So I'm going to create two functions. There's going to be one called Powers and that's going to take this
input x and y and what's going to happen inside this function.
So what this function does is going to be to print out that X to the power of y equals and then whatever
x the power of y is.
So I'm going to use some latex coding to make sure that the printing looks good. I will write display
math.
And then it's goinbg to be x to the Y.
Now remember I'm going to be using latex coding here and in latex,
You indicate a superscript using the caret symbol like this. In Python code,
You use a double asterisk like this.
All right.
So we want this for Python so x to the Y equals and then whatever that happens to be it's gonna be let's
call it z.
So now that I've written out a little bit of code here; now I need to replace these with our integer
place holders that we've been using a lot.
So % G to the power of percent G equals percent G.
And now of course we need to replace all of the
Percent G's here with actual numbers.
There's going to be x to the power of y equals x to the power of y.
Okay.
So I have more functions to do but before getting to the other functions I want to test this one and
make sure that this is correct.
So what I'm going to do is type powers and then let's say two comma four.
Okay so we get an error message and this says name.
Math is not defined.
The math is this function that's being called here and possibly you already caught this before I made
this mistake, before this error happened. The issue here is that the display function and the math
function are not packaged with the default Python environment. So therefore we need to import them.
So from IPython dot display import display and also import math.
Okay.
So now I'm going to run this cell again and then I run this cell and now we get a result.
And furthermore, it's also the correct result which is really good.
So two to the power of four is sixteen.
One way you can think about this is by breaking this up into two squared times two squared.
And that is possible because of the law of exponents which I covered in a previous video.
So two squared is four.
And then two squared again is four and four times four is sixteen.
All right.
So obviously we are not yet finished this project but we're getting there.
So now I want to create the other function.
And that's for divisions. I'm to say def division that will also take as input x and y.
And here I'm also going to display something.
So I'm going to actually copy and paste. Now, whenever you copy and paste code you have to be really careful
that you're correctly changing everything that needs to be changed.
So now this needs to be % G and now this is going to be divided by % G.
But I want this to look like a nice fraction in latex.
So you might remember that to create a fraction in latex you do slash slash frac and then in the first
set of curly brackets is the numerator and then the next set of curly brackets is the denominator.
Now it would be really easy to just stop there and keep going.
In fact I think I even will.
So now I'm going to say... I just ran this cell that runs this line and I'm going to say division here
instead of powers.
Now on the one hand this function runs.
So that's good.
We don't get any error messages or anything, but two divided by four is clearly not sixteen at least
not in our universe.
And the problem here is that I only changed, so I copied and pasted this code but I only changed the display
part here.
I didn't actually change the math.
I didn't change that computation so fortunately it's a pretty simple fix.
We just say x divided by Y.
So run this cell again.
Now I want to run this again just to make sure that we are really getting the right answer.
And you know, it's generally a good idea to test this out over and over again just to see what happens
and confirm that you're getting the right answer.
And out of curiosity I'm going to say four divided by zero.
OK here we get an error it says division by zero.
That is illegal in mathematics.
If you tried to do this the math police are going to come after you.
So I'm going to get rid of that error message as quickly as possible.
OK.
So we are off to a good start.
We've created these two functions and now I'm going to create a third function and that is going to
be the main function that will give the inputs and call one of these two functions depending on what
I specify for inputs.
So because this is the main function I'm actually going to call this main function.
Now this function doesn't actually take any inputs.
Instead, all of the inputs are going to be defined in or I should say the inputs into these functions
will be created inside this main function by inputting from the user.
So let's do that first.
Let's say I get input from user and I write a helpful comment here.
So X equals int input and let's just say input x and then I will copy and paste here and then we get
Y and then we also need a switch variable so we can think about calling this switch and let's see that's
also going to be an input.
So let's say input which algorithm to compute.
So again now this function doesn't really do a whole lot yet.
It just inputs these variables but I would like to run this function just to make sure that it hasn't
produced any errors yet.
So let's call this main function. We see input x I'll call that five; input y let's say three.
Which algorithm to compute.
Well you know we don't know anything yet.
So I'll just do this big number here.
But actually this isn't really what I wrote in the slides in the slides.
I showed that it should print out
nice looking text that gives the two options for whether to compute this or whether to compute this.
So in fact, before getting this input from the user I would like to display a nice message. So display
math.
And then this should say Press one to compute and then I'm actually just going to copy and paste from
here
or press two to compute and then I can copy and paste from here all right.
So we're getting a lot of percent G's in here.
So you have to be really careful that we are keeping track of all of these. So let's see.
So actually it's not so hard the first three.
Oh and you don't... actually, I don't want to give the answer right away.
I just want to give the options, so let's get rid of these equals signs here.
So this is actually easier.
We just need X Y and this one is also x y.
So X comma Y and X comma Y... oops so we need a comma in here.
And then I think we don't need this whole message.
We can just give a space for the user to input.
All right.
So I'm going to run this cell to run this function again.
And now I'm going to run I'm going to call this function again.
So far this isn't going to actually compute any of these things.
I just want to make sure that it's working up until this point.
That's always a good idea when writing code to check that your code is working at each step of the way.
All right.
So I'll just say three here and five here.
Whoops and I already get an error. OK so I actually had to pause the video and look at this for a good
10 seconds before I figured out what was actually going wrong.
This was a really simple mistake.
I just had this parentheses in the wrong place, this percent sign and all of this business.
These replacements for the percent, they need to go immediately after this
end quote here.
So in fact it just needs to go there be parentheses was in the wrong place.
All right.
So let's try this again.
And so let's try three and two and this kind of looks OK.
OK.
Let me just finish running this except this is in italics and there's no spaces in here.
So it looks a little bit awkward.
Now what we need to do here is tell latex to print out this stuff like normal text, here it's trying to
print it out like variables and it's ignoring the spaces.
So we write slash slash text and then in curly brackets everything we want to make as text.
So let me just show you what this looks like.
So I input four and three and now this part looks good here, and this part doesn't look good here.
So we need more text so slash slash text or press 2 to compute and then another end curly bracket.
So
let's input about just three and two.
Now it says press 1 to compute three to the power of two or plus press two to compute three divided
by two.
All right.
So this is looking good.
We are almost finished here.
The last thing we need to do is call either the powers function or the division function, or print out
an invalid selection warning message, depending on the value of switch.
So for this we need an if statement.
So if switch equals, now up here I converted the variable x that was input it from a string into an integer.
And likewise here for y but here I didn't.
So in fact switch is going to be a string.
It's not going to be a [number] variable.
So this should say 1 like this the string one, not the number one.
So if the switch input was 1 then we called Powers X comma Y and here we say else if or else if switch
was equal to two if we input two, then we call Division inputting X comma Y else.
So if neither of these is true.
So if switched does not equal one and if it does not equal two, then the result is we will print out
invalid selection.
All right.
Okay.
Three exclamation points is probably a little bit overkill.
So I'm going to run that cell to recompile all this code and I'm going to type.
Main function.
I'm going to press control enter and let's try this with the code that are the numbers that I used in
the slide.
So 2 and 4 and we press 1 and we get two to the power of 4 is 16.
Brilliant.
Now I want to try 2 and 4 and I'm going to press 2 and we should get that 2 divided by 4 is 1 1/2.
And finally I'm going to say 2 and 4 and let's say 3 and we get invalid selection.
Very nice.
The last thing I want to cover in this video is how to change this from integers into any other number
that can have a decimal point.
And as a reminder of how this will crash I'm going to say two point three instead of two and we already
get an error.
Okay so turns out that the solution here is pretty straightforward.
We just type float instead of int. So float is a different class of number, int is for integer.
And those are just whole numbers like 1 2 3 4 and so on.
Float is for floating point numbers and that means that they can have a decimal point in them.
So now we're going to run this cell again run this cell again and let's see two point three to the power
of four point one.
Okay so now we get the option to choose two point three of the power four point one or this thing and
let's say I'm going to press 1 because I'm quite curious what in the world this number is going to be.
All right.
So two point three to the power of four point one is thirty point four one for seven.
Pretty interesting piece of knowledge to have.
Great.
So I hope you are starting to feel more confident in your ability to create and use functions in python
as a way to help you learn mathematics. In the next video,
we are going to create a game using functions.
It's going to be really exciting and I look forward to seeing you then.