The topic of this video is the singular value decomposition which is often abbreviated as S V D so singular
value decomposition.
I'm going to show you the big picture of the SVOD and then we'll spend most of the time working in Python.
I will show you how to perform an SVOD and a little bit about how to interpret the results of an SVOD
and you will also learn about how to import pictures into the python workspace.
So let's begin.
Here is a rather daunting looking picture.
This is the big overview of the s the D.
So we start with some matrix A maybe that's a picture that's what I'll show in a moment.
When we switched to Python maybe it's a data matrix.
Now this matrix does not need to be square like with Icon decomposition.
So the idea of SVOD is to decompose this matrix A into the product of three other matrices.
Those matrices are called U Sigma and V transpose so you and V transpose are a little bit like the Ion
vectors in the sense that they point in directions that are invariant to multiplication by matrix A
and they identify important features or components in this matrix and these Sigma matrix is a diagonal
matrix so it's all zeros except for the diagonal elements which are going to contain non-zero values.
Those are called these singular values of matrix A and these singular values are a little bit like the
eigenvalues that you learned about in a previous video.
Now there is a ton to be said about the theory and applications and all the nitty gritty details of
SVOD how you create these matrices how to interpret them exactly how to use them in practical analysis
and so on but in the context of this video and this course the main idea is that The Matrix you and
the matrix v transpose are identifying features or patterns in Matrix a for a picture.
Those are like spatial patterns in the matrix and the singular values correspond to the importance of
those patterns.
So some patterns are more important and some patterns are less important.
Okay.
So with that said as a brief introduction let's switch to Python and have a look at what the LCD looks
like so we are going to need num pi and matte plot lib and I'm also going to import another function
from P I l import image with a capital I.
This is a function that we are going to use to import a picture from the disk.
So along with the code that you got for this section of the course you also got a JPEG file and that's
called so image dot open.
It's called Einstein dot j peg like this.
Okay.
So now I'm going to run this notice.
Didn't get any errors and give me Python warnings or messages and let's see what I and looks like.
I'm going to just look at these shapes so print.
Pi dot shape and then I'm.
So we see that this is a four hundred and five by three hundred and fourteen by three matrix.
So this corresponds to the rows and columns of the picture and the three.
Here this third dimension corresponds to the RG B or red green blue channels.
So we can view this image using P L T that I am show and P L T dot show.
Okay.
So here is this picture of Einstein you've probably seen this picture before.
It's a pretty famous one.
Now as I mentioned in the slides a moment ago these singular value decomposition is built for a two
dimensional matrix or matrix that has rows and columns not a cube of data.
If you want to decompose cubes or tensor is of data then you need to use different kinds of methods.
So what we need to do is basically get rid of this third dimension here and the way that I'm going to
do that is simply by averaging over the color dimension.
And that's going to transform this picture from having our G.B. intensities at each pixel even though
it's a grayscale map it still has RG B values and instead it's just going to be an intensity image.
So we're going to get the intensity of the image.
So the total brightness of the image at each pixel.
So the way that I'm going to do that is by simply replacing the matrix ion.
So this variable with itself except it's going to be the means.
So no I don't mean of iron and then I'm adding a comma to here because I want to average over dimension
number two.
So this would be the zero with dimension the first dimension and the second dimension here.
So the colored dimension so and then actually I'm gonna put this line before the print sign.
OK.
So now we see a couple of changes.
First of all we lose the three here.
So this is now just a two dimensional matrix and now we have also lost the color scaling or the gray
scaling so we just see this image in intensity.
Now I'm going to compute the singular value decomposition.
So the function is known pi.
Lin ouch dot SVOD and then we input the matrix and now there's going to be three outputs they are in
order.
S sorry you comma s comma V.
So this is the U matrix.
This is the singular values.
And then this is the V matrix.
Now it's interesting to have a look at these things so I'm going to print out the shape num Pi the shape
of you and then repeat this for S and V.
So here is V and here is s.
So you see that you and v are both square matrices but they're not the same size as the original matrix
in fact you is a square matrix and that is the number of columns and V is a square matrix that corresponds
to the number of rows and s here is actually not a matrix it's just a vector.
So in the slides I illustrated that s was a diagonal matrix but here num pi just exported these second
variable as a vector.
So what I'd like to do now is show some images of these three matrices and I'm also gonna need to convert
this into a matrix.
So let's see I'm going to show this in subplots that are all next to each other.
So p t that subplots this is going to be a one by three geometry three because we have three matrices.
So let's see in the first axis we make an image of you and I will set the title to be set.
Title you.
Okay.
And then the next one we have was let's see.
So then the first index is going to be s and we're gonna have to figure out a way to fix this.
I'm also going to make the title be later coding for Sigma.
So this is going to give us the uppercase Greek letter sigma and then here we have v and that's also
called V over here.
Okay.
P L T the show and then I notice almost made a mistake here.
Oh maybe I did actually make a mistake.
So you plotted correctly and then it crashed at plotting.
S It says invalid dimensions for image data.
That's the key part of this error message here.
We're trying to make an image but this is actually just a vector.
So what we want to do is convert this into a diagonal matrix.
So I'm going to write MP dot the bag of S and now we see the you matrix the V matrix and the Sigma matrix.
Now it doesn't really look like there's anything here it looks like.
You don't really see any thing on the diagonal or off the diagonal.
And that's really because of the scaling of these segments.
And I'm going to show you the scaling in a moment but for now what I want to do is just take the log
of these values so end PDA log and really all this is doing is compressing down the really really large
values so that the large values and the small values are all more or less in the same scale.
So here you see a square matrix that corresponds to Sigma.
Now what I showed in the slides is actually not a matrix of this size I showed in the slides that Sigma
is actually a matrix.
That's the same size as the image.
It's still a diagonal matrix but it's the same size as the image.
So this is actually probably not really the right way to represent Sigma and that is something that
you should keep in mind in the exercises.
But before getting to the exercises I want to explore this Sigma a little bit more.
So these singular values and in particular what I'm going to do is plot them.
So let's say plot s and I'm going to make this black squares and with a marker face equal to whites.
So let's see what this thing looks like.
Whoops.
What did I do wrong.
Right.
This should be marker face color.
Apologies for that.
Okay.
So here you see all of these segments.
And you can see that most of them are really really really really tiny.
And a couple of them are large and there's one that's huge.
So in fact I would like to zoom in here a little bit.
So let's say peel T dot X limb.
Let's go from about zero to 50.
Let's see how that looks.
So zero actually cuts off this one a little bit.
How about minus one to 50.
Okay.
And then I'll put in a title because I want you to see what this is called.
So this thing when you make a plot of these singular values it is often called an icon spectrum.
And I'll even call this an icon spectrum of Einstein.
So I again spectrum that's what this sort of thing is typically called.
Now what does this mean.
What do these numbers mean.
Well as I mentioned in the slides the idea is that there are patterns that are encoded into the columns
of you and the rows of V transpose and those patterns are telling us about the important features of
this picture.
This matrix here now the patterns that are stored in U and V transpose don't have any importance.
They just have a direction.
So they just point to a pattern in the matrix.
It's these singular values that identify the importance of each feature.
So what this is telling us is that there is one big spatial feature that's really prominent in this
image.
And then there's a couple more maybe like half a dozen maybe there's six or seven features that are
also pretty important in this picture in this matrix.
And then there's a lot of other features in the data that just aren't really important.
They don't take up a lot of variance in the picture.
Now this ability of the singular value decomposition to identify important features that are distributed
across a matrix or across the data set is exactly why the SVOD and the icon value decomposition are
so important in machine learning and A.I. in this video I introduced you to the big picture idea of
the SVOD.
Of course there are many details and subtleties and applications of the SVOD that I just don't have
time to get into.
But I hope you at least get a bit of a sense of what the SVOD can do.
And if you want to learn more about working with the SVOD then keep watching because the next video
will contain an exercise that will allow you to explore the effects of using the SVOD to reconstruct
the Einstein picture.
So I will see you in a moment.