This video contains the exercise corresponding to the SVOD or the singular value decomposition.
Following up from the previous video.
So what you want to do is bring Einstein back from the dead.
Okay.
That's not really true.
What you want to do in the first of three exercises is reconstruct the original image from the SVOD
so you might need to consult the formula that I showed in the slides in the previous video in order
to successfully complete that.
But essentially what you want to do is make sure that multiplying the three SVOD matrices together will
reproduce the original Einstein matrix and then once you've done exercise 1 then exercise 2 is essentially
to repeat exercise 1 except you are shuffling these singular values so you're basically changing the
order of the singular values and that shuffles the order or the mapping between each spatial pattern
that the SPDC has identified and the importance of that spatial pattern and then exercise 3 is also
following up on exercise one and there you want to partially reconstruct Einstein so not fully reconstructed
but partially reconstruct Einstein using only the first n components.
And by this I mean that you only use the first and singular values so to solve Exercise 3 you're basically
going to do something that's really similar to exercise one except the Sigma matrix or the Matrix the
diagonal matrix that contains the singular values you only want to include.
Let's say the first 10 singular values and the rest of them will be zeros.
All right.
So switch to Python.
Write some code.
Good luck.
Keep in mind this is a bit of a challenging exercise particularly if you are not already familiar with
the SVOD operation.
Nonetheless I encourage you to try your best and then when you're ready come back to the video and you
can watch me walk through my solution so I have open here all the code that I wrote in the previous
video and that's important because in this video basically we need everything that was already computed
here.
The SVOD importing the Einstein picture and so on.
So let's see.
I'm going to start with exercise 1 and that was just about perfectly reconstructing the original matrix
so the Einstein picture from the result of the SVOD.
So what we want is something like reconstructed Einstein and depending on you know your hobbies and
what language you natively speak you might pronounce this as a rain like what you would attach to a
horse to guide it in direction or maybe if you're a German or a German or file.
This might be your aim which is like clean or pure anyway or maybe it's just arbitrary.
I'm using this to be reconstructed Einstein.
So what we want is something like you matrix multiplication with S matrix multiplication with V.
Now the problem is that I haven't yet created this matrix S this needs to be the diagonal matrix containing
these singular values.
However if you tried to make this pretty simple and say something like num PI that dialog of little
ask these singular values in a vector then this is not going to work.
You're going to get some dimension mismatches and that's because let's see so print num Pi the shape
of S and print num pi shape V.
And also so I guess it's you that we want here.
So we are trying to multiply this matrix U which is 4 0 5 by 4 or 5.
So the inner dimensions here do not match.
So what we need to do instead is say that this matrix S is going to be a zeros matrix and the size has
to correspond to the shape of matrix A up CI A.
This should be fine.
Okay so now you can see I ran this cell of code we didn't get any errors.
There were no Python errors of course.
This is also just a matrix of zeros because this is a matrix of zeros.
So what we need to do now is populate the diagonal of this matrix according to the individual elements
of the singular vectors.
So to make this very clear I'm going to do this in a loop.
So I equals our eye in range that goes from zero to the length of S..
And remember now this is lowercase s so I'm going to specify that s I comma I.
So the diagonal the I.S. diagonal element is the ISF element in S and then I run this code again and
let's see I'm going to make a image.
So let's do P.L. T dot subplot one comma to come a one an appeal to you that I am show.
Let's show the original matrix here on the left and I will turn the Axis off and let's see the plot
title will be that this is the original matrix.
Okay.
So now this is not super amazing.
This is what we've seen before.
Now I'm going to copy and paste a bunch of this code.
Now in the second subplot this is going to be crime or the reconstructed Einstein.
And now these look really really really similar.
In fact they are identical.
Whoops.
And then this should be of course the SVOD version.
There you go.
OK so that is for the first of three exercises.
And what I'm going to do next is the second exercise and I'm just gonna keep can continue with this
same code here.
So my strategy here is going to be to keep all of this code the same.
And what I'm going to do up here is shuffle.
So I'm going to say shuffle the order of the singular values.
So to do this I'm gonna come up with a random shuffling orders.
Let's say Rand order equals NPD at random and I'm going to use a function called permutation and that's
going to be length of s.
So before going any further let me just print out what actually I guess a better way to introduce this
to you would be to print this out in smaller numbers.
So instead of the length of ask.
Because that's quite long.
I'm going to say let's go for five.
So NPD a random permutation five so you can see that this gave us the numbers 4 0 2 3 1.
So it's numbers 0 through 5 exclusive and it looks like it's a random order.
So here now it's a different order.
And notice that each of these numbers appears exactly once.
So what this function permutation is doing is shuffling the order of integers from zero to whatever
this number is minus one.
Okay.
So with that in mind now I can show you this variable Rand order and.
Well it's just a bunch of integers that are randomized.
So that means that now instead of reconstructing these two B S or the I.S. element of S this is going
to be the rand order highest element.
So that means for this particular run what should be the first singular value is actually replaced with
the one hundred and sixty fifth singular value.
And of course that number is going to change and each run because this is just totally random each time
I run this code.
Okay.
So I hope that makes sense.
Essentially we are not changing you and we're not changing V and we're also not really changing all
the elements in s all we're doing is shuffling the order which means changing the mapping of the singular
values which indicate the importance of different features of the data with the spatial patterns that
are encoded in U and V.
Okay.
And you can see that even though we haven't changed you and we haven't changed v just by changing the
order of the singular values we've really totally screwed up this image.
This is obviously just noise unrecognizable.
Okay.
So that was for the second exercise.
What I want to do now is basically undo what I just did.
And that's quite simple I just get rid of this variable by the way notice that I didn't actually reassign
s and that was important because if I had reassigned s itself.
So if I just shuffled all the elements and asked and I would actually lose the original order of the
singular values.
So here we haven't actually lost any information by going through the second exercise.
Okay.
So what I'm gonna do now is reconstruct this picture using only the first ten components and the way
that I'm going to do that is by initializing this matrix to zeros which I already do but then populating
the diagonals of this matrix not with all of these singular values but instead just lets say the first
how about the first 20 and let's see what this looks like.
Okay.
So that's pretty interesting.
We see that this picture is still definitely recognizable as Einstein sticking out his tongue.
It's a little bit fuzzier but we can still recognize it.
Okay.
Let's go for.
How about the first 10 mm hmm.
I think it's still pretty recognizable we're starting to lose some subtle features but still easily
recognizable.
How about let's see.
Actually I want to scroll up here.
So here we see the singular value.
So let's try one two three four five six.
It looks like there's six relatively large components or features and the rest of them are are smaller.
So let's see if Einstein is still recognizable.
With only six features and I think so maybe it looks more like a baby.
This is like Baby Einstein.
Let's even see what is this first component so I'm just gonna do.
Number one.
Okay so that's pretty interesting because what the singular value decomposition is telling us that this
one feature the first largest feature the first component of this matrix is actually just as really
low spatial frequency feature that just says that you know the image is really bright around here and
it's really dark around here.
Okay so the last thing that I want to do which actually wasn't specified in the instructions but I think
it's pretty interesting just to explore around is to say instead of using just the first and components
let's use the last and components.
So what if I look at 10 to the length of s.
So this means I'm ignoring the first 10 components and reconstructing the image using all of the later
components which means basically all of these really really small features of the data.
Ha so that's pretty interesting.
It looks like a high spatial pass filtered version of the image so you can see a lot of the edges here.
But you don't see a lot of the like really low spatial frequency the broad features in the signal.
So I am going to call this the successful completion of this project this exercise.
Obviously I encourage you to continue playing around with this code to try to gain some intuition about
what the SVOD does in this and the previous video.
You gain some insight into the singular value decomposition and importantly you learned how to use python
as a tool to explore these kinds of Matrix compositions.
And of course as a side bonus you also learn how to import pictures like J pegs in this particular case
into the python workspace to work with pictures as matrices.