In this video I'm going to tell you about factoring polynomials.
So let me first tell you what it means to factor a polynomial.
And before telling you how about factoring polynomials I'm going to tell you about factoring integers.
We can take the number four and represent four as the multiplication of two other numbers: 2 and 2.
So what we're doing is taking this larger number and expressing it as the product of simpler terms.
That's the general idea of factoring.
So here we can also take 16.
Now you can represent 16 as being two times eight.
But the number eights of course can be factored or broken down into four times two.
And of course four, as you learned here, and I'm sure you knew even before this course, four can be represented
as two times two.
So we can also factor the number 16 into two times two times two times two.
OK.
So that's just a general principle of factoring. Applied to polynomials, the concept is the same.
It's a little bit more challenging but the idea is that this polynomial can be represented as the product
of two terms.
One of those terms is X plus 1.
And the other term is x plus three and you can do the math fairly quickly in your head to confirm that
these are equal.
So X times X is X squared and then X times three is three x plus one times X gives us four X and then
one times three gives us three.
Now when you learn about factoring polynomials in a math course, then there are some tricks that you
can learn to help you figure out whether a polynomial is factorable and how to do this; things like completing
the square and so on.
But in this video I'm going to show you how to get Python to do this for you.
So let's start by creating some symbolic variables x and y because later on in a few moments I'm going
to create some multi variable polynomials.
So we need X comma Y.
So let's just start by taking a simple polynomial p and let's set this to be X squared plus four times
x plus three.
So that's in fact the same polynomial that I just showed in the slides. So I can just print this out
like this or I can use sym dot factor.
So this function factor and that is going to express this polynomial this polynomial as one plus or
so x plus 1 times x plus three.
Now you've probably learned in your math course that not every polynomial can be factored like this.
Only some polynomials can be factored.
They have to be, you know, they have to have the right coefficients and so forth.
So for example if we would say minus three instead of plus three.
Now it turns out that this polynomial on its own is no longer factorable.
And now what's going to happen when we put this polynomial as input into the factor function?
And the answer is that we just get back exactly the same result.
And this is a feature of sympy that I've introduced you to in previous videos.
So if you want simply to do something like factor or expand or simplify but it's just not possible with
the input that you've given it, then the output will be exactly the same as the input.
So this polynomial is not factorable.
It is as simple as it gets already written out like this.
And so the output of the Factor function is just the same as the input.
All right.
The next thing that I want to show you is factoring a polynomial with multiple variables.
So let's say two times X cubed times Y minus two times X squared plus two times X squared times Y plus
six times X squared minus six times X times Y.
Now it may actually seem like I'm just making this stuff up as I go along but actually I've already
worked through this problem to make sure that this polynomial in fact is factorable in two variables.
So let's see what that looks like.
So sym dot factor and then we input expr like this.
Okay.
And now you can see that the simplified version looks, or the factored version is a little bit simpler.
And in fact what you can see here, which you can also see when looking at this original equation, is that
there is a two X in every term.
So there's a 2 x here and you pulled out and you get X squared there's a 2 x term here and you got 2
times X that's actually this term here.
And then you might think that this is a mistake because there's a minus sign here and there's no minus
sign here.
However, we have this other term here six X squared.
And so the two X comes out of this leaving us with three X..
And then that gets subtracted from one X leaving us with plus two X.
Of course I encourage you to get out a piece of paper and a pencil and confirm that this expression
really equals this expression.
But the main point is that factoring in sympy is pretty straightforward.
You use the factor function.
So here is the exercise for this video.
Essentially what you want to do is write out these three expressions and determine whether each of these
expressions is factorable or not factorable.
If it is factorable, then you can display the factors like this; and if it's not factorable then you can
print out this message that says that it's not factorable.
Now I'm going to give you two hints. As in previous exercises, if you don't want any hints; if you want
to see if you can figure all this stuff out on your own,
then now is your last opportunity to pause the video before I reveal the hints and switch to Python
and work through this on your own.
OK.
So the first hint is that factored polynomials have a parenthesis in them.
This is not a typo.
I'm not missing the end parenthesis here.
This is actually just indicating an open parenthesis. So you can see these polynomials here are not factored
and they have no parentheses.
These polynomials have parentheses in them.
OK so that is one hint.
If you think that that's a good enough hint for you to get started again.
Now you can pause the video. Otherwise, I'm going to give you another hint, which is based on just expanding
on this point a little bit more.
Okay.
Here is the next hint: the next hint is to convert the polynomial into a string and then use a method
on a string called find, so the string and then dot find.
So those are your two hints.
And now I'm going to switch to Python.
And first I will introduce you to this method a little bit. I don't believe I've talked about this in
the course so far, so I'll spend a minute basically showing how to use this dot find thing and then we
will solve the problem.
So here.
So let's start with a string.
How about a name equals Mike.
Okay.
So now I can.
So we can just write out a name and we get Mike.
I'm going to say name dot find and actually even better.
So this is not really how you spell my name with an extra i.
But that's okay.
So let's find the "i" in this string.
So the result here is one.
And that tells me that the string the character I appears at least once in this string and the first
or the index where it first appears is index 1.
And remember that Python starts indexing at zero starts counting at zero.
So index of 1 actually means the second element.
Okay.
And then I can go through this for other strings.
For example is in the second element here.
And let's see what if I do.
How about Q?
So now you can see that Q is not in this string at all.
So then we get a result of minus one.
So therefore, if the output of some string variable dot find is minus one then that means that that character
doesn't appear anywhere in this string.
Okay.
So with that introduction in mind, the first thing I'm going to do is create a list of all of these expressions.
So the first expression was X squared plus four times x plus three.
And then a second expression was two times Y squared minus one.
And then the third expression was three times Y squared plus twelve y.
Okay.
And now what I want to do is loop through all of these expressions.
So for X, let's call this ei in expressions. And what I'm going to do is factor the expression and then
export that as a string.
So let's call that string fact for the string version of the factor.
So that's going to be some that factor and then e I for the E I s expression inside this list here and
then this has to be converted into a string.
Now for starters I'm just going to print out this strfact just to see what this looks like.
Okay so what you can see is that the first term was factored, the third term was factored, the second
term was not factored; it's printed out here.
Exactly as I've written it up here.
So therefore what I can do is say, let's say I'm going to say if string facts dot find, if there is an
opening parenthesis, which there is for the factored cases but not for the non-factorable polynomial.
So if this equals... Well actually we want to say if it's not equal to minus one.
So if it's not equal to minus one then that means that it is factorial.
So therefore I'm going to write display math and then I want to print out the expression and
then have an arrow, so right arrow, and then I want to print out the expanded or the factored version.
Okay.
So we therefore need to replace these two strings with sym dot latex ei and then sym dot latex
sym dot factor.
So the factored version of E I.
All right.
So let me just run this code so far and see if this works.
So this looks pretty good.
So here we see the expression.
Here we see the expression and then a friendly little right arrow and then the factored version of that
expression.
So these are a little bit close I'm going to put in a quad here and quad over here just to give us a
little bit more space.
I think that looks visually a little bit nicer.
Okay.
So now if this is not true that means that it's not factorable; the polynomial is not factorable.
So therefore we want to say, let's see I'll copy and then paste this and start working from here.
So we want to say the polynomial... a bit of a space... the
right
arrow and then I'm going to say in text
not factorable.
OK so now we only have one substitution, one string replacement.
So I'm going to get rid of this here and let me make sure I've gotten the parentheses correct.
Yeah this looks good.
All right.
So now we have solved this problem. So in this video I told you about factoring a polynomial and in general
what it means to factor a number or polynomial when you get to linear algebra.
You can factor a matrix.
It's a similar concept and you learned how to do this in Python.
And you also learned about finding string searching through a string for specific characters.