This video contains the exercise that follows up on the previous video of computing the area between
two curves.
Now what I've done here is write some markup code and latex code and I did it all in an AI Python notebook
and so essentially your goal in this exercise is to reproduce what I what you see here.
So what I wrote here so you can see it's a mix of large bold text and normal sized text.
There's latex code that appears in the same line as the regular text and there's also latex code that
appears on its own line like this.
And this.
So essentially you want to write text markup code that will reproduce exactly what you see here.
So computing the area between two functions.
The area between two functions is given by the formula a the integral between A and B.
F of X minus G of X d x.
In our example f of x is x squared G of X is X therefore a is the integral from A to B of the quantity.
X squared minus X.
D X we will compute the area between two crossing points.
That is where the two functions are equal.
This is given by two solutions to the equation x squared equals x.
And of course you know that there has to be two solutions to this equation because of the fundamental
theorem of algebra and I introduced you to that concept in the section on algebra.
I think it was algebra 2.
So the two solutions are 0 and 1 and that gives the integral of a equals the integral from 0 to 1 of
x squared minus x d x.
The final answer will be given in the code below 0.
I don't see any code below that means that it's your job to write the code below.
So what I want you to do after you've finished getting a nicely formatted text that looks like this
is two things First of all I want you to solve analytically for the intersection points.
Now we know that it's 0 and 1 but I want you to use simplify functions to show that it's 0 and 1 and
then you can print that out using LaTeX code and then of course you have to compute the area and you
should also report that out with latex code.
Okay so good luck.
See how you can do reproducing exactly this cell of text and now I'm going to switch to Python.
And in case you have any uncertainty then you can watch me come up with a solution.
So I'm gonna leave this picture here because this is the area that we are trying to compute.
Okay so the first thing that I'm going to do is go to this menu option here and change the property
of this cell from code to markdown.
So now to get that larger bold text that's three hash marks and then computing computing.
Come on computing the area between two functions and I'm already going to press control enter so you
can see how that looks and that looks quite different from you know if I would just write the same thing
here.
Well I'll just write texts here now in this case that just stays looking like comments.
And that's because this is Python code in this cell.
This cell is not markdown code.
All right.
So now this is just gonna be normal text so we can just start typing.
We don't need any special characters in front like this.
So the area between
two functions is given by the formula.
Now here I want to have latex coding inline with the text.
So I use a single dollar sign a equals it and then the subscript will be a and the superscript will
be B and then we have f of x minus G of X D X and then we need to add another single dollar sign so
that latex or that Python knows when to stop interpreting as later code.
And you remember I think I made a mistake about this in a previous video.
Okay so I just ran this cell again just to test that this looks how I want it to look and maybe if you
want you know you can put some square brackets in here like this just a group these together.
That's not necessary but maybe you prefer it that way.
All right.
In our example here more later.
Code F of X equals X squared.
And remember that the carat symbol here is the latex code for the super description or getting a power
C and G of X equals X.
Okay.
And notice that every time I write a little bit of text and latex code I'm evaluating the cell and pressing
control enter on my keyboard in order to check that it looks good.
Okay so let's see therefore.
Therefore I just want to copy this latex code here and replace the generic formulas of F of X with these
specific functions that we have here.
And now I could write x squared minus X but because X squared is underneath it's gonna be a little bit
awkward to write x squared minus X because then we're gonna end up with a negative area which isn't
technically incorrect but it does make more sense to set up this problem to make sure we get a positive
area.
So therefore I'm actually gonna write G of X minus f of x which is x minus X squared
okay.
And again that looks pretty good.
I would say Okay so let's see there's a little bit more text here.
I'm going to uh just copy from my other monitor and paste in here just so that you don't need to watch
me type this whole thing out.
I'll probably make a bunch of embarrassing typos and feel ashamed and get bright red in the face and
so on.
Okay.
What we want now is a little bit of latex code for a formula in its own separate line so not inline
formulas like this but formulas on their own line and the way you do that is by using two dollar signs
instead of one dollar sign.
So this is X squared equals x.
And now notice what's going to happen when I format this markdown cell by pressing control enter this
formula.
Here is all the way on the left but now because I've given it to Dollar Signs on either side it actually
gets center the text gets centered in the final output.
Okay so let's see the two solutions are x equals zero and X equals 1.
And now I left the dollar sign off on this one just to show you the difference between late tech mathematical
formatting and just regular text formatting so you can see this one looks a little bit nicer it's not
a huge deal.
Either way is is generally okay.
All right.
So dollar sign dollar sign.
This gives the definite an integral of.
And now here I want to have something that looks like this again except this is also going to be on
its own line.
So therefore I'm going to use two dollar signs and the only difference here is that we now know these
these specific bounds.
So it's gonna be between 0 and 1 0 right.
That looks pretty good except you know square brackets are useful here because I'm using parentheses
here so I'm going to actually replace this with parentheses and also down here.
I think this will look a little bit more professional.
This looks a little bit more mathy to have the parentheses like this.
All right.
So that's for the markup so this looks really nice.
This looks professional.
This is the kind of thing that you could just immediately print too you know for example PDA.
And then submit as a report in a course.
Okay.
So now I said we need to do two things in Python or actually in simple mostly.
And that is to solve formulae for where these two functions intersect.
So let's create a variable F G.
This should be not in quotes f g I call it intersect and what are we going to do here.
Well what we want to solve is for basically X minus X squared equals zero.
That's just another way of writing X squared equals x so x squared minus x equals zero.
Or you could have the minus sign any other way it doesn't change the answer so to do that I'm going
to use the solve function in the simple module and here we write simply some f minus some G.
Now I already created these symbolic variables in the previous videos so this is all the code from the
previous video.
So if you're starting here fresh and you have a clean workspace from the previous video then you will
need to run some of this code over again.
OK.
And let's see what these are.
So I want to print this out in a nice latex code.
So this is going to say display math.
I'm going to write F of X and G of X more text
intersect at X equals.
And now actually let's even have a look at what this thing is.
So f g intersect Okay so we get a list of two numbers zero and one and that confirms what we calculated
in our heads.
And here this looks good.
So X equals we want a substitution.
So percent G and percent G.
So here we need two substitutions and that's going to be f g intersect 0 and f g intersect one.
All right.
Looks almost almost perfect except I have text in here and I forgot to embed that in the latex code
for text.
So let's see.
All right.
Now that looks pretty good.
And now we get to the final conclusion.
If I had a drum I would do a drum roll here.
Let's see.
So now we want to compute compute the area this is like the whole thing that we're building up to over
the past two videos.
So the area I will call that variable a because that's what I call it here.
So we want to compute the definite integral so that's going to be sim that integrate and what is the
function.
Well it's actually the difference between two functions.
So it's Sim G.
Remember we're actually going to compute G minus F so Sim G minus M F and this is our function.
And then in this tuple here as the second input into the integrate function we write the variable that
we are integrating with respect to which is x and then we write the bounds for the definite interval
our integral.
So we could write 0 and 1 but I'm going to make this a little bit fancier and say f g intersect 0 and
f g intersect 1.
Okay.
And let's see what that area is.
Okay so that area happens to be 1 6.
And if that sounds familiar then that's probably because this is you know a pretty typical problem to
work through in the beginning of a semester long course on integration so you will often come across
this number 1 6.
All right.
And so let's print this out that will be the last thing we do here.
So display math and I will write in text the area between these functions is 10 percent G and whoops.
But that goes outside the text and then we go.
Percent a okay.
So I said this was gonna be the final thing but I do want to point out two small things one is that
noticed that when I set this formatting to be a G then this a gets converted into a number which means
it is point 1 6 6 6 6 6 and then a 7 somewhere at the end.
But if I were to make this s so it gets formatted as a string then we actually get the symbolic answer
of 1 6.
So that's one thing I want to point out.
The second thing I want to point out is that if you would reverse this and set this to be so not this
that should still be the same bounds.
I meant to reverse this.
So if we make this f minus G instead of G minus f then we get the magnitude of the area is the same
but the sine becomes negative.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
I think there were two main take home points from the previous video and this video.
One of course is about computing the area between two functions.
And the second one which is also really important is to give you an example of writing something like
a short report.
This is a beautiful formatted report that you can hand in to your teacher and he or she will be very
very impressed.
And if they're not impressed then you tell me to talk to me and I will make them be impressed.