This video is a bug hunt.
So what you have to do is go through this code, look through each cell and basically run the cell and
try to figure out what the problem is.
Every one of these cells contains at least one problem.
Sometimes there is a full blown error -- you will get an error message in Python -- and there'll be a couple
of other cases where you don't really get an error but it's probably not doing what you want the code
to do.
So in those cases you have to do a little bit of guesswork to try to guess what....
whoever wrote the code (i.e. me) was intending to be done with it.
All right.
So if you haven't already gone through this code then now is your chance to pause the video and go through
it.
Because now I will start going through cell by painful cell.
All right.
So let's see.
So my approach is just going to be to run each cell and then start looking at the error.
All right.
So this error is about,
so it's coming from this line.
It's coming from the first line.
Now maybe you think that the error happened because we didn't yet import these sympy module.
However, in this case I'm not actually importing the entire module, or we don't need to import the entire
module.
We are importing only x2 from part of the module ABC.
But actually it turns out that you can only import single letters, so either
so we have two options here.
Either we change this from X2 into x, and now it's going to work.
I can type x here or I would have to,
Let me see it.
Undo. I'll leave this... or this can be x 2.
But then I would need to say X to equals sym dot symbols, and then X2 like this.
Now in that case this is also not going to work.
Sym is not defined because I haven't yet imported the sympy toolbox.
However, you can see that we're going to need the sympy module further down below.
So I'm also just going to import sympy as sym.
All right.
So now that also works.
So now we get to the next one and let's run that and see what happens.
OK.
Name D is not defined.
That's a pretty simple one to fix.
We can say comma D and here comma D.
All right.
So that one looks good.
Here we see import math.
And then we were using the greatest common denominator function to determine the greatest common denominator
between these two numbers.
So that seems like it should be fine.
And you learned that the G C D function is in fact contained inside the math module... oops but we get
named G C D is not defined.
So we have two options for fixing this. One, which is my preferred option,
I think this is the best way to do it, to type math dot to make it clear that G C.D. is in the math
module.
So that one works.
Another way to do it would be to say from math import G C D.
And then we don't need this here.
So now this is actually importing the G C D function from the math module and then this gets imported
directly into the main workspace of Python.
Now this is also fine.
The reason why this is a slightly less preferred solution is that this now means that G D cannot be
used as a variable or shouldn't be used as a variable because we are having it be this G C D function
from the math module.
Furthermore, there are other cases which you will see in fact you've already seen this and you will continue
to see this as use python more and more, that different modules can have functions of the same name but
they might operate slightly differently.
For example, there is numpy dot square root and there is scipy dot square root and there is sympy
dot square root.
There might also be a math dot square root.
Yeah.
So there you go: the square root function exists in at least four modules.
Maybe there are even more that I'm not aware of at the moment.
So for this reason I generally find it a good strategy.
Good
python programming to say import math and then to use the name of the module and then a dot.
All right.
So now.
Oh look at this.
This one has pretty much the same problem, so name solve is not defined.
So here that's also in the sympy module.
OK.
So there's actually another problem, which I inadvertently caused, and that's because I set X to be the
number four
down here.
So I'm going to redefine x so x equals some symbols X.
There you go.
So this looks better when x equals two.
This expression, which equals zero, is true.
So let's see what's going on here... huh.
So here there's nothing wrong, we don't get any error messages or anything, but there is a comment in
here that says make it look nice.
So my guess, based on my knowledge of whoever wrote this code, is that we probably want to make this thing
look a little bit nicer.
For example using LaTeX coding.
So then the arrangement is display and then math and then sym latex.
All right.
So I realized that I just gave you this whole long lecture about how you shouldn't import individual
functions directly into the python workspace and yet I do it all the time with display and math.
So I guess I'm not always entirely consistent with the advice that I give :\
Let's see.
So we want to, let's see from Ipython dot display import  display and math.
Right.
So this is looking a little bit better maybe.
But you might remember from the video on using matrices to store data that in fact what we need to do
is also sympify this.
So a is currently a numpy array but we need to make it into a sympy object, so sympy dot
sympify
all right.
And now this looks much better.
OK let's see.
So here we are doing prime factorization of the number 44, putting the results into dictionary and then
getting all of the keys out of that dictionary.
And then here's a loop and it looks like we're looping through the number of keys and printing out number
was present number time.
So I think this is supposed to say the prime number -- the prime factor -- and the number of times that that
prime number was present in... goes into making up this number 44.
Okay.
So let's see.
Huh.
Here we get an error.
This is not subscript double.
But you know I don't even think this is a good approach.
So I'm going to do some pretty drastic editing here.
I'm gonna get rid of this entirely.
In fact I'm even going to get rid of this entirely.
I'm going to simplify this.
We're doing whoever wrote this code
we're doing them a big favor.
So for i in fact dict and then we say that the key was present fact dict I times see all that looks
Two was present twice and 11 was present once and that makes,
We have eleven times two twice.
That would be 11 times four makes forty four.
All right.
That's for that cell.
Let's see what's going on here.
Okay invalid syntax.
All we're trying to say.
X equals five.
What is going on here??
You will remember from the subs method that one way to input the variables in the replacements is to
use a dictionary.
But this is not the way the dictionary works.
We need to say the key and then the value.
So the key is X and the value is five.
But in between them is a colon like this.
So now we get when we replace X for five we get twenty four times five is 20.
That's this term.
And then well this term has no x's.
So it stays as itself as a function of y.
Okay.
So here it says The goal is to show a fraction.
So let's see.
Run this cell and we do not get a fraction. So again, there's no explicit coding errors here but I don't
think that this is actually doing what the author -- the writer of this code -- wants us to be doing.
So how can we show this as a fraction?
Well one thing we can do or one thing we can try is to convert this from a number
So the number five divided by nine into a simple object.
So let's try sym dot sympify and then putting the fraction in here huh.
And that doesn't really change anything.
Now the reason why that didn't change anything is because five divided by nine is already computed.
This is evaluated as a number and then that number which is point 55555555 becomes simplified
So in fact what we want to do is sympify the individual numbers before they get divided.
And it turns out that one way to do that, or a good way to do that, is just to sympify one of those, so
now five is no longer a number;
so in here actually 5 is still a number.
But out here before we get to the division 5 becomes the sympy version of 5.
So a symbolic number five rather than the analytic or numeric number five.
And then we get the right answer.
Now if you want.
You can also make nine be symbolic like this.
However as you can see from this example that is not actually necessary so basically in this expression
here this is a symbolic representation of five.
And this is the actual number five.
But as long as one of them is symbolic we'll still get a fraction like this.
OK.
Here we want to print the last three items from a list.
So this seems like it should work.
We have minus three.
So that means from the end minus three and then minus one.
And I think this should work because if we just say list minus one we do get the final item.
So let's try this with minus three colon minus one huh.
And now this actually returns just five and three and not the very last one.
So we actually just need to get rid of this minus one and say minus three until the end.
So there you go.
All right.
So let's see what's going on here.
This says solve for y.
And here, it looks like, so we get a dictionary and it looks like it's actually solving for x.
So we get x in terms of y.
So the solution here is we say comma Y.
So we are explicitly telling the sympy module and the solve function that we want to solve for
y.
And then the answer is minus X over two, and that you can also we can even just compute it in our heads
here.
So this is implicitly there is a equals zero over here.
So then we subtract two X from both sides so that gives us the minus two X over here and then divide
by two.
And that gives us minus X divided over two.
All right.
So let's see what we're doing here.
Here we create a matrix.
So the first row is 1 to the second row is 3 4.
And now what we want to do is set the element in the second row and second column to be nine instead
of four.
So the error message.
It's an index error.
And the message says index 2 is out of bounds for Axis 0 with size 2.
So an axis in Python is just the dimension.
But the problem here is that Python starts counting at zero.
So in fact, the second row second column has index 1 comma 1.
So there we go we've replaced the second row.
And so the second row and second column which was originally a four.
We've replaced it with a nine.
All right.
So I hope you enjoyed working through this bug hunt.
And I hope you feel like you've improved your coding skills and I hope you're really excited for the
next section of the course.
It's going to be just great.