I know I know you've been waiting the entire section of this course just for this moment the opportunity
to go through the calculus bug hunt and now is your opportunity.
If you haven't already paused the video work through all of this code find the errors in each one of
these cells.
And don't forget that there could be Python errors.
There could also be some math errors that are not explicitly coding errors but still not really the
right thing to do.
All right.
So now I'm going to go through each of these cells and fortunately there's already a bunch of libraries
that are already imported for us here.
So let's just start going through and see what we can do.
All right.
So we get an error.
This says X and Y must have the same first dimension but shapes are two hundred and one.
So it's definitely a line with or a problem with this line of code.
So let's see that one is here and I can already see the problem.
The problem is that here we've specified f of x as a simple object.
Here we convert that simple object into a function that we can call and evaluate.
But that has to be evaluated at specific points and those I guess correspond to the X Range variable.
Let's see.
All right.
So this looks pretty good.
It's a pretty interesting looking function.
Let's see next one here we are trying to compute the limit of this function here.
So 1 over x plus three at the limit point of minus three.
So that's pretty interesting because when x equals minus three then the denominator is going to be zero.
So looks like we are trying to compute the limit for variable X function f of x or if X at the limit
point.
Coming from the positive direction.
Okay.
So let's see what happens.
Oh so we get an error.
Can't convert expression to float that's over here.
I see the problem the formatting string Here is G.
Which means that we are telling Python that we are going to give it a number of floating point number
but actually limit is the output of a simple high function.
So in fact this is a symbolic variable.
So we have to use s here O K so now we get this but not really sure what to make of this.
The limit as x goes to minus three from the plus side can't really be X. It doesn't make any sense.
I think we're not really going to understand what's going on here until we can visualize this function
and see what it looks like.
So let me make a plot of this.
I'm gonna say P equals Sim dot plodding dot plot and then effects.
And now I will say show equals false and then P does show here.
Okay.
So can't really see what's going on although you can kind of already guess that at X equals minus 3.
This function is gonna blow up to infinity and down to minus infinity.
So let's see.
I'm just going to make this I'm going to zoom in on the y axis a little bit so y Lim equals minus 10
plus 10.
All right.
So now we get a better sense of what's going on in this function.
So when we approach minus three from the positive direction then it looks like this function is blowing
up to plus infinity all the way up here.
So why do we get this X.
Maybe there's something wrong with Howard setting the endpoints here.
Let's see.
I'm gonna press shift tab to see the help file here.
And this says ah compute the limit of e is the expression at point Z 0.
And variables that.
Okay.
So we actually just have these inputs in the wrong order.
So it should be the function first and then the variable.
Aha.
And now we get that the limit is who this is actually the simple way of expressing infinity.
So I'm gonna convert this into later latex and now this looks better.
All right.
And this is also consistent with the plot here.
So whenever you're looking at these functions you should definitely make visualizations of these calculus
functions.
This is a huge advantage of using Python for helping you figure out math because it's really easy to
generate this plot for.
Well I mean this is a pretty easy function you could have done this by hand but if it's a more complicated
function with some polynomials embedded in here it's not really feasible to plot out any arbitrary function
by hand but putting it into simplify or NUM pi then you can make a plot and get an immediate sense of
what's going on with that function anyway moving along.
Let's see.
Oh there's already an error there's this red text that's just screaming at me to fix something.
Okay so here is a closing parenthesis but this is an opening square brackets so I can already see that
that is a problem.
Now clearly it's not the only problem.
There's still something else going on with this function.
Oh I see what it is.
You see we're actually giving this piece wise function.
1 1 2 3 inputs but these two inputs actually belong together.
This is the piece 1.
So the first function and the boundary conditions for that function.
So this all has to be in a tuple like that oh still get an error.
What is the problem here.
Well the problem is happening on this line which is this line here.
So let's see we have this function F of X..
That's our piece Y's function.
And then we are converting it to an evaluate able function with simple lambda Fi.
That part's fine.
And we are inputting the oh this is the symbolic variable X. We actually want to input a num pi array.
So that should be X X here.
Hey we got it.
This is a pretty neat looking function.
It's like some cartoon surf or something.
All right.
So the first and second derivatives of sign of X..
Okay so here we have the function sign.
And now notice there's no simple objects in here.
This is all with NUM pi.
So none pi dot diff is just computing the discrete temporal difference.
So this will compute the first derivative and then I guess this is the second derivative because it
says second derivative.
And here's a two let's confirm that here.
So this is a.
So the discrete difference and then N equals 1 Let's see what it says about n so n is an integer and
it's the number of times that the values are different.
Okay.
So that means that this is the discrete version of the second derivative.
So let's see what we get here.
All right.
So there is an error here.
Let's see.
Okay.
So we do get one plot so that at least tells us that something is going right.
This says X and Y must have the same dimensions but they have shapes two hundred and one ninety nine.
So and again that's happening on this line here showing the first derivative here and now the problem
here the issue is that computing the discrete difference means that you end up with N minus one points.
So therefore we can only actually consider the x axis values from zero up to the penultimate point.
Okay.
Now we're getting another error and it's actually on the next line.
So here we have the same exact issues.
So this should go from zero.
So from the first index up to minus two all right.
So now we get the plot.
We don't see any errors however.
These lines don't quite look right to me.
And in particular they're way too small these derivatives are way too small.
Because remember that there's this cyclic nature of the derivatives of all the trig functions and there's
nothing in there about them getting smaller and smaller with each successive derivative.
And actually what's happening here is that we are only computing d y but what we really want is D Y
by D X.
So therefore what we need to do is divide d y.
We will do it here divide D Y by D X which is actually called D.T..
Here it's maybe a little bit confusing but in time series analysis and time series data people often
call this d t before where the T is for time.
Okay so that looks much better for D.T. and now we need to do this for d d y which is the second derivative
of D.
Mm hmm.
But it still looks a little bit small actually what we need to do is say the second derivative divided
by D.T. or D X squared.
And the reason is that we are computing the difference twice.
Now I just made a little typo that's supposed to be asterisk asterisk.
All right.
And now this looks good.
I'm going to call this a successful completion.
All right.
Let's see now we have another point here.
So we are trying to compute critical points using simple.
So it looks like we have two functions here or sorry one function and a symbolic variable x.
And then let's see what this looks like.
Okay.
So this is the function derivative and the critical points are zero.
Now critical points are defined by the derivative crossing zero or if the derivative is undefined for
example if it's minus infinity.
Now in this case it looks like the or not it looks like it's quite clear that the derivative crosses
zero at three points.
So why is only this point being indicated.
Well let's see here.
So we compute the derivative and then we find the critical points by solving for where the derivative
is equal to zero.
This should say D affects because we want where the derivative is equal to zero.
All right.
And then we get the right answer very cool.
It looks like we are on the last problem here.
The last bit of code so this says compute the area between two curves not the same thing as between
two ferns.
OK.
I think whoever wrote this code is trying to make a little joke between two ferns is like this YouTube
comedy thing you can look it up if you want.
Anyway so I ran this cell and we don't get any coding errors and we do see this interesting shaded region
here between these two functions.
Let's see this function is cosine and so the blue line corresponds to cosine and the orange line corresponds
to the function X..
Now I don't see anything explicitly wrong here but I think this is an error of omission.
In particular the instruction says compute the area between the two curves but nowhere in here is the
area actually computed.
So let's do that let's compute the area between these two curves.
These two functions in this shaded region.
So that is going to be between zero and this intersection point whatever that intersection point happens
to be.
Well fortunately we know that that intersection point is here it's given by this variable f intersect
and the way that that is computed is by finding the location of the minimum of the absolute value of
the difference between those two functions.
So it seems a little confusing at first although I have gone through this general formula for identifying
the minimum at some point in this course.
I don't remember exactly which video it was but the idea is that where these two functions intersect
is where their difference is close to zero.
So you subtract one function from the other and then take the absolute value of that.
And you can already imagine what that absolute value of difference is going to look like here at the
absolute value of the difference is large here the absolute value the difference is going to be zero.
So these two functions intersect when their difference is zero.
And that's essentially what we're finding here.
OK.
So what I want to do is compute the area between these two functions from the boundary points of 0 or
whatever is the first point.
Let's see it's from zero up until the intersection point.
So these are simple objects so I'm going to use some dot integrate and then the thing that I want to
integrate is the difference between these two functions and then I'm gonna say you know the one on top
minus the one on bottom.
So that is f one SIM minus F two SIM.
And then the second input is a tuple that contains these symbolic variable that we're looking for.
And then the starting boundary which would be the first data points in x x.
So this x axis variable here and then the point of intersection now you have to keep in mind that this
point of intersection here is an index.
This is not the actual x value.
This is the index into the value into the vector x where this point is located.
So therefore the appropriate way to set up the upper bound is x x and then f intersect OK.
Let's see.
So I don't know what the answer is because I haven't printed it out but I don't get any errors.
And that was the main thing I was looking for here.
So I'm going to write that in the title.
So let's say the title is going to be a shaded area is percent s and then percent a.
All right.
The shaded area is basically point four.
And that also seems pretty plausible.
Just looking at the plot you can imagine if this were a straight line going up and we didn't have this
other function here or imagine this other function were constant at 1 then this whole area here including
this piece here that would be point five.
We already discovered that in a previous video.
So this whole area is point five.
So it's pretty plausible that this area here is point for all right.
So that concludes this book hunt.
And that means this also concludes this section of the course on calculus.
I hope you enjoyed it.
I hope you found it a useful supplement to your otherwise regular studies in calculus and I look forward
to seeing you in the next section of the course.