I am guessing that you and I have never met in person.
However I believe that by this point in the course you know me well enough to know that I really like
to use art and visualizations and aesthetics basically pretty looking things to illustrate concepts
in math and in programming.
And that is the whole point of this section of the course.
This is a follow up to the previous section on trigonometry and the goal is basically to construct a
bunch of pretty looking things using trigonometric functions and that's going to provide the opportunity
for you to get more comfortable with thinking about and working with trig functions in particular signs
and coastlines and things like parameters nations and powers and of course this isn't only about math.
You are going to learn new things about Python coding in the process.
All right.
So the goal of this particular video is to create something called an asteroid radial curve.
So what on earth is an asteroid radial curve.
Well you'll probably more likely to find them in outer space but an asteroid radial curve is a function
that looks something like this.
So you know it's pretty neat looking it's curvy it's a little bit like a diamond.
So how do you create this thing.
Well it's actually fairly straightforward.
You plot X by Y.
So this is just a function of x and y and then you set X to be some parameter a or a vector A times
the cosine of T and T is you know a time vector or a particle vector cubed.
So X is a times cosine of T cubed Y is a Times the sign of T cubed and then in this particular case
we are just going to set a to be equal to T.
You'll see in the exercise for this video we are going to change the parameter a but for now a is simply
equal to t the same t that appears here.
So this is already pretty straightforward.
I think you could basically already arrive at this kind of a graph based on these equations in Python
pretty much in your sleep.
The only thing that I haven't told you yet is what to set t to so what the boundaries of T should be.
And if you're curious if you would like a little bit of a bonus challenge then you can pause the video.
Now switch to Python and see if you can reproduce this thing by figuring out or you know just kind of
guessing with trial and error what t should be.
Okay but now I'm going to switch to Python and we are going to produce this graph.
We are going to need the NUM pi so import num pi as MP and we're going to need for plotting of course
Matt plot lib dot pi plot as P L T.
All right.
So now we are going to define T.
So again this is the only thing I haven't really told you.
So there is no real correct answer you could try a variety of boundaries.
I'm going to use minus six times pi to six times pi so minus six pi plus six pi and I'm going to go
in a thousand steps so one thousand steps between this number and this number.
Okay so then we set a equals T.
Now you're probably thinking that you know we don't even need this line of code we can just write to
you in the equations but this is just a little bit more formal and it also helps set us up for the exercises
to come.
All right.
So a equals our X equals A times num pi cosine of T and then of course this needs to be cubed and I
think I will copy and paste here for Y.
So this is going to be sine and that's why.
All right so I'm already going to run let's say I run the salaries I'm just gonna run this so it's not
going to produce any outputs or graphics of course but just to make sure that I haven't already made
some silly typo or something like that.
OK so people tweet out plots.
Now we just plot X comma Y and I want to spend a moment to make this plot look a little nicer but just
make sure we that we can already produce this graph.
So this looks good.
Let's see.
So I want this to be a magenta line because I happen to like purple a lot and make this slightly thicker.
That looks good.
And then I went to set the Axis off and almost perfect.
I'm just going to say P L T that axis square.
There you go.
Now we have successfully created an asteroid radial curve so that was pretty cosmically cool but it
gets even better because it turns out that this asteroid radial curve that we created here is one member
of a family.
It's a family of curves that is defined by parameter arising.
This variable a and in particular what we do to t over here.
So here you see other members of the families so this is nine members of the family.
This is the one we've already created.
So how do we get all of these.
Well you follow your you define x and y according to exactly these same equations here.
So this part doesn't change at all.
We are going to change this parameter here a and in particular we are going to set a to b equal to t
to the power of n where n is drawn from this set of integers here.
And I see now as I'm looking at this that I made a mistake when I made this light.
So my apologies for this error.
This too here is confusing because when you look at this it looks like it's supposed to be just that
even numbers so 0 2 4 6 8.
In fact this should be a one so n is drawn from zero one two three four five six seven eight.
So the natural numbers non negative counting numbers from zero up to eight.
And when you insert these ends into this parameter a that's going to give you these nine different graphs.
So this is N equals zero.
And when n equals zero of course anything to the power of zero is one.
So in fact a is just all ones here.
And then this is t to the power of one.
This is what we already created.
And then this is T squared and so on.
So you can see they'll look a little bit similar and some of them look a little wobbly or a little weird.
So these are all different idiosyncratic members of this family of asteroid radial curves.
So this is your assignment.
This is your exercise.
Create this series of nine plots.
Now the thing is if all you had to do was modify this equation that would be way too easy.
You guys are way too smart way too good for an exercise that only asks you to do this one tiny little
manipulation.
So instead what you should do is figure out how to construct a three by three subplot geometry so that
inside a for loop where you're looping over these end values you can put each member of this curve family
into its own subplot like this.
So that means so let me show you.
So I did this using axis.
So this is axis 0 0 which means it's the first row or rows 0 column 0.
This is row 0 column 1.
And for example this is the axis that is contained in row one as well.
Yeah row number one which means the second row.
So the first row the second row the third row and column number two which means the third column here.
Okay but how do you get these numbers one comma two for example from this parameter n which is what
we are raising to the power this parameter n is gonna go zero one two three four five six seven eight.
So this is the challenging part of this exercise.
You have to figure out how to convert this linear index that goes from zero to one and then two three
four five six seven eight into this pair of numbers that gives you coordinates of this three by three
subplot geometry.
Now if you would like to figure this out on your own then now is your chance to pause the video.
I'm gonna give you a hint if you don't want the hint and pause the video now.
All right.
The hint is you can use a method.
Figure out how to use a method called Ravel.
It is a Ravel method.
Now this isn't much of a really great hint because you still have to figure out how exactly to use this
this is just a little bit of like a flashlight in the dark to tell you kind of give you a directional
vector here.
Now I also want to say that there are multiple ways to solve this problem.
So the solution I am going to show you is using the Ravel method.
If you come up with a different solution that still gets you to this plot then that's totally great.
It doesn't matter exactly how you solve it.
All right.
Now is your last opportunity to pause the video switch to Python and produce this graph on your own.
Now I'm going to switch to Python All right so let me get a new cell down here and we've got insert
a few more cells just so you know we can put this in the middle of the screen here.
Now what I want to do is make all of these individual plots first and then worry about how to put them
together into a subplot geometry.
So I'm going to make a for loop.
I'll call it the looping variable I and it's going to be in range 9.
So that's gonna go from 0 up through 8 in integers so we specify let's see.
I think I will actually copy and paste some of this code down here.
So let's see.
So this is all correct this is going to be d to the power of AI and then we don't need to change those
things.
So what I'm gonna do first is just say P L T dot plot x comma Y and then peel T dot show.
So this is not the correct solution to the exercise it's going to put each of these individual plots
in it's own figure in its own axis.
That's not what we need to do.
However it's good just to make sure that we are doing this correctly so we don't see any error messages
or any warning messages.
And this looks like all the individual figures that I already showed in the slides.
Okay.
Very good.
So now let me get rid of this thing here.
So now we can just worry about the plotting code.
I'm going to begin by creating a figure that contains a three by three geometry of subplots.
Fig comma X equals BLT the subplots three comma three.
So this is going to give me a pointer to figure and a variable for the axes for all of the subplots
in this three by three geometry.
So then down here it's gonna be something like X and we are going to need to access individual elements
from this X matrix.
So it's gonna be something like you know I'll just start with zero zero dot plot and then it's gonna
be x zero comma zero dot axis off and then axis square OK so let me try running this code.
Now we are slowly getting somewhere.
What we've done is create this figure with a three by three geometry but of course we are plotting everything
into the first subplot.
So.
So basically we need to figure out how to replace these zeros the 0 0 things.
OK.
So what I'm going to do is just show you a little bit of code down here before we apply that code to
the subplot geometry.
So I'm going to say Rho comma call equals num PI that indices three comma three.
So what am I doing here.
What is this function doing.
Let us display our silent print row and print call.
So what this function indices is doing is converting a major.
Are these numbers these sizes of matrix into a matrix of X coordinates and y coordinates.
So this is 0 0 0 1 1 1 2 2 2.
So this is Rose 0 row 1 and row 2.
And this is column 0 column 1 and column 2 and then that gets repeated for each of these rows.
Now this should look a bit familiar.
We learned about things like this with creating images and using mesh grid.
Okay.
So that isn't exactly what we need but we are getting close.
So what we want to do is access for example this element here.
So we want to know that this element over here which corresponds to this subplot here is row 1 and column
number 2.
So how do we do that.
That is where the Ravel method comes into play.
Let's see.
So I'll leave these printed out here and maybe just to make this a little bit easier to look at.
I will put a space in between them.
So I'm going to apply the method Ravel Ravel and let's say let's start with zero.
Okay.
So this tells me zero.
Well let me try one and let's see what happens when I do one.
Mm hmm.
It's still zero.
And what happens when I do to still zero.
And now here's where it's going to start getting interesting.
I'm going to write three.
So now I said three.
This corresponds actually to the fourth index.
So index number three which is the fourth element and that is actually returning a one.
And what does that mean.
So that is zero.
So this is location in the matrix 0 1 2 3.
So this is going to be 4 5 and my prediction is that if I replace this with 6 the output is going to
be 2.
So there you go.
But now if I say call that Ravel what is that going to return.
That's going to return 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 so that should actually return 0.
And that is the key insight here.
So let me move this code up here and then what we want to do is say I'm gonna say ah for the row that
we want.
This is row dot Ravel and then we want to input or extract the index corresponding to the ISF element.
And then this is going to be C for column and that's call.
And now I just have to replace this with R C for row column.
All right.
Let's see.
Huh.
This looks great.
This is really beautiful.
The last thing I want to do is I'm just kind of set this to be black.
I think that looks a little bit nicer actually.
You know there is one more final final thing I want to do here and that's just to make this figure a
little bit bigger.
This looks a little bit small maybe you know I'm getting older my eyes aren't what they aren't as good
as what they used to be.
So I'm going to say fig size.
I'm just kidding by the way.
I'm really really young.
Let's say 10 by six inches and that alone makes this figure quite a bit bigger so in this video you
learned how to create an asteroid radial curve both the kind of basic one and also a parameter sized
one.
And you learned about converting linear indices into subscript.
I'm really looking forward to the rest of the videos in this section and I hope you are too.