The goal of this video is to learn how to use Python to implement basic arithmetic.
Essentially we are going to use python as a calculator and it's easier than you might think.
So let's jump straight into it.
Once you have a fresh Jupiter notebook open you can click inside this small window here and then write
out some arithmetic equations just like you would with a calculator.
So let's say for example four plus five.
Now I know that the answer has to be nine because I am a genius mathematician and to confirm that the
answer is going to be nine.
I'm going to press on keyboard control and then enter and that gives me an output of nine.
And you can change these numbers as you like.
So I could set this to be four plus eight.
I'm just overwriting the five with an eight.
And again I press control enter and now I see that four plus eight is twelve.
Now I want another one of these input bars here.
So I'm going to press shift enter instead of control enter and that will evaluate this equation and
it will also give me a new line here and now I'm going to show you that you can add multiple numbers
at the same time.
Let's say four plus 1 and this is going to give me five.
But then I'm going to say plus five.
And so that result should be 10.
So that's for addition.
Now we get to subtraction.
And again it's exactly how you think it should work.
But with the minus sign instead of the plus sign.
So I'm going to say let's go five minus three.
And now I press control enter and that gives me a two.
So far pretty easy. One thing I would like to point out already is you'll notice that spaces are not
important here.
You will see later when we get to control statements like if statements and for loops that sometimes
in Python spacing is important.
But here spacing is not important.
So I can say with no spaces or with spaces I can even have lots and lots of spaces.
This is probably too many spaces but the answer is still two.
All right.
Now let's move on to multiplication.
Now you might think that multiplication should be something with an X because this is probably how you
would write it down if you're writing down three times three on a piece of paper or if you see the expression
three times three in a textbook then it's going to be written down with an x.
However that is not the correct way to do it in Python and you can see you when I tried to run this
so by pressing control enter.
We see this error message.
So it says there's an error and it shows me this little carrot here indicating where on the line the
error happens and the error message says Syntax Error Invalid syntax.
Now sometimes in programming languages like Python the error messages are more useful, and sometimes they
are not quite as easy to interpret.
But in this case I know the problem: X is not the multiplication sign.
Instead the multiplication sign is an asterisk it's this little star here.
So now I'm going to press control enter and then we get an output of nine, which is indeed three times
three.
So far I've only been implementing one operation -- one arithmetic operation -- per line of code per cell
but you can also mix these together so I'm going to say three times three plus one.
And how about minus five.
So three times three is nine plus one is ten and then minus five gives me five.
And here you see the answer is five.
Now if you're having multiple operators in the same line you have to be careful about something called
the order of operations. The order of operations is which arithmetic operator gets implemented first.
So this is three times three and then plus one and not three times three plus one which would be 12.
This would be three times four.
There's gonna be a whole separate video dedicated to order of operations and how to override order of
operations using parentheses.
So for now just keep in mind that order of operations is something important to keep in mind when doing
arithmetic with Python and I will talk more about it in a few videos.
The last arithmetic operation that I'm going to discuss in this video is division.
Now the way that division works is kind of like forming a fraction.
So what you want to do is convert every division into a numerator and denominator and make that be a
fraction and then you use this slash operator.
So for example three divided by four looks like this.
It's like you're writing out the fraction three fourths. So we can see that is point seven five and you
have to be careful that it's the forward slash and not the backslash.
So if you did the wrong slash if you did it this way then that's going to give you an error.
Again this is maybe not the most informative error but in this case I do know that we are trying to
do division.
So it seems reasonable to suspect that we might be using the other slash operator here.
So that looks nice.
The last thing that I want to point out before getting to the exercises for this video is using parentheses
for implementing arithmetic like this.
The main use of parentheses is to group certain numbers together.
There are other uses of parentheses in Python and you will learn about those later in the course.
So for example let's say we wanted to compute one plus three divided by four.
So if you would say one plus three divided by four.
The answer here is actually one point seventy five and that makes sense because python is grouping these
two together and then it's adding of the one. Again, that's because of the order of operations which you
will learn about later.
But if you want the one plus three to be in the numerator then you would use parentheses like this.
Now you are specifically telling Python to group these two numbers together in this operation and then
divide by four.
And it might even be useful to use the spacing here to indicate that.
Now we have one plus three grouped together divided by four.
And of course the answer here is going to be one because one plus three is four divided by four is one.
There are two exercises for this video and that is basically to implement these two expressions here
and figure out what the answers are.
So what I encourage you to do now is pause the video write out these equations in Python and make sure
you get the right answer. So pause the video, have a go at it, and then come back to the video and you can
watch me solve these two problems
okay.
So I'm going to give myself a new cell here.
So here was the first problem it was five minus...
and now I'm going to use parentheses just to make sure that we are doing the right thing.
So two divided by four times the fraction
three divided by five.
And the answer there is four point seven.
And then the second problem was four minus five divided by....
and this one's a little bit tricky because the wrong way to do this would be to say three plus five
times six.
And the reason why that's wrong it's sort of visually looks like it should be right.
But python is going to group these numbers together this operation together and then it's going to add
five times six.
But we want three plus five times six all to be in the denominator.
So now I'm going to put those in parentheses and that gives me a funny looking answer of minus zero
point 0 3 0 3 0 3 0 3 and so on is pretty funny number. So in this video I showed you how to implement basic
arithmetic in Python essentially using python as a calculator. Of course python is way way way more powerful
than just a basic calculator but that's the way to start. In the next video,
you're going to learn how to use variables in place of numbers.
And that's going to help bring you to a new level of using Python to learn mathematics.