Let's begin our discussion on probability by talking about history.
Probability densities and the difference between a probability and a proportion.
So let's start by talking about this dataset here.
This is a set of letters and what we want to do is create a histogram from this set.
So creating a histogram from a finite set like this is pretty straightforward.
All you do is look at all the unique elements in this set and then count the number of occurrences of
each element.
So we have on the x axis the letters a b and c and on the y axis the occurrences or the counts.
So the histogram of this set looks something like this a appears twice B appears twice and c appears
four times.
So pretty straightforward I think.
Now here you see a probability plot.
Now you'll notice that it looks overall the same.
The main difference is that the y axis is changed here compared to here.
So this is in just the raw counts and this is a probability.
So A is associated with a probability of point two five or 25 percent and b also and then C is 50 percent
or point five.
Now importantly a probability density has to sum up to 1.
So all of the values in this entire histogram have to sum up to exactly 1.
And of course that's the case here point to five plus point two five plus point five equals 1.
So we have a histogram.
We have a probability plot and then here I call this a proportion.
Now this looks remarkably similar to this probability graph.
In fact in this case there are exactly the same except that the interpretation is quite different.
So this y axis here proportion means that a appears 25 percent of the time b appears 25 percent of the
time and c appears 50 percent of the time.
Now that is slightly different from the interpretation of this probability graph here.
What this means is that if you were to pick a letter totally at random from anywhere in this set there
is a 25 percent chance that you're going to pick the letter A.
So you'll notice that that is a different interpretation from proportion.
Now to make this distinction between probability and proportion a little bit clear.
Let me show you another example.
So here is an example of coin flips.
These are U.S. pennies.
So imagine you flip a coin ten times and six of those times that lands heads.
So we can say in this dataset this finite dataset with 10 coin flips the proportion of heads was 60
percent.
So six out of ten times we got heads but the probability of getting ahead with any given coin flip is
point five or 50 percent.
So here you can see the difference between proportion and probability.
Now let's switch to Python and see how to produce a histogram and a probability density in code.
So we're gonna need the NUM pi and Matt plot lib modules and I'm going to start by creating a dataset
that's going to contain a bunch of numbers let's say 1.
And how about a couple of twos three and four five maybe we need some sixes in here.
Seven eight nine maybe we need another eight and a six and how about three.
OK.
So this is our dataset and now I'm going to write P L T dot hist data and we need an x axis label that's
going to say value and a Y axis label and that's going to be number of appearances or the count and
that I think should be enough.
Okay.
So here you see the histogram.
So that count by the value.
So let's see there was 1 1 and looks like 5 2 so 1 2 3 4 5.
That's correct but we get here.
This is starting to look a little bit weird because kind of seems like there's zero fours there's clearly
a four There's also five.
So what's going on with this missing gap here.
Well to understand this a little bit better to understand why this looks a little initially weird compared
to what you see in this dataset what I'm going to do is instead of just drawing the histogram directly
I'm going to use the NUM pi histogram function to extract these values.
So get out these x axis values and get out the y axis values.
So I'm going to write test data that's gonna be output of the histogram function and let's say data.
Okay.
And let's start just by looking at hist data.
So hist data provides two outputs or in this case a tuple that both goes into the Hist data variable.
So here you see the y axis coordinates.
So 1 5 2 1 0 and so on.
And then this second output corresponds to numbers that go from 1 through 9.
And this is the actual range of the numbers that I wrote in the dataset but they don't have integers.
So it's like 1 to one point eight and then two point six three point four.
And so on.
Now it's also interesting to count the number of numbers in here.
So this has 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 elements.
And here we have one two three four five six seven eight nine ten eleven elements.
OK.
So there's already a couple of bizarre seemingly bizarre things.
So first of all I only have the there's only nine unique elements in here integers 1 through 9.
And here we have 10 integers.
And here we have eleven numbers.
So I'm going to talk more about this in the next video.
But essentially what's happening is that the function hissed as well as histogram is by default trying
to group the data into 10 equally sized bins.
And so what this zero here means is that there is no numbers in our data set that fall between four
point two and five.
And that's an exclusive thing.
So 5 the number five appears once in the data set.
And that's going to be counted as between five and five point eight not between four point two and five.
And of course the number four in the dataset is between three point four and four point two.
OK.
So how can we make this a little bit more sensible.
So what I'm going to do is specify the exact bins that I want to use and I'm going to make this be a
range.
So num pi range function from 1 to 10.
Now let's see what this looks like.
Now we see that these values are 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
And then the values here are a little bit more sensible.
But still there's only eight numbers here.
So one two three four five six seven eight.
And that's because it's actually excluding the number nine here.
So you can see the number nine appears once in this dataset.
And although the bins the bin boundaries go up to nine.
This is exclusive on the top level.
So we actually don't see the number nine in here explicitly.
So therefore what we actually want to do is go from 1 through 10.
And now you can see there's one two three four five six seven eight nine elements in this array and
that's kind of correspond now to the individual integers that I specified above.
So the first bin is going to go from one to two and then a second bin is two to three and so on.
Up until nine to 10.
So now what I'm gonna do is make a plot of these outputs.
So let's say P L T dot bar hist data one by hist data zero.
Let's see and then I will just copy and paste some of this stuff here and we get an error.
Why do we get an error.
This says something about the shape.
So the problem is that the bins on the x axis have one number larger than the number of bins for the
y axis plotting.
And again that's because these numbers here do not correspond to the centers of the bins they correspond
to the bin boundaries.
So the first bin here goes from one to two and then the second bin goes from two to three and three
to four and so on.
So therefore the way to plot this is to write that we are going to use just the first elements up to
minus one.
Okay.
And now finally after all this time we get a histogram that looks like what you would expect.
So you see the values here go from 1 through 9 and the accounts here correspond to the accounts that
I specified here.
I hope that all makes sense.
If it's still a little confusing enough it's not totally clear then don't worry I'm going to be talking
quite a bit more about creating histogram over the next several videos so you'll get quite a bit more
practice.
Well I'd like to do now is convert this histogram into a probability density and to do that I think
I will actually just comment that this code because I don't we don't need it right now okay.
And then rather than just getting hissed data I'm going to write to outputs.
I'm going to request two outputs from the histogram function.
Now notice that this is why comma X and not X come a Y.
And that's because the first output from the histogram is the counts which is the y axis values here.
So let's see then this will need to change to X and this will need to change to Y.
And I'm just gonna run this again just to make sure I haven't made any silly typos.
Okay so to convert this to probability what we want to do is make sure that all of the values on the
y axis for all of these bins will sum up to 1 and the way to do that is to say that Y equals Actually
maybe I'll make this a new variable Y P for probability equals y divided by num piled up some of Y.
So now I'm going to change Y to Y P and you'll notice that the X X or the y axis values have now changed.
But the legend is now incorrect.
So this is going to say I'll write this as proportion and let's see I think it would also be nice to
show that all of the numbers here.
So I'm gonna change the x stick labels so P L T that X ticks equals our is set to numb pi to a range.
I want to go from 1 to 9.
Okay.
So I think this looks pretty good.
So now we have our plot of proportion which is also probability but again I just say this again as a
quick reminder the difference between proportion and probability is that this value here means that
literally 25 percent of all the numbers in here are have a value of 2 and probability means that if
I gave you this dataset and you were to pick one of these numbers at random from this entire set you
would have a 25 percent probability a 25 percent chance of randomly getting the number two.
All right.
So there is one more thing that I want to show you one more way of plotting and that is to convert this
to a maximum value of one that's sometimes called normalizing.
So now instead of dividing by the sum we are going to divide by the maximum.
And now we also have to change this because this should say proportion and I think I'll just specify
that this is Norm for normalized.
So this is not a probability distribution and you know that because I told you that a probability distribution
has to sum to exactly 1.
Now the sum of all these numbers is obviously greater than 1 the largest value is 1.
So this is a normalized proportion plot and this is often a useful normalization for example if you
are comparing across different datasets and you might norm all the data sets to a maximum value of 1
which facilitates averaging across them.
I hope you found this video insightful.
I talked about histogram as probabilities and proportions and I showed you how to create all these things
in Python which as you saw is actually a little bit trickier than you might initially expect.
Now don't go away.
Don't go too far in the next video.
There's going to be the exercise associated with this video.
It's going to be really really interesting.
I'm already excited to make the video.