The importance of visualization cannot be understated.
In mathematics neither in applied mathematics nor in pure mathematics.
It's really important to visualize mathematical formulas and data results.
That's really the best way to gain intuition about how math works.
And so this section of the Course is all about introducing you to plotting and graphics and visualization
in python.
Now data visualization and mathematical visualization in Python is also a huge topic so you are not
going to learn everything about graphing in python just from this section.
The course.
However what you will get from this section of the course is a really firm grounding on which to build
your skills in graphing and visualization.
All right.
So let's get started.
The main goal of this video is to plot coordinates or points at single coordinates.
So here we have some coordinate x come a Y equals 3 come a 5.
So that means that we go three units over on the x axis five units up on the x axis and then we are
going to plot a dot just a little point that looks like this.
So to do the visualization we are going to use a Python module called maths plot lib.
So we write import maths.
Plot lib dot.
In particular we are going to be using pi.
Plot for Python plotting.
And then this is quite a mouthful.
This is a lot to write down each time we want to make a visualization so we are gonna say as P L T.
All right.
So now to generate a plot.
Let's see.
We want to plot a point at X equals 3 and y equals 5.
So the basic way to plot is you type P.L. T dot plot so P L deeds indicate that we are calling this
module the map plot.
Live that pie plot module and then plot.
Now there is a number of possible inputs that the plot function can take.
In this case I'm going to say X comma Y.
So how far along the x dimension how far along the y dimension.
And then optionally you can plot these coordinates using a specified visualisation parameters.
So in single quotes I'm going to type r to indicate red and 0 to indicate a circle.
So after you run this plot actually you can already run the code like this.
It's going to give two outputs the plot itself and also the output of this P L T dot plot function.
So typically what you would do is generate the plot and maybe there's going to be multiple things plotted
on top of each other.
Maybe you're going to specify some parameters of the plot and then at the bottom when you're done specifying
everything you write.
P L T show which is a function and that will display the the final version of the figure.
Okay so we got a red dot at X equals 3 and y equals 5.
Now this is not really like what you would probably have expected to see.
You might want this to look a little bit nicer.
So now I'm going to show you a few additions to this plot to make it look a bit better.
So first of all I'm going to make this be square you can see this is rectangular so I'm going to type
P ulti dot axis and then in single quotes square.
So now let's run this again.
Okay.
Now we get a square plot and now another thing that I don't like is that the limits go from here it
looks like two point eight to three point four.
I would like this to be centered at the origin.
So the graph has zero zero at its origin so to change the axis limits I'm going to type BLT dot axis.
Don't notice this is actually the same function as here.
Here I input it square and what I'm gonna do here is input a list of numbers and in particular we need
for numbers.
So it's going to be minus six plus six that corresponds to the x axis limit.
So the X axis limit will go from minus six to plus six and then two more numbers for the y axis limits.
Okay so now you can see X goes from minus X plus X Y goes from minus X to plus six.
This is starting to look better.
The last thing that I want to put into this axis here into this figure is a grid.
So I will type plot dot grid all right.
And now we get a nice grid.
And this is looking a bit better.
This looks like the kind of thing that you would expect to see in for example a textbook.
But already you can see the general flow of how it works to set up a plot.
So first you use peel to eat up plot to plot all of the coordinates or lines or whatever you're plotting
and then you have however many lines you need to make the plot look a little bit nicer.
And then you end with plot dots show.
Okay so here we made a red circle.
There are other options as well.
You can make for example a green square so that gives us a green square.
How about a black Pentagon so you can see there are many different ways to represent these plots.
Now if you put the cursor inside the plot function so inside these parentheses here and then press shift
tab on the keyboard then you can see there's more options.
This will tell you lots and lots and lots of options.
Now you don't have to.
So for example here are the various colors that you can use.
Here are the characters so I showed you a circle and I showed you a Pentagon.
Where is the Pentagon.
And I showed you a square.
So those are in some.
Oh yeah.
Here you go.
Now I don't recommend memorizing this list or trying to memorize this list as you go further along in
coding in Python.
You will naturally learn a lot more of these individual elements.
Another thing I want to show you is that sometimes the order in which you call these different settings
matters.
So for example if I move the access square to beneath the Axis setting setting these axis limits then
the plot will look a little bit different and it looks initially like the plot moved or the coordinate
moved actually the coordinate didn't move.
It's that the instructions that we gave here were then overridden by this setting here.
So that's just something to keep in mind that order is important here.
OK so this is for one point one plotting one coordinate.
I'm now going to show you how to plot multiple coordinates in a in list using a loop.
So let's say we have various numbers for x.
How about like I don't know.
Minus 4 5 2 I'm just making up some numbers here and then we need y axis coordinates maybe 0 and due
to do.
I'm just making up these numbers all right.
And now what I'm going to do is essentially something like this except I'm going to put it inside of
a for loop.
So for i in range 0 to length of X so however many elements are in the x variable the X list we are
going to plot the ISF element in X by the ISF element in y and I'll just make these a circle for now.
Okay.
And so now I'm gonna type BLT show and let's see what this looks like.
Okay so this looks pretty neat.
First of all we see that all of these different points are appearing so that's already pretty cool.
And then you see that they each have a different color so each point has a different color.
And that's not something that I specified.
That's something that python will do automatically.
All right.
So now before I show the plot I want to make a few additions so plot that axis square and I'll add a
grid.
Whoops.
Plot grid.
Now what I'd like to do is label all of these different points and then we can have a legend appearing
in the plot here.
So to label the different points you can add another input into the plot function and it would be label
and then whatever you want the label to be.
So for example let's just make it Cordy.
Now this is not a very informative label.
And that's because every single point will have the label of Cordy.
So let's see what happens when I run this.
So actually nothing happened.
We don't see any label we don't see any legend here.
And what's going on here the problem here is that I need to first activate the legend functions as a
p ulti legend and that is sufficient for turning on the legend.
So there you go.
Every point is labeled Cordy.
Looks kind of funny.
So let's consider changing this now.
This is not just some special text here you can make any string appear in here including the kinds of
strings that we've been making previously in the course for printing out information.
So for example I can say point percent s and then here I say percent I so now this is going to be replaced
with I as a string and I of course is the number.
And then that's going to be different for each element.
Each plot each coordinate.
OK.
So now we get point 0 up through point 6.
And if you want to start at 1.
No problem whatsoever you could say 1 plus I like this.
All right.
So there's one more key concept that I would like to illustrate to you in this video and that is how
to extract information from the axes so we know that the axis the x axis goes from minus four point
one let's say to a little bit over six because I can just look at this and I can see it but somehow
we should be able to extract those numbers that exact axis limit from Python.
And that's what I want to show you how to do now.
So let's see plot.
Let's make a point.
How about for karma too.
And I will make it a red plus sign.
Okay.
So let's start by just seeing what this looks like.
All right.
We got a little red plus sign.
And now what I'm going to do is access this plot object and I'm going to do that by assigning it to
some variable and for convenience I'm going to call that variable axis.
So now I say plot dot G C A.
That stands for get current axis.
So this is going to output an object that points to this axis here.
This entire thing and from there I can access information.
So for example I can say why Lim equals axis that get why Lim not I'm going to print out this variable
here so you can see that the y axis limit goes from one point 89 down here up to a little bit over two
point one so two point 1 1.
Lots of zeros and then a three.
So once I have this information I can then use it.
So why Lim here is a tuple.
And so I can access each individual element so I can type.
For example axis dot set y Lim.
Notice here it was.
Get why Lim.
And here it's set.
Why Lim so this got the information.
And now I'm changing the information I'm setting the new Y axis limits and then in a list let's say
how about y Lim.
So we'll set let's say I'm happy with the lower bound but I'm not happy with the higher bound maybe
I want it to be five points some number like this.
Okay so now you can see that the Y axis changed.
So the initial or the lower bound the axis is still what it was before is a little bit below 2.
And here it's at a bit over 5 and actually to be very specific to be very precise it's this number here
so in this video I gave you a quick introduction to graphing in Python.
In particular I showed you how to graph single coordinates and multiple coordinates that appear in a
list in the next video.
You will have the opportunity to apply the skills the knowledge that you learned in this video to generating
a function and visualizing that function using colorful dots.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next video.