Do you know what it means for a function to be even or odd if you don't then this is going to be a really
exciting video because you are going to learn something new and really interesting about certain kinds
of functions.
Now if you already know what an even and an odd function means then oh well OK let's say this video
is still going to be exciting because you'll get to learn how to use Python data visualization to test
whether a function is even or odd.
Now I'm going to provide a mathematical a formal definition of even functions and odd functions but
first I want to give you a little bit of visualization to build some intuition.
So imagine we have these two functions.
It's the blue line here and the blue line over here.
Now what I've done here is flip the function and that is the red dots so you can see that when I flipped
this function which is like rotating it around on this x equals zero axis then the resulting function
is the same as the original function.
So that's for an even function for an odd function.
You can see the original function in blue and then I flipped it around so I rotated it on the x equals
zero axis and now the function was flipped.
So it's like the negative version of this function.
So this is called an odd function.
All right I hope this builds a little bit of visual intuition.
I'm not gonna show you the formal definition.
So a function f of x is an even function f f of minus X equals f of x.
So that means you take X and you just multiply all of X by minus one.
And if that does nothing to the function then it's an even function.
And that's essentially what I did here.
So I took all of these x values embedded it into the function but multiplied all the x values by minus
one.
And we got the same result.
So that's an even function f of x is an odd function if f of minus X does not equal F of X but minus
f of x.
So it's like the minus sign comes outside to the function rather than being inside in the X..
So if this is the case then the function is odd and that's what you see here.
So here I flipped around the x axis I multiplied the x values by minus one.
And what ended up happening is that the function flipped on the y axis.
So this is now the negative version of this.
So that's an odd function.
Now not all functions are even or odd.
You can have functions that are neither even nor odd.
So even an odd is not necessarily a property that applies to every single function.
All right let's have a look at this.
In Python we are going to be using the NUM pi module and the map plot lib that pi plot module.
So I'm going to start by creating an even function so X will be Linda space so linearly space numbers
from minus five to plus five and let's have 20 of them.
So I'm going to call this variable f even because it's going to be an even function and X squared is
a perfect example of an even function.
So let's start by plotting this.
So plot x by F. even.
And let's do p t that show loops P P L T.
Not plot.
Okay.
So here we have our even function x squared.
Now you can already tell even before we generate the plot you can already tell just from looking at
this function that this is an even function.
And that's because when you set X to be minus that actually doesn't change anything.
For example when x equals to 2 squared equals 4 but minus 2 squared also equals 4.
So therefore we can create f even I'll call this f even neg for negative.
Now you have to be really careful here because what we're not doing is saying minus minus X squared
like this.
And let me show you why that is the wrong thing to do.
So plot x f even neg.
So that is actually applying the minus sign to the X squared term.
That's not what we want.
What we want is just to replace this X with minus X.
So we need to use parentheses here to make sure that the association is correct.
Okay.
So now you only see one line and that's because they both overlap perfectly.
So I'm gonna change this to be red dots.
All right.
So this was a even function I'm now going to illustrate to you an odd function so I'll call it F odd
and that one I'm gonna set to be X cubes.
X to the power of three.
So let's call this f od neg and that's going to be minus X to the power of three.
And then we want to plot.
So this is basically going to be the same plot functions I showed here so appeal to up plot x by F OD
and then P L T dot plot F by F od neg and let's make this also red circles.
Okay.
So now looking down at this function you can see that we don't get the same result.
And so this is definitely not an even function.
Now what we have to do to actually get this result to show that this is an odd function is to compute
minus F of X..
So I'm gonna say now f maybe cause f neg odd because now I'm going to be negating or multiplying by
minus one.
The entire function and not just X. So I'm going to write minus f odd like this.
Okay.
And then let's plot this.
So that was f neg odd.
Let's plot this as how about green squares
okay.
So now in fact you don't even see the red circles anymore you just see the green squares.
And that's because these green squares perfectly overlap with the red circles.
So maybe I'll just make it a green line.
All right.
So now look at this graph and recall the definition in the formal math definition that I showed at the
end of the slides.
So we took f of x and then we said minus X inside F of X..
And that is equal to minus the original function.
And that's exactly what you see here.
So this provides visual confirmation that this is an even function.
So this was the function x squared.
And this is an odd function x cubed the exercise for this video is to determine whether the sine and
cosine functions are even or odd.
Now maybe you already know the answer.
But if you don't then you can use python as a tool to understand this important property of these two
trig functions.
So essentially what you want to do is just implement the sine and cosine functions and apply the two
methods that I just showed you to determine whether the function is even and whether it is on.
So you need to do this for cosine and for sine All right.
So now you can positive video switch to Python and determine on your own whether sign and cosine are
odd or even functions.
I am going to begin by defining the variable as I'll call this theta because I always use a variable
X but maybe X gets overused a little bit.
So let's say theta equals linearly space numbers and you can kind of use whatever range you want but
it does make sense to use a range of minus two pi two plus two pi and I'll go in.
How about thirty nine steps because thirty nine is a good number of steps in fact thirty nine steps
is the name of a movie by Alfred Hitchcock from I think it was made in the 1940s.
Okay so let's define the cosine function to be equal to num PI that cost theta.
And then I will define costs fun n for negative and that's going to be and P that costs minus theta.
Now I'm going to do something else with spacing which is to put an extra space in here.
In my opinion this code now looks a little bit nicer it looks neater and more readable compared to this
where the equal signs are not aligned like this.
Okay.
So let's already try and determine whether this is an even function that will make our lives pretty
easy because we could just stop right there.
So we could test whether it's even and then we don't need to test whether it's odd.
So theta costs fun.
And then P L teed up plot theta cost fun and and I'll make this red circles to be consistent with how
I was doing this stuff up here.
All right.
BLT dog show huh.
Look at that.
That was pretty good.
Let me actually put a title on here.
So appeal to the title.
This is the cosine of X right now we've just demonstrated that the cosine is an even function and the
cosine is an even function.
Because when you input minus theta you get back exactly the same function.
All right.
That was pretty cool.
Now I want to try this again for a sign.
So in fact I'm just gonna start by copying and pasting and then this needs to be changed to sign this
gets changed to sign this gets changed to sign this gets changed sign and sign sign sign.
So is an interesting question when you're copying and pasting code whether it's actually faster to copy
paste so sometimes it's actually less work just to write everything out from scratch again okay.
Nonetheless let's see what this looks like.
Oh this looks like it's not the same function when we flipped the theta inside the sine function.
However you can already kind of start imagining that if we were to make the original sine function negative.
So if you would say minus sine then the blue line and the red line would overlap.
So therefore what I'm going to do is say minus the sine function and then I'm also going to change this
to be latex code.
So this is going to be instead of sign of X it's gonna be a sign of theta groups.
That's two slashes here like this.
Okay.
So now we get sign of theta.
So now what I've done is shown that sign of minus X is the same thing as minus the sign of X..
And that means that the sign is an odd function.
So I hope you enjoyed this video I enjoyed making it for you.
You learned about even and odd functions and you learned how to use python as a tool to help you understand
whether a function is even or odd that is actually a pretty handy method to have in your data analysis
toolkit.