Let's start by talking about limits and the limit of a function.
So what does that mean to have a limit of a function.
Well let me start with the notation.
So the notation looks like this.
So you would say you would pronounce this as the limit of F of X as X goes towards a.
And essentially what this means is what is the value of the function when X goes towards the value of
a.
Now sometimes the limit of a function is really easy even trivial to compute and you can see that in
this example.
So the limit of the function x squared over 2 as X goes towards for that.
In this case computing the limit is really simple.
All you have to do is plug in for for X and then you just see what the function ends up being.
So for squared is 16 divided by two is eight.
And we can draw this on a graph and then you see that as X goes towards four.
The function goes towards eight.
So that's a pretty easy example.
Limits can be trickier in some cases.
For example consider this graph.
This is a graph of the function f of x equals X squared divided by X minus two.
So what is the limit of the function as X goes towards two.
Well you can try to just plug in two into this equation A you get four that's no problem but here you
get two minus two which is zero.
So you end up with four divided by zero.
And we're not allowed to divide by zero and furthermore when you look at this graph you can see that
the limit isn't even the same when you approach the function from the from the right versus when you
approach the function from the left.
So in this particular case for this example we actually need to have two separate one sided limits.
So you would right the limit as x approaches two from the positive direction or from the right and there
the limit is plus infinity.
You can see this function goes up to infinity here and here you say the limit of F of X as X goes to
two coming in from the left or from the negative side.
So that would mean coming in from here and you can see the function goes down to minus infinity.
So let's switch to Python and see how to implement the limit of a function in this video.
We are going to use several modules including simplify and map plot lib dot pi plot for plotting num
Pi.
And from the Python display the display and math functions.
And that's because I'm going to show you how to write out the limit in later coding.
All right.
So let's start with a fairly simple function.
I'm going to say Actually first I will import a symbolic variable X and then let's say F of X equals
X cubed so x to the power of three and let's say we want to compute the limit points.
So the variable that I called a in the slides but here in code I'm going to call it Lim point because
I think this is a little bit more informative than just saying that variable a.
Okay.
So now we say that the limit is Sim dot limits.
So it's a pretty easy function name to remember.
So some limit and then let's see how to use this function.
So I just pressed shift tab on my keyboard to get this doc string here.
So we see that the help file says e said and said not okay.
So what does this mean.
This means that we compute the limit of e of Z.
So that means that this is a function that's in the slides.
What I was referring to as F of X at the point z 0.
So this is what I was calling a in the slides in here I call Lim point.
Okay.
So the way we set this up is to write F of X or effects and then X which is the key variable that we're
looking for.
And then the Lim Lim point.
All right.
So let's just see what that is.
Okay so we get a value three point three seven five and a bunch of zeros.
And really what.
You know what is going on here is that this limit point just gets plugged into this equation so we can
also see that one point five to the power of three is essentially that same number.
Okay.
Now I'm just gonna print this out in later coding so it looks a little nicer.
So display math.
And now the limit function in latex is probably not so surprising.
It's just Lim.
And then you use an underscore like this now normally in later coding an underscore gives us a subscript.
But now with this limit function in before it then latex will know to put whatever character comes after
the underscore directly beneath the limit and not just in a little subscript to the right but of course
we don't just want one character.
We want actually an entire expression.
So therefore we put it in curly brackets and now everything in the curly brackets is going to go underneath
the limit.
So just to show you what this looks like.
So we have Lim for limits and then.
OK so a SDF is not really a sensible thing here but I just wanted to print something out okay.
So X and then to get the little arrow use slash slash to.
And then this is going to be % G because I'm gonna replace this with the limit point and then I want
to write the function value and then the actual limit itself.
Okay.
So now we need to do some replacements.
So this first replacement here was X goes to.
And then that variable is Lim point.
And then I want to write the function here so that s f of x and then I want to write the actual limit
which is Lim.
Okay let's see if this is gonna work or if we need to fix anything in this line to make it look a little
bit nicer.
Okay well this doesn't really look nicer so we certainly need to fix this.
That was actually not intentional.
In fact I was referring to fixing this to make this look nicer.
So of course you already know how to fix this.
We want to convert this expression from Python code into latex formatting so that is going to be Sim
dot later like F X all right.
Now this looks pretty nice.
This is some beautiful latex formatting here.
So now we know what this value is but in mathematics in general and particularly in calculus visualization
is really important.
In fact I think visualization and calculus is so much more important for building intuition and understanding
than is often taught in high school or university level calculus courses.
So therefore what I'd like to do now is basically plot the function and also plot the limit on top of
that and to generate this plot.
What I'm going to do is generate a function that will allow me to evaluate this function.
So X cubed based on whatever values I want.
So that's not possible here because X is a symbolic variable.
So I'm going to use a function called Sim that lamb defy and then I'm going to provide two inputs which
are x variable X and the function or the expression.
Now lambda Phi is a simple function that will return another function that we can provide inputs to
and get outputs from.
I mentioned this function and showed you briefly how to use it a while back in the course that was in
the section on simplify and latex introduction but it's a pretty important function for calculus.
I'm gonna be using this function fairly often so let's see what this output is.
So notice that this output is actually a function.
It's not a variable on itself.
And what this allows us to do is use this as a function providing an input for what to replace with
F to a sorry X to evaluate f of x.
So for example if I input zero course the result is gonna be zero because zero cubed is zero.
And you know I can input 3 for example and 3 to the power of three is twenty seven.
So now I'm going to come up with some x axis range that's going to be Lynn space.
How about this go from minus five to plus five in two hundred steps.
Okay so now what we can do with this lambda fired expression is say that you BPL t that plot x x by
f of x.
Now this is not going to work on its own.
And that's because this isn't actually a list of numbers.
This is a function and it's not really possible to plot a function.
So we provide input to the function and that is x x.
So this gives us an evaluation of this function f of x whereas that up here for values it corresponding
to this variable I call X X here.
Okay.
And now once we have that we can add to this.
I'm going to say P L T dot plot and now I'm going to plot the Lim point by the limit and let's make
this a red dot.
So now I plotted the function and I've plotted the limit on top of it.
Now if you like you could take a few moments to make this plot look a little bit nicer.
You could change some of the axis limits you could give access labels and a legend and so on.
But you know how to do that by this point in the course what I'd like to do now is show you another
plot of the function that I showed in the slides.
And that's also going to allow me to show you a little bit more about using this limit function.
So let's start by defining that function.
So that was F of X equals X squared divided by X minus two.
And in fact don't even need these parentheses but that's okay.
Okay.
And now I'm going to immediately skimmed that land defy variable X and F of X. The expression and then
for this function I'm going to evaluate it between 1 and 3 and let's go for one hundred and about one
hundred and two steps between 1 and 3.
Okay.
So now this was an interesting function because we cannot simply plug in for the value of two because
that gives us zero in the denominator.
So let's see.
So let's say the limit point is 2 and then Lim equals in the limit.
So I'm gonna try doing essentially what I did before what I did earlier limit point and then let's see
what what Lim ends up being.
Okay.
So we get what looks like 0 0.
Or you might be tempted to think that this is Python saying you maybe python is trying to give us a
hard time about computing the limit of this function but you saw in the graph in the slides and we'll
make another graph in a moment that the limit is actually different depending on whether you're coming
in from the right side or whether you're coming in from the left side.
So how is that incorporated in this expression here in this line of code.
Actually it's not incorporated.
So we want to change this a little bit.
I'm gonna add a fourth input and that's dir 4 direction equals plus.
So this means we're coming in from the plus side we're coming in from the right over here.
So you can still see that says you.
And now when I change this to minus it says minus 2 or minus infinity.
Okay.
So now let me make the plot quickly so appeal to you that plot x x by f of x x and then we input x x.
So here you see that plot again and then I'm going to whereas it here I want to copy and paste this
code time here and I just want to show you how to make this small in addition to this formula so that
we get the one sided limit because this statement as it stands is actually not technically true.
This is not really a valid statement because without a plus or minus sign here this implies that the
limit is double sided and that is the case here.
So when you approach this point here for this particular function from the left and from the right or
from negative and from positive you get exactly the same limit here you get a different values.
So we need to specify that this is coming in from the left which means we need a little superscript
after the two over here.
So now this is actually the correct way to format this expression to show this expression in this video.
I introduced you to the idea of the limit of a function and how to compute limits of functions in Python
and also a bit of a review about using simplify to create functions that can be evaluated and you learned
a little bit more about later coding and making beautiful math notation.
Now don't go away.
Don't run away too quickly because the next video is going to contain the exercise for this video.