This video is a follow up to the previous video on plotting coordinates in Python.
And in this video you are going to get to apply the knowledge you gained in the previous video to working
through this exercise.
So if you haven't yet watched the previous video and you're not super familiar with generating plots
in Python then I recommend going back to the previous video before trying to work through this one.
Anyway the goal of this exercise is basically just to generate this plot.
So this plot shows data points on a function and the function is Y equals X squared minus three x and
these points are plotted for X corresponding to integers between minus 10 and plus eleven.
And actually when I'm looking at the plot now I see that this.
Here the instructions say to go up to eleven although this last plot here this last point here is just
a 10.
So a part actually doesn't matter you can plot including point eleven or just up to point ten.
That doesn't matter.
Notice also the x and y axis labels which include for the y axis the definition of the function.
Okay so you should pause the video and see how you do in Python work as much as you can to get this
plot to get your plot to look like this.
And now I am going to switch to Python and you can watch me work through this exercise.
So I am going to solve this using the simple module so import Sim pie as Sim.
Now it's not strictly necessary.
You can also solve this exercise without using simple pie.
But I like some pie so I'm going to use it here.
It's also makes it convenient for plotting the y axis label.
So first I'm going to create a symbolic variable X so some symbols X and then we set our function that
was Y equals X squared minus three times X and now I'm gonna specify all of the points to be plotted
in a for loop.
So let's say for P and T I.
So for point index i n s i in the range from minus eleven to an hour.
Here is where you know you can go up to plus eleven or up to twelve as you like.
That part doesn't matter so much.
So then what we want to do is plot.
Now we need to specify the x axis and the y axis coordinates for each point.
So the x coordinate is actually in this coming from this range here.
So I'm just going to write P NTI and then the y axis comes from evaluating this function y.
This symbolic object substituting X for point or know no p NTI.
So this is going to be y dot y dot subs and then I'm going to substitute X for P and T I.
And then I want to make these a points so so I draw it with a dot at each coordinate.
Okay so now let's type peel t peel T dot show and see what we get.
All right.
So already this is looking pretty good we're almost already finished the exercise.
The other thing that I want to do here is added the axis labels so let's say P L T the X label that
was pretty simple that was just X and then peel BLT y label and this one I'm gonna write f of x equals
percent s and then percent Y.
So let's see how this looks.
All right this looks good.
We have all the points this time going up two point eleven or x coordinate eleven we have the x axis
label and the y axis labels showing the function all right.
So I hope you enjoyed working through this exercise.
There's a lot more to learn about graphics in Python and so keep watching.