So let's continue our exploration of using trigonometry to make beautiful simple art.
In particular we are going to make roads curves.
This is rose like the flower Rose.
So you're going to learn the formula for making roads curves.
And there's an interesting relationship between the key parameter for this formula and the number of
pedals or the number of leaves in the flower in the Rose okay.
And then the exercise will get to make some more interesting looking graphics.
All right.
So this is an example of a rose curve.
You can see so this one has four pedals and it almost looks like you know to infinity signs is like
a horizontal infinity sign and a vertical infinity sign.
So how do we create this rose curve.
Well we plot X comma Y where X and Y are defined according to these expressions.
So X EQUALS COSINE of k Times T where T is some vector you can think of it as time K is a parameter
it's a single number.
I'm going to talk about how to define this number in the next line.
So X equals cosine of k Times T times cosine of T.
So it almost looks like cosine squared but it's not if you are as long as K is not equal to 1 then this
is not cosine squared and y is equal to cosine of Katie again this same term.
And then the sign of T.
So it's a little bit tricky.
This is not the sign of the sign times a sign.
It's always the coastline of k Times T.
And then for x you multiply by cosine and for y you multiply by sine.
All right.
Pretty straightforward to implement.
Let me talk about this parameter k.
So it turns out that if k is drawn from these set of natural numbers so the integers now K doesn't have
to be an integer you'll see that in the exercises.
But if you set k to be an integer then here's the rule for the relationship between K and the number
of pedals.
So if k is an even number then the Rose curve will have two times K pedals and if k is an odd number
then the Rose curve will have K pedals.
So pretty bizarre looking rule.
So my question for you put your thinking cap on what is the parameter of K in this particular Rose curve.
Well the only possible answer is to.
So it has two times K so two times two which is four pedals.
Now you could just look at this rule and say well you know couldn't K also before but that.
So this rule is only valid if k is odd and for of course it is not an odd number.
All right.
So now let's switch to Python and we are going to implement the formula and create some rose curves
so we're still using known pi and map plot lib dot pi plot.
And let's see.
So I will set k equal to and then I'm going to set t to be known pi to linearly spaced numbers from
now of course.
This is also a bit arbitrary.
It is good to have a minimum number of cycles which would mean going through two pi and I will let you
play around with this.
This this range on your own.
I'm going to set it from zero to 4 pi in.
Let's go for 1000 steps.
All right.
So now we need to create X and Y.
So remember X was the cosine of k Times T times the cosine of T.
So that was X and then we have Y is almost exactly the same except for of course we have changed the
variable to y except for the cosine here it turns into a sine this first term remains a cosine.
All right.
So then let's plot some peel to eat up plot x comma Y I'm going to make this a nice thick magenta line.
Why does it have to be magenta.
You guessed it because magenta is basically purple which is a great color.
So BLT that axis square.
And I'm also going to turn the Axis off because we don't actually care about the values on the Axis.
We don't need to see the grid of the axis and boom there you go.
So we set k to be two and we get this for pedaled Rove's curve as I said in the video.
So let's see or in the slides so we can set k to be three.
And now we get a rose curve with three pedals.
Pretty neat if it's four.
Then we get not four pedals right.
Because remember if k is even then we get to Times K pedals.
So here we have one two three four five six seven eight which happens to be two times four.
Now I mentioned briefly before switching to Python that K does not need to be an integer.
So there you go.
Now I set k to be four point two and it makes this kind of interesting looking pattern with overlapping
pedals it even looks more like a rose now than it did before.
It's also interesting to see the line just stops here.
So I think it looks like that we should really set this parameter here for Pi to go higher.
So it seems like for the value of four point two maybe we want to set this to strike eight pi.
Okay.
So that looks pretty good now.
This looks like a full rose flower.
Very nice.
So here is your exercise for this video.
What you want to do is create nine rows curves by parameter R setting K to be different values so zero
point five one one point five.
So this is one point five.
This is two.
And so on up to four so you can see it's quite similar.
You know there's some similarities to the previous video.
You can set k to go from 0 to 4 in steps of point 5.
And you also want to put this into a three by three geometry just like what you did in the previous
video.
So good luck.
Have fun enjoy working through this exercise and producing this series of Rose curves.
So now I am going to switch to Python and walk you through how I came up with a solution to this all
right.
So let's do that here.
Now some of this code is actually gonna be pretty much exactly the same as in the previous video.
So BLT the subplots three comma three and I'm going to set this fig size also to be ten by six.
And then I'm going to specify or create these new variables Ro and call these are going to be the matrices
that I will index in order to convert from linear indices into subscript.
And that's for calling up the specific subplots.
So and P indices.
And that's going to be a three by three.
Geometry.
Now of course you are welcome to and I encourage this to try changing this geometry you can make it
three by four if you want to get more parameters and there were five by five.
That would give you twenty five different rows curves but I'm just gonna stick to three by three here.
Okay.
So now we need a loop.
I'm going to say so there's a couple of ways you could setup this loop.
You know we could set up a parameter k to go from 0 and then point 5 and then 1 and one point five.
Obviously this is not valid code but just to illustrate the concept that you could already create a
a vector a list k of numbers that go from 0 to 4 in steps of point 5.
But I'm going to accomplish this in a slightly different way which may also be the way that you did.
So I'm still going to specify a range that goes from zero to nine.
And now what I'm going to do is specify that K is I divided by two.
So that is going to give me in fact that I think I'll even print this out just to make sure that it's
super duper clear.
So here we have.
Well here we have our our axes.
You don't have to worry about those for now.
So here we say that we go.
We count from zero to eight.
And then I specify k to be I this looping index over are divided by two.
All right.
So then let's see I'm going to do a bit of copying and pasting and now I'm not redefining T because
I've already defined t up here so I'm not redefining it down here either.
So let's see just tab indent all of these lines.
So let's see what do we need to change here.
Well we already have t and we are redefining k up here.
So that looks good.
This looks good.
So this is fine except now of course we need to specify that this is going to be axis are comma c.
So then I say R equals road that Ravel and then I'm going to index the ISF element.
Now if you have no idea what I'm doing here if this looks really mysterious this is something I explained
in the exercise of the previous video.
So you might want to go back and consult.
That's OK.
So let's see that is for the plot and then for changing the axes and then I will say P L T dot show.
Let's see.
All right.
This is pretty good but it's not quite perfect.
So one thing is that this line you know a line with the three looked pretty good here when we just had
one.
But it's getting a little bit thick here in particular for this.
You know this just looks like a mess in here.
So I'm going to specify that the line with should be equal to 1 which is the default and also change
this to black lines.
OK.
So I think this looks a bit better.
However this is still not exactly what I said you should do in the slides because we are missing the
titles of all these graphs that indicate the parameter the value of k.
So let's write X R comma C dot set title and I'm going to set the title to B K equals and then use a
substitution here and then percent K like this.
All right.
This looks really good.
It's also interesting to see that when K equals zero and when K equals one we just get a pure circle.
In both cases and I encourage you to take a moment meditate on this fact this observation and think
about what that means here when K equals zero.
And when K equals 1 as I mentioned of course as always for every video in this course I encourage you
after this video to spend some time exploring different parameters of K you can explore different bounds
for tea.
You can do all sorts of things and play around if you happen to discover something really amazing and
beautiful and outstanding please please please post it to the Q and A.
I love looking at what artwork and creativity you have come up with okay but so in this video we covered
Rose curves which are these interesting curves they have a neat looking formula and a pretty interesting
rule for the parameter that that K parameter and the number of parameters are the number of petals in
the Rose curve in the next video I'm going to ask you to do a little bit of web searching to find your
own formula.
It's gonna be a slightly different approach from what I normally do in this course.
So keep watching and I will see you soon.