In the previous video I showed you how to install the anaconda program so that you can run Jupiter notebook
locally on your computer.
And in this video I'm going to show you how to use Python online.
That means you don't have to worry about installing anything on your computer.
So let me say in advance that the advantage of using Python online is, as I just mentioned, you don't
need to do any local installations.
This can be useful if let's say I don't know you have an old laptop and there isn't a lot of space on
it or you're concerned that it isn't fast enough.
Or maybe if you're using a computer at work or at your university and you don't have administrator privileges
you're not allowed to install anything new on the computer.
That said there are a few disadvantages of using Python exclusively online.
It depends on Internet availability.
So if you want to do some Python coding at a cafe somewhere in the cafe is crappy Wi-Fi then you're
kind of out of luck with Python online.
Also you have to deal with some hassle of uploading files and then downloading files again.
It's pretty easy to lose work.
I've done that before.
You know you put a good hour or so into a script and then you close the browser and you forget to download
the code and all of your precious work is gone.
So for these reasons I generally recommend a local installation of Python.
And as I mentioned in the previous video most people go with the anaconda package.
That said there is nothing particularly wrong with Python online.
And so now in the rest of this video I'm going to spend a good couple of minutes showing you a few different
options for how to use Python online and all of these things are free by the way.
You never have to pay any money or you should never pay money to use Python certainly not online so
here we are at jupyter.org/try. When you scroll down this page you'll see there are many buttons.
These are all different languages that you can test.
So here's Julia.
And, R and C++ and Ruby and so on. For this course for Python notebooks you're going to want either the classic
notebook or the Jupiter lab they're both more or less the same.
The Jupiter lab has a slightly nicer looking interface so I'm gonna show you that.
But the classic notebook is also fine it's a little bit simpler it's a little bit more kind of a I don't
know.
Shall we say 2017?
Anyway let's go to try.
Jupiter Lab. So I click here.
And eventually that's going to lead to a page that looks something like this.
Now you might get some intermediate pages getting here but just wait a moment and eventually the screen
will start to look like this.
So here you see all of these files.
These are the notebooks the data files and so on.
Here you see the main notebook that you are working with.
And here is just some reference documentation.
So I'm actually going to close this documentation just so it's less annoying.
And now here the idea is that we want to upload our own files onto the server here so you can click
on this up arrow here upload files so then you want to navigate to the folder on your file where you
have downloaded the python files from this course and then essentially you're looking for this one that
says I P Y and B so this is an I Python notebook and then you select that file click on open and now
you'll see it appears here and then you can double click on that file.
And now that file is going to appear here in this window as soon as it loads.
Okay.
There we go.
So now you can use this python notebook just the way that I'm doing it on my computer.
In the video that you're watching.
So if you click inside of a cell you can press control enter to run all the code in that cell.
And here we see here some output here and so on.
Now you can change this file as much as you want.
You can type you know obviously it is not real python code but you can change this file and then if
you want to save all of these changes you can right click on this file and select download then you
can download this file back onto your local computer.
And this is actually one of the disadvantages that I mentioned in the slide because if you just close
this tab then hopefully you'll at least get a warning that says changes you've made may not be saved
but if you're not really thinking about it and you press leave then you're going to lose all the changes
that you've made.
OK.
So this is for the Jupiter Web site.
Now there's also colaboratory, that comes from Google research. And this is a really similar concept
so there's code here.
Now the thing about the cloud is if you try to run the code it will say Google sign in required.
So basically you can use colab.research.Google.com only if you sign in with your Google
account.
So you know if you're not really comfortable with signing in and using your Google account then you
might not want to do this option.
OK.
So I'm now going to sign in with my Google account
and now I'm able to run the code that's in these notebooks now.
One thing I want to warn you about if you want to use collab then you have to be aware that some of
these special formatting that I use in this course is actually not going to work directly in code.
So let me just show you what I mean.
So display math.
Now if you don't really understand what I'm writing then don't worry I'm going to explain this throughout
the course.
So it's a B F of X and d x.
So essentially what I'm writing down here should be nicely formatted math code.
And let me run exactly this same code over here in Jupiter lab so you can see what this is going to
look like.
Maybe I'll zoom in a little bit.
So this code that I just entered creates this really nice beautiful looking latex formatted mathematical
expression with this integral sign and all sorts of nice looking things.
And when I run exactly the same code in collab it just comes out looking like this which is raw latex
code.
Now it is possible to interpret latex code in colab; it just requires a slightly different approach.
I'm not going to discuss that in the course.
You can look it up online.
It's slightly more involved but it's still possible.
So mainly for this reason I actually do not recommend using collab while you are following along with
this course.
Now that said one advantage of using collab is that if you do have a Google account and you use Google
Drive to store your files you can actually just mount your google drive directly onto your collab session.
Once you've logged in.
So that's actually pretty convenient.
OK.
The last thing that I'm going to introduce you to is Kaggle. This is another Web site Kaggle.com.
And here we can just scroll down a little bit and click on try now.
OK.
And that takes a moment to load in depending on your internet speed and how busy the Kaggle server is
and so on but you still end up with a notebook like interface that looks something like this.
And here I can actually run this code that I showed you before which worked well in Jupiter Lab. It
didn't work in Google collab and now it looks really nice in Kaggle as well.
And here also of course you can upload your own files so you can say upload notebook.
And now here you see the script that I downloaded from the course.
And you can follow along with the course in this session.
So to conclude there are several ways you can use python online.
In general I recommend using Jupyter.org/try not because it's necessarily the best but because
it's going to be the easiest for you to follow along with in the course.
That said I also generally recommend using a local installation of Python whenever possible.
Personally I find that to be easier and more convenient.