I realize this is a rather unconventional way to start a course, but I am going to dive right into an
advanced topic before even covering the basics.
And the reason why I'm doing that is because I want to get you excited to see what you are going to
be learning about throughout this course and what you will be able to do and understand by... not even
the end of this course, even towards the middle of this course.
So here I have the wikipedia page for a harmonograph.
So what is a harmonograph?
You might have seen a harmonograph before, for example at a science museum.
It's typically this kind of, you know, mechanical device that's going to draw out these beautiful looking
kind of circly, wiggly shapes like this.
Here you see a few more examples of really beautiful abstract shapes.
So how do these come about?
It's actually a pretty simple set of formulas.
It's two equations here.
You have an equation for x and an equation for y.
And it's basically some sine waves and this e thing, which turns out to be a tapering function.
It's called an exponential.
So what we are going to do now is switch to Python, and implement these directly and produce beautiful
graphs like this.
So here I am in a Jupiter notebook and I'm looking at the file called pymath
harmonograph.
So this file you can download in the resources section for this video and you can either open this file
locally on your computer using Anaconda or you can upload it online.
As I showed in the previous few videos.
Now if all of this code looks really bizarre and intimidating, then don't worry!
The whole point of this course is for you to learn exactly what this code means and how to work with
it.
So if you're totally new to Python then don't worry.
All you need to do is follow along and trust that we're going to make some beautiful graphs.
And later in the course you will understand what all this stuff means.
Okay.
So we click inside this cell this little box here. And we need to run these two lines of code and we
do that by holding down the control key and pressing enter on the keyboard.
You can see that that gives us a little number one over here.
And then we need to run this code here.
So again we click inside this cell hold down the control key and press enter and voila!! We get a
harmonograph!
This is a beautiful beautiful image that we created just by running these basically these two lines
of code.
This generates the data that is then plotted over here.
So it looks kind of like... I don't know...
To me it looks a bit like an H?
Like a cursive H.
So what I encourage you to do at the end of this video is to change these parameters here and rerun
this code and you'll come up with new harmonographs.
So let me just give you a sense of how you can change this code.
So there's three sets of parameters: A D and F. And you can see that they are lists of numbers.
So each of these parameters, A D and F, is actually a set of four numbers.
So one two three four.
They're separated by commas so you can change these values, for example I'm going to change this one
to a two and then I'm gonna press control enter to rerun this cell and that actually change the plot;
it made it a little bit wider here.
So let's see now maybe I'll change this number one to...
How about a four.
Woah! that changed it a lot.
So you can see some of these parameters will have large effects on the plots and some of them will have
small effects.
I actually preferred it like this so, I'm going to go back to this one.
So what do these parameters mean and what is going on in this formula?
So what we have in this formula is sine waves that are tapered by exponentials.
So to make that a little bit more clear, what this function is doing, I'm going to scroll down here to
this cell. And essentially what I'm going to do is visualize some of the elementary
components of this plot above.
So you can see here we are generating a variable X and a variable Y and then we generate a plot of X
by Y, so x comma y.
So to make this seem a little bit less mysterious I'm going to just copy and paste so this is literally
just copied and pasted down here. And then put this into the plot function.
So now when we run this we can see what is actually being generated by this code above.
So you can see it's like a sine wave.
It's a wiggly line it goes up and down. And the sine wave is getting faster as it goes to the right.
And it's also tapering down.
So why is the sine wave getting faster?
And why is it tapering down?
Well it's getting faster because of the way that I set up this variable here T.
And it's tapering down because of this exponential function.
So for example if we delete this exponential like this, and then rerun the code, you can see we have a
sine wave that's getting faster but it is not tapering down. And I can taper this to a larger number.
So this is D.
This means the first element of D.
So the first element of D is point 0 0 4.
So let's plot this again.
So here's what it looks like when D equals point 0 0 4.
What I'm going to do now is multiply D by let's say 5.
So I'm just making this value larger and then I rerun the code and you can see that the tapering happens
faster and it's a more intense taper.
Basically we get down to zero faster with larger numbers.
So I hope this gives you a little bit of intuition.
So essentially what we're doing is we have this function here and then we are generating -- well, we add
two of them together, and then we mix one set of parameters for X and one set of parameters for y and
then we plot one as a function of the other.
And that is how we get this plot.
All right.
So what should you do right now?
Well, what I encourage you to do is change these parameters a little bit, come up with some really beautiful
harmongraph that you are happy with.
Take a screenshot and then post it to the Q&A forum for this video.
I would be very happy to see what you have come up with and you can also, if you like, you can list the
parameters that you use or if you prefer you can leave these parameters mysterious and then we just
see your beautiful artwork.