This video is an exercise and it follows up on a previous couple of videos about generating random numbers.
So what you want to do in this video is come up with a plot of unit vectors so vectors with the length
of one that have random phase angles.
Now you already know several different ways of coming up with random numbers.
So a couple of different distributions and ways of stretching and shifting those distributions so I'm
not going to tell you exactly which parameters to use but you can figure that out.
I think there are some sets of distributions that are more sensible for generating vectors and a unit
circle with random phase angles and other vectors that are not so sensible.
So it's a bit open ended so you can pause the video switch to Python and write some code and when you're
finished writing your code then come back and you can see what I have to say about this problem.
So let's start by generating some random numbers.
I would call this variable NGS for angles not to be confused with angst which is a quality that teenagers
tend to have.
So let's say num Pi at random and let's start with normally distributed random numbers.
I will generate 100 of them and then to plot them I'm going to put this in a loop or I'm going to loop
through all of these angles and let's see it.
Each iteration of this loop but we want to do is generate a vector in the unit circle and I talked about
this in the section on algebra 2.
So the x component goes from 0 to the cosine component of the angle which is now variable.
I in this for loop and the y axis change goes from 0 to the sine component of the angle and I'm not
going to specify a color actually we'll let Python pick some random pretty colors for this plot.
All right.
So then we want to excel.
Let's see how it looks like this.
Okay so I'm kind of have a few things to say about these angles in a moment but first I want to make
this plot look a little bit nicer.
So let's say we should make the axis square for one thing.
Let's see.
Okay.
That looks a bit better.
And then I'm going to define the ranges.
Actually no I think I'll just turn this axis off.
Let's say whoops not f f but o f f all right.
Actually you know I do want to set the Axis explicitly so I will write that the axis should go from
minus one to plus 1 and minus one to plus one.
Oh right.
So now you can see the circle clearly you can see all these unit vectors with random angles.
Now why are there so few angles over here and more angles over here.
Maybe that's just how these happened to be randomly drawn.
So I'll run this again a few times and you can see that it's basically always the same we always get
not zero vectors there are some vectors pointing off to the left but relatively few and it seems like
there's more clustering around here and now the reason why that's happening is because this is a normal
distribution that I'm drawing from so that means that most of these angles are close to zero and zero
for an angle is pointing over here and these values are vectors with angles over here pointing off to
the left are going to have angle values close to PI so close to around 3 and you will recall from a
few videos where I talked about normal distributions that values around 3 are relatively unlikely.
Okay so that means that I would argue that a normal distribution of random numbers is not really.
Well it's not wrong but it's not really the most appropriate distribution to draw from for random phase
angles like this random angles for these vectors.
So therefore let's just get rid of this in here and make this uniformly distributed numbers all right.
And now it looks kind of funny.
Actually I wouldn't say funny.
This looks like a fan.
It looks like a beautiful colorful fan.
Again this isn't really wrong because I didn't give you any instructions for what the right answer should
be.
However I think you can also agree with me that this is probably not the most appropriate distribution
for phase angles on the unit circle.
So what is a better distribution.
Well I think a better distribution will cover the entire range cover the entire circle basically randomly
and uniformly.
So therefore what we need to do is convert this distribution from a range of zero to one to a range
of zero to two pi and two pi is sensible because that's going to go all the way around the circle.
So what I'm going to do is multiply this by two times.
Now I'm pie the pie.
And now we get vectors that are in theory uniformly distributed all around the circle of course you
can see there's a gap over here and there's some higher concentration of vectors over here.
But that's really just because of the random features of generating this distribution here.
So you can run it again and you can see that these little gaps will appear in different places.
And if you run more vectors if you select more vectors from this uniform distribution then that's going
to fill out this circle even more fully.
Now I am specifying these angles here in terms of radians but it's possible that you are more comfortable
working with angles in degrees.
So if you want to know how to convert between radians and degrees then keep watching because that is
the entire purpose of the next video.