After going through the previous two videos I guessed you are now fairly comfortable with plotting individual
points on a graph and what could be better than plotting two points on a graph.
How about drawing a line that connects those two points.
That is the big goal of this video.
I'm going to show you how to create lines in graphs.
It turns out it's really easy.
And once you get the hang of it you'll be able to do it with no problem along the way.
You will also learn a little bit more about plotting lines in Python or plotting in general in Python
including how to come up with any arbitrary color that you want.
So the way to think about drawing a line in a graph in Python is to consider that.
Also in math you need two points to define a line.
So in Python the way you specify a line is by coming up with two points.
The start point and the stop point and that's why I call this the line and start stop form.
I will show you in the next video How to generate lines using the slope intercept form but for now I'm
going to show you how to create a line using two sets of points okay.
So the idea is that you start with this point and this point so let's call this point p 1 the coordinate
is minus three minus one.
And this we will call point b 2 and there and his coordinate is 4 4.
So then to draw this line you have to specify the x coordinate of this start to stop points.
So that would be here.
The x coordinates and then you specify the y coordinates.
All right.
So let's switch to Python and see how this gets implemented.
So anytime you are doing plotting or almost anytime you're doing plotting in python you are probably
going to be using the map plot lib that pi plot module so you will pretty much always have to start
your code with a line that looks something like this.
All right.
So what I'm gonna do now is specify these two points so p 1 was minus 3 comma minus 1 and then p 2.
This is just the points that I discussed in the slides a moment ago is for comma 4.
OK so now you might think that it should be something as simple as this P1 comma P2 and then I type
plot show and technically that does draw a line but it doesn't really look like it's the right line.
It doesn't look like what we expect it to look like.
So you expect that the line would look something like this like what I showed in the slides.
So what is going wrong here.
Well what's going wrong here is that this is actually technically correct code but it's not doing what
you think it should be doing.
What we actually need to specify is the two x coordinates here and the two y coordinates here.
So in fact what this code is doing or the way that Python is interpreting this code is that the x coordinates
are minus 3 to minus 1.
You see that here minus 3 to minus 1 and python is interpreting the y coordinates to be 4 to 4.
But actually that's not really what we want.
The x coordinates from point 1 To point to are minus 3 to 4.
So really the right way to do this is to list the x coordinates like this.
So the first element of p 1 and then the first element of p 2.
And then we need the y coordinates.
So that's going to be exactly the same list of numbers but it's going to be the second element instead
of the first element.
Okay.
And now we get the line that you would have expected based on how I wrote out these points.
Okay so let's say you really don't like blue.
I don't know blue makes you feel sad or something that you want to change this color so you can pick
a few of the built in colors like red or there's also K for black.
But what if you want to specify the color however you want.
So for that you can use color.
So you just write the word color and then you provide a list of three numbers and that corresponds to
our G.B. or red green blue value.
So for example you can type 1 comma zero comma zero.
This means 100 percent red zero percent green and zero percent blue.
And here's what that line looks like.
So then you can do about 100 percent red and 20 percent saturation on green.
Well okay.
It's a little bit orange ish.
Let's see if we do.
Point seven for blue.
This is starting to look slowly a little bit better.
Let's see if we do.
Point four all right.
This is looking good.
I like this shade of purple.
However I want to see more of this purple this line is way too thin for me.
So therefore I'm going to type line with equals how about 30.
Okay.
That's maybe a little bit excessive.
Let's scale it back a little bit.
How about a line width of 10.
Still a little bit comically thick.
Maybe let's go for a line with the five.
Okay.
This is starting to look pretty good but I think you see where this is going.
Now I want to make this graph a little bit nicer looking according to properties of the axis that I
showed you how to change in the previous video.
So let's make this a square axis and then the axis the square shape and then I'm gonna set the Axis
limits to be how about six all around.
So the X axis limit will be minus six to plus X and the y axis limit will be minus six to plus six.
All right.
So I'd say this looks pretty good.
If you want you can spend some more time sprucing this thing up a bit but I'm going to stop here and
move on to something else.
So what I want to show you now is basically just a bit of an extension of what you learned in this video
and what you learned in the past couple of videos.
So now let's imagine that we have a single point so I'll call this X equals three and Y equals.
I don't know how about five.
So you already learned from the previous video how to plot a dot at that coordinates something to say
peel to dot plot X comma Y and let's make this a red circle and I'll say BLT dot show by the way.
Probably the most common mistake to make when you are generating these plots in Python is to accidentally
type plot here instead of BLT.
So you have to always be looking out for this kind of an error simple typo.
So here we go here's our red dot in an otherwise empty white universe.
Now what I'd like to do is draw a line from the zero zero point.
So from the origin of the two dimensional space to this dot.
So the way that I'm going to do that is by typing P.L. teed up plot.
Now we have to think again about drawing lines so what are the x coordinates for this line.
Well it starts at zero.
And it goes to X is variable X and then likewise the y coordinates we need to specify to y coordinates
to draw a line.
And I want that to go from the origin to y well to you know this variable Y so the number five.
And then I'll also make this red.
Okay.
So now we get this line.
It goes from the origin so from 0 0 up to this line.
But I would like to make this a little bit more looking like you know what you might see in a textbook.
So I'm going to start off by actually I think I'll even just copy and paste this because I think these
are pretty good.
Axis limits and I'm also gonna add a grid.
Okay.
So this is looking a little bit better but you know when you see a plot that looks like this in a textbook
or online or and of course whatever you often see that these 0 lines are thicker than the other grid
lines.
So how can we do that.
Well one way to solve this is by drawing more lines on top of this plot and we make those lines black.
So let's see how to do that so I'm going to say peel teed up plot.
So let's start with a horizontal line that goes here.
So the X coordinates will go from minus six to plus six.
So X goes from minus six to six and then the Y actually also goes from minus 66.
And so what are the y coordinates going to be here.
If we think about where we want this line to go it's gonna be flat here.
So it has to go from minus six to plus six.
But it actually never changes on the y axis so it stays at zero on the y axis.
So that means that this coordinate is just zero comma zero and then we make this a black line.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
That's our horizontal line.
And then you can probably imagine how we're going to make the vertical line essentially it's the same
thing.
We just swap the X and the y coordinates here.
So now from X or on the x axis we always stay at zero.
And on the y axis we go from minus six to plus six.
All right.
So I think this is starting to look pretty professional there are two exercises for this video and basically
that those exercises are to draw this graph and to draw this graph to draw this graph.
You have to implement this function so y equals the square root of the absolute value of x and I implement
this for the values of x.
So integers have X ranging from minus 20 to plus 20.
If you want to reproduce this exactly then you can use all of these numbers.
These values of x but of course you're welcome to play around add more numbers or fewer numbers.
You can change the colors if you want.
The important part is making sure that you get this formula correct and you'll get a graph that looks
something like this.
And then the second exercise is basically just to create this box here with these colors.
So it's green and then red and magenta and black.
All right.
So now is your last opportunity to pause the video before I switch to Python and start showing you all
of my secrets or at least you know my solution to these two problems.
So the first graph that we have to create was that kind of beautiful looking and almost looks like a
little bit of a bird.
So I'm going to specify X to be a range from minus twenty to twenty one and then that's gonna give me
integers between minus 20 and plus 20.
So then I'm going to do this in a for loop I'm going to implement this in a for loop where each element
of the for loop draws a line from the origin to that point.
So let's say for i in X we can write P L T dot plot and now we want the line on the X to go from zero
to I and the y component of the line should also start from zero and then the second part is the implementation
of that formula.
So that was first we take the absolute value of x or each element of x which gets called I here.
Actually maybe I should call this X..
It's a little bit more informative and it's really clear that X Y are indices within X or individual
elements within this range X OK.
So then this and now we need to take the square root of this.
So if you like you could import the number pi module and do this as an P..
That square root.
However you can also implement the square root by taking the power of one half.
OK.
So I believe that this is going to work.
Let's see you peel BLT the show and then Yep this looks really nice.
And now there's all sorts of other interesting things that you could do with this to explore this further.
You could try changing the range this go up to like two hundred or something.
So that's going to change the shape a bit.
There's lots of things you can do you can specify the colors but I'm not going to do any of that right
now.
Instead I'm going to move on to the second exercise which was to draw a square.
So drawing a square is actually not so difficult.
And there are multiple ways to draw squares in Python it turns out that there's a module called Turtle
like the little animal that you can use to also draw squares for you.
But I'm going to do it here manually and that is by specifying each line individually.
So let's say BLT dot plot and now I'm going to draw.
Actually let's let me scroll up here and let's think about it.
So we're gonna use the same principle that I used to draw these lines except we specify them to be smaller
so we can make a square that goes let's say from here or actually I'll make it here.
So it'll just go from zero up to two over to two down and then back to zero.
So that means each line gets drawn by fixing the values on one axis and drawing the values on the other
axis by two.
So let's say let's draw the first line from 0 to 2 So X equals 0 2 x equals 2 and then Y equals 2 to
2 so why stays on the 2 line and that draws a horizontal line that looks like this.
So this is like the top of the square here to draw the bottom of the square.
I'm actually just going to copy and paste this code and notice and I'm gonna keep the x values the same
I'm going to change the y values to zero zero and I'll make this a black line.
So now we have a set of parallel lines here and you can see this is the top and the bottom of the square.
So now how do we draw.
Let's start with the left line here.
So the left line is defined by x equals zero 2 x equals zero.
Right because the entire line the x axis or the x coordinate stays at zero and the y coordinate is going
to go from zero to two groups that should be at period common that period.
Okay.
And this one was green if I remember correctly.
All right.
And then we have one more leg to draw and I will copy and paste and change this to two comma two and
this has to be two comma two on the x coordinates because I want the line to go here.
So it's gonna go from zero to two on the y axis and just stay at 2 on the x axis and that one will be
magenta or this nice purple color.
So that's for the square.
I would like to change a few things about this axis.
Let's say plot the axis square.
And how about plot dot axis.
Let's set this to be the x limits will go from minus three to five and the Y limits will also go from
minus three to five.
All right.
So that's looking a bit better and now I think I'll also put a title on here.
So how about P.L. t that title and let's set this title to a colorful square
nice.
So now you've extended your knowledge of graphics in python from coordinates two lines in the next video.
I'm gonna show you how to create lines using the slope intercept form that you often come across in
your algebra textbooks and math courses.