In this video you are going to learn about matrices and about learning how to work with matrices in
Python. Matrices are super important for mathematical programming and scientific programming.
So this video is going to be a great introduction to matrices.
Now let's start off with a little bit of terminology.
When I say the matrix I'm not actually referring to this old movie from the 90s. The sequels were admittedly
a little bit questionable, but the original movie was great. Anyway....
This is not what I'm referring to when I talk about The Matrix or matrices.
In fact what I'm referring to is something that's maybe a little bit less exciting, less entertaining,
but much more important. A Matrix is simply an ordered set of numbers.
Here you see two examples of matrices.
You can see that there are rows and there are columns of numbers in this matrix.
There's more columns and fewer rows.
And, well, here as well.
And sometimes you see matrices referred to more abstractly just by using these brackets here and having
a little bit of discoloration inside. The word ordered
here is important.
So these two matrices are totally distinct from each other.
These are not the same matrix.
They do contain all the same numbers.
So the set of numbers is the same in this matrix.
and in this matrix, but I've swapped the one and the four here.
So these two are not the same matrix.
If you are studying matrices then you're probably studying linear algebra. Linear Algebra is one of my
favorite topics in mathematics.
It's beautiful.
It links between algebra and geometry really nicely, and linear algebra is also really important for
modern applications. Linear algebra
really all starts from the study of matrices, Working with matrices, operations on matrices, storing data
in matrices, and -- importantly -- extracting information that's embedded into a matrix.
Linear Algebra is really important for Data Science and machine learning and artificial intelligence
computer graphics and so on.
Basically anything that's digital is built on linear algebra and linear algebra all starts from this
very simple concept of putting numbers into rows and columns in a matrix. Matrices are typically referred
to by uppercase letters.
So you might see the letter A referring to this matrix. As I mentioned, matrices have rows and they have
columns going up and down so the rows go left and right the columns go up and down. When referring to
individual elements inside of a matrix,
you always index the matrix by the row first and then the column.
So for example, the element in Matrix a -- notice when referring to a whole matrix you typically use an
uppercase letter and for an individual element of a matrix you would use a lowercase letter --
so the element in the second row and the first column is 0.
So the second row and first column is 0.
Here's how you would say that: the element in the second row in the first column of matrix A. So it
always gets indexed by row and then by column.
Now this is something that creates a little bit of confusion initially in Python and that's because
Python starts counting and starts indexing at 0. So here we are in Python.
I have already imported the sympy and numpy modules, and the display and math functions from the
python dot display module.
OK so to create a matrix you specify the matrix each row at a time and the rows have to be encased inside
square brackets.
So for example I can say one comma two.
So this will create the first row and if I want a second row then I use a comma and then I write three
comma four.
So this is the first row and this is the second row.
Now this is not quite enough to create a matrix.
And that's because Python doesn't yet know that these two things go together.
So therefore we actually need another set of square brackets to go around each of these rows.
So it may look a little confusing at first because of all of these square brackets lying around, but
the outermost square bracket indicates that we are creating a matrix and then these inner brackets are
for each individual row.
So let's see what this looks like that looks like this.
Now this turns out to be.
I'll show you what class this is.
This is actually a list.
It's a list of numbers.
But we want this to be represented as a matrix.
And so to do that we actually need to use a function in numpy called np dot array. That's going
to convert this list into a numpy array.
It's an n d array for n dimensional array.
So that's what a matrix is stored as.
So now I can type.
Print a.
And now here you see the same numbers but they're arranged according to rows.
And now what I'm going to do next is display this a little bit nicer using latex.
So let's say display and then math.
And now we convert this matrix into latex code using sym dot latex.
All right.
I forgot that we need to convert this from numpy into sympy.
So to convert something into sympy we use sympify.
And this is a function that I've introduced you to before.
So we have our matrix A that's stored as a numpy array, and then we convert it into a sympy object
using the sympify function and then we get latex code corresponding to that sympy object and
then display that here.
So now you see this nice looking matrix, where the first row is one two, the second row is three four.
The next thing I want to show you is how to create an empty matrix, or a matrix of all zeros.
So I'm going to use a function called n p, numpy dot zeros. And the way this function works is that
you can input sizes of the matrix.
So let's say we want a four by six matrix and it's going to be a four by six matrix of zeros.
So there are four rows and six columns.
So you see one two three four rows six columns and these are all zeros because they use the function
zeros.
So let's set this equal to a variable.
So I will say mat equals numpy zeros.
Then we can see what that looks like and now what we can do is assign different numbers to individual
elements inside this matrix.
So for example, let's say I want to set the element in row 0 and column 1.
Now remember because of Python indexing this actually means the first row and the second column -- equals
how about... let's make it the number two.
So now let's see what mat looks like.
So now you can see it's almost all zeros, it's almost a matrix full of zeros, except for this one element
here, which is the number two.
And now I can specify, let's say 2 and 4 and I'll set that to be... how about 7.
So now what I've done is specify that the third row and the Fifth Column, which is this element over
here, becomes number seven.
Now in this case we lost the two that I previously specified, because this matrix got re initialized
to zeros.
So let's try adding adding this back in and say 0,1 equals 2.
And now we see that we have this element equals two from this line and this element equals seven from
this line.
So that's about manually setting each individual item two particular values.
Of course this wouldn't be very useful if we couldn't use variables.
So I'd like to now quickly show you how to use variables to populate a matrix and in particular I'm
going to do this using a for loop.
So let's say num range equals range 0 to 2.
And now basically what I'm going to do is setup a double for loop to loop over rows and over columns
and basically fill in this matrix.
So let's say for I in num range and for J in, actually I'll make these even a little bit more interpretable.
So row I and let's call this column I also in num range and this should be, I know what I'm going to
do is specify that the row I f element column I if element equals let's say minus 1 to the power of
I row I plus call I.
So this is a kind of weird looking expression -- minus 1 to the power of the i-th row and the i-th column, but
you will see that it starts to produce an interesting looking pattern.
So let's see what that looks like here.
So this is all zeros out here and seven out here and then here we have a little box up here where we
get one minus one minus one and one.
Now we've only filled in this little part of the matrix because I've only actually looped through two
elements zero and one so I can set this a little bit bigger.
Let's set this up to four for example.
And now you can see there's there's kind of an interesting pattern that's starting to emerge, where we
get one minus one, one, minus one And then on the next row is minus one plus one minus one plus one.
So in fact when you set up a double for loop like this and specify elements in the matrix to be minus
1 to the power of the row plus the column index you get this alternating pattern of minus ones and plus
ones.
This is actually one way to make a checkerboard, which is pretty neat.
The exercise for this video is to revisit this function that you have seen in a previous video.
So you'll remember that from that previous video I gave you this function it's a function of two variables.
And I said you should create a double for loop over X and Y where X and Y are in a set of 0 1 and 2
and then you print out all the results for all the possible combinations of X being equal to 0 1 and
2 and y be equal to 0 1 and 2.
So what you're going to do in this video for this exercise is essentially repeat that formulation.
But now all of the results are going to be organized into a matrix. So you can see by looking at this
matrix that the rows correspond to different values of x and the columns correspond to different values
of Y.
And that's also sensible.
For example, when you look at this third column it's all zeros.
That is when y equals two.
Then you get two minus two zero, so then you have zero times this term.
So of course the output of the function is going to be zero.
Right.
So good luck, pause the video, and work your way through this.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I solved this exercise.
All right.
So the first thing we need to do is to define this function.
So I'm going to first create these symbolic variables for x and y and I think sometime previously I
probably showed you this with a comma and this is just to show you that you can also have a space in
between these symbolic variables here.
Now we create our function.
So that was four plus X times two minus Y then we need to have our range of numbers the set of numbers.
Let's call this X Y set equals range zero comma 3, because it's 0 1 and 2 so we those are the numbers
we want 0 1 and 2 so we can use range zero comma three.
OK.
So now we need to initialize this matrix.
So let's call this outmat
for output matrix.
I'm going to specify that to be a zeros matrix.
And now I know that this needs to be three by three.
But in fact I'm going to use the len function for length and say length of X Y set comma length of X
Y sets.
Okay.
So now before going forwards, I want to run this code and see if we get any errors.
We don't get any errors.
And now I want to check out what this output matrix looks like.
And this looks good.
It's three by three three rows corresponding to X and three columns that will correspond to the different
values of Y.
All right.
So we are now ready to set up the for loops. Let's say for I in X Y set and also for j in X Y set.
Here is where we evaluate the function.
And if you got stuck a little bit here then you can consult that previous video that was about substitution.
So let's see.
This was f x y dot subs.
And here we needed to input a dictionary.
So X gets replaced with i and then Y gets replaced with J.
And then the idea is the output of this function goes into the output matrix in row i and column J.
All right.
So I just ran this cell and I didn't get any error messages.
So that's a good sign.
And now let's see what this thing looks like. So first let's just print it out so outmat.
Just to make sure it already looks good.
So there's the eights and the fours and the zeros in this column.
So this seems correct.
And now I just want to make this look a little bit nicer.
So display math and now I'm going to need to convert this into latex.
But before I do that, I need to convert this from a numpy array into a sympy object. So simple dot
sympify.
And then we have a bunch of end parentheses here... and brilliant!
This looks really nice.
I hope you enjoyed this video, and I hope you found it interesting to learn a little bit about matrices.
You will learn more about matrices as you go through this course.
And as you start using Python more and more you will see that matrices are all over the place.
They're really important for programming.