Let us begin our exploration of trigonometry by talking about what I consider to be the most annoying
part of trigonometry and that is dealing with radians versus degrees.
I will start with a quick review of what these two things mean how they are related to each other which
leads to a couple of simple formulas for converting between radians and degrees.
And in the exercise you will learn more about writing functions in Python.
So here we have a circle that say this is the unit circle.
And the question is how far is it around here.
What is the distance around this curve.
Measured in angles.
So it turns out so.
Yeah.
If you were going to walk around this entire circle now it turns out the answer to the total angular
distance around this circle is well it's either two pi radians or it's 360 degrees.
Well I shouldn't say or these are actually exactly the same thing.
They're just different measures.
Sometimes you see angles reported in radians and sometimes in degrees.
So this leads to the fairly straightforward way to convert between radians and degrees.
We start by considering that two pi radians is the same thing as 360 degrees.
So this is in units of radians units of degrees.
So if we wanted to convert between them and ask you know how many radians are there or how many degrees
are there in one radians then what you have to do is divide both sides of this equation by 2 pi and
that leads to this formula that radians equals 360 degrees divided by 2 pi which you can actually simplify
just by dividing by two to get to one hundred and eighty divided by Pi.
And of course you could convert the other way.
So if you want to convert from radians into degrees then you divide both sides of this equation by 360
and essentially you just end up with the reciprocal.
So one degree is pi over one hundred and eighty radians.
So let's switch to Python and implement these two fairly straightforward formulas.
For now we will use the NUM pi module.
I'm actually not going to use the MATLAB live module in this part of the video but it will be used in
the exercise so we might as well already load it in.
OK so let's say we want to convert from degrees to radians so we start with degrees and let's start
with 180.
That's a pretty simple degree to convert and then the formula is degrees.
Times pi divided by s num pi pi divided by one hundred and eighty.
And so this conforms to what we expect.
So 180 degrees is halfway around the circle and that corresponds to Pi which is also halfway around
the circle and let's print this out again just so we don't lose practice with printing.
So I will say percent G degrees is percent G radians.
So then we need to substitute deg for deg times pi divided by 180.
Okay.
So there you go.
And now you know it's kind of interesting you can test different values.
This corresponds to one quarter pi and who knows what this number of degrees means but it happens to
be one point two times tend to the eleven radians.
Okay.
So that's actually a pretty big number.
And that seems a little bit weird because one full with around the circle is only two pi.
So in fact what we're doing here is looping around the circle many many many many many times.
And so therefore it actually makes sense to convert this back into a number that is between 0 and 2
pi.
So how do we do that the way that we do that is by using the modulus.
So what we want to do is take this number divided by two pi and then see what the remainder is.
So let's say red equals and now I'm going to just move this up here.
So this is a variable for radiant.
So so far I'm not doing anything remarkably different.
And now what I want to do is convert this from this number that is potentially really large to whatever
is the remainder after dividing this number by two pi.
So we write red percent and then known pi times 2.
So 2 pi.
OK so then we find out that this is four point eight one radians.
And again the reason why this makes sense is because the more you go around the circle or I should say
each time you go round the circle you're passing the same angle multiple times.
So therefore although it's not technically incorrect to say that some angle is you know what whatever
this number ends up being this really huge number of radians it is more sensible it's more interpretable
to bring this back into the scale between 0 and 2 pi.
OK so this is for converting degrees to radians and now let's go the other way.
So let's say we specify the angle already in radians and I'll start with using PI because then we know
the answer is going to end up being 180.
So now we want to convert from radians 2 degrees so degrees equals one hundred and eighty times the
radians divided by pi and let's just see what this is.
All right.
So this confirms what we already know has to be the right answer which is that pi is equal.
So pi radians is equal to 180 degrees.
And again we can specify this to be let's call this.
How about for pi.
So now we end up getting seven hundred and twenty degrees.
And again this number isn't really wrong but this means we're going around the circle twice so therefore
it makes sense to use the modulus operator.
And now we want to go or we want to divide not by 2 pi but by 360 degrees because that corresponds to
once around the circle.
So then we get a degree of zero.
And that also makes sense because for Pi is exactly twice around the circle which means you end up at
an angle of zero.
All right.
So it turns out that I've been making your life a little bit more difficult than it actually needs to
be.
And that's because none Pi has a built in function to do all of this or at least this part for us.
So I can write.
Red equals num pi dot.
Now we want to convert from degrees to radians.
And let me bring this back to some sensible numbers.
So let's say one hundred and eighty and I know that the answer is going to be pi or three point 1 4
and then let's see.
So here we discovered that seven hundred and twenty degrees corresponds to zero pi.
So if I write 720 here huh.
Now this function here is actually returning the radians directly.
It's not going to give us the radiant value bound between 0 and 2 pi.
So if you like this is not mandatory but if you like you can also add this modulus operator in here
as well.
And that will give us back 0 radians.
OK.
And now you will also not be surprised to learn that the function to convert the other way is going
to be called RAD 2 deg for radians two degrees
in this video.
You learned or got a review of converting between radians and degrees for trigonometric angles.
Now in the interest of time I decided to put the exercise into a separate video because that's a relatively
involved exercise that involves writing functions not only to convert between radians and degrees but
also to generate plots of vectors.
So stay tuned.
Don't go too far come back and watch the next video to learn more python and math.