This video contains the exercise that follows up on the previous video.
So in the last video you learned about simulating a coin flip for a fair coin and a weighted coin or
a biased coin and what you want to do in this exercise is essentially extend that idea to create a weighted
die or a biased die.
Now to be clear I'm using die here as a noun not as a verb the noun die is the singular of dice.
So it's like that little cube with numbers on all six faces and you roll it it's in board games and
you see it in casinos anyway.
So you want to create a way to die.
That is twice as likely to land on the number one as any other number.
And then you want to simulate a dye roll 50 times so you roll the dice 50 times and then you want to
make a probability graph and also an empirical proportion graph.
So the result is going to look something like this.
Now the black bars will be different of course for yours but the purple line should actually be the
same.
So let me walk you through what this plot shows.
So here we have the dice face.
So numbers 1 through 6 and then you see on the y axis it's either the probability or the proportion
for the Purple Line.
It's the true underlying probability.
So it's the probability that you will get the number one when rolling this die.
So that's like the theoretical distribution or the probability.
So that is 28 percent for the number one and 14 percent for all these other numbers.
And then for your experiment where you roll the dice 50 times you're unlikely to get exactly that theoretical
distribution.
Instead you're going to get some empirical proportion.
And in this particular case when I made this graph we happened to get for example 36 percent of roles
had the number one 10 percent of the roles had number two and so on.
And then if you like this is a bit of an extra challenge.
You can also figure out a way to get the text to look nice inside the bars like this.
So here I have the actual result is 36 percent 10 percent and so on.
You can see the text printed in here.
So now is your chance to positive video.
Have fun.
Good luck working through this exercise.
Reproducing a graph that looks something like this and now I'm going to switch to Python and show you
how I solved this problem.
So there are several ways to correctly solve this exercise.
I'm going to walk you through my solution and I'll show you what I did.
But I want to be clear that you could have come up with a very different solution and still arrived
at the same correct result.
So I'm going to start by defining a few variables.
So n is 50 that's the number of roles for our day.
I'm going to initialize a variable a vector called outcomes and this is just going to have six elements.
So the way that I'm going to set this up is I'm going to run through the experiment Fifty times roll
the dice fifty times and if we got for example a three then I'm going to say outcomes index three equals
itself plus 1.
I'm going to build up the distribution this way.
It's a slightly different approach from my approach to the previous video where I had a whole matrix
in which I saved the result for each individual experiment run.
OK so that is for the outcomes.
Now what I want to do is come up with a vector of the pure probabilities.
So this is like the theoretical distribution.
I call this pure probs and this is going to be an array.
And now the idea is that we want six numbers and the first number is going to be twice as likely to
appear as any of the other ones individually.
So let's see that's 1 2 3 4 5.
Yeah.
So this is not a probability distribution.
This is just an array of numbers to convert this to a probability distribution.
Like I showed in the previous video we need to order actually that was in I think the first video of
this section.
We need to make sure that all of these numbers together some 2 1 and the way to do that is by dividing
each element in this vector by these sum over all of the elements in the vector.
So pure props and now we can take a look at this pure probs and see that this is point 2 8 and then
the rest of these are all point 1 4.
Now it's time to run our experiment.
So I'm going to loop over for i in range n now the way that I'm going to set this up is actually by
rolling a seven sided die.
So let's start with this.
Roll a seven sided die.
So I call this die roll equals numb Pieta random and now I'm gonna say Rand inch.
And this is going to be a random number between 0 and 6 so I write zero comma seven because it's exclusive
on the upper bound.
So this is going to produce a random number that's between 0 and 6.
Now why am I rolling a seven sided die when this is really about a six sided die.
Well what I'm going to do is say if the die roll equals six then I'm going to force the die roll to
be equal to zero.
So this is how I'm imposing this bias.
So we say if you ever get the number six from this random integer then set that 6 0 force that this
variable die roll to be equal to zero.
Now because the number is 0 through 6 are all equally likely to occur whenever 6 happens I set it to
0 and that means that a die roll equal to zero is going to happen approximately twice as often as any
other number.
Again this is one way that I am showing you how to solve this problem.
There are several other correct solutions that you can also use.
All right.
And now I'm going to say that the outcomes for this variables so now I'm using this variable die roll
as an index into this factor outcomes equals.
Now I want to write something like this equals itself plus 1.
So this is correct coding there's nothing wrong with that but we can make it a little bit more efficient
by saying that this variable plus equals one.
Okay.
So now before going any further I want to run all of this code and just print out what this variable
outcomes is going to be.
So this is pretty interesting you can see now outcomes is 13 10 6 10 6 5.
So that means that I roll this die.
It's a seven sided die.
But I forced the top value of six to be equal to zero corresponding to the die Phase 1 and that is the
mechanism by which I implemented a biased six sided coin so phase one occurred or rolled 13 times.
Phase 2 rolled 10 times.
And so on.
All right.
So that's actually the end of the computational part of this project.
What I want to do now is basically just a lot of plotting.
So let's start by plotting a bar of the outcomes.
And I'm going to write outcomes divided by n.
And the reason why I want this to be divided by n is so that this will still be interpretable the y
axis values will still be interpretable even if I change the number of experiments to run.
So let's see.
OK so I actually have to write the x axis labels in addition to the y axis coordinates or the heights
of the bar.
So I'm going to set this up as a range from 1 to 7.
And the reason why I'm setting this to be 1 through 7 instead of 0 through 6 is that I want this to
correspond to the numbers on a on a die.
So those start at 1 and go up to 6.
All right.
So these need to be black.
So I will say color equals K for black and the label is going to be the empirical distribution which
is also called the proportion.
So this is the empirical proportion that we actually observed in this experiment.
And now we need to plot on top of this the same exact access range.
So 1 through 6 and now it's going to be the pure probabilities and let's make this magenta with a square
and a line connecting them and marker size equals 10 just to give us slightly bigger markers and the
label is going to be theoretical or probability.
All right.
That should be plot.
So this is starting to look pretty good.
Now you might object to the fact that I drew lines between these dots and that is a fair objection because
there is no such thing on a tie as a face corresponding to three point five.
So formally technically this actually should look like this.
However sometimes for visual reasons it's also useful to you know sort of bend these rules a little
bit and draw lines.
I think this looks a little bit nicer.
All right.
Let's see.
So I'm going to set the x axis labels to be the di did face to be face and P.L. t the Y label is going
to be the probability ability or pro portion and then I will turn on the labels so legend.
Okay so so far this is starting to look really good.
The only thing that we're missing here is the little white text underneath or just underneath the tops
of these black bars.
So to put those text labels there I'm going to use the function BLT.
Text and I'm going to do this in a loop.
So let's start by writing for I in range.
Now this range has to go one through six because I'm gonna specify the x axis coordinates to be this
looping index variable I so P L T dot plot.
Now we want to plot at coordinates I.
And then the y axis coordinate is going to be defined by the outcome.
So it's gonna be outcomes and then it's the highest outcome divided by n.
And I'm even gonna just start this just to make sure that we get part of this right because this is
actually not correct.
And I want you to see that is not going to be correct.
Okay.
So in fact we get an error.
And the problem here this was actually not the error I was expecting.
The problem is that I'm using the wrong function.
This should be BLT text.
Okay so the problem is that index 6 is out of range so this needs to be I minus 1 because we're starting
here with 1 but the first index of course is 0.
Okay.
So you can actually kind of see the bottom of the text high here.
So we actually need to do is set the y axis coordinate to be a little bit below the actual outcomes.
So I played around a little bit and figured out that point 0 2 5 is a pretty reasonable distance to
go underneath so that's looking good.
Except it's a little bit small so I'm going to change the font size to be twelve.
Now it's a little more legible.
You can also see the text here is actually starting at the center.
But I want this to be center aligned so I'm going to write horizontal alignment equals center.
Okay so this is starting to look pretty good.
The text is all in the right place.
It's just the wrong text.
So obviously this is high.
This needs to say whatever the actual proportion is.
Now you can also see this line is starting to get a little bit long and it's going to get longer.
So I am going to set this to print out into the next line of code just to make sure that it's still
readily visible.
Okay so let's replace this high with some text.
So what does that text going to be.
So I can just set it to be the outcomes of I minus 1 divided by n and let's see how this looks.
So that's looking pretty good.
It's getting there but I want this to be printed in percent so in the slide I showed the picture had
a percent sign here.
So it's a little weird to get a percent sign because we already have a percent sign here.
What would happen if we just write a percent sign.
Well then we get an error that says incomplete format.
In fact python is expecting some formatting letter after the percent sign like for example.
Percent G.
So actually the way that you can indicate a percent sign is percent percent.
Okay so this is starting to look good except it's not actually technically correct because this numbers
the dye Phase 3 doesn't appear.
Point one percent it's point 1 proportion so to convert this into an actual percent we need to multiply
this by 100.
So I'm going to say 100 times the proportion okay.
And this is looking much better and now the last thing that I want to do is just round this to the nearest
percentage point.
So therefore I'm going to just convert this whole thing into an integer.
So this is a floating point representation.
I'm going to convert it into an integer and that's going to give us these numbers.
In percent so I think overall this looks really good.
I'm going to call this the successful completion of this project.
I hope you enjoyed this and the previous videos you learned about generating binary distributions and
then in the exercise in this video you learned how to extend this to any arbitrary number of outcomes
with probabilities that you get to define and you also got a very very small introduction into the panda's
data frame in particular importing data into append US data frames and doing a little bit of manipulation
and table formatting.