Continuing along with the discussion of how to plot lines in Python.
In this video I'm going to show you a different way of plotting lines.
And that is the slope intercept form the slope intercept form essentially looks like this and that is
the way that you are normally presented with lines in math and also in statistics.
So you often think about the equation of a line as being Y equals M X plus b so X of course is the x
axis here and M is usually called the slope.
And that basically just tells you how much you have to go up for each unit that you go over.
So it's sometimes called rise over run but it's basically just the tilt of this line if it's positive
it's going upwards.
If it's negative it's going downwards and then we have this other parameter here B which is often called
The Intercept.
And that basically just corresponds to where the line goes through the x axis when the y axis equals
zero.
And then you can see from the equation.
So when x equals zero then this term goes to zero.
So then you just have Y equals B.
So what x equals zero then Y equals B.
So no big surprise.
We will need the map plot lib that pie plot module in this video.
Okay.
And so I'm just gonna put a comment up here as a reminder.
So the goal is to draw a line using the formula Y equals M X plus B.
So let's say that our x values will go from minus five to plus five.
So the line is gonna be drawn from minus five to plus five on the y axis.
And then I'm going to specify m to be two and b to be 1.
Now you might think that it should be something as simple as writing out Y equals M times x plus B.
That certainly seems like it should be the right answer.
However if you run this code you'll get a strange error it's a type error and python is saying can only
concatenate lists to list not integers.
And essentially what's happening is that this variable x is a list and so it's not really possible to
do these mathematical operations on a list.
The way you expect it to work like this now it is possible to get a form like this using num pi and
I'm going to show you that in a moment in the next cell.
But what I want to do now is show you the non num pi method of solving this problem.
So what I'm going to do is specify y to be two points and these can be any two points.
You know not zero zero.
These are just initialized some random numbers I'm just basically creating a two element vector for
y and then when I'm going to do is essentially evaluate this equation here.
One point at a time rather than evaluating this all in one line of code.
So in the previous video I was doing something like 4 x i in X but now what we need to do is specify
these values for y in indices.
So we need to specify that the first point in Y is going to be m times the first point in x plus B.
So it turns out that this is not very useful because I need to say something like the X I if element
in Y is going to be equal to m times X I plus B.
Now the problem is this is not going to work because on the first iteration we are trying to access
the minus fifth element of Y.
In fact here we want to access the first element of Y and then the second element of Y.
So the way to solve this I'm going to set this back to being I so I can stay in range 0 2 the length
of x.
So now instead of this looping variable I being the actual values in X it's going to be integer starting
at zero and going up to the length of X or actually 1 minus the length of x.
So therefore this becomes y x y.
And now we specified x and y so I'm gonna say print x come away so X is well x is the same thing it
was before but importantly Y is now minus 9 and 11.
So this is the value of Y at x equals minus 5.
This is the value of Y at x equals plus 5.
Okay.
And now what we can do is plot these two.
So now I can say put that plot X comma Y.
Now notice that in this case this actually is the correct formatting because the variables x and y here
are not individual points.
This is not point one and point two.
These are the x coordinates and these are the y coordinates.
Okay.
So what I want to do now is spend a moment to make this plot look a little bit nicer.
So some of these things you've already seen before.
So axis square and I'll put a grid on let's see how this is starting to look.
Okay it's getting a little bit better and now I want to change the x and y axis limits because I think
it looks a little bit awkward here.
But what I want to change the limits to is basically just the ends of the line.
So I want the line to fill up the entire plot.
So I'm going to write BLT.
X lim x and peel teed up y Lim y and actually know what this is.
I'm not really happy with this Y limit.
Let's try something a little bit creative here.
I'm going to set the Y limit to be the x axis limit as well so that's gonna give us a nice square plot
here.
Okay.
So now I'd like to draw black lines on the 0 lines here.
Just like I did before however.
Now I don't want to have to specify what these lines are appropriate.
I want to be able to draw this information from the Axis itself.
So let me show you what I mean by that I'm going to write.
Access equals BLT dot GC A get current axis.
You remember I introduced you to this idea in a previous video.
So now from this variable axis I can access multiple features of this plot including so for example
as just print out axis dot get X limb.
So now this tells me that the x axis limit is minus five to plus five.
Now on the one hand that's not so surprising because that's what I set it to appear according to what
I specified X to be up here.
But being able to access this information is really useful because now I can make the lines a little
bit more dynamic so I can say that I want a line that has the x axis coordinates from minus five to
plus five or whatever the x axis limit happens to be and then the Y is going to be 0 0.
And now I'm gonna specify this as a dotted black line like this.
All right.
So this is for the horizontal line.
We need a vertical line as well of course.
And so that is almost exactly the same code except here.
We need to specify that we want to grab the y axis limit instead of the x axis limit.
Okay so this is looking pretty good.
There's one more thing that I would like to add to this plot and that is a little legend a label up
here that would tell us the actual formula for this line.
And so to do that I've also introduced this in a previous video.
But it's one of the options for plots peel teed up plots.
You would type label equals and then whatever would be the string that you want to appear in the legend.
So y equals.
Now I could just hard code this I could write two x plus one.
But what if we wanted to change these values here then we would also have to manually change these values
here.
So a much better solution is to say percent s x plus percent s and then I'm going to substitute in for
those percent S's.
It's going to be m comma B all right.
So now I'm going to run this code.
We still don't see a legend.
And that's because we haven't activated the legends.
We have to activate the legend by typing appeal to the legend.
All right.
And then we see this.
And now this is a pretty useful tool because you can start changing these parameters these two parameters
of the line to see how the plot changes.
So let's say minus have a point three.
And how about point 1.
Okay so now we get a line that is negative it has a negative slope and you can see it s it's not exactly
at the origin it's a tiny tiny smidge above the origin here.
All right.
So I promised that I would show you the NUM pi solution for this problem here.
Now there is nothing wrong with generating the variable y one point at a time like this.
However it's also useful to know how to do this in one go.
And so for this we need the NUM pi modules.
I'm going to import num pi as MP and then I have to run this code again and essentially the trick is
simply to convert this X from a list into a num pi array.
So I'm going to write y equals m dot x plus B.
Now we already know that this doesn't work on its own.
However if the variable x gets converted from a list which it currently is into a num pi array.
So we see an array and then this is going to work.
And the result is exactly the same the exercise for this video is basically to produce this plot.
You can see that there are two lines being drawn here with a friendly little informative legend here
that tells us the formulas for these two lines.
So this blue line here is Y equals point seven times X looks a little strange here to say plus minus
two.
But that means that the intercept is minus two.
And here the orange line is minus one point two five times x plus point seven five.
All right.
So this is your task.
Implement these two equations in Python and produce a plot that looks like this including the legend.
So now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I came up with a solution to this exercise.
All right.
So let's make a new cell down here.
So I'm going to create a couple of lists here for all the parameters.
So first of all let's set X to go from minus five to plus five.
And then I'm gonna come up with an an also a list for the m and b parameters or the slope and intercept
parameters.
So the first equation was point seven for M and the first equation value of the intercept was minus
two.
And then the second equation was minus one point two five.
And the second equation intercept was point seven five or three fourths.
All right.
And so now with this information I'm going to basically draw a line like this.
Now it has to be two lines.
Now you could do this in two separate lines of code.
You could say why one equals and y two equals.
Totally fine.
However that wouldn't really scale if we wanted to add more lines let's say there is another line with
M equals 3 and b equals also 3.
All right.
You know I said three but I wrote two.
But anyway the point is it's good to have code that is scalable.
So therefore I'm going to do the rest of this in a for loop.
So what I'm going to do is loop over the length of M and that's going to allow me to draw a different
line inside this for loop for each set of parameters.
So for I in range 0 to length of M we want to first of all come up with the formula for Y.
So that was Y equals M and now it's the ISF element in m times X except this has to be converted into
a num pi array plus B.
And then of course it's the element of B.
So before getting any further and actually doing some plotting I'm just gonna run this code and check
for any errors and I didn't see any errors in fact nothing printed out.
So that's a good sign when you don't see any errors of course.
That doesn't mean that there's nothing wrong with your code.
It doesn't mean that your code is perfect.
However it doesn't mean that you don't get any errors.
So that's an encouraging sign.
Okay.
And then I'm gonna say P L T dot plot and now the X is going to be X the y coordinates will be the y
coordinates and then I'm also gonna have to come up with a label.
But for right now I think I'll just set this to be I because I just want to make sure that this plot
is looking good before getting too much further.
I've mentioned several times before in this course that it's generally good to work on your code piecemeal
so you write a little bit of code and then you test it and then you write a little bit more code and
then you test it and so on.
All right.
And this looks pretty good.
We see the two lines they intersect and it roughly looks like what the plot in the slides look like
that I showed a moment ago.
OK.
So let's set this label to b y equals then this is gonna be replaced with the M X plus and then another
replacement for B.
So then this has to be the F element in M and then the F elements in B.
All right.
And then we can activate the legend.
So this is starting to look good.
And in fact this is mostly the end of the assignment.
There is a couple of other lines of code that you could add to make this plot look more like the plot
that I showed in the slides which is actually this.
So I'm really just going to copy and paste.
Let's see.
If I'm lucky enough that I will be able to just run this and all right.
This looks pretty good.
Now you may think that this was just a weird excuse to generate an X on a plot and X does happen to
be a pretty good letter but in fact this is more important than this.
When you get to solving systems of equations you will learn that a system of equations like this so
a pair of equations has a solution.
When the graph of those two equations shows that they intersect at a point that in fact this point here
is the simultaneous solution to both of these equations.
So not really going to talk about that yet in this course that comes up later but I just want to give
you some insight into why this kind of an exercise actually is pretty important.
So the main goals of this video and the last video were to show you how to draw lines in Python.
And now you know two approaches for drawing lines.
You can specify the start and stop points on the x and y axes and you can start from the equation y
equals M X plus B for two points and then draw the line that way.