I'm actually going to start this video by showing you a screenshot of a google image search for the
term logarithmic spiral nature.
Here you see some of the first results and it's pretty interesting we see some shells some see shells
that are cut in half.
We see some plants some ferns some other plants.
We see galaxies here and these are this a galaxy.
This looks like a hurricane spinning around.
What do all these various biological and physical objects have in common.
Well you probably guessed it.
They are well modeled by something called a logarithmic spiral.
And the goal of this video is to introduce you to the logarithmic spiral.
All right.
So it turns out that it's pretty straightforward to create a logarithmic spiral in math or in python.
All you need to do is combine a cosine with an exponential the natural exponential.
So here we have cosine of T.
This is E to the minus T and these are the same t here and T is just some time vector.
Now this yellow line here shows the function e to the minus T.
This white line is a little bit confusing here because this is this white line is actually not the cosine
of T per say this is the coastline of T times e to the minus T.
And that gives us this tapered cosine so it's a cosine and you can see it's getting closer and closer
to zero.
Now this is not a logarithmic spiral.
This is a logarithmic spiral.
And to create this logarithmic spiral we plot X by Y where X is cosine of T times e to the t divided
by K and Y is almost the same as exponential term as the same but we have a sine instead of a cosine.
Now you might be looking at this formula and thinking that I made a mistake maybe I made a little typo
because there is no minus sign here and there is a minus sign here.
So if we say that this is this.
So this is the.
This gives us the the decay the exponential decay with a minus sign.
So I tell you that this expression and this expression are consistent with each other.
What does that tell you about how we have to define K in this equation.
That's right.
It tells you that we set k to be a negative number.
So what is the effect of dividing by K here.
So let's assume that K is always negative and then I just want to take a few moments to think about
what it means for k to be really large.
So a really large number like one hundred or a thousand or ten thousand first is if k is really small
like close to one or maybe even closer to zero.
So let's think about this.
So when K gets really really big this fraction goes to zero.
So imagine t is a time vector is going from I don't know let's say 0 to 4 pi.
So it goes well let's make it even easier let's just just say t goes from zero to 10 and let's say k
to be a hundred billion.
So now this is you know 10 divided by one hundred billion is essentially zero it's a tiny tiny number
it's very close to zero.
So that means that when K gets really large this whole term here is gonna go to 1.
And that's because E 2 the 0 or e to the tiny tiny tiny number very close to zero is basically 1.
So now if we set this term to be 1 it's essentially not decaying at all or is decaying really really
really slowly.
So this cosine goes on and on forever with very gentle tapering and in contrast as K gets smaller and
smaller than this tapering gets more and more steep.
So when K gets smaller then this goes down to zero faster.
All right.
So what we're going to do now is switch to Python and implement this equation to create a logarithmic
spiral so I will set this variable t to go from linearly spaced numbers from zero to 10 pi and let's
say a thousand I set it to be one two three four points and of course you can pause the video or after
the video is over you can try playing around with different ranges here for a time notice sums on keeping
time positive here okay.
And then we specify.
Okay let's start with minus three minus three.
And then I'm gonna set X to be num Pieta cosine of T times e to the T divided by K and then of course
copy paste because y is nearly identical y is just the sign of T times this same exponential.
All right.
So that's essentially all the math that we need to worry about.
I'm just gonna say plot X. come a Y.
Let's make this a black line.
So Red let's do uh.
Actually now that I say the word red.
That sounds nice.
Let's try Red BLT.
That axis square and peel to that axis off and let's see what this thing looks like.
All right.
Here we go we get our nice logarithmic spiral not too difficult and so I'm gonna switch to the exercises
but of course I encourage you to play around with the K parameter.
Play around with this range of T and see how much intuition you can build about the logarithmic spiral
so the exercise here is to great this really beautiful looking logarithmic spiral.
It looks like some abstract cosmic seashell or something.
You know it's a a sea creature from some other planet.
I don't know what it is but it looks really cool and it's nice to look at.
So in fact it turns out that I've created this by plotting a lot of different spirals.
So this is one logarithmic spiral.
You can change some of these parameters are actually t you set the same for all the lines so you really
just are changing the parameter k.
So change k.
A lot of different times that's going to create a whole family of logarithmic spirals and you plot them
all on top of each other on the same axis and that will give you a graph that looks like this.
Now the reason why this looks kind of 3D ish is because I've changed the color.
So every line every exponential every logarithmic spiral has its own color and I set them to go from
being really dark so very close to black.
And then they get lighter and lighter into lighter colors of purple and eventually this kind of pinkish
magenta color in the middle.
So you already know the basics and you just have to figure out what to set what range to set.
K 2 to produce a graph that looks something like this.
So good luck.
Switch to Python do some coding make some art.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I've produced this graphic here Oh right.
Let's begin.
So I created one hundred and fifty separate lines.
I'm going to specify n to be one hundred and fifty and then we need the parameter k.
I think I'll actually call it k s because it's plural so case this is going to go linearly space numbers
from minus six to minus two in n step so a hundred and fifty steps.
Now there's really no you know correct or single correct way to set up these K parameters these are
parameters that I you know I spent a few minutes just playing around with the parameters.
These are ones that I liked but that doesn't mean that you have to come up with or you have to prefer
exactly the same range.
So let's say for I in range n.
And what do we want to do.
So we need to define x and y.
And I think I will take that from here.
Let's see.
In fact I think I can copy and paste all of this stuff so plot that show is gonna be at the end in fact
all of these lines here are gonna be at the end.
And this these three lines need to be tab indented here because these are part of the for loop and this
is just some specifying things about the plot that comes after the for loop is finished.
Now this is not really correct because this is just plotting the same K over and over again which we
defined all the way up here.
So we need to change this.
This has to be the ISF elements in K and actually it's k s like this.
Okay so let's try running this.
I already know that this is wrong here the color but I just want to make sure that we get something
that looks like what it should be in terms of the shape.
Okay.
So the shape is correct.
We didn't get any error messages or anything like that.
So that's good.
Now we basically just need to figure out how to specify the color here.
So the way that I specified this is to define the color parameter of the of the of the plot function
to be our G.B..
And so g there's no there's no green in here.
So that's always going to be zero green value of zero for every curve.
And then I just specify this to be I divided by n and the blue channel is also I divided by n and there
you go.
That's what we got.
So this looks really nice.
I think maybe you are a green person.
Maybe you like green.
That turns out to be yellow.
Okay so maybe you're a yellow person or maybe you know maybe you like black and white actually maybe
you like grayscale.
So that is this is also quite beautiful.
Now I challenge you to make a nicer looking more beautiful more interesting looking logarithmic spiral
based graphic than this.
Please take me up on this challenge.
Make something that looks better than this with a different color scale different.
You know whatever you want and then post it to the Q and A form.
I really enjoy seeing how you can take some of these basic building blocks and make really nice artwork
out of it.
OK.
So in this video to conclude you learned about logarithmic spirals.
These are really simple mathematical objects and yet they are ubiquitous in nature you see logarithmic
spirals everywhere.
And now that you know what a logarithmic spiral is I encourage you.
Next time you go for a walk through the park or through a forest or if you're on the beach look around
for logarithmic spirals you will see them all over the place.