In this video I'm going to tell you about peace wise functions.
We'll start by talking about what a peace wise function is how to create one inside pie and if you are
not already familiar with X Casey D then I will introduce you to that phenomenon.
So whenever I think of peace wise functions or anything in pieces I often think of this comic it's a
pie chart with the label showing fraction of this image which is white and fraction of this image which
is black.
I think it's a pretty funny take on using visual graphics and statistics to simply point out the obvious.
This comes from a Web site called X Casey D which is a great Web site for all sorts of interesting funny
insightful comics and they'll have this kind of funny looking artistic style.
So it's a little bit wobbly and the characters the text is also a little bit wobbly anyway.
This is not a piece Y's function.
This is a piece Y's function.
A piece Y's function is a function that cannot be expressed using one single expression.
Instead it must be expressed using multiple expressions with different ranges.
So here you see a pretty simple example of a piece Y's function f of x equals zero.
So the function equals zero.
If x is less than or equal to zero and F of X equals minus two X.
If x is greater than zero.
So you can see that this function is not the same expression everywhere in the domain of x.
We can also make a plot of this function a graph of this function and it would look like this.
You can see the function is flat at zero before x equals zero and then after x equals zero the function
goes down according to minus two times X so there's a few different ways of showing piece y as functions.
This is one way sometimes it's also written for X is less than zero instead of if you can also see them
written this way.
So without any English words in here like f or 4 so this says f of x is 0 from minus infinity up to
zero and it's minus 2 x from zero up to plus infinity.
Now of course peace Y is functions are not limited to two pieces.
You can have any number of pieces.
Here's an example of a three piece function so it's similar to this function except the minus two expert
extends only up to X is less than 10 and when x is greater than 10 then we have point 1 times X cubed.
So what does this function look like.
Well I don't have a graph here so therefore I suggest that we switch to Python and make our own graph
of this piece Y's function in this video.
We are going to use the simple simplify and num pi modules the display and math functions in the exercise.
And of course the map.
Plot lib function.
All right let's start by importing a symbolic variable x.
I'm going to write from simple dot ABC import X and now what I'm gonna do is first start by creating
the three pieces so piece 1 with zero piece 2 was minus 2 times X and piece 3 loops that should be a
two piece 3 was point 1 times X cubed which I'm actually going to write as X cubed divided by 10.
Okay so now we need to put them together but we have to put them together in coordination with the conditions
so that is we have to know we have to tell the function in simple there's gonna be a simple function
simply needs to know not only what are the different pieces but also what are the conditions on X for
each piece being valid.
So that gets implemented using a function called piece y.
So some dot piece wise is once with a capital P for some reason and the way that this piece Y's function
works is you specify some number of inputs and each input that you specify has to contain the expression
and the x axis limit.
So let me show you an example for the first piece.
So the first input into this piece Y's function is going to be as a tuple here.
So with parentheses piece 1 comma X less than zero and now simplify and the piece Y's function will
know that when x is less than zero then piece 1 gets evaluated.
And so then we go to the next set and actually let me write the third one first because that one is
a little bit easier.
So piece 3 if x is greater than or equal to 10 okay so then what do we do for the second piece here.
Because this one actually had two conditions.
The first condition was that x is greater than or equal to zero.
And the second condition was that X is less than 10.
So that we do with an ampersand.
So this is going to be expressed as.
So first of all piece too.
And then here we simply write X greater than or equal to zero.
And x is less than 10.
We get an error.
I actually forgot this is supposed to be also in parentheses here.
So each one of these individual pieces has to go in parentheses.
Python needs that basically to know how to associate the end symbol that it's not the end symbol isn't
connecting the zero and the X. It's connecting this expression and this conditional.
Okay.
So now I run that again and we didn't get any errors.
Let's see what this thing looks like.
So I'm just gonna write up F X so you can see that this is a piece Y's object.
And here this is pretty much just what I wrote in here.
This is true here.
And that's because this basically covers the rest of the options.
So if you don't have this option or this conditional I should say or this conditional then piece 3 gets
implemented.
And now to view this function to make a graph of this function I'm going to use him dot Lam defined
to convert this python object into a function that we can evaluate for particular points of X..
So we say lambda phi X comma F X and then let's set our X range to be.
How about minus 3 2.
Well it certainly has to be higher than 10 because of this conditional.
Let's go to maybe 15.
And how about one two three four steps.
Why not.
Okay.
Now we can simply make a plot of this that we want.
Plot X X comma f x x.
And then again as I showed you in previous videos we cannot simply just plot this function.
Instead we have to evaluate this function at these specific points that we are interested in.
So that is X X like this.
All right.
So that looks pretty good although it's kind of hard to see.
I guess you can see.
So it's a straight line here and then it's a very gentle slope downwards and then it suddenly shoots
up.
Maybe this is gonna look a little bit more interpretable.
If I set this boundary piece here to be three let's see how that looks okay.
So that's looking better but I think you know all the interesting stuff is happening around here there's
not too much interesting parts of the function happening around here.
So maybe let's try setting this upper limit of x down to five.
OK.
This looks good.
So here you see the first piece.
The second piece and the third piece up here.
Now there's a particular reason why I had wanted to do this and start with a boundary of ten and an
X limit of 15 and then work my way down.
And the point was to show you that it's often useful in mathematics in particular when graphing functions
in calculus not to show the entire range of the function but instead to zoom in on the interesting bits
where there are more changes happening in the function.
So you know we could plot this from like minus three hundred to plus five hundred and then you don't
really see much of anything it's kind of hard to get a visual sense of the important features of this
function.
So you see that a lot better by zooming into an appropriate range.
So how do you know what an appropriate ranges.
Well you know part of it comes from looking at the boundaries part of it comes from looking at the function
and part of it comes from just a little bit of exploration the exercise for this video is to implement
this piece what is function in Python or in simply print it out in nice latex formatting so actually
it should look like this in your Jupiter eye Python notebook and then you want to make a graph but you
want to make this graph in X case style.
What does that mean to print it out in X KCET style.
Well it means that your graph is actually going to look like this.
It looks kind of funny it's a little wobbly here in there but this is an X KCET comic style of making
graphs in python.
Now I haven't told you how to make these kinds of graphs but it is an option that's built into matte
plot lib.
So with a little bit of ingenuity and a little bit of searching you should be able to figure out how
to make your plot look like this.
All right so pause the video write some code get your screen to show this and to show this.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you my solution
Well we certainly need a symbolic variable X but I've already imported one here so I don't need to do
that again.
So let's write f 1 this was piece one that was X cubed and then F two was the log of x.
Now in the slides This was actually written as log base 2.
And so to get log base anything in Python then use the base as a second input.
And you can tell that by looking at the dock string or the help file.
So simple dot log ARG which is the input into the function and then base equals none.
So the default value is None which will actually give you the natural logarithm.
Okay so let's see now we have our two pieces.
And now I'm going to create my function using piece wise and the first piece is f for X is less than
or equal equal to zero.
And the second loops f that should be f 1.
And the second piece which is the second input into the piece Y's function is f 2.
And that is the case for x is greater than 0 and now excel just even run this code.
Okay.
I don't get any errors so that's good.
Now I'm gonna print this out so display math and then printing out this piece Y's function in latex
is actually pretty straightforward.
I'm going to write f of x equals.
And now you could use a substitution and say percent s in here but because we're only adding one additional
object I'm just gonna use the plus sign say plus same dot latex f of x.
All right.
So that looks kind of interesting because in fact what we computed was log base 2.
But what simplify.
And Python printed out was log of x divided by log of 2.
So the natural log of x divided by the natural log of 2.
Now that may look a little bit weird but that actually is correct because log base 2 of something is
equivalent to the natural log of that something divided by the natural log of the base.
In this case too.
So this actually is correct.
And it's also interesting to see how latex and Python chose to format this function.
So it wrote for X is less than or equal to zero and then it wrote otherwise here.
And that's also consistent.
This otherwise with this what we discovered here when we look at how simple is representing this object
that it says true at the end.
So essentially this value of true gets interpreted by late latex as the word otherwise.
OK.
So now we need to make a plus.
So how do we do this.
I'm first going to make a plot.
J You know just like a normal plot just to make sure that we're on the right track.
So this is now all code that you have seen before.
P L T dot show.
Okay.
So here we get the plot.
Whoops I haven't actually remade this function yet I need to do f x x equals sin Lem defy and x and
f of x.
Okay there you go.
Now it's interesting to see that we get a warning here.
There's a warning about complex numbers that says casting complex values to real discards the imaginary
part.
Now this is actually not a problem.
What python is concerned about is that it sees that there is a log in the function and then we are requesting
negative values of x that in theory could go into the log function.
And of course the log of a negative number is is not defined on the real axis.
So you need complex numbers however because this is a piece Y is function.
We're not actually evaluating the log for any negative points or even any non positive points so this
is a warning Python's giving you a warning but it's totally fine.
It's nothing to be concerned about.
All right so I want to make this part look a little bit nicer.
So I say set the X limit to be from minus two to plus two and the Y limit to go from minus 10 to plus
three.
Again I'm just zooming in to the interesting part of the function where it's changing the most.
OK.
So this is definitely not an x k C.D. style plot.
How do we make an x k C.D. style plot.
The way to do that is to activate P L T dot x k C.D. And then parentheses like this.
So you basically just run this function.
However before running this function I have to warn you this is a little bit dangerous to run this function
exactly just like this.
And that's because once you've activated this X Casey D function is going to remain active and it's
going to affect all of your future plots until it gets deactivated.
So therefore a better approach to doing this in Python is to say with plot X case C D and then tab indent
or have four spaces before only the command that you want to be associated with this function.
So this is a python keyword you can see it's printed in bold face green font.
So now I can run this and that means when I go back and run previous plots it's not going to be drawn
using the x KCET style.
All right.
So that is pretty neat looking in this video.
I talked about peace wise functions and implementing peace wise functions in side by.
If you weren't already familiar with X KCET then congratulations.
Now you are and you saw how to make pretty interesting.
Billy looking plots in python using the x KCET map plot lib style.