Perhaps the most famous polynomial is called the quadratic equation.
If you haven't already come across the quadratic equation in a math course then I'm sure you will soon.
So in this video I'm going to introduce or maybe reintroduce you to the quadratic equation.
You will see that despite the really fancy term which starts with a Q. It's actually nothing special.
It's just a regular polynomial and also in this video I'm going to give you some more experience using
functions in particular.
Creating your own functions.
In this case with outputs.
OK.
So what is this famous quadratic equation.
Well it's really just a polynomial set to zero.
So A times X squared plus B times x plus C equals zero.
So that is the quadratic equation.
You can see it's simply a degree to polynomial.
Now one thing that we want to do with this equation is to solve it.
We want to solve it for X..
So how many solutions is this equation going to have.
Well you already know from the previous video that a degree to polynomial because this is X squared
has two solutions.
And how do we find those two solutions using this formula.
And this is that formula that I'm sure you've memorized like 18 times in your life and then completely
forgot about it another 18 times so you can see the two solutions to this equation embedded in here.
So plus or minus.
So one solution is X equals all this business plus this thing and the other solution is minus this square
root term here.
Great.
So I'm going to switch to Python and essentially what we're gonna do is implement this formula here
and then I will show you that actually num pi is limited for solving this problem and therefore I'm
going to introduce you to a function in Sai Pi which is another module and then we're going to create
a function that will essentially return the two solutions given the coefficients a b and c.
Okay so let's start using num pi.
So here I import num pi and now I'm going to set these variables so let's say a equals.
I said variables I meant coefficients.
So equals to b equals 7 and C equals 5.
So now we can write out the equation the solution to the quadratic formula.
The quadratic equation so that's let's call this quad peak and call this P because there's two parts
of this it's the plus with the square root and then the minus with the square root.
So that was there's a numerator and then there's a denominator that denominator is actually really simple.
So let's start with that.
That's 2 A the numerator was minus B plus the square root.
So N.P. dot square root B squared.
So B starts are two minus four times a times c.
By the way I've spoken a few times in the beginning of this course about using spaces in code to help
make your code more readable.
So I think this is pretty readable like this grouping the four in a and the C together of course technically
you could also space it out like this but I think this is slightly less readable for humans even though
pythons will interpret those in the same way.
All right.
Anyway so that was the positive part of the solution.
And then we have the negative part and I'm calling it positive and negative because of the sign here.
Okay.
And now let's try printing out these two solutions.
So print quad eek P and quad ink and all right.
So we get two solutions to this quadratic equation using these coefficients minus 1 and minus 2.5.
So minus 2.5 isn't exactly the easiest number to do mental arithmetic with but minus 1 actually is a
pretty easy number.
So I encourage you to pause the video go back to the original quadratic equation plug in these numbers
for a b and c and then plug in minus one for X and make sure that that solution is actually valid.
Make sure that that equation eventually goes to zero.
So one weird aspect of the quadratic equation or the solution to the quadratic equation is this term
here and in particular it is not possible to take the square root of a negative number.
So square roots are only defined for positive numbers.
So anytime for a C is larger than B squared then you're going to run into trouble with this square root.
Now if you've already learned about complex numbers then you'll know that that's actually not a real
problem.
It's just that these solutions end up being complex value but let's see what happens.
How about if we change a from two to three and now all of this code is exactly the same but now when
we run the code it looks like the answers are n n n n n.
So what is n n.
Well if you like Indian food then you might think that this is non like non bread that's Indian bread.
However that is not what N N stands for.
In this context and I N stands for Not a number so not a number and a N and the issue here is that none
pi or the square root function in num Pi is not by default able to deal with complex valued solutions.
So therefore we are going to start using a different module called Sai pi.
So import CI pi it stands for scientific Python as and then people often will import this as.
So NDP for num pi SB for CI pi.
So now all I'm gonna do is actually let me have to run this again.
Now I'm gonna change the end to an S It's a pretty small change.
So now instead of calling the NUM pi version of the square root function we are calling these CI pi
version of the square root function.
And now we actually get answers and we don't get warning messages anymore.
Those answers may look kind of weird.
So it's minus one and then something plus point five.
J So this is called a complex number.
If you're not familiar with complex numbers you're not comfortable with working with complex numbers
then don't worry I'm gonna have several videos I think maybe even four videos coming up that will introduce
you to complex numbers but for now the important point to realize is that complex numbers have two parts.
There is a real part which is this first part and then plus and then there's something called the imaginary
part and that's associated with J or sometimes people also use the letter I.
Okay.
So the point is now we get to solutions which we know we have to get because this is a degree to polynomial.
What I'd like to do now is create a function that will take these three coefficients as input and provide
one output which will be an array a two element array that contains these two solutions.
Okay so you will recall that to create your own function and you start by writing def for define and
then which we call this function.
How about quad week seems like a good name for a function that computes the solution to the quadratic
equation.
So we are gonna need three inputs A B and C and of course we're always going to need this semicolon
here.
Okay.
So what do we do inside this function.
Well we basically want to implement these two expressions here.
So I'm doing a tab here to get the force bases in here except now I want these to be in a single variables
I'm going to change this to say let's just call this output variable out.
Seems pretty sensible pretty interpretable.
So out zero and out one.
So that means that the first element of the output vector the output array is going to be the solution
with a plus sign and then the second one is going to be the solution with a minus sign.
So now I just need to initialize this variable out let's say out equals.
Now previously I've shown you initializing things using for example num pi zeros and then we can specify
that this is going to be a two element vector.
But here we want to make sure that this is initialized using CI pi so we can get these complex solutions.
Okay.
I think I'll add a comment in here.
So this is initialize and then here we compute.
Okay.
So now I'm gonna run this cell and don't get any errors.
So now what I would like to do is in a new cell try out this equation or this function and see how it
looks.
So let's try a quad peak and then I'll input how about two comma seven comma five because that was what
we used earlier to get the solutions of minus 1 and minus 2.5.
Okay.
Mm hmm.
So it seems like it ran it didn't give any errors but it also didn't give any output.
Maybe I should try encasing this in print.
Mm mm mm mm.
Now this has none.
Unfortunately none is not a good solution.
So what is going on here.
Did we make some coding errors where is something going wrong.
Actually what's going wrong is.
Well nothing.
The function is doing exactly what it's supposed to do.
However it's not going to output anything.
Python doesn't know that we want to output the variable out from this function.
So we have to tell Python explicitly that there should be an output.
So you write return out.
And now when I have to run this again and now when I run this.
So now we get the two solutions because out is going to be the output.
It's but what's returned from this function.
So here we can write or call this solve for solution.
So I can say so equals this function.
So quite easy with these coefficients and then I can write.
So now we see that the result is this array with these two solutions the exercise for this video is
basically to produce this image.
So what is this image showing here.
Well what you want to do is compute the quadratic equation for these parameters so you fix the coefficient
a to b 1 and then coefficients B and C you vary according to these sets.
So B goes from minus five to plus five integers and C goes from minus two to plus 10.
Also in integers.
Now of course the quadratic equation gives you two solutions to solutions for x and what you want to
plot here is really just the first solution.
So this is the one associated with the plus side.
You will go back.
So when you solve for x here you get two solutions.
And just keep the one associated with the plus sign.
And then you make an image of that.
Now notice that the tick marks here on the x axis and on the y axis actually don't just go from zero
up to you know however many numbers there are instead these are showing you the actual values of the
parameters here.
Now I haven't yet showed you how to incorporate that into making an image.
So I haven't yet told you exactly how to solve this part of the exercise if you would like to figure
this out on your own.
Then please pause the video now because I'm about to give you a hint.
All right.
So here is the hint the hint is when you're creating this image.
Use the code BLT that I am.
Show em.
So I'm assuming that you're calling this matrix M and then the second input is extent equals.
And then well you solve to figure this part out.
So use square brackets to create a list and somehow you use this.
And that's going to give you these values on the x axis and on the y axis.
All right.
So good luck.
Pause the video see if you can use these parameters to produce this image.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and walk through the solution.
I'm going to get started by defining these coefficients.
So a we fixed to one B is going to range from minus five up to plus five which means I have to write
six here in range and C goes from minus to up to 10.
Okay.
And then I'm going to initialize the matrix and I'll call this MIT M for Matrix.
Of course you can call this whatever you want.
I'm going to initialize this as zeros and the size of this matrix is going to be the length of B and
the length of C.
All right.
Let's already run this.
Make sure there's no errors anywhere in here.
OK so that's good.
And now I'm going to create a double for loop so one loop over the B parameters and one loop over these
C parameters.
So I'm going to call this looping index variable B I in range.
Now you might initially think of setting this to be range B or sorry in B like this.
However I also want to use this looping index to access individual rows and columns for C of the matrix
M so therefore I'm actually going to write in range 0 to the length of B like this and then we need
another loop.
Let's call this C I in range 0 to length of C.
Okay.
So now inside this double for loop we want to run the quad peak so basically calling this function for
parameter a.
And now you have to be careful again here because the wrong answer is to say B I in fact it has to be
the B S element of B.
So the first element in the first iteration through this loop it has to be minus five.
So therefore the way we set this up is B.
And then in square brackets to access the B I S element of vector B.
Okay.
And then of course it's the same for C S C and now based on how we created this function it's going
to return this vector here containing two elements.
So you might think of writing something like this.
So out equals.
And then here I can say M and then the B I F row and C I S column equals out zero.
So this is totally fine there's nothing wrong with this.
However in Python we can actually make this a little bit more efficient and the way that I'm going to
do that is by moving this here and now you might think that this isn't going to work in fact let's even
try running this.
So we get an error and the error happens because the output of this function is two elements but we
are only accessing a single element in here.
So what you can do here is type with square brackets zero.
So that means we are indexing the first element or the zero with element that is the output of this
quadratic equation function.
All right.
So now run this code.
Now we don't get any errors that error went away.
We do get a warning in this pink box.
Now it's important to appreciate the difference between an error and a warning.
Errors mean there's something wrong with your code and you have to fix it.
A warning is just Python's way of telling you that it might be doing something that's a little bit different
from what you are expecting and that's totally fine.
So what's happening here is that some of these solutions are complex valued and here python is telling
us that it's going to discard the imaginary part and just keep the real part.
And it turns out that that is sufficient.
That's what we want.
All right.
So I will thank Python for giving me this warning but then I will basically just ignore it.
OK.
And now what I want to do is plot this BLT that I am show em.
Now I haven't yet imported BLT.
So this on its own isn't going to work yet.
So I need to go all the way up here to the top and right import met plot lib dot pie plot plot as P
L T run that code again.
And now I'm gonna be able to visualize this matrix.
All right.
So this is looking pretty good if you check this against the image that I showed in the slides you'll
see that the image part is correct.
However the index labels are actually not correct.
So we need to fix those now I give you a little hint there.
And that was to use an optional input called extent extent equals.
And now here basically what we want to do is specify for the x axis the first and last values.
And for the y axis the first and last values.
So what is the first and last value of the x axis.
Well it can be a little tricky.
It's either the first and last values of B or it's the first and last values of C.
And that really depends on how we've oriented the matrix here.
So remember that these matrices get plotted rows first and then columns.
So these are the rows which means the y axis corresponds to B.
And these are the columns which means that the x axis corresponds to C so that means I need to write
the first element of C and then the last element of C and then I'm putting some spaces in here just
to make it a bit more readable than we specified the extent for the y axis.
And that is the first element in B and then the first hour or so the last element in B.
All right so let's try running this and this looks much nicer.
So we c minus two to 10 and minus five to plus five.
Okay.
So that's basically the end.
There's a few more things I'm gonna add just little odds and ends to make this look a little bit nicer.
So the X axis label is C the y axis label is B.
And then I showed a color bar.
So let's say plot that color bar that activates the color bar and I think I was I had a title so I'll
just add that quickly.
So BLT the title and let's say a equals and then plus string a s I need to convert a from a number into
a string in order to be able to use the plus sign here which I'm actually using here is concatenation
not as summation not as addition.
All right.
I think that is the successful completion of this exercise.
Very nice.
So in this video you learned a bit more about the quadratic equation and this video in combination with
the previous videos.
I hope convinced you that the quadratic equation is not anything super duper weird.
It's actually just a regular degree to polynomial and you also got more experience defining your own
functions in python in particular with giving outputs and also adding more to images created from matrices.