In this video I'm going to introduce you to the order of operations.
This is an important principle in arithmetic and I'm also going to show you the importance of spacing
in Python and the importance of parentheses and you will see the difference between spacing, which is
used for visualization and parentheses which is used for grouping.
So let's begin with this equation here.
Four plus three times two minus one equals... what does it equal?
Now it may seem strange that I don't already know the answer because this seems like it should be a
pretty trivial arithmetic equation.
However, there's multiple ways that we can interpret this so we can get very different answers depending
on how we group these numbers, these arithmetic operations, together.
For example if we would grouped together 4 and 3 that would give us seven times to minus one equals
13 because seven times two is 14 minus one is 13.
Or we could group together the three times two, that would give us the four plus six from three times
two minus one, and then four plus six is ten minus one is nine.
Or we could grouped together the two and the minus one.
And that gives us one so then we have four plus three times one.
And now here we could either group the seven, the four plus three times one or the three times one plus
four.
So in this case because this is a one that ends up working out seven either way.
OK.
So it seems like there is some ambiguity and this isn't good.
We have the same collection of numbers we shouldn't be able to get very different answers like this.
Now it turns out that the correct answer in this case is this one here, the correct answer is nine.
We grouped together the three times two.
And that takes priority over the addition and subtraction.
So how do I know that this is the right answer
and this is the wrong answer?
Well, that is because of the order of operations.
So this is the order of operations parentheses come first.
They take precedence over all the other operations, and then exponent and multiplication and then division
then addition then subtraction.
Now this seems like it's a really difficult list to memorize and that's why we have these little shorthand
memory tricks or mnemonics.
So we have P E M D A S.
Some people will remember this by PEMDAS and some people remember please excuse my dear Aunt Sally.
So parentheses exponent multiplication and so on.
So now when you look at this equation you see there's addition, but addition is all the way here in the
back, then there's multiplication which is comes before addition and then subtraction which is all the
way at the end.
So we have to do the multiplication first because that comes first in this order.
Please excuse my dear and Sally.
And that gives us four plus six minus one.
And then there's a question of whether we should group four plus six or six minus one.
Now in this particular case with these numbers it turns out it doesn't matter.
You can do four plus six.
That gives you ten minus one is nine.
Or you can say six minus one is five plus four is also nine.
So in this particular case it works either way.
However, the correct order is to group the plus signs together.
And that's because of this -- Aunt comes before Sally.
All right.
So let's switch to Python and see how this gets implemented and in particular I want to show you how
to use parentheses to basically override any other order.
The first thing I want to do is confirm that without applying any parentheses I'm going to be able to
reproduce the answer that I claimed was correct in the slide because it's one thing for me to say that
some mathematical equation is true but it seems much more convincing when a computer does it.
So let's say print and I'm going to say so that was four plus three times two minus one.
All right.
So now we get nine.
Now I would like to show you that spacing actually has no effect whatsoever.
So when I wrote it out here I put spaces between each number and each operation but I'm going to say
four plus three.
And then with spaces, so maybe I'll even do it here as well... two minus one.
So now when you, as a human,
look at this line of code, what you see -- what your brain is doing is grouping together the four plus three
and it's grouping together the two minus one.
And those are separated by multiplication so in your mind you might be thinking that this should now
be seven times one.
However when we run this code again we still get nine.
So the point here is that spacing is really important for humans.
For you looking at your code and for other people to be able to interpret your code and read your code
However, the computer -- Python -- doesn't care about spaces. You can have as many spaces as you want like this.
And python is going to completely ignore all of these spaces here.
However, we can override everything using parentheses.
So remember parentheses was the first order of operations in.
Please excuse.
So now I put four plus three in parentheses and now.
Okay.
Get rid of a little bit of this spacing... it's a bit excessive.
So now we have four plus three times two minus one.
So now we get a different answer and let's see if we can figure out why we get this answer here.
So this comes because we say four plus three.
Now this gets grouped together.
So this is seven.
And now what gets grouped over here.
So we still have the multiplication.
So actually python is grouping together the seven times the two.
So this gets run next and seven times two is 14.
And then we say minus one is 13.
So again we can override this by saying by adding parentheses here and now we are really going to get
an answer that is consistent with the visual grouping.
So now the answer is seven.
And that's because this gets grouped together as four plus three equals seven.
These get grouped together and the two minus one gets evaluated first and that's one of course.
So seven times one is one.
Here are your two exercises for this video.
What you see here is two exercises and each one contains four numbers and three arithmetic operations.
And I also give you two answers here.
So what you need to do is write these expressions write these equations into Python -- actually not the
whole equation, just the first part, just the left hand side of this equation. And then figure out a way
to add parentheses to make the following equations true.
So you need to add parentheses wherever appropriate to get this first expression equal to two.
And this second expression equal to zero.
So now is your opportunity to pause the video, switch to Python on your own, work through these two exercises.
And then when you're finished you can come back and watch me solve these problems.
OK so let's add a new cell here and let's start with the first one. So let's see, that one was four times
five divided by seven plus three.
So if we just run this on its own without any parentheses then we get some answer: five point eight
five whatever.
This is definitely not equal to two.
So that means that the default order of operations is not going to give us the right answer.
We need to add some parentheses.
So there's essentially two ways you can go about solving this problem.
One is you can just kind of randomly poke around and add parentheses wherever you feel like you know
maybe here and.
OK.
That doesn't change anything but that's not necessarily the best way to go about solving problems in
math or in programming. A better way is to sit down and first think about what the answer should be.
Now in this case we have only four numbers and three operations so it's not so hard to try to do some
mental grouping, mental arithmetic.
So I know that the answer needs to be two.
And so looking through this I can see four times five is twenty, seven plus three is 10.
OK.
So we want to have an expression that equals twenty divided by ten.
So it's pretty clear that we need to group these together. And then the question is do we need to group
the four and five together or can we just leave it like this?
And to think about that we can write down the PEMDAS, so please excuse my dear Aunt Sally and so here
you see that multiplication comes before division.
So that means that Python is going to group four times five together first and then it's going to apply
the division.
So that means we don't actually need parentheses here in order to get the correct answer of two.
Now this is already the correct answer.
However if this were my code I would do a few other things.
I would remove these spaces here so that it's really clear not only to Python but also to humans who
are looking at this code that this is grouped together in the denominator of this fraction.
Secondly I would also remove the spaces here also just to make it clear that the four and five are clearly
grouped together as the numerator.
Okay.
And now if you like for additional readability you can add parentheses to the numerator here.
Notice I'm going to run this code again.
That doesn't change anything because multiplication already came before division.
However, I think you will agree that with the parentheses in the numerator it just looks a little bit
easier to parse, compared to without the parentheses.
All right.
So that was the first one.
Let's now try for the second one.
That was nine divided by three plus six minus one.
And somehow we have to get this to be equal to zero and it is not equal to zero, it's equal to eight.
So again one thing you could do is just kind of randomly poke around and start adding parentheses here
and there and see what happens.
But I don't think that's really the best strategy.
A better strategy is to just kind of look and be inquisitive about this problem and see if we can figure
it out in our heads.
So this is nine and then divided by three plus six of if we group these together we get nine divided
by nine which is 1 and then minus 1.
And that'll give us zero.
So I'm going to put parentheses around here again unnecessary spaces but this helps visually group and
then we have a question of whether we need to put parentheses around all of this to make sure that python
will say nine times nine minus one as opposed to nine divided by nine minus one.
And the answer is we don't need parentheses because again division comes before subtraction.
So I believe that this will give us the right answer.
Again this is technically correct if you like to remove some spaces to group these things together then
that's great.
I definitely encourage that. So in this video you learned the mnemonic -- that's a memory trick -- for the order
of operations. That was PEMDAS or please excuse my dear and Sally. And I also highlighted the importance
of spacing and Python for ease of visualization and parentheses for actual grouping in code.