This video is a follow up to the previous video where I introduced you to plotting using the simple
module.
So if you haven't gone through the previous video then I recommend having a look at that before moving
on to this one.
All right so this video is basically going to involve generating this plot.
Now this plot is showing the function Y equals X divided by the quantity x squared minus a.
So you want to do is define this function using simple.
So these are symbolic variables here and then you want to substitute for a the numbers one two three
four.
And each time you substitute that's going to generate a new line in a plot.
So ultimately you're going to get a result that looks like this.
So you can see that the x axis limits go from minus five to plus five the y axis limits go from minus
10 to plus 10.
And there is a legend showing what each of the functions are.
Now the way that I generated this plot was by having random numbers assigned to the color.
So that means every time I rerun this piece of code the colors are going to be different the functions
will all be the same the legends will be the same but the colors will all be different.
So you can think of that as like a little extra bonus to try and get that to work otherwise that the
color doesn't matter so much.
The more important thing is getting this function with these parameters for a to produce a plot that
looks like this.
All right.
So now is your chance to pause the video work through this code on your own.
And now I'm going to switch to Python and show you how I went about producing this plot so I'm going
to continue working from the script that I showed from the previous video.
So we start by defining our function.
So y equals a divided by x squared minus a k.
So there's the function and now the way that I'm going to do this is setup a loop.
So it's gonna be for i in range of something.
I'll get back to that something in a moment and then I'm gonna write p dot extend to extend the plot
and then I will say then I'll basically have to change the label.
Okay.
So this is not yet operational code of course but I just want to paint a little bit of a high level
picture of what I'm going to be doing that helps me organize my thoughts to write out a little bit of
kind of pseudo code first and then I'll go back and fill in everything.
Okay.
So actually the first thing I want to do is make sure that this variable p is cleared and that's because
I've already been using this variable p for the plotting object earlier in the code.
So I'm going to write p equals none.
I can see that none is green and boldface.
So this is a reserved keyword and effectively this is just clearing out whatever information is in this
variable.
So now when this code gets run P just gets cleared out to be nothing.
Now the way that I'm going to solve this is by first writing up the initial value for Pete.
So I'm going to setup a plot some plot and then the function is Y.
So the simple type object but this mathematical function is variable y dot subs.
And now we start with substituting a for one.
And then I input as a list the x axis limit so X goes from minus five to plus five.
And then I write a show equals false okay.
And actually let me say P that show and now I'm going to comment out these three lines here.
So I just want to make sure that I haven't made any mistakes so far.
OK.
So so far this looks pretty good.
The y axis limit is also not correct.
So maybe I'll change that real quick.
So p dot y Lim equals.
So in the graph that I showed in the slides that was from minus ten to plus 10 and all right.
This is starting to look at this looks recognizable from what I showed in the slides.
We're also gonna need to activate the legend.
So while I'm down here I'm already kind of right.
Legend equals true.
So this auto generated a legend which is technically correct.
This is the function that I input it however I want this to appear in nice latex formatting so therefore
I actually need to change the legend explicitly and that is with p 0 because remember now these are
properties of the entire plotting object.
This is just a property of this particular line.
So the label for that line equals percent s and then percent Sin Lei tech.
And then why That sub's a comma one.
Okay.
So now we're in the same situation that we were before.
So this has to be dollar signs around it and that will tell Python that whatever is in between these
dollar signs should be interpreted as latex code which is what we're inputting here.
All right.
So this is not the end of the assignment of course.
This is just one of the lines and this is where the for loop comes into play.
So now I've already done the first line corresponding to a equals one.
And what we need to do now is replace for a goes from two through four not one through four because
we've already done the first plot so to come a five and then my strategy here is to extend this plot
by adding more and more Simplot functions.
So I'm just going to copy and paste that in here.
And now we're not substituting one.
Each time we are substituting for AI.
Okay.
So and then we can change the label.
So I'm going to copy and paste this in here.
And now of course this is substituting for I not for one.
And here what number should we what should we replace this with.
It's certainly not going to be zero.
Actually I can show you what happens if we do that then essentially we're just replacing the first line
or the label of the first line with each individual element inside this for loop.
So that ends up being wrong.
Maybe this should be P I.
Huh.
And now we get an error.
Why are we getting this error here.
Now of course I could just tell you the right answer.
But what I want to do is show you how to debug in Python.
So if you have an error that says something like index out of range or something to this effect and
it's inside a for loop then a good thing to do is to print out basically whatever you think is relevant
to print out.
In this case the most relevant thing to print out is the looping index I hear.
So let's print that out so you can see that this crashed basically right away.
So it we print it out too.
So I is first equal to 2 which is of course how we specified this and then it immediately crashed over
here without getting to the next iteration without getting to I equals three.
So the problem here is that when I equals two that's totally fine here we're just substituting I equals
two is totally fine here we're just substituting and just printing text but here to the number two as
an index means that we are trying to access the third element of this P object but there aren't three
elements here.
Here there's one element with an index of zero.
And here we extend it.
So then there's two elements with an index of one.
So we are trying to access the third element of a two element object and that is the problem.
So the solution is that we have to say I am minus 1 and it's minus 1 because we're starting with I equals
2 but the way that I'm using IE here is to substitute into this expression and the way that I'm using
I here is as an index into this object.
All right I hope that makes sense.
Essentially I'm using i in to this variable i in two different ways.
Here for substitution of a number and here for indexing into an object.
Okay.
So now this plot is almost complete.
We are almost finished with the exercise.
The problem now.
The remaining issue is that we don't know which line corresponds to which value of this function.
So therefore what we need to do is change the line color.
So this is going to be p and it's still I minus 1.
I minus one and what we want to change is the line color.
So the way that I'm going to set this to be a random color is using num pi.
So MP for num PI that random to generate random numbers whoops and then dot Rand for uniformly distributed
numbers and then I went three random numbers.
So that's going to correspond to our GDP.
Now later on in the course I'm gonna have a lot more to say about generating random numbers and interpreting
random numbers from different distributions.
But for now suffice it to say that num pi random dot Rand will generate random numbers that are between
0 and 1.
So with the decimal point somewhere between 0 and 1.
And that's exactly what we need for colors because to specify a line color you have to specify the RG
B values in fractions so in numbers between 0 and 1.
Okay.
Now you might already guess that this is not going to work and that's because we haven't defined end
P so I need to import the NUM pi module so and say import num pi as in P.
By the way you might notice that I often say I'm going to say when I'm actually not saying something
I'm just writing it down and my view programming is like talking to the computer.
So whenever I type in code I'm imagining that I am talking to the computer.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
So we still get an error.
Let's see what this area is.
Okay.
So this is actually not a very usefully interpretable error but it turns out that what we need to do
is input a list into the line color argument.
So we embed this call inside a list because the output.
This is a num pi array.
And the line color needs to be as a list.
All right.
So this looks pretty nice.
Now these lines all have slightly different colours.
These two are a little bit difficult to distinguish from each other.
So I'm just going to run this again and then up.
This looks nice.
I think this is a pretty nice set of pastel colors.
This reminds me of early summer somehow.
So in this video and in the last video you gain some expertise with generating plots in simple as I
mentioned at the end of the previous video in general I recommend sticking to Mat plot lib whenever
possible.
Just because it makes your code more consistent.
But there are definitely cases where it's useful to use the plotting methods in simple.