In this video you are going to learn about the central limit theorem.
That's a pretty important theorem in statistics and machine learning and other aspects of data science
and I will also give you a little bit of an introduction.
So a pretty quick simple intro to the seaborne module.
And that's basically something that people used to make really nice looking graphics in Python.
So we'll do a little bit with Seabourn and in the next video then you'll see even more applications
of seaborne.
OK.
So the central limit theorem basically says that random samples from independent variables will tend
towards a normal distribution or a Gaussian distribution even if the variables themselves are not normally
distributed.
Okay.
So that is quite a mouthful.
Here you can see an example of the central limit theorem at work.
So what you see on the top row is two sets of numbers.
So this is a sine wave.
And this is a uniformly distributed set of numbers.
And here you can see the histogram.
So this is what the histogram of a sine wave looks like.
You can see it's kind of flat towards the middle and then it comes up at the lower edge.
And at the upper edge.
And basically this corresponds to the peak up here and the trough down here.
And to interpret this you can actually think back to the video a couple videos ago where we had the
exercise of showing the probability distribution of certain mathematical functions that was X and X
squared and X cubed.
So basically the sine wave gets a lot denser as it gets towards minus 1 and plus 1.
And that's why you see these clusters in the histogram here.
Anyway the point is that this is a strongly non Gaussian distribution.
This is not even remotely a little bit kind of like a galaxy and is totally anti Gaussian.
Here we have just some uniformly distributed numbers with a distribution that is essentially flat.
In theory it's flat.
But then of course we are just randomly sampling.
So it looks like there's a bunch of roughage in here.
Okay.
And then what I do here is literally just combine these two signals.
So I say the sine wave plus this uniform noise together makes this kind of like fuzzy looking sine wave
like this.
And now it turns out that the histogram the distribution of values of this combined signal which is
literally the sine wave plus the uniform distributed numbers looks like it's not exactly formally a
gaussian but it's tending towards a normal or Gaussian distribution.
And that is pretty remarkable because neither of these distributions on their own looks anything like
a normal distribution.
And this is essentially the central limit theorem at work.
Now there are some qualifications.
So just by combining different distributions you don't necessarily get a normal distribution.
It depends on the number of values that you're sampling.
It also depends on suitable normalization.
So the values have to be roughly in the same scale.
There needs to be some appropriate normalization in order for this to work.
But this is the idea of the central limit theorem that when you combine you randomly sample values from
many different kinds of distributions there are some altogether is going to tend towards a Galilean
distribution.
Let's check this out in code.
Essentially what we're going to do in Python is reproduce this graph and then we can manipulate some
of these distributions a bit.
We will use num pi and map plot lib and also as I mentioned seaborne but we'll get to that later.
OK.
So what I'm gonna do is specify that we are going to create two signals with two thousand points each
signal one is going to be a sine wave and I'll set that to be linearly space numbers from 0 to six pi
so six times num pi it up pi and we want any of these guys and then Sig 2 is going to be known pi dot
random numbers and we want a uniform distribution end of them and then I'm going to scale this up by
2 and subtract 1.
So this is going to give us a uniform distribution of numbers that has an average of 0 and a range from
minus one to plus 1.
Now I'm going to generate some plot so let's see I will start by plotting the individual signals and
their distributions.
So let's see fig comma X equals pelted subplot.
So we need this subplot geometry to be two by three because we want two rows the top row will correspond
to the signals and the bottom row will correspond to the distributions or the histogram and then the
columns will correspond to the three signals so these two signals and then the combined signals so two
comma three and I will set the figure size to be equal to ten by four.
Which is just some numbers that I played around with the bit before starting the recording and they
generally look good.
All right.
So now in the first row and first column I'm going to plot the signal so call that Sig 1 and let's see.
I will set the title to be so set title and this is a sine wave so I'm going to set the title to be
sine wave.
Now we want the histogram.
That is going to be in the second row still in the first column and that's going to be hist of SIG 1.
And let's try 100 bins.
All right.
So let's see.
I'm going to run this code already just to make sure that I haven't made any mistakes so far it's looking
good.
Although it's a little bit crowded we're going to need to figure out a way to make to clean this plot
up a little bit.
OK.
So now that was the first column for the sine wave and now I'm going to copy and paste this code for
the second column.
So all of these indices change to 1 and this changes to Sig 2 and let's call this uniform you need firm
numbers.
All right.
This is also looking good.
I think actually I'm gonna change this from a line plot into plotting.
Let's try dots.
Let's see how that looks.
OK.
So that's pretty good.
And I think I'll even make it look a little bit nicer by setting the alpha to be maybe point three.
So this is the transparency set to be 30 percent.
OK.
So these are for the two individual signals.
And now we need another signal that is literally just the addition of these two.
So maybe I'll call that comedy.
So comedy equals Sig one plus Sig two.
Now notice here that I'm not combining the histogram.
I'm combining these signals and then later on I'm going to combine or create the histogram from the
combined signal.
So let's see I'll do a copy and paste again actually just paste I did the copying.
So now this is the third column and this is now comedy and comedy and which we call this maybe I'll
call this the combined signal.
All right so there you see the combined signal in the.
Maybe this is the time domain this maybe this is like at a time varying signal.
And here you see its distribution and it is tending towards a normal or Gaussian distribution.
So just to make this plot look a little bit nicer I would like to get rid of all of these X ticks and
Y texts.
So how can we do that.
Well the direct way to do that is to say x 0 0 dots set X ticks and then I'm gonna set them to be empty
so you can see that that gets rid of the X ticks on this plot and then we also have to repeat that for
the Y ticks.
So that deals with this panel over here.
But now you know it's a bit tedious to have to deal with all six of these.
I'm gonna need basically 12 lines of code to get rid of all of these ticks.
So what is a better way to do this.
Well we can put this in a loop.
We can say like for i in range of 2 and then set this to be I
but you can see at this also isn't really such a great way to solve this because now essentially we
need to have a double loop in here.
Wouldn't it be nicer if we could just loop through all of the elements in the variable x for axis.
Let's see.
So we can try doing something like this to say for AI in X and then set this just to be ice and now
we're not looping over numbers we are looping over elements in X however we are getting an error here
and this error essentially comes from the shape of the axis variable is variable x.
So let me just give you a better sense of what this what I mean by this.
So I'm gonna say print num pi dot shape of x.
Now of course that's still going to give an error but here we see that this variable x is a matrix.
It's not a vector.
So what we want to do in fact is write code that looks something like this except that it has to loop
through all the elements in the matrix.
So all six of the elements in the matrix A X and so to do this I'm going to apply a procedure that's
in mathematics and linear algebra is often called vector ization here in Python.
It's called flatten.
So I'm gonna write num pi dot matrix dot flatten.
And actually you know I should show you what this will look like now.
So I'm going to copy this and paste this in here so now you see the size of the flattened version of
this variable x is now six elements.
It's a vector with six elements.
So that corresponds to one two three four five six.
And then we can loop through all of these and just have two lines of code to get rid of the X sticks
and the Y ticks.
Very nice.
So this is all pretty interesting you learned a little bit about code a little bit about generating
plots modifying plots and of course a bit about the central limit theorem.
What I want to do now is take a moment to show you that it's not necessarily trivial that this distribution
will tend towards a gaussian just because we are summing up a bunch of numbers.
So for example let's say let's imagine that the two signals had a different range.
I'm going to just divide this signal two by 10.
Now that doesn't change the shape of the uniform distribution.
It doesn't change the shape of this distribution here but you can see the combined signal.
Now looks a lot more like a sine wave and then distribution also looks a lot more like the distribution
of a sine wave it doesn't really look like a galaxy and although you can see you know when you compare
this distribution or the shape of this distribution to the shape of this distribution this one I don't
know.
Is it fair to say that this is tending towards a Gaussian distribution anyway.
So there are some constraints there are some assumptions for the central limit theorem to work.
And one of those assumptions is that the data are all suitably normalized or in the same scale.
All right.
The last thing that I would like to do here is to introduce you briefly to the Seabourn module.
So the Seabourn module it's called sea born and it's often abbreviated as S and S so import seaborne
as s and s.
And essentially what people mostly use the Seabourn module for is to produce plots that are essentially
showing this information but look a little bit different and they look a little bit nicer I think.
So I'm going to activate the Seabourn set of default visualization schemes by typing S.A. dot set and
then I'm going to type S.A. dot dist plot.
So this stands for distribution plot and we want to make a distribution of the signal with one bin.
So it's going to look a little bit like this except not quite exactly it's gonna look a little bit cooler
and oh yeah.
This wasn't called signal.
It was called Camby of course.
So you can see that the thin lines here these thin vertical lines are the same as the vertical lines
here.
So the same as the bars here.
And what we also have from this distribution plot is an overlay of the lines and this is essentially
a smooth version of this histogram.
It's called a kernel density estimate her and I'm not going to talk much more about that in this video
but you can also just see that a lot of the visual aesthetic aspects look a bit different although the
information conveyed in this plot in this plot is fundamentally the same.
In this video you learned an introduction to the central limit theorem and you saw an example of the
central limit theorem in Python.
There is of course an exercise associated with this video and the exercise involves producing a graph
that looks like this.
This will allow you to explore the central limit theorem in a little bit more detail but that is the
main topic for the next video.
So keep watching.