It's pretty likely that you have at least heard of this operation before called transposing or to transpose
a vector or transpose a matrix.
If you haven't heard of it then you might be disappointed to see that it's a really simple operation.
And if you have heard of it then.
Well I hope you enjoy this video anyway.
But the good news is that at the end you are going to see how the transpose operation relates to one
of the most important applications of the transpose and matrix multiplication which is creating a square
symmetric matrix squares symmetric matrices are really important.
They have a lot of great properties.
They're important for statistics and machine learning and deep learning.
Square symmetric matrices are all over the place in Applied linear algebra.
So let's get started here I have a vector.
This is a five dimensional column vector and I'm going to transpose this vector.
So first of all transposing a vector or matrix is indicated using a capital T in these superscript like
this.
So what does it mean to transpose this column vector.
Well it's pretty straightforward.
It really just means to convert this into a row vector.
So it was a column vector we transpose it.
We get the row vector notice that the values haven't changed their order hasn't changed.
All we've done is taken the column and turn it into a row.
Now of course you can take this row vector and transpose it again and you're going to get back to a
column vector which of course is the original vector.
So that leads to an interesting property of the transpose operation which is that if you take some vector
and then transpose it twice you get back the original vector.
So this is for transposing a vector for a matrix it's basically the same thing you really just convert
all the columns into rows which is the same thing as converting the rows into columns.
So this matrix transposed becomes this matrix.
So the first column becomes the first row the second column becomes the second row.
Or another way to think about it is that the first row becomes the first column the second row becomes
the second column and so on.
And no surprise if you transpose this matrix you will get back to the original matrix.
So again that leads to this property that a matrix transpose transpose gives you back the original Matrix
what I'm going to do is illustrate a few different ways of transposing vectors and matrices.
So let's start by creating a row vector so set this to be known pied at random that Rand and and this
is going to be a random matrix of size 1 by 10.
So this is definitely a row vector we can type and P the shape of R and you see that it is a one by
ten matrix so this is a row vector.
And now what I'm gonna do is transpose this I'll call this R T for transpose and then a one because
I'm gonna show you two different methods of transposing so none pi dot transpose so using a function
called transpose and then another method is gonna be r t two equals R dot capital T.
So it's even shorter notice here I'm calling a function and that's in the NUM pi module and providing
an input into that function which is the variable R and here what I'm doing is calling a method directly
on R and that method is Dot T which is for the transpose okay.
And so now let's see.
So I will print this and then I'm going to print out two more things so r t 1 and R T 2.
So here you go.
We have the size of the original matrix was a row vector so one by 10 and then both of these methods
basically converted this row vector into a column vector so now it's 10 by one.
So that's four vectors.
Now what I'm going to do is transpose a matrix and then show you the matrix as an image before and after
being transposed.
So let's say maths equals num Pi the random round and let's make this how about like an eight by four
matrix.
So then I will say Matt t equals Matt Dot T.
So that's the transpose of the matrix.
So this is eight by four.
This is going to be a four by eight matrix.
And now I'm gonna plot both of these in two different subplots of the same figure.
And that's going to allow me to illustrate also a different property of working with axes that I think
I haven't yet introduced to you in this course.
OK.
So fig comma X equals BLT subplot.
So this method I've shown you before for creating subplots so I'm gonna create a subplot geometry that's
going to be one row and two columns so there's gonna be an image here and an image over here.
Okay.
So now I'm going to draw into the first axis I am show Matt and then x zero dots.
Let's see set the title going to be M and let's already have a quick look at this.
Just to make sure I haven't made any mistakes.
And of course I have made a mistake if this is an error of omission I forgot to import import the Met
plot lib dot pie plot library as P L T.
All right.
Hopefully we don't get any errors.
Okay.
And now we see our friendly little image and then here I will write X one that I am show Matt T.
And then the title is going to be set title.
Now I'm gonna make this m transpose however I want this transposed to be in the superscript.
So I'm going to use some dollar signs here to make this look more like what you would expect for math
notation.
All right.
So this is looking pretty good.
However let's say you don't like all these tick marks here on the y axis and on the x axis.
So I would like to get rid of them.
So one thing I can do is write a x 0 that sets X ticks and then I set it to be empty.
So that removes the X ticks here.
Now notice the matrices also changed because I'm you know they get randomly generated each time I run
this code.
So this is fine.
And then I would have to repeat this for y ticks and then for the first axis X axis zero and also axis
one.
But you know this isn't really a scalable method.
Let's say you're plotting like 20 different axes and you have to write this out 20 times that's a little
bit tedious.
So what I'm going to do is put this in a loop.
So I'm going to write for i in X and then I can just write I got set X sticks.
Now each iteration inside this for loop I is going to correspond to a different axis which is gonna
be this one and then this one.
So this is for the X ticks and then also for the Y ticks of course.
All right.
So then this gets applied to both of these subplots.
And the idea when you're looking at these images is you can see that the first row here becomes the
first column here.
And likewise the first column becomes the first row so I used this term symmetric in the beginning of
this video to refer to a matrix.
So what is a symmetric matrix.
Well if you think of a square matrix like this then you can draw a line going through the diagonal like
this or the diagonal going from top left to bottom right now this matrix is symmetric because all of
the corresponding elements are mirrored across the diagonal.
So this is the same as this.
This is the same as this and so on.
It's like if you would take this matrix and fold it across the diagonal so imagine a crease going here
on the diagonal and you fold this upper right triangle down to this lower right triangle then all the
elements would be exactly identical.
And that is the definition of a symmetric matrix.
Now there's a formal mathematical definition which is a equals a transpose.
So why is this the correct definition of a symmetric matrix.
Well think of it this way the first column of this matrix is the same thing as the first row and the
second column is the same thing as the second row.
And so on.
So each corresponding column is the same thing is the same values in the same order as the corresponding
row.
So that means you could transpose this matrix and you would get exactly the same result.
So a equals a transpose.
This is the definition of a symmetric matrix.
And so with that in mind what I would like you to do in this exercise is show that a matrix which can
be square or it can be non square times its transpose is square and symmetric.
So write some code in Python that will show that when you take a matrix and multiply it by its own transpose
the resulting matrix is going to be square and it's going to be symmetric.
Now I'm about to give a little bit of a hint for how to figure out whether a matrix is symmetric if
you don't want to hint then now is the time to pause the video and switch to Python and figure out how
to to solve this exercise.
So the hint is nothing super fancy it's basically just looking at this little equation here and thinking
about what would happen if you subtract a transpose from both sides of the equation so you would get
a minus a transpose equals zero which in this case would be the matrix of all zeros at the zeros matrix.
All right.
So now you should pause the video switch to Python and now I am going to switch to Python.
I'm gonna start by generating some variables for Matrix sizes so let's see m is 14 and and is 19 all
right.
And now what I'm gonna do is create a matrix so a matrix a matte of random numbers.
It's going to be m by n and then I'm going to compute the matrix times it's transpose.
So I'm gonna call this a mat and then how about Emma so this is a match forwards and backwards is called
a palindrome.
And we write that up palindrome a palindrome is a word that spelled the same forwards and backwards
like mom and dad and my ma how are you pronounced.
Amanda Ma all right.
So that's going to be aim at times aim at DOT T.
So the matrix times it's transpose.
So the first thing I want to do is show that this is square.
So even though this is a non square matrix this is a rectangular shaped matrix.
The resulting matrix times.
So the matrix times is transpose is going to be squares.
I'm gonna print out the shape of my Tama and let's already see what that is.
Okay so that ends up being 14 by 14.
So this is a square matrix.
And how about if I make this Let's say I don't know how about if this is like four and this is maybe
I but also 19.
Okay so now it's four by four and forty by nineteen forty by forty.
So you can see no matter how much you change these sizes the result is always going to be symmetric.
So I'm gonna make this a little bit smaller.
How about four by nine matrix that's gonna give us a four by four matrix.
So now I'm going to show that this is symmetric so the way that I'm going to do this here is by printing
out the matrix minus the X it's not the matrix not the original Matrix it's the matrix times it's transpose
minus the matrix times it's transpose and then transpose.
Okay let's see.
So that is a matrix of zeros gets a little bit tricky if you actually try this with the matrix times
it's transpose that's not even a valid operation it's not possible to subtract which would be the same
thing as addition it's not possible to subtract two matrices that are different size.
So the idea is that even though this matrix is not equal to its transpose this is not symmetric.
This matrix actually is symmetric.
So this matrix minus is transpose gives us the zeros matrix in this video you learned about the transpose
operation and a few different ways of implementing the transpose operation in Python and you also learned
about square symmetric matrices which are pretty important in applied linear algebra.
As I mentioned in the beginning of this video square symmetric matrices come up in multivariate signal
processing statistics.
Machine learning all kinds of applied applications.