Now it's time to learn about division with complex numbers and in particular taking a division where
a complex number is in the denominator and just simplifying the expression a bit.
So I'm going to show you how to do that using what's called the conjugate trick.
So this is about division with complex numbers and math.
And then there's also an important python or a programming concept that you're going to learn in this
video which is how to break up complicated or really long lines of code into multiple individual lines
of code and also a related concept is how to break up a complicated equation into separate pieces of
code each of which is simpler and easier to read.
So let's get started.
If you would see a complex division that's expressed like this.
The question is could you simplify this expression.
And the answer is yes you definitely can.
In this case it's really simple.
You divide both of these terms by two and you end up with two I.
All right.
So that's pretty straightforward.
But what if you had a complex number in the denominator.
Now what can you do.
How can you simplify this expression.
The answer comes from thinking about the complex conjugate and multiplication of a complex number with
its conjugate that I introduced in the previous video.
So the complex conjugate trick for division is to take this number multiply both the numerator and denominator
by the complex conjugate of this number.
So of the denominator.
Now you can see that that's not really changing.
This number is not changing this expression because this term multiplies both the numerator and denominator.
Of course you could just cancel these out.
However if you implement this multiplication this denominator now becomes a real value.
No it doesn't stay complex.
So in particular it's just the real part squared plus the imaginary part squared.
And if that seems a little confusing how to get from here to here then you might want to go back and
consult the previous video.
All right.
So that simplifies this equation like this.
And that's generally the accepted or most appropriate form of representing a fraction or a division
with complex numbers to make sure that the denominator is real valued.
So this is an example using specific numbers.
Now I'm going to show you what that looks like more abstractly.
Here we have two numbers Z and W..
You can imagine that both of these are complex numbers but certainly w we assume is a complex number.
So to simplify this expression you just multiply both the numerator and denominator by the complex conjugate
of W and then you do whatever simplifications you can.
All right.
So now let's switch to Python and see some of this stuff in action in this video.
We are going to be using num pi simplify and the display and math functions from already importing them
up here.
So I'm going to start by creating a complex number let's call it Z.
And this is going to be an pita complex.
I'm going to say the real part is for the imaginary part is to then.
And now what I'm essentially going to do is print out the simple equation or the simplified expression
that I showed in these slides so that's math or display math and then I'll have a fraction with a percent
s so I'm going to replace this with the complex number.
And then the denominator of the fraction is just going to be two and then I'll set that equal to and
then I'm gonna just print out this number.
So now for these substitutions we have the first substitution was the complex number z and the second
substitution is Z divided by two.
All right.
And now we see that this division simplifies to two plus 1 J.
So nothing particularly earth shattering the amazing here but I think it's always nice to be able to
demonstrate some concepts yourself using Python as opposed to just trusting everything you see on a
screen or in a book or on the Internet.
You certainly shouldn't trust everything you see on the Internet.
All right.
The next thing I want to do is illustrate the complex conjugate trick that I showed.
So what I want to do is print out something that looks kind of like this except there's gonna be two
equals signs.
I want to have first the expression showing the division of one complex number by another and then the
same division but with multiplying the numerator and denominator by a complex conjugate of the denominator
and then all of that's going to be simplified and we'll see what the actual answer is.
All right.
So first we need to come up with some complex numbers and I will use the ones that I showed in the slide.
So let's say Z one is and P complex.
And that was the real part was for the imaginary part was to then we had said too complex and there
the real part was.
And the imaginary part was minus three.
Okay.
So let's start printing this thing out piecemeal so one simple step at a time.
So let's start with just showing this fractions so that's going to be frac the numerator is z 1 and
then the denominator is Z tubes.
Actually they're not doing that the right way.
These have to be percent s and then here we say percent s and substitute said one and Z two if you want
you could simplify and then run this through simple latex to get this to look a little bit nicer.
Maybe I'll show you how that would look here.
So sim that latex and then Sim the fi
loops that's a sim simplify.
So it looks slightly different.
There's no parentheses and now there's an eye instead of a J.
But in this particular case because I'm going to be doing some multiplications I actually prefer to
keep these parentheses here for now.
Okay so this is one part.
Now I want to say equals and then I'm going to copy and paste this a little bit here.
So that's going to equal in the numerator.
It's gonna be said one times percent.
S and this is going to become the complex conjugate of the denominator.
And then here we have to do the same thing of course.
So times percent s for the complex conjugate of the denominator again.
All right.
So now.
So these two variables were for substituting in the first fraction the first term.
And now we need said one and and P Doc carnage said 2.
So this is for the numerator and then for the denominator we need Z to an and p dot coms Z 2.
Okay.
Let's see how this looks all right.
So this looks pretty good.
Now you'll notice that this line of code is starting to get really really long.
And I'm not even done yet.
I'm gonna add even more stuff here.
So if you have a really long line of code sometimes it's useful to find a natural breaking point in
the code.
So a natural separation in the line of code and you just press enter and let the rest of this line be
on the following line of text.
And I'm going to do even more so I'm even gonna separate this multiple times.
This is kinda let me see.
This ends here.
Yeah.
So now I have this.
This is kind of one line of code but it's actually spanning now four different lines of text and you
can see if you press control enter.
It still runs fine so python is totally fine interpreting this in the way that you think it should.
Now when you were writing code like this it's generally recommended this is not strictly necessary but
it's generally recommended to have a backslash in here like this and the backslash.
Let me show you that having that backslash doesn't produce any errors it doesn't change anything but
this is used for like human readability.
So now when someone else is looking at your code they will see this backslash and they will know that
this means that you are intentionally wrapping this code around to the next line.
And then again to the next line.
And again to the next line.
OK.
So back to the main goal here.
So now what I want to do is basically solve this equation or solve this division and put that answer
here song and say equals one more percent s and that is going to be down here.
So let's say Z one divided by Z two.
Okay.
Invalid syntax I'm actually missing a comma here.
Just because you're breaking up the line doesn't mean you can avoid any syntax.
Wow.
Okay so this is quite a long answer but that's just what it is.
And now if you like.
So this one actually could be converted into simpler maybe.
So let's say Sim dot latex and then simply simplify
starts with a Y simplify.
Okay so that didn't change it a whole lot although it got rid of the parentheses.
I think that part looks nicer however.
Now you see there's a little bit of inconsistency within the same equation here.
I'm using J to indicate the imaginary operator but here I'm using IE to indicate the imaginary operator.
Now either one is fine J is fine I is fine but it's good to be consistent certainly within the same
equation.
So in fact despite what I just said I think this is probably not the best idea.
I'm going to remove that and leave it with J as the imaginary operator the exercise for this video is
to implement this really really really long expression.
This is a really difficult multiplication and actually if you were up for a little algebra challenge
you can try solving that or simplifying this as much as you possibly can by hand using a piece of paper
and a pencil.
But that's not actually required what you really just need to do for this exercise is to implement this
in Python.
So this is super long this is gonna take a really long line of code so you can try and come up with
some ways to make this simpler so that this becomes a readable piece of code in Python as opposed to
being one single line of Python.
That's really really really long.
Okay so you can implement this multiplication with Z and W and then of course you replace Z and W with
these particular numbers and then basically see what it simplifies to.
And this actually turns out to have a really nice solution even though it looks like a really complicated
problem.
All right.
So pause the video switch to Python.
Get to work and see how well you can simplify this equation all right so I am going to start by writing
out these complex numbers so Z was and Peter complex 4 and 2 and W was MP that complex and the real
part was 3 and the imaginary part was 5.
So there is essentially two ways that you can go about breaking up that really long expression into
simpler code.
You could basically keep it on one full line of code that spans multiple lines like this.
But actually what I'm going to do and what I recommend doing is breaking that up into multiple different
parts so in particular I'm gonna come up with a bunch of different variables so I'm going to say left
numerator equals and then the left denominator equals and then the left part equals.
So what I'm doing is taking the left part of the equation and breaking that up into two separate parts
so I'm just gonna say the numerator and there the numerator was Z minus one times Z times w plus W and
the denominator was w times Z minus W.
So then the left part of the equation is simply the left numerator divided by left D nominated.
So in my opinion this code even though it technically takes up more characters I think this is much
cleaner and it's easier to read it's easier for someone else to interpret and that also means it's less
prone to errors.
So if you break up equations into individual parts like this you are less likely to make simple typing
mistakes.
Okay.
So now we need the right part so right Numa equals writes D num equals and the right part equals.
So this one was W minus one times one minus W it's a funny set of expressions there so then the denominator
was this was probably the most difficult part of this to get right.
So minus W squared times said minus W squared plus two times w times Z plus two times W minus said minus
one.
Quite a mouthful.
Now if you're thinking that I have like some amazing memory for these kinds of things I don't um actually
cross referencing this with my other monitor.
Okay.
So anyway the right part is right.
Numerator divided by right denominator.
All right.
And then the last thing I'm going to simplify is actually creating a variable called solution and that's
just the left part times the right part.
Now again I'd like to highlight that this is seven lines of code and technically you could put all of
this stuff into one really really really long line of code.
However I think you agree that this is more readable and less likely to produce errors.
Okay.
So now let's print the solution.
Huh.
And that's pretty interesting the result happens to be just one.
I mean this is is technically a complex number but the imaginary part is zero.
So really all of this stuff just worked out to one that is pretty funny.
And what I encourage you to do is change around some of these numbers and see whether this solution
changes as these numbers change.
So in this video you learned about division with complex numbers and simplifying complex division using
the conjugate trick and I discussed two different ways of breaking up long lines of code into multiple
lines.
So one way it was just literally moving parts of a line of code underneath and a second way is using
separate variables for different parts of the equation and then combining them later on.
Now in the past several videos I've been talking about complex numbers from a purely algebraic perspective
but it turns out that complex numbers also have a really interesting geometry associated with them and
that is the main topic of the next video.