In the previous video I introduced you to lists in Python and I introduced you to the concept of indexing
a single item in a list and also indexing multiple items at the list which is also called slicing. Indexing
and slicing is a pretty important concept in Python and programming in general and so I thought I'd
spend just a few more minutes going through the concept of indexing and slicing again just to drive
the point home a little bit further and give you a bit more experience with it.
So let's start by creating a vector.
Now in this case, I'm going to create this vector as a range and let's say we want this range of numbers
to go from 10 to 20.
So that means in the range function we actually type 10 comma 21.
And now if I just look at what this variable vec, it is simply a range.
So this is basically just what I typed in.
And in fact if I would type the type.
Now this is not the verb to type,
this is the function type which returns the class of this variable.
And it is a class range.
And if I want to convert this into a list, which I showed you in the previous video then you can use
the function list and the input will be a range.
And essentially that's going to convert the variable from the range 10 to 20 to the list of numbers
from 10 to 20.
So now you can see that this variable is now of type list, and if we just look to see what that list
contains, it is the integers 10 through 20 separated by commas and surrounded by square brackets.
So that's how you know that it's a list.
All right.
So now if we want to access an individual item within this vector, this variable Vec, this list, you also
do that with square brackets just like this.
So for example if I want to access the first element keeping in mind that Python starts counting at
zero, then you type Vec 0 and then you get the answer of 10 and that's the correct result because 10
is the first element or the element number is 0 in this list.
So if you wanted to access the number 13, which number would you have to put here? So to access 13 it's
actually the fourth element in this list, which means the index would be 0 1 2 3.
So this turns out to be the third, or index element number three, and that gives us the number 13.
Now if I wanted to access 12 13 and 14 how would we do that?
So there we use the colon operator.
And essentially what you want to do is specify the first element here and then one plus the last element
after the colon. So to access 12 13 and 14.
The first element that would go to the left of this colon here is the 0 1 2 element 2 or index 2 and
then to get to 14, it's 2 3 4 and then you have to go one more to 5.
So this returns 12 13 and 14.
And this procedure here, this is called slicing, because we are taking a slice out of this list.
Okay.
So a couple of other things you can do if you wanted to get from let's say element 5.
Up until the end.
So now I'm not writing anything after the colon I just leave the colon as it is.
And that's going to return 0 1 2 3 4 5.
So element 5.
And again you have to be a bit careful here because this is the way you know the way that like normal
humans would count.
This is the first second third fourth fifth sixth element but Python starts counting at 0.
So that's index number five.
And it goes all the way up to the end and that's what this notation means.
So based on this syntax, I'm sure you can guess how the syntax would look like if we wanted to go from
the beginning up to and including the number 15.
So how would you do that?
So keeping in mind that when you specify the top index you always do one plus the number that you want.
So this will be index 0 1 2 3 4 5 6.
So here we would write nothing.
And then colon six.
And that gives us the numbers 10 through 15.
So up to this element here.
All right.
The next thing I'm going to show you is how to count backwards or how to index backwards from the end
towards the beginning.
So I already showed you how to access the first element, so that would be zero or if you want the second
element then its index number one.
What would you do if you wanted the last index in this array, in this vector?
Now you could figure out what is the size of this list and say it's element number 0 1 2 3 4 and so on
but that's not always such a scalable method.
So the way to automatically get to the very end of a list is to use minus one.
So you say minus one and the way to think about this is that it's like you're starting here at zero
and imagine that when you go to negative indices you're wrapping around to the end.
So this is the index number two index number one index number zero and then index minus 1 is wrapping
all the way around and we get to the end.
So index minus 1 corresponds to 20.
And that also means that index minus 2 is going to be 19.
So that's actually pretty handy.
We can access the second to last element, which is also called the penultimate element, by using minus
two.
And this is handy because we don't need to know exactly how many elements there are in this list for
this procedure to work.
Now if you wanted to flip this list around and count backwards from the end to the beginning there's
a little bit of a funny notation here.
Essentially you go
colon colon and then minus one.
So why is this the right thing to do?
Why does this make sense? To explain this,
I'm going to introduce you to something called skipping.
So let's say we wanted to go from the first element of this list to... I don't know how about the number
14.
So let's say we want to count from 10 to 14.
So that's no problem.
You already know how to do that.
You can say 0 2 and then it's the element or index 0 1 2 3 4.
OK.
So that gives... oops, you can see this confusing I already just made a mistake :P
So this gives us the indices 0 through 4 which corresponds to the numbers 10 through 14.
Now let's say that I only wanted to skip every other number, so I don't want the eleven and I don't want
the 13.
I want to go from 10 to 14 but skipping in steps of two.
So the way to do that is you add another semicolon here and you tell Python here after the second semicolon
how much you want to skip by.
So this is saying we skip by two. So now this returns 10 12 14 and this is not just about counting even
numbers; you could say three.
And now you're counting in steps of three.
So it goes from index zero and then one two three.
And then well then we go up to this number but there's no more steps of three that go after this so
it stops at 13.
So now let's try
for example if I would type colon colon three.
Now this is going to return the first element or basically it returns all the elements skipping in three.
So we get this.
And then one two three one two three one two three.
And then it gets to the end.
So the colon Colon is actually just a shorthand for writing zero.
And then to the end in steps of three.
OK.
So with that in mind, we can also count from the beginning to the end of the sequence in steps of two.
We can go from the beginning to the end of the sequence in steps of 1 and now in this case.
You know this is extra text but just to show you that that works.
So now when I write minus one what I'm actually doing is going from the beginning to the end but I'm
skipping in steps of minus one.
And that's how you get the list flipped backwards.
So I hope this makes sense, and I hope you see that indexing and slicing and Python is not really so
fundamentally difficult.
There are a few little tricks and shortcuts that you have to remember, but don't stress yourself out
about trying to memorize these. As you go throughout your programming,
you will naturally become more and more familiar with this and eventually it will become second nature.
The main thing that you have to be mindful of is the fact that Python starts indexing at 0.
So that can sometimes cause a little bit of confusion and you have to be careful with that.