By this point in the course you now know all about plotting coordinates on a graph you know about plotting
lines rational functions polynomials using simplify to generate plots.
What I'm going to introduce you to now in this video is making images from matrices.
And you've already been introduced to the idea of storing data in a matrix.
And now I'm gonna show you how to visualize a matrix with images.
So let me first start by explaining how images are represented as matrices not only in Python but in
computers in general.
So if you have a picture that looks something like this maybe this is just a zoomed in part of a larger
picture so you can see each of these blocks here that have one common color to them.
So these are called pixels of course and you can think of each individual pixel as being a separate
block and then the idea is that computers will represent each block as having a different number.
So this pixel has a number twenty two and that's just some value in a matrix so you can see this is
a matrix.
These are the rows and the columns of The Matrix and The Matrix contains a bunch of numbers that you
see here and what the computer is doing what Python is doing is assigning color values to each different
number so larger numbers have darker colors and smaller numbers have cooler colors.
And then the exact color is called the color map and you can change the color map so you can make a
really pretty looking image that looks something like that so you can see all of the numbers from this
matrix.
So this is a matrix that has 10 rows and 14 columns.
So the numbers tell you what are the what is the value of the elements at each location in the matrix
and then those get mapped onto colors.
Now this is an exact picture that you are going to make in Python in a moment.
Very exciting in order to make this matrix.
We need to know this formula.
So each individual pixel each element.
So the eighth row and the JF column is defined by this simple formula three times I.
The row index minus four times J or the column index.
OK.
So now let's switch to Python.
I will first introduce you very briefly to generating images from matrices and then we'll work through
this particular matrix right here.
We are going to be using map plot lib dot pie plot and name pie.
So let's start by creating a matrix.
This is not the more detailed larger matrix that I just showed in the slides.
I'm starting with something a little bit simpler just to give you the basic idea.
So let's say this matrix has the first row of one comma two and the second row of one comma for us.
So we can print this matrix and it doesn't really look super nice.
It doesn't look like a beautiful mathematical matrix you learned in the last section of this course
about how to use the display and math functions and later coding to make this look like a nice formatted
matrix.
But for our purposes in this video that part doesn't really matter.
Instead what I want to show you is to use the function in the map plot lib module called I Am show.
So for image show and then I'm going to say a in here and then appeal to that show.
And now you can see what this image looks like.
So we have different colors for these different blocks and that corresponds to one two and one four.
So you can see that these two blocks these two pixels have the same exact color in the image and in
the matrix they have the same exact values one and one.
All right.
Now this labeling here is a little bit awkward because in fact this is really just for pixels.
So it's not really I think it's not really appropriate to have so many pixels in here because a little
bit of a misleading impression.
So what I'm going to do is change the x ticks and the Y ticks so the tick marks here.
So you can see here there's tick marks at minus point 5 and 0 and so on.
So I just want to have the x ticks at 0 and 1.
All right.
So this looks good.
Now you just see the 0 with element and the first element are really it's the first and the second according
to the way that human beings count.
But Python starts counting at zero.
Okay.
And then for the Y ticks I guess in theory this should also be 0 and 1.
But I would like to show you that you can actually set whatever values you want here.
So let's say we want tick marks at point eight five.
And how about one point zero four.
OK.
So for this particular matrix this isn't really a sensible set of Y ticks but that does show you how
easy it is to define the Y ticks however you want them to be.
All right.
Now what we're going to do is implement the formula that I showed in the slides to create that nice
looking matrix.
So let's start by creating a matrix that we initialize to be zeros.
So this is going to be a 10 by 14 matrix and let's already even look at this thing.
So you can see it's a matrix of all zeros and we can confirm that it is in fact a matrix that has 10
rows and 14 columns.
I mean here you just see it right here.
But I'm going to use a function and PS num pi dot shape and this is going to return the shape of this
matrix.
So the shape is the number of sizes in each dimension.
So the first dimension which is the rows has 10 elements.
And the second dimension which is columns has 14 elements.
OK so now what we need to do is assign this formula to each individual element of the matrix.
So it's gonna be something like the I.S. throw and the J column equals three times I minus four times
J.
Okay.
So that's generally how we implement the formula for element y's population of this matrix.
And now of course we need to loop over all the rows and all of the columns.
So let's say for I n now this is going to have to be a range and it's going to go from zero to the number
of rows.
So how can we figure out what is that the number of rows.
What should be the number here.
Now of course you can just look at this here and I could write 10 and technically that works but that's
hard coding this number here and hard coding is generally something that should be avoided whenever
possible.
The reason is that if I want to make this matrix bigger let's say I just want to make it eleven then
all the sudden this is not going to work anymore.
This would also need to be adopted.
So therefore what I'm going to do is change this to be the shape of matrix A.
So I'm going to write and p dot shape of matrix A and now this is going to return to numbers it's going
to return a tuple and that you can see here and for the number of rows we just want to access the first
element of this.
So therefore I'm gonna write in square brackets zero like this and this will only return the first element
here which is of course the number of rows.
All right.
Now I want to write another for loop so for J.
In range 0 2 and p doc shape a.
And now of course we want the number of columns and so that's going to be 1.
All right.
So we try running this code.
Let's try running the code huh.
So this gives us an error.
It says expected an indented block.
And what's going on here is that this line of code assigning the result of this algorithm to the to
each element in the matrix A that actually has to be done inside this embedded for loop which means
we need to have the proper spacing here and the proper indentation.
All right.
So let's see what this looks like.
I'm going to start by just printing out this matrix.
OK.
So we get a bunch of numbers and it looks already kind of neat it's already kind of interesting to look
at.
You can see there's like this band here of small numbers and then there's larger numbers down here and
larger negative numbers over here.
And looking at this algorithm this actually does make sense.
This pattern does make sense.
And basically when these numbers are close to each other.
So when I is close to J then this result is going to be close to zero.
And the further away I is from J.
The larger the number is going to be.
And as you get down to later rows and earlier columns then this number becomes large relative to this
number.
So there we get large positive numbers.
And when you get to later columns and earlier rows then this term becomes large relative to this term.
And of course this is negatives.
Then you get large magnitude negative numbers over here.
Again I'm just showing how to use a combination of Python and visualization to understand mathematics
OK.
But what we want to do is actually see what this thing looks like as an image.
So plots that I am show a.
And then we already get this nice looking matrix down here.
All right.
So there are a few other things that I would like to illustrate to you here.
One is that we can draw lines on top of these matrices.
So for example I'm going to draw a line using the plot function that goes from 0 to 3 on the x axis
and 8 to 2 on the y axis.
I want to make sure that this line is really visible really easy to see.
So I'm gonna make it thick and red.
Okay.
So now let's look at this line of code and see how that maps onto this line.
So the x values go from 0 to 3 and then you see here zero up to three and then the y axis values go
from eight to two.
So eight up to two.
So notice here that the rows actually correspond to the y coordinates here.
So these are the rows of the matrix but this is the y axis of the matrix.
These are the columns of the matrix and that is on the x axis okay.
And that is the key insight to the next thing that I want to do which is to get all of these numbers
to print inside this matrix here.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do is write another for loop it's gonna be another double for loop here.
And what I want to do inside this for loop is plot a bit of text and the text is going to be each individual
number from this matrix A and it has to be plotted into the right location in the image so P L T dot
text.
Now I haven't yet used this text function so this might be a bit new to you essentially the way that
this works is you supply three inputs corresponding to the x axis location and the y axis location and
then the actual text that you want to display.
Okay so now because of what I just said we actually need to plot at index J.
Comma I.
And then the text is going to be the.
Well let me first write it as the matrix and then the I.F. J ith element OK so what you see is that
we get a bunch of decimal points in here so it's kind of hard to see what's really happening it's hard
to make out the individual numbers.
So therefore I'm going to write it basically just to convert these into integers just so it's less to
look at.
All right.
So this is starting to look a little bit better.
But one thing I don't like about this is that the numbers are not really centered so the numbers are
kind of OK for these single digits.
But out here.
You know it's like the numbers are kind of spilling off into the neighbors into the next pixels.
So what I'm going to do is adjust the alignment of these numbers of the text so horizontal
alignment equals center.
So this is an optional input that you can give into the text function to make the horizontal alignment
be centered.
So that's starting to look a little bit better.
And now you see that the numbers are also kind of shifted up.
So I'm going to copy and paste here except now it's going to be
vertical alignment center.
All right.
And this is starting to look really nice.
So let me explain once again very quickly why the order is swapped here.
So the order is swapped here because I want the number from the Matrix to be plotted in the correct
row and column.
So when you're storing information in a matrix you always store it using row first and then column.
However when you're making a plot the x axis corresponds to the columns and the y axis corresponds to
the rows.
And that's why the order is different here.
Okay.
Now there is one more thing that I would like to do and that is to change this color plot so change
the color scaling.
So I'm going to write P.L. t the set C map and the C in map is for color.
So I'm going to change the color map to be from its defaults to something called a map called purples.
So this is a pretty nice looking color map.
It goes from white to purple so large positive values will be deep purple and large negative values
will be white.
Now how did I know that that was a color map.
And how can I find all of the other color maps that python can show essentially the way that I did this
was by opening up an Internet browser and searching for Python color maps.
So the Internet is your friend particularly when it comes to programming in Python.
One of the nice advantages of Python as a language is that it has a very large user base all over the
world of people who post a lot of things on the internet about using Python.
So here this first result choosing color maps in map plot lib.
Now there's a lot of text and I encourage you to go through this but basically I'm just going to scroll
down and show you.
Here are some of the options for various color maps.
So let's try.
For example Twilight shifted.
That looks pretty interesting.
So Twilight shifted.
OK.
That's also a nice one in this video you learned how to make images from matrices of data and I also
showed you several new functions in the NUM pi tool box and I showed you more details about generating
plots in the next video.
There is going to be a challenge and exercise for you to complete based on the knowledge that you gained
in this video.