There might be times when you're tempted to immediately jump in
and just start coding a solution with the CDK.
But I encourage you, take time to go in and review the documentation,
and that's exactly what we're going to be doing here
before we start building anything.
So here we're first going to be launching the CDK documentation,
which, of course, we've done multiple times.
And we'll be reviewing the packages that we're going
to need for our implementation.
So let's dive in.
So I'm here within the terminal, and just like before,
I'm going to launch the documentation using cdk docs.
So here within the documentation, I'm going to click on API Reference.
Now one of the first places that we're going to go is
we're going to go to look at Lambda.
So I'm going to scroll down, and I'm going to look at AWS Lambda,
and I'm going to click on the Overview page.
Now you'll see here the TypeScript package that we need to worry with.
You also can see here that both our L1 and L2
constructs are stable for AWS Lambda.
And I wanted to showcase a few things here.
So here's an example of using the L2 construct.
We can go in and create a new lambda function,
we can specify a runtime, we can specify a handler,
and then we can specify where the code is located.
Now in this case, we're going to be using local code for this.
So we're going to have a directory within our project where
we'll have the code for our lambda function,
and we want it to take care of packaging that up for us and deploying it.
And that's what's shown here.
We can use this lambda.Code.fromAsset and actually tell it
the directory to go look for this in.
But if you remember, we're going to be building out our API in TypeScript.
That means we need to worry about things like building it
so we actually have a JavaScript output,
packaging it together with our production dependencies,
and then creating that bundle file.
So let's just hold that for a minute,
and we'll talk about how we do that in just a bit.
So here you can see that we have three different
options for using our handler code.
We can actually do it from a bucket.
So if you've already deployed a ZIP file, you can use that option.
And next, you can do it inline.
And again, this should be something that you do rarely.
There can be some cases where this makes sense,
but usually you're going to want to choose one of the other two options.
And then the third option is the one that we just
discussed where we can utilize the fromAsset,
which will allow us to point to either directory,
and it'll take care of bundling that for us.
Or we can specify a ZIP file.
Now you also can go through here,
and you can specify a lot of additional options.
You can go in and define some different information about
the role that's used for execution.
You can go through and specify versions and aliases.
But let's not worry with that for the moment.
Here,
we're going to be able to accept most of the defaults that
are included within the L2 construct.
But we need to think a little bit more about this bundling process.
So here, I'm going to go to another package, and that's going to be s3‑assets.
Now you'll note here that the CDK constructs that are
used for this are experimental.
Now this is also a package that is in addition to AWS S3.
So when you have three elements within a particular package,
that means that this is something in addition to
what's included with CloudFormation.
So we don't have L1 constructs for this.
These are designed to make key tasks easier.
So if we look here at s3‑assets,
this includes the option for us to create an asset.
And an asset is what is needed when we're actually specifying
where our code is within our lambda function.
Now this gives us the option here to just specify a directory.
We've already seen that.
But we also have some other options.
So if I scroll down, we can look at the actual asset bundling process.
So there's an option within this particular package where we can
specify a Docker image and then a command,
and it will handle building for us.
Now for us, when we're talking about our lambda function,
this is going to mean installing our production dependencies,
building TypeScript into JavaScript,
all the things we need to do that would be handled
within the asset bundling process.
So we could specify a Docker image,
and we could go through and specify each of those commands.
But if this is in a Docker image,
that's going to take quite a while during the build process.
So there is another option that we can take a look at.
There is an option to do a local build process.
Now there are some reasons why you wouldn't want to do this.
Let me just give you a quick download of the different approaches.
First, if you just have normal dependencies, you can use a local process.
And instead of taking maybe 3 or 4 minutes to build,
it might be done in 5 seconds.
But if you have dependencies that have to be compiled natively,
and you want be sure that's done in the exact same
container as what would happen within Lambda,
then you won't want to use the local option.
So there's an option here where you can configure it.
You can run through this try bundle function,
and if it succeeds, it will just do it locally.
If not, it will actually use the Docker image.
Now if you're looking at this saying you know what,
there's a lot here, but I think we can make this work,
I want to encourage you, you actually don't have to worry about this.
I want to make sure that you know what's happening behind the
scenes, but the CDK has made this process even easier.
So I'm going to scroll up back to aws‑lambda, and I'm
going to look at aws‑lambda‑nodejs.
Now this is another package where we have three different
elements in the name, and that means, again, this isn't
analogous to CloudFormation.
This is something extra that's provided to make things easier.
And we can see here that these CDK constructs are
experimental. So they can change.
However, they will make your life quite a bit easier.
So here, if we look at this process,
we can simply go in and define our entry point and our handler
function, and what will happen behind the scenes is it's going to go
through and handle that build process for us.
It knows how to deal with package.json files. It
knows how to compile TypeScript.
In this case, it's going to be using Parcel for that.
It's going to bundle together your needed dependencies and create the
ZIP file that's needed for it to be used as an asset.
Now there are some different configuration values that are supported.
We can specify different environment variables for our container
environment in the build process or specific build arguments.
We also can go through and work with Parcel to
configure the specifics of how it builds.
For example, we can specify external modules.
We would almost always want to specify the AWS SDK as an external module
because it's going to be included within the Lambda environment,
so we don't need to package it in with our code.
But if you're using an external layer where you have additional dependencies,
you want to be sure those are not included as well.
Now we're not going to be using a layer in our case,
so we'll just make sure that we're specifying the AWS SDK for this value.
Now with all of this said,
that pretty much gives us a pathway to implementing our lambda function.
There's one other thing I want to point out.
So I'm going to scroll to api‑gateway. And immediately, you'll
notice that there are two different options.
We have api‑gateway and api‑gatewayv2. Now api‑gateway
refers to the REST‑based endpoints, and api‑gatewayv2
refers to the HTTP API endpoints.
Now we're going to be using the HTTP option. These are actually newer,
and in most cases, they're going to be a little bit faster. If you don't
need all the capabilities of the REST endpoints, the HTTP API endpoints
would probably work really well for you.
We can see here that the L1 constructs are stable.
The L2 constructs for HTTP APIs are experimental, and we don't
have any L2 constructs yet for WebSocket APIs.
Now we're going to be using HTTP APIs, so we're not
concerned about the WebSocket APIs right now.
And if I scroll down a little bit here, you're going to see a great example.
This example here is going to be very similar to what we're going to
be doing within our API. We're going to be creating a lambda
function. We'll then be creating a lambda proxy integration. And then
with that, we'll create an HTTP API. And then we'll create a route
where we specify a path,
a method, and then we link that in with the integration. With
all of these pieces that we've researched,
we should be able to build out an HTTP API that we can use for our document management proof of concept.