So now we'll walk through the process of updating our existing CDK app.
So here within this demo we're first going to be creating a custom construct.
And we'll spend some time looking at this.
Now,
the focus on creating reusable constructs will be covered
within the next course in this path.
Then we'll be adding a VPC to our CDK app using L2 constructs from the CDK.
Then we'll be utilizing the diff command from the CDK CLI to
see the difference between what's in the cloud and what is
within our local environment.
And then ultimately we'll be deploying our app update.
So, let's dive in.
So I want to start in a bit of an unusual place.
I'm here on GitHub looking at a sample that is provided by AWS.
Now this is within their WordPress reference architecture,
and this is a CloudFormation template that is a nested
stack within a larger CloudFormation stack.
Now,
what I want to showcase here is this is how they create a
configurable VPC using traditional CloudFormation templates.
Now if you remember,
looking back within the previous course in this path we talked
through declarative templates and some of the difficulties that exist
And we're going to see this played out here.
You can see here we can have potentially up to six different
availability zones that are supported with this template.
And that's great.
However,
to have this level of customization within a declarative template we're
going to have a lot of boilerplate and then a lot of these configuration
values for the different conditions that exist.
So if I scroll down, just as an example,
and I get to the Conditions section,
you're going to see that we're going to have to define a
lot of different values here based on the number of
availability zones that we pass in.
So if we say that we want six,
you can see here that we'll go through and set the value of these conditions.
And maybe where this was really best shown is if I scroll all
the way down to the bottom of the document where we actually
have the outputs of this template.
When we get to these outputs we're creating this tree of conditions to actually
get to the point where we're outputting the correct subnets.
And you can see here that to create this configurable VPC
we have about 1000 N1 lines of YAML.
So, we're going to talk about the way that we go about this.
And instead of putting that configuration within the
CloudFormation template we let the CDK do it for us.
That's what we're going to be adding to our existing application.
So, now let's navigate over to VS Code.
So I'm here within VS code,
and right now if you remember within our CDK stack
we have two different resources, our bucket and our CloudFormation output.
Now we could keep building things this way.
We could just keep going in and adding new resources here within this stack,
but that's going to become difficult at some point because we're
going to have enough resources that aren't really grouped
together that we're just going to have a huge long class that has
all the different resources.
So one of the things you will generally do is you'll create
some constructs within your overall stack,
and that's what we're going to do here.
So I'm going to go here under the lib directory and
I'm going to create a new file.
And we're going to call this one networking.
Now here within networking I have a snippet that we're going to use
And we're just going to call this one Networking.
And I want to point out a few things with this.
So first of all,
this particular snippet assumes that we're going to
be passing some properties in.
So, in this case I'm going to add a value to this.
And this is going to allow us to pass in a value for the
maximum number of availability zones.
And here with this we'll use that when we create our VPC.
Now the next thing I want to point out is within these custom constructs.
We also need to be able to expose variables because we want to be
able to make our VPC that we create here within our networking
construct available later within this course when we create our
Fargate service because it will need to know what VPC it needs to
launch that service into.
Now we're not going to implement this just yet because we need some
additional information because here we haven't yet installed a
package for EC2 that will allow us to get access to all the
different ways that we can create VPCs.
So, just like before, let's go ahead and jump over into the CDK documentation.
So I'm going to open up the terminal, and I'm going to type in cdk docs.
Once this opens up, I'm going to click on API REFERENCE.
And then here in the left pane I'm going to scroll down until I get to ec2.
And then I'll click on Overview.
So first of all, we're going to see here the package that we need to install.
So I'm actually going to grab this and we'll copy it.
We'll need this in just a bit once we get back over into VS Code.
Next thing you'll note here,
both the L1 and the L2 constructs are stable for this particular package.
Now the initial section that we have here is around VPC. And
you can see here that creating a VPC can be just as simple as
this single line that's shown here.
However, in most cases we're going to want to customize this to some extent.
So this includes some generalizations that exist.
If you've ever created a VPC from scratch you know that
you need to go in and create the VPC, create the different subnets,
go in and create the route tables,
go in and create the NAT gateways and potentially the Internet gateway,
and so on and so forth.
There's a lot of different steps that are taken. But here within
this L2 construct it's going to generalize a lot of this while still
providing room for us to configure it.
So I'm going to scroll down here.
First, note that it supports three different subnet types,
public, private, and isolated.
We're going to be using both public and private subnets.
So I'm going to keep scrolling down,
and you can see here that it does give you a level of
control over availability zones.
We'll talk about that in just a minute.
But I want to get here to this section of Advanced Subnet Configuration.
And here this allows us to pass in the cidr block,
the maximum number of availability zones,
and the different subnet configurations that we're going to need.
And this looks perfect for what we're going to do.
So, with this being said,
let's move back over to VS Code and let's start the
process of implementing this.
Now the first step to implementing this is we need to install our package.
So I'm going to do npm install.
I'm going to paste in the package that we copied from the
documentation, and then we'll save this.
Now I'm going to close out the terminal.
From here we can now import this package.
And now that we have this imported,
I'm now going to add a property in on the class.
So here we're going to have a public property, it's going to be readonly,
and it's going to be our vpc.
And this is going to be of type ec2.IVpc.
So now that we have that in place, we now need to create our VPC.
So here, I've pasted in a configuration for our VPC.
You can see here we have a defined cidr block and we have a
defined set of public and private subnets.
Now I have maxAzs here set at 2, but, if you remember,
we don't want to just use a static value here.
We want to be able to pass that in.
So here I'm going to change this instead of being just a static
number we're going to call this props?.maxAzs.
And now we're able to actually utilize that value.
Now in this case,
we're going to want this to not be optional so I'm going
to remove the question mark because we do need this value
to be able to create our VPC.
So perfect.
At this point we have a VPC that's configured,
we're able to receive props in, and, in addition to that,
we're exposing our VPC for future use within our application.
So at this point I'm going to save this and I'm
going to go back over to the stack.
Next, I'm going to go in and we're going to import this.
Now that I have this created,
I'm now able to go in and create a new instance of our custom construct
And we can see here we need to pass in the scope,
which is going to be our stack, and we need to give it a name.
We'll call this our NetworkingConstruct And we now need to pass in the props,
which in this case is going to have a single property,
which is going to be the maximum number of availability
zones. And we'll just set this at 2.
So now that I have that in place, we now have a change to our application.
So at this point I'm going to go in and I'm going to open the terminal back up.
And now I'm going to go in and type cdk,
and I'm going to type in a command we haven't yet used which is diff.
And so here we can see that we've added a lot of resources to our stack.
If I scroll all the way back up here to where we ran the command,
we can see here that we're adding in a VPC,
a subnet, a route table, subnet route table association,
route, Elastic IP,
so on and so forth You can see all of the different types
of resources that are created here.
And these are all things we would need to create explicitly if we were using
either L1 constructs or a CloudFormation template directly.
But in this case this has been abstracted for us in an L2 construct
that we can easily integrate within our application.
So now that we can see the changes that exist, we can now run cdk deploy.
And now we can see that the deployment process has
completed for our application.
So let's move over into the AWS Console.
So I'm here in the AWS Console and now I'm going to
navigate over to CloudFormation.
From within CloudFormation, I'm going to click on our TypescriptCdkStack.
And here, if I now go under Resources,
we're going to see that we have many additional
resources beyond what we had Initially.
We still have our CDKMetadata and our DocumentsBucket, but now we have all of
the additional networking components that we've added in,
everything from our VPC to the Internet gateway to all of the subnets
and the route tables and route table associations,
Elastic IPs, NAT gateways, all of those things are included within here.
So,
one of the things we're going to need to look at next is we're going to
need to look at how we categorize different components of our application for the purpose of cost allocation.