So now, to help us understand better what the CDK is actually doing,
we're going to be generating the CloudFormation templates for our CDK app.
So first, we'll use the CLI to generate those CloudFormation templates for our
CDK app, and then we'll be reviewing the generated templates.
So, let's dive in.
So first, just as a reminder, here is our current CDK application.
We have two resources that have been configured within our primary
stack, and that is an S3 bucket that has encryption set to be
S3_MANAGED, and we have a CloudFormation output,
which is going to output the bucket name of our bucket.
So now I'm going to navigate over to the terminal, and we'll
generate the CloudFormation templates for this stack.
So I'm here within the base directory of our project,
and I'm going to create a new directory called templates.
And then within here, I'm now going to run cdk synth,
and I'm going to pass it the directory that we just created.
And now I'm just going to run the command.
So now that the command has completed, I'm going to move over back into VS Code.
So now I'm here in VS Code, and I can see that I now have a templates directory.
I'm going to go ahead and open up this directory, and I'll see that I have
the name of a template that corresponds to my stack,
which is TypescriptCdkStack. So I'm going to click on this, and I can
see now that generated JSON template for my stack.
So if we look here,
there's a few things to point out. Here within the Resources
section we do have our bucket, our DocumentsBucket.
So there's a few things I want to point out here.
First of all,
you'll notice that we gave it a name of DocumentsBucket, and you can
see that that becomes the base for the name within CloudFormation, but
it does have an identifier placed after it.
In addition, you can see that our BucketEncryption option is configured here.
We can see that we are using AES‑256 server‑side encryption. And again,
this is going to be managed by S3. We also have some
specific details included here, such as the DeletionPolicy,
which in this case is set to Retain.
It also includes some CDK‑specific metadata, which in this case lets
it know what the CDK path is for the resource.
So if I scroll down here,
we also can see that we have our output configured, and this output
is going to be the output that will appear within CloudFormation
that will have the name of our bucket.
And we can see here that the name of this export is
going to be DocumentsBucketName.
So this is what we have in terms of our generated stack.
So now that we have this in place, and now that we've had a chance to
review the generated JSON template for our app we're now ready in the next clip to go through the process of deploying it.