So now we're going to be deploying our container with the AWS CDK.
So here within this demo,
we're first going to be creating a new construct for our web server.
We'll then be configuring a Docker image asset to store in the ECR, we'll
be deploying our container as a service on Fargate,
and then ultimately, we will be verifying our deployment,
so let's dive in.
So the first thing I'm going to need to do is I'm going
to need to install some packages.
So here, we're basically going to need three different packages.
First is AWS ECS, and again, that is the actual service package,
but then we also have AWS ECS patterns, and again,
this is a three element name, meaning it is provided in addition to the service,
and here,
they're going to be some great constructs that we can leverage that
make deploying our service on Fargate even easier.
We're also going to be using AWS ECR assets,
which provides an easy way for us to take our directory
that contains a Docker file and make it a container that we
can reference within the ECR.
So I'll go ahead and install these packages.
So now I'll navigate back over to VS code.
So here, within VS code,
I'm going to go in my lib directory and I'm going to create a new file.
We're going to call this webserver.ts and here I'm going to use the same
snippet I've used before to create a custom construct.
We're going to call this DocumentManageWebServer,
and then we're going to need to import some different packages.
So first,
we're going to need to import path because we will use this to get a
reference to the directory where our Docker file is stored.
Then we're going to need to import a Docker image asset from AWS ECR
assets, and then we're going to need to import AWS EC2 because we're
going to need to get the type of IVPC to specify that as a specific
parameter that needs to be passed in.
Then we're going to import ECS patterns,
which we're going to call ECSP, which is different from a regular ECS,
which we'll also be importing because we'll need that as well.
And in addition,
we're also going to need to bring in API gateway and I'll show you why.
Here within our document management web server props,
we're going to need to get references to two different
things to be able to launch our web server.
The first is going to be our VPC and that's going to be of type ec2 IVpc.
Now the next thing we're going to need a reference to is we're
going to need a reference to our API and the reason is is because
we need to be able to pass in that base URL as an environment
variable which we can get from this.
So we're going to have this be of type apig HttpApi.
So those two props are going to be required,
so I'll remove the optional statement here.
Now the next thing I want to do is I want to
actually create my Docker image asset,
so we're going to call this webserverDocker and this is
going to be a new Docker image asset. Now,
just like any construct, we'll pass in this and then we need to give it a
name and then we need to pass in our parameters object.
Now here, we really only need to specify one thing and
that's going to be the directory.
So now that we have that in place,
that's all we need to do to deploy our Docker container into the ECR.
But now that we have that in place,
we're going to be using another construct here and this is
what's going to automate our use of Fargate.
So we're going to call this our fargateService and here we're going to use ECSP,
which is the AWS ECS patterns package,
and there is a construct for ApplicationLoadBalancedFargateService,
and here, this is what we're going to be leveraging and this is
going to take care of much of what we covered earlier within this
module where we talked through how you deploy a fargate task and
then make that a service.
So here, we're going to need to give it the scope, we need to give
it a name, and then we need to specify our props.
Well, there is a couple things we're going to specify here.
First,
we need to specify our VPC. Now you don't have to, it
actually would create a VPC for you, however,
we created one already and we want to use that one so
we're going to say props.vpc. Now,
the next thing that we need to specify is we need to
specify the task image options.
So here, within the task image options we're first going to specify the image.
Now here, we're going to say ecs.container image and then we're going
to specify fromDockerImageAsset, and then from here, we can simply
pass in our webserverDocker image asset.
So now that we have that in place,
we can now specify those environment variables that we mentioned earlier.
So here, we're going to create an object,
and the first one is going to be server port.
Now again,
we could probably just hard code this in, we
wouldn't have to include this value,
but I'm showing you how to pass in multiple environment variables.
What we do need though, and what is required for this to
work properly is that API base value.
And so, what we're going to do is we're going to use props,
and we're going to reference our API, and then we're
going to specify the URL of the API,
and we want to be sure that is present and that's not an optional value.
Next,
we need to specify the container port because we need to know what
port it is going to be broadcasting on, and so,
in this case, it's going to use Port 8080.
That's really all we need to do.
It's going to go through the process of looking at our VPC,
determining how many public and private subnets we have,
putting fargate within our private subnets and putting the
application load balancer in the public subnets. Because we haven't
specified a certificate or a domain or a hosted zone, it's just
going to be using HTTP and not HTTPS,
but that's perfect for what we're looking to do.
But we're going to go through and we're going to do one additional thing,
and that is we're going to create a new cloud formation output, and then
we're going to specify for our export name this is going to be web server
host, and for the value, this is going to be the
fargateService.loadBalancer and then the loadBalancerDnsName.
Now we need to integrate this construct into our stack.
First,
we're going to go in and actually import this and then we're
going to go in and create a new instance of it.
Now, if you remember, we need to pass in two values.
The first is going to be the VPC,
and that's going to be under our networkingStack.vpc.
The next thing, though,
that we need to pass in is we need to pass in the API, but
the problem is is we haven't actually exposed the API yet
within our DocumentManagementAPI.
So I'm going to click into this construct.
So here, we're first going to go in here and create a property,
and we're going to make this a public read‑only property,
and it is going to be httpApi and it's going to be of type apig.HttpApi.
Now the next thing we need to do is just change how we reference this.
So here, instead of having this be a local variable,
we're going to make this that property,
and then we just need to reference everywhere where we're
using httpApi to use the correct value.
So now that we have this in place, we now have exposed our httpApi.
So now I can go back over to the stack, I can go here under api, we can now
go to api and then do httpApi and now we've included it.
The last thing we need to do is probably not a surprise.
We're going to tag all of the resources within this construct.
So we're going to say Tags.of (webserver), we're going to add the module,
and we're going to call that Webserver.
Now that we have all of this in place, we're now ready to deploy our stack.
So I'm going to navigate over to the terminal. Here within the terminal, I'm
going to run cdk deploy. So here, we have a lot of security changes. Now
we're not going to walk through these line by line,
but we're adding in some new security groups and some new IAM permissions.
I'm going to accept these and we're going to continue deployment.
Now that our deployment is complete,
we can see that we do have an output here that's going to give us the
URL that will allow us to access the load balancer.
So I'm going to go ahead and copy this value,
and now we're going to navigate over to the browser.
So I'm going to paste this value in, and when I do,
you can see that it does give us our list of documents.
And just as before,
we can open up one of these documents and actually see it using the signed URL.
So let's quickly dive in and take a look at the AWS console.
So now that I'm here in the console,
I'm going to navigate to the elastic container service, and when I do,
you can see that we do have one service and one
running task on our Fargate cluster.
And if I click into this,
I can see the particular service that we have configured.
And then within here, I can see the given tasks that we have.
You'll notice here, for example,
when I go into the task and I click on our current task,
you can see that we do have the configuration included,
including our API base value and our server port.
But hopefully you see here that through using these
reusable constructs and ECS patterns,
we have greatly simplified the process of deploying our container in a load balanced manner to AWS.