So now we're going to talk about how we manage the CDK dependencies
that we leverage within our CDK applications. So here,
over the course of this demo,
we're first going to be accessing the CDK documentation because you'll
find this is an essential part of working within the CDK.
I generally always have a tab open to the CDK documentation.
Also,
we're going to be installing service‑specific packages for use within the
CDK because if we're going to be using most any service,
we need to be able to install its package into our project.
And then we're going to be reviewing some best practices
for managing dependencies for a project.
And then we're going to be creating our first bit of infrastructure in
TypeScript when we configure an S3 bucket for use with the CDK.
So, let's dive in.
So it might seem strange, but to get to the CDK documentation,
I'm going to start here within my IDE.
I'm just going to open up a new terminal,
and I'm going to run the command cdk and docs.
This will open up the latest documentation for the CDK. And so
here I can see that it has launched the latest version of the CDK
documentation here within my browser.
So I'm going to click on the option here for API Reference, and as
mentioned, you'll spend a lot of time here. Now,
first of all,
I want to call out on the left side, we can see most all of the
different services that are supported within the CDK.
And so if I scroll all the way down here, I'm first going to go into S3.
So I'm going to click on S3 and then I'll click on Overview.
Now,
I want to call out here at the top, there's a couple things I need to
mention. First is you can see here with the TypeScript language, we
have a specific reference to the package that we will need to install
locally within our project.
Now,
we can't actually create an S3 bucket if we don't have
this particular package installed.
The second thing I want to call out here is we can see here both the
CFN‑RESOURCES, meaning CloudFormation resources,
and the CDK‑CONSTRUCTS are both listed here as stable.
We'll talk more about what that means within the next clip and why that's
important, but that is something that you need to watch before you create
some infrastructure so that you know whether or not the underlying
constructs are going to be changing.
Now I'm going to scroll down and look at some of what is included here.
First of all,
I can see here that it gives us the ability to create an S3
bucket, and it gives us a sample for this.
Now, this is a construct that we're using, and we can see here on the left,
we can see this listed under Constructs.
And here we can see a lot of the different types of
settings that we can configure,
we can see things like encryption, we can see things like
different permissions that we can set.
So, this is perfect, this is exactly what we need.
So I'm going to go up here to the option where it shows
encryption, I'm going to copy this particular option,
and I'm now going to bounce back over to Visual Studio Code.
So here,
I'm going to go ahead and close out my terminal just to give me
some more screen real estate, and I'll slide this pane over, and
here where we have the comment,
I'm going to delete this, and now I'm going to go and I'm
going to paste in this particular value.
Now, you'll notice here that we're getting errors because we don't have
the AWS S3 package currently installed, so we're going to need to fix
that so that we can get a reference to these.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to open back up the
terminal and here within our project,
I'm going to go in, I'm going to say npm install @aws‑cdk because
everything for the CDK exists under the @aws‑cdk scope.
And so, if you're looking for a specific package for the CDK,
chances are it is also going to be under this scope.
And most of them are structured like this, aws, and then dash, the service.
So in this case,
we're looking for aws‑s3. And then I'm just going to say Save
because we do want this to be saved as a dependency within our
project. And we can see that we have installed aws‑s3 as a
dependency for our project.
Now, we still have errors here because we haven't actually imported this.
So I'm going to go in and I'm going to say import,
and then, in this case,
we're going to say bucket and a bucket encryption, and we're going to
import these from, so now you can see that in doing so,
we've now actually fixed the errors that we were seeing.
So now I'm going to close out the terminal, again, just to
give us back some screen real estate, and now I'm going to update a few things.
First of all,
we're going to actually give this an ID, and we're going
to call this our DocumentsBucket. Now,
you'll notice here that there are several arguments that need to be passed
in, and this is going to be a common pattern that we'll see when we're
working with the TypeScript version of the CDK. First,
with any construct that we create,
we're going to need to pass in a reference to the stack that it exists in.
That's why we have the this value that gets passed in as the first argument.
Next, we're going to need to give it an ID.
And this ID is going to be the basis for the CloudFormation
logical ID when we actually launch this within AWS. And then the
third thing is, a properties object that will show us the
different values that can be passed in.
And you can certainly find those within the
documentation that we just saw in the browser.
I also can hold down Command and actually click here on the name, and
I can see here that we have an option here called BucketProps, that's
an optional object that gets passed in.
If I click on this, if I hit Command+Click,
I can see all the options that are available.
We can see here encryption, which is what we're working with.
We can pass in a value for that encryptionKey, bucketName,
RemovalPolicy, whether or not it's version,
all of these things are included.
So in this case,
I'm going to close this back out, and we'll go up here to
where it says BucketEncryption, and we can see here that I'm
just going to choose S3_MANAGED, because in this case,
I do want it to be encrypted, but I'm not actually going to be
maintaining my own encryption keys within kms,
and so this enables me to get encryption, but without
having to manage those underlying keys.
Now, I want to go in and look really quickly at the package.json file.
So I want to call out here that, first of all,
you'll notice that the aws‑cdk/core and aws‑cdk/aws‑s3
are both the same version, 1.62.0.
Also, under devDependencies,
we have the assert package and the aws‑cdk package, both of
those are also under the same version.
Here's something that's critical.
You need to make sure that every single package that you pull
in for the CDK is using the same version.
They all have the same release cycle,
and there could be issues that occur when you're
trying to use different versions.
In some cases, you might get some weird errors,
and it might not be immediately obvious what's going on.
Your first step, if that happens,
is to check and make sure that every single CDK package that you
have is using the exact same version. And the easiest way to keep
up with this is just to be sure, before you're installing any new
package, just to go through and then update all of your packages
before you do that.
Now,
if you have a production application and you're concerned about always
updating because you want to be sure that you don't have to go through and
potentially fix some of your elements of infrastructure,
you can simply install and then utilize a specific version.
So, for example,
if I wanted to go back and install the AWS S3 package again, and so I could go
in and I could say npm install, and then I could say @aws‑cdk, which is the
scope, aws‑s3, and then I could finish it with an @ sign and specify the exact
version that I wanted to install. In this way,
you could make sure that you're installing the exact right version if you're
using a single version for your production application.
But the key is just to make sure that you don't mismatch the different versions of the CDK packages that you're using.