The default implementation actually supports both Basic and formLogin.
Let's configure the application to just use Basic.
Now to do this,
we will need a configuration class that extends the
WebSecurityConfigurationAdapter and add the Configuration annotation.
Recall the SpringBootWebSecurityConfiguration class,
which was imported by the SecurityAutoConfiguration class.
It will now detect that there is a bean of type
WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter and will not configure the default one as a bean.
This is important.
Otherwise, we would have two filter chains configured.
The default one will have an order of -5 with an AnyMatcher.
Hence requests would not reach the new filter chain unless
we specifically set a lower order value.
We are going to override the configure method that
accepts the HttpSecurity as a parameter.
The parent method has the form and basic.
We will override this and just have basic.
(Working) Let's start the application at a breakpoint and
try to access the portfolio site again.
As you can see,
the username and password authentication filter is
no longer present in the chain, just the basic one.
Also, the basic entry point is now the default in the exceptions filter.
If we allow the request to progress, we get the browser's default login pop-up.
I'll cancel for now.
You can see that when we try to access the portfolio site,
Spring returned a 401 Not Authorized, as well as a header property,
WWW-Authenticate, with a value of Basic and Realm.
This informed the client browser that basic authentication was required,
hence the browser displaying the login pop-up.
If we log in this time,
you can see that the browser sends a response with a header
property Authorization: Basic and an encoded string.
The basic authentication filter will be looking out for this header.
The value here can be a bit misleading as it looks encoded or encrypted.
But in reality, it's encoded in base 64 and it's easy to convert back.
I just Googled a random site that converts from base 64 to base 10,
and here you can see the format, the username: password,
which is why it is recommended to transmit basic over HTTPS so
that a hacker sniffing network traffic cannot capture your
credentials or perform replay attacks.
Now the upside of basic is that you don't need a login page.
You don't need session IDs, you don't need cookies, and the user can also embed the credentials directly into the URL.