To authorize requests to URLs, you use the authorizeRequest builder.
Let's go through the current setup.
You can use the antMatchers to define different
authorization strategies for your URLs.
You can define one or more URLs in an antMatcher.
Here we have the URLs we want to allow our users to
access without being authenticated, such as the login page,
by using the permitAll, which will just return true.
Next we match the two-factor authentication pages and use
the hasAuthority method to indicate only users with the TOTP
authority can access this page.
Finally, we say that for all other URLs,
we require an authenticated principal that has the role USER.
Now in Spring, roles and authorities differ in naming convention.
A role will have the ROLE_ prefix in front of it, and authorities do not.
Hence, when you use the hasRole USER method,
Spring will search for a value in the granted
authorities that has the role _USER.
However, when you use the hasAuthority,
Spring will look up the value that matches exactly.
Now conceptually,
the idea behind this is that roles are more course-grained
and essentially containers for authorities.
Example, both a user and admin might have authorities of paid services access,
but an admin will be the only one that has the admin area authority.
Again, nothing's stopping you from using just roles or just authorities.
In fact, in our two-factor authentication scenario,
after authenticating, the user is assigned an authority,
and only after providing their two-factor authentication code successfully,
they are assigned the ROLE_USER with full permission to the site.
In effect, they don't initially have a role,
but have the authority to access the TOTP login page,
hence not quite following the convention here,
but it works.
Finally, we have a catchall, which states that for any other requests,
the user must have the user role.
Now the catchall is very important.
It should be the final line and catch any requests that might slip through.
A good practice is to simply deny access completely.
Now as you can see, order is key here.
The matches are evaluated in order.
And now that we have the catchall denying everything,
it forces us to provide matches for all the URLs in our application.
Here we specify that for the portfolio and account URLs,
the role USER is required.
The \** means that it will match the entire directory tree,
basically everything after the portfolio.
Whereas if we just used /portfolio or portfolio/*,
it would not match other directories after the portfolio.
And order is key here.
If you were to switch the following around,
then a user would be able to access the admin pages as the
second matcher would not be reached.
So ensure your more precise rules go first.
This can be an issue with Spring Security as your config size grows.
So a good comprehensive test suite is advisable.
You can also provide multiple roles with the hasAnyRole,
which gives access if a user has either the role user or the role admin.
Now we probably want to give our admins access to the
portfolio for debugging purposes.
You can also define more finer-grained access
restrictions to a URL based on the HttpMethod.
Example, by adding the POST method to the matcher,
restricting users with the role admin to this URL
now only applies to POST requests.
There is, however, one issue with the AntMatchers.
Here we have added a RestController that returns
our list of users in the system.
We can configure it so that only admins can access it.
If we change the catchall to hasRole USER and try to access the URL,
as expected, nothing is returned as the user is not an admin.
However, if I add a /, the IDs are returned,
and file extensions can also get around this.
Now this is because Spring MVC sees both URLs as the same
and maps them to the same controller.
However, for the AntMatcher, they are two different URLs.
Hence, it defaults back to the catchall,
which allows access to users with the role USER,
again, why a catchall that denies all access is a good idea.
Now to fix this, you should use the mvcMatchers,
which use the Spring MVC API for matching,
meaning it matches the same way as the MVC controllers.
Here we have a URL that returns the portfolio of a user.
The username is a path variable so we surround it with the curly braces.
Let's configure it so the admin user can view any portfolios,
but users can only view their own.
To do this, we need an expression.
Hence, you can use the access method, which allows you to use expressions.
We can now select any of the expressions provided by Spring,
like hasRole to check if a user has the user or admin role.
Next, we can use the principal to get their username.
We can also use operations like and or or or equals.
Now if the user is an admin, they are now authorized to access the URL.
We can add the all, and if the principal has the role of user,
and the username matches the URL of the principal by
using the hash to reference the username,
then the user can also access the portfolio.
Now let's test this.
As expected, the logged-in user can view their portfolio,
but they cannot view other people's portfolios.
They would need the admin role for that.
As you can see, expressions are very powerful.
However, they could end up making your configuration look less readable.
Now SpEL allows you to reference beans using the ampersand.
Hence, if we create a class to handle the authorization logic,
let's call it IsPortfolioOwnerOrAdmin,
with a method that accepts the username as a string,
we can then get the Authentication object from the SecurityContext.
If the user has the admin role, we return true.
Of if they have the ROLE_USER and the username matches the authenticated user,
we also return true.
Otherwise, we return false.
We then annotate the class as a component or service to
add it to the application context.
Now back in our Configuration class,
we can change the expression to reference the bean using the ampersand,
starting with lowercase and call the check method,
passing in the username.
Much neater.
You can also restrict access based on how the principal was authenticated.
Perhaps you want certain sensitive parts of the application
not to be accessible if a user was authenticated by the
remember-me token in case it was stolen,
like for the admin sections of our application or the
Update Account Details sections.
For this, we can use the isFullyAuthenticated,
which would return false if the user was logged in
anonymously or via Remember me.
Hence,
the user would need to relog in with their credentials to access these sections.
Now to combine the role with this check,
we can use the access method and use the isFullyAuthenticated
expression and hasRole ADMIN expression.
Okay, now that covers the first layer of defense for authorization.
Next, we will take a look at the second layer, which is method-level authorization.