Hi everyone.
My name is Wojciech Lesniak, and welcome to my course,
Spring Security: Authentication and Authorization -
Building Effective Layers of Defense.
I have been using Spring now, back before it was even called Spring Security.
Getting security wrong can have significant repercussions,
especially to your users.
Hence, in this course,
we will take a peek under the covers of Spring Security at the moving parts,
which will allow you to more effectively mold the
framework around your security requirements.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include
multi-factor authentication; user sign-in,
additional security challenges, two-factor authentication,
email verification, and enforcing HTTPS,
authorization in your pages, URLs, methods,
and domain objects; dealing with common security threats and how Spring
Security protects you against them right out of the box; securing
secrets and user credentials; social sign-in,
outsourcing authentication with Spring Security OAuth2.
By the end of this course,
you will have a deeper understanding of the Spring Security framework,
allowing you to tailor it to your security requirements,
as well as allowing you to more easily debug issues when they inevitably arise.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with Java and the Spring framework.
I hope you will join me on this journey to learn how to build secure
applications with the Spring Security Authentication and Authorization: Building Effective Layers of Defense course at Pluralsight.