Hi, it's Wojciech Lesniak.
Welcome to this course on Spring Security Authentication and
Authorization - Building Effective Layers of Defense.
Why Spring Security?
Spring Security has been around since 2003, and that's a long time in IT terms.
It's supported by a large open source community who have a
vested interest in ensuring the framework keeps up to date with
the latest security trends and threats.
So why reinvent the wheel?
Spring Security provides authentication and authorization right out of the box.
It's an application layer security framework,
which means you're not tied to a particular web server.
It's loosely coupled.
You can use it in such a way that you can easily
migrate security to another framework.
It's very flexible as no two applications have the same security requirements.
Spring Security allows you to tailor it to your application needs,
and it also, by default,
protects you against some of the common security threats.
It begins protecting your application at the browser by instructing it
to communicate more securely with your application,
at the resource level by protecting your URLs and methods,
as well as your domain objects.
Now when considering a security approach,
you should consider a layered approach.
This is also known as defense in depth or the castle approach.
Just take any defensive structure, like a castle for that matter.
It doesn't only consist of one line of defense, like the outer wall.
There is usually a moat, an inner wall, a keep,
some towers perhaps, and, of course, a dragon.
Well maybe not a dragon, but you get the point.
There are multiple layers of defense.
And if you want to take control of the castle and steal the crowned jewels,
you have to penetrate all the layers.
Penetrating just one layer is self-contained.
Now this is how most modern well applications are secured.
You have your network defenses, like a firewall.
Then there is what you know, login, security questions perhaps.
Then there is what you have, like two-factor authentication on your phone.
And once you get authenticated, there is authorization,
what you can and cannot access.
And then there is hashing, encryption.
So even if the attacker was to gain access to the resource,
it most likely will be useless to them.
Hence, in the subsequent modules,
we will build layers of defense into our demo application using Spring Security and Spring Boot.