Hi, it's Wojciech Lesniak.
Welcome to this module on Persisting Access with Remember-Me.
Security has to be balanced with user experience.
If you make security to onerous,
it could discourage your users from using your site due to frequently
having to reset their credentials because they forgot them,
being locked out or throttled due to unsuccessful password attempts.
It can result in them using your site less often.
Just think of Amazon or EBay.
You generally don't need to log in each time you access their site to
browse their catalog or to add times to your basket.
Now Spring provides a solution to this with
persistent login through Remember me.
In this module,
you will learn how to securely implement Remember me using Spring Security,
the security challenges it introduces,
and the pros and cons between the different flavors
of Remember me offered by Spring.
Also,
you will learn how to add a CAPTCHA using Google reCAPTCHA API to
protect your site against scripts and bots.
So I hope you will join me for the remainder of this module where
you will learn how easy it is to add Remember me and CAPTCHA to your application using Spring Security.