Implementing a custom PermissionEvaluator is simple.
You need to create a class that extends the PermissionEvaluator
interface and override the two hasPermission methods.
Here is the first one.
We have access to the Authentication object,
the Domain object, and the permission required.
Because you can only have one evaluator added to the SecurityExpressionHandler,
I have created a DelegatingPermissionEvaluator that simply delegates to
other evaluators depending on the target domain class name.
In the first method,
we look up the evaluatorMap for the target evaluator using the qualified
class name and execute the evaluator's hasPermission method.
In the other method, we look up using the targetType.
We have one implementation of the evaluator for the portfolio.
In the first hasPermission method,
we check the instance of the object is a portfolio.
Check if the user has read permission for the portfolio instance.
Now to store the ACL, we use a PortfolioAccessControl entity,
which has a username, portfolioId, and type.
The type is either read, write, or any custom one we need for our application.
We retrieve the access control entry for that user and check
if they have access to that portfolioId.
Otherwise, we return false.
In the other implementation, we do the same,
but we need to look up the portfolio instance as it
is not passed into the method.
Again, you can implement your own logic here based on any requirements,
and you would need to using caching here,
particularly for the ACL entries as your application won't
be able to scale well if you create a datasource each time
an instance is accessed.
Next,
you need to add the expression handler to the MethodSecurityExpressionHandler.
We create a configuration class that extends the
GlobalMethodSecurityConfiguration and override the createExpressHandler method.
We create an instance of our delegating expression handler and add it
as an expression evaluator for the new instance of the
DefaultMethodSecurityExpresionHandler and return it.
Now our has expressions are available in MethodSecurity annotations.
In the portfolio repository,
you can add it to the findByUsername method using the PostAuthorize to ensure
the user has permission to read the returned portfolio object.
And again,
you can also use the PostAuthorize and the pre and postFilter methods as well.
Here we have the PreAuthorize where we check the user has read permission to the instance of the portfolio class with that portfolio ID.