A common feature on many web applications is email
verification following registration.
Now this gives you a number of security benefits.
It reduces the effectiveness of registration spam or bot registration,
ensures the user actually owns that email and is not someone trying
to impersonate the owner for malicious purposes,
gives you the ability to contact the person for feedback,
notifications, marketing,
and also a valid email can be used to automate
password reset and account recovery.
Let's implement this in our demo app.
Add the spring-boot-starter-mail dependency to your POM so
that we can send emails from our application.
Now for the purpose of the demo, I'm using gmail as my SMTP server.
You can add your email server details to the
application.yml under the mail property.
Now the email registration logic can go into the Registration
Controller after saving the new user's profile.
However, let's take advantage of Spring event handling.
This is a cleaner design approach, adhering to the open and close principle.
Now out of the box,
Spring provides many authentication events your application can subscribe to.
Their names are quite self- explanatory,
like the AuthenticationFailureBadCredentialsEvents.
You could use this to keep track of invalid logins due to bad
credentials provided to perhaps detect DOS attacks,
brute force attacks,
or to lock or throttle account after a certain number of failures.
In our case, none of these suffice, so we need a custom event.
To do this, create a class that extends the ApplicationEvents.
Here we can simply include the user property and a constructor to set it.
Next,
you need to create an event listener that implements the ApplicationListener
interface and set the new UserRegistrationEvent as the type.
Override the onApplicationEvent method, annotate the class as a service,
and Spring Boot will do the rest.
To send the verification email, you need to generate a unique code,
which will be included in the verification link sent to the user's email.
Now our site uses MongoDB, so we can use a verification entity.
MongoDB actually generates very long, unique identifiers, so I will use this.
However, if you are using a traditional database,
they generally increment their identifiers,
so they can be predicted.
Hence, it's not recommended to use that.
Now you need to ensure the user cannot access the
site until the email is verified.
In the UserDetails object that is returned by the UserDetailsService,
there are a number of Boolean properties that are quite
self-explanatory from account expired, locked or enabled,
and credentials expired.
If any of these are set to true, the user will not be authenticated,
and an exception, an event of that type will be thrown.
Now we will use the enabled property.
To trigger the event on user registration,
in the RegistrationController,
we wire in the Spring's authentication eventPublisher and use
it to publish the UserRegistrationEvent,
passing in the user entity being registered to the constructor.
Next,
we need a controller class that will handle the verification
when the link is clicked to enable the user.
We use the ID submitted to look up the username in the verification entity.
And if we can find the user, we activate the account.
Let's give this a quick test.
We now have registered, but we cannot yet login.
Let's verify our email and try again. We now have access to this site.