Remember me, or persistent login authentication,
refers to websites being able to remember the
identity of the user between sessions.
In Spring, this is handled by sending an additional cookie to the user's browser,
which is included in all future requests to the server.
Now if the session cookie expires and the remember-me
cookie is present and not expired,
the server will use the details in the remember-me cookie
to re-authenticate a user automatically.
Spring supports two flavors, hash-bashed token and persistent token.
Let's set up the hash-based token.
The cookie for hash-based has the username: expiry time: and md5
of the username: expiry time :password and key.
The username as identifiable in the UserDetailsService,
the password that matches the one retrieved in the UserDetails,
expiry time,
the date and time when the remember-me token expires expressed in milliseconds,
and the key, a private key that prevents modification of the remember-me token.
To set it up, it's very straightforward.
In our Configuration class on the HttpSecurity object,
we simply add the Remember me filter by using the rememberMe builder property.
The Remember me filter requires the
UserDetailsService to retrieve the role password,
which is used in the signature of the cookie.
In the Configuration class,
we can override the UserDetailsService method and
return our custom UserDetailsService,
which we can wire into the Configuration class.
You now need an authenticationSuccessHandler.
You can use the same one as the login because if the user
has two-factor authentication enabled,
we need to prompt them to re-enter their verification code before
authorizing them to access their portfolio.
Now the reason for this is if the remember- me cookie was stolen,
it is just like the password was obtained by the hacker.
You can use the cookie to access the site.
Hence, two-factor authentication would protect the user from that scenario.
Finally,
we add the Remember me checkbox to the login page with the
name Remember me as this will be the property the Remember me
filter will be looking out for.
Okay, now if we log into the site with Remember me selected,
you can see we have two cookies, the session and the remember- me cookie.
If we remove the session cookie and close the tab and
try to access the portfolio page,
you can see we are prompted to re-enter our two-factor
authentication verification code.
However, we are not prompted to login with the password and the pin.
Remember me saved the user from having to retype the username,
password, and pin.
Now a few useful properties of Remember me.
You can set the remember-me cookie name.
By default, it was simply Remember me and also the key.
If you don't provide the key, Spring will autogenerate one,
which means when the application shuts down, all remember-me cookies will be invalidated as the key will be different.