HTTPS is a protocol over which communication between the
browser and the web server is encrypted.
It protects your users from eavesdropping by third parties on the
communication between the user's browser and your server,
which could reveal some sensitive data,
or the communication could be tampered with by injecting undesirable content,
exposing your users to Trojans, viruses,
malicious scripts, or even unwanted ads in fake news,
which could damage the reputation of your brand.
As of July 2108, Google Chrome now labels HTTP sites as not secured.
There now really isn't any reason not to completely
serve your content over HTTPS.
In this module,
you will learn just how easy it is to set up HTTPS with Spring Security.
And I will also show you how to obtain a TLS certificate
signed by a certificate authority for free.
You will also learn how to protect your users from man-in-the-
middle attacks and how to configure HSTS,
HTTPS String Transport Security to enforce the use of HTTPS in your application,
as well as public key pinning.
Now let's clear up some of the terminology here.
TLS stands for transport layer security and is the
official protocol used to encrypt HTTPS.
SSL is secure socket layer.
It's the predecessor of TLS.
However, these names can sometimes be used interchangeably.
For development purposes, we can create a self-signed certificate.
But in production, only use a certificate from a certified authority.
I'll show you how to get one for free in the next section.
The easiest way is to use the Java's Keytool with the following command.
The alias is a unique name/identifier for this certificate.
Then you have the keystore type.
In this case, it will be RSA the size of the keystore,
in this case, is 256-bit, and the password for the keystore,
and the validity of the certificate in days.
Now with Spring Security and Spring Boot,
all we need to do is add the following properties to your
application properties file or YAML file,
the server port 443, which is the default HTTPS port,
the keystore password, the location of the keystore,
the type of the keystore, and the alias of the key store.
If we restart our application, you can see that we can now connect via HTTPS.
Now because this is a self-signed certificate and not
one issued by a certificate authority,
the browser complains and warns the user that they cannot
verify the server is who they say they are.
For now, we will proceed and add the exception.
Again, you wouldn't want your users to do this.
Generally, users omit the protocol when typing the URL into the browser.
Now currently browsers will default to HTTP.
So if we do this for our portfolio site,
we get the error page as the application is no longer
listening on port 80 for HTTP requests.
One way to do this is to send a redirect response to the user
instructing them to redirect to the HTTPS endpoint.
Now Spring Boot will only allow us to configure one
connector via the properties.
And since we already used the one for port 443 using HTTPS,
we need another one for HTTP in port 80,
which will do the redirect to the HTTPS one.
To do this, we need to access the TomcatServletWebServerFactory,
which is used by Spring Boot to configure the embedded Tomcat Server.
We will override the postProcessContext method and add the
securityConstraints of CONFIDENTIAL for all requests,
meaning that we want HTTPS for everything.
We add the connector that will listen on port 80 for HTTP requests
and redirect them to HTTPS on port 443 where our other connector
configured by Spring is listening to.
We then expose this factory as a bean,
so Spring Boot uses it to create the embedded Tomcat Server.
Now I have deployed this site on my AWS EC2 server,
so it is now accessible through the web via the public host link. If we now access this site via HTTP, we get redirected to HTTPS.