Bcrypt is a password-hashing algorithm that is
specifically designed with passwords in mind.
The key feature is that it is designed to be slow,
hence reducing the number of passwords per second an attacker can hash,
which limits the effectiveness of brute force attacks or dictionary attacks.
It does this by using a configurable work factor.
The higher the number, the more work is required to match the password,
hence the slower it is.
Now you should aim for about 1 second as the user
will not really be affected by that.
Now I have created a small app to test the processing time of different
work factors for Spring's implementation of bcrypt.
Now as you can see,
the matching time significantly increases the higher the work factor.
Now this gives you the ability to scale your security
as your hardware improves over time.
Now by default, Spring's bcrypt encoder uses a work factor of 10.
The other constructor field is the SecureRandom object.
Now you can just leave this as is as, by default,
Spring uses the Java's implementation of SecureRandom,
which is used to generate the salt for the hash.
Now bcrypt internally generates the salt,
which protects you against rainbow tables.
And the format of the bcrypt hash is as follows.
It's separated by the dollar sign.
So the first part indicates the algorithm, which here is 2a, which means bcrypt.
The second part is the work factor.
And finally, the last part is the salt and the cipher combined.
Now pass phrases must be between 8 to 56 characters and
are hashed internally to a 448-bit key.
So leave around 60 characters of space in your identity store.
Otherwise, it will be truncated,
and your authentication will fail as you also have to
factor in Spring's prefix for the encoders.
One final point worth mentioning.
Now if we print the hash generated by the bcrypt encoder,
you can see bcrypt's internal salt generation in action.
The password hash is different each time the encoder method is called,
even though the password is the same each time as the random salt
is combined with the password before hashing. Now this protects you against rainbow tables.