We now need a user registration page that accepts the email,
username, password, and other details and persists them in our identity store.
Here we have a regiser.html form.
I'm using Thymeleaf,
which submits to the RegistrationController class
that handles the form submission.
It then calls the user repository to persist the user.
Now this all works fine, but there are some validations missing here.
We need to ensure that all the mandatory fields are populated,
that the password and the confirm password match,
and that the username and email are unique and don't
already exist in the identity store.
Also,
we need to apply some password strength rules so the user can't just
simply submit a 1-character password for example.
Now to do all this validation,
we can use beans declarative validation with JSR303.
Hence, in the UserDto,
we can annotate all the fields that are mandatory with
the NotEmpty or NotNull annotation.
as well,
we can use the Email annotation on the email field to
ensure that that is in the correct format.
Then in the RegistrationController,
we add the Valid annotation around the UserDto object,
and Spring will do the rest for us.
Okay, let's give this a test.
Hmm.
Now it seems we can't access the registration page.
The reason for this is that in our configuration class,
any requests require authentication.
Hence, Spring will redirect back to the login page.
We need to allow the registration page to be accessed
without requiring authentication.
Hence,
you need to let Spring know that the registration page does
not require a user to be authenticated.
To do this,
we can use the antPath request matcher to specify that requests to
/register or login are permitted to be accessed by everyone.
However, the remainder of the application will still require authentication.
So let's restart and test this.
Hmm.
It doesn't look quite right.
It looks like the CSS is not loading here.
Again,
it looks like Spring is blocking everything from
non-authenticated users by default.
That seems to also include the static content to the resources
folder like CSS and scripts that we need to configure so that CSS
and JavaScript is made available to the registration page when the
user is not yet authenticated.
To do this,
we can override the configure method that accepts the WebSecurity
object and use the ignoring method for css and webjars.
Now the reason for webjars is that I am using the webjars library
for my Bootstrap in jQuery in my HTML pages.
Spring Security will now ignore these paths.
Now typically,
you only want to use this for static content and not for any dynamic content.
Now the registration page looks correct,
and our validation messages are being displayed.
Now to ensure that the email and the username are unique,
we can create a custom validator.
To do this, we create a class, UniqueUsername,
and set the return type as the interface annotation to indicate
to Java that this is an annotation class.
Add a Target annotation to indicate that this
annotation is for fields and methods only.
In the constraints,
we specify the validator that will do the validation to validate
elements annotated with the UniqueUsername annotation.
In this case, it will be the class UniqueUsernameValidator,
which implements the constraint validator interface.
You then override the isValid method where you can place the validation logic.
Here we check the repository to see if we can find the existing user
with the username and return either true or false.
Now in our UserDto object,
we can now annotate the username field with this annotation.
That's it.
Spring will now perform the checks when the registration form is
submitted and ensure that the username is unique.
Now we can do the same sort of thing for the email as well.
Next, we need to validate that the password and the confirmed password matches.
Now we can create another validator annotation for this and
annotate the interface in a similar way as the others.
However, in the target, we will have TYPE,
which allows us to place it over the UserDto class.
Now in the implementation of the PasswordConfirmedValidator class,
we specify the property type is the UserDto object.
Hence,
our isValid method will then have access to the UserDto
instance where we can retrieve both the password and
confirmedPassword and then perform the matching.
Okay, now let's give this a test.
You can see the form displaying the appropriate validation errors.
The last important thing that is missing here is password strength.
If we look at the OWASP's website for guidance,
the following recommendations are provided.
The password must, at least, have three of the following four complexity rules,
at least one uppercase character, at least one lowercase character,
at least one digit, and at least one special character.
Also, the password should be at least 10 characters long and,
at most, 128 characters.
Also, there should not be two identical characters consecutive in a row,
example 111.
So let's implement this.
Now rather than reinventing the wheel here and creating a
large number of complex validators, we can use the Passay Java library,
which provides an API to validate password strength,
as well as even generating passwords in accordance
with the strength rules provided.
Now in order to use this library,
we just add the Passay dependency to our POM file.
You can then create a single validator that
contains your password strength rules.
And in this case,
we have called it the PasswordPolicy annotation at the method and field level.
Now in the validator class,
we can use the Passay library to create a list of rules.
The first one is the length rule,
which checks that the password is a minimum of 10
characters and a maximum of 128 characters.
Then to meet the requirements of a minimum of three of the following rules,
we can use the CharacterCharacteristicsRule set to a
minimum of three of the following rules must be met and add
the rules as recommended by OWASP, at least one uppercase character,
one lowercase, one digit, and one special character.
Then finally, we add the maximum of two consecutive identifier characters rules.
We then create an instance of the validator using the rules and
then use the instance to validate their password.
You can then return the output of the isValid method
of the returned result set object.
That's it.
We have now implemented the password strength recommendations by OWASP.
Easy peasy, right?
You'll probably want to provide more meaningful
messages though than I have done here.
Okay,
now that the password is secured and compliant with
OWASP's strength recommendations, there is still one thing bugging me here,
and that is the keystore password for the HTTPS in the
application.yml file being in plain text,
along with the database credentials. Now let's look at options to fix this in the next section.