Avoiding problems,
or an alternative title for this section may be
avoiding problems in the first place.
So we will discuss a variety of topics to better prepare you ahead of time.
Organizational culture verses adaptive planning.
So what does that mean?
As we know, Agile and Scrum are based on adaptive planning.
That's been our norm for a while now.
We are always making little course corrections as needed
with each and every sprint and release.
But do organizations understand this approach?
Does yours?
Many do not or may give lip service.
That is their commitment is expressed in words, but not backed by actions.
Organizational cultures.
They are all different and varied.
What is yours like?
Most do not have any form of adaptive planning.
Agile, Scrum, lean manufacturing,
and all the rest have been around for a very long time,
but not all companies embrace these approaches.
Management wants budget and schedule upfront and early or
they may not even approve your project.
Now, I think this is a good thing.
Management is doing their job by allocating and
managing limited company resources.
Typically, executives want concrete plans,
deliverables, and milestones throughout the project's lifecycle.
So the project manager, technical leader,
or the leader of the self-directed team will still need to
have the necessary business documents, reports,
and statuses for your collective leadership,
that is managers and executives.
So you should not snub your Agile nose at your organization.
I have seen this at times from Agile purists, and that is very disrespectful.
Senior management is running the company.
They have budgets, schedules, milestones, timelines.
Please respect your organization's culture and methods.
You may need to adapt your behavior to match theirs.
Striving to work within your organization's culture might mean presenting
artifacts to the executives while running an Agile project.
This is not an easy endeavor for most Agile and
sprint teams that I have observed.
The team is focused on delivering working software,
not status in upper management.
That is why I like, at times,
to have a project leader on the team to provide the
communication conduit to management,
thus allowing the engineering team to do what they do best,
and that's write great software.
That is why having a solid product vision,
roadmap, and release plans, which are regularly updated,
is essential to show your executives just what you're doing.
Those artifacts tend to be more understandable to executives,
and be sure to include budgets, schedules,
and feature milestones.
Please note every company is different,
so the point of this slide is to make you aware of the potential
circumstances which may affect your Agile projects.
So reflect for a moment where your organization is relative to
the topics and issues we discussed here,
and think about how you might adapt and relate your agile work in a
more effective way to your organization's management. This is important to your success in your Agile and Scrum projects.