As we all know, not everything goes according to plan.
You will not be able to avoid all problems certainly,
but maybe we can do a couple things to minimize a potential dumpster fire,
so we want to discover unexpected problems as early as possible.
So, work on the hardest, most uncertain tasks early in the sprint,
or just do them first.
This will help you find the tough problems sooner,
and you will have more time to fix them and get the help you need.
Share issues with your team ASAP, or at least by the next standup.
This will give an opportunity for the team to solve
collectively any issues or blockers.
Now let's see how we cope with them once we find them.
Here are two options for dealing with unexpected problems.
With small setbacks, absorb them into the sprint by using slack,
or reduce non- critical refactoring,
that technical debt you were going to work on.
Well, put it aside now, and focus on the issue at hand.
Another option is canceling the spike.
Maybe that research can just wait.
Or work an extra hour or two.
If some issues are just too big to absorb in the slack
or any other way and the team agrees, then here are some other options.
It is time to re-plan,
so call a meeting with the full dev team and more than likely
the product owner as well since it may affect the outcome of
the sprint or even the release.
Consider reducing the scope of the story.
This is a good approach since the product owner will at
least get some functionality delivered.
So take that user story, and decompose it into two or three user stories,
and just commit to one of those, not all of those.
Or remove scope.
That is, the user story that is causing the issue,
remove it completely from the sprint.
You can readdress this story in the review or in
the next sprint planning meeting.
This is not unusual, so don't be alarmed.
Again, it may be caused by complex business rules, technical challenges, or even things beyond your control.