Handling a lost sprint.
Sometimes life happens,
and you realize mid-sprint you have nothing to demonstrate to
the product owner for the upcoming demo.
Then the sprint is declared a lost sprint.
Well, what to do?
Roll back the code,
but you can likely just keep the sprint moving forward for the next sprint.
Use your last velocity moving forward,
not the velocity of this spring since it's dead on arrival.
Inform your product owner.
Now, this could be a tough conversation,
so clearly convey your rationale as to why this sprint is lost.
Focus on your sprint review and retrospective on what
happened and how you will move forward,
and also discuss how you can avoid this situation in the future.
Now this should only happen rarely.
If it happens more than you think it should,
then something is wrong, maybe seriously wrong.
Seek out other Agile and sprint experts in your company
or maybe external consulting firms,
and see if they can provide insights and recommendations. Make your process course corrections, and move forward.