Here is the summary of the key points and takeaways of this module.
Estimation.
We learn that solid estimating skills are critical
to the Agile team's productivity, reliability,
and predictability of sprint planning.
Velocity is the amount of work a team can produce in a single sprint.
Knowing your velocity helps you better predict the amount of
work you can commit to in your sprint planning.
Timeboxing is a set length of time that is applied for Agile events,
such as the sprint itself, the daily standup,
and sprint planning to name the most obvious.
Release planning a series of sprints are contained within a release,
and a series of releases are contained in a project.
To develop a release plan, we take as input the product vision,
the product roadmap,
and the product backlog and as output of the releases
with each feature and story identified.
These would be our release goals,
and possibly target dates and budgets are added as well.
In sprint planning sessions, we will refine the backlog,
estimate sprints, prioritize the backlog,
and use our known velocity to make sprint commitments.
Daily work.
This is where the dev team is excelling and producing results,
writing code, testing, and producing usable software.
Daily scrums are an essential element of the dev team's daily activity.
Sharing what they have done since the last standup,
and what they plan to do today,
and discuss any roadblocks or issues is so important.
Based on the complexity of the issues.
Based on the complexity of the issues,
follow-on meetings may be conducted with a subset of the team,
and they go and resolve that.
Sprint demonstrations.
Now is the chance for the team to shine and show the
product owner the results of the sprint.
Here you are demonstrating your workable features to the product
owner and potentially other user representatives.
Reviews.
Don't forget to do your reviews.
The sprint review is focused on improving the process that created the product,
and it is just the development team that usually attends.
Retrospectives are really just a team self-audit,
and you would discuss things like what went well,
what didn't, should we try some new things in the next sprint,
maybe we stop doing something that we were doing.
They tend to be more around people in relationships and
soft skills and those kinds of things.
Okay, as we know, life is not always perfect.
Things can go wrong or maybe just need adjusting.
In the next module,
we will explore several topics to help prepare you for those contingencies. I will see you there.