Here is a great quote: "You adapt, you overcome, you improvise, let's move!
" by Clint Eastwood in the movie Heartbreak Ridge.
There are Agile and Scrum purists.
What I mean by a purist is someone who insists on absolute adherence to rules,
structure, or style.
And that is fine if you would like to apply the Agile
and sprint principles in that way.
But life at the workplace is not so simple.
You have a confluence of people, budgets,
personalities, milestones, management, technology,
process, the lack of process, business drivers,
customers, and more all competing and vying to get things done.
I am suggesting to you for you, yourself,
to be agile, adapt, and overcome, and improvise as necessary.
What I am presenting in this course is the generally known and
accepted practices of agile and sprint planning,
but I am also giving you the okay, the validation,
to make any adaptations to your Agile/Scrum activities that will
improve your product quality and delivery. Let's get started.