"kali linux"
www.kali.org
HTTPS
"kali Linux64bit"
ISO
"ISO"
"Save"
"okay"
"torrents"
"open"
"VirtualBox"
VirtualBox
1/2/3/4/5
...
"new"
"kali"
"Next"
virtualbox
"Create"
VDI VirtualBox
Disk image
"Next"
Dynamically allocated
"Dynamically allocated"
"Next"
"create"
ISO
"Settings"
"Display"
"Storage"
"Empty"
"choose a virtual CD disk file"
ISO
"Home"
kali Linux 1.0.9a-amd64
"kali Linux 1.0.9a-amd64.iso"
".iso"
"OK"
"kali"
"starting"
(amd64)
Live forensic mode
USB Persistence
live USB Encryted Persistence
USB       "Live"
USB, CD
USB
Internet Explorer
Fail-safe mode
Live fail-safe mode
Forensic mode
Live USB Persistance
USB
Live CD
CD
USB
Live USB with persistance
Live USB Encrypted Persistance
Live USB
VirtualBoxGuest
Guest