Hello everybody and welcome to this tutorial.
Today I will continue with the installation of Kali Linux
within a virtual environment.
You might have noticed that I have two screens
on which is  written "Kali Linux"
and they are exactly the same
except one has a bigger font and a zoomed-in picture, so to say.
Over here on left side, this is my virtual machine
the window that I am moving now.
This is the actual virtual machine
and the window on the right side
that is just a zooming in app that I have installed in order for you
to able to better see what I am about to show you here
primarily because I don't have guest additions installed
in the virtual machine
that you cannot install them
until you actually install the operating system first.
Therefore I can't zoom in on anything.
I cannot perform any operations of the kind
and you can see that the font on the left side is rather small
and a bit difficult to see.
Therefore you can...
I will perform the work there on the
left side
and you can monitor what I'm doing on the right.
There is no difference between left and right in terms of actions
only in the in terms of font-size.
Anyway I'm just gonna go ahead and
scroll down to install.
Press "Enter"
That is what want
and the installation procedure is under way.
By the way, if you boot into live version
the default password for root is just root in reverse, so "toor"
Just a bit a brief mention there.
A bit of extra info that I wanted to throw in there
that might come in handy from time to time.
Anyway, pick whatever language is suitable for you.
You can also take the uppermost option
where it says "C No localization"
So if you want a greater degree of
anonymity, or something of a kind
you can even pic that
but for the sake of this tutorial, there really isn't any need
and even if you do pick a language
I mean, a lot of people pick English
so that will not footprint you or anything of a kind.
Just press "Enter"
and here you can actually choose a country, territory, or area.
Well, I don't know, you can choose whatever you want here.
I'm just gonna go ahead and click "UK"
because it immediately offers me a British keyboard that I use.
So that's very nice in terms of settings
but again, you could have chosen "No localization"
and this, you would not be asked any of these things.
Well, for keyboard you probably would
but for the country, area, or anything
of a kind you would not.
In any case, even if you don't pick the
right one here, it doesn't matter.
Later on, after the installation, you can configure it anyway you like
but it's very nice to do it straight away
saves a bit of work later on.
Anyway, the installation is now underway.
I'm just gotta unbind my mouse.
It seems to get stuck in a loop there.
Basically, you bind and unbind your
keys
by simply put pressing the right control key.
That is how you control the mouse
Let's just move this a bit so you can see it better.
There we go.
Anyway, there's some other configuration going on now.
Nothing really noteworthy, so to say.
Let me just change this a bit.
There we go
and you can pick a host name here
unless you have some sort of specific
preferences
and you actually have a registered host name or something of a kind
which you do not want to use here, by the way.
You can just leave it as default.
You can leave Kali
or you can actually write whatever you want your computer to be called.
So I'm just gonna leave the default
but as I said, you can write whatever you wish to write there, no problems
So, let's just go ahead on to continue.
By the way, you don't have a mouse option here
while you're doing this installation.
So tab
Pressing "Tab" switches between fields and options
If you press "Space"
that means you're marking the field and tab means switching fields.
So you use tab, space, and enter to actually call a function
to execute something.
In this case, I'm just gonna say "Continue"
Here, you can type in your domain name.
No I do not want a domain name at this time.
Keep in mind that you can configure this later on as well
should there be a need for it.
Just click on "Continue"
or hit "Enter"
Now, root password
I would suggest picking something ridiculously complex and complicated
and lot of people worry that they won't remember their passwords
if they're long and complicated or
something of a kind
but assign a certain logic to your
password.
Something that reflects the way you think
and then the password can gain in length
and you can still manage to remember it.
So for example, you can insert a certain word that you use
that you use or that you're attached to or something like that.
Something that you like but you don't need to type the word
You don't need to spell the word correctly in the English language.
Rather instead, you can spell incorrectly
and then add, I don't know,  like exclamation marks
question marks
greater than signs, lesser than signs, add signs
and so on and so forth
but figure out something that refelcts your logic
your way of thinking
and make sure that it is above eight characters.
Like, above eight characters is a
must-have.
It needs to contain capital letters.
A few of them, not just one.
You need also a different form of signs
You cannot use just one sign -- that's not a good idea.
You need to use like three or four of them, in the mixture.
The more, the better
and don't just type in word in English language
and then type in numbers
and then type in signs.
So you are already assigning a very strict order
so any brute forcing attack will go much easier
if you do something like that.
Rather instead, try to have a mixture
Try to randomize the position of the types of characters
that you're gonna put in your password.
Give some thought to this.
Don't just type in something at random.
Don't just type in something easy here.
Just give some thought to it for the time being.
For the sake of the tutorial
I'm going to use one of the dumbest passwords possible.
I'm going to type in "Test"
That's gonna be the password of this virtual machine
and then I'm gonna hit the "Continue" button
but it's gonna ask you to verify it
by forcing you to reenter it
and there we go.
It's going
but once again, I emphasize USE A STRONG PASSWORD
Above eight characters
plus with characters and capital letters as well.
So now we have partitioning methods
and if this was my main machine if this
left post machine
if this was my host machine
I would definitely do this manually
I would want my partitions to be configured in a certain way
but since this is a virtual machine
I'm just gonna go ahead and say "Guided - use entire disk"
it doesn't matter to me as there is only one partition anyway
and it's 138 gigs.
It's pretty much better like this
as we don't really have any legit need for  anything of a kind
unless you wanted to set some sort of encryption
or something of a kind.
Press "Enter"
All files in one partition.
Recommended for new users.
Sure, we can do that.
You can separate home partition.
You can separate all the partitions.
For example, this is something that I did on my host machine.
You have a lot of things that are separate
and my main drives are also fully encrypted.
So it would
even if I lost my laptop, or worst -- it got stolen
it would be really difficult to access pretty much anything.
Even the BIOS is locked, so you can't even reinstall it.
You would literally have to open up the laptop
take the BIOS battery out
which is underneath my main
processor
and you're more likely to basically
permanently damage the motherboard
then you are to actually remove and put back that battery
in order to reset the BIOS.
That's one of the very nice fail-safes for devices
especially for compact laptops
but in this case, we don't need any of that
primarily because such configuration and such things
are done on the host machine.
You encrypt your partitions there
you lock the BIOS there, and so on and
so forth.
While on the other hand, with virtual
machines
there is no need to do anything other kind
primarily because the host machines are the fail-safe.
If that fails, everything else will fail.
So you don't need to worry about it.
You don't need to add those unnecessary layers, I would say
primarily because they're gonna slow you down
in the greater scheme of things.
So press "Enter"
Finish partitioning and break changes to disk.
Before I do that, let me just go ahead
and explain the partitioning scheme here.
or partitioning layout here.
So you have primary hash 1
Primary 126.5 gigabytes
space F, space ext4, space slash
Now all these things have a meaning
but what you need to know is that, like in Windows
you have NTFS partitioning.
NTFS partitions.
In Linux, you have "ext4" partitions.
They are a bit faster.
That's one thing that goes in the favor of Linux
and you also, during the partitioning of the disk with a Linux system
there is only one partition which is a
must-have
which is an absolute requirement
and that is this first partition that I have selected.
It's marcation is just "slash"
That is the root partition and you always need to configure it.
Without it, manual partitioning will not work.
You will get error messages saying that you must specify a root partition.
Down below we have "Swap"
Swap is basically a fail-safe method.
So when you run out of RAM memory
you basically tell your system
"Okay, you can have this portion of the hard drive and you can use it as RAM"
which functions in a very slow matter
but it will prevent your machine from crashing.
Usually swap partitions are configured to the double size of your RAM
My RAM is 8 gigabytes, but here by default
the computer has assigned 4
because this is a virtual machine
and if you remember at the beginning
I have assigned two gigabytes of RAM to this virtual machine.
So you just multiply it by two.
It wasn't exactly two.
It was just above two and it has multiplied by two
so I get 4.3 gigabytes of swap space
Now of the modern systems
on most of the modern computers
you will not require swap partitions
even though if you don't make it, you'll get a warning
but rare are the cases when you will need a swap partition
when you will waste all eight gigabytes of RAM, or something of a kind.
I mean, it happens to me from time to time
but usually if it happens there's something wrong with the system.
I don't want it to continue consuming resources.
I want it to stop there
Anyway, now that you know what some of these options here mean
you have marcation for the disk here -- It's "sda"
but we'll get into that later as we configure the system.
So you also have some other options here.
It says "Configure encrypted volumes"
"Configure the Logical Volume Manager"
LVM
"Configure software RAID"
and you can go back to "Guided
partitioning"
So these are all very nice options that come for free
and you I think "Oh, well that's no big deal"
or something of a kind
but believe me when I tell you
these things in proprietary operating systems
they cost a lot of money.
While here, they are free and generally work better.
What we will be interested in today will not be RAID
because we don't actually need it.
You can configure encrypted volumes as well.
I will demonstrate in a later time
encryption methods.
You don't need to encrypt your volumes in a virtual machine
but you can encrypt certain files or folders
if you don't want to grant access to them.
However, my hard drives here on my host machine are encrypted
so I am pretty safe in that regard.
I'm just gonna go ahead now to the bottom, press "Enter"
and finish partitioning and write changes to disk.
Excellent
So now
Oops
Let me just move this a little bit so you
can see it.
Basically it is asking me for a
confirmation.
So if you continue
the changes listed below will be written to discs.
Otherwise you will be able to make further changes manually.
Now it is informing me of the changes to be made
and telling me basically that all the information will be lost
should there be anything there
and you can see that by default, it is set to "no"
so that you don't press enter by mistake
and erase pretty much all the data on your disk
because this installation
this ISO file that you are installing
it does not know that it's being
installed in a virtual machine
on which nothing pretty much exists
and there is nothing to be lost.
So, write changes to disks.
Yes
Go ahead and continue with the procedure.
The installation process is now underway
and this is going to take awhile, I can tell you that much.
So while this is going on, I just wanna go ahead and pause the video here
and finish this tutorial
In the next tutorial, once the installation is complete
I will actually get into Kali, start configuring it
and introduce you to its interface.
In any case, I bid you farewell and I hope to see you all in the next tutorial.