Welcome all to this tutorial. Today, I am
going to go ahead and show you how you can
set up VirtualBox with Fedora 22 and how you
can install the new Kali Sana in it. Before
I begin, I have a few things I would like
to go over with you. First off, I would like
to sincerely apologize for the delay. I have
reinstalled my main system and I have created
Fedora 22 on it. Before installation and upon
installation, I've encountered a few issues
that I needed to resolve. Let me tell you
this way: I started working one day at ten
o'clock in the morning and I ended up working
till six o'clock in the morning the next day.
I didn't even see the time pass by. Don't
be afraid, I didn't have a lot of problems
with VirtualBox. Actually, I did have some
problems with it. That went relatively smoothly.
In comparison to a lot of other things, namely
my sound. It just didn't want to work out.
I first thought it didn't work well with Fedora,
then I thought didn't work well with KDE.
So, I installed the gnome and all the other
thing. I worked with Gnome, then desktop environment,
then I went back to KDE. It was just a painful
experience all around, until I realized the
VLC had problems in Fedora 22. I could play
everything in it. It worked properly but I
couldn't record sounds with it for some strange
reason I don't know. So I decided to go with
another screen recorder and now it's functioning.
Now, I can actually begin recording. This
is actually the morning of that day when I
fell asleep at 6 o'clock in the morning. So,
I started working back at around 10 or 11.
This is the second day pretty much almost
straight in a row. It was kind of a funny
experience. I just wanted to share that with
you before we get started. So, first off,
what you need to do is open up a terminal.
I customized Fedora 22 appearances to my liking.
It's still a bit messed up. Okay, so let's
use this one. Clear it. Anyway, first thing
that you will need to do, is you will need
to become root. In order to do this you must
type in SU, enter and then type in the password.
What was the password again for my computer?
I love reinstalling things late at night and
typing in the password. So that can be an
interesting experience. I guarantee it to
you. Okay, let's try this one. Yes, it's that
password. Lesson learned: do not change your
passwords at 3 o'clock in the morning before
you go to sleep. It's a bad idea in general.
Anyway, let's go ahead and type in CD -clear.
Now, what you need to do is run "dnf update."
Notice that before we used to use "yum," now
we use "dnf." That is literally only difference
relevant to you. Okay, so I have already done
my updates. There is no need to go over the
process. It lasted for a while. Next thing
that I want you to do, although it is not
mandatory. There is a web browser embedded
into KDE, it's called conqueror. You may have
installed the gnome version of Fedora 22,
which is also fine, it's completely relevant.
Use whichever one you want. That's just a
different desktop requirement. That's all
there is to it. As I said, primarily making
this tutorial for all those who have already
installed Fedora 22 and have had problems
with VirtualBox. So, this is the web browser
Conqueror. You can use it, but I like to use
Firefox. So, I'll type in "dnf install firefox."
Okay, it says nothing to do, task complete.
I already conducted the installation of Firefox.
Now, I'm going to go out and started, and
here we go. So, we are we are connected to
the Internet, but let's go ahead and verify
that, just to be on the safe side. I type
"ping google.com." The fact that your default
website, or your homepage opens up the browser
is not a proof that you are connected to the
net. Those things can be cached. So, just
use the use the ping command to get a reply.
Once you get a reply, you know that you are
connected because the packets are traveling
to God knows where, then they're coming back
to you. Okay, so let's go ahead and first
set up our RPM fusion. Just type in "RPM fusion."
Go ahead and go over to their website, the
first one that pops up, rpmfusion.org. On
the main site, you literally have it here.
It says "enable RPM fusion on your system."
Then you see, "RPM fusion free for Fedora
22." Just go ahead and click on it, save file.
Okay to download. Then click "RPM fusion non-free
for Fedora 22." Click on it, save file. Okay
to download. I won't do this because I've
already downloaded them. They will be in your
downloads folder. So, "cd /home/chronic/Downloads."
I have them here. Ihave downloaded Kali Linux
as well. So, you have to go through the download
process here. All you need to do here really
is type in "rpm -i rpmfusion." Use tab for
this, don't type in the whole thing. It says
it's already installed-- great! Again type,
"rpm -i rpmfusion nonfree" to install the
other one, which is nonfree. Okay, so it's
already installed, no problems. Let's go ahead
and clear the screen. Type in "dnf update"
again. I've done it so no worries there. Once
you complete all these updates and with the
setting up of the RPM Fusion, I would recommend,
at this point of time, to reboot your machine
and come back to this just in case. So here's
my kernel output at the time. Type "uname
-r." It's 414 200. fc22. It
doesn't matter if yours is different, this
procedure should be universal. It should work
across the board without any problems. Then
again, just perform the updates. That's it.
So next up, we need to go ahead and actually
install VirtualBox. I've already installed
it, but let's just go ahead. I haven't fixed
the issues that I was, and that you are facing.
We're going to go ahead and do together. First
off, type in "dnf search virtualbox." You
can see-- oh wait. I do have the kernel modules
for my kernel. It doesn't really matter if
you don't for yours. I will show you a way
in which to do it. So, you need to go ahead
and find this package, VirtualBox.x86_64.
Type in, "dnf install virtualbox." Okay, so
this is going to install for you with no problems.
I already have it here. I just don't want
to go through the installation again. There's
truly nothing to do there, just press "y"
at a certain point of time. That's all. Next
up, we are going to go ahead and start VirtualBox
and begin to solve the problem that you have
been facing. So, type, "virtualbox." Okay,
so I've already made one Kali machine so I'm
going to go ahead and remove. Delete all files.
Click on new. Type in the name of your machine,
I just type in "Kali Sana." Choose Linux.
The then I'm going to type in, Debian 64-bit.
Okay, so let's go. Next, I'm going ahead and
giving it 1.2 gigs of RAM, but you can give
less if you want. I don't think you should
go below 800. It's up to you really. See what
works best for you. Let's go, Next, create,
next, next. Here, I've noticed that a lot
of people have been making an error by assigning
too little disk space. Some people
give it 6 MB or 30 MB or something like that.
There is no way that is ever going to work.
So you need to give it at least 30 GB for
daily use, so it's go ahead and give it 30
GB. You can get away with less. I mean, you
are going to have some files that are stored
there in addition to the instillation, and
you will want to do some things. So, I do
believe that 30 GB is one of the optimal amounts.
Sometimes I like to give like 128 GB, just
in case. That's just because I have a lot
of space to waste. If you're if you're in
a tight budget in terms of disk space you
can give a 30 gigs and you should be fine
working with no problems or anything of the
kind. So, let's go ahead and click on create.
That's it. We have now created a Kali machine.
What we need to do now, is go ahead and download
the Kali Sana from the net. So let's go ahead
and open up a web browser once again. Type
in "Kali." That's all you need to do. Open
up the first website that comes along. It's
www.Kali.org. Go into downloads, download
Kali Linux. There it is: Kali Linux 64-bit
iso Version 2.0. I would advise you to go
and get the torrent version because I've noticed
a lot of people have had corrupt .iso files
due to slow connections and the breaking of
connection. So just go ahead and download
the torrent. It's a safer way to go about
things. Anyway, just go ahead and click on
it and the download will begin automatically.
There is nothing else that you need to do
there. Once the download is complete, it's
about 10 minutes to downloaded, I already
downloaded it as you can see, go ahead right-click
on this. Go into settings, go into the storage
controller IDE. Click on the empty one. Click
on the blue disk image here. Choose a virtual
CD DVD, navigate over to your downloads folder.
Is this the
right one? Hold on. There it is. This is the
iso file that I need, that I want to see.
It is right there, .iso. Go ahead and click
on okay. so I this is a normal set up that
we've done before. Nothing really strange
you about. Just go ahead and double-click
on the machine. You're going to get this error
message. So, failed to open a session of the
virtual machine Kali Sana. Then, you're gonna
get this error from VirtualBox as well: VirtualBox
Linux kernel driver, blah, blah, blah, was
probably not loaded. and I'm sure that all
of you have seen this message a lot of times
and this was problematic for a lot of you.
You couldn't go pass this. I try to help out
people by manually installing the kernel drivers.
Really, what we could do, because I didn't
have Fedora 22, and I didn't really see this,
I didn't know you can actually do this as
well. You can just basically follow through
what the but the suggested solution from the
VirtualBox is. That should in itself solve
the problem. Basically, it's instructing you
how to install the mods for the for the system
that you're running this on. So, let's go
and expand this. We need to type this in part
that is marked with blue letters. You can
literally just copy and paste it. Just an
error on my part, you should not copy the
quotation marks. So just, "ctrl v" then "ctrl,
shift v." Since you are using the Fedora 22,
just replace yum with the dnf. If you type
in yum it's automatically redirected you to
dnf, so no worries there. Either way this
should work. If this doesn't work, you always
have the one below. This is the one that I
actually used, so I'm gonna go ahead and go
with it. This one Below is a more general
way of doing things. I don't know why I grabbed
the first one, but this is what we have been
doing before. This is what we have been attempting
to do before, but you know you couldn't find
the proper versions the system couldn't find
the proper versions and it was a pretty big
problem. So instead, we are going to go ahead
and use this one, which is going to help you
install the proper ones or a meta-package,
so to say, which one-size-fits-all. Let's
go ahead and press enter. Okay, so this is
done. Now we are going to copy this one below.
So you see, there is nothing extremely technical
about this. I mean you just basically copy/pasting
things. The system tells you what you need
to do. Okay, so now that is done. Go ahead
and click on abort, and I'm going click here
on "Okay. I'll close the VirtualBox. Then,
start the VirtualBox up again and then double-click
on Kali Sana. As you can see it is booting.
So, I am here in the boot menu and I am free
to choose what ever I wish from the options.
In the following tutorial, I'm just going
go briefly through the installation process
of Kali Sana. That will be it. I hope that
the solution provided here does work for you.
As you can see, this is a fresh install of
Fedora 22. I have updated it. I have imported
the RPM fusion repositories and then I installed
VirtualBox from the RPM repositories and followed
the suggested solution to what the error was.
As you can see, it is working without any
problems whatsoever. In the next tutorial,
I also promise to show you how to install
and run Kali Sana. I mean, it's not a terribly
difficult thing to do. It's pretty straightforward.
So, we will go through that as well. Until
then, I bid you all farewell.