Hello everybody and welcome to this follow-up tutorial.
Today I will show you how to actually install tor itself.
We'll go through the installation procedure
and in order for us to do that, we will need to use the new user that we have created -- test
That's the user name off the new user.
Anyway, in order for you to do that, you need to log out
and in order for you to log out of Kali Linux
just go ahead and click in the upper right corner, where it says root.
Go scroll down to "switch user"
and yep, there we go.
The screen is going to resize a bit, perhaps.
Excellent
So it says here "test"
I'm already logged in a test because I have done this previously
but it's gonna prompt me for a password as well
but the user test is running in the background
So just go ahead and type in the password for it
Press ENTER
Very simple
You will follow exactly the same procedure.
There is nothing different that I'm doing
that perhaps you need to change or alter or anything of a kind.
There is a browser icon in the upper left corner.
It's blue
It's the iceweasel browser.
Go ahead and press on it.
Use your favorite search engine, type in tor, press Enter
and go ahead and open the first site that pops up.
It's Tor Project: Anonymity Online
Absolutely make sure that you are downloading this browser from a proper site.
From the official sources.
So it says HTTPS
Make sure there is an S marcation at the end
that's not HTTP, rather HTTPS
and make sure that the domain is correct.
So https://wwwtorproject.org/
It's not dot com, it's not dot some country extension, it's not dot anything else
it's dot org
Anyway, go ahead and click straight away on "download tor"
and I need a 64 tor browser GNU/Linux
That is what I want to download
but in case you're using some other operating system
over here you have Microsoft Windows, Apple OS X
We are currently going to go ahead and use the Linux/UNIX version
and there are some additions in all downloads section as well.
Feel free to check that out.
Perhaps go ahead about the site and see what you can find
There are some interesting things here
Forums, FAQ, and some other things as well.
I would strongly advise you to actually just browse around the site a bit.
For the time being, I'm just gonna go ahead and on Download.
Yes, I wish save file.
Okay, the download will proceed
and it only takes about a minute.
The downloads are a very short amount of time
that I will use to actually tell you what tor is.
Now basically what you do with tor is simply route your traffic to go through certain points
and every time it hops, there is an encryption layer
It make your connection very secure
and there are these things that are called the internodes.
Nodes are basically computers or servers through which you go
so you make a request to a certain website
and then your connection goes from your computer to some other computer
and then from that computer to some other, and so on and so forth
until it reaches the exit node.
All of these devices are a part of the tor network
and once it reaches the exit node
it is the exit know that actually makes the request towards the site that you wanted.
Basically you are using a lot of proxies.
That would be the very basic explanation, but there is a lot more to it.
The encryption being the major part of it.
So there are multiple layers of encryption there, and it's not that that easy to figure out
or should I say it is rather impossible to figure out where the connection is coming from
if you are a system administrator
unless you are controlling these nodes or something like that
which is highly unlikely.
Basically this is a fantastic way of staying anonymous
but you do not need to necessarily use tor as a tor browser
just to go and access the hidden web.
Rather instead, you can use tor to actually torify...
That is the term, I am not making an error here
That is the term to torify your applications
and once you have torified them
all traffic generated by those applications will be routed through the tor network
and you will be anonymous to a very large extent.
Although keep in mind that all things using tor are very slow
primarily because your connection is being routed through a lot of devices
and there are a lot of people out there that are using those devices.
Anybody can contribute, really.
You can see a bit more on the website, and so on and so forth
if you have any interest in such things
but for the time being, I'm just gonna go ahead and skip that .
Rather instead ,I want to start using tor and show you the dark web.
So just go ahead and click on your download.
Just give it a moment of time.
It says "Reading archive. Please wait"
Excellent
I want to extracted it to test desktop.
So go ahead and proceed.
Let's see if it's gonna succeed.
Extracting files from archive
Don't cancel it, just quit it.
Excellent
So just go ahead and open up this folder.
In the browser folder section, you have a lot of these things
if you want to check them out
but for the time being, what you need is "Start tor browser"
These are just the files that the tor browser uses, so no worries there.
Anyway just go ahead and click on "Start tor browser", run
and this process may take awhile.
It's shorter for me, but it might take a bit longer for you.
I don't know, it just depends I suppose on many things.
Don't worry about it.
It's gonna take up to minute, maximum, to connect to the tor network.
Anyway, just go ahead and expand it.
Now you might ask yourselves "Well, what is so special about the tor browser?"
It's like a regular browser.
Maybe it loads a different website as the default, but that's it.
Nothing really special there.
However, it gives you the ability to actually access the .onion domains
and here's how we do that --
The first thing that I'm going to do is type in "hiddenwiki"
It's one of those websites where you have a link to a large amount of other .onion domains
to those of significance anyway
and its URL changes continuously.
That is why I am actually searching for in the video, as opposed to just pre-loading it
primarily to show you how you can find
It not really that difficult
you can just type it in to the search engine and it's fairly simple.
There are no difficulties
So just go ahead and open up a couple of these websites.
You will get one of them to work for sure
So these are .onion domains.
A list of them
Quite a large list, but I'm not actually interested in those.
So the hidden wiki has been hacked.
This is the new URL
Don't worry about this, this happens like all the time.
So it's just one of those things that you have to learn to live with.
I know it's a bit inconvenient to have to search URL all the time
but if you want to the dark web
things are not as stable as they are on the on the regular web
so that can be problematic to the point of extreme
So it says "Welcome to The Hidden Wiki"
"New hidden wiki url 2015. Add it to bookmarks and spread it!!"
Excellent
So this is where we want to be.
Let me just explain where we are
This is a rather large list of links for .onion domains, as I said
and you have a lot of things here.
Some of them are illegal and we will not go into those.
Basically where you have people who are selling PayPal accounts, credit card accounts
credit card numbers, and so on and so forth.
Those are really not the places where we should go.
Perhaps if you want to check out if your PayPal has been hacked or something like that.
If it has, you can go onto those websites and search for it
to see if it's actually there
and other than that, I really see no other reason why you should visit them.
Okay, so we have some editor's picks
If you want to volunteer or something like that
Introduction points
We don't really need any of those things.
Financial services
So you have a ton load of things here.
A lot of things concern the anonymity of payment online.
So Bitcoin or you can buy prepaid cards
or something like that.
If you buy prepaid card, I suppose it's okay
because, you know, you can get a prepaid card at Walmart or something like that.
They give them out practically
They're gift cards, or something like that, that you can use for online payments
so you are completely anonymous with those
but never ever buy a genuine credit card because that's illegal.
There are no cases where it is legal
I thought it might be when the person actually owns it, but no, not really.
Anyway, down below, you have commercial services where you can find all sorts of cheap things
I  wouldn't really recommend buying anything from here
to be shipped to your address
primarily because you have no guarantee whatsoever that that is what you  have ordered
or that you'll get the genuine stuff.
Here we have Anonymity & Security
There are some things concerning good proxies, concerning the tor.
You might wanna check these four out.
So that's not a bad idea there.
These are all external resources that I'm showing you now that you can use on the hidden web.
That is the primary purpose of why I am showing you how to access to hidden web.
So you can use a large amount of these external resources during your pen testing exercises.
There are lots of useful things here
and I definitely encourage you to go over some of them
and see if you can find something of use to you.
What we are today mainly interested in are the forums.
So you have Forums/Boards/Chans and so on and so forth
and there are a lot of things here, so let's just open some of them.
Keep in mind that they tend to be down, that the URLs tend to change
and it can be problematic.
So let's just try BlackBook
Maybe something's gonna be there.
HackForum
Yep, you see there is a problem loading this page.
This is not gonna open
This one might
The Secret Story Archive
No I don't need that
Deep Web Radio
Hack the Planet -- Let's see what they got there.
The Intel Exchange
Excellent
Intel Exchange -- I think this is one of the better ones.
So you can just go ahead and go through these pages
and see if you can find anything of use.
We are in IntelExchange
This is most likely not gonna open.
Excellent
So this is one of those forums where you will need to register
but I mean, nobody's asking for your credit card information.
Just fill in the basic information, like your user names, passwords
how you wish to be addressed, and so on and so forth
and then you then you have a lot of things here which can come in handy.
So you have general discussions.
We don't really want that.
This is what we were looking for -- Software
So hacking, programming, tor, and everything else about software
Let's see what's there.
By the way, whatever code you download from these websites
either run it within virtual environments or do not run it at all.
I'm just gonna go ahead and say that.
Do not run it on your regular machines or on anybody's regular machines
because that's never a good idea.
So what do we got here?
"Best Programming Language for Making an OS"
Well God, we don't really need that. That can be rather complicated
Down below --  "Is it safe to download pdfs on tor?"
You shouldn't do that. You shouldn't download anything on Tor that you will use on your regular machines.
We have some pretty stupid things here which we will never get to use
but there are some very nice things.
We have IP address questions
so what can we do with an IP address, and so on and so forth.
I can't open any of these because I am not registered
but I have been in these forums and they can be quite useful
I don't think I've been on this one in particular, but I have been on forums in the dark net
and you can find some interesting things that people have done.
Some interesting methods.
Usually things tend to come out here first and then they hit the general public
or the regular web, which ever way you want to see it
and there we go.
We have keyloggers here.
So you can find some information on keyloggers
how to use them, where to find them
but I would suggest reading the reviews mainly here and the suggestions
and then figuring out where would you download it.
Seeing if a keylogger is open source or close source.
If it's open source, perhaps you can go to their website and downloaded from there
and be safe in that manner.
So that's not a bad idea
and you have a ton load of other things you see --
Hacking tools, SQL Injection, Operating Systems for hacking, and so on and so forth.
You have a ton load of information here, which I would strongly recommend that you use
that you just go over it, see what people are doing there.
Do not do anything illegal.
Just go ahead and visit the forums
and see what sort of information can you extract from it, that's all.
In any case, I will conclude the tutorial here.
I hope you find the dark web to be a useful asset in your pen testing career
or your pen testing activities in general.
Believe me, it is
You can find a lot of useful things, as I keep restating
and the connections can be rather slow
and it is safe to install a tor browser on your regular machines
as long as you download it from the official site, which is torproject.org
but under the protocol of HTTPS, and not HTTP
In any case, I bid you farewell and I hope to see you in the next tutorial.