Ok, so let's go ahead and continue
If you're just tuning in we've changed the DNS servers and I strongly advise you to
view these tutorials in the order in which they were posted
But the change of the DNS servers was necessary in order to hide the DNS servers
from out ISP provider
Anyway, let's go ahead and open up our browser
I already have mine open here and one of the first things we're going
to need to do is to disable WebRTC, I have it written down in the upper right corner
if you can't see it, it's perfectly fine
because now I'm gonna go ahead and type in "about:config" and then it's gonna say
"This might void your warranty!"
notice that I'm using Iceweasel which it's basically Firefox,
for Chrome it's a little bit of a different procedure, if you're using that
let me know, I can help you out there, in any case WebRTC
it can leak your data, it's one of the new things that have embedded into Firefox
and Chrome, but in Firefox they made it relatively easy to disable, I mean, it's not a big deal
you just have to go into about:config and you're gonna get this warning, and this warning
is here for a reason, this is not here because somebody decided that they should just
put a warning without a purpose or anything like that
this is here for reason, if you go about messing with these things, be sure that you know
what it is that you are doing, otherwise, leave them as they are because you can brake your browser
to the point where it's not longer going to work or it's gonna severely jeopardise your safety
the safety of the software, integrity of your browser, etc.
So I'll be careful, I promise just go ahead and click on it, and in the search bar you need to search
the same pattern that I am searching now, here, let me zoom at it as much as I can
it says, media.peerconnection.enabled
Ok, so here, boolean is set to false, you can just double click to change it to true
but don't, only if this is true, double click and change it to false and that is all you really need to do,
no big deal there,
so just go ahead and close, it just needs to be false, that's all it needs to be
so just go ahead and close the browser after that and reopen it
type into your favourite search engine, or which one you're using
I'm just using the default one here
Open VPN free, just type that in
and I have a site that I've used before
Yep, there we go, so, we're gonna... it's VPNBook
We're gonna go ahead and use one of these, so I'm gonna go ahead and use the German one
but you can use the Canadian one, US one, I don't know where this one is located but I'm sure we could
figure it out but it doesn't really matter, I'm gonna use a German one, you can use whichever you want
Feel free, so I'm just gonna download it, it's gonna be in download folder, there we go
Here is the username, I'm gonna remember that, it's VPNBook, and I'm gonna go ahead and copy the password
because now I need to close the browser, so in order to start the VPN we need to close the browser, we
cannot have the browser open while the VPN is running, while we are setting up the VPN, sorry, my bad there
So we need to set the VPN up, start it, let it run and then open up the browser, so the browser cannot be open before
that, it needs to be closed, completely, all your tabs, the entire browser needs to be closed, it cannot be active
set the VPN up and only then start your browser, then it will work, otherwise it won't
It shouldn't anyway, so, let's go ahead and type it in
and let's go to Downloads/
"ls"
and this file is zipped, so just go ahead and unzip it,
unzip VPNBook.com
and there we go, do "ls" again, you will see that you have a good number of these
let's just clear the screen to make it a little bit clearer
"ll" is not installed here, but it doesn't really matter
and I'm going to use a TCP 443 Open VPN
What do I type in? I just type in "openvpn" space and then just go ahead and type this in
"tcp443.ovpn" start it up, type in the username, the username is VPNBook
the password is the one that I've copied from the net
Press Enter
And just let it run, I only advise you to let it run for like a minute
for everything to be setup and initialized
and functional and so on and so forth, it says here "Initialization Sequence Completed"
that is what we were looking for and waiting for and now let's go ahead and start up our browser
and let's go ahead and type in "What is my IP?"
Ok, so it says that my public IP is this one here, and let's see where will that IP put me
Wait, this is not a good one, let's go to DNS leak test
It's putting me in Germany, that's where I'm located at the moment... not at the moment
That is where this IP is located at the moment
That is the location for this IP address and this is the one that is shielding my real one
To just give you and idea of what I mean by it, I can go ahead and open up the terminal
stop this process with Control + C and let's see if this will work if I reload the site
I don't think it's gonna actually work I think I should need to reset the browser
and yes, I need to reset the browser, but you saw that my IP was in Germany
and let's do it again, DNS leak test, and here we go
There you go, it says... now it's giving my real IP address
A lot of people are covered up on youtube... on the net
I personally think it's a completely pointless thing to do because these are dynamic IP addresses provided to us by our ISP providers
and this is gonna change about twenty times by the time I actually publish these videos,
I can actually change it myself, If I just reset the router basically
plug it in, plug it out, that's the quickest way to do it, or you can actually log into your router and
release the DHTP and then acquire a new one but it doesn't really matter, you see the idea
I mean I had German one and when I covered myself up and now I have this one
Okay, so let's close it
Let'st fire apart VPN again
There we go, it's starting, wait for it, don't just go and click and open up your browser immediately
Wait for this "Initialization Sequence Completed" and then open up your browser
and make sure as I said before that there are no other browsers that are open at all
No big deal, let's start it up
"DNS leak test", ok, click on it
Again I am in Germany, so do the standard test.
And now it says the ISP is Open DNS because I am using Open DNS DNS servers
I know it sounds a little bit confusing because of their name but basically I am using
the DNS servers of this company
The DNS servers that belong to this company.
What is important here? I know that I stated before you can just choose a DNS that is different
from your own country, yes, that is true, definitely useful, but also
keep in mind that the primary thing that you are hiding from... that you are trying to hide is
your ISP DNS server, that is the one that you're trying to conceal
so as long as your real ISP DNS server is not listed here and preferably but not mandatory
that this is not the country where you are actually located, you are good to go
if your ISP server shows here, the DNS server, your real ISP DNS server then
you have misconfigured something you are not completely anonymous
also if this is your country of origin, I'm not talking about the United States, it doesn't matter which one is listed here
I'm just saying that If here, it says a country, and this could be Czech Republic or Canada, it can be
The United States as you see here, it doesn't really matter, but as long as...
If that is your country of origin, it's not that bad, somebody could perhaps see that you're coming from that particularly country and
that might be your real country where you're located, but do you know? these are public DNS servers
if you pick a good one they won't keep log files and you're pretty much good to go because they won't have record
they won't have anything showed, also as I said you could pick a DNS server which is not in your own country
Here it's the United States because Open DNS is in the United States but doesn't matter as I said, it could be any country here
and let's say you're a citizen of Norway, and you have a Norwegian DNS server listed here and you're using that one
Well, you could try using a DNS server which is in South African Republic and it's gonna say here South African Republic
and you're gonna have a very different ISP here but as I said just make sure that they are reputable
now I hope that I have helped you out, that I've shown you can set up a free VPN service, completely free of charge
You don't have to pay for anything extra and how can this actually work out
If you're using Virtual Box you can also go and. Let's go ahead and stop this
You can go under devices and network settings, and change from bridge adapter to NAT
because sometimes bridge adapter doesn't work for anybody due to the drivers and OK
and now you can reset the network manager
"service network-manager restart"
Let's see if I can ping google.com
Ok, NAT is working, and let's see If I can connect to the Open VPN
let it go through
Ok, "Initialization Sequence Completed" so it does work, but you see, I have my browser open
so this is a bad, bad, bad idea, this is something you should not do, close the browser and redo this process
Once you have redone it, open up your browser again
I mean it's not like it's gonna reveal if you're using a browser straight away but the changes may not be applied to your browser
that's the problem, so "DNS leak test"
Again, it's working in NAT just fine but let's see if the DNS is going to pass
Yep, it will, so NAT is also working just fine, you can use both NAT and bridge, if one doesn't work try the other
this is just for people who are using virtual machines, you can switch between NAT and bridge for virtual machines
For everybody else if you're not using a virtual machine, if you're using a real installation or if you're using a USB, forget about NAT and bridge
this is all you can and need to do
Anyway I bid you all farewell and I hope that this was helpful who have struggles with VPN and Kali 2.0