Hello and welcome to this tutorial
Today I will begin a chapter on wireless hacking.
So first off, you need to know that there are different types of encryption.
There is WEP
and whoever is still using WEP doesn't really deserved to have a wireless
primarily because it's practically as if you had a free password or an open wifi.
It doesn't really matter.
It's quite easy to crack, no problems.
However, if you're using WPA or WPA2, that is another story.
That's quite difficult to crack, especially if the passwords are longer or something of a kind.
There are different methods for direct wireless hacking
and I really would not recommend it in all circumstances.
There are some circumstances which are favorable to these sort of methods.
However, what is always better is to actually get an IP of the router
and then attack the router itself
because usually it has far more vulnerabilities than the WPA2 encryption that you are trying to crack.
However, since we are cracking wireless, I'm just gonna go ahead and type in "ifconfig" here
and you will notice that I don't have a wireless interface here.
Why is that?
Well even though I have a network integrated card, a wireless one, within  my laptop
this is a virtual machine, and virtual machines do not support integrated network cards.
They can only go through your host machine
and in such a way
virtual machines are secure, so you can install all sorts of stuff on them
viruses, etc
and you'll still be safe.
They won't be infecting you and they won't be able to disrupt the normal functioning of your host machine.
However there are methods where you can get a USB wireless card and plug it in
and you can set up a pass through for your wireless machine
and in such a way, gain access to wireless.
However, password cracking from a virtual machine is not a good idea.
I mean it's a terrible idea, especially using VirtualBox
Maybe if you are using send or something of a kind
where you have 90 - 95 native performance,  that would be great
but using VirtualBox for password cracking is a really bad idea, primarily because...
Let me just show you here --
If you go to devices
and I can click on network settings
and then I will get the menu for the other things.
So let's just go ahead and click on General
Systems...sorry
Look -- First of all, it has base memory.
This can be altered when the machine is off.
You cannot change the settings here, while the machine is turned on.
First of all, it says that I have two gigs of ram available for this particular virtual machine.
Now that's great for day-to-day operations
especially for Linux that requires 512 megabytes to run.
However, you want to brute force a password
if you want to take that path
if you want to use a brute force method just by generating huge password lists and trying to guess it
this is not really a good amount of ram.
Actually, this is a terrible amount of RAM for such a task
and if we go ahead and click on the processor
you will see that execution cap is 100%, but we only have a single core assigned.
It says here one CPU core in the upper status bar
It says processors
It's gray at the moment, because you can't change the amount of processesors that are machines is using
while it's running.
So that makes no sense whatsoever.
You wouldn't be able to do that in the real world either.
Maybe of some large servers or something like that
but even there, very doubtful that you can actually swap a processor.
That's mainly for swapping disks or adding RAM or something of a kind.
In any case, it has only one CPU assigned to it.
I know it says here four, but I have an Intel i7 inside
and the VirtualBox supports only four CPU of cores for its machines
and you should take into consideration that you really won't need more than four for your virtual machines
especially if you're performing some testing tasks
or I don't know, even if you're programming
unless you're doing something specific that is strongly related to graphics
you won't be needing that many cores or anything of a kind.
One CPU is perfect.
That's fine, you won't need anymore.
So anyway, I'm just gonna go ahead and click "Okay" here
and I just wanted to show you that, in order to demonstrate that the resources of your virtual machine
are simply not sufficient in order to support a brute force method
As I said, you can actually buy for about 20 bucks somewhere in the store
a USB network card, a wireless one.
Plug it in, pass through the ports, and it's gonna work
but it's gonna be terribly slow.
What you need to do is either set up a dual-boot
or if you are running a Linux machine as your host machine,
you can do what I will do now.
Excellent
So because my main machine is Fedora Linux, I have installed all the necessary tools on it
pretty much you can install the same tools on Fedora as you can on Kali
and I will be doing my pen testing from here, from Fedora.
I will exit the virtual machine.
I will no longer use Kali for this purpose.
However, if you are a Windows user
if you don't have a native Linux system as your host machine
you will also be able to do this in Windows
I will show you the installation process alone
I will not show the actual method, but principles are the same
primarily because when you do it in Windows, you have to use the GUI mode
and quite frankly for these sort of things, I personally do not like to do them via GUI
it's far more effective to do it in from the terminal to some of
So some of the tools that we will need
I will just mentioned them here
and feel free to read up on them a little bit in the net, as you progress through the course
and then go through the videos as well.
So there's a lot of extra information out there on the net
especially if you're facing some sort of bug or something of a kind.
Also, feel free to post it in the question section if something is not working.
I will be more than happy to try to fix it for you.
So just type in "yum search aircrack -ng"
Press ENTER
and it should find it shortly.
There we go
aircrack is in the default repositories of Fedora
and you'll be able to find it there without any sort of problems.
So it says "aircrack -ng . x86_64"
This is a standard for wireless
and it says "sniffer and WEP/WPA-PSK key cracker"
We're interested in this part -- "key cracker"
Basically, you can install it anywhere.
You can even install it in a virtual machine, capture the file in the host machine, transfer the file there
but there really is no point to do that.
Now we will install it and I will teach you how to use it.
There are lots more things related to aircrack
but there is one more tool that we will use that employs a completely different method
use a completely different way of tracking wireless passwords
and we'll mainly be talking about WPA and WPA2 password encryption methods.
I will do a brief demonstration of how to crack the WEP
but I mean, chances of you encountering WEP in today's world
are practically non-existent.
Just open up your cell phone...
I don't know if you're using Android or Apple phones or Windows phones
and whatever else is out there
just take a look at the wireless networks around you
and take a look at the encryption methods, because they will be shown to you
you will almost never see WEP
If you ever do see it, it's practically open wifi.
Because WEP has been cracked, it takes a very short amount of time to break it
without any sort of problems.
You don't need to use any sophisticated methods of any kind or sort.
A child could crack it without any problems.
Basically just follow through the procedure and that's it.
Now as I was saying, there was another method of doing this for EPA
and the tool name is "reaver"
Now, reaver is not in Fedora's default repository
so we will need to go through the installation process and find it on the net
but basically what reaver does is guesses the pins on your router.
So most routers these days have pin authentication
whereby you press a button and everybody around you can connect to that router, basically.
These things have been invented primarily for Windows users.
Very rarely will you find a Linux with support for pins
primarily because the method is highly insecure.
I mean, that is really one of the downsides of wireless.
If you're using pin authentication, you should definitely disable it on your home routers
as it enables malicious attackers to take your wifi, get your IP address
then from there, move on to more serious things.
I will show you how to disable these things as well
on one of my routers that I have here.
I think I have a dp link or something like that.
I will plug it in later on and show you what it does
but in any case, as a part of the aircrack package
you will get a few other programs, which we will use
and later on, there is one program in aircraft package
that enables you to perform a DoS attack  on wireless networks around you.
So you will be able to pretty much deauthenticate whoever you want, whenever you want
as long as two conditions are met --
The first condition is proximity, that you are close enough to the network
and the second condition is that you actually have to scan in monitor mode with your network card
and figure out what is going on around you.
What is the MAC address of that access point and what is the MAC address of the person you want to jam?
This is not that difficult to do.
This is easy
Both MAC addresses are public information.
Pretty much all you need to do is listen for them, and that is what monitor mode is.
Basically, network cards have a lot of modes that they can operate in.
Well, maybe not a lot. I think it was six or something like that.
but there are only two which are of interest to us --
There is the promiscuous mode, where your network card will only process traffic
that is meant exclusively for it, regardless of
I don't know, capturing some of their traffic that is being transmitted wirelessly through the air.
I mean, just think about it --
You have so many wireless access points around you and they are all communicating with devices
and it's not like that wireless access point can send a signal in a specific direction to your device.
No, it sends it in a ciracle fashion and your device catches it.
A lot of other devices catch it, but sine the information is encrypted
and since the information is not for them, they immediately figure out it's not for them
namely your network cards figure it out, and they immediately disregard the information.
They don't do anything with it.
However, if you put your network cards into monitor mode
they will actually take all of this traffic, process it, and see what they can get from it.
Some of it is encrypted
Most of it is encrypted
but some of it isn't
like the MAC addresses, which can be encrypted
and that's the bright side of it all.
You can take it and you can jam whoever you want.
You can deny wireless access to pretty much everybody within range, with just having your laptop
and no extra devices are needed.
This is all pure software.
You don't need any extra devices.
Of course, it is necessary that your network card supports monitor mode.
There is a compatibility list on the net.
I will show it to you in the follow-up tutorial
but for the time being, I just wanted to introduce you to the chapter
and to see what we shall be doing.
Now I would advise
you don't have to, of course
and you will be able to fully follow through the next tutorial without doing this
but I would just advise typing aircrack -ng on Google, or whatever your favorite search engine is
and type in "reaver"
Just read the first couple of sentences of the first post that comes by
and see if you can collect some information there.
Then you can continue on watching the next video
where I will show you how to install these things.
I will show you how to install aircrack -ng on Windows, and I will attempt reaver as well
but sometimes reaver tends to break on Windows, and that can be problematic
but primarily, I will show you how to install aircrack -ng
I will show you how to use it there in a bit.
It's not that hard.
There's a graphical interface, practically.
You can just click through it, no problems.
However, I restate once again that you should have a Linux host machine
which you can use, to which you have access
primarily because a lot of these tools are a lot faster on Linux machines.
They work much better, they are faster
and quite frankly, they are easier to install.
Plus, you get a higher degree of anonymity.
Anyway, I bid you all farewell and I'll see you in follow-up tutorial.