Hello everybody and welcome to this tutorial.
Today I will show you how you can actually crack WiFi
Today we will actually get into it, now that all the prep work is done
and now as we have all the tools installed and our system set up.
The first thing that we will need to do is set our network wireless card
into monitor mode.
Type in ifconfig, press ENTER
and this option will display all the network interfaces that are available.
My wireless interface is called wlp2s0
a bit of a strange name, I know
but Fedora has a custom for giving strange names
like my wired connection is called p8p1
which is kinda weird, but okay nevermind
just see which ones yours is and how is it called
and adapt accordingly.
Anyway I'm gonna use wlp2s0 in order for me to configure it
function in monitor mode.
There are two ways --
So the first one is what I usually use to set it in monitor mode
and the second one is what I usually use to actually check
if there are any problems whatsoever.
So go ahead then type in ifcongif again
wlp2s0
which is the name of my wireless network card
and type in "down"
Let's shut our wireless card down completely.
Let's turn it off
and now we can do some modifications to it
Type in "iwconfig wlp2s0 mode monitor"
Again, "ifconfig wlp2s0 up"
and now our network card is configured to function in monitor mode.
While before this it was functioning in the promiscuous mode.
There are several names for it, but promiscuous mode is the most common
and the difference between the two operating modes
is that one mode allows...
and there you go.
I have my wireless connection deactivated in the upper right corner.
The difference between the two modes is that in one mode
general network cards are configured to accept all packages
regardless if they were meant for them or not
and in promiscuous mode, they will accept packages
that are meant specifically for them.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and clear the screen
and finally start using some of the software packages
that come with aircrack.
I have a list of commands here for you which we will use today
on my right side
and we're gonna use a few other ones
but these are the basic ones.
These are the ones that you absolutely need to know.
So let me just go ahead and type in "airmon-ng check wlp2s0"
I want to see if there are any possible processes that could cause problems
that would cause interference
and I see that there are quite a bit of them.
Now one of the first things that you need to kill is the network manager
or you should
because even though it doesn't actually directly interfere with the functioning
it does spawn some other processes that might interfere
like your active internet connection here
The dhclient
especially if your network manager is configured to automatically connect
to a certain network
or to a wired network that you plug into your computer.
So let's go ahead and kill...
I'm not gonna take any chances today
I'm gonna go ahead and kill the network manager
and then I will start killing the rest.
So let's repeat the airmon-ng check
Excellent
Now I have a few more of these.
Next one to kill...
You do need to kill them in a certain order though
because they tend to spawn each other and you kill a process
but you do a check once more
and you realize it's still up and running
even though you've killed it as root.
It will kill it but it will restart it as well.
Let's just go ahead and kill the dhclient as well
in order to prevent interference
and the rest of killing can be done in any way you like.
Let's just go ahead and kill 1556 1215 1216
Excellent
Let's check one more time
So 1556
Let's see...Will this work?
avahi-daemon are the only ones running.
Apparently I have to kill the wpa-supplicant first
and then I can kill these.
It can be frustrating, primarily because you can't do them all at once.
You gotta type in commands time and time again.
Excellent
No such process running
There we go
Let me just go ahead and clear the screen
and always perform a second check.
You see nothing has popped.
Nothing should present any problems now.
Let's just go ahead and clear the screen.
The next thing that we want to do is perform a scan of our environment here
to see what sort of networks do we have
and who is connected to which network.
Now this you cannot see with the network manager.
With network manager
you can only see visible wireless access points around you
while on the other hand, one of the tools that comes with aircrack
you can actually see not only wireless access points around you
but you can also see who is connected to them, which is a very nice feature.
Let's just go ahead and type in the first command from my selected list here.
It's "airodump-ng wlp2s0"
wlp2so is our interface
So "airmon-ng wlp2s0"
Not airmon. Sorry
"airodump-ng wlp2s0"
A bit of an inconvenience with my talking and writing.
Never was good at that
but you can see here, these are all the wireless access points.
This one is mine
I have created this specifically for this purpose, for this tutorial.
It has a good password...strong password
and we are going to be cracking it today.
Keep in mind that the signal strength...
Okay, let me just cancel the scanning process now
and I just want to explain a few things that you can see here
during the scanning process itself.
BSSID is the MAC address of the device, which is a wireless access point.
Excellent
So the BSSID is the MAC address of that wireless access point
The PWR is the strength of the signal
-15 is a lot better than -30
Let's put it so
-57
It's not going to be the best of connections.
-78 or -84
You might be able to connect them
but this is not going to be a good connection at all.
However, even though the signals are this weak
if you have a good enough wireless card
you will be able to perform the authentication
and therefore, I will be able to render any of these networks that you see here
pretty much inoperable
but that we will do it the later tutorials.
For the time being, I just wanna show you one of the ways
in which you can actually crack the wpa2 encryption.
The DoS attacks are very useful.
They can practically render almost any WiFi network out there useless.
Nobody will be able to connect to it
or you can deauthenticate a specific client on the network
which is also extremely useful.
Let's just go ahead and clear the screen.
Once again, I will run the airodump and I will expand this terminal
so we can see some other things as well.
So it says something...It's 90:F6
I am looking for something to be associated with 90:F6
and that is what I shall use in order to actually deauthenticate
because we are looking for a four-way handshake.
It will appear in the top right corner.
There we will be able to see all the packets that are coming in
and there we will be able to actually capture file
and see what is going on
but that is not possible to do at the time being
primarily because we're scanning
for pretty much every single network out there
and I just wanted to show you how it looks like.
The next thing that we need to do is perform a specific scan.
So now we will be targeting this network here, as it has a good signal
and more importantly than that
I have a permission to do whatever I want with this network, as it is mine.
These down below are not mine.
Also keep in mind that we are not doing anything illegal here
or anything of a kind
Everything that you see here is pretty much public information
because this is what all the WiFi routers around me are broadcasting.
They are broadcasting their MAC address
and they are broadcasting the name basically.
The ESSID name is not a technical term
ESSID is the term
but everybody refers to it as a name of a wireless access point
or something of a kind
Anyway, as I said, all these are public information.
This is all the WiFi spots around me are broadcasting
and this sort of information you can also see on your cell phone
by just using the network manager
or you can use a network manager on your computer
and you will see pretty much the same things.
You will see that it's wpa2 encryption, you will see the MAC address
and you'll see the ESSID, of course.
The ESSID will be the first thing that you see on the network.
Also, you will see the channels as well.
This stuff in between -- You have to worry about those
They're not that relevant for our purpose today.
Anyway, I will call the tutorial here
and in the next one, we will be performing a specific scan
where we will capture information
and use that capture file in order to crack the encryption.
Until then, I bid you farewell
and I hope to see you in the next tutorial.