Hello everybody, and
welcome to this tutorial.
Today I'm gonna go ahead and
start configuring my computer,
my network settings, in order to be
able to strip the SSL encryption
from various packets that I'm
going to redirect to myself.
Anyway, one of the first things that we
need to do is take a look at the list
of these commands here.
So it's echo 1 to this file here.
Let me just show you,
I'm going to copy basid.
I am deliberately not giving you the text
files from which you can copy paste.
I mean,
I know that it's perhaps tiresome or
something like that but
try typing the commands in.
It does help you a great deal
to understand them better,
because you're gonna make mistakes and
you're gonna correct them and
you will understand and
remember the commands as well.
A very good way to remember
them is just to type them in.
Also, you will be able to
understand a bit more,
because you're gonna get error messages
that are gonna tell you stuff about it.
Anyway, I have buried a file for
myself here to save us a bit
of time today and to save myself
from making mistakes when typing.
But, anyway.
What we need to do is type this in.
It says echo 1 and
then put it into this file here.
I can go ahead and press Enter.
It's already set to 1 but
it doesn't matter.
I can also verify that it is
1 by catting the content.
So, it is 1.
If you wish to revert it back
to dual state, just type in 0.
And if I type in cat again,
it's going to be 0.
By default on your machines, it will be
set to 0, so you do need to change this.
I have done this before,
so it was already on 1.
But it doesn't matter.
It does no harm to type
it in one more time.
Now there is this rather lengthy
command in terms of IP tables
configuration that we need to
configure our firewall for
port redirection because
we need to redirect traffic
from a certain port to a certain port.
So from port 80 to the listening
port of the SSL strip and
iptables as I mentioned before
is a fantastic firewall.
Completely open source and
it can be used to conduct extremely
complex operations and it can be used for
the simplest of things.
The wonder of it is that it's free and
that it's very good.
Anyway, type in ip.
There's also graphical interface, but
rarely people use it on
very rare occasions.
I don't think that that
is the general approach.
Usually people prefer to just
type the commands in themselves.
Anyway, iptables, space -t nat.
So, nat is a table for
Network Address Translation.
-A, that stands for append.
I could also type in here -I for insert or
-D for delete, but we need append.
And chain prerouting.
PREROUTING.
Excellent.
We're going to specify a protocol.
So it's gonna be tcp --destination-port.
You can also use deport argument.
I don't know, I suppose for some strange
reason, I've opted for destination port.
It's a lot easier to
understand when looking at it.
It's practically written as though
it was literally English language.
It is English language, but
how would you tell somebody to
redirect to a certain point.
You tell them redirect to port and
type in the port.
You use the same syntax you
would use when telling somebody,
a real person, to redirect something.
You would use the same syntax to
actually tell the machine as well.
So, they've made a great effort
to make it as simple as possible.
Although at first glance
it can seem a bit complex.
So, It's tcp the destination port is 80 so
-j and I want to redirect the traffic, so
just type in REDIRECT --to- port 8080.
Now port 8080 is going to be the port on
which SSL strip will be listening on.
Go ahead and press Enter.
There is no output there
is no information nothing.
The exit code is zero so
nothing happens here and
if nothing happens that's great,
it means it has worked.
Not necessarily but 99% of the cases
it means that it has worked.
However I do like to run a verification,
and I'm gonna go ahead and
type in iptables -t nat
-L to get a listing.
And I want PREROUTING,
I want to see what I've done there.
Excellent!
So, you see, it says redirect
tcp from anywhere to anywhere.
Destination port of you see dport,
dpt, it's a short version here.
So, this nation port is port JD,
which is HTTP.
Redirect towards 8080.
Excellent.
I've already inserted,
I have a bad feeling I've inserted
this root three times by now,
cuz I've done some test runs in order to
not make any mistakes during your
tutorial to save us all time.
But it seems to be effective.
It seems to be working so
let's just go ahead and clear the screen.
Keep in mind that while you're doing this
you're gonna encounter a lot of problems.
There's gonna be error messages.
Things are not gonna work.
You're gonna need to
reinstall some things,
install additional libraries perhaps or
something of a kind.
Don't sweat it,
that is all standard procedure.
It happens to everybody quite literally.
You just need nerves of
steel to go through it.
Now I've written for
myself here find a target.
Now you can use,
I know what target I'm going to use but
you can use nmap and
before you use nmap just like an ifconfig.
Clear, ifconfig p8p1.
Excellent.
So I just wanted to get a listing for
the interface that I'm using because you
need to be using the interface that you
are using to connect to the Internet.
So this is the IP address that is assigned
to me, usually the default gateway is
simply the lowest one, but you can check
the default gateway by typing in route,
press Enter and there we go.
Gateway 192.168.1.1.
That will be the IP address of
my router within a LAN now.
Looking at this, I'm guessing it's
assigning IP addresses from 2 to 254,
because it can't assign 255.
255 is the broadcast.
Anyway, so
from 2 to 254 it's going to be assigning
IP addresses I can perform
a nmap scan of the network so
nmap, and I'm going to go ahead and And
type in 192.168.1.1/24.
So please scan the entire subnet or
I can just do this, 2-254,
to save myself a couple of IP
addresses here, two IP addresses less.
And I want -vv after it.
This might take a while
if you're doing it.
This will reveal all the hosts that are up
on the network and that nmap can reveal.
I've also told it to scan
on all ports as well.
However, you're gonna have to do this,
basically,
if you're in a real life situation and
it's gonna keep on scanning.
And it says, okay, host down.
I only have one host that is up here.
That is up and running,
which is my Windows machine.
And I'm not gonna go and
sift through all these up.
I'm just gonna go ahead
over to my VirtualBox,
and open up my Windows 8 machine.
There you go.
So it says, scanned hosts, never mind.
Anyway you will need to perform this scan
if you want to figure out who's alive.
But I've just shown you how to do it.
Just do nmap and
if you don't find any hosts try passing
on some different arguments through nmap.
Try saying like -Pn or
something of a kind, and
see if that yields any different results.
Also you can use -o for, oops, -o for
OS detection and something of a kind.
Yeah, there we go.
So, I'm gonna open up my Windows machine.
Type in ipconfig into the CMD, oops.
Is it IP?
Yep, it's ipconfig into the CMD, and
I'm gonna get a lot of information here.
Basically I'm only interested to see which
IP address is actually assigned to this
machine.
It's 100.
Excellent.
So this machine,
this Windows 8.1 virtual machine
is functioning on 192.168.1.100.
That is my victim that is a machine
that I wish to vandalize,
that I want to actually strip of it's
encryption and view it's traffic.
So just go ahead and minimize it for
the time being as we know
what the IP address is there.
And if you're wondering why I
have all these terminals open,
we will need two terminals
to perform this attack and
a third one to view
the results of the attack,
because we don't want to stop the attack
while we are viewing the results.
Anyway, second part in the followup
tutorial, I'm gonna go ahead and
go over arpspoofs, since we have
completely prepared our machine.
We have found our victim.
Now we need to do the arspoof and
we need to conduct an SSL strip,
and then we need to have a live
report of the log as well,
in order to pull out some of
the valuable information from it.
Anyway, I bid you all farewell and
I hope to see you in the next tutorial.