Hello everybody, and
welcome to this tutorial.
Today, I am going to just
continue up on evil twin.
We have managed to get
the client to associate with us.
But what good is it?
Primarily because that client will not
have infinite access until we configure
our network settings so that there is
a bridge between our fake wireless
access point and our network interface,
which actually has internet connection.
Only then will the client on the other
side actually be able to access Internet
and only then will we actually be able
to harvest any sort of information
whatsoever.
So on the right side for this purpose
I have made a series of commands
which you will need to run and
they're not really complicated.
It's more or
less the same command running over and
over again with different interfaces.
What you will need first is bridge-utils,
so go ahead and type yum_search, and
I'm just going to copy/paste the name.
Excellent, there we go.
So it says bridge-utils.x86_64.
You need to install this,
hopefully by now you have learned how
to install these things, but just in
case you didn't, all you need to do is
type in yum install and then paste it.
By default it will pick up that it's this
package x86_64, just type in yum install
bridge-utils -y, and that's gonna install
without asking you any questions.
Now, I have it already installed here so
there's no need to go through the process.
Next up,
what we need to do is have this one,
it says brctl addbr evil.
You can name it any way you
like I have named it evil,
but it doesn't really matter.
Whatever the name will go.
This name is completely irrelevant,
as far as I know.
So just go ahead and type in.
It says, device evil already exists;
can't create bridge with the same name.
It doesn't matter for me it already
exists because I have previously created.
For you, this command will just fly
without any sort of problems whatsoever.
Now the next thing that you need to do.
Well this is where it says p8p1, that
is the interface, let me just show you.
IF config.
There is a whole lot of interfaces and
information out here.
I'm gonna need to change the zoom here.
Excellent.
This is much better.
So look, the interface p8p1 is
the interface that I'm currently using.
That is my wired interface and
that interface has Internet access.
What I need to do is bridge evil and
p8p1 and that is exactly what
this command will do for us.
So, just go ahead and copy.
There we go.
Okay,
p8p1 is already a member of bridge;
can't enslave it to the bridge evil.
So I've already added it, so it can't
repeat the process twice for you again or
the command will fly.
Now we have linked this intermediary
interface named evil to
the interface p8p1,
which actually has internet connectivity.
However, we also need to
add to this the interface
which is created by airbase and
that is at0.
Basically what we are doing is
repeating the process twice.
Let's just go ahead and clear the screen.
Paste.
So you see, previously, I have added p8p1,
which has Internet connectivity to evil.
I have bridged them.
And now, I am going to bridge at0 to evil.
Don't worry, at0 should be the same on
your system because airbase will create
this interface for you.
No problems there, all you need to do
is bridge it to this intermediary, and
you should eventually have
Internet connectivity.
Press Enter.
Again I get an error message
because it says that the process
has already taken place,
and it cannot duplicate it.
For you, it's gonna fly.
Next up,
basically what we need to do is add IP
addresses to the exempted interfaces and
furthermore, we need to change their
state to up, primarily because
the states of these interfaces are not
up by default and that can be a problem.
So you just need to bring it up manually.
No big deal.
These commands are pretty simple and
straightforward.
So ifconfig, which you've used before,
name of the interface this is,
strange as it might look,
this actually is the IP address.
And just say up.
Excellent, there we go.
Confirmation.
No confirmation message.
Nothing.
The command has passed through.
Excellent.
Now we need to bring evil up as well,
also our bridging interface,
ifconfig evil up.
No need to assign an IP address there.
And we don't need to bring p8p1 of course
up, primarily because it's already up.
It has Internet connectivity.
Just copy this as well.
Paste.
So dhclient3 evil &,
press Enter.
Press Enter.
Yep.
There we go.
Hold on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Why are you giving me this?
Let's remove the redirection.
Excellent, there we go.
You you can just type in dhclient evil and
that should work as well.
I'm fairly certain that this
command worked a moment ago,
but it doesn't really matter.
It says dhclient is
already running- exiting,
so no need to actually
do anything here for me.
But for you, you will just need to go and
follow through pretty much
exactly what I've said.
Now once this is configured you see that
my airbase on this side is still running.
So I have not shut down from
it since last time I did this.
Now the client on the other side, either
the phone or a tablet or a computer or
something of a kind that is
connecting to our fake access point,
to our evil twin,
will have Internet connectivity,
will be able to browse the net and
will literally suspect nothing.
Cuz you get disconnected from wireless.
It's not uncommon.
I mean be honest with yourselves,
ask yourselves if I get this disconnected
from a wireless for a couple of seconds,
will I suspect that there's some foul play
here that somebody's doing something,
or that somebody's hacking,
or something of a kind?
No, of course not.
[LAUGH].
If you get the authenticator
you will simply press reconnect.
Or the device will reconnect automatically
for you, and, while you're waiting for
that reconnect,
you'll probably be staring at the device,
literally looking at it and
not suspecting a thing.
Anyway, in the follow-up tutorial,
I am going to show you
how you can actually monitor the traffic
of somebody that is connected to your
fake wireless access point and
how you can extract that information.
Until then, I bid you farewell and
hope to see you in the next tutorial.