Welcome to this tutorial.
Today I am gonna finish
up with this section.
I will show you how you can actually
monitor all traffic that goes on
the cloned network that you have set up
on your laptop or desktop, or whatever.
Anyway, why is this important?
Well, first of all,
don't get your hopes up too high.
Because you won't be able
to actually get passwords,
or user credentials,
by just listening to traffic.
You can, if they are not using
any encrypted protocols, but
if they are using HTTPS,
you can forget about it there.
That's gonna be too difficult.
I mean, there are some methods
that are experimental today, but
I haven't really included them here
as they are still experimental.
If you just go back a tutorial or
two you have an option of SSL strip.
So you will be able to rid
yourself of that encryption and
read the credentials in clear text
without any problems whatsoever.
It doesn't always work with all
browsers and all websites, but
like 90% of the time,
it will work without any bigger problems.
Now, why then you might ask yourselves,
why would we do this?
Well, you are able to see who is
browsing what sort of content.
You are able to see who is logging
into the back ends of the web servers.
You're able to see if somebody is
using official email, or any email for
that matter.
And you are able to see who is using
which type of services on the net.
And in such a way will be able to pick
your target in a relatively easy fashion,
you will see who has what.
And okay, I need this, so let's go for it.
Anyway, this is not the only
reason why we have accessed it,
why we have created an evil twin.
We can use it for other purposes,
such as a DNS change of the DNS
servers and the router.
And, as I have stated previously, that's
gonna enable us to do some wonderful
social engineering whereby we
will be able to take user names,
passwords, user credentials in general,
without any bigger difficulties.
But for the time being, let's just
see how is traffic actually analyzed.
Let me just go ahead and
clear the screen here.
Zoom it in, move it here.
For this purpose we will,
of course, need a tool.
With which we can actually
listen to traffic.
And that tool is called Wireshark.
That's one of many,
there are others out there.
Wireshark is the most used one.
I would definitely recommend it,
but if you don't feel like it just go on
the net and see what else is out there.
Now it's pretty simple, it comes with
a pretty simple installation method.
So, yum search wireshark, and
it should pop up here somewhere.
You need to install two packages,
It will enable you to listen
to pretty much all traffic that goes
through your network without any problems.
However, as I said before,
you won't be able to take
passwords from encrypted traffic.
Moreover, Wireshark is, I mean,
that's a course for itself and
its rather lengthy, there are a lot of
options, it's a pretty sophisticated tool.
I won't go through all of
the options today, but
I will show you some of the basics and
how you can actually monitor traffic based
upon the information that I give you.
So you will need this package
here that I am selecting, and
you will need the bottom one.
Hopefully by now, you know how to install.
It's, yum, space, install space,
the name of the package, space -y.
So you wouldn't be prompted for
any questions, and
it would install it without any problems.
Now I have Wireshark
running here somewhere.
Yep, there we go.
Now I have opened it, and
here you can take a pick from the list of
interfaces on which you wish to listen.
Our interface is of course Evil,
and that is
what we want to listen to all
the traffic that goes on it.
Now there isn't much traffic here,
primarily because there
isn't much that is going on.
But you can see immediately there are some
basic packets that are going through.
And let me just see if I can
browse something on my phone, or
something of that kind.
This is just router communication.
So let's go over to Firefox over here.
I've just literally opening up
a website on my phone, and that is it.
You can see that immediately the amount
of traffic is jumping insanely.
Look at how much of it there is.
So all this traffic is
generated basically,
well most of this traffic is
generated by one single device.
And I'm gonna go ahead and
stop the capture here because I
am no longer interested in this.
Over here you can see the queries.
And here you can actually see
the URL from time to time.
The URL is a small piece of all of this.
But I'm not sure if I can find
it now as there is a lot of it.
Look, here's one that says,
standard query response,
safebrowsing.cache.l.google.com.
And you can see the IP address
that was accessed from
which I do believe the response came.
Anyway, again we have
something related to Google.
Again, I don't have a browser open.
There is literally no traffic going on,
on my network here.
However, there is traffic that is
being generated from my phone.
Or, yeah, there we go.
And this is www.google.ba.
You see here, you have the URL
here that is being accessed.
And you can see that,
that has been requested here.
If I just double-click on it,
if I open it,
I'm gonna get a listing of pretty
detailed information here.
So, domain name, if I just click on it,
there's some sort of information here,
not very useful to you at the time.
But you can just go down to queries,
and you can see the URL.
That is probably the most important thing
for you at this particular point in time.
This is how you can actually
see who is browsing for what.
Who wants what, who is going where.
Not a bad idea, pretty good thing to do,
especially because you can, as I said
before, you can actually pick the targets,
and you can see the IP addresses here.
I mean, you can see which IP
address has requested which site.
So this first colon that
you are looking at now.
Sorry, not the first colon,
where it says source.
So source, IP addresses, and then you have
the next one is destination IP addresses.
I'm clicking on the two of them.
So if you take a look at the top right
corner, it says 192, the grey one.
It says 192.168.1.101, and
then there is destination,
which is 173.194.116.225.
So, the device with this first
IP address,192.168.1.101,
has requested something from
the destination IP address,
173.194.116.225.
There was a communication in
between these two IP addresses.
Now that can be different
sorts of traffic.
And for the time being,
you can disregard most of this.
What you are interested in are those URLs.
To see what sort of information
are people browsing, and
you can see and get the addresses.
For example, if they're logging into their
company's servers that have an external
IP address, you can actually see it here
in the destination IP addresses part.
And in such a way you can go ahead,
try to open it up in your browser and
see what sort of login procedures
does it actually require.
How hard is it?
Is it HTTP or is it HTTPS?
It can give you a lot of information.
Now, this is just a raw overview of data.
I encourage you to expand
upon this subject further.
In the upper left corner,
there are filters and
here you can type in various values.
Do try to pick apart the information.
For example, I can type in DNS.
So, give me all the DNS queries,
and it's gonna give me all the DNS
queries that have been made.
Which is very nice, because I now
know what my phone has requested.
So look, It has CCNA.
That's for Cisco.
It has requested Google.
It has pulled some,
is this an image from YouTube?
I have no idea what this is.
I don't know.
In any case, it has contacted YouTube.
Again, it went over to Google,
and, yeah, there you go.
There's safe browsing, Google clients.
Yeah, okay so, I have opened up Firefox,
I've seen something on Google.
I obviously can't see the search results,
but I can see when a person clicks
on one of those search results and
requests that particular URL.
For that purpose,
DNS filter is your friend, but
it doesn't necessarily need to be.
You can just leave it empty and
see how it goes.
You can also type in IP.addr == and
then you can type in the IP address.
Here for example, 192.168.1.101.
So now we have all the traffic,
which has either a source, or
a destination IP address of 192.168.1.101.
So if you wish to see a traffic
of a particular IP address,
you can use the filter
that I have just used.
I would strongly encourage you to
expand upon this subject further.
There is a course on Udemy
that I have made, as well.
But you don't have to go there.
I mean, you also obviously have a great
deal of knowledge on the Internet as well.
So you can explore it there.
Because Wireshark and networking traffic
monitoring is a subject of its own.
That's like a course of its own.
There's a huge amount of information.
But you are able to get
the basic information,
which interests you at this point of time.
In any case,
I am going to wrap the tutorial up here.
And in the next chapter,
we're going to get into routers and
how to break the first line of defense for
pretty much any major network out there.
Until then, I bid you farewell, and
I hope to see you in the next tutorial.