Hello everybody, and
welcome to this tutorial.
Today I am going to show you,
or today I'm going to just continue the
demonstration that I started previously.
I'm going to show you how you can extract
credentials from this particular router.
Now, the same procedure applies elsewhere,
but
you need to grab that model number,
either by doing extensive nmap scanning,
or by just using a far simpler method,
trying to authenticate.
Well, actually we don't need
to type any credentials,
you can just go to the website.
Go to the login website, and
see if any information is revealed there.
Apparently, for most of the home routers
you're going to get a model number there,
or at the very least,
you will get the manufacturer name.
Anyway, I've attempted to download
rom-0 file from my browser.
But now I am going to use wget.
And wget is a piece of software that
should be installed by default.
But just in case it is not,
type in yum search wget.
Press Enter.
And there you go, the last one is wget.
Just type in yum install wget,
and it will be installed.
Clear the screen.
So, wget http://192.168.1.1.
Keep in mind I'm using the local address
here, but you can use a public IP address.
So this router, for all intents and
purposes, could be in Japan,
on the other side of
the globe from myself.
It would not matter,
this attack would still go and fly.
/rom-0, that's O, -0.
Press Enter.
And there we, oh,
it has saved it from the rom-0.2.
So I have already downloaded it twice.
I guess this is the second time around
that I'm attempting to make this tutorial.
For some strange reason either
the connection crashes, or
I have some problems.
But in any case, let's just go ahead and
proceed with this.
Well, let me just clear the screen.
And now we need something
to read that rom.
Let me just show you how that looks like.
I'm gonna use the original
one that I've downloaded.
I don't know why, it just feels right.
Because I'm downloading it already for
the second time.
Anyway, with is how
a binary file looks like.
You can't really read through this,
you might get here and there,
pieces of readable code.
There you go, at the bottom.
At the bottom,
you have a little bit that's readable.
But none of this information is
actually of any particular use to you.
Just go ahead and press quit to quit it.
And we need something to
actually interpret this.
In order for us to interpret this,
I have a bunch of websites here that
I have opened for this purpose.
And you can see here, you have ZTE,
TP-Link, ZynOS,
Huawei rom-0 Configuration Decompressor.
So this will make the file
readable in short.
You can just go ahead and
copy this script into a file.
And now I want you to do this on your own.
If you fail to do it, feel free to
post it in the question section.
I will be more than happy
to explain it to you how.
Here's a bit of a hint.
You need to just copy this
text into a text file.
That text file must have
an extension of .py.
And you must make it executable.
So chmod +x, and
the name of the file then follows.
This is the format of the file, so ls.
This is how your file should look like.
It should have a .py and
it should have a +x.
So type in chmod +x and
then name of the file.
Just let's clear the screen.
ZteRomReader.py rom-0.
Press Enter, and there we go.
It actually just reads right through it,
and
it converts it to a human-readable form,
you can put it so.
But it doesn't actually bother
to go through the whole file,
to give us the contents of the whole file.
Its main concern is with the password for
the router.
So there you have it here.
Usually these things are the password.
And there you go, here, and
then you have the password alone.
So router password is 263297.
You can use this password that is obtained
in such a manner to log in to the router.
Now, there comes a problem
with this method.
If anybody has messed
around with the router.
Well, actually, on some of these routers,
I've noticed that you can't
actually change the user name.
Which is very interesting.
And that the default user name is admin.
So you can just use
admin as a log in name.
Maybe, maybe sometimes I've seen
that they use a login name root.
But you can also go on the net and
type in default login names for
that particular brand of the router.
And you can try a couple of them.
Usually, there's like maximum of four or
five, something like that.
You're not going to get
100 different variants.
Just try a few of them, see how it works.
But this is the password, for sure.
You will be able to log
into the router with it.
All that remains is finding the user name.
But 99% of the time,
the username will be admin.
So no worries there.
Although some of the routers,
they give very unique user names.
But they are public.
So just go on the net,
type in the router model.
And apply that particular user name.
Now, before you actually try to
do something crazy like this,
try the default login credentials.
Type in admin, admin.
And if admin, admin doesn't work,
take the model number,
type it into your favorite search engine,
and type in, default credentials.
Because default credentials can
vary from router to router.
And if the router is in
a different country,
see the IP address of the router,
see to who it belongs.
Let me just show you how you can do that.
Major IP blocks.
I believe I've showed
you this website before.
Come on, there we go.
So it says here,
it gives the IP addresses.
It gives the IP address ranges, and
then the owner should be
written in the far right.
But apparently I don't have it.
Come on.
Look at how many IP address are for
US alone.
That's like a lot.
And it doesn't list the owners for
the US, strangely.
But it doesn't matter.
Look, I can just take this address,
copy it, oops, come on.
Why are you doing this to me?
Why, why, why?
I do not care for the Google Store.
I gotta delete this somehow so
I don't click on it.
Who is.
And so it doesn't, you'll get
the owner of the IP address here.
Once you get the owner of the IP
address here, if it's a telecom,
and if it's a router then
it's definitely a telecom.
If it's a home router, then what I want
to say then it's definitely a telecom.
Once you actually figure
out which telecom it is.
You can go ahead and type on the net
configuration manuals of that
particular telecom for
that particular router.
Because usually telecoms
keep such files public.
And you can read the default username and
default password there which
are unique to that particular telecom.
Cuz they can vary from
one place to another.
This is primarily to prevent people
from just mass scanning the Internet.
Well, one of the reasons, anyway.
To prevent people from mass
scanning the Internet, and
then just trying the credentials admin,
admin.
They still have default credentials,
they're just not admin, admin.
So a lot of the scripts will actually
fail to authenticate against them.
But if you just bother
to look a bit further,
you will realize that
the credentials are still public.
They can be changed by the users,
of course, but users rarely do this,
and I mean rarely.
Anyway, I'm going to
call this tutorial here.
In the next one, we're going to do
pre-authentication exploitation.
And until then, I bid you farewell.