Hello everybody and welcome to this tutorial
Today we're gonna just continue on, as this is a follow-up tutorial
so without further ado
let me just show the modifications that I have made to the SQL map command.
I have it here somewhere.
Yep, there we go
So the address is pretty much the same as it was
except there is this bar thing at the end.
It was in the address of the site.
I've removed it
I have literally no idea why
but it's supposed to be there.
I'm sorry for that.
Anyway, in the cookie section
you will also need to make some modifications.
So this is the cookie that we have previously used.
I have closed and reopened the session since then
so it is likely that this has changed
but you will need to identify the cookie
So it's PHPSESSID
This is a type of cookie that we have picked up
So just type it in
and you can also specify the security level equals
and then you specify it here
It's low
Sorry, let me just change that quickly.
Excellent! There we go
So I've been playing around with it
and I've been trying to see what happens with different sort of settings
and you see it, just to confirm on the website.
It is on high
So you see the setting here is on high.
However, even though the setting is on high here
you can play around with these cookies
and you can do this on any other site pretty much.
You can also modify the cookies to get different sort of results
and if its high here
and even though the site is set to "high"
I can type in here "low"
and it's gonna go as "low", no problems.
Now, as I said, this is not something that you can apply here in here alone
This can be applied pretty much anywhere.
Open up your burp suite
take a look at the cookies section
and see what happens there.
Try logging in and out of the website, wiping your cookies clean
wiping your browser history clean
and see you have five consecutive cookies
and see what happens
or log in through a different browser or log in through a different virtual machine
and just have five, or something like that, consecutive complete cookies
and then see how they change.
If you can figure out their rates of change
and if you can figure out how they're assigned, well...
There you go
You need nothing else pretty much.
However, that is not really likely to happen
unless somebody has some really bad cookie keys
then you can do pretty much whatever you want.
So let's just change this to high again
and I already have it cached
I have done it several times, but if it doesn't work with high
leave the high setting on the website, but modify the cookie to low
and trick it in such a fashion
I have a bad feeling its gonna pull it from cache
and it did pull it from cache.
It doesn't really matter.
Yours is just gonna take a bit longer.
Maybe 30 seconds more or something like that
and you'll probably be prompted with a
question.
Read through the question.
If it finds some vulnerabilities, it will stop
and it will ask you do you want to continue scanning
even though I found vulnerabilities.
You can say either no or yes
Just type in N or Y
For the time being, if you wish to follow exactly through this tutorial
You can just answer with no
because we are focusing on a particular vulnerability
and we're not expanding on it
but on your own, I would strongly recommend that you do keep on scanning
and try out different stuff
and as I said, if it doesn't exactly work with high
just try modifying cookies to low and leave it on the site as high.
Anyway, so we have some information here.
Again, go ahead and read through it
It says "Parameter: id (GET)"
"Type: boolean based blind"
Title it says "Payload"
Excellent
Okay, so this is definitely vulnerable
and all this information tells you a bit about the vulnerability
and it confirms that it is vulnerable
but you still need to actually do something with it.
You still need to try to extract information.
By the way, your log files are here.
You see this file that I am selecting
do not forget to type in the dot here, the one that I'm selecting now.
So just type in "/root/.sqlmap/output/"
and this is my current IP address
but you know, IP addresses vary from one web server to another
so just use the one that is written out here, in order to access the logs.
There will be all sorts of files there
but you can just go ahead and use the file named quite literally log
open it up and see what's written in it.
Basically you will have this here in it, no problems.
Anyway, now that we've established it is vulnerable
I have a few commands here that I have written out for myself
So let's just go heading clear the screen now.
We know that this is vulnerable.
We're going to use pretty much exactly the same syntax.
However, we want to add a few things, so "dbs"
Let's see how this works out
"unable to retrieve the database names"
Okay, let's try tricking the website from high to low
and there we go.
It's right there
So once again, see I've just modified the cookies themselves.
I haven't actually modified the site
If I go back to the site
if I click on security, it is on high.
You see, this has not changed at all.
Let's just go back to the SQL injection (Blind)
Go ahead and open up the terminal
and it says here "available databases"
So we have "dvwa", "information_schema", "mysql", "performance_schema"
and so on and so forth.
So if we just go back to our command, we can type in "D" for database
and now we can retrieve tables from individual databases.
By the way, the DBS just gives you gives you the database basically.
It says "available databases" and ones that you want to access
depending on what sort of information is contained where,
You can't, of course, know
but it doesn't really hurt to just check them out.
Sometimes there is a lot of them and it can be a drag
but it doesn't matter.
As soon as you get to this part
as soon as you manage to go through the first barrier
and actually access through a database remotely
you are there.
Then it's just a matter of time.
Far less time, primarily because you are able to go through those databases
and figure out what is where.
Now if somebody's keeping an active track of what is going on
and if somebody's monitoring this live
they will be able to see that there is a incoming connection
That can be problematic because they can kick you off, but so what?
If you do this at some ridiculous hours of the morning
depending on which time zone the database is
you can actually pull the databases
just download them and then analyze them later.
So you have all the time in the world to analyze them
after you have pulled the information and after you've seen
then you can just sit back, relax, disconnect your machine
and risk-free basically.
Just go through the files and see what is contained therein.
Now I have immediately written here "dvwa"
but let's just go through some of the other ones as well.
Let's see what's in there
"mysql --tables", press ENTER
Is it gonna pull? Yep, there we go
Since we have "user",  we have "columns_priv"
This is for the SQL
Excellent
We got a lot of tables here.
Let's see what we can do with this user.
There is bound to be something there
I mean, you can go ahead and check the others as well.
Usually there's something that says "user password" or something of a kind
Go and check it out
I personally would go through every single thing once I fetch the database
because you never know how somebody is going to name something
what sort of identification are they going to use.
They might as well name this table "user" to...
maybe not this particular one
but on the sites, on the web servers elsewhere
they can put their usernames and passwords in a database
called, I don't know, Santa Claus
under a table called wooden door, pretty much.
So once you have it, invest a little bit more time
and go through these tables, go through all the databases
go through all of their tables, and go through all the contents of the tables.
Just try to see
even though some of it is encrypted, fine
Okay, store it, maybe decrypt it later
but go through all of it.
Have a look at what is within those databases
because as I said
a lot of things can be just named differently and you might skip it
thinking it's nothing.
Okay, so let's change the pace a little bit
Let's say "T" for table
and let's say that I want table user
"user --column", press ENTER
Okay, let's see what do we get you want
"Do you want to use common column existence check?"
Sure, why not?
Let's see what happens.
"Please enter a number of threads?"
This is a pretty small one, but the more threads your enter
the faster it's gonna go
but the risk of detection is higher, I guess.
I don't know
Let's see if you can support four threads on this virtual machine.
Apparently we can
I could have probably told it more, but it doesn't really matter.
This is gonna run for a while
and then we're gonna see the contents of the other table
Basically, we'll see the columns and we'll see what's actually written in them.
Anyway, I will pause the tutorial here.
I will let it finish
and then we'll pick up from where we left off in the follow-up tutorial.
Until then, I bid you all farewell and wish you a lot of luck with this.