So far, in the previous module, we have spent a lot of time discussing theory.
It's finally time where we get our hands dirty and begin
setting up our CloudFront distribution.
I mean,
it's not like people are moving closer to our origin to access our content,
so let's move our origin closer to them.
Let's begin by taking our demo application and
assessing its current performance, that way we have a baseline measurement.
Once we have that,
we will set up our CloudFront distribution so we can
better deliver and optimize our content.
We will finish off by reassessing the performance of our website to
determine how much improvement CloudFront has provided.
I bet you will be surprised how much we can improve by the end of this module. Let's get started.