If the objects that you're serving through CloudFront
are unavailable for some reason,
your web server typically returns an HTTP status
code to CloudFront. For example, if a viewer specifies an invalid URL,
your web server returns a 404 status code to CloudFront.
CloudFront returns the status code to the requester.
The browser displays a brief and sparsely formatted default message similar to
this. But you can display a custom error message instead.
You also have several options for managing how
CloudFront responds when there is an error.
To specify options for custom error messages,
you need to configure your CloudFront distribution under the Error Pages tab.
If you'd rather display a customer error message instead of the default message,
for example,
a page that uses the same formatting as the rest of your website, you
can have CloudFront return to the viewer an object,
such as an HTML file that contains your custom error message.
For example,
the following is a customized error message handled and served by CloudFront.
You can specify a different object for each supported HTTP status code,
or you can use the same object for all of the supported status codes.
You can also choose to specify objects for some status codes and not for others.
The objects that you're serving through CloudFront can be
unavailable for a variety of reasons.
These fall into two broad categories.
Client errors indicate a problem with the request.
For example,
an object with a specified name isn't available or the user doesn't have the
permissions required to get an object in your S3 bucket.
When a client error occurs,
the origin returns an HTTP status code in the 400 range to CloudFront.
Server errors indicate a problem with the origin.
For example,
the HTTP server is busy or unavailable. When a server error occurs,
either your origin server returns and HTTP status code in the 500
range to CloudFront or CloudFront doesn't get a response from your
origin for a certain period of time and assumes a 504 status code due
to a gateway timeout.
The HTTP status codes for which CloudFront can return a custom error page
include the following: 400 Bad Request, 403 Forbidden, 404 Not Found, 405
Method Not Allowed, 414 URI Too Long, and 416 Range Not Satisfiable. And
for server errors, 500 Internal Server Error, 501 Not Implemented, 502
Bad Gateway, 503 Service Unavailable, and 504 Gateway Timeout. I have
added a custom error page for when 404 status codes are returned for my
origin.
As you can see,
I have an S3 bucket for storing error pages. In this bucket, I have
saved the custom 404 error template as 404.html.
This document is styled to look like the rest of my website.
It is recommended you keep your error templates in a
separate origin like an S3 bucket. That way, if there is
an issue with your other origins,
custom error messages can continue to be served. If you click the blue
Create Custom Error Response button when on the Error Pages tab of the
CloudFront service, you'll see the following options: HTTP Error Code.
We'll choose 404 as our error code. Error codes default to using a TTL
of 300 seconds, but you can override them when creating your custom errors.
We'll leave 300 seconds, or 5 minutes. Customize Error Response.
Once we click Yes, you'll see two new fields appear.
Response Path will add the path to our 404.html document from our S3 origin.
And since we're actually loading a real HTML document,
we can send a 200 response code.
You can choose to respond with any of the supported response codes.
Then we'll click Create.
You should now see your custom error response configured here.
Since my custom error template is in a different
location from my default origin,
I will need to add a new origin and a new behavior to to connect
CloudFront to my S3 bucket. Once that is completed and once my
Distribution Status returns to Deployed,
then I can test my site to see how it will return a 404 error.
If I use something like www.dyrcz.me/fileshouldntexist.html,
which is an HTML file which does not exist on any of my origins, so my
origins should return a 404, and CloudFront should return my custom 404
page and respond with a 200 status code.
Now we have proper error handling when it comes to a 404 response.
You can now replicate this process for any additional custom error responses that you'd like to implement.