In the last video,
we discovered that it takes around 7 seconds to completely load our website.
In this video, I challenge us to get it under 2 seconds.
How you ask?
By simply creating what is called a CloudFront distribution.
A distribution is the collective name of all of the
configurations you enabled to delivery your content.
This means setting your origin and all of the associated
rules for caching and traffic handling.
In this lesson,
we're going to create a distribution that will sit
between our web content and the browser.
While we'll go through this quickly,
we will deep dive into each element in the following videos.
Basically,
this run-through is to build your familiarity with the
CloudFront distribution options.
From within the Management Console, let's head over to the CloudFront service.
If you have not created a distribution before,
the first screen you should see is the Getting Started window
with the big blue Create Distribution button.
For now, click this button.
Next, you will select the delivery method.
We want to use web method.
Choose getting started.
Alright, now there are a lot of options to fill out, but don't be intimidated.
While there are a lot of options,
just know that there are really only three main sections,
default origin, default cache behavior, and distribution settings.
At the top, we have the Origin Settings section.
This is where we assign our origin to our distribution.
To set our origin domain name, click on the empty field.
You'll notice a drop-down menu.
If your origin is hosted within your AWS account,
then you should see it as an option.
Our event website is hosted on EC2 instances with an ELB in front of it.
So we'll find under Elastic Load Balancers,
the Pluralsight-demo ELB hostname listed.
We'll discuss other options for choosing origins in the preceding lessons video.
For now, we can leave the origin path blank.
We'll give the origin ID something more familiar than this.
You can leave this as the ID that AWS generates for you,
but as time goes on, it's kind of nice to have a friendly ID here.
Minimum Origin SSL Protocol is listed as minimum because you need to set it
to the lowest level of TLS that your origin supports.
Our ELB is using ELB security policy TLS 1.2.
So here, we will choose TLS version 1.2.
Try to avoid TLS version 1 or SSL version 3 if you can.
I know some applications out there still need to support those,
but please choose wisely as those versions are known to be insecure nowadays.
You might need to work on upgrading your TLS on your origin,
but that's for a different Pluralsight lesson.
Let's set the origin protocol to HTTPS only since our origin
is currently listening on HTTPS port 443.
For the time being, we can leave all timeouts, ports, and headers as they are.
Let's move onto default cache behavior settings.
Remember, we are setting the default behavior,
that's why our path pattern is set to default.
Let's enable redirect HTTP to HTTPS for the viewer protocol policy so
that way if someone requests our content through HTTP,
they will automatically get redirected to HTTPS.
For now, we will only allow get and head methods.
We don't need options or anything else with put, post, patch, or delete.
Okay, we're going to jump down to cache based on selected request headers.
Since we're using an elastic load balancer as our origin,
we need to either enable all or whitelist which headers reach our origin.
We're going to go with whitelist and then add host to our whitelist
which will set the value for the domain name of the origin that is
associated with the requested object allowing us to cache objects
requested at our domain name.
Object caching,
let's pick customize so we can set out TTLs at CloudFront
and not rely on our origin cache headers.
We'll leave these as the defaults.
For the time being,
we don't need to afford cookies nor do we need to afford query strings,
so we can leave them set to none which will improve our
caching by caching every request that we get so anything in
the future will already be cached.
And we can leave Smooth Streaming and Restrict Viewer Access set to no,
but we will move compress objects automatically to a yes
and we can skip over lambda for now.
Alright, and now we're on to our distribution settings.
Price class.
Let's use all edge locations right now.
We're not working on our WAF, so we can just leave that for the time being.
For our CNAME,
we're going to want to put in the domain name that
we will use to reach CloudFront.
So we're going to put in www.dyrcz .me.
Leaving the default certificate is just fine if you're going to use
the CloudFront domain name that is generated for us.
Since we're using a custom domain, or a CNAME,
we will choose our certificate from ACM.
Leave supported HTTP version as-is.
We're going to set index.html as our default root object.
Leave logging off for now.
We'll discuss that in a later video.
Okay, we can leave everything else and we're ready to create our distribution.
But before we do so, if you hop into your terminal,
if you followed along with the previous videos,
you should be able to list any existing CloudFront distributions from here.
If you run this command, you can list all of your distributions.
An empty return means that there is no CloudFront distributions.
Okay, we can go ahead and click our Create Distribution button now.
So we can now see that our distribution is being deployed.
We've been given an ID and AWS has created a domain
name for our CloudFront distribution.
If I hop into Route 53 real quick and add a record for www
pointing to my CloudFront distribution,
we should see some major improvements right off the bat.
In the meantime, if we run this command again,
you will now see your distribution with all the same
details such as distribution ID, domain name,
CNAME, and origin, plus more.
Okay, the moment of truth.
Go ahead and open up a browser, toggle your Developer Tools,
and load www.dyrcz .me.
And there we go.
We can now see that it took less than 2 seconds to load everything.
Isn't it amazing how much of an improvement we can get by
setting up a CDN in front of our content.
Alright, there you have it.
We have a major success.
Just by setting up the CloudFront distribution,
we've seen our response times reduce drastically.
In the next videos, we'll discuss everything we just went through in much more detail.