When you create a distribution, you specify default caching behavior.
Behaviors are the real substance of your CloudFront distribution.
The simplest way to describe behaviors is that they are a set of
rules which are bound to an origin that define how CloudFront
handles and process incoming requests.
You can create as many behaviors as necessary.
This might be for path patterns, multiple origins,
forwarding query strings,
accessing secure objects through HTTPS or assigned URLs,
or setting specific TTLs.
Now here are just a few of the many possible elements that
we can define while creating a behavior.
The highlights to focus on are origin definition,
caching duration or TTLs, forwarding of cookies or query strings,
the HTTP request headers, file compression,
and encryption.
While there are many, many more,
we'll hit on those as we review our default caching behavior which
we set up when we first created our distribution.
If you go into the CloudFront service within the AWS Management console,
you should see your list of distributions.
I'll click on the distribution we created for our demo
app and then head to the Behaviors tab.
Here you'll find your default behavior.
You can define as many behaviors as necessary and you do that from this console.
Let's head into our existing default behavior to review what we have.
At the very top, we see path pattern.
This is where we define any path from our URI that
will need specific caching behaviors.
Since this is the default, it includes everything,
hence the wildcard after the word default.
For example, maybe you have some sort of Admin panel at example.com /adminpanel,
you might not want to cache those pages.
Since it's using the same origin,
you'll want to include a separate behavior defined where you
can configure to prevent caching that path.
From the last lesson, we should know what origin is now.
Viewer Protocol Policy is how we define how the Edge
locations handle the initial request.
The Edge locations can listen on both HTTP and HTTPS,
they could redirect an HTTP request to HTTPS,
or completely disable the HTTP listener opting in to
only listen for HTTPS requests.
Next, the Allowed HTTP Methods.
Option one will use CloudFront to get objects from your origin,
as well as headers.
Option two is the same,
but has the ability to list options that your origin supports.
If you enable options,
you will have the ability to optionally cache those headers as well.
Option three allows CloudFront to handle all of these methods.
This option will only be used if necessary.
like if viewers need to submit data.
On top of that, CloudFront will only cache the get, head, and options request.
All others are uncacheable.
The field level encryption goes hand in hand with option three
because it can help you protect sensitive data by encrypting
specific data fields that your viewers might possibly submit
through your applications.
By default, get and head requests are cached.
But if you chose option two under the allowed HTTP methods,
you can choose to make options request cached as well.
Cache Based on Selected Request Headers is a very important setting.
There are only three options,
but they can create widely different experiences based on what you choose.
None, while this option improves caching,
it does not listen to your origin's header values.
Whitelist allows you to specify the headers you want
CloudFront to consider when caching your objects.
This means any headers you choose to whitelist in the next field below,
CloudFront will respect their values from the origin and base caching on them.
If you choose the All option,
CloudFront won't cache any object that are associated with this behavior,
instead, it'll forward every request to your origin,
and as you can see,
I'm basing caching on host header right now as it's the
only one I'm currently whitelisting.
Within the Object Caching setting,
you can allow CloudFront to handle caching based on
the headers you whitelisted above,
but you still have the option to override them anyways and create custom TTLs.
These TTLs can be a little confusing to begin with.
We have minimum, maximum, and default.
Minimum and maximum are impacted based on how you
handle caching based on request headers.
Minimum, by default,
is set to 0 because if you whitelist or allow all request headers,
then CloudFront needs to pass requests directly to your origin,
therefore, the 0-second TTL.
Maximum works the other way.
Obviously, it means the maximum TTL for the object,
but it only applies when you add the cache control or
expires headers at your origin.
The maximum TTL's default setting is set to 31, 536, 000 seconds or 1 year.
Default is where you really can specify the TTL from CloudFront because
the default TTL only applies when you don't whitelist or you don't set
cache control or expires headers at your origin.
This setting defaults to 86, 400 seconds or 1 day.
Forwarding Cookies and Query Strings,
both of these options have a similar set of choices to
handling your origin caching headers, none,
whitelist, or all.
In regards to cookies, I think none and all are pretty self-explanatory.
Either you forward none of your cookies or you forward all of your cookies.
Whitelist allows you to specify which cookies you want
to allow to forward to your origin.
You won't need to use this if S3 is your origin unless you've
configured S3 to act as a website endpoint.
When whitelisting query strings,
you should choose this if your origin returns different versions of your
objects based on one or more query string parameters.
You can specify the parameters that you want CloudFront to
use as a basis for caching in the whitelist field that
appears when you choose this option.
Okay, only a few more options at this point.
Smooth Streaming is only used if you want to distribute media
files in the Microsoft Smooth Streaming format and you don't
have an IIS server to do so.
Restrict View Access is something we will go further
into detail in a later module.
For now,
just understand that this gives you the ability to restrict access
to a specific path pattern through signed URLs.
Now for me, Compressing Objects Automatically,
I don't understand why this one is not set to yes by
default with the option to turn it off,
but if you haven't compressed your objects at your origin,
if the visitor browser sends an accept encoding gzip request header,
then CloudFront will compress your content.
This makes downloads faster because the files are smaller
allowing your web pages to render faster.
The final configuration choice is associating lambda functions.
We'll go in depth in the next module,
but this allows you to specify a lambda at Edge function,
which can be triggered by any of the viewer requests to CloudFront.
And as you can see,
there are many options which allow us to create very specific
behaviors allowing CloudFront to respond exactly as we need to our
requests and interact with our origin.
By learning all these configurations,
you can really begin to understand how CloudFront can help us deliver your content faster and more securely.