Hi.
Welcome to the complete Android O developer course.
My name is Rob and I've taught over half a million people how to code with over fifty thousand five
star reviews.
You know you're gonna get a great learning experience with me and this course is my biggest and best
ever.
No coding experience is required and neither is any paid software.
You can run the course on any platform Mac Windows or Linux and we'll start at the very beginning.
Installing Android Studio Three on your machine will then go on to build basic apps like a currency
converter and a to do list app and we'll build up to more advanced apps including clones of Instagram
and Uber as well as games like Super Mario run and flappy bird.
But you get a lot more than just the best experience for learning Android available.
You get a year's free web hosting with my company eco web hosting.
You get a copy of my five star rated book How to earn ten thousand dollars by learning to code you get
one hundred dollars worth of a W s credit to store your social apps like Uber and Instagram and you
get over 500 dollars worth of visual assets to use freely in your apps.
So what are you waiting for.
Bring your coding career to life and join me on this exciting journey today.