Well congratulations you made it this far in the course.
I'm really proud of you.
Go ahead and give yourself a nice little pat on the back there because we've learned so much.
We covered two different programming languages.
Java and colonies should be very familiar with Java at this point and now you probably have a good grasp
on cotland and if you'd like to go further with that I'm sure you're going to have absolutely no problem.
You've learned so many different apps and how to make them.
We've covered topics like GPS yes Bluetooth data storage with an s q all database that was really awesome.
We've also learned how to make social apps.
We made the Twitter clone we made the Instagram clone.
I still have more for you if you'd like to go further.
We have some bonus content after that and that kind of leads me to the next point is you know where
do you go from here.
And like I said I have some bonus content for you.
Couple of other apps from a previous class that you can check out that a lot of that is still relevant.
But the bigger thing that I'd really like to emphasize here is that I think the best way for you to
grow and move forward from this point is to be working on your own apps if you have some idea for an
app that you've always wanted to make or you thought that would be really cool or maybe it's an app
that already exists but you just thought Ah if they would have done things this way I think it would
have been that much better.
I want you to pursue that go after your dream of making some out because when you're creating an app
you're drawing out the sketches for it and you're gonna have to figure out how to add all the different
features for it.
That's where the real learning takes place.
I know in my personal development journey that's when things really took off for me when I stopped doing
tutorials and I said I'm building this and I had to figure out how to do this.
For me that's where the real learning took place.
So again thank you so much for checking out this course.
Go ahead and look at the bonus content.
But please go attack those apps.
You can do it.