Hello and welcome to the lecture we're we're going to be learning how to create a picture and picture
functionality in our app.
I had a blast making this one I think Android has absolutely killed this with making this so easy for
developers and just a pleasure to use.
So the basic idea here is you have an app.
This is mostly intended for apps that are streaming video and you want to have that video streaming
you can kind of do this picture in picture and thing and have it in the bottom corner and still use
other apps but still of that video player.
So let's go ahead and start a new Android project and let's maybe just call this picture and picture
fun.
All right.
And we'll go ahead and create this.
We need to have the latest API 26 in order to do this so make sure you have that selected and we want
an empty activity.
So according to my understanding picture a picture was a thing in API 26 with TV devices but is now
officially available on mobile devices with Android which is pretty great.
So I do want to mention here I thought of a really cool cause I thought why would you want to do Picture
in Picture if you weren't going to be playing video.
And so I kind of was as I was messing around I thought about it.
And if you were someone who was super into stocks or at a cryptocurrency that you're like always watching
the price of bitcoin or something like that.
A pretty funny picture in picture app would be showing the price of bitcoin down in the bottom corner
so that no matter what app it is what ever you do in your life you can see to the second updates on
the price of bitcoin or your favorite stock whatever it is.
And I thought ha that's the situation when you wouldn't need video.
But also if you're that concerned about your investments and stuff you probably need to be checked into
a mental hospital.
So with this let's go ahead and talk about how we can implement this like I said I just think that it
was absolutely nailed by Android.
So let's go ahead and open up first the visual side of things.
We want to make it so that when our user hits a button they can make the app go into picture in picture
mode.
So what we're going to do is we're going to bring a button into our project.
We're going to have to wait a second here for Android studio to finish itself up.
Come on.
There we go.
And so I'm just going to take this button and I'm going to put it right below this other button or the
hello world that we have there.
I'm going to go and hit its upper constraint so it is connected to Hello World and will go down and
change the text of this button to say something like Go picture in picture mode.
OK.
So we've got that button.
It's connected to Hello World and I'll go ahead and get the emulator ready to rock and roll here because
that will take a little bit of time to set up.
So with this button let's have it have a proper ID here.
When I go back to android studio and while we are really lagging right now let's try this again.
We've got the button select that I'm going to call this Peepy button.
And if you don't know p p stands for picture in picture.
Now with this we want to go ahead.
Oh I need to set in on click for that button.
So the unclick Maybe I'll call this like go pee IP so well I'd like to do that but wow Android studio
right now is just crawling
K
I think it's just great or great will build that's killing us but we'll go ahead and set up the method
while we're waiting for that to load.
So we want public void and we'll call it maybe go pee pee.
We've got to take a view with this.
Let's make sure we hit enter on that so we get the proper view imported in our curly brackets.
So it's when the user hits this button wants to go to picture in picture.
This is when we want to get things set up so you will not believe this this is how easy it is to go
into picture in picture mode.
Are you ready for this.
You just type that and her picture in picture mode semi-colon.
That is it.
That is all you have to do.
So let's see we're still having beef with our little friend there but that's really all we need in order
to move forward.
So let's go back.
I think this is finally ready to cooperate with us.
I'm going to type this.
B go pee pee.
That's the name of our method that we have there.
And on our emulator you can see we have to go pee pee but it's not exactly centered so let's.
Right click and say hey you should be centered and let's try running that one more time.
Now that we got it in place so.
And then we'll be able to test out this Enter picture in picture mode.
Now I'm not sure why this is crossed out I got the message that this was deprecated but the research
that I did was showing that this was new to API 26 Not that it was deprecated and the functionality
is still completely there.
So I'm not sure why that's the case but everything was working for me.
So look at the button here is working.
And if we go ahead and click on this boom well says PKP has stopped.
Let's go ahead and see what problems we got going on here.
So this is the problem is that we didn't specify that this activity can handle picture in picture.
So not only do you have to do this you have to specify that you can handle picture and picture I guess
I oversold the simplicity of things are going to go into our Android manifest.
Well go ahead and open up that file and there's a few changes that we want to make inside of here.
And so let's go ahead and we want to with our activity here set a few options to say hey we can handle
this picture and picture stuff.
So one of them is going to be Android and we are looking for resizable activity.
So scroll down till we can find resizable activity.
There we go.
We want to set this to true.
Another option that we want to set here is the support picture in picture so we're going to Android.
Scroll down to our asses and say this supports picture in picture.
We're going to say that is true as well.
And then the last one that we want to do is Android and we want to do config changes and we want to
set this equal to a couple of things so one of them is going to be screen size and then we're going
to do a straight line and then say smaller screen size.
We also wanted to screen lay out another line and then say orientation.
So make sure when you're doing these this is part of the activity tag here for your main activity not
part of the application don't get it mixed up with these other ones have it down here with this.
But with those in place you should now see picture and picture work without things crashing.
You know hopefully I won't embarrass myself this time.
So Apple opens up.
I hit the button boom.
Look at that.
How cool is that.
Our little things showed up on there.
And if we click this it's going to give us the option to open it back up and we hit that again boom.
It shrinks down.
Now we have an issue here a couple of issues one is we have still the bar showing up there at the top
and for a second you could see the button but like nothing is clickable inside of picture in picture.
The only thing you can do is have it come back to life and so in fact I think we should make it so that
when we go to a picture in picture we get rid of this top toolbar we get rid of the button maybe for
fun we'll change the text here on the text view.
So let's go back I want to make sure a text view has an ID and yes it does text view.
So let's go into some coding.
Now we do get some information whenever we're trying to go into or out of picture in picture mode there's
a function that's called.
And so we're just going to type out here on picture and it should be the first one that pops up on picture
in picture mode changed.
So this will alert us whenever you know we are going into a picture and picture Moeder out of it and
the way that we can tell whether we're going in or out.
Is this is in picture in picture mode.
So we're going to do an if statement like this and we're going to check that is in picture in picture
mode.
And so it's in the top situation.
This is where we are saying we are going into a picture and picture and the situation here is that we
are going out of picture in picture.
And so those are the kind of two situations that are going into picture and picture.
Like I said we want to get rid of the button and we want to get rid of the toolbar there and also for
fun we should probably change the text so in order to do all those things we have to have access to
them.
So let's go ahead and first get access to our text view and to give this name of teks view and say this
is equal to find view by ID.
ID dot text view.
Excellent.
And let's get Also access to that button.
So I'm going to say i.p button is hard to find view by our idea.
P P button.
Ok so now that we have access to those two the first one is we want to just get rid of the button.
So we're going to set it's visibility to blank basically So we're going to say set visibility and we're
just going to type in capital in visible.
So that turns into view Capitol all caps invisible and that will get rid of it.
All right the next thing that we want to do is we want to get rid of the action bar up at the top so
we're going to say get support action bar dot and then we just want to do a hide going to say let's
get rid of this then just for fun let's go ahead and change the text for you.
Text I mean this is completely unnecessary.
But let's have it for example be like it was a Bitcoin thing right.
So this is going to show the price of bitcoin and so maybe will say Bitcoin just broke 10000 so I'll
have it be some random amount of bitcoin here.
Or go ahead and put that in.
So now when we're going to the picture in picture mode we're going to change the text we're going to
get rid of the action bar and get rid of that button and hopefully it'll be that much easier to read.
So we'll go ahead and run this I guess you could even want to this text you might look a little bit
small so you could change it so that it's going to be a little bit bigger so that people can read that
all the better.
But look we go ahead we hit that button boom.
I get that.
It shows us that price isn't that cool again.
This would be the weirdest app in the world but kind of a cool example since we don't have video to
play.
But you know we have one issue and that's when we come back to bring the full screen.
Well we no longer have the action bar.
We no longer have that button that says go into a picture and picture and I'd kind of like to change
this back to hello world.
So to do that you can probably guess we just need to reverse everything that we did here.
So I'm going to copy and paste this rather than invisible.
We're going to change this to visible rather than hide.
We're going to change this to show.
And rather than having this be some crazy Bitcoin dollar amount we're going to say hello world.
Again if you want to change the text size on things you could you know edit this text view to change
the font and whatnot.
But let's go ahead and run this and see if we can get this rolling.
OK.
So here comes the app.
We are going to go into a picture in picture mode that changed everything like just like we were hoping
for we hit it again to make it full screen and ah it brings back that button the top action bar.
Pretty awesome stuff.
So hopefully enjoyed learning about this again.
I just think it's so simple how all this works.
We just have to at some point call enter picture in picture mode.
We've got to have this function where we can you know handle some design changes we're moving in and
out and we have two on our Android manifest say which activities are allowed to do picture in picture
mode.
So there's all sorts of cool neat tricks that you can do to make it so that if you're in one particular
activity and someone hits the home button from there that it's you know saying oh they probably want
to have this go into picture in picture mode you can automatically do it without the user hitting a
button.
All sorts of fun stuff you can do but I just at least wanted to show you the basics here.
So I hope you enjoyed that.
Still got more to learn.