So in this lecture we're going to be talking about nullable.
And if you've ever worked with swift programming before this is the same concept as optionals.
I know this is in a couple of different programming languages but do want to go over here and we actually
do touch on this inside of one of the Android apps but I figure we've been rolling through you might
as well see what this is all about.
So any time you see question marks exclamation points inside of cotland that's usually because it's
dealing with a nullable in the basic idea is if I'm going to make something like a variable for my age
I set it equal to like 28 or something.
You know I should be able to change this as much as I want.
So all of sudden my age is now 45 but if you want to make this nullable this variable here nullable
that's so that you can eventually say something like age is equal to null and it's sort of your way
of saying it's equal to nothing.
And you might be wondering why like why would you do that.
Well we typically see it in functions where it's a way to say that you know something hasn't been set
up yet or maybe something went wrong.
There's all sorts of different situations for this.
But in order to make something nullable for example because this variable.
This is a variable if I want to make it a nullable variable I have to specify here that this is of type
int and then just simply put a question mark after it and then all of a sudden this code becomes valid
where I can say OK age is now equal to nil and I can sort of move on from there.
All right.
So you can make any type that you want nullable In fact you know if we end made like our dog class for
example and we go ahead and create a dog object var my dog I could specify that I want this to be a
dog nullable so that when I create a new dog object at some point if I want to say you know what dog
you are no longer existing I can set it equal to null.
That's totally valid.
OK.
So you might be wondering OK well how is this going to affect my code like what do I need to know in
order to work through this.
Well something to note here is let's say for example you want to turn something unknowable.
You can do that by saying age.
In this case which is knowable and then do two exclamation points after it and that's why if you're
saying I'm going to turn this into a non-nil I guess calling it non-nil assertion.
But you know just to kind of prove what's going on here if I say create a new variable called like new
number and I set this equal to age as I type.
Start typing out new number.
You can see over here that it's type isn't it.
Nullable but if I say age when I first set something into a new number if I do age exclamation point
exclamation point.
Now when I type out new number it's just a straight up and object so that's kind of how that can work.
You can unwrap neoliberals if you want to you know check and see if something is known or not.
Probably the most typical way to do something like this is you say all right if in parentheses age is
not equal to M. Then you can go ahead and then print the C's write some code and that's in this situation
that you're then safe to say something you know like Ades exclamation point exclamation point because
now you know for sure OK this thing is not equal to Nolte's when I put two exclamation points there.
I know for sure that there's an actual number inside of there and it's not equal to nil.
OK.
So those are the basics what I'm going to do for you is just provide a very simple challenge.
I really think you're going to want to see what Knolles in nullable stuff looks like in the quote unquote
wild as you program as we work through our different projects one example that I guess I'll show you
before the challenge here is let's say I make a dictionary or a map I keep referring to it as a dictionary.
Let's say you know the variable dogs map and I set this equal to map of and I'll provide something like
you know Feydeau to and then do that.
This is kind of an example we had earlier right.
So let's say I try and pull something out of this dog's map but I give it a key that doesn't exist like
I just try to pass and something like ABC if I go ahead in print what's going to come out of here.
You'll notice that it will be a no.
Because this is kind of a good example of that where you know and map says hey you pass me a key here
ABC that doesn't exist inside of this map so I'm not sure what to give you back so it gives back Noal
is sort of its way of saying that thing does not exist and you can really see this.
You know we put this into a new variable where we assume this would be something like the dog age you
know is equal to this.
If we check out the type of dog age you can see that is an innate nullable because it's saying I'm not
for sure if that you know is going to come through or not.
So that's kind of one I guess more concrete example that you can look to for that.
So my challenge for you here is I want you to make very simply a string nullable that's it.
I just want to make sure you know what the syntax is and can move forward so go ahead and do that now.
OK.
So hopefully that went well again.
All you got to do is take some sort of string and set it to be a nullable.
So I'm going to do like my fav candy which is equal to Snickers.
All right.
But let's say you know I want this thing to be knowable.
I can just say all right you know what.
This is going to be a string knowable and then it for whatever point let's say I'm going on some sort
of crazy diet where I don't eat sugar.
I can now all of a sudden say I don't have a favorite candy anymore because I don't eat that.
But hopefully that never comes for me because I love candy.
All right.
So that give you a nice little introduction into Nolla.
Again one more lecture here to talk about Cartland and Java.
How you could integrate it into an existing project.
And we'll talk about that in the next one.