The purpose of this lecture is to fix two keyboard issues.
So one of them is that we have this background space right.
Like when I tap on this white space the image here I'd like for the keyboard to disappear a little bit
frustrating that doesn't happen.
The other one is is that as I'm typing out the password I'd like to just hit the little checkbox down
here and have that automatically initiate the log in process which right now is not happening.
So the two things I want to fix so let's fix the problem first of you know if I have entered in the
password you know and I want to hit that checkbox that I can sort of complete and move on to doing the
log in or sign up process depending on which one is selected right.
So let's go into Android studio and we are going to have to implement something else here so after we
have implement view on click Lisner we are also going to implement capital view dot and we went on key
not inti on key Lisner this time.
Now we do this we're going to get a little bit of an air here because that saying hey you don't have
the right stuff and we need to add a new function here called on key and just go ahead and hit enter
on that.
And as soon as we do that that error will disappear up there then the code that we want to right here
is basically telling us you know hey when someone hits a key how do we want to handle this situation.
So before we dive into that code let's go down to our own create method here and sort of set up this
on key listener and we're going to do it for our password at Tech So we're going to come down here and
let's make sure we have our password techs at a place that we can get to it.
And we currently do not.
So for both these texting going to just copy this one paste it up above and we'll do the same thing
for a password here.
Copy that and paste it up above.
OK.
And we'll go ahead and say that now we can access these anywhere inside of the class.
So since we have that option now we bring out a special little code here that says OK with this password
edit text and realize in here that we probably need these in the uncreate so I'm going to cut this code
doing all sorts of moving around here but we'll add this code.
And now I can say all right passwords edit text.
I want to set in on the listener and the listener that I want to add is this.
And since we had added on key listener up here's something that this class implements we are then able
to move forward with the following function.
So a very simple if statement we want to provide here and it's basically just saying hey did they you
know is this the right key event here.
And so what we're going to check with is first into I.
This tells us what kind of key event it was.
And so we're going to check first and see if it is equal to.
Don't forget to equal signs.
Capital key event and that's key event dot.
And then all caps key you can see there's all sorts of things here.
Want key code underscore.
Enter.
OK.
So that's if they've hit the enter key.
So we're going to check that.
And we're also going to check for a key event and we want to get action from that.
That's another options that the passed inside of here.
We want to see if this is equal to the action down.
So we're going to say capital key event that action down.
So this is checking to make sure that is the you know return key the enter key that we have and that
it's being on the press down because this can be entered multiple times so if this is the case we want
to then run the code inside of this sign up clicked.
So we'll simply just type inside of here sign up clicked.
We're going to have a pass that a view which we have a view here so let's go ahead and throw that in
there and this should solve our first issue.
So we'll go ahead and run this on our emulator and see what that looks like.
So again we're trying to fix the issue that when we open the app when we're you know entering in the
information we should just be able to run everything from the keyboard there.
So looks like the emulator is going to take a second here there is a little bit of busy work that we
can do while that's running.
And that's that in the next portion.
In order to get access to this relative lay out in this image you have to give them some idea.
So with this play out remember I gave it the name lay out because I had accidentally mistaken this for
the text.
But anyways I'm going to call this background lay out.
Give that a proper ID there.
And I'm also going to select the image view and I can just call this maybe logo image view with I want
to make sure that we give proper names to those so then we can reference them in code.
So now with those two things in place we need to be able to access these in our code.
So we're going to get access to them in our on Create are going to add to all this code where we get
everything set up here so we need to get access to an image of you that we are simply just going to
call logo.
That means you will say this is equal to find you by id want capital art ID logo image view.
There we go.
The other one the one you want access to is that relative layout so we're going to say relative lay
out what is called background layout equal to or find view by id capital or dot ID dot background layout.
So we'll come and deal with these in a second.
It looks like your emulator has finished.
So let's see if this first part works or if I want to come into a user name maybe I can type like Nick
inside of here and if I hit this next button you'll notice automatically we get a come down of the password
which is pretty great but then you know let's say I go ahead and put in some sort of password or put
some jibberish and I hit this button.
Well now it comes out and says hey there's already a user account there and if I switch to log in and
you know I hit enter on this I got to make sure my cursor is there but if I hit that's going to say
oh invalid username and password so that's successful.
That part is working.
But now we want to make it so that if I tap in this white space or on the image view that we get the
keyboard to go away.
So in order for this to happen remember how we did the set on click listener for the log in text you
were going to do it for the image view and this relative lay up.
So just like we simply have above we're going to take first my logo image view and I'm going to say
Dot set and want to do on click listener.
There we go.
And I just want to pass and this will do the same thing with the background.
Lay out say set on click listener it'll pass in this.
So then it sort of alerting us about that.
Now once we've done this this function up here becomes a little bit more complicated in this on click
right so we do this check here to make sure we're working with the log in text view.
We're going to put in a situation here where we sort of want to say hey well if it's not that maybe
it's you know they've tapped on the background or they've tapped on that image.
So if that's the case we're going to run another statement here so whoever else if and what we're checking
for here is we're going to say All right let's get this view and we're going to get the ID and check
and see if this is equal to capital our DOT I.D. dot logo image view.
So I would tell us if it was equal to image view or we want to know if the same view get ID is equal
to our DOT ID dot.
And this is where we want to get our background way out.
So if it's equal to either one of these we know that they're trying the users trying to dismiss the
keyboard.
So we're going to use something called the input method manager.
So makes you go ahead and hit enter on that so you get the proper things imported.
And we're just going to call this an input method manager and say this is equal to get system service.
And the one that we're looking for is an all caps input method and service.
Look at that it pops right up.
So once we have this in place we've got to make sure that we cast this the correct way so you don't
have to go ahead and put in parentheses here.
Hey this thing coming back.
This is an input method manager but then on a new line we'll be able to say OK we're going to take this
input method manager and we're going to say hide soft input from the window.
And with that we're going to say get the current focus datt get window token and then we also are able
to pass on some flags we don't want to do anything extra special this will just close the keyboard for
us.
So go ahead and hit run.
Now you may be thinking man this whole lecture this was kind of some simple boring code nothing intricate
was going on here.
But it's these tiny small details that I think really makes an app for a user and if you know most apps
they're able to just hit that next button to get to the next field and then that final one to say log
in.
It's going to be a little bit frustrating if they try that and nothing happens so this just makes it
that much easier for them if they have a smaller device if they need to get to that.
You know get the keyboard to go down or whatever this is going to help them immensely.
So let's go ahead and test this out.
Right so I guess I don't have to click here to get the sophomore keyword to come up and if I now click
elsewhere boom look at that goes away even on the image it's showing up.
And I'll just hit this next key.
I'll do some sort of password switch that's logging when I hit that button look invalid username and
password.
So we know that that's working.
OK.
We'll go ahead and cover more in the next lecture.