All right.
So now that you have a good grasp on Copland right we need at least know the basics that are going on
here.
It's time to move over and talk about how do we take these skills that we learned in cotland and then
apply them to Android studio.
So let's go ahead and open up Android studio now.
We're you're first going to just create a new project in cotland we're going to talk about how we can
convert things with colleges just all sorts of bits and bobs here.
So go ahead and get Android studio opened up and here we want to just create a new Android studio project.
So this is going to be just kind of a test funded app for this let's just go ahead and call this cotland
fun maybe.
And now the big thing is come down and make sure that you have include Cartland support check.
That's the big thing that we're trying to do here.
So I'm going to make sure I get this saved in the proper location.
There we go.
I want that slash Tolland.
Fun.
Good with that then go ahead and select what you want here.
I'm going to go with the latest and greatest API 26.
And I want an empty activity and we'll just do the main activity there
soon known as this looks a whole lot like our old stomping grounds.
Maybe just a little bit slightly different with the column but I'm going to walk you through all of
that here in just a second.
So we'll wait for this to come through.
It Right you can do it.
Android studio we believe in you.
That's something I really like about a Tele.
It's a little bit more thinned out you know more specific on what it's folky not focused on.
And it just goes a little bit quicker I think.
So here you can see a lot of things look pretty similar right.
Like when we have this on create function the same things are coming through but it's going to be just
a little bit different here whenever we're going to work with code.
So let's go ahead and go to our lay out file here and you know let's walk through the process of how
do we bring something from here into our code.
I think you'll find that to be kind of interesting so we'll give this a moment to load up there and
here we go.
We've got a text view.
So let's go ahead and make some changes to this text view song and give this the name of text for you
just like that.
That will come back to our main activity and we're going to say you know what we want to create a new
text for you and before you know we had always done something like say text view and then you know give
it the name text you.
But in this case you know we would want to create a variable so we would say something like var text
view and we're going to say this is going to be equal to.
And then we'll do our find view by id and we are looking for a text view.
So that's what we should anticipate coming back to us and we'll still do our classic our DOT I.D. dot
and this is where we would find our text view.
Excellent.
And boom all of a sudden we have a text field right.
Just like we had before and let's say you want to set something inside of this right text view.
Set text.
And we can do that and just put in a string like hello.
Fam we'll do something a little different than Hello World so we can just prove that this is working
and I'm so used to doing something Colon's look I'd put a semi-colon there when it didn't even need
to be.
So let's go ahead and just test this out.
I know this is a simple app but let's just confirm and see if this is working.
So go ahead and put this on one of our devices here.
So we're finally finished building here.
And look at that.
It's a work of art.
Hello Pham.
Again very very simple app here.
But I want you to just to kind of get used to this whole feeling of looking at something in cotland.
And so to sort of get used to that I'm going to give you a little challenge here.
I want you to make a counter app so this is sort of similar to something that we're going to build later
when we're going to be talking about Android Wear.
But the basic idea is I want you to make an app where you can add a count button that's going to add
plus one to a counter and a reset button.
So maybe you're counting the number of people that come into the museum or you're counting the number
of birds fly by your window.
I don't know what it is but you won't have a text view in the middle of the screen.
A button that's going to add things and then a button that will reset the counter.
So that's my challenge for you try and do that all in cotland.
Good luck.
OK so hopefully that went well for you.
Let's go ahead and work on the visual side of things first.
Again this shouldn't be too challenging for you.
At least you know Android wise we know how to do all this stuff is just making sure we can get it done
in cotland.
So we're going to put a button a little bit below the text few here.
Going to go ahead and connect it to that and I'm going to change its name to say plus one.
So that's where we're going to use to count up.
Also bring a button above our Hello world here.
Connect it down to that text for you and I'll make it 31 just like the other one so that we have some
consistency.
And this is going to be a reset button.
OK.
So the on click for the reset button here is going to be reset and the click for the plus one is going
to be plus one.
Yeah I know.
Who would have guessed these crazy function names.
But with that in place we're going to go ahead and create our new function.
So we're going to say function and we're going to call this reset.
We'll go ahead and do our parentheses and we need to take in something called a view with a capital
view here.
Go ahead hit enter on that for the import and then we'll go ahead and do our curly brackets.
So with this now in place that's the reset.
We also need to make a function for when we get the plus one we'll do plus one then we're going to take
in the view there go do our curly brackets and I like them with spacing you can do without kind of up
to you.
The real goal of this app is to be able to count something we've got to keep track of that count somewhere.
So I'm going to create a new variable as a property up at the top which I'm going to call count and
we're initially just going to set that equal to zero.
Then when someone wants to reset we'll take this count and again set that equal to zero.
But then we want to update the text view.
So we'll take a text view and say set text and inside of here we're going to take our count and this
is so cool with Cartland.
Look at this we do count two string.
It's that easy.
All of a sudden now we can display the count inside of the text view.
And what happens inside of the plus one.
Well let's say we want to do count plus plus then we want to update the text for you again.
We can just copy paste that right inside.
So let's go ahead and give this a roll.
I guess one thing that we should change here is we should have the starting text for hello world to
be zero.
Go ahead and fix that real quick.
And with that in place let's go ahead run this if it gives us a chance to we might just have to look
like how it is as soon as we hit reset.
It's going to go back to zero.
So just know the changes that we made will work and I'm going to show you a thing in a second here and
we forgot to center a button so that looks really tacky but we hit reset.
Look that goes to zero.
But now I can hit this button as many times I want and I can reset that goes back to zero.
So functional up pretty cool right.
Style wise few things that I do want to change this button.
I want to make sure that this is centered song and right click center horizontally again here and then
right click center horizontally and the next thing is I really want to beef up the size of this text
view.
And so we're going to go inside of the detailed attributes and let's scroll down to our friend here.
And for text size Let's go ahead and beef this up to something like 40 maybe even 60.
Let's go a little bit crazy here.
So that looks good to me.
Now something that I want to show you here that will hopefully blow your mind and just make cotland
that much cooler is we've been setting the text what I consider to be quote unquote the old school way.
It's kind of the retro way whereas you know count here this is shown sort of showing the new way that
we can do things in cotland So instead of saying here set text to hello fam we can do text view dot
text and simply just access text attribute and say this is equal to hello fam or something like that.
Right.
Like this is all it takes.
So again here when we're setting the text view to the count we can just say text few text is equal to
count two string.
It's that simple.
There's no need to keep putting things in parentheses like.
I don't know about you but I think this is so much more readable than this.
I mean even in cotland This makes it even more easy to check out in C but it's just one step further
and I just think wow this is you know so much cleaner so I'm going to go ahead and copy this pace that
there we actually don't want this to say hello fam when we start.
Let's have that beat zero and we'll go ahead and run this one more time just to prove that we can make
things work in this new way.
So we'll go ahead and run this
way for our app to pop up here and look at this so we can add up these numbers hit the reset button
goes back to zero.
We are in a great place hopefully starting to see not only was it fun learning about the principles
of cotland but we can do some awesome stuff with our Android programming and I still got more to show
you.