In this lecture we're going to be talking about a really interesting topic which is how we can get a
watch and a phone to talk back and forth with each other and it is simpler than you think it might be.
In fact I think Android has done a great job with this.
I've worked on the iOS side of things with how to communicate between iOS app and an Apple Watch app
and I think this is much much cleaner.
So props to Android for this.
So let's go ahead and start a new project.
You can go ahead and call this whatever you like.
I'm just going to maybe call this watch and phone fun and we'll go ahead and hit next here.
Now the important thing here is this is something you know sort of new that we haven't done before.
We're going to have both a phone app and we're going to have where apps are going to put both of these
API I-26 just to have the latest and greatest on both.
And this will be interesting you'll see here first it's going to ask us what activity you want for the
phone side of things and I'll say empty activity that seems fine.
Then it asks also for the ware app.
You know what do you want there and same thing.
I just want blank activities ready to rock and roll.
So we'll go ahead and move forward with that.
And unfortunately this is going to be another situation where we can't really test this out on the emulators
to see what it would look like.
You have to have an actual Android Wear device in order to do that but we'll get pretty far here with
walking through the code and if you were to run this it would work.
So let's go ahead first we're going to start on the watch side of things so we're going to go to your
main activity that is included here for that extends wearable activity because this is where the basic
idea here is that we'd have some piece of information that we want to send from the watch to the phone.
So let's say on your watch you know you had selected a friend maybe from that friend list that we had
done earlier.
Right.
So let's say you have a string here that we're going to call friend and this is equal to Bob or something
like that.
OK.
So we have a friend Bob that has been selected on the watch.
That's what we're just kind of setting up here and we want to send this to the phone app.
Well how do we do that.
So it's going to be through something called a put data map request and let me just go ahead and walk
you through how to create one of those.
So we're going to make a new put data map request just like that and we're going to give it some sort
of name I'm going to call it just lower case put data map request simple enough I'm going to say this
is equal to in capital.
Put a map request and then we're going to do dot create and then this is kind of interesting and you
can create directories where you want to be storing this information.
So if you hadn't that that did a lot of different things like you might want to have a directory for
images one for data and one for you know X-amount whatever it is that your story in there.
But in this case we're just going to have one general one called data so we're just going to do a forward
slash data just like that.
OK.
So this is saying we're making this new put data map request and we want to save it at a location in
a directory called data.
So once we have that there we're going to take this put data map request and we're going to say get
data map dot put string and you can see there's all different types that you could add onto here ints
floats strings longs bytes.
But in this case we just want to put a string.
So first you have to give a name to what it is that you're trying to save.
So this we would probably say something like a lowercase friend and then we would provide the actual
friend string which in this case is Bob.
So we'll go ahead and pass that in there.
Once we've done that then we're going to create a put data request so that you can see it's mid in the
map there but we're going to say put data request that we'll just call this put data request equal to
put data map request dot as put data request.
So it kind of does some conversion from a map request down to this put data request and if you're wondering
why this is the case.
Well this is what the Android where documentation told us and so we're just following their orders with
this when we go ahead and send this information we want to have it come forward as something called
a pending result.
And so we're going to say pending result.
And this is going to be of a particular data type here and that is capital data API.
So go ahead and hit enter on that dot data item result.
Okay.
So go ahead and call this pending result.
I will say this is equal to capital.
Where will dot data API not put data item and we are going to get something called a Google API client
which we have to create.
So we're going to take a quick pause here.
We're going to go up to the top where we have this text view which we're not really currently using
but I don't think it's worth it to even delete it at this point.
We're going to make a new Google API client and this is really what allows us to do the communication
between the two devices and we'll just call this lowercase Google API client and we're going to pass
in this Google API client that we have let's say lower lowercase Google API client and then we're going
to add this put data request.
So go ahead add that in there and that allows us to then send that information.
Now in order to do this there's a few things that we've got to do with the class that we have.
So after we extends wearable activity we're going to say this class implements we're going to do first
data API dot data Lisner that's one that we want to add in there do a comma the next one is a Google
API client dot connection callbacks There we go and we'll do Khama one more to add here.
Google API client dot on connection.
Oh forgot my capital on connection failed listeners so that's in case things didn't work out.
So with all these things in place we're going to get this red air.
But if we go ahead and hover over this with this light bulb we can say hey go implement the methods
for this we'll go ahead and hit OK there and you can see we get all these awesome results here that
say whenever and these basically tell us hey when their connection has started when it's lost if it's
failed or when we start getting some data or stuff.
These are functions that we can use to kind of maintain the communication between the two devices.
So this is going to right now we're only simulating you know sending data from the watch up to the actual
phone.
But this is going to get us to a great starting place.
So with this we still have an air here and that's because we actually have the wrong pending result.
In fact if we go up here to import and we go ahead and look at this is in the broadcast receiver We
just want to go ahead and delete that and we're going to change this to be just a pending result.
And we've got to make sure now as we type out this pending result we want to get the one that comes
here from the Compaq Google Android long list there.
So make sure you have that in place and that should get rid of your.
Now with this all in place this will be able to send the information and we can have some awesome communication
with the phone here.
But we want to do essentially the same thing over on the phone side so I'm going to copy all this code
that we did for the implements and we'll go ahead and copy that and come now to the actual phone device.
Then after we do the extends we'll go ahead and say OK there now we've implemented that and we're going
to get the same error here saying hey you've got to you know implement these methods all say OK implement
methods and that's going to go at the appropriate methods there for us.
Now in order for this phone app to listen to the watch for any information that's coming through we
have to set up a Google API client just like we had done earlier.
So we're going to set up a Google API client the world's called Google API client here inside of her
and create.
We're going to set up some listeners and different things here so to say Google API client is equal
to new capital Google API client.
And with this we don't want a hole that we just cut here.
So let's go ahead and say we want the new Google API client and then dot builder.
And this is where we're going to set this up so we're going to first pass in this next thing after that
is we're going to do dot and we want to add an API so the API we're looking for is the wearable stuff
so we're going to say wearable DOD API just like that.
Then we're going to say Dot add connection callbacks.
There we go.
And we're going to pass in this for that we're basically saying look to this class for all your information
like when you get back information send it here.
And again we're going to have to add an add on.
Connection failed listener.
We want that to be this and then we'll do a build.
OK.
So if you wanted to get all this information back on the watch device you would have been sending that
up inside of uncreate there.
But in this situation we're just trying to send it over to this activity.
So we'll get all of this set up in place and then we're going to come down and implement some functionality
on these methods.
So there's a few things to set up here.
The first one really is just that in this unconnected if this is all working then we want to set up
our listener.
This is when it first connects with the watch device.
So we're going to go ahead and say wearable dot capital data API.
And listener and inside of here we want to pass in that Google API client and we also want to pass in
this.
So it's saying hey we've made a connection.
Now we're going to be listening for any data and it's up to us inside of this on data changed method
to then take the appropriate data and handle it accordingly.
So you'll see what we get from this is a data event buffer.
So we're going to use this to turn it into some actual data.
So first thing that we're going to do is a for loop where we can go ahead and move through everything
inside of that data buffer.
So we're going to say for data event and we'll go ahead and call this just an event.
Colon data event buffer this will go ahead and loop through all the data that we're getting now we're
going to say if set up if statement here if event get type is equal to capital data event dot an all
caps type changed.
OK.
So to say if you know we have some sort of new data we want to know about that.
We're going to create a new data item and we're going to simply call this item and this is going to
be equal to an event dot get data item.
So with that in place we'll go ahead and do an if statement here and the next thing that we want to
be checking for is to make sure that this information is coming from the correct path.
And so remember here when we said you know we want to do this in the slash data directory.
That's all we're going to confirm here.
So we're going to say item not yet you are I dot get path as we go.
Compared to how we're going to pass in our slash data just like we had done on the other activity and
see if this is equal to zero.
So if this is the case this means we actually have some data there and we can now go ahead and create
a data map which will just call lower data map and this we can get that data map by saying Capitol data
map item data map item dot from data item.
We're going to pass in our item and then we'll see it get data a map.
So a lot of work here but that eventually gives us this data map which then we can simply say lower
case data map dot get.
And you can see we can get bite's booleans double's floats.
It's just like you know we could have set them before but we can also get a string.
So we're going to get a string for the term friend.
OK.
So if we do that we could then you know put this inside of a new string.
We could say you know something like string friend is equal to this and then we're free to use friend.
However it is we would like.
So we'll just kind of leave a comment here that says Use friend.
So there you have it.
This is the full steps that you need in order to take something from your where device here like the
string Bob.
You go ahead and get it inside of this data request and we send it out comes over here because we've
set up this Google API client and we set up all these listeners once we have a connection we add that
and then we can go ahead and sort of breakthrough and get that information.
So a little bit wordy with all the information that we've got to put out.
But essentially once this is here we now have open communication between the two devices.
OK.
So I hope you enjoyed learning about that.
We have covered a lot here with Android Wear but still a little bit more to cover.
So let's keep moving forward.