Now that we've learned how to add videos to our apps let's do the same thing with Odeo.
So as usual we'll start a new project and we'll see that the process for working with sound is very
similar to working with video.
But we do have a little bit of extra flexibility built in which we'll use to create our own buttons
to control the audio while that's setting up.
Let's just download a sound effect to use within our app there's loads to play online when you can get
free sound effects.
I'm going to use sound byte build at home.
If that was not available when you're watching this video just Google for free sound effects and you'll
find a bunch of options.
I'm going to look for this Mobbles clip here.
And I just use quick flash to listen to it.
And there it is
wonderful and it's downloaded as well.
It's right there has a wav file.
You can get it as an MP 3 as well.
Either will work fine.
I'll stick with the wave file.
Ok so to add the file to our app works in exactly the same way as it does with video.
So it's open the resources folder in Finder or Windows Explorer
create a new folder called roll and then just simplify the phone name a bit.
Drag that into the roll fold up again if it doesn't update just right click and synchronize.
OK.
Now unlike the video player there's no actual visual component to the audio player by default.
It just plays in the background.
So all we need to do is write a couple of lines of code in the uncreate method.
And we'll start by setting up a media player.
Which will call media player and this is going to be set up purely to create our one sound effect.
So Media Player don't create and the context again is this app I guess and we want to create a sound
effect for our roar.
I forgot what I call that Mobbles.
That's it.
And then the location of the resorts are taught.
Roar taught Mobbles and just a note it might come up with an error here.
I've actually just waited five minutes or so for it to detect the wrong folder because the roll was
coming up in red.
It didn't detect it so I just ran the app and then it worked fine.
So if you have that problem that it doesn't detect the roll folder just complete the app run it and
hopefully that'll fix the issue for you then to make it play.
We just use Media Player don't start.
Simple as that.
So two lines of code to run some audio in your app.
Let's give it a listen.
Hopefully you heard those lovely Marples there.
OK.
So super simple but of course what we don't have is any kind of interaction with the audio unlike what
we did with the video.
So with audio we have to create our own system to control
our sound.
So let's do that now.
We'll get rid of the text few more drag in a couple of buttons.
We would just give them some
constraints so they don't move all over the place.
When we run the app so we'll have a play button
which will run the play method.
I also have a pause button
running the pause method.
OK.
So a quick challenge for you.
Can you reconfigure the code so instead of playing the media at the start it plays it when you press
the play button.
Go for it.
All right.
How you manage that.
It's really just a matter of creating the play method and moving the code into let's say public voyde
doesn't return anything.
Methods could play.
It's called by a view that is the button
and this is the code that we need.
To play our sound simple as that.
Let's give it a quick go.
OK so we'll press play and then we have
notice you can actually create several instances of the sound playing over each other.
That can be quite handy if it's a game or something and you want the sound to play over and over again.
But if you play music you might not want that behavior.
So you might need to adjust for that.
All right.
I'm going to hit the pause button as a challenge as well to see if you can work out how you would set
the pause button to pause the sound there for it.
All right.
Have you managed it.
You may have spotted that there's a method inside the media player class called Paws.
That's the method that we want.
The trick is to connect to the media player but that's fairly straightforward today.
We'll create a method called Pooles
called by the other button and we just need to use media player or pause but we need to be able to access
the media player.
So the trick is to take the media player out of the play method and define it inside the main activity
class.
So we can create it.
They're just an empty variable.
And then set it up on play.
And now we can use Media Player pause to parse it but can you see what error that might cause.
To just put it that if someone presses pause before they press play this will actually cause the app
to crash because the media player is simply an empty object to them.
There's nothing to pause.
So the way I'd get round that would be to set up the media player in the on create method.
So that set up when the is open and then the pause button would do anything.
But it also would break
the app which is the behavior you want.
So now the media player button is created in the class itself.
It's set up in the create method.
It started in the play method and it's paused in the pause method.
So let's take a look.
Did you hear that.
Hopefully say
comply and then pause stop it play starts again.
OK.
There's a few other options there so feel free to play around with those options.
But we're going to stop it for this video in the next video.
We'll look at how to control volume and that will involve bringing in a new interface element that we
haven't used before.
The slides.