All right it's time to learn a new skill and it's all coming around the idea that basically every app
that we've made is a one screen app nothing ever moves to a different page or does anything else just
sort of all on one screen and that's been fine.
We've been able to build some really cool stuff.
But if we want to take our app abilities to the next level we're going to have to be able to move onto
some new screens and have multiple screens.
And so in the Android world a screen is called an activity so when you're moving from screen to screen
those are you're moving from one activity to another.
So let's go ahead and learn how we can do that.
We're going to start a new project and let's just call this multipole activity demo and we'll go ahead.
Hit next on this.
We just want the empty activity to start out with.
Now of course we're going to show you how you can add your own after this but you know we've got to
start at least with a blank one or go ahead and wait for Android studio to finish up here.
I mean if you think about it it's actually quite impressive how much we've been able to do with just
stain on one activity.
And now once we have this in place.
I mean the world just really really opens up here.
As far as potential apps that we can do.
So step number one is we've got to go add a new activity to our app so to do that.
Go ahead and go up here to file and you want to go to we want to go to new and we are really waiting
on Android studio here.
There we go.
File new.
And then we want to come down here to activity.
So there's all sorts of different activities that we can add if you'd like to see them all.
I recommend just clicking on gallery here so you can see what your different options are.
So go ahead and pick this up again.
All sorts of stuff look there is that cool Google Maps one that we had worked with earlier.
So nice little starting points if you're going to be adding ads a full screen thing.
In our case we're finally just an empty activity so let's go ahead and select that one.
Then it's time for you to choose a name for your activity so typically the first activity you're in
your app is called The main activity so I wouldn't recommend naming the change changing the name of
your original activity that's the one that's already there.
But for this one main two is not a good name for your next activity you should describe what's going
on.
So in this simple example we just want to move from one activity to the other.
So I'm going to simply call this segment activity.
I know pretty weak sauce here but I just you know it should be descriptive of what it is and having
the named main If it's not the first one probably not a good idea.
So go ahead and hit finish here as that will add that to our app.
So you'll see now we have the main activity and we also have the second activity so it's nice that we
have two these now also if we go into our resources and lay out you can see we have lay out files for
each of these.
So that's pretty cool.
And let's talk about you know so how are you going to make it so that we can move from one activity
to the next.
So we've got to start paying attention paying attention to names here.
Let's open up our activity main and not to be confused with activity second.
Right.
That's for our second activity.
So an activity mean we have to have some way to let the user say that they want to move on to the next
one so let's just add a button to that that's going to be a really simple button.
In fact let's just right click this puppy and just center it both horizontally and vertically so that
that way it'll just be right there in the middle and we'll change the name to say go to next.
All right.
And then with this button let's go ahead and give it a click name we'll say maybe you just call it go
to next.
Probably seems fine.
It's all copy that text.
Once we have that in place now we have to write the code for when the button is tapped to go to the
next activity.
So we'll go up here.
We've done this a million times I'll just say public void and we'll paste in that name go to the next.
And now we can run some code whenever that is tapped.
So the way to move from one activity to the next is using something called intent.
The intent basically triggers this whole process.
OK I was in this activity and now I'm moving to the next one so let me go ahead and type it out and
hopefully you can learn from this example.
So we're going to say capital intent.
All right.
And I'll just call this intent.
So this is going to be equal to a new capital intent.
Now there's a couple of things that we've got to pass in here so the first one is the context so let's
just go ahead and say get application context.
The next one is the class that you want to move to.
So in our case we want to go to second activity right if we go ahead and click on this file.
This is a public class called second activity whereas then the main activity that class is called main
activity so let's just go ahead and type the name of this one where it's going to be second activity.
And then after second activity want to say Doc class because we're saying that's the class that we want
to move to.
And so we're not going into a specific instance of that class we're just going to that class.
Okay so that's all it takes to make an intent but this is only making the intent this is saying this
is what I would want to do but to actually make it happen.
We have to call a separate function where we're going to say start activity and you can see it's looking
for an intent.
So if we pass an intent in there boom that's going to move us from our first activity to the next.
So let's go ahead and hit run on this.
Well my app finally opened up but I realized I had a big year here I forgot to go to next function to
put in the view parameter.
We'll go ahead and add that in and that's going to fix our deadly air that we had before.
It was funny I hit the button and all of a sudden everything just went bad it exited out of the app.
But anyways we should be good now.
All right.
So app opened up.
Let's go ahead and tap on this button.
Look at that.
It moves onto the next activity so it's pretty cool.
Here is that in Android you have your back button right so if we just go ahead and hit this that takes
us back to the privacy right so we can just hit this button and go back just like that.
So this now gives me the opportunity to present you a challenge.
I want you to make it so that when I open up the app and my goodness we lost the app or to go here to
want pull There we go.
So I want you to make it when you hit this button goes to the second activity we've already finished
that.
But then I want you to add a button to this screen so that when we hit that button it will automatically
take us back to the other screen.
OK.
So that's my challenge for you.
Go ahead.
Hit pause now right.
Hopefully that went well for you.
So it takes a couple of steps you're the first one is to dive into the ex-MIL for the visual side of
this activity so pretty cool that we get to see that we're going to keep it real simple here by just
adding a button.
And again just centering this thing horizontally and vertically and we'll call this maybe go back.
All right.
And that's probably a good name there.
Go back.
OK.
So then we'll go to our second activity that Java Java.
Did I say Jabba the Hutt dot Java.
There we go.
So we're going to say public voyde go back in which we take in capital view and will do lowercase view
on our curly brackets.
So there's a couple of ways to handle going back so one of them if we just use the knowledge that we
had before where we say capital intent right we can do this and say we're going to make a new intent
and we're going to pass in here and get application context and then we'll just write the name of this
main activity.
So main activity class room.
We now have an intent and then we just need to say start activity and I'll pass in that intense and
that will do it again.
So go ahead and do that.
Well hit around here
get our emulator up here so we can see how this all works.
All right.
So we'll hit the button.
Now we have this button if we tap on that.
Look at that.
We can go back.
So the one thing that I want you to see here though that's a little bit freaky about this is so let's
say I've opened the app and you might have just seen it here.
I hit go to next and I hit go back and then I say go to next and I go back I mean we could just do this
forever but when the user hits the back button you know it keeps going forward and backwards because
we've essentially piled a bunch of intense on top of each other so eventually it finished up there.
But you would hope that if you hit go to next and then you hit go back that you would think oh if I
hit the back button it will take me back to like the android devices homescreen.
But now it takes you back here and takes you back there.
So the other possibility if you're moving backwards you're not doing an intent forward you're simply
just saying hey go to wherever I was previously.
Let me go ahead and just comment this out for a second.
You can very simply just go ahead and type finish.
OK.
So we'll say finish here.
Go ahead and check out this piece of code
again this is in the second activity.
Right because we're just saying we want to go backwards so we hit go to next.
And now when I hit go back it still takes us back to the home.
But if I hit the back button Well it just takes us out.
So up to you about how you want that functionality to work I think from a user's perspective if you're
going to be providing a back button that it's probably best to just go ahead and.
Well number one let the user just use the back button of the devices have a back button for a reason
that's probably the most intuitive for the user.
But if you're going to have a button I will go ahead and use this finish function if you're moving backwards.
But of course if you're going forward you've got to provide an attempt to say where it is that you want
to go.
Now a very common thing that people want to do when they move from one activity to another is they want
to pass along some information.
So let me show you how we can do that with an intent.
You have the ability to add something called an extra that gives a little piece of information or I
guess a bigger piece of information if you want to that as you go forward and you simply just type out
the name of your intent.
So we called ours and temp kind of boring name.
We'll just say intent.
Put extra.
And then this allows us to pass whatever it is that we want.
So I mean the first thing that we have to provide is the name of the extra.
So in this case let's say I want to pass forward my age so I'm going to put age inside of here.
OK.
So that's our first parameter then you can see you can pass through a boolean byte char short and long
float double string.
I mean there just a jillion things that you could pass through here.
So let's maybe just pass through an right because we're passing through age so I'm going to go ahead
and pass in twenty eight.
That's my age and now that can be accessed on the second activity and you might be wondering how do
we get access to that.
Well here inside of our create method right.
This is the function that gets called when our activity opens up the first time we can get the information
by going ahead and typing out k we want to get the activity so the first thing that we got to do is
we've got to get access to the intent.
So if you just type get intent that gives us back the current intent that got us here.
So I'll just use capital intent and call that intent and say this is equal to that then with this intent
to object we can go ahead and grab the extras out of there.
So instead of saying put extra We are going to say get.
And then you have to specify what type it is that you want.
So if I want an end I have to say get indexed if I wanted a string I would say get string extra.
In our case we wanted that song I say get it extra and we have to provide the name of what it is that
we're looking for.
So we're going to go ahead and provide a name there and if we go back to the name that we had used was
age.
So we'll just do lowercase age in there and let's put this inside a variable so I can say it.
Age is equal to this guy right here.
Now when you're working with getting an extra you'll notice there's the option here where you have to
set the default value so if that's for some reason you know it didn't come through or whatever so just
go ahead and put zero for there.
But just to confirm that this information came through.
Let's go ahead and make a toast message.
So we'll go ahead and say that make text and inside of here we'll pass this and then intent dot.
Well we already have access to the age so then we just have to turn this into a string so will say integer
to string and we'll provide age right inside there.
Then the last thing that we need to provide is whether it's going to be long or short so just say capital
toast length short and also a show on the end of this and do the semi-colon.
OK.
So hopefully we should be able to get the age of 28 to pass through and have that show up in a toast.
Let's go ahead and run this on the simulator and make sure that that's the case.
So let's go back to the home screen here.
Opens up.
I say go to next and look at that the number twenty eight passes through.
Awesome stuff.
OK.
So that brings us to the next part of the lecture here where I have a little bit of a challenge for
you and simply put I want it to be a little bit more than just hitting a button and having it show up
I want you to take the concepts that we've learned from being able to pass information and do the following.
So I want to add a list view to your app here in the main activities are going to go back to the main
activity here.
OK.
In this main activity I want you to do a list view of some friends and when someone taps on one of your
friends it should go to the next activity and it should show a text message saying whoever you tapped
on.
Right.
So list out some friends make it so when someone taps on one of those it shows that their name in a
toast in the next activity.
All right.
Go ahead.
Hit pause do that now.
All right.
So hopefully that went well for you.
And of course in order to do this we're going to start first visually we're going to get rid of this
button which then means we've got to go back to our main activity we're getting rid of this whole go
to next things will go ahead and delete that then we'll go back to our main activity and we need a list
view.
So we're going to go to our layouts and excuse me not our layout see a list view there.
So there it is List view must be in containers.
So go ahead and bring this out.
We want to fill the whole screen it looks like it's doing pretty good.
I might just hit the plus buttons here and just kind of confirm Yeah that's what we're looking for.
I'm going to give this idea of list view.
Very boring but we're just trying to get to the point here.
So here inside of our Creator I want to get access to this list views on the set list view and I'll
simply call it list view is equal to find view by id capital art ID dot.
You can.
So now we have access to our list view.
The next thing that we need is an array list of all of our friends.
So I'm going to type out a re list and I want this to be an array of strings because it's just going
to hold the names I'm going to call this friends and I'll say that this is equal to a new array list
which should also be of a bunch of string objects and we don't put anything in there to start.
But then with this we've got to add some friends inside of there so I'll say friends got ADD and let's
go ahead and maybe put our friend Fido in there and I'll copy.
We've got to have a little bit of a list of friends so maybe let's have four friends in total so of
Fido Sean Sarah and Jane Jane.
So those are going to be the four friends that we have now.
Those are out in there we need to create an array adapter so go ahead and type out a re adapter and
we want to specify that this should have the name of array adapter.
Well set the sequel to a new array adapter and then here we want to provide this as the context.
Then we have to specify We just want the simple list item so lowercase Android
it and then we want capital are not way out and we just want simple list item one.
There we go that's a long one to type out and then we have to provide the array lists all do friends
right there.
So now we've got this Bawler array adapter and then we've got to connect it with the list view.
So we'll go ahead and say list view set adapter and we'll go ahead and pass in this array adapter so
that should be able to show a list view of all of our friends.
But now this is sort of where the real magic happened so this is kind of the core of the challenge that
I had for you is that that is when someone taps on one of these friends we want to be able to do an
intent move on to the next activity.
So we're going to set it on click listener.
So we'll say list view.
Set on item click listener.
So this we need a new adapter view on item click listener and boom.
Look at that.
It gives us this awesome on item click method.
So inside of here we want to create that intent.
So again just capitol intent I'll call this intent.
And this is equal to a new intent.
Now we got to go ahead and get the application to lower case or get application context.
Next thing that we're looking for inside of here is where is it that we're moving to.
So I'm going to say second activity class and boom we've gotten intent.
So with this we want to go ahead and pass forward some information.
Remember we want to pass what friend it is that their name was selected so we'll take this intent and
we'll say put extra.
We have to give it some sort of a name and I'll just literally call the name name because we're passing
the name of a friend and then we need to pass forward that friend's name so we can get that from this
friend's array list so just go ahead and type friends dot get.
And we want to pass on.
Because I here's whatever the index of whatever friend it is that we're working with here.
So go ahead and put a semi-colon on that.
And once we've have the friend inserted as an extra We just need to go ahead and say start activity
and we'll pass in that intent.
Jane now when this goes to the next activity right now we have the code to say OK when we get the on
create here we're going to take a look for this extra called age and if we get that you know we're going
to go ahead and show that there but that's no longer what we want.
Instead what we're looking for is we want a string that we're going to call name and we're going to
say this should be equal to intent get string extra.
And remember we've literally provided the name name for the name because that's going to be the name
of our friend.
So here inside of our toast rather than you know doing this energy conversion we'll just type name.
All right.
So let's go ahead and hit run here.
This is sort of our big moment of truth.
We'll see if we got this working.
OK.
We'll open up the emulator here.
And here comes the app.
So look at that.
We've got all our friends listed.
Let's tap on Jane boom look out we get Jane let's go back tap on Sean.
Oh it says Shaun.
I'll hit the back button this time we'll do Sarah.
And just to make sure Fido isn't feeling lonely we'll tap on him as well.
All right.
We just have one more lecture one more apt to build in this section and that's going to wrap it up for
us as far as learning about maps and geolocation so this one's a little bit of a hefty one.
So let's go ahead and dive headfirst into it right now.