Are right in this lecture I'm going to show you how you can integrate Java and Codlin in the same project
and even do some conversion if you decide to go all the way with cotland and how to do that.
So we're going to go ahead and start a new Android studio project and we're going to call this project
the Java faithful because we're going to take this Java a faithful person and convert them into a Cartland
believer.
So we want to uncheck include Codlin support on this one we want to just do Java faithful here go ahead
and hit next.
Yes just making a phone app.
MT activity finish.
So the first thing I want to show you is how both Java in cotland can coexist inside of the same project.
Then from there I'm going to show you how you can convert whole files and then get everything up and
running.
So let's go ahead and wait for everything to set up here.
Looks like we're in a pretty good place so let's open up our app directory.
We're going to go down to where we have all of our Java code right.
We have our main activity here at showing us some stuff that we have inside.
So what we're going to do is we're going to right click where it says compact Zappy code Java faithful
years might say something a little bit different but we want to go ahead and create a new cop files
we're going Right-Click we're going to say new shoes cotland file here and I want to make a file that
maybe holds that new class maybe it's like a dog class so I'm going to say name this file dog.
And so it makes this new dog Katie and look at this we have a cotland file and a java file co-existing
in the same project.
And there's a little work we have to do.
So we have to hit this configure button in order to get everything working here.
And so we're going to go ahead and hit.
OK.
That Android studio is going to go do its thing.
We've got to sync the cradle and just all these different things have to happen.
But eventually this is going to get to a point where we can have both files together and to really prove
this to you.
Let's go back to our dog dog Katie.
And inside of here we're going to make a new class of Let's Make a class called Dog and inside of here
the dog maybe has a property called name which is a string and maybe also has an age which is a it will
we'll go ahead and have those two options there.
So maybe we have this and let's make sure well it's still doing that sync so we'll go ahead and give
that a second to finish up here.
But the idea is things that we have inside of our Java files we can still access inside of our Cartland
files and things that are inside of our cotland files we can access inside of our Java files.
So looks like this is about coming to a close here.
I just want to give a full time to finish its process.
Let's go ahead and type and see what we get as we're waiting for this here.
So I'm now in Java world right because I'm in main activity Java and I'm trying I'm going to try and
make a new dog object so I'm going to type inside of here.
Capitol dog and look at that look what comes up a new dog saw that say you to make a new dog called
my dog.
And this is going to be equal to a new Capitol dog object.
And I'm going to have to pass in a name and an end so you know I'll maybe pass in something like dick
inside of here and I'll go ahead and do an age of five.
OK.
So we have a new dog object.
I even put the semi-colon in there bottom being bada boom.
It works.
So you can see that we successfully have two projects living next to each other side by side and everything's
still OK.
So the big magic that comes with this is to know that you know maybe you have a huge Android app that's
already written in Java and you want to start adding some cotland to it.
You can do that piece by piece.
Maybe whenever you're writing a new class or something like that you say I'm going to make this new
file in cotland and you can go ahead and do that.
And the two can sort of live in their own worlds and the same goes for you know if we had made a class
here inside of Java and wanted to reference it over here we could definitely do that as well.
Now something else that we can do.
Let's say we have this main activity which is the java file and we want to convert it to a Scotland
file.
We can totally do that.
We're going to select main activity go up to code and choose this convert java file to cotland file.
So go ahead and select this and boom just like that.
The whole Java files Now main activity dog.
And look at this.
It even changed where I had you know Capitol dog my dog is equal to a new dog.
It change it to evolve here.
That still named by dog like it just did everything for us it's amazing.
And this last bit this is really going to blow your mind.
So let's say we're searching for an example on how to do something on the Internet.
And that example is in Java but we're working on a cotland project so let's say for example I have something
like trying to learn how to make an array list.
And I'm trying to learn how to do it or for example the only option I find is in Java.
So usually you would just search for cotland or whatever but let's say you find something that's in
Java right.
So maybe I find this code snippet here and it's like oh this is how you make an array list.
But I got to convert this to Java or cotland and you think and I can probably do that in my head but
it take a little bit of time.
Watch this if you copy this Java code.
Come back to android studio and you just simply paste it in.
It's going to say hey this looks like it's Java code.
Do you want to convert this over to Scotland.
I'm going to say yes and all of a sudden just like that boom it did the conversion for us.
So even if you find code examples that are in Java you can simply paste them in the Android studio.
It'll turn it into cotland for you.
So if you want to slowly introduce Katelin into your life or you want to do some big conversions these
are some awesome tools that can help you.