All right welcome to this lecture.
This is going to be a really quick one but before we move forward to our news reader app there's one
more skill that we've got to learn and that is web views that basically allows you to add Web sites
into your app full native web sites and it's just going to make it that much easier when someone finds
a news article that they like that they could look at with in your look at it in your app without having
to move over into their browser.
So what we're going to do is just create a new Android studio project or simply call it web views.
And we just want default for everything here.
So again the idea is basically that you can create this little web view inside of your app you tell
it what Web so you want to go to or we could pass it our own custom each email.
Either way that you want to work it.
This is going to allow us to display something from the web.
So let's go ahead and move first to the visual side of things.
We just want to drag in a web view into crap and make sure that it sort of fills up the whole screen
here.
So we'll go ahead and give Android studio just a second here to get up and running.
So once that finally opened up let's go ahead and get rid of this text.
Phew.
Go ahead and delete that.
And if we go down to our containers there you can see there's a web view.
We'll go ahead and drag this into the project and again looks like it's filled up most the space all
just stuff those constraints to make sure that's the case.
And let's give it a proper ID like a lot of new web web view.
There we go.
So we've gone ahead and we've done that.
Let's go ahead and move to our main activity and talk about how we can get this filled with the information
for a web site.
So before we move into that I guess we let's go ahead and do this because the Web is going to be accessing
the Internet.
We've have to ask for that permission.
So open up your Android manifest file and like we've done before you want to do are uses permission
and we're looking for the Internet.
So we'll go ahead and put that in and that's all we need to do with that.
So go ahead x that out then back inside of our main activity first let's get access to our web view
or say capital web view and we'll just name it web view here is equal to find view by id our DOT ID
dot would view.
Excellent.
Once we have access to that particular web view then we want to put a little a few settings on there
so the first one is about whether javascript is enabled or not.
So Javascript is a separate language from Java that allows you to do more interactive things on the
Web sites.
Almost every Web site these days now uses Javascript so we need to say on our Web view Web site get
settings and then on those settings we're going to say that set javascript enabled and we want to go
ahead and pass True into here.
Because if you put false inside of here a lot of Web sites are just going to flat out not work.
Now there are some situations you would want to do this would be more particularly if you want to have
more control of what the user can and can't do.
But in this case let's just have it equal to true next step for us is we need to say that we want this
to open on our app.
So I'll just show you this line of code and talk about it.
So when you dot set web view client and inside of here we're going to pass new capital web view client.
So the basic idea here is if you do not provide this information a new web view client it'll just say
oh I'll go find the default default browser on the user's phone whether it's chrome opera or whatever
it is Firefox it'll go launch that up.
And so in this you're saying no no I want you to open things up here inside of this web view.
And that's what that web View client is all about.
Then it simply let me go ahead and get the emulator up and running here so that I know that will take
a second there.
Then we want to go ahead and get our web view and we want to give it a you Arel that we want it to go
load.
So we're going to say load your l.
And here we just simply pass it a string.
So with this make sure you give it the full HTP colon slash slash you Colon slash last WKOW dot and
then some website.
Let's go ahead and do like Google dot com.
OK.
We'll go ahead and put that in there.
And now our Web view should display that Web site to us.
So let's go ahead and run this on our emulator cable hit that run button and we'll give this a moment
to pop up here.
OK.
So here comes the app and look get that all of a sudden it shows up.
It's the fully functioning Google dot com.
So for example here you could go ahead and search for something like If I'm a big BYU fan so I want
to I want to say like you I you score to find out if they won or not.
And look it shows the recent football games in Bewley football stinks right now so maybe they actually
don't want to see these results.
But it's a fully functioning Web site and it doesn't have to be Gool you could go put your home page
in there in your favorite place that you like to go visit whatever.
One more thing I'd like to show you is you can actually load raw HDMI all into a web view.
So for example if we take a web view and we say Dot load data so let's select not load your all we want
to load data.
You can provide a string with some email like you would have for web site so for example let's do an
opening H.T. mail tag which then means we should have an ending age e-mail tag if you don't know how
to work with H.E. mail there's some tutorials we don't really have to get into it for this to work.
I'm just showing a quick example you can copy my text exactly if you'd like with this then we've got
to have a body opening tag.
And then which means we should have an ending body tag then inside of there.
We could go ahead and put like a one tag and say something like Hello world.
Exclamation point and then we'll do our ending.
Page one tag and maybe after this we could add a paragraph where we say something like this is a cool
word website summation point and then we'll do our ending tag there.
So you put in all that H.T. mail then you've got to provide a few more things so the next thing is you
got to say what type this is coming through.
So for H.M.S. you do text slash HVM L and then the last thing that you need to provide here is the encoding
that you want.
So we're going to use the standard UTF all caps the Dash 8 case if we've done all of this make sure
you got your semi-colon.
It's going to load this little T.M. string that we created into the browser as a web view.
And so let's go and get our emulator here opens up and boom look at hello world.
This is my cool web site so you will see this low data use for example some people create apps that
are completely just a web view of some HCM shellcode and they do this so that they can make their app
work on iOS and Android or Windows Phone whatever new thing comes out.
They can all just use the web browser inside of it to kind of.
So they don't have to repeat stuff.
But to me it's always a little bit cheesy because it's like you know early on here you know how to do
native code like roll with that go make a native app that people really enjoy.
But it is an option there.
So I wanted to you know show you what that was all about.
OK.
Now that you have this skill in your tool will you are now ready to move forward and create the news
feed app let's go do it.