In this last video before we make our app at the end of this section we're going to look at classes
in a little bit more detail.
So we've seen them popping up every now and again but we haven't really created our own and seen what
they can do.
Now they're very powerful things.
So I'm going to show you what we can do with them in this video.
So it's going to create a new program for us and we'll call it classes.
OK.
So as I've mentioned before our class is kind of a template or a blueprint for an object that we could
create several times in our program.
Now that's the sort of thing that doesn't make a lot of sense until we put it into context.
So let's say for example we've got a game that we're programming and in this game there are several
uses of the game that it might be useful to create a class called user notice.
Classes generally have a capital letter at the beginning of them unlike variables.
So we could create our User class and within this User class we might have some variables and we might
have some methods that apply to the user class.
So for example we might have a variable SCORE which represents the score that that particular user has
got so far in the game.
How would we access that outside of the class.
Well first of all we'd have to create a particular user so we would do that by first defining the type
of the object that we're creating which is a user.
So it's not a string or an int or any of the other types that we've seen so far.
It's a user.
And we might call the user Bob.
So this is a particular user bulb that we're creating here.
And he is going to be a new user.
So we've seen this kind of construct as well but now we're using it with our very own code.
So we've created a class of user which has a score variable within it.
And then we've created a specific instance or object with that type and that's bold and that is a type
of user.
So then if we want to set Bob's school then we would say Bob don't score is equal to and then whatever
10 let's say then if we wanted to display that or use it somewhere we just are in the same way.
So system out.
Print helène Bob dot school and then we run that and we get a score of 10.
So you can see what we're doing is quite similar to what we've done before.
And to be honest I won't be able to convince you that you should always write your code like this rather
than just having a variable called score and setting it equal to 10 but you might be able to say that
this is quite a convenient way to set up your card.
And it really helps when you start building big libraries of code that when you've got all the logic
of the user together in one place rather than spread out all over the place then it's much easier to
maintain and keep control over.
So let's see how else we might use this.
Let's say that in our game we've decided that when you get to 100 points you win the game and we want
to check whether a user has won the game or not.
Then we could create a method within our User class that's going to return true or false depending on
whether the user has won the game whether they've got 100 points or more.
So we do that by creating a public method public so that we can create it from anywhere.
Now we're used to using void because we usually return nothing but this time we're going to return true
or false depending whether or not the user has won the game.
So instead of a void we're going to return a boolean true or false and then we'll call the method has
one
and parentheses because it's a method but it doesn't need to take any variables.
And then we can do a check if score is greater or equal to a 100
then we're going to return.
So that means we're going to return the value true to where the method was called in the first place.
And if it's not
we're going to return false
that we got it because the user hasn't won yet.
Now how do we use that down here.
The obvious thing would be to just change this to Bob.
Dot has one.
And then because it's a method rather than a variable we need parentheses afterwards.
So this will run the has one method on bulb which will then go up here look for has one then check if
Bob score is greater than or equal to 100.
If it is returned true if it's not returned false.
So let's take a look and see what that returns as we would expect it returns false.
And let's just check if we suddenly give Bob 200 points then it returns true as we would expect.
So that means if I want to suddenly change the winning score of the game then I change it here in the
User class with all the other user information and logic and data which makes a lot more sense.
So once again we could of course write this code in a simpler way in a way that works for this level
of program.
But hopefully you can see that this would be a useful construction and a useful way to write a larger
program to make it more maintainable and more logical in terms of its layout and structure.
So here's your challenge.
Can you create a class of number and then that number class.
I want to have an integer value associated with it which could either be positive or negative or greater
than zero or less than zero.
And I want and is positive method which will return true if the number of the object is positive and
false.
If it's not and that will be just a good test to see if you've got the idea of what these classes are
doing.
If not don't worry it is a complicated and quite tricky concept.
So if you want to watch me do it then that's absolutely fine.
Best of luck.
OK.
How did you manage that one.
I would do something like this say class of number with a capital N for our class definitions and then
we get into heaven into which I'll just call a number with a lower case in
and then we're going to have a public method which again is going to return a boolean and we're going
to call it is positive.
Pair of parentheses because it's a method but it's not receiving anything.
So we don't need to put any variables in them and then we just do a check if
number is greater than zero.
Return true.
Else
return false.
There we go.
So that's how class we've done let's just create a new instance of it an object just to make sure that
everything's as we would expect.
So we're creating a new number I'll call it my number.
And that's a new number.
As we've seen.
And then I'll just set that number so my number DOT number I'm going to set equal to 7 which is of course
a positive number so I'm expecting a true result.
And then I'm actually going to use an if statement and I'm going to use my number that is positive as
the test for that if statement because this is a billion.
I can just put it straight into an if statement and if it's true then my statement parses as true and
then I'm going to be a bit fancy.
And rather than just printing to a false to the console I'm going to use this system to print and I'm
going to get my number DOT number plus is positive.
Every day and else
I say in this case it's not positive.
So my number two number is not positive if you're being really precise Be careful about saying my number
that number is negative because it could of course be zero.
Which generally speaking is accepted to be neither positive or negative.
But I won't take marks off if you put negative there OK.
That's it.
Of course the important thing here is what we're doing here.
So we're creating a new object called my number or that type number and then we're setting the number
variable within that to 7 and then we're doing the test for is positive.
And if it is we're saying that it's positive.
If it's not it's same but it's not positive.
So let's just check that.
I've got an error in there.
Did you see that coming.
I forgot to put my pair of brackets after is positive because this of course is a method not a variable
so it needs an open close pair of parentheses.
There we go.
Seven is positive.
If I change it to minus seven
we get minus 7 is not positive.
There we go.
So I hope that's helped clarify a little bit of what a class is what an object is and how we might use
classes in our code.
And the next we're going to create the second and final map of this section and I'm going to encourage
you to do it in an object oriented way.
So that is using classes and objects.
So you then.