Congratulations on making it to the end of section 3 of The Complete Android develop because you've
covered a lot of stuff already in the course as well as making your currency converter app.
In the previous section in this section we've looked in Java in a lot more detail and we've covered
variable's arrays lists maps loops we've created random numbers as well as our little higher or lower
app.
And then we've looked at classes as well.
And also if statements so we're going to try and put as much of this together in this little app and
I've called this app number shapes.
There are two types of numbers that generally have shapes and they are triangular numbers and square
numbers.
And what we're going to do is create an app which allows the user to put in a number and it will tell
them whether it's a triangular number or square number both or neither.
Now this may not be the most useful app in the world but it will allow us to practice almost everything
we've covered.
And also does require you to do a little bit of searching online as well to find a couple of new techniques
that we haven't looked at yet.
You may even need to look up what a square number is if it's been a while since you've worked with them.
So that's it.
If you don't really sure where to get started then just follow along with my explanation but otherwise
give it a go.
Best of luck and remember to try and do it in an object oriented way with classes if you possibly can.
Best of luck.
All right.
I hope you managed it.
You may notice that I've actually settled in the browser rather than going over to Android studio.
And that's because I'm actually going to create the logic for the app in the browser and then move it
over into Android studio and that's slightly more straightforward for me here because I can then run
the logic several times without having to compile the app every time.
So let's start afresh with a new hello world program get rid of that one line that we don't want and
then save as number shapes.
So remember our main aim here is to work out whether a particular number is a triangle a number a square
number neither or both.
So let's start off with a number class.
You may notice now that I gave you a bit of a clue as to how we might set this out in the final example
of the previous video.
So here's our number class which is going to have our number variable contained within it.
And then our tests for is it a square number.
Is it a triangular number.
So let's start by creating a variable number
and then I'll work first on whether it's a triangular number.
So let's create a public method that returns a boolean
and we'll call it is triangular.
Now let's just remind ourselves what is a triangular number.
Here we go.
So it's the sequence 1 3 6 10.
So the difference goes up by one every time.
So the way I'm going to test for a triangular number and you can of course do this many different ways.
I'm going to have a count of variable x int x with initials which is initially 1 and just like we had
when we displayed the first 10 triangular numbers a few videos ago.
I'm going to have a triangular number integer as well which will work my way up through the triangular
numbers.
And essentially what I'm going to do is keep generating triangular numbers until we get to the number
and either the number will be equal to a triangular number or it won't.
If it is then it is a triangular number.
If it's not then it's not.
So we want to keep going as long as so while.
How triangular number
is less than how number that we're working with.
And essentially we want to keep going up the triangular numbers as long as this is the case.
So how do we build triangular numbers.
Well what we did before was increment our counter variable.
So X is now 2 and then take our triangular number and add X to it.
So this will create a series of triangular numbers and it will keep on going until either triangular
number is greater than the number or triangular number is equal to number.
So once we're there we can check to see if triangular number is equal to number.
That means our number.
Must be a triangular number because it's in the sequence of triangular numbers.
So if that's the case
then we guarantee return true.
But if it's not we're going to return false
and that's it that's how method for testing where the number is triangular or not.
Of course we should definitely test that.
So let's create our
new number I'll call it my number which has a new number.
Hopefully you're writing out this object oriented code quite smoothly now which is a big step forward
because it's by no means easy to get to grips with.
And then we'll set my number to number initially.
Let's set it to a triangular number.
So say 6 for example
and then because we're just testing I'm going to just output the result to the locks to the console.
So my number is triangular and then brackets and with any luck then that will return true because sex
is indeed triangular.
Let's take a look.
OK.
Looking good.
Let's try it on a non triangular number.
False.
Brilliant.
OK.
Just a couple more.
Ten is triangular.
So that's true 20 isn't false.
Fabulous.
OK.
So we've got our is triangular test up and running.
Now we need to create and is square test.
So I'm going to do that up here.
So same as before public.
And we're returning a boolean and we'll call it is square
so we're ready.
Hopefully you can see the sensibleness of keeping all this logic in one place.
It just makes a lot of sense.
And then when we're working down here we don't really need to refer to the logic much at all.
Square number let's just have a quick Google is a squid number
so square number is the product of a number multiplied by itself.
So one is a square number because it's one times one.
Four is a square number because it's two times t nine is a square number because it's three times three
etc..
So probably the best way to test whether a number is a square number or not is to find the square root
of that number and see if it's a whole number.
So the square root of four is two.
For example because two teams do it four square root of 9 is 3 because three times three is nine.
Cetera so how do we find the square root of a number.
Well that's one thing we haven't covered yet so I would expect you to search for something like Java.
Well you can see I've already done it just to check that it's Java.
There's a square root method.
Perfect.
That's exactly what we want.
So it looks like the method that we want is math not square square x.
So I'm just going to copy that and jump back over now just to check that this works.
I'm going see
do a quick test.
Say
let's take the square root of my number number that we get.
Let's take a look.
So that should give us the square root of 20.
OK.
Fair enough.
Perfectly reasonable request.
I've said this is going to return a boolean and it doesn't say.
Just for now returned true so that we can run our code.
That looks like the square root of 20 to me.
Brilliant.
So that is exactly the function or method that we need.
So let's copy it again.
Here in
so let's create I double
the square root like that.
And that's going to be math dot squirt.
And here I just want to square that number.
All right so if you're still with me the main thing I want to test about this is whether or not it's
a whole number because if it is then we're dealing with a square number.
If it's not then we're not.
That's another thing we haven't worked out how to do.
So let's do a quick google Java test.
Well again you can see I've been there just to make sure that everything is available online or how
to test if a double is an integer.
That's a perfect question for us.
So yes that's exactly what we want.
OK.
Let's say it looks like we use the math.
Top floor method.
So math.
Top floor.
If you don't want to read that is a method that finds the integer below the number that we're looking
at.
So at the moment we've got say four point four seven.
So the integer below that is full.
So actually that makes a lot of sense.
If the number that we're looking at is the same as the number when rounded down then it must be an integer
or whole number.
So that's what we want.
I think if we have a look at the other part that tests whether it's infinite or not which probably is
not going to be relevant for us.
I'm just going to leave that bit out.
But if you want to just copy that in then it's not a major problem.
OK.
So this is our test so we want to test if we had one variable this time we want square root is equal
to a math top floor of the square root
then it is a square number so it returned true.
If that's not the case
returned false.
There we go.
So just to recap we've found the square root of our number and then we've done a test to see whether
that number is equal to that number when it's rounded down which is just another way of saying is that
number a whole number an integer and if it is then our original number must have been a square number.
If not then return false OK.
So now let's use my number is square.
And of course we don't need anything in those parentheses anymore.
So 20 is not a square number.
So when we run this should give us false rah let's try a square number then nine nine is a square number
and it's giving us true.
Fantastic.
I think I'll just try a couple more.
50 is not a square number so that's false.
But 49 is a square number and that's true.
So that's pretty good.
So now we've got a bunch of code that we can just copy straight into our app because it's so nicely
set out.
It doesn't involve any buttons or getting the value of text edit fields or anything like that.
It's nice and clean as far as that's concerned.
Which means we can just use it straight away.
And of course we could copy it into another app if we wanted to use this somewhere else as well.
So that's one of the advantages of this nice clean class structure.
So let's take this code and make number shapes app.
So Android studio.
And I'm going to start in the usual way creating a new project.
I'll call this one number shape's
and we'll go for all the usual options.
And as usual we'll start with creating the layout give us a bit more room
get rid of the text view and bring in our.
And then let's write our text.
So say it into a number below
to find out if there is a triangular
number or square number or by
having carried it nicely guys on a two lines for us.
And I think I'll just change that to send that
greats and
all that top and left and right constraints.
OK.
And our number
textfield
this when I stretch out a bit bits
and then I have the constraints make the match
excellent.
And finally
bottom which we'll say test number and again we'll send to that.
And at the constraints
I'll add an on click method of test number and then I'll run the app while we write a bit of code.
So as per usual let's create a method called Test number which is called by a we call the
Laux
button pressed
and I'll rerun the app so I can test that.
But I'll also copy in our number class
without the actual code to make it run because we'll add that ourselves.
In a minute there you go.
OK let's just have a quick look.
Well definitely an issue with our lay out there but let's just quickly test the button make sure that
works every day.
So the button works.
What's going wrong with the layout.
Most likely I've forgotten to add some constraints.
We get a top constraint is needed
for the added text.
Lovely let's just check make sure that that is now displaying correctly much better.
There we go.
All right.
So this should now be fairly quick because we've already written the code which does the work of our
app.
Let's just remind ourselves how we use it.
So I'll put the code into the Test number method.
So we create a new object called my number of the number class which is the new number.
And then we set the number equal to.
And this gets 49 and then we check to see if it's a square number.
So let's do that.
But instead of using 49 we'll use the number that the user has entered.
So we're pretty used to doing this now.
We're going to find the added text using find view by id and then our ID edit text and then we want
to convert the value of the text to a number 0 to an integer to be more precise.
So we'll take at it.
Text
dog get text to string and then we want to take the integer class and we want to pass integer
from that string.
So we're going to create an integer from the number that's been entered.
And with any luck we'll find out whether it's a square number or not.
That's like
so let's take a great number first of all 25 see the number true.
That's looking promising.
Now let's take a number which is not a square number 26 fourths wonderful looking great.
OK.
So now we just need to give the user some feedback and we'll do this in our usual way with the toast
and we'll start them by creating a message string
and we want to test to see if
my number is square.
And my number
is triangular.
Then we want to get the message equal to where we want the number itself first of all.
So that's the value of the added text.
Two string.
And in this case we want to say is square and triangular
else.
If my number is square.
Now we don't need to check for triangular because if we're here we know that it's not both Square and
triangular because we used an else.
So if we're here and it's square then it must just be square.
In fact I've just thought of a bit of a shortcut
we can use
message and then set that equal to the number urgently because we're always going to start with the
number in our message rather than having that every time.
And then there's a couple of ways that we could add that on.
We could say message equals what message or it is plus that or there's a nifty way to do that.
Plus equals.
So that will append is square and triangular to whatever is already in the message variable.
In this case the value of the edit text the users number goes out make everything a little bit neater
and again easier to update and manage.
So it is square but not triangular.
Keep on getting
if it's triangular then the opposite is true.
So it's triangular but not square.
And then finally
if we get to here it's neither triangular nor square.
Get the full stop that
ranks and let's update our code to do a toast instead of a log.
With the message and again I think we'll make this a long message.
All right.
That all makes sense as always.
Quite a lot to get the hang up there.
It might be worth just going back and relistening to the last three or four minutes if you're not sure
how we put all that together.
But otherwise Let's check it out and see if it works.
Let's find a square in the first nine to nine is square but not triangular.
That's right.
Now it's trying to triangular number 10 triangle it up and all square.
Excellent.
And then let's try a number which is both triangular and square 36 for example.
A It's got that C.
And then one that's neither.
Well try seven.
Fantastic.
Now we're just going to do one slight tweaking.
You may have noticed with this app and indeed with a higher or lower app that we made.
If the user presses the test number button without entering anything into the app app crashes.
Now obviously the user shouldn't do that but it would be nice if we could offer them a friendly message
rather than just the app crashing.
So I'm going to suggest a way to do that.
Here now
test number method.
So what we want to do is check to see whether or not the added text field is empty.
And there's actually a really easy way to do that so if we take our text get the text in the usual way
and then we look for is empty.
That will tell us whether the string has a value or not.
So if it is then let's set the message to be a certain thing.
So what I'll do a is I'll define message up here.
And then we'll just update it where we need to.
Please enter a number and then if that's not the case then we'll do everything else.
So let's just quickly check for that works.
To find out test number it says Please enter a number of fantastic.
So that's just a basic bit of error checking there's a lot more that we could do.
For example if the user tries to enter a negative number that's going to cause problems or decimal but
I'll leave that to you as a challenge.
We will be dealing with a similar and much more complicated errors than that.
Later on in the course of an hour.
Once again congratulations on getting to the end of this section.
You've learned a huge amount about programming in general and Java specifically and hopefully you'll
be pleased to hear we'll be staying in Android studio for pretty much the rest of the course apps as
we go along.
And in the next section we'll be focusing on media Killy images animations and music and have that congratulatory
cup of tea and I'll see you in the next section.