Congratulations on making it to the last video in this section of the complete Android Developer course
and now going to put together everything that we've learned so the out and behavior of Android studio
adding images buttons text fields and text views.
And of course writing Java code make our apps interactive and we're going to do that by making a currency
converter app so the app on the surface is pretty simple.
It converts from pounds to dollars which at the time of recording this video is about 1.3.
And if I put in say 15 pounds and top convert it tells me that 15 pounds is about $19 50.
So that's all the app does.
Mostly it's a good opportunity for you to practice the app layout.
I'm writing a bit of simple java but it's also a bit more than that because you'll learn a little bit
about variable types if you try and take the value of the text field and then multiply it by 1.3 to
convert it to dollars.
You'll find you get an error because this is a string and you need to convert it to a number type what's
known as a double in order to convert it in order to multiply by 1.3 to get it to please.
So you'll need to write some code to convert the string to a double then multiply it by 1.3 to get the
dollar amount and then convert it back to a string to be able to display it in the toast.
And unless you already know Java reasonably well expect you'll need to do a little bit of googling to
figure that out.
So I think you should be able to manage that.
But if not don't worry at all I will of course go through the whole process in this video and you're
very welcome to follow along.
If you'd rather do that I would recommend giving it a shot by yourself.
So now's the time to pause the video and give it a go.
Best of luck.
All right.
Hey that one for you.
Let's give it a go.
So file new project with very used to this now.
Currency converter for the application name everything else keeps the defaults.
Well that's lighting up.
I'm going to jump back over to Google images to borrow a nice image for
as always need to be very careful of the copyright images you're actually distributing.
But for our purposes
we'll just use one that looks nice for our practice app.
That's not a problem.
OK so I'll start by bringing in that image
to find.
Can get a name or an extension.
I've just had it one on.
That seems to have worked fine.
Slightly strange but there we go.
Come on C to copy the image and then command V to paste it.
And when dies you can just drag it straight in.
OK let's design up to get rid of hello world
and we'll start off with our image.
With currency image.
And because of the nature of the image we can try a different scale type
and I'm going to go for a fit x y which will just stretch it out to the width of the device.
Of course if you prefer you can use the more usual fit center or something like that.
OK.
And then we're going to constrain it to be linked to the left right and top of our screens.
And next we'll add our text.
And we'll change the text to enter
the amount you want to can that
there we go next we'll have
plain text you can see we can select a number type
which will give us the number keyboard and I'll go for decimal so that you can enter three point to
one if they want to and that ahint amount in pounds
and then at a button.
Center at
the button will say
convert
that we get.
Let's just add some constraints in four elements here.
So I don't need to worry about the width or height of that one but I'll just constrain it to the left
and to the top for the text field I'll make this one more or less full width
and let's just change those constraints to make it equal on both sides 16 and 16.
Lovely.
And finally the convert button
will add top and left and right constraints to keep it centered.
Excellent.
So are you.
As we've done before.
I'm just going to run the app on our device while I jump over to write some code and it's the code that
we use now.
So we're going to create a public method which doesn't return anything that's void I'll call it convert
currency.
As usual it's going to take a variable of type a few that will call you that in the view class with
old enter and then find out
which just logged in five
and
button pressed
OK let's have a quick look.
Something has gone wrong that I think I've forgotten the top
that we got.
Yep the top constraint on the textfield that's from that again.
OK.
Looks much better.
And that's type convert.
Have a look in the Lokes
don't see anything that's try that again.
What mistake if I made.
Hopefully you notice that as I was getting along I didn't at the on click method.
There we go.
That's the downside of writing the method first.
Sometimes you forget to add the on click method.
But that's why it's a good idea to check the app in its very basic form.
Before you write any complex code because at least I knew that it must have been an obvious problem
there rather than an issue with my code.
All right so now it's time to get the value that the user has entered in the edit text ready to convert
it from pounds to dollars so that you should be fairly comfortable with going to create an edit text
which will get from find view by id product ID edit text and only to convert that to an edit text and
then briefly let's just log that value
say some more and find
and then the value that we want is edit text not get text dot to string OK.
So let's just check that that's working and then we can do the that we'll need to look up online which
is converting that to a number so that we can convert it to a dollar amount.
OK let's take a look.
So let's say that we want to convert 23 pounds.
There we go.
OK.
So we've got the number.
And as I mentioned we're going to multiply that by 1.3.
So the first thing we're going to need to do is to get this value as a variable.
So we'll create a string variable with a capital S for string and I'll call it amount in pounds and
that's going to be equal to the added text value added text don't get text start to string.
Now what we'd like to be able to say is create another variable called amount in dollars which is equal
to the amount in pounds multiplied by.
And if you've used something like Excel before you'll be familiar with using an asterisk for multiply
and then 1.3.
But as you can see that gives us an error so we can't apply that to the string variable type.
We need to use a double.
OK.
So I have to Google again Java Android and will search for convert string to double and let's have a
look.
OK.
I think the Google answer looks like it's what we need.
So we create a double which is double with a capital D pass double and then the string.
OK.
That looks like what we need.
So let's take a look said double creates a double variable instead of a d.
We'll use something that makes a bit more sense.
So this is going to be amount in pounds but as a double but it's a nice bit of spacing.
And then we want double dot pass double.
But the thing we want to pass as a double is amount in pounds so we've converted amount in pounds which
is a string to the same value but as a double.
And now we should be able to create another double
code amount in dollars.
Double But of course instead of amount in pounds which is a string we're going to use amount in pounds
double and multiply that by 1.3.
And now we're going to want to initially log that and then we'll put it in a toast.
So we're going to need to convert that back to a string that's used that opportunity to do another quick
search.
So Java Android double to string.
How do we go the other way.
Looks like there might be several ways to do it.
That is often the case.
So here it looks like we can just use double dot to string and then our number which actually is extremely
similar to this are used double dot pass double to convert a string into a double.
And then when you double dot to string to convert it back to a string.
So let's create a string amount in dollars
string and using the code that we just looked at we want to use doubled up to string
and then out in Dolan's double.
And then let's have a look.
We should just be able to put this straight in amount in dollars string.
And just to make it clear.
I change the tag to amount in dollars.
All right.
That makes sense if not might be worth just re watching the last five minutes or so just to get clear
on the process of what problem we needed to solve and how we went about doing that.
Using Google to find some carry for us.
OK.
So let's say we want 10 pounds amount mountain dollars 13 fantastic.
Just try slightly now CNN but
ok.
There we go.
Now we've got a very very accurate number them.
I'm going to be a little bit fuzzy about this.
If we can convert it to two decimal places as currency usually is.
So again Android Java convert double to two decimal places.
We hope you're getting the idea of how we can quite easily solve a lot of problems with a quick google.
Now it looks like using one of the other ways to convert to a string.
It will convert it to two decimal places.
So let's change now converting it to a string code to this one.
But of course instead of D we'll use amount in dollars double.
So let's have a quick look.
Make sure that works.
And then if it does the anything we've got left today is to write the code for our toast.
I say it's go for a nasty amount of pounds and then we get a nicely rounded to two decimal places.
Fantastic.
So let's change our look command to a toast and use the down hour to automatically create the code for
us.
So the text is going to be a little bit complicated because we want to show the initial amount and they
convert the amount.
So we'll start with a pound sign and then we'll combine that with the original amount amount in pounds
and then we want to say that that is
and then our dollar sign for dollars.
And finally we'll share the amount in dollars.
And we'll give them a bit more time to register the answer.
All right.
Here we go.
So if everything has gone well this should give us the final result that we're after.
So we want three pounds twenty three pounds twenty four dollars 16 which seems about right to me.
And forgive 20 pounds 26.
Fantastic.
So that brings us to the end of the first section and hopefully you now feel reasonably comfortable
with Android studio how it all fits together how you create a simple layout for your app how you integrate
code and the content of the app.
And you've written a little bit of Java and hopefully done a bit of googling to figure out the solution
to problems that you hadn't seen the answer for.
So that's quite a lot.
Congratulate yourself on getting this far.
Of course we are only just at the beginning and in the next section we'll be really focusing on Java
and writing code which will stand us in good stead for creating any type of app we want.
So go get yourself a congratulatory cup of tea maybe even a biscuit and I'll see you in the next section.
Our Java deep dive.