In this lecture we're going to be learning about adaptive Eikon So this is something brand new in Android
8.00 Orio that is excellent.
It allows you to make app icons that are going to look great on any device some devices choose you to
use round icons Some choose to do more of a square thing and then maybe a mix in between the two and
this is supposed to help make app icons look great on any device.
So the basic idea with this when you really bring it down to its core your app icons need to have two
different files and they both need to be 108 by 108 and you're going have a foreground and a background
in the background needs to be completely full of color you can't have any transparency in your background
but your fork foreground can have some transparency.
And the idea is that they're not going to touch a certain circle within the inner part the inner 72
by 72 that's always going to be visible.
But then you can have some transparency.
Well you don't have as much transparency as you want in that inner part but it's a guarantee that inner
72 by 72 won't be cut off at all.
So the basic idea with all of this is that like for example if you want to have like some parallax features
with your app then if they're going to be circles or square or some combo of the two the both of them
are going to work.
And so you just need to have a foreground and a background and shows you a quick little example about
how you can get this working inside of your app.
So let's go ahead and create a new project here.
Let's open up Android Studio 10 and we're just going to go and see how this works.
Now it's important to know when we're creating this that we're going to be using the latest Android.
So we need to use API version 26.
That's the latest.
So let's go ahead and make a new project we're just going to call this app Divx.
Icons.
Go ahead hit next and this is where it's important make sure you're on API 26.
8.00 will hit next on here.
Empty activity will finish this.
Now it's also important to note that in order to test this you're going to have to have to have a simulated
Android O device that's you know running 8.00 there so if you need to go into your virtual device manager
and make sure that you've got the correct die's device that you can build on that's what I've got on
the emulator here.
Ready to rock and roll.
So as this is getting going.
Let me just basically talk through these foregrounds and these backgrounds because we can choose for
these foregrounds and backgrounds to be actual image files like a PND or you can choose for them to
be for example here like just one solid color.
This is how to do an image but you can also have X-amount files that define what should be going on
there so there's all sorts of different ways that you can handle this.
But the first step for us is we need to go ahead and move into our manifest here and open up your Android
manifest.
So you can see right now it's showing for Android the icon is at this map map slash I.S. launcher.
So if we go ahead and go to our resources and we go to a map we can see oh look there's this icy launcher.
X also will go ahead and take a look at this.
And right now you can see it's using draw will I see launcher background and I see launcher foreground.
So if you want to know what those are about let's go ahead and open up see launcher.
Oh excuse me I need to go into the Drobo folder and then we're going to go to the background for example.
It's got all these options here.
It's basically doing a drawing here in the foreground.
Also it's got a drawing there as well.
But so this is using the new adaptive icon but you'll notice also an MIT map here there's for example
like these I see launcher files and not only that like there's these round ones too if we go ahead and
click on these and this is not what we want to do we want to use the new stuff here.
So in order to do that we've got to go back to the Android manifest.
And because here right now this for the round icon is saying hey this is going to be using the icy launcher
round.
And if we go ahead and click on the launcher around here these are going to be working with you know
these particular images and stuff and that's not where we want to be going with that.
And so what we want to do is we want to go back to our manifest and we're going to change this from
going to map to instead we are going to say I see underscore launcher just like that so both of these
are going to be looking at the launcher.
And if we go ahead and move over to our draw bull excuse me or I.S. launcher here so now this is Exham
l file that we're going to be using instead of the classic background.
I guess let's just go ahead and run the app now so you can see what it looks like.
So go ahead and run this and again remember if this is your first time doing the 8.00 Appiani to make
sure you have a virtual device of 8.00 so that you can successfully run it.
But you know if not you should be able to go so will go ahead and give the emulator here a second to
open up.
All right so that finally opened up.
And if we go ahead and hit the home button here and then open up our apps we've got the adaptive icon
app if we click on hold we can get this on the desktop a little bit be a little bit easier to see.
So for example instead of this green background with the grid there if we go here and say rather than
point to that instead we want to do something like at color and we can choose something like color accent
which I think is that pink color we can see on the left.
You'll notice that that will now get a cool little pink background here.
So let's wait for the app to open up and here comes the app if we hit the home button back there boom.
Look at that.
Now we've got you know this little color here and you know same thing with the foreground.
We could change this to a solid color like primary dark it's going to be sort of this purplish color
this sort of defeats the purpose though because this allows us to the foreground is where you're sort
of doing the thing that's on top of it so the solid color in the background that's probably fine to
have it be a solid color.
But when we do it is the foreground will then you just have one solid color is your thing so that's
where we might want to control the back to that.
So we've made our Apso that everything looks at this icy launcher.
Ex M-L if you want to have different versions for the regular launcher and then also the round version
like you can see these are pointing to the same files I decided on Android manifest that we wanted to
have both of them point to the same one so that regardless we were using the same code there but that's
up to you about one wall how you want to handle that.
So again up to you how this all works out.
And again you can use like images so much good information here on the web site but wanted to give you
a quick intro into that so that you can see the future of icons and Android.