The complete Android or you develop of course it's not just the best way to learn app development but
it also gives you everything you need to start a career developing apps.
Absolutely free.
So you get a year's unlimited web hosting with my company eco web hosting you get a copy of my book
How to add $10000 while learning to code.
You get a hundred dollars of free AWOS credits to allow you to build social apps like the Instagram
and Twitter Collines will be making later in the course.
You get a free Java certification from the CCI.
And of course you get $500 worth of ethical and audio assets to use in your apps.
So how do you get all this great free stuff.
Well first off just go to eco web hosting Dockerty UK Ford slash C-p Ford slash Android.
Then enter your email address a nice secure password and your utility username.
If you don't know what that is.
Just go to any web page on the dot com.
Click on the icon on the top right.
Make sure you are logged in and then click View Public Profile.
And you'll find all you to me use a name at the end of that you are I'll say mine is Rob Percival.
So copy that pasted in and then click sign up.
This will then verify your purchase.
And if all goes well you'll see this sign a successful message.
Then you can get some getting started emails if you like and leave us a bit of feedback.
And once done you can click update account details which will take you to your profile page.
Here you can see which courses you verified verify any other courses that you've bought.
And most importantly down at the bottom you can get your course extras so you can download three different
versions of the ebook.
Get your dollar AWOS credit access they CCJ accreditation using this code and finally download the graphical
and audio assets.
Great stuff.
Now you've got all your free extras.
Let's go and learn Android development.