All right.
It's time to learn how we can take these apps that we've been building all our own and sharing them
with the world.
One of the coolest things that I love about Android development is how quickly you can get your apps
on the App Store.
So the reason that I say this is because I initially started as an IOW developer and I remember my first
time trying to get my app on the App Store.
It took weeks to figure out the whole process about how to upload my app to apples App Store.
I got it rejected two times before I finally got approved in between each decision was about a week
and a half's worth of waiting.
And it was just awful.
It was terrible to see this thing that I spent so much time on.
Take that much effort to just get through to the App Store.
Whereas with Android with the Google Play store it's much much simpler.
So you can take this thing that you created and very quickly share that with family and friends.
That's that's one of the things I love about Android now in order to get this rocking and rolling.
I'm just going to use one of our past apps here.
I'm using this list view demo that we had created before this.
I just want to show you what the process would be I'm not actually going to put this into the store
but I want to walk you through everything that you would need.
So the first step is to go to developer dot Android dot com.
And so you're going to need a Google Developer account now if you don't have one of those yet.
It's going to prompt you for everything.
But once you're to this page you want to click on this play console.
So this is going to take you to a screen where it's going to ask you to sign in then with an account.
So go ahead and do this if you don't already have a Google account get one but do that and I'll meet
you at the next step.
So once you're there you're going to have to go through a series of steps here.
And it's essentially you have to agree to the terms and you also have to pay a registration fee and
it's a one time twenty dollar twenty five dollar fee.
So I know that's kind of annoying that you got to pay money to get your app on the App Store.
But again compare this with the Apple world.
It's ninety nine dollars per year.
It's an ongoing reoccurring payment where this is a one time twenty five dollars thing.
So we're in a pretty good situation comparatively to what's out there.
But go ahead and go through those steps and then I'll meet you once you're finished with all that.
So once you've gone ahead and gone through that process you should be at this console screen here and
you can click on this publish an Android app on Google Play.
So we want to make a new one here.
It's going to ask you for your language.
It's also going to ask for a title you can always come back and change us so don't worry too much about
this.
So I'm going to call this list view fun something like that and I'll go ahead and hit create so this
will then take you to the details for your app and there's all sorts of information that you can fill
out here.
So there's stuff like the title The short description full description all these things that are going
to show up on Google Play.
There's graphical assets.
So this mostly includes screenshots but also you've got these high rez versions of your icons and even
TV banners.
I thought this was really interesting the daydream 360 degree image for those people using the daydream
VR stuff.
You can even include like a promo video you've got to say what category you want this information to
be in just all sorts of details that you want to fill out.
So we're going to come back and talk about screenshots in just a second.
But I do want to focus on one thing and that's actually uploading your app to the App Store here because
you know you can fill in these details but it's another thing to actually get a file up to say hey this
is what I want to release to the store.
Now to do that you want to go here to app releases over on the left.
And here this is where you're going to release an AP case file so the AP case contains everything about
your app all the images that you have in there.
All your main activities.
I mean your manifests the layouts everything is inside of the AP file and so when you're here you can
actually use this to do like some beta and alpha testing.
That was pretty funny that they split between the two there.
But we want to work with production because we have an app that's ready to rock and roll so you just
want to go to manage production and you want to create a release and you want to go ahead and say I'm
going to continue with the signing stuff.
Yes accept the terms.
OK.
And this now allows you to add in a P.K. which we have to go get this from Android Studio.
So let's move back to Android Studio and what we're going to do once we're here is we need to open up
our variance.
And so if you have build variance over here on the left side needs you to click on that.
If not go to help but if you just search for variance you're going to get the build variance options
up there.
OK.
So with all of that in place what you want to go to do is click on this build variant and change it
from debug to release.
So every time we've been running our app it's been in quote unquote debug mode now we want to go to
release mode which is going to create an AP Kay File for us.
All right.
Now before we can go ahead and just you know build this and let this thing rock and roll.
We have to sign our app and basically what signing our app does is it says hey we are the only people
that are going to be able to make updates to this app for the foreseeable future.
So in order to do this we want to go up to the top here to build and then we're going to come down and
say generate signed a peak.
Remember that's the file that contains everything.
So go ahead click on that and it's going to ask you what module you want to do this from.
We just want to choose the default app that we have there.
Now when you get to this next part it's going to ask for this key store pass.
So it's basically saying you know do you want to make any one of these and yes we don't have an existing
one so we're going to say create new.
Now once you click on that it brings up even more details here in this first can ask where do you want
to save this.
So I'm just going to go ahead and throw mine on the desktop.
So I'll go ahead and choose that.
Then you have to make a password for this.
I'm going to do a fairly simple password but you know feel free to do something more complex for your
app.
Then you've got to make a alias here and go ahead and choose what you want this to be.
I'm going to call it something like a list view key something like that.
I know it's kind of simple and again up up here in the key store path.
We should also give this a proper name.
So I'm going to call this maybe something like a list view key store.
OK.
So with that in place again you've got to have another password.
So we'll go ahead.
I'm just going to reuse the same one.
Feel free to do different if you'd like.
You've got to choose how long you want this to be valid for and I think twenty five years is pretty
good.
I don't know if the Google Play store is going to be around in twenty five years who knows what kind
of tech we're going to have in that timeframe.
So with that in place you want to go ahead and put in your information.
So I'll just say Nick Walter here organization unit.
Honestly you can just copy and paste your name for each of these it's not too big of a deal city or
locality.
Again listen if you want I'll do SLC Utah in the old U.S. of A.
OK so with all that information in place you're going to go ahead and hit.
OK.
And it's going to say hey I've got all this information is this what you want.
The next thing that you want to do is make sure that this remembers your password.
So go ahead and check that box.
So go ahead and hit this next button.
And with this you want to make sure that you save this to a place where then you can go get to it and
upload build type we want to make sure this release and have both of these signature versions checked.
So with that go ahead and click on finish here.
And this is going to go make that AP case file and it might take a little bit of time because it's trying
to recreate your app as a whole but luckily for me that didn't take too long.
But if you do does take a bit of time don't worry.
That's usually expected.
So with that let's go back to safari here and now we'll just say browse file I have saved mine to my
desktop so look here it is it came in this release folder and there's that app release that AP.
So go ahead and choose that.
That's going to upload it here to Google Play and it will tell us what it thinks and oh it is not happy
with what we've given it.
And that's because we had when we were setting this up just the com dot example package name in there
which I guess has been taken by someone else that was you know working through an example.
So in order to fix this we can do this let's go back to Android Studio.
This will be a good process for you to see because we've always mentioned you know you can have it be
your Web site in reverse.
You can have it be your name but you can always come back and change it.
Well this is how you can change it if you need to.
So you're gonna go here make sure you have the Android view selected.
And once you have that you just want to hit the settings icon and you want to uncheck this hide empty
middle packages.
So what that does it sort of breaks these out into the full you know com example zap code.
So unfortunately for me I had this example if it had just been com zapping code I would've been fine.
So we actually just want to move that directory up to there and saying Hey are you sure you want to
move this.
And you just say yes to all this for you you might be renaming the folders rather than moving it up
because I just needed to get rid of the example and you just say yes go ahead do this refactor and it's
going to go through your project and make sure it can handle all of the changes for this.
So it's you know going to go through and do its thing and we'll give Android Studio a second here.
So once we have that in place you know you would want to do the same thing here for you know like the
tests and everything.
We're not using the test in our app and so I'm just gonna go ahead and actually just delete these so
I'll get rid of the Android test and we'll come back and do the second test here once Android Studio
has finished up.
So it looks like it did that and then we'll go ahead and delete this one as well.
So we'll go ahead and get rid of those.
Okay.
So once we've done that we can go ahead and change this back to the compact view so that we can go ahead
and see those items a little bit easier.
You can see we have a little bit of an issue here because we had to get rid of this example directory
in that one and there we go.
Now if we go back to compact.
There we go.
That's looking a lot better for us.
OK.
So with this in place that was a good change to make.
There's also one more thing that we need to change.
And so we need to go open up one of our great all files so we're gonna go down here to the great scripts.
Make sure you open the one that says module app and once you have this open.
This is where you'd want to have the appropriate application I.D. and it looks like we've got this in
place we've got comm dots app barcode that list view demo it's listing what we have there so that must
have done that and the refactor so good to know that that'll work.
But now that we have that in place we can go back and do our build and do generate the AP okay we'll
say next to this put in our password and with all that make sure both those are checked.
We will hit finish Gates will give Android Studio a second to finish up here and there we go now after
this unfortunate error let's go ahead and try this one more time we'll browse our files.
Try this new release dot KPK and come on be nice to us Google Play
moment of truth here drum roll.
Look at that it's processing it's kind of going through the app and look at that good news.
So we have Version 1.0 here ready to rock and roll and that means that we now have an AP Kay file.
So with this you know the next step for us would be to review and roll out.
But there's so many details that we have to go sort of fill out here in our app and so as I mentioned
before if we go back here to the store listing this is where the real meat and potatoes of the Google
Play Store is one of the big things that you'll need is screenshots.
You don't necessarily need them but I think it makes your app that much better.
Well in fact I'm reading the texture at least two screenshots are required.
I know before maybe they weren't but it looks like now you need at least two.
So I'm going to show you how you can go ahead and get these in case you're not sure how to do that so
we're gonna go back to Android Studio and under build variance we're gonna switch this back to debug
so that we can run the app on one of our simulators.
So we'll go ahead and help my devices weren't showing up for a second I was wondering what was going
on there.
But basically you're going to run your device and I'm going to show you how you can very quickly take
some screenshots from it.
It basically consists of hitting this little camera button here and what that does is it takes a screenshot
and then you can upload that full rez image to the Google Play Store here which is pretty great.
OK.
So that's one thing that you're going to want to set.
Really the less the rest of these options you just want to go through like the content rating going
to tell you you know what kind of stuff is going to be inside of your game game your app whatever it
is that you're making pricing and distribution.
Do you want this to be a free app.
If you do want to do a paid app you have to create a merchant account with Google and get that all set
up.
But it's not too much trouble.
You can set where you want this app to be available there's just all sorts of good details here is your
app going to contain ads.
Is it primarily directed at children.
Does it can intrude include Google Android Wear stuff.
There's just so many things that you've got here.
Also in app purchases you know if your app contains that then you know you can go ahead and get that
all set up here.
All sorts of information.
But I'm going to leave that up to you because this is gonna be so specific for whatever app it is that
you're uploading to the store here.
It's really just direct to you about how you're going to go ahead and work with that.
So let me go ahead and show you here on the emulator.
Looks like the app opened up here.
So if we go ahead and we hit this little camera button that's going to save a screenshot and I believe
it saves that to our desktop.
No it doesn't.
So let's see if we can do that one more time and find where it is.
Oh there it had taken a screenshot it was just taking a while to show up.
So there it is we've got the screenshot it's showing up on the desktop.
We could then take this and go back under store listing and upload this as one of our screenshots.
So there you have it.
I'd love to see whatever app it is that you've created.
Please feel free to share it with Robyn I.
On Twitter we'd love to see what your app looks like.
My twitter handle is at Nick Chuck Walter and Rob is at Tech Rob.
So please let us know how the app goes.
And we can't wait to see what you've created.