Well I'm so excited that you're here for the Copland section.
Like I said in the intro this is one of my favorite sections because I think Collins just so exciting.
I personally think it's going to be the next big thing an Android development and just all Java development.
In general it just to me is so much better than Java.
I love programming with it.
I think beginners will be able to pick it up better than Java and it is just gaining so much popularity.
If you just go ahead and google Codlin popularity I mean you're just going to get tons of results here
and I just checked out a few of these.
But I mean big big you know rising star here.
Codlin I believe in Java is one of the most popular programming languages in the world.
And so for example on this I've never know how to pronounce this tyo Bay tyo Bay index here.
If we go ahead and look at job it's the number one programming language in the world.
Now it's slowly.
Well I don't know about slowly it's pretty quickly dying from that position and it's you know coming
down it had a real dominance at one point and I think that's because a lot of people are seen.
Java is you know a little bit outdated.
Some of these other programming languages are much easier to work with and that's the case with Cartland.
So if cotland can keep getting the globe growing popularity and all these top Java developers will start
switching to cotland.
I think we're really going to see Collin's shoot up because right now Cartland it's way down here let's
go ahead and see.
Yeah it's position 48 right now which I'm sure you know.
Years ago when it started it was down maybe in the hundreds or something like that.
But I mean just to be on this list is a pretty big deal but when you look at its potential of where
it could go Cartland is just an awesome investment to get into right now.
I think and come in for an awesome thing about Collen is if you know Java you'll be able to pick up
KOPPLIN very quickly and you know it's not too big of a switch.
So well it is a switch.
I mean that's why we have this section here to teach you all about it.
But you know I don't think it's like earth shattering or anything like that.
So just start here.
I honestly think the best way to learn how to work with Java is to use this intelligent idea.
So these are actually the same people behind helping to create Android studio but I find their program
to be better for just this one individually focused on just being an idea for Java or Cotman.
And so we want to go ahead and take this and use it to first learn Kotla and then we'll come back and
make some apps with Kollin an android studio.
So go ahead and go to Jepp brainstorm com slash idea that gives you this intelligent idea.
So we'll go ahead and download this.
And whatever your operating system is.
Go ahead and get that now.
There's the ultimate version which is got all these bells and whistles and stuff.
The big one is looking for is that it has Cartland which this free open source one has and so we're
going to go ahead and use that again.
I don't think we're going to need any of these so we'll go ahead and get the community option here.
So wait for this download page and boom that starts coming through.
OK.
Now I have already gone through and gotten intelligence all downloaded and installed so I'm going to
go ahead and open that up on my computer and go to my applications.
And let's get to delegate.
There we go
wait for this to pop open here.
Yeah by the end of this lecture you will have written your very first line of Cartland code which will
be great.
So really excited for you to check that out.
All right.
So this opens up and this had a project that I was working on before.
So I think we can probably go ahead and close out of this and we want to start a new project so as you
can tell.
Yes very similar to Android studio.
You can tell it like the same people you know have been working on that.
So we want to create a new project and you can choose what type of project you want to do here so there's
you know the classic Java stuff.
But for us we want Cartland and we want the Cartland slash JVM.
You can use cotland that will be converted into javascript.
That is a very interesting subject that I cover and a separate course that's just focused purely on
Kollin but for this one we want Koblenz flash JVM.
So go ahead and select that then we're going to need a project name.
And I think we should just kind of have a little file that we can use to play around with and have fun.
So I'm just going to go ahead and call this cotland fun and I'm going to save this into my idea of projects.
Remember that's the name of this ID and I'm working on STK one point eight and we'll go ahead and just
use the Cartland Java runtime.
So go ahead and hit finish there.
And if we go over here to the left you can see some of the files that we're going to have.
So there's these dot idea files these are all have to do with the actual you know idea getting things
set up for you.
But it's inside of the source where we want to work.
So in here we want to go ahead and create a new file.
So we're going to make a new and we want it to be a cotland file so we can call this whatever we'd like.
Maybe let's go ahead and call this one something like Hello Kitty.
Because this is sort of like our Hello world.
Now in order to be able to run some code here there's a few things that we've got to do and the first
one is we have to create a main function.
So when you just have an independent Scotland file you have to have this main function that says I'm
running this essentially it's like if you're running from the command line.
But what we're going to do is we're going to type out here just start typing main.
You should get an auto complete where you can hit enter and then that's going to pop up this function
main args and don't really worry about you know what's this main function.
How does it get called.
But just know everything inside of these curly brackets is code that we can run.
So for example if we want to write our very first line of code here like let's just print something
out which is essentially the same thing as logging.
We'll just go ahead and say print line and we'll put inside of here a new string that says Hello Codlin
exclamation point and look at this is so cool in cotland you don't need semi-colons that's one of the
many pluses that you're going to see here with Caitlin.
But once we have that in place we have our main function we have a line of code there.
I'm going to open up our SIRC here and I'm going to select our Hello Dom.
The Cartland files and and Katie we're going to Right-Click click and we're going to say run.
Hello Katy.
So it's going to go run this file and it's going to spit out some information for us about anything
that we print for example here.
Printin Hello Caitlin.
OK.
So go ahead and wait for this to pop up and you can see down on the bottom there's lots of different
text with all sorts of different colors but just know the stuff that's in black is the stuff that's
been printed.
And so there we can see the yellow cotton column.
And now that we've run this for the first time we don't have to right click this file anymore to say
run instead we can just go ahead and hit this run button up top and that will automatically do it for
us.
So any changes that we want to make we can go ahead and just do it right here.
So I have for you about an hour's worth of lectures that are going to teach you about the basics of
cotland for someone with a Java background.
I recorded these for my cotland programming course.
And so this is specifically for your situation right.
We've been through a bunch of apps you know Java pretty solidly now but you just want to know about
Cartland.
So I'm going to teach you the basics.
I'm going to run you through all those videos then I'm going to have some extra special lectures for
you at the end of that to say OK you've made it up to this point with Kopplin.
Now let me take you one step further and show you how it all works with Android studio and whatnot.
So I'll go ahead and pass the torch off to the other me.
Go ahead and start learning cutline.