Congratulations on making it to Section 9 of The Complete Android and develop of course now if you're
fairly familiar with Passover on AWOS I'm going to challenge you to build a clone of the popular taxi
app Uber.
Now this is rather more complicated than the Instagram app that we built before.
For two reasons the first of course it requires geo location and maps.
So we'll need to integrate the skills that we learned a couple of sections ago with what we know about
Passover but also will need to have two sections of the app one for writers and one for drivers and
then both of those We're going to need to communicate with each other.
I'm also going to expect you to do a little more of the work yourself this time around as you are fairly
familiar with as I say Passover and the geo location aspects of Android apps and the more you do yourself
the more you will learn.
But of course I'll go through the whole process step by step and you can watch me doing it if you'd
rather learn that way at the same time be of course thinking how you might apply this to apps that you're
building and how you might work in both geo location and some social features using Passover.
So enjoy making the overclaim and I'll see you at the beginning of the next section.