Hello and welcome to the section here where we're going to be building a Twitter clone.
So the idea with this right is you can make an app where you can create a user account log in share
some tweets and also look at other people's tweets.
So you'll notice we have a very interesting homescreen here where there's only one sign up and log in
and it's kind of all combo with each other.
So the idea here is someone puts in a name and a password.
And if it's their very first time it'll try logging well regardless someone puts in a name and a password
it will try to log them in if the log in doesn't work.
It will try and sign them up with that name and password.
So if that names already been taken then it will say hey you know there's a problem there but if they
have a name and a password will just log them in the first time or it will make a new account for them.
So there are some drawbacks to this.
For example if I misspelled my name Nic for like two days for example it would sign me up with a new
account with Nick K-K rather than you know saying hey you misspelled your user name.
So there's some drawbacks but it's going to be fun to experiment with here.
But anyways you put in your information you log in it comes to a list of some users except for yourself
so notice Nick is excluded here.
And I can choose people I want to follow or not follow.
So for example right now I'm only following phyto and if I want to go see my feet of people I follow.
Look there's a tweet by Feydeau but if I hit the back button I say you know what I do want to follow
John and Sarah.
So I go and select those two checks.
And now I go back to my feed.
Well then I can now see tweets from John and Sarah.
The other thing that we want to mention here is that we can post tweets as well.
So if I go to here and I say I want to tweet and I'm going to send out a new tweet like this app rocks.
OK.
And I go ahead and send this.
I should be able to log out and then come see that tweet so I'm going to log out here and log in as
Feydeau.
So let me go ahead and put in my information there and if I go Follow Nick and I go look at his my feed.
I should see look at that.
This app rocks.
OK.
So I'd really encourage you to go do this by yourself it's going to be a really good exercise for you.
But of course you need any help you can always watch the lectures.
All right go ahead and get to it.
All right well let's go ahead and get started on our Twitter app here.
And the first thing that we want to do is we want to be able to get a parse server up and running.
So I actually reuse the one that we had used before from Instagram I just got rid of some classes.
You can create a separate instance if you want but you're gonna have to be a little bit careful there
because if you have more than one easy to instance you're going to get outside of that free tier and
you're not looking to pay for it.
This might not be you know you don't want to have more than one but you either create a new one you're
the one from last one but you need to get parce server up and running.
And then we need to get a partas starter server ready to go so this is where we need to go to Rob's
Web site.
So we in a new tab are going to go to Android of course.
Com and we want to do flash.
And this is where we're going to go get the download.
So we're going to do slash parce project all lowercase.
Zip OK so we'll go ahead and download that.
And while that's there I just wanted to show you that I have an android studio my last project which
has the appropriate application ID client key server all that good stuff.
So we now have access to those things.
And if you need any help on setting up your parse server you can always go back and reference the instagram.
But we got everything set up for that very first time.
So that's they're available for you.
All right.
Looks like that download finished.
I'm going to go ahead and throw this on to my desktop.
I'm also going to give this a new name.
I'm going to rename this Twitter so it doesn't have the name of parce starter project anymore.
And so then I'm going to go open an android studio this new project so I'm going to go to the desktop
here.
I'm going to open up Twitter.
So it's going to go set up the new STK path.
That's fine with me.
Go ahead and wait for this to open again.
We're going to have to with this project go you know take all this information that we had just got
and set it up for our new Twitter up to make sure it can connect and we'll go ahead and do a test to
make sure that everything works out.
So here we have our new Twitter application.
And like I said we do want to go back here to the Instagram app and we want to go get the appropriate
information.
Yes we want to do all the applicable updates.
So I'm actually just going to go ahead and copy this line in parts and we'll come back to our Twitter
project here and we're going to replace that line you just go ahead and paste that in.
Excellent.
And we shouldn't now have access to everything that we need for this.
We still have to do a few updates here.
But at least as far as connecting to our server we should have everything in place that we need.
And the real way to test this to see if everything is up and running is by running this app and see
if it creates this example object like we had before.
So we'll go ahead and keep moving through these updates to make sure we're at the right level with everything.
So once that finishes we're going to want to go ahead and hit run here so we can test this out on our
emulator.
And again if everything's working correctly we'll see this new example object class that we have here
show up inside of our parse server.
So we'll go back and see if that works for us.
So the emulator finally opened up here but I did have a pretty nasty error and it was saying something
about a session token that was bad.
So there was two things I did to fix it so one is after you do a partial Nissel initialize and I think
these errors are coming because I'm using a parse server and I'm using the same emulator device and
I had deleted some classes.
But you want to do a parse user log out here at the very beginning before you create an object.
We only have to do this this one time and then also down below.
You want to comment out this parse user enable automatic use.
We were going to have to end up doing this anyways because we're going to be handling our own server
or user sign in process.
But go ahead and do those two things and you should have success and if you did you'll notice there's
no example object here but when we reload the page like it that we have an example object and mine has
to.
Because I ran it twice and that's where the two of those came from.
But if you had those issues that's what should get you to that point.
So from there now that we know that parts is working the next step for us is we want to go ahead and
get the design of our app correct.
So we want to go ahead and get a logo for our Twitter application.
So we're going to go to my favorite flat icon dot com and I'm just going to go ahead and search for
Twitter.
I think that's too many eyes for Twitter.
We'll go ahead and search that and we have some nice looking ones here.
I'm going to say you know maybe something like this bird with the circle that looks really good.
This is by free pick again if you're going to be using these images.
Make sure you have the proper license to do everything here and we'll go ahead and grab a PMG for this.
And let's maybe do this at one twenty eight.
So go ahead and grab that and I'll add this to our project here.
Let me go ahead and open it up and down here in Razz.
We need to have a drawable folder.
So I'm going to make a new resource directory and we want this to be drawable.
There we go.
Now that we have that let's go ahead and we want to reveal this in Finder.
There it is.
And so now we can take this image and bring it in.
OK so with that in place and if you're not seeing your image you might want to right click here and
say synchronize and look.
Now we get that awesome Twitter PLG.
So let's go ahead and move over to the lay out side of things going open up the layout folder here and
open up activity main.
So there's a few things that we want to add here.
One is the Twitter logo up and the top that's going to be a big thing.
But also we want to be able to add the edit text for this and we want to be able to add the sign in
button.
So let's go ahead and add a new constraint lay out I'm going to go ahead and add this we need to get
rid of our relative lay out.
Let's go ahead and delete that you know it's not playing nice with me so let's go ahead and just add
a constraint layout here.
It is really not playing nice with us.
So go ahead and change this to a constraint.
Lay out excellent and we'll come back to design here.
Now remember from last time there's a few issues with lay out here so there's a couple of things that
we're going to have to fix.
Let's go down to our grade old build to make sure you do this for the module.
And we just want to update this to be a key SDK version 26 also minimum SDK version we want 26 there
and target STK version let's do 26 and we're going to come back down and change this to twenty six point
zero point zero.
So once you do this you're going to have to sync your cradle project and go ahead and give this a moment
to run.
But once it's finished through we should be able to come back to that main activity and start working
with it.
So once that's finished we can go back to our main activity here and we'll be able to start designing.
So the first thing that we want to add is that image view.
So I'll just go ahead and click drag that out to our project and we'll go ahead and put that in in the
drawable it's going to be looking for a name here so we want to search for Twitter and it will go ahead
and grab that case or we're going to have this up at the top.
And you know we're going to figure out how big we want this to be and you know it looks like an OK size
but I don't know if there's going to be enough space to even type up there.
So maybe let's constrain the width and height.
Let's maybe see what like 50 and 50 looks like that's probably a bit too small.
It's not bad let's leave it at 50 and 50 and then we can come back and see what we think about it later.
With that in place we need to go ahead and add some edit text so we'll go ahead and drag one below here.
And this is going to be for that user name.
So for the width Let's go ahead and have this match the parent We're going to get rid of the text inside
of there and instead provide a hint to say this is where that user name should go should probably spell
user name correctly.
We are also going to bring out one of these for the password.
So go ahead and bring one of those right below.
Again the width on this should match the parent and we'll get rid of the text instead.
Put a hint that says this should be the password.
Now we want to go ahead and change the input type for this one because it's going to be a password and
we want to have that blurred out so we're going to come here and choose text password uncheck person
name that's going to help us out.
So go ahead and hit OK there.
Now last thing that we need to add is a button.
So again we're going to do that.
Interesting button where there's only one button here that allows us to both sign in and sign up.
I guess the better name for this would be sign up slash log in.
But you know it kind of performs those two actions so we're just going to type out here sign up slash
log in because those are the two functions that we want to have happening with this button and it's
on click name here.
I think probably that's a good name.
I'm just going to say sign up capital log in.
And that's going to represent when someone tries to sign up or log in.
OK.
So let's go ahead and give appropriate names for these added.
I'm going to call this user name at a text here on the password.
Say yes to that.
I want this to be password and text password Capitol and a text we can get rid of too probably.
And then on this button let's go ahead and call this the sign up button.
Although I don't think we're going to need access to that in code.
But let's go ahead and give an ID just in case.
So let's get back to the Java code here.
Now we can get rid of a lot of this so we're going to get rid of here the parse user Well all of this
code.
We don't want to get rid of this Parslow user all that stuff.
Just leave the initialiser here with this in place.
Now we want to go move over to the main activity so we'll double click on that.
And then here inside of our main activity this is where we want to get things rolling.
So the first thing I guess that we should do we have in our copy and paste board here the name of the
method that we want so let's go ahead and just do it.
Public void.
Sign up log in.
This will take in a view which we'll call you then we'll go ahead and do our curly brackets there.
So now we can write some code whenever someone hits that button.
One other thing that I'd like to do is kind of just clean up the app a little bit.
Is going to set the title here.
So set title and I'm just going to have this be equal to Twitter colon log in.
So with this in place let's go ahead and write the code that we're trying to do and basically what it
is is we need to get the information out of the user name and the password edit text we need to attempt
to first log in the user if that's unsuccessful then we will sign up the user.
That's kind of our process here.
So let's get access to those texts.
The first one is going to be the username and text and we'll just have this be equal to fine view by
ID.
Our dot ID.
User Name and we're not getting the proper ID here.
So this is an error sometimes I see with Android studio sometimes as simple as hitting this bill button.
Sometimes you have to completely close out and open it up again.
But through a little bit of work here by just closing and opening I got it too.
Now if I type out user name edit Tex it shows up but it really didn't change any code.
I just closed and open so it's just something freaky that Android studio is doing that gets us the username
edit text.
Let's go ahead and get the edit text for the password.
And that text and we'll have this be equal to fine view by ID.
Our idea of password at text.
OK that gives us access to both of the edit text.
So then next what we want to do is we want to try and log in.
So I'm going to take our parse user and I'm going to log in in the background so I'll go ahead and do
this.
First it needs to get the string for the user name.
So we're going to take user name edit text dot to string so will have access to that.
I guess before this we have to get the DOT get text and then to string.
There we go.
Same thing for the password so password edit text get string and
password edit text get text us trying to get string to string.
That'll get us there.
And then the last thing that we need to pass is a callback.
So we'll go ahead and do a new log in callback and that'll add excellent code for us to tell us hey
whether or not this thing worked.
So with this the first thing we want to check and see is if we have an error or an exception so we're
going to say if E is equal to no meaning that you know nothing's gone wrong then we want to go ahead
and log out that everything worked out so well say log I and we'll say log in and say this was a success
summation point and that's our happy news.
Now if it's the users very first time and we're assuming that would be the case if the log in failed
then we want to say hey let's go ahead and try and sign up this user.
So we're going to make a brand new parse user who we're just going to call user and we're going to say
this new user equal to a new partas user just like that.
Next we want to set this user's name so we're going to say user dot com I guess we're already using
the name of user there so let's go ahead and call this guy parce user or maybe a better better yet another
name his new user.
There we go.
So now we can say new user set user name and just follow the same path we're going to get that username
edit text that get text to string.
Next thing I want to do is take this new user and say set the password for this user and that that'll
be password edit text get text to stream.
So now we've set the username and the password.
And the next step is going to be signing up this user so we're going to see new user dot sign up in
background.
We want to get the option here with the callback and which will type the new sign up callback and we
get this awesome function telling us how that worked out.
So again we want to do an if statement where we check the exception so it will do if with our curly
brackets and we'll see if he is equal to know.
There were no problems and we will simply only say success.
But in this case we're going to say Sign-Up success and in the situation here.
Well you know we weren't able to log them in.
We weren't able to sign them up.
There must be some sort of problem.
So this is where we would want to create a toast message for the user.
So we're going to say toast dot make text and inside of here we'll just pass in main activity this for
the context and we'll say we get message because this is what we want to print out and show.
And then the next thing is how long we want this to last.
Well just keep us nice and short and then we'll show this.
Hopefully this will either log in sign up the user or tell them why this didn't work out.
So with this we'll go ahead and run the emulator here.
Now I have to admit this isn't the greatest situation and the biggest pitfall that I can see if someone
puts in the incorrect user name all of a sudden will make a new user for them with you know whatever
password they had entered in so they may think that they had logged in when in reality they had just
created a new user so there can be some confusion that way.
But I thought it would be an interesting exercise to see hey how could we make this just that much simpler
for the user right.
Like all they do is put in a user name and password.
And if they're logging in.
Boom get them in.
If they're trying to sign up then we'll sign them up.
But as I said there are some drawbacks to that.
So let's go ahead and give us a test.
We're going to need to have dog cat open here.
Let's try first user name of Nick password one two three four will try to sign up.
Log in.
So let's go ahead and take a look at what we got so we didn't see anything I said log success which
tells us we came down to this statement and look we had Sign-Up success.
And if I hit this button again we now see logons success.
That's pretty great right.
But let's say I put in the wrong password here like and add an extra letter there.
Well then we get an error that says an account already exists for this username.
So again this isn't the ideal situation because we would want to then present a message that says hey
you know you had entered in the wrong like the username and password don't match up.
But in this case we're getting the sign up here.
So not everything's perfect here.
And we also have another issue that for example let's say there's no password here.
And we try and do is sign up.
Well the air that we're printing out here it's kind of a nasty one right.
Like we've got this Java Lang illegals exception I don't want to say password cannot be missing or blank.
So in order to fix that we're going to come here to where we're just taking this message which gives
us a string and we're going to do a little bit of string magic here.
In order to say hey we just want everything after the first space because in those text messages it's
this nice job.
Long Java thing colon space and then that message.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to take our e get message and then on this we're going
to say Dot sub string just like this and the substring that we want is easy to get message and we're
going to do this get message and then on this we're going to do dot index of.
And we're going to pass in a space.
So it's saying go to wherever the first space is and that's where we want to start our substring.
OK so with this in place let's go ahead and run this on our emulator here.
And we should see a successful log and slash Sign-Up screen.
It's a great start to our app.
So we'll see your honor app open up here.
Let's say I type in Nick but no password I sign up.
Look at that password cannot be missing or blank.
Great stuff.
OK.
So with this all in place we're ready to move on to the next lecture and keep driving on this Twitter
app.