All right let's go ahead and get started with talking about how it is that we can save data permanently
inside of our apps and we kind of had the big example from last time when we tried to save our favorite
memorable places.
And every time we reopened the app essentially everything that we had just saved those memorable places
they were gone.
So there's a couple of ways that you can save data inside of Android.
You can work with shared preferences.
That's where we're going to cover right now.
You can work with databases that's kind of the more big a robust option there.
And for different apps different situations are going to you know the share preferences versus the database
is going to work better.
There's all sorts of different use cases out there.
But let's go ahead and start first with our shared preferences.
We're going to learn about that make an app or two and then we're going to move on to databases and
talk about that and again make an app or two there.
So let's go ahead and start a new Android studio project to learn about shared preferences Let's go
ahead and just make that the name of our out of our shared preferences.
Excellent.
We'll just do the default for all this good stuff and we'll get moving forward.
So the basic idea was shared preferences is supposed to contain small amounts of information.
So ideally you know maybe the user has for example the way they want the background color in the app
to look or if they've chosen to have dates displayed in 24 hour increments versus the 12 with AM PM
I don't know just little tiny things you know you should be able to save inside of the shared preferences.
Now if you're making some super big robust app right where you're saving a ton of data shared preferences
are going to really get stretched.
In fact when we go and apply this to our memorable places app you'll see how it kind of has some limitations
there.
But enough with that let's go just go ahead and dive in with an example so we don't need to do any lay
out stuff here.
This is all going to be code for the beginning part of this.
So first let's just talk about how we get to the shared preferences.
Well there's a class called Shared preferences and it looks like I've type too early that an android
studio hasn't had a chance to catch up to me.
So we'll go ahead give us a second we go so we get our shared preferences.
I'm just going to call this lowercase shared preferences and lets give ourselves some room to type.
So this should be equal to this.
Does it get shared preferences so this kind of gets us to where those are stored.
Now you want to go ahead and reference or the first thing the name that it's looking for this parameter
here is it's want to know what the name of the app is.
So lucky for us if we just go up to where it says package if we just copy exactly what's up there we
want to copy paste that right below.
That's what we're looking for.
OK.
Now the next thing that it's asking for here is it's asking you know how is it that you want this to
be saved.
So if we type out capital context on text dot there's a couple of different options in here.
But we want mode and we want private.
So let's add a semi-colon at the end there.
So the basic idea here is that you can have shared preferences that can be shared between apps like
if you have a series of apps that you know you all want to use sort of the same combined piece of data
you can do that but in our situation we want all this information just for apps.
That's why I provided our app name and said hey we want mode private.
Just keep things right here.
OK.
Now that we've got that in place let me go ahead and walk you through a very quick example so the things
that you can share save inside of shared preferences there like strings arrays ints doubles kind of
basic types of information.
So let's go ahead and just try and save a string for example.
So we're going to get access to these shared preferences that we had before.
Notice the lowercase shared preferences so they shared preferences don't edit because we want to alter
save some information in there and we're going to say Dot put.
And this will show you the different things that you can put in there for example booleans floats long
strings of string set.
Right.
So in our case we just want to learn how to add a string.
So first you have to give a name to the string.
This is not the actual string that you want to save.
So in this example let's save you know what the.
Let's say we have an app that takes in a user name right whatever the user wants to call themselves.
If we're taking in a username the first string should be called a user name right.
That's not what the user typed in.
It's just saying hey the thing that we're trying to save is a user name.
This is kind of similar to when we were working with extras right.
Whenever we put an extra into an intent we had to give it a name so we pulled it back out we could grab
that.
So then the next piece of information the next string that we want to add in here is the actual name.
So if it was my user name I'd want you know my username to be something like Nick.
So I want to put a string inside of shared preferences called user name but it holds the actual value
of Nick J.
So once we've got that you want to do a dot apply.
That essentially saves that into the shared preferences.
Now if you go ahead and grab information out of the shared preferences right.
This right here this is putting information into the shared preferences we're editing there.
Now to get information back out again we're going to type out shared preferences.
But in this case we're going to dot get.
And you can see we can get strings longs floats booleans all this awesome stuff so we want to go ahead
and get a string.
So we're going to say get string.
Now it's going to ask us for the name of what it is that we're looking for.
So in this case we'll just provide user name like we have right there.
And the next thing that we need to provide here is a default value.
So this is just in case you know it's not able to find anything under the user name and it's going to
give back sort of the default information so we'll just put an empty string here to say hey if you can't
find anything just give us an empty string.
All right so this will kick us back a string.
Let's go ahead and save the somewhere song say capital string user name should be equal to this and
to confirm that this is working.
And I should get our emulator up and run in the background because that does take a second to get going.
I'm going to go ahead and say All right let's log out this information.
So I'll say opes.
Not that big thing.
Oh and looks like I'd want to try and run that one more time.
Says it's already running.
You mean it's just being finicky.
I don't know.
But remember we want to log out some information so we'll say log I.
And we want to first say that you know something like this is the username and then we'll go ahead and
provide whatever's inside of that user name string just like that.
Now that we've got this all in place let's go ahead and see.
Oh yeah our emulator still kicking up there so I'll go ahead and start the video once this loads up.
All right we've finally got the app to open up here.
Go ahead and check log cat see if we've got anything that says something like this is username.
So go ahead.
Move up for a second here.
Not seen anything.
Oh there it is.
This is the username Nic.
OK.
So this worked and just just to kind of prove that this is actually working and that you know this wasn't
just some sort of fluke that oh we just made it here saved it does not actually saved in there.
Let's go ahead and comment out this line of code where we save in the name Nick.
And let's just say you know open up the app go and try and pull something called user name OK.
So we'll go ahead and hit run here.
This is sort of our test to see hate was able to save the information that we put inside of shared preferences
last time.
So app opens up.
Look at that.
This is the username Nick.
So this means we were successfully from last time able to save some information and this time we didn't
put anything inside we just simply said pull out whatever's inside of username and we were able to do
that.
OK.
So give yourself a nice little pat on the back.
You've successfully saved your very first thing inside of shared preferences.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and comment out the rest of this code for a second here because I'm going to show
you then how we can save an array of things because remember with our memorable places app we wanted
to save an array of the places and the particular locations where they were associated with right like
we want all that information.
And the problem is right now if we go to like shared preferences dot and we want to say put whatever
are we have to do share preferences not at first.
Here we go.
Put right like we can only do put string put Boullion and you might be wondering Well how's all of that
supposed to work.
Well let me show you here.
So the first thing we've got to do is you got to create an array list so let's just say we want to save
an array list of some friends.
So we'll just say array list that's supposed to be out of a bunch of strings and we'll just call it
friends.
OK.
So this is equal to a new list.
So I mean call on that and then let's add some friends in here so say friends and I misspelled friends
up here wonder why the autocomplete wasn't going friends that add maybe add Fido friends that had let's
say had like Sarah in there and we'll do one more.
Say friends dot finish and remove Teske friends Dot had said our last friend Jones.
OK so we've got an array list of three items in there.
Simple enough right.
But again if you were wondering.
OK so I've got this now fresh array list.
I go to my shared preferences I say Dot added on this and I'm going to put.
But we can only put a string boolean float in long or string set now might be tempting to do the string
set because you know sets kind of like arrays except for sets don't hold order.
They just hold uniqueness so we could have an issue if we have duplicate items.
But even more like with a memorable places we want to make sure it's in a particular order and you know
maybe our friends here this is our ranking of our top friends and that you know we want it to stay the
same.
So something that we can do is we can.
Cyril serialise this array list and turn it into a string and serialising basically it's kind of like
turning when we turned our data into Jason Jason back into data.
It's a way to kind of turn everything into a string.
And so that then we can pull it back out.
So in order to do this I mean ultimately what we're going to do is put a string but we're gonna have
to serialize this information first.
So we're going to go up to Android studio file new and we want to add a new class.
So just go here to Java class and the name that we're looking for here is object serial
Isar.
Make sure we get that spelled correctly S E R I know ICR K once you've got that go ahead and hit OK.
And then there's this class called object Serializer that allows you to do this with Java objects although
Rob has created one specifically for this course that's pretty close to the original it just handles
exceptions a little bit differently.
So for this one just go ahead and go to Android
Android of course.
Dot com flash object Serializer dot HCM L K.
So if you go ahead and go to this page this is going to contain the code that Rob has created for us
that's going to allow us to serialize the stuff.
So again this is really close to the object Serializer that we have in Java.
I mean if you want to know more information about this just go ahead and type out object Serializer
or Java and you can see what that looks like.
But for our course here let's go ahead and copy this code and we'll come back to android studio and
we'll just go ahead and select everything except for that top package part can and we'll go ahead and
paste that information in there.
OK.
So basically the code inside of here it allows us to again turn something and serialize it and I'll
show you how to use it now.
So we're going to come back here.
Remember we want to do a put string but before that now what we're going to do is we're going to make
a new object from this so we're going to see a capital object Serializer dot the serialise excuse me
here.
So we've got this.
And we want to say objects Serializer the DC realized when we want to like undo it but want to say serialise.
And we're going to pass in our friends array list just like that.
And once we've gone ahead and done that then this should give us back a string.
Now we're getting a little bit of a thing here because we got to surround this with a try catch because
something might go wrong here and I'm going extend this out to be just a straight up exception.
But really this is all we need in order to make things work like this will give us back a proper string.
So what we're going to do is I'm going to cut this line of code here.
Paste it.
And so the string that we're going to put in is actually just going to be all just copy this excuse
me cut it and paste it right inside of there or put our semi-colon at the end.
And this essentially will take our array list here and it's going to turn it into one single stream.
OK.
So once we've gone ahead and done this we want to make sure that we apply all of it.
So we're going to do it dots apply at the end there.
And let's see oh with this I forgot we've got to put a name inside of here so make sure you have double
quotes and then a comma.
So just like before when we were saying you know this is user name right.
Like we have to give some sort of name here let's call this just simply friends.
OK.
So now putting in a string called friends and we're using this object Serializer to turn this list of
friends into that now.
Something I think we should do.
That will be just kind of interesting is to see what the serialise string looks like.
Let's go ahead and just larget So it's a log.
And we're going to pass inside of here.
The name friends will go ahead and paste that.
And then let's go and add this whole thing here.
OK.
Because I will you know kind of giving you an idea of what's going on in the background here.
But once we go ahead and have this in place let's talk about how we can then take these friends back
out.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create an array list of strings and let's just go ahead
and call this new friends because this is going to be the information coming out of shared preferences
so we'll have this equal to a new array list.
Great.
And then this is the part where we take our new friends and we set it equal to the DC or realization
of something.
So we're going to say here capital object Serializer dot de serialise gay and you can see that it was
looking for a string inside of here.
So the string that we want to pass It is whatever we get back from the shared preferences so in here
we're going to type shared preferences dot get string and we've got to provide them what name we're
looking for and so that's lowercase friends.
And then the next thing is we have to provide some sort of default value.
Now it's a little bit tempting here to just put in an empty string but for some reason we aren't able
to get back the proper piece of information.
Well then we would just want to pass in you know like the serializer is going to break.
So in this case we want to pass in just a new serialized empty array list.
I know it sounds a little bit confusing here but that's essentially what we're looking for so we're
going to pass inside of here.
Object Serializer dot serialise and we're going to do a new array list of type string.
OK.
So again nothing inside of here.
In fact we got that open and close parentheses.
But essentially what that does is it allows us to put in and give back an empty string just in case.
So let's go ahead and surround this also with a try catch.
So do a try here.
Then we'll go ahead and catch it with exception easy and we'll do our Iuda print
stack trace.
Now the last piece of information that we've got to do to make this work is we have to cast back this
object Serializer to say hey that this thing's going to come back as an array list.
So what we're going to do is just put our parentheses here and say hey this thing is going to come back
as an array list of type string.
So you can even autocomplete help us out there to get that all working.
Now let's go ahead and run that.
So there's a couple cool things that I want to check out here we should one make sure that you know
when we do this log we want to see how it did the serialization stuff but then we also want to print
out or log out this new friends which I guess I forgot to do so let's go ahead and do that on the say
log I.
And we want to log out new friends.
I guess I should call it first in a string we'll say new friends just like that.
And then we're going to pass in new friends dot to street.
So there's two logs that we're looking for the first one is how did the serialization.
And then the second one is that we're going to get back the new friends Israel is to make sure we got
back everything correctly so let's run this now get our emulator up here get log cat to
and here it comes.
App opens up and let's go ahead and scroll see what we got.
So first off we can very simply see here that new friends the successfully turned it into Fido Sarah
Jones right.
And that was the exact order that we had filed Asser phyto Sarah Jones.
Right.
We got those back.
That works completely just like we were hoping for.
Now the surprising part when we said turn our friends list into a serialized thing which turns it into
a string.
Look at what it gave us this.
I mean it to us as humans.
This just looks like absolute jibberish but to Java it will be able to take this and it did successfully
turn it back into an array list.
And this is all about sort of machines being able to talk to machines efficiently in a very efficient
way.
So I know it looks a little bit crazy but I want you to sort of see how the sausage is made here with
all of that.
Now just like we did earlier just to confirm that this is all working.
Let's go ahead and comment out all the code where we add in our friends array list so let's go ahead
and do a multi line start in there and we'll end it there.
And I just want to see if we can log out the new friends from what should be saved inside of shared
preferences.
So go ahead and run this and see what we get back.
OK so looks like the emulator opened up so let's open up Blog Cat and look at that.
We get Fido Sarah and Jones so we know for sure that we were able to save in that information and pull
it back and turn it into an array.
It's pretty cool stuff there.
All right with all of this in place it's now time to move back into our memorable places app and apply
this so that we will be able to successfully you know save those places from session to session.
Now I'm going to offer this is a challenge right.
I just Tochtli this new skill and I want you to apply it to our previous project.
Of course if you're not feeling 100 percent comfortable you can just go ahead watch it with me.
But I would recommend going and giving this a try.
So if you're so inclined go fix memorable places so that it will save in the places into shared preferences.
Go ahead.
Hit pause that.
All right so we want to make changes to our memorable places absolute's go ahead and open that.
I'm going to go to my recent projects and look there's a memorable places so don't open this up in a
new window here.
Now in order to work with this we're going to need that object Serializer class that we had before right
here from Rob.
It's actually going to go ahead and just copy this name so that I make sure I don't misspell it.
And in this new project is a file class paste and object serializer.
I'm going to go back to Rob's code copy of all of this back to android studio make sure I keep the package
but then paste in all that information.
OK so that's a nice starting point for us then.
Let's go ahead and move over to our maps activity.
OK so the place that we want to make some changes to here is whenever we are going to be you know saving
a new piece of information.
Right.
And so right now whenever someone does one of these long presses you know we go through all this information
to get the address come down here and then we have the marker and then right now we're adding that new
address into you know the places array list and we're adding the lat long object into the locations
and we say hey you know this view go notify yourself of all these new changes and that stuff is all
fine that's good.
But then after this.
This is where we want to say hey what's inside of this place is re what's inside these locations.
Let's go ahead and save these things into shared preferences and then afterwards we'll still do that
toast to say the location was saved.
So what we want to do here is first get access to our shared preferences.
So we'll just say shared preferences is equal to this don't get shared preferences and then we'll go
ahead and pass in the name of our app which is up here at the top excellent and we'll paste that then
we've got to go ahead and say how we want this to be saved and we want this to be private so we're going
to do mode private and add ours semi-colon there.
OK.
So that gives us access to shared preferences then what we've got to do is we've got to start to say
things so for the places array list we know how to save an array list via a string.
Right.
We just did that with the whole serialization stuff.
So let's go ahead and create first a try catch because we're going to need that.
So try and catch where you look for the old exception we will print that out.
Awesome.
And then the code that we want to run inside of here is we're going to get access to our shared preferences
we want to do an edit because we're trying to save.
So we're going to say edit and we want to put a string.
And this is going to be for the places R-ALA So just let's go ahead and type out lowercase places just
like that.
And then the next thing that we want to do is you want to serialize the places array list.
So all say capital objects Serializer dot serialise.
And again what we want to pass in is this main activity that places all this type out main activity
places just like that.
OK.
Once we've done that we want to do a apply to sort of save our information there and that's all it takes
in order to save the places array list inside of them.
Now when it comes to locations it's a little bit trickier because places let me go ahead and go back
to that man activity so you can see this places is an array list of string objects where locations is
an array list of lat long objects and the serializer class that we have isn't able to take a lat long
object and serialize it into a big string.
It can work with like strings doubles ints floats kind of the basic types.
But for a lat long that's not one of the options for us so we kind of have to deconstruct or longs in
order to do all of this and essentially all that all out long is a latitude and longitude is sort of
right there in the name.
So what we're going to do is first we're going to get create two new array lists for latitude and longitude
longitude So we're going to say let's make an array list.
And it's important we want these to be strings because an array list of strings can be saved and serialized
into shared data.
All say a list of strings that we'll call latitudes is going to be equal to a new array list just like
that.
And we're going to copy this so that we can paste it down below and say we also want to do this for
longitudes.
OK so we have this new array of risk list for latitude and longitude and we want to fill these up with
the correct information so probably best to do that with a for loop.
So let's go ahead and make a for loop here.
Was this do our ints is equal to zero.
Classic.
Then we want to go ahead and do this for however many things are in the locations array and so we're
going to go ahead and type out.
I well in fact if we're doing a for loop here maybe it's better to do a for loop where we don't use
AI and we just move through each of the objects.
So in fact let's go ahead and change this we're going to do lat long and I'm going to call this cord's
for coordinate.
And we're going to say Do this for main activity locations.
So this says go ahead and loop through everything inside of locations that way this will make it just
a little bit easier to work with because each time it just gives us a different coordinate.
So now we can say latitudes dot add and what we need to do is we need to turn that double into a string
so we're going to say a capital double to string and then we're going to pass and chord dot latitude
so that is going to fill up our latitude array list and let's go ahead and copy and paste this for our
longitude so unimportant that you change this to longitudes and you change this to longitude there.
All right so now that we have that for loop in place that means we now have two array lists that we
can save in the shared preferences.
So I'm going to go ahead and just copy this line of code right where we are right now serializing the
places.
And I'm just going to paste it twice for our latitudes and longitudes and I'm going to call the string
for this one lapse and I'm going to call this one lawns and I'm just going.
Rather than saying main activity up places is going to be latitudes and this is going to be longitudes.
Well it looks like we missed.
Oh no we just had the places.
We go.
So now we are essentially saving three different light array lists into shared preferences.
Right we're doing the places.
But then also this new latitude and longitudes.
All right.
So with those pieces in place let's go ahead and just make sure our app works as it is right now so
let's go ahead and run this on our emulator.
And really the next step for us is we just want to make sure that we can get this information out of
our app successfully meaning that when we open the app again that we can pull that information.
So we'll wait for this app to open up.
There it is.
And let's say we add a new place and let's go ahead and give it a position so that we can not be in
the middle of the ocean.
Yeah we're back in New York so I when to do a long press year on the map and look at that location saved.
So we should have something saved there but we don't have any code so that if we were to example open
this app again right like if I did a double click on this
that's shared preferences and oh no I want to do this memorable places.
OK I got to go home first.
No I should not have long press that.
There we go.
OK.
So let's say I go home and then I double click this and I X out.
This is driving me nuts.
Supposed to be able to.
OK and let's try it one time.
I guess it only needed one click.
But if I close out of memorable places and then I come back and I open it up
there's memorable places it should have had my location saved but it didn't.
So that's the code that we want to right now.
So that's going to be inside of our main activity right when the main activity opens up here and it's
listing everything in that list view.
This is where we want to show other locations from the shared preferences.
So here inside of main activity before we go ahead and do this places dot ad and all that good stuff
right.
We want to go ahead and write a little bit of code before that.
So up here at the top first thing that we got to do is we've got to get access to our shared preferences.
So again just shared preferences lowercase shared preferences is equal to this get shared preferences
and provide the name of the app and go ahead and copy and paste that and then also want to go see a
capital context dot moed private.
So that gives us access to shared preferences.
The next thing that we want to do is we want to be able to have the array lists for the latitudes in
the longitudes.
So let's just go ahead and create new array list that's going to hold a bunch of strings and we'll just
call this in fact let's just go back to the maps activity.
We're going to copy these to array lists because they're essentially going to have the exact same name.
We'll just go ahead and paste it right like that.
OK.
So we're making our way lists of latitudes and longitudes.
Then we want to go and attempt to pull this out of shared preferences.
Let's get a try catch ready.
There our trying.
And then we'll just catch any and all exception that we'll call each and go ahead and print that out.
All right.
So inside of the trial now this is where we want to try and go and get things so the first thing let's
just go ahead and get the places.
So we're going to say places is equal to and we want to get to object Serializer dot de serialized so
this is looking for strings so let's go ahead and give it a string.
We're going to say let's go to our shared preferences dot get string and we have to provide the name
first of what we're looking for in this case we're just looking for places that will go ahead and put
that.
And then we have to give it you know some sort of example or default in case we weren't able to get
things back.
So let's go back to here where we were adding in our default and oh no we did that in the other application.
So let's go back to our shared preferences.
Remember when we just created said hey object Serializer make a new array less blah blah blah we'll
get all of them in place so just go ahead and copy that come back to our other project here and go back
to main activity and we'll paste that right inside.
OK.
So with this we have to go ahead and cast this to say this is going to come back as an array list of
strings.
And that is all it takes to get our places.
But the next thing that we need to do here is we need to go get the latitudes and longitudes So it's
kind of eerily similar to this line of code.
So in fact let's just go ahead.
Don't forget your semi-colon.
Let's go ahead and copy this line of code and we will paste it twice so that we can change it for the
latitudes and longitudes.
So in this case we're going to say latitudes and when we come down here for places Remember we call
this Latz Let's confirm and we call that Latz and lawns.
So we're going to get our laps.
This one we're going to get our lawns and we'll just change this one to longitudes.
OK.
So with all that information in place that should go ahead and grab each of the things right it should
grab the places latitudes and longitudes.
Now if this is the case you know we want to go ahead and we have a little bit of a tricky situation
here right and that's what these latitude longitude these ultimately need to go and fill up our locations
array list.
And so you know we're going to have to do a little bit of work to make that happen now before we do
any of that.
We need to clear out everything here to make sure that we're working with fresh array list so places
to clear.
We want to do the same for the latitudes.
Clear wanna do this for our longitudes.
Clear.
And we also want to do this for our locations.
Let's just go ahead clear out all of these arrays make sure nothing's inside of there that we can start
fresh.
OK so we've done all that clearing them we're going to come down here and say after we've done all this
try catch stuff.
We want to do a check and make sure that we can actually take these latitude longitude and put them
into locations.
So first let's read an if statement here and this statement is just going to check and see if we have
the proper arrays that we're looking for.
So first let's go ahead and check places we're going to see if places Dotts size is greater than zero.
And we're going to say and we want to go ahead and check latitude sort of say latitudes that size is
greater than zero.
And if longitudes size is greater than zero.
So this essentially says we're not moving forward unless we've got latitudes longitudes and places arrays.
Then the next check that we're going to see is make sure that the latitudes and longitudes are the exact
same size as the places.
So we'll do another statement here and this time we're going to say places dot signs and check and see
if this is a doubles equal sign equal to latitudes dot size and let's do the same thing for the longitude
will say places that size is equal to longitude size.
OK.
So that's going to be a quick test for us.
Make sure that everything's you know of the same size here.
Now if that is the case then we're going to go ahead and move forward by doing a for loop and this is
where we're going to take the latitudes and longitudes in merge them into the locations array list.
So we're going to say four and this time we actually do want to go ahead and use an eye because we're
going to be working with two different arrays less here.
So when I say it is equal to zero as long as it is less than the latitudes that size and you could have
chosen places latitudes longitudes because we just checked here that they were all the same size.
And then we'll just go ahead and say I.
Plus plus.
OK.
So now that we're here this is where we sort of add everything together so we're going to say locations
not and and remember it's looking for a lat long objects are going to say new lat long.
And it's just looking forward to doubles and this is the latitude and longitude.
So the first one we'll say the capitol double parce double so if we pass this the string will go ahead
and turn to a double so it will just simply say latitudes not get at a high tank.
And then we also want to do this for our longitudes.
And I say double parse double.
We're going to say and longitudes not yet and that will pass in an index.
I can say let's not forget our semi-colon there.
So this is the line of code that sort of reconstructs everything and adds all of that back together.
Now the last thing that we need to do is we need to have an else statement on here so if these things
aren't the same size right.
All that information if they're stopped for some reason they didn't come back.
Well that probably means that this is the first time that the apps been open.
So in that case this is where we'd want to add you know a new item into places and location right for
the very first ones who will go ahead and place that code right inside there.
OK.
So with that in place let's go ahead and run our app see what it looks like.
This is sort of a big moment of truth for us.
So looks like everything finished up it's going to relaunch our app.
So here you can see or already had a location from before so that should tell us you know that we were
in a pretty good location but let's you know go pick a new place on the map here something on Rikers
Island.
OK.
So if I hit the back button look at that.
There's something on Hazon street if we click on it it's going to take us back there.
Now let's go ahead and say you know we do our double click here.
I think only one click.
I keep wanting to do double but if I hit the X on memorable places so we've essentially cleared out
the app right like when we come back to it here and we open it up.
Oh my goodness look at that.
It has the same locations that we can click on these and get back to them in just a really prove that
this is the case.
I'm going to go ahead and run this app one more time on the emulator so you can see whether we physically
close out of the app or we just relaunch it here from Android studio.
Look at that.
The information is saved here.
So give yourself a nice big pat on the back.
We turn to what essentially was an app with a ton of promise but didn't ultimately deliver because it
didn't say anything and now it's completely functional.
So you did see we had a little bit of struggle here right with this whole having to take the lat long
objects put them into two separate rainless save those and pull them back out then recreate the locations
like it was kind of messy so you'll notice as we go through and learn about databases there will be
some situations where it's like oh the database makes sense but there will be also be situations where
the shared preferences makes sense.
We're going to making notes app that you'll say oh yeah that's definitely a good idea there.
So we have two Android skills that we need to learn before we go ahead and make the notes apps all going
to go ahead and cover those first then we'll go make that notes out OK.
So let's keep truckin.