Hello and welcome to the lecture where we're gonna do a little bit of prep work before we dive into
making our guest the celebrity app.
Basically in order to get all these celebrities and get the right information and images and stuff like
that we're going to have to be able to work with text and be a little bit more advanced with how we
can work with string.
So there's this Web site that I found posh 24 dot SC slash Candace SA 4.
I'm not exactly sure the whole background behind the site but they seem to have a top one hundred of
celebrities who knows how they go ahead and choose these.
But this is gonna be a great resource for us to say oh look here's the top 100 celebrities and pictures
of them.
Now in order to get access to them if we go ahead and inspect the page source again depending if you're
Chrome or Firefox it might be different how you get to that but if you right click you should be able
to see that.
But at some point you know if you scroll down here you can see there's like different sections for everybody
so here's like the Taylor Swift section and here's the link to the image of her.
And then also in the alt tag like there's her name and so there's Taylor Swift and then Blake Shelton
and then Sophia Ritchie and like if you just kind of go down through here like you can see each celebrity
has their own little thing and so it's our job to be able to find sort of take this whole H team and
document as a big string and pass it to say Oh hey what's the you are all for this celebrity and what
is the name for the celebrity if we can do that we're gonna be able to make our next app so in order
to learn this we're gonna move over to brow x y dot com just to get a little bit of practice here so
let's go ahead and hit try on the hello world thing and hit start just to get this up and running and
that looks really weird on my computer how all that Texas laid out and then open up maybe something
like Firefox and we'll open up the same Web site but just so that you can see it a little bit better
there at the try button.
Yeah that's looking a lot better.
Guess I'll hit start.
Make sure we get the proper output there.
Yep.
Looks good.
Now the first thing that I want to show you is how we can split a string which is basically taking a
big string and splitting it into smaller pieces.
So in order to do that we have to make our big string first.
So I'm going to go ahead and make a string and I'll simply just call my string and I'll set this equal
to basically a bunch of names so I'm going to have Nick X Sean X Fido X Sarah.
So I'm sort of just listing out a bunch of names with sort of these X's in between and then what we
can do is we can split this string into smaller pieces and what that actually does is it gives us a
string array.
So when I say string with the square brackets which gets us the string array and we're going to call
this may be split string and this will be equal to my string right.
This variable that we just created up there dot split.
And with that we have to say how it is that we want to split the string up and in this case we want
to go ahead and split it up by X or we're saying hey wherever there's an X that's where you should cut
this up.
I forgot the semicolon up there but if we've successfully done this we should be able to print it out
and see what this array looks like.
Now in order to do that we're gonna have to import some core code here so when I say import Java dot
you till dot capital arrays.
All right then we'll come down here and say system dot out the print line and we are going to print
out arrays with an S dot to capital string and inside of there we're going to add these split string.
Let me make sure I don't forget my capital there and the semicolon.
So let's go ahead and hit start here and when we do this C we're loading look at that.
We have Nick Sean Fido Sarah and it looks pretty good although we do have one issue and it's you know
there's kind of some random spaces like why is there space in front of Sean and you know Fido and like
space in front Sarah but not after but there was space after Nick.
Like it's kind of weird right.
Well the issue is is when we do a split you basically say whenever you find this character take whatever
was before it and you know put a slice and then you know start taking whatever after it.
So if we literally are slicing on these X pieces we're getting Nick space and then we're getting space
Sean space space Fido space and space Sarah.
So if we want to fix this we can go into the head and say oh let's go ahead and split on space x space
so then it will take you know anything that's in between those two.
So let's go ahead and hit start and you'll notice when we do this it's just very simply Nick.
Sean Fido Sarah.
We don't have any of the extra spaces in there.
All right so let's go ahead and try this with an actual word here.
This will be a little bit fun.
So we're gonna make a new string here and it's gonna be Mississippi for the Mississippi Roper so am
I SSI SSI P P I that was the little song I learned on the playground but so we're gonna make this new
string called River.
That's Mississippi and let's say we want to split this string everywhere that there's an S..
So let's go ahead and put an s in here.
So we're gonna take this new string River and we're going to split it wherever there's an S and then
we'll still call the split string and go ahead and print that out but go ahead hit the start button
here and you'll notice it's pretty interesting with what we get.
So we have M I.
And then then s come so you would expect that.
Right.
Like we do a split here but then there's another S and there's no characters or anything in between
it.
So the next object we get in this array of strings is actually an empty string like there's just nothing
inside of it.
Then there's an eye and you know then there's another S so then we get like an empty string and then
there's the I BPI.
So when you're doing a split you need to know that it is possible to get you know empty strings inside
of there if you have two things right up next to each other.
Now the next thing that I want to talk about is let's keep this string for the River Mississippi.
But rather than doing a split on this we can actually go get a substring which is a way to just get
a portion of the bigger string and so we're gonna go ahead and create a new string which we'll call
river part.
And this is going to be equal to the river string dot and then we're gonna type out sub string.
And this allows us to provide you know the numbers of where it is that we want to cut this.
So for example if I put it to column five I'll go ahead and run this and you'll see what we get here.
And we want to now print out.
River part instead of doing this whole arrays to string stuff.
So let's go ahead and run that and there we go.
We get SSI.
So here's basically what's happening.
So when you get these substring of a string you the first number that you provide is where you want
to start.
So if we start counting this with a zero based index we'd go 0 1 2 and that would give us this beginning
s and then the second number that we provide is where it is that you want to stop.
So 0 1 2 3 4 5.
It's basically the second ask but it doesn't include that one it's basically saying that's where I want
to stop.
So if we say 0 1 2 3 4 and then stop before we use 5.
That's how that works.
OK.
So a little bit of a challenge for you.
I want you to write the code so that you can go get the term from this string.
I SSI so I want you to get back to substring of I S S I can.
Go ahead hit pause on your video and write the code in order for that to happen.
Now OK.
So hopefully that went well for you.
You would have had to just count on this thing.
So there's two ISIS size that you could choose.
So the first one would be 0 1.
So we changed this to one and then we go 0 1 2 3 4 5.
We'd keep that at five.
If we go ahead and run that we get EI SSI.
There's also a second I SSI there and that's 0 1 2 3 4.
So we could put a four inside of there and then go fives five six seven eight so eight is that p we
don't want the P so we'll put eight.
That's our stopping point.
So if we do four and eight for example that will also give us EI SSI.
OK.
So pretty cool how that all works there but there's still yet another way that we can work with these
strings which is pretty cool and it's something called regex and Reg X is really powerful it's not something
unique to Java you it can be used in almost any programming language regex stands for regular expressions
if you'd like to know more.
There's some awesome tutorials online.
If you just search regex plenty of information out there and it can get really complicated really quickly
which is why I don't want to get too intensive with it but I'm gonna show you how we can use it because
the big goal that we have is we want to be able to get all the information about these celebrities and
you know put that into usable information for us so we're gonna keep this string river.
But now we're going to sort of dissect it using regex.
So the first thing that we need to do is we need to create something called a pattern.
So just type out capital pattern and we'll give it the name of P. and we're gonna say capital pattern
dot compile.
And with this we are going to then provide a string inside of here and this is where the actual regex
lives.
So let me go ahead and make some space here.
So inside of this string we need to say what the beginning part that we're looking for so let's say
we want to get everything between M I NPI we want to get the rest of the string that's in the middle
of that so we can provide type out capital M I.
And then this is where we're gonna say to parentheses and then within those parentheses we'll do dot
star question mark.
And then afterwards we're going to type API.
So again don't want to get into all the nitty gritty details of regular expressions but basically what
we're doing here is we're saying Go find it wherever you find M I then go find anything you can until
you hit P I once you find P.I. stop and then give us back this portion so we're basically saying start
at P.I. or start at M I wait till you find P.I. and give us everything in between those two.
OK.
That's what this code is doing then once you have this pattern you need to create something called a
matter.
So I can say match or M is equal to p dot matter and we're gonna pass in the string here.
River OK so once we get this these pieces in place then we need to go ahead and do some code to get
this information out.
So we're going to do a while loop and let's go ahead do the parentheses and then the curly brackets
in inside of here we're gonna say M which is our manager dot find with parentheses and this will basically
go through and try and find this pattern as many times as it can.
And then inside of here we want to do our system thought out up print line but we want to print out
m dot group and inside of the group we're going to pass in the number one and that basically gives us
access to this sort of whatever between M I NPI.
OK so before we can go ahead and run this code there's a little bit that we have to import up at the
top of our code.
So let's go ahead and scroll up to the top here.
We need to say import Java you still dot rejects regex capital pattern and we need to also do this for
the matter.
So I'll just go ahead and copy paste but change this to match.
All right.
So let's go ahead and run this.
See what we get and looks like a probably misspelled something on line 10 pattern Dot.
Oh I misspelled compile compile.
There we go.
Let's start here and look at that.
We get SSI SS IP.
So it basically just grabbed like we had said here everything between my NPI and if you notice if we
copy this and paste it let's do it like three times so we have Mississippi Mississippi Mississippi and
we go ahead and we run this.
You will notice it gets printed out three times and that's because this wall loop keeps looking through
this string until it finds it as many times as it needs to.
OK.
So this is pretty excellent this regex thing.
If you haven't sort of seen the light yet let me sort of show you how this is gonna be applicable to
what we're doing.
If we go back to this code here where we're searching through the celebrities we need to go through
this big thing this big string to where we can find where this images and then also where the celebrity's
name is.
Right.
So we need to kind of go through each of these.
So let's go ahead and grab Taylor Swift I like Taylor Swift and we want to grab just for example sake
everything from this first div down to the second.
So again if you go to this Web site patch 24 that a slash Candice SAR you need to right click into either
inspect element or page source you just need to get to the HDL and copy this chunk here case so the
div class image image with this source all Taylor Swift and that ending div.
So we're going to copy that and we're going to come back to brownout x y and rather than have these
string river we are going to have a new string called H T Mal and this is going to be equal to.
I'll do my double quotes the semicolon and I'm going to paste in that big chunk.
Now a couple of things one we need to get rid of the spacing.
So go ahead and do some deleting and tell this is nice one big thing but then also there's lots of double
quotes or double quotations inside of the string right.
And whenever you have one like Java thinks that this is the end of the string here.
So we need to escape those by putting a backslash and we just everywhere that we see a double quote
If we put a backslash there we can extend this out go ahead and just keep doing that all the way.
That should be our last one.
There we go.
Now this is one big string so my challenge for you is I want you to be able to find a pattern that you'll
be able to determine what the you are L is for Taylor Swift.
OK.
So go ahead.
Hit pause on the video try and get a regex pattern that gets us the U.R.L. OK.
Hit pause.
Now all right.
So hopefully that went well for you.
First what we need to do here is because we have a new String name h t AML.
We're gonna go ahead and paste that in there and so rather than doing the MRI in the P.I. the thing
that we should probably look for before we get the URL is this source equals with the double quote.
OK.
So this is in h t mail you'll see this every time before you see an image and in fact if you want to
be even more careful you could do like this full image named source with that double quotes we'll go
ahead and copy that in a pace that in there and then sort of the ending of the U.R.L..
Is that double quotes will go ahead and copy that one and say that's going to be our ending portion.
So let's go ahead and start this and hit run and look at that.
We successfully got the U.R.L..
So now my next challenge for you is go ahead and make it so that you can get the appropriate name for
the celebrity.
So in this case you should be able to do a separate rejects for Taylor Swift now for this.
You're basically just going to write out the same code here except this time you don't have to re-establish
pattern you can just say you know P is equal to this and Emma's equal to this but you're gonna have
to change a regex code to go ahead and get the name.
So go ahead.
Hit pause now all right.
So hopefully that went well for you.
So when we're looking for the celebrity name we're going to do this.
Ault equals where we escape the quotation so we'll go ahead and put that there and we still I think
just want that double quote as our ending one so we can keep that the same.
Let's go ahead and hit start here and look at that.
We get the image U.R.L. and we get the celebrity name and that's it.
With this information we are an excellent point now where we could take a whole HCM El string here and
be able to run through and say OK I've got this celebrity image this celebrity image this celebrity
image this name this name this name you know it's sort of we can match it up put that in an array and
use it for our guests.
The celebrity app.
So with that let's go ahead and end this lecture but then move on to making that app.