Hello and welcome to the lecture we're we're going to build the guests the celebrity app.
So with this the whole idea is that we're going to have an app that has a picture of a celebrity with
four different names and you're supposed to guess OK which celebrity is this.
And I'm going to guess Mauleon Griffith look that was correct.
Oh I know this one.
Nicki Minaj.
That was correct.
You know if for some reason I said Alec Baldwin It tells me that you were wrong.
If I say it is Vin Diesel right so wrong.
Oh that's Daniel Radcliffe I know that one.
Pixi Yeah I got it.
So anyways kind of a fun little app that you can just try and guess who the top 100 celebrities are
in for this app.
We are going to be using the information from this past 2014 as the flash.
Candace Sarr so we reference this in the previous lecture but just wanted to reiterate this is what
we're going to be using.
So you have the skills to be able to actually go ahead and create this whole app like you have everything
that you would need to do this.
So what I would really encourage you to go do this as a challenge on your own but of course if you need
any help I'm going to be walking you through it through the rest of the lecture.
But see how far you can get with this and maybe just come watch with me when you get stuck on something.
But remember when you go on your own that's where the real learning takes place.
So go ahead get at it.
And good luck.
All right let's go ahead and get started here with a new Android studio project.
We're going to call this guess.
So Bridie just go ahead and do defaults on all of this.
So the basic idea here is that there's going to be an image of a celebrity.
There's going to be four different options to select from.
Of potential names of that celebrity and then you pick one of those.
And the apple either tell you whether you were correct or incorrect.
So let's go ahead and move into the SML here.
Want to get the design side of things working first and then we'll go ahead and start working about
you know downloading stuff and getting images every everything there.
So first thing that we need to add to here is a image view.
And so I'm going to go ahead and just select an image for you and we'll just go ahead and give it some
sort of default color for now as a background.
But with this we want to go ahead and say that it should be a certain distance from the top left and
the right.
But we want these to be much bigger so maybe just 10 on the sides of each of here.
And let's go ahead and change this to actually fill up the space and have this maybe be like 10 there.
The next thing we want to do is we want to add our buttons inside of here and then we'll have the top
button be connected with the image view to get the correct size there so let's go ahead and back to
all I'm going to add a button down here at the bottom of the screen.
So for this button I want this to be 10 from the bottom and it should also be 10 from the left and 10
from the right.
Excellent.
Let's change that.
So it goes ahead and fills up the space.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to copy and paste this button so we have a second button
there now button two.
We're going to go ahead and move up a little bit here and we're going to change its bottom constraint
here to now be a certain distance between the other button and let's change that to be 10.
And we go and we're going to copy button 2 and paste that.
So copy and paste I will have button three and again move button up there.
Delete its bottom constraint and go ahead and have its new spacing be 10 and then one more time here.
Copy Paste we get our fourth button we put up the lead and add and we'll change that to be 10.
Excellent.
So now that we have those things in place we can go ahead and select the image you and now add it's
bottom connection here and we'll go ahead and just make this 10 as well.
And now you can see the image of us taking up the right amount of space there.
So with each of these buttons we want to go ahead and change the text to just be blank.
So if you go ahead and select one and then hit shift to select all those together you can kind of edit
things and mass that's you know a little bit helpful there.
But you know we've got the basics here we've got the image you we've got buttons we're ready to go as
far as the visual side of things go.
But now we need to make it so that we can actually go download the data about the celebrities and then
you know we can then go about putting in particular images and random guesses here.
So let's go back to our main activity here.
And let's just go ahead and write the code that we need in order to actually download the code from
our Web site right.
The posh 24 This is where we're going to get all that data from.
So let's go back to android studio here.
And the first thing that we need to create is our own download task right.
The thing that extends a sync task.
So we're going to say public class and let's go ahead and name it download task.
We're going to say that this extends a sync task hit enter on that.
Now this is going to go back to our classic here where we say string void and then string because we
want it to return X back an actual string object will hover over this and implement the methods there.
So go ahead and hit.
OK.
So as always let's change this to be you are els just to kind of keep consistent there.
And again the big goal of this method is to eventually return a string.
So in order to do this let's go ahead and make a new string that we'll call result and that'll just
be equal to an empty string.
Next thing that we need to do is make a proper u r l object and let's go ahead and hit enter on that.
So we can get the proper imports and then we need an H TTP u r l connection and we'll just simply call
that your all connection and start by setting that equal to no.
All right so there is our set up for that then what we need to do is we're going to convert the string
into a u r l but of course that in several hours things are going to require a try catch.
So we'll do our Try here.
And then a catch that we'll just get any exception that we'll call.
And if there does happen to be an exception we want to do in print stack trace and return.
No.
But then inside of this try the first thing that we need to do is try and convert this string into actual
you IRL.
So say you are l is equal to capital U R L and then go get the first object out of our little Uriel's
pseudo array.
Then once we've got this in place.
Oh I forgot the term new in front of there we go.
Once we got that in place we need to set up our your L connection.
So we'll say this is equal to you r l dot open connection.
And we're going to have to cast this to say that this should be an H.
TTP Yoro connection.
Once we have a U R L connection in place we're going to create our input stream which we'll call I N
and will say you r l connection not get input stream excellent then we need to get our input stream
reader almost you know missing our
bitmap example from last time because it's a little bit less work than having to go through all this
but that's OK we're going to make it through this say new input stream reader and just go ahead and
pass in our input stream and I should probably call that reader.
There we go.
Once we have our reader in place we'll make our inte that we'll call data.
This is going to be equal to the reader not read like sort of moves on to the next one and then we'll
use a while loop to successfully move through everything so we'll say as long as data is not equal to
negative 1.
So then we need to go ahead and make a character which we'll call Current I'll say this is equal to
data.
We need to make sure that we cast this to be char excellent.
After we've done that we're going to say result plus equals current.
Here we go.
And then we are going to take our data and we're going to say this should be equal to our reader reader
so we'll move on to the next one.
Jane So that's all the code that we need in order to get you know the downloading happening.
But then we have to actually provide a u r l and get this up and running.
So then inside of her create we are going to create a download task which will just simply called task
and set the sequel to a new download task.
We also are going to have a string we'll call a result which for the time being we'll just set equal
to no.
And then we need to have a little try catch for actually going out and working this code so well Drew
a try catch again we get any exception we call it the on doing each print stack trace.
All right.
So the actual code that we're going to try here is we need to say task Gadot execute Tang.
It's looking for you or else we'll just put an empty string for now and then we need to do the dot get
the dot get is really important because that's what gives us back the actual string.
And because we're getting back a string that's when we would want to feed it into result and to make
sure that this is working.
Let's go ahead and do a log and let's just log out we get sold say contents of your L should be the
result.
All right.
So with this in place let's go ahead and get the L of this Web site remember GWW posh 24 that see slash
can do SAR.
So go ahead and copy this.
Come back and we'll paste that in there.
Make sure you got that HTP if your browser doesn't automatically add that.
And with all of this let's go ahead and run this on the simulator and see what we get.
And I realize there's one last area here that I forgot to address and that's the inside of our DO IN
BACKGROUND method here we forgot to say return and then return the actual results so we're going to
say return result here and that's going to make this app work a lot better.
Also important to note that you need to go to your Android manifest X amount and add this used permission
for the Internet.
So we've done this a couple of times before but just make sure you add this because since we'll be accessing
data from the Internet we need to have this line somehow.
My app was able to run without it but make sure that you go ahead and add that.
All right.
All right back to getting the app running.
So this will go ahead and load in the emulator now.
Now I do want to point out as you'll probably notice that it takes quite a while to load up the particular
web page and you may see some similar message messages to what you see running here saying that you
know it's processing a lot of stuff.
And this is not the most efficient way to be downloading stuff.
We're going to be covering this more as we move further.
There's actually a lot of great libraries that can do a lot of this stuff for us.
So it's kind of good to know that if things are going slow for you that's expected we're going to cover
better ways to handle this in the future.
But with enough time we will see this e-mail come out right.
This is you know the age to mail for the web page that talks about all the different you know celebrities
and whatnot so this is good.
This means we have access to that HQ mail and now it's just a matter of parsing that and pulling out
the link to the images and also the famous people's names.
All right.
So let's go back to the browser and I just want to look at the source text for this web page right.
So we have inside of here we have all the different you know celebrities right and they've got their
images and their names and so you know we might just think OK we'll just go ahead and search through
here anything that has like an image tag that then has a source.
So if we say image space SIRC it looks pretty good but you notice we have 105 matches which isn't good.
So the first celebrity here Taylor Swift gets that so you know you might say OK is there something at
the bottom that this matches up with if we scroll up.
Yeah we can see that there's some other articles here and that's not necessarily a good point for us.
So one way that we can fix this is we can kind of break up the Web site by something that sort of stinks
like oh hey you know we are now approaching a different part of the Web site.
So for example here this div class equals listed articles or something I it sounds pretty unique.
And let's see if there's really only one of these.
And look at that that only occurs once on the page so we can use this as a split in our string in order
to move forward and say OK we only want the information before this.
So in fact that's what we're going to do.
Let's go back to android studio and we're going to come here to after we get our result and we're going
to do a little bit of work here to sort of split this up parse it in the whole reason for that last
lecture that we had where we were working with all the strings like Mississippi so that we could come
here and do this.
So first thing that we want to do is make a string array or a string array called split result should
be equal to this result dot and this is where we want to do a split and with this split we want to put
in this div class whatever.
Right because this only occurs once so it's going to split it before and after this and we want the
first part of that.
And you'll notice this is an awesome feature of Android studio when we pasted this in.
It automatically you know escaped those double quotes by putting the backslash in front of them.
So that's very nice thank you.
Android studio for that.
Now the next thing that we need to do is we need to be able to do some rejects on this and we're going
to use the exact same code that we had before.
So if we just go back to our Brau X-Y dotcom we should have this code right where we essentially ran
through that HCM code so I'm just going to go ahead and copy that come back to our project I'm going
to paste this in now.
There's a couple of things here so we've got to make sure as we type out pattern we hit enter on this
same thing with the matchers so that we can get the proper stuff imported there will no longer be working
with each.
In fact it's going to be the first item in the split result so we'll say split result.
Give us item at zero index and same thing goes for down here stead of doing that can.
So if this all works if we go ahead and run this we should see you know all the image yourselves and
all the celebrity names working.
So go ahead and give that a run.
Now it's not just enough to go ahead and have these things printout we actually want to put them into
a list so then we can go ahead and use them inside of the different parts of our code.
So let's go ahead and take this moment to go make some a re list up top.
While we're waiting for app to load up here.
So over here at the top of our class for example we're going to make a new array list we want this to
be an array list of type string and we're going to call this one celeb your Elle's came got a spell
that correctly celeb your Elle's and we'll set this equal to a new array list.
We want to make sure that this is a whole array list of string objects.
OK.
And same thing we want to do this but we want to do it for the celeb names so let's go ahead and copy
this.
We'll paste that one more time.
We're going to call this celeb names.
OK so now we have these two lists.
So if we go ahead and look in our logs here it was successfully able to go grab all these cool images
and also the names they're getting.
So again taking a long time I promise there is going to be better ways to handle this.
And it's also worth noting what we're doing here is kind of risky with our code right like inside of
our job file.
This is where we're parsing.
You know this HCM that we get back.
The problem with that is let's say you know posh 24 decides to change how they lay out their code.
They get rid of this Divx thing.
Well that completely breaks our code.
So the more proper way to work with something is using Jasons and API is what we're going to talk about
the incoming lectures I wanted to give you sort of a rough and tumble way of downloading some web content
and being able to use it.
So back to the code we know that this is working so now rather than just logging out the information
let's go ahead and put these into a these array lists.
So we'll start here first where we're getting the images and so we'll go ahead and say celeb your Elle's
dot ad and we're going to go ahead and add that am group and we're going to we want group one there
and bam that's all we need.
We're going to do essentially the same thing but instead with celeb names so we'll go ahead and paste
this and just change this to celeb names and then that will go ahead and give us now to array lists
that are filled up with both celebrity your L's and celebrity names.
So the next step for us is we need to pick one of these celebrity at random and download their image
so that we can display that for the user and then we'll work on getting the name stuff right so we need
to extend another async task to be able to download an image.
So we're going to say public class and you can call this whatever you'd like but I'm going to call it
image downloader and this is going to extend a sync task just like before.
Now with this one we're going to say strings for the progress will be void and it's going to return
back a bitmap.
So go ahead put down their curly bracket this bad boy.
And with that let's go ahead and implement the methods that we need.
Let's go ahead and do that then here inside a bitmap of course everything's got to be inside of a try
catch.
So there's a try.
Here's the catch.
For any and all exceptions we'll call e and we'll go ahead and print out e.
Excellent.
Now inside of our Try this is where we got to do our classic conversion stuff.
So first thing we need to create a new york L which will call u r l and this will be equal to a new
U R L and we want to pass inside of here the string so remember we want to rename this to you or else
and will reference that by saying you or else get us the very first item.
And that's going to be.
Are you at all object now we need to create an h t t p u r l connection.
We'll just call connection and we need to make sure this is cast as an H TDP your L connection.
But this is going to be your all open connection.
OK.
Once we got that in place we're going to say Connection dot connect.
After that we'll go ahead and start an input stream that will just simply call input stream and all
set this equal to connections that get input stream.
All right.
So hopefully this is starting to feel pretty familiar.
We've done this a few times.
Next step for us is we've got to create a bitmap so we're going to say bitmap my bitmap it's going to
be equal to a new bitmap factory.
OK.
And then with that we're going to do dot de-code stream and we're going to go ahead and pass in our
input stream to make that all work.
Then once we have that we have our bitmap we just simply have to return that back.
So I'll say return my bitmap and we just want to make sure in case we catch something here we are going
to return NULL.
Just in case something goes wrong there.
OK.
So this looks pretty good for downloading an image.
Now we have to go about the business of making sure that we can get some sort of random celebrity.
So we'll come down to our on create code.
All right so after we've done all of this about finding the celebrity right or putting them into array
lists then the next thing that we need to do is create some randomness are going to say random that
we'll call rand is equal to new random can then with this random we need to create a chosen celebrity
that we actually need to be accessing this in several places.
So we're going to define this up at the top.
We're going to say inte chosen and I'm going to do a lower case here chosen celeb and will initially
just set that equal to zero.
But then here down on our own create After we've got our Random we'll say chosen celeb should be equal
to random or Rande that next.
And and as far as what you know and how many different possibilities there are.
It should be however many celebrities that we have.
So one way that we can do this is we can go ahead and just say all right however many celeb Uriel's
there are we're going to go ahead and get the count of that.
Excuse me.
What we're looking for is the size and that'll give us back a proper answer.
And then that way we can you know have a number between 0 and whatever it is.
So remember when you're trying to get the next random act like if you're doing zero on Ford you'd have
to put in 41.
But because a list or zero based accounting we can just use the size and that's going to give us an
equal chance to get anybody in that list.
So once we got that in place let's go ahead and fire up our image downloader image downloader and we're
going to go ahead and call this image task.
This is equal to a new image downloader.
All right then with this image task we have to go ahead and get the bitmap out of it.
So we're going to say bitmap let's give it some sort of name we'll maybe call it like celeb image.
It's going to be equal to image task to execute and we're going to have to pass it to your all was just
making an empty string for now and then we want to you get good which gives us that map.
Now as for what you are Ehle we passed through there.
Well this is where we're going to use our chosen celeb and we need to get that from the celebs your
ell's a list so to say celeb you are Elle's got get.
And we're going to pass in the chosen celeb just like that and they'll give us the proper role.
And then once we have that we have to update the image view with whoever the random celebrity is.
So let's get back to our main activity let's see what name we have given this image view.
OK.
So let's go ahead and define this up top will say image view that we'll just simply call it image view
is equal to.
Well I actually will just define it here and then create this is where we'll get it all set up.
So even before we do any of this we'll just say image view equal to find view by id our ID image view.
OK so now that we've got that in place then we'll go ahead and update that image view by saying all
right image you set image bitmap and we'll pass in celeb image and just like that we should have a celebrity
showing up.
So I'll go ahead and get this running.
So if we just sort of follow what's going on here we want our app to go out get the list of celebrities
we're going to do all this sort of crazy parsing here to you know figure out you know who what are the
celebrity image or els what are the celebrity names that are going to put those in the proper array
list then we're going to choose one of those your L's at random and then we're going to go ahead and
download that image and then we want it to display here.
So as I said earlier this can sometimes take a little bit longer than you would enjoy.
But I'll just go ahead and wait for this for a second to pop up.
All right so the app finally opened up here and ran it's course.
We've got the image of some celebrity.
I'm not sure who it is.
So it will be helpful for us to figure out you know do the quiz here fill in these buttons so that we
can get the name and we can figure out who some of these people are.
So the first thing that we need to do is scroll up to the very top here and we need to add a couple
of different properties for handling.
You know what our answers are going to be and who which one of those answers is going to be correct.
So the first thing that we need to do is we need to make an array of string objects and we're going
to go ahead and call this answers and we're going to set this called a new string array of four objects
because we're always going to have four answers so that's something we can know for sure and just always
do.
OK so once we've got that in place we also need to know what the location of the correct answer is going
to be so we'll say it.
Location of correct answer.
And we'll go ahead and for the time being just set that equal to zero though that will be updated.
And I'm also realizing that I have choose in Celeb it should be chosen celeb.
So doing that I'm sure we're going to get a couple of errors down here.
And if we scroll down you know look at that we'll have to delete there have to delete one o there but
I think that should fix everything for us.
OK.
So now that we got those items in place now we can go ahead with actually writing some code to pick
out you know what the correct and incorrect answer should be.
Before we do that I want to point out one thing that we should look at before we do this is just make
sure that you have this image tagged before the SIRC.
If you didn't have this from before you just had SIRC you'll notice that you're going to have some problems
there but things should be pretty clean.
Now that we have that in place.
OK.
With that said first thing that we've got to do is we've got to create or choose the location of the
correct answer.
So if we just type out location of correct answer we're going to set the will the Rand dot next.
And and it could be four possibilities so we'll just put the number four in there and that should work
out OK.
The next thing that we want to do is we want to create a variable to be the location of the incorrect
answer.
So we'll call this incorrect answer location and we'll just go ahead and define this for the time being
and then we'll update it here in a second.
Then we want to do a for loop where we loop through four times to fill in the answers.
So we're going to pay for it equal to zero.
As long as it is less than four we want to do.
Plus plus.
OK.
Go ahead and do our curly brackets there.
Then the next thing that we want to do is first and check see if I is equal to the location of the correct
answer.
So I'll say if I is equal to the location of the correct answer meaning that this should be our correct
one we'll say okay answers at position 0 answers with an S answers that position should be equal to.
We want to go get our celeb names array and we'll do dot get.
And we're going to go ahead and pass in the chosen excuse me only one s now or 1 0 now chosen celeb.
So that's as simple as it is for if it's the correct answer.
Now if it's the false one you should remember this from our number guessing game is that we're going
to have to do a little bit of work to make sure we don't have repeats here.
So first of all we're going to do is we're going to say are incorrect answer location should be equal
to new random numbers I'll say Rand that next ant and we'll go ahead and pass in however many celeb
your L's that we have will say dot sized just like that.
OK.
So that's going to go choose one at random there.
And you know eventually what we want to do is to say OK answers at position.
I want you to be equal to celeb names don't get and we can go ahead and pass in an incorrect answer
or location.
So this is sort of the dream that we want.
But the problem with this one is we could accidentally choose the correct answer amongst them.
So this is where that nifty little while loop comes in handy that we did before.
Right.
We want to say while incorrect answer location is equal to the chosen celeb.
Right so meaning if we accidently got the correct one.
Well then we simply just want to run this line of code again and say let's let's try another random
number and we'll just keep going until we get the correct one.
So once this is in place once we've gone through the entire four loop we want to update the buttons
text.
Now in order to do that we have to have access to those buttons.
Let's go back to our main activity and we'll just work on these different buttons so I'm going to call
this button zero and call.
Yes we want to update this.
I want to update this button to be button 1.
Update we want to update this one to be 0.
Luckily button too.
So that kind of worked out for us and then we just want to update this one to say button three.
So now we have the appropriate names for all those.
The top Here's where we want to set those buttons so will say button and we'll call that button zero
to be the first one.
I'll just copy and paste this three more times.
OK so we've got button one two and three that will come in are on create.
And after this image you here will go ahead and set up all the button so button 0 is equal to find view
by ID card that Id button 0 OK and copy and paste three more times.
So we get all our other buttons all just to update this for button 1 2 and 3.
And we also want 1 2 and 3.
So once we have these in place then we can actually go ahead and set up these buttons properly.
So for instance let's set up the first button will say button 0 that's set text and inside of here we
want to pass hey whatever at answers in position 0.
Go ahead and do that.
And we just want to do this for all four of the buttons.
So that button 1 2 and 3 1 2 and 3.
So let's go ahead and give this a run and see if we get the correct celebrity image with at least one
correct name.
And then you know three false names that you know makes it so the user has to guess.
All right.
The gap opened up.
I'm pretty sure this is Angelina Jolie and that kind of leads us into the next step of our app is we
need a way to sort of test whether our answer is right or wrong.
When we tap on one of these we should know whether we got it right or wrong.
So let's go back to our buttons.
Let's make sure that we have an on click for each of these going to go ahead and select all the buttons
here.
You have got all four of those.
I'm going to give all of these in on quick even though for some reason when I selected all the buttons
that won't let me choose the on click.
There we go.
Makes go way I go self to scroll down here to the on click.
So I'm going to call this celeb chosen and go ahead and have that name.
So that means we have to go back to our code here and make a new function.
So we're going to do public void celeb chosen.
All right and this is where we're going to take in our view that we'll just call you and we'll do our
nice curly brackets there.
So the first thing that we want to do is you want to compare which celebrity was chosen with the one
that is the correct answer.
Now in order to do that we have to have tags for each of these buttons.
So we're going to go ahead and just move to the TX side of things here for a second work through each
of these buttons.
So we need to add a tag to each of these.
And let's go back let's see can we set the tag here.
All right.
So we're going to set the tag for one of these on button 0 just like 0.
So you can see what that text is going to be.
And let's see where is that.
OK.
Android tag 0.
So for Button zero we want that to be zero.
But let's copy and paste this for button 1.
We want this to be a tag of one the other button button too we want that to be too.
And for the top button here we want that to be three games.
So we've set all the tags for our buttons so that now we can come do this awesome if statement here.
So the thing that we want to check is first get access to our view and say Get tag.
All right.
And with this tag we want to convert that to a string and once we've converted the string we want to
see if it is equal to the tag or the number of the correct chosen celebrity.
So inside of here we want to do integer dot to string and the integer that we want to pass and there
is a location of correct answer game.
So this will tell us if we're in this portion and this means that we got the answer right.
So this is where we would want to do a toast.
And with this toast we'll say toast.
Make text inside of here we're going to say get application context.
Then we have to provide the string that we want to know say so will say.
Correct exclamation point.
And then finally we want to provide a toast with a you can choose whether you want it to be long or
short.
I'm going to choose length short just so that we can you know get three or more of these answers and
the user doesn't have the message lingering around too long.
So in the ELTs situation meaning that they got the answer incorrect.
You know we could just go with simply a saying wrong you know just like that but it would be nice to
tell them who the celebrity was so that they were trying to train and for some reason memorize the top
100.
You know they could do that so we'd want to say some message like it was and then we'd want to provide
the actual answer.
So to get that actual answer we'd reference the celeb names get and then we simply just have to pass
in whoever the chosen celeb was.
OK.
So we'll get rid of that semi-colon there and then that should show the answer.
So I'll go ahead and hit run here on the app and we'll be our first live quiz where we can actually
see if we were able to successfully guess who the celebrity is.
So here the app opened up it's our very first live question.
I'm excited about this because I'm not sure my guest is Sheryl Crow.
And I get no such message anywhere.
So my big guess is that when I'm ever I tap on any of these I'm not getting That's because I forgot
to do a dot show at the end of each of these.
All right.
So I've added my dot show.
I'll run this one more time and we'll see what we get.
All right.
We've gone ahead and run this again.
I should have the show messages showing up.
I think this is Serena Williams I'll go ahead and click on that and look at that I'm correct.
And just to check.
We'll try some of these other ones and say oh it was three and a Williams looks like I should add a
space there so will say wrong.
It was space.
And then the celebrity's name change.
So now that we've got that in place really the last thing that we need to do is after someone chooses
one of these things we want to give them another question.
And so basically what we just need to do is take our code where we you know go through and pick random
answers and all this stuff like we just need to do this inside of its own function.
So we go ahead and make a new method here.
Public void and I'm going to call this new question and we'll do our nice little curly brackets there.
Now we don't want to always go download you know the code to go hit the Web site and put these into
the proper Rayson stuff it's really from this random portion down this is where you know we're going
to want to just do this every single time so we're going to go ahead and copy from random all the way
down cut rather and we'll go paste this side of New question and then what we'll do is inside of our
create after we've done all this we do want to say new question for the very first time that the app
runs with the code that we have inside of here.
We need to have this wrapped inside of a try catch.
Let's go ahead and do an opening try here.
We'll put that at the end of all this.
And then also provide a catch where you get an exception that we'll call the do either print stack trace.
With that then we also want to do new question whenever somebody chooses a celebrity whether or not
they got it wrong or correct.
We do want to do.
New question.
OK.
So let's go ahead and give this a roll.
And if this all works out this means we have a fully functioning app ready to go.
All right.
App opens up.
I'm not sure about this one I'll try.
Kiki was Eamon.
OK.
That's not Vin Diesel.
Natalie Dormer.
Oh that's Jimmy Fallon.
I got that one for sure.
This is the only female name that I see.
Oh no.
I was wrong.
Melanie Griffith Yeah I got that one.
Per Nello.
Oh looks like I got that right.
You look like a puzzle.
Oh looks like I was right.
K. ball dude.
It's not Jimmy Fallon Glahn thing.
Well anyway as you can see we've got a completely functioning app here and there's so many different
additions we could make to this right.
We could do score counter just like we had with our brain app we could do other things about the way
that we display the message rather than doing a toaster that kind of shows up above the buttons we could
display it inside of a text view maybe up top that makes it a little bit easier.
So the user doesn't have to kind of look around that for their next pick.
All different things that we could do but a very solid app here.
And you've been doing great truckin through the section we've still got some more for you but we're
definitely more than halfway done and we're just going to add a few more things to your knowledge base
here and then we'll go ahead and move forward.
But still more great stuff for you.
Let's go to the next lecture.