In this video I'm going to show you how to download the one and only piece of software you need for
this course Android studio.
If you're on Windows you can jump straight to the next video where I'll lead you through the process
using Windows 10.
But in this video I'll show you how to get Android studio on Mac OS so all you need to do is go to your
favorite search engine.
Type in Android studio and you can see the top result there for me is developer dot Android dot com
slash studio.
That's what you want.
So Android studio is currently on version 3 and it's a complete system that allows you to both design
and Cojo apps and you can also run them in an emulator on your computer so you don't need a phone or
a smartwatch or a tablet to actually test your applications.
I can do everything from within Android studio so click the big green download Android studio button
agree to the terms and conditions and then click the blue download button that will maybe take a little
while to download it is a pretty big file.
So have a break have a cup of tea.
Come back when you're done.
All done then you just need to flip over to find the look in your downloads and you should have this
address judaeo DMG file which you just double click on and then it will verify unpack and allow you
to install it.
Now we're going to just drag Android studio over into applications and it will complete the installation
process.
And that's it.
Once you've done that open Android studio in the way you would any application I use command space to
open spotlight's and then just search for Android and it should be towards the top there.
DoubleClick on George do you ask you if you want to open it and we'll say yes you will then get this
loading screen.
It might need to download some extra components and then you get to the set up with it which just allows
you to choose a few options.
We're going to go for the standard installation.
I'm going to use the default like theme but if you prefer dark you can choose the dark killer theme
then next.
Again I would allow it to choose all these default SDK that is software development kit components and
then click Finish.
Again it'll take a little while to download but when it's done you'll finally be ready to get started
with developing for Android.
And then when you're done you should see the Wolken to endorse Judaea message.
And this is where will kick off in our Andrys to yota at the beginning of the next video.