So as I mentioned earlier there's two Android concepts that I want to teach you before we move forward
and make our notes app.
So the first one that I want to teach you about is menu so this is a way to add some actual options
for our users and they're kind of in their own menu place you'll notice as soon as we build it in an
app about where this is and how different apps use them.
So let's go ahead and start a new project I'm going to name mine just simply the menu demo.
Nice plain vanilla title there and we'll go ahead and hit next on this.
We want this to be an empty activity and we'll finish up there.
So it's been a little bit interesting with the android studio in the past.
It used to be that there always used to be apps that start with a menu.
Now that is not the case you can choose an activity habit in there but I'd rather just show you how
to make an empty app and be able to add a menu and later than have you have to depend on a certain you
know template when you start an app if you know how to add it in.
It's just going to make it that much better of an Android Developer.
So with that the first thing that we need to do is we need to be able to go and get the particular menu
that is that we want to create.
So there's a couple of steps that have to happen here so if we expand our app out here we're going to
go to our resources and we're first going to create a new folder here.
So let's go ahead and Right-Click we want to do new directory.
There we go and let's just simply call this menu right like that.
OK.
Now once we go ahead and grab that the next thing that we're going to do is we're going to have this
menu selected and then we're going to say file new menu resource file right here so go ahead and select
that.
Now for the name that you want to give this you simply just doesn't matter immensely what this says
but let's just go ahead and call ours underscore main menu.
This is our way of saying this is going to be you know the one and only sort of main menu that we have
in the directory name.
Make sure the menu right we're trying to put it in that folder there we'll go ahead and hit OK.
And now once we've done that you'll see we get in SML file which is very similar to like our activity
underscore main X-amount right where we can kind of set things up visually see what they look like.
But this is going to be for the menu item.
And if we go ahead and write or click on this little menu directory here we can see we've got that main
underscore menu X-amount.
That means we're in a good place.
Now the next step for us is we've got to fill in this main menu with the appropriate information so
I find this easiest to do via text.
So let's go ahead and go to the text.
View here so in between these two menu tags This is where we want to add what are called menu items.
So these items we've got to give them a title we got to give them an idea and really that's it.
So let's go ahead and create our first item.
You'll see as we do that we get some nice auto complete help from Android studio so the name that we're
looking for here is Android title so I'll type out Android Colan title and it we've got to set this
to some strings so in this case let's maybe call it like settings.
All right.
And we'll do a space the next thing that we're looking for here is Android.
I will scroll down there that is.
So then we've got to put some sort of idea in here and I'm just going to call this maybe you'll see
at plus ID slash and I'm going to have this be equal to the settings.
OK.
So once you've gone ahead and got that in place we can go ahead and do our ending and that will automatically
add the back side of that item tag there.
OK.
So just to see what this would look like if we go back to our design view look at that we get the three
little icon menu item here.
And then whenever someone wants to check out one of the menu items it's going to show up here like this.
So let's go ahead and go back to our text.
We want to add another menu item here we just simply have to copy this and paste it down below.
And we're going to change this from settings to help and instead of the idea of settings we'll call
this one help.
So now if we go back to our design view.
Right.
Someone can either check for more information about the settings or they can suffer help.
And as you can imagine you can put as many or as little of these as you would like.
So with those in place we've got to write a little bit of code here.
So let's go back to our main activity.
We're not going to touch this on create method but what we're going to do is we're going to add a new
method up top and we're going to call if we just start typing out on create options menu.
That's what we're looking for it's going to go do a ton of stuff for us.
Basically this is going to allow us to get the menu all set up so what we're going to do first is get
something called the menu inflator or want to say capital menu in Fator lower case menu inflator is
equal to get menu inflator.
And how many times you say inflator.
Then once we have this menu inflator we go ahead and type that out then we are going to say Dot inflate
and this is where we're going to give access to our menu that we had just created.
So we're going to say capital our DOT that we want to get to menue that gets us to our menu directory
and then we're going to say Dot main menu.
OK.
That's how it connects there.
And the next thing that we need to pass this is this menu object right up top so just go ahead and pass
that through.
And so now with these things in place let's go ahead and hit run.
We want to see what this looks like on the emulator.
So again what we should see showing up here is the menu popping down and showing the settings showing
the help.
And then I'm going to show you how you can go about making it so that when someone selects one of those
you can write some code to appropriately respond to that.
So let's go ahead and get her emulator all set up here and we'll just wait a moment here while this
is getting all ready to rock and roll.
And there we go as soon as you mentioned the emulator taking a long time.
That's as soon as the menu or emulator starts working.
So let's hit the little gypsies here for the menu and look at that.
We get the settings we get the help just like we were looking for and if you decide user decides they
don't want to pick something they just tap out here.
But then the next question for us is you know someone wants to select the settings or they select help
right.
Like we should have the ability to run some code.
And let me show you how we can do that.
So we're going to come back to our code that we have here but we're going to create Now a new method
and the method that we're going to create is called on options and on options items selected.
So this gets called when someone selects one of these items so they give us a couple of things here
first it's calling superdog on item selections we want to keep that.
But we do with this want to return back a boolean about true or false about whether we were able to
successfully provide the user what they needed.
So right now it's calling to the Super one we want to leave the super call but we want to do this return
later so I'm going to cut out the return and I'm going to pases it down below and we'll do our own return
later and again we have to return a boolean.
So maybe for the time being we'll go ahead and return true to say everything works out.
Now with this on options item selected it passes us this menu item and we can go ahead and check with
this menu item and see what it's ideas in.
Depending on the ID we can do something with it so this is a great situation to use a switch.
You could also use these statements but I think a switch is a little more elegant.
So we're going to say switch print the season do our curly brackets like that.
And the thing that we want to inspect is this item over here.
So when I say item dot and then we want to get item ID.
So this is going to provide us for example if we go back to our menu item it's either going to give
us like settings or help right and then we can move forward from there.
So one of the cases would be we're going to say case capital R ID dot settings just like that.
So after that we're going to do a colon make sure it's not a semi-colon and in which case then we'd
want to log out some information so maybe you would say something like item selected and then we'd specify
here what menu item it was that was selected.
And if this is the settings we'll say settings can do our semi-colon there.
Once we have that in place if we were able to successfully do that we would want to return true here
to say Yep the user.
We ran the code that we needed to return true and that then makes it so to make sure that no other code
gets run.
Another case that we would want to check for would be capital our DOT ID dot.
In this case we want the help.
So go ahead and do that and we're essentially running the same code right like we're going to just copy
and paste this instead of settings will say item selected.
And I guess we should put an extra he's selected.
There we go.
This one should say help if they select that.
Now any time that you have a switch statement you have to have a default there to say you know in case
it didn't equal anything from above and in this situation let's just go ahead and return false because
that's saying hey something went wrong we didn't run the code that we wanted to there.
All right.
So with all of this in place that means we can now get rid of this return in fact you can see Andray
studio saying this thing's on resettable you've already handled all the situations there.
So let's just go ahead and get rid of that and with this this is everything that I wanted to teach you.
Let's go ahead and test it out to make sure that this works.
So we'll pull up our emulator here.
We should also get Lague cat up and running so that you can see what gets logged whenever we select
one of these items so here comes the app and we'll hit the menu and let's select one of the items maybe
help and look at that item selected help.
Now let's go ahead do the same thing for once someone taps on settings and look it up.
Item selected settings.
So this is a quick little lecture I wanted to just teach you this one concept very simply remember the
whole process for creating a menu item is you've got to create a menu directory.
Then one of these menu layouts once you do that you've got to put in the correct items and then these
are the two main functions that you'll be working with.
The create option menus that just make sure that this shows this menu over here and then on option items
select it says ok when someone clicks on one of these or taps on one of these.
Go ahead run a code depending on which item it is that they selected.
OK.
All right so let's go ahead and learn about dialog boxes and then we'll move forward with making our
app.