So we're at a point or app where we can successfully log and we put in a password.
If we do the sign up or Lagann we can get a message that tells us hey we have successfully logged in.
So the next step for us is to show a list of all the users that the person is either following or not
following and have appropriate check marks next to their name which means we need a new activity.
So let's go ahead and go file new.
We want to bring in a new activity so let's grab one from the gallery here.
Empty seems great and let's go ahead and call this user's activity.
So we'll go ahead and create that and with this it's just going to be a big list view so let's go ahead
and get the lay out for this opened up.
Go ahead and give ourselves some space to work with.
And again we just want to fill it up with a list view and then we'll go through the process of getting
you know all the users inside of there.
And it looks like it's taking a second to load up here so I'm going to go back to our users activity
java file and I can start getting things set up.
So we're going to have to have an array of users so let's go ahead and make an array list.
So we're going to make a new array list and I'm going to have this be an array of string objects.
So go ahead and do that.
I'm going to call this user's experience.
Going to be a bunch of user names I will say this is a new array list can so get that all set up.
We're also going to need an array adapter at some point here and a second and we'll want to be able
to update that at various points so let's make a new array adapter that we'll just call adapter.
And for the moment being we'll just define that.
Then inside of the create method this is where we want to fill up that user's arrays so we'll take our
users and let's add a few people inside of there so let's maybe do we'll put Nick inside.
And let's also add Sarah inside of there.
So go ahead and add Sarah.
Excellent.
So we've got a couple of users there.
Then it's time to create the list view which hopefully now our activities lay out is open and ready
to rock and roll.
So let's go ahead and go to arge containers.
We're going to bring in a list few and look at that.
It is filled up the space let's give it a proper ID.
I think I should just be the list view.
There we go.
And now we can come back to our users activity and we can get access to that list.
So I'm going to say List View with the name of list view is equal to a new or this is where we want
to find view by id our DOT ID list view of the Capitol there.
And again it's barking at me but I know that's going to come around here in a second because that was
the name we had just given there.
The next thing that we want to do is we want to be able to say that this list view should be able to
let users add a checkmark next to it so this is kind of a new thing that we haven't done before but
we're going to say List view not set choice mode.
And we're going to set this equal to a B-S list view.
OK.
And then we're going to do it in all caps choice mode.
Multiple.
OK.
So go ahead and get that set.
You're going to love what this looks like now.
So with that list fuel in place we are going to create an array or set up the adapter we had already
defined it before up at the top here and we had just called the adapter.
There we go.
So adapter is going to be equal to a new array adapter.
And inside of here we're going to pass this for the context that we're going to do our classic Android
dog our dog lay out.
And this is where we're going to get a little bit different.
Instead of choosing simple list item one we're going to choose a simple list item checked.
So let's go ahead and move down until we find that simple list item checked.
There we go.
So we're going to add that in.
And then lastly of course we have to add our users.
So go ahead and type that there.
So that's our new array dafter and it's using this new layout for the items checked.
And we had said that you know this is going to be a choice mode list view here.
The next thing that we want to do is we want to be able to set an on click listener so that when someone
clicks one of these people they can actually check to say yes this person is you know I'm following
them not following them whatever.
So we're going to take our list view and we're going to set on item click listener and we want a new
adapter view on item click listener inside of there.
OK.
So basically what we're going to try and do here is see whether this is checked or not and we want to
be able to let the user know about that or at least get a log in.
We want our selves to know about that.
So what we're going to do is we're going to take this view that comes through and turn it into a checked
text view because that's what's coming through in this new light out here.
So we're going to say checked text view and let's just give this a namecheck text view in case.
We're going to say that this is equal to our view that's coming through here but we're going to go ahead
and cast it as a checked text view just like that.
With that in place then we're going to do an if statement where we can actually use this checked text
view to see if it's checked or not.
So we're going to say OK check text view dot and we all just want to do is checked.
And if it is checked then we should go ahead and log out that information.
So we'll go ahead and say log that.
And we'll say info and then the second part that we'll pass through is all say checked exclamation point.
All right.
And then the else of the situation is that things are not checked and so would want to copy this log.
Paste it down below.
But instead of saying checked we will say it not checked.
Let's do that in big bold letters so we know the difference between the two.
OK.
So with that there we're going to need a way to get to this activity because as of right now it's just
going to be on this log in screen we have no way to get there.
So let's move back to our main activity and we are going to create a new method here so public void
and we basically want a method that's going to redirect it to the user list so redirect really direct
users what I'm going to call this.
And we don't need to have to pass in a view or anything like this because it's not connected to a button.
But the basic idea here is we check and see if the users logged in and we can do that with an if statement
where we say all right.
Capital parse user dot get current user.
And we're going to see if this is not equal to null so if it's not equal to know that we know we have
a user which then means we can successfully log them in.
So we're going to make an intent that we'll just call intent and say that this is equal to a new intent
and we want to the yet application context and then we want to move over to our user activity thot class.
OK.
So with that in place then we just want to simply start that activity and we'll pass in that intent.
All right.
Now with this redirect user we want to call this in a couple of places so I'm going to copy this.
The first one is when we log in if we're able are that when the user tries to log in if they're successfully
able to log in we should redirect the user.
OK that's one situation.
The next one is if they're able to sign up successfully we should redirect that user.
And then the last one is if they just open the app for the first time they've already logged on before.
Well then we should go ahead and redirect that user.
Those are sort of the three use cases there.
All right.
And there's one last little point of touch that I want to add here and that's that inside of our user
list view we should set a title there just to make everything nice and pretty looking.
And we're going to call this the user list King.
So with all of this in place let's go ahead and test out our project here.
Hit Ron and hopefully this will finally get rid of this error for list view Android studio being all
weird about that.
Again will go ahead and give that a second.
Well the app finally opened up here but it dawned on me something was wrong.
There's no list items inside of this list view and it's because I never set the adapter to the list.
So we've got to say list view set adapter and we'll go ahead and pass in the adapter.
So with that in place we'll go ahead and run the Senate finally did recognize my list view which I was
happy to see because I know I was right that just Android studio didn't have my back which was the first
time in a while.
This has been pretty consistent here for us which is great.
But there's me rambling against a computer program arguing with it but here it comes.
Opening up.
And look at that.
We see our users Nick and Sarah.
And even more importantly we've got these cute little check boxes so if I check on Nick look it turns
green.
And let's check out Lague cat here.
It should tell us checked and I'm going to open this up again.
Let's say I checked Sarah look that says check.
Now if I go check that it says not checked I checked Nick says not checked so I can go back and forth
back and forth just all the time with these to see what that looks like.
OK.
So this is a great starting point for us but the next thing that we need to be able to work with here
is we want to be able to see a list of the actual users not just these two that I randomly created here.
So in order to do this we need to have a couple of users to work with because right now if we go over
to our parts dashboard inside of users we only have one user which is Nick and so let's go back to our
app and if we hit the back button here this will actually take us to the log in sign up screen and let's
just make some new users so I might do Cerra password one two three four.
That will create a sign up and then take us here.
I'm also going to do it a new name like John will do a sign up slash log in and let's even do one more
here we'll do Fido.
Fido the dog is now going to have a Twitter account so we'll go ahead and sign up for Fido.
So if we do this and we reload the user's page here look we've got all these new users.
Pretty cool that we have an app that can quickly make users like that.
And now let's go about the business of trying to get all these user objects.
So let's go back to our app here and in Android studio.
We're going to go ahead and get rid of these two lines where we're adding names arbitrarily to that
users list and we'll go ahead and clear that out and after we've set the on item click listener down
here is where we want to make a new query and this is going to be for Parsee users so we're going to
say parse queery and we want this to be a query of parce users.
So say parse user we go and let's just go ahead and call this a query.
Say this is equal to capital parse user dot net query.
OK.
With that in place then we want to say that this query should be for all the users.
Well except for us.
So we'll add that one detail there will say queery dot where not equal to.
And this is where we want to say anywhere that the user name is not equal to.
And then we're going to pass in the current user's username.
So do parse user get current user dot get username.
So that's an important distinction there to make sure we don't get ourselves back then with that in
place.
We're going to go ahead and do a query where we say that find in the background because we want to go
get all these new users in the background.
So we'll have to do a new fine background for all these parts users.
Now once we get this back we get this cool list of parts user objects.
So let's first check and make sure that there's no exceptions.
So say let's make sure it is equal to no.
And if that is the case forgot one equal sign there.
So if that is the case you want to make sure there's enough objects so we can actually just add onto
this honoraria say if is equal to nil and objects that size is greater than zero.
So that makes sure there is something in that list there.
If that's the case we can do this.
Awesome for loop where we can go ahead and move through each of the items in that list which are going
to be users so we're going to say parse user call them user.
This is going to loop through all the objects.
And then here this is where we would want to add their user names into the user list that we have up
top.
So we're going to go and say users which is that array list up there add.
And then we're going to add whoever the current user is not get username so it's going to get that current
user's user name and add it to that list up top.
Now once we've gone ahead and loop through all the different users we do want to take our array adapter
and we want to update that.
And it's not giving me access to the array adapter because I called it adapter.
All right.
So adapter dot and we want to notify data set change just say hey you know we've downloaded all these
new people you should know about it.
Let's go ahead and run this see what it gives us it'll be interesting to see whoever was last logged
in that person should still be logged in so they should see everyone but themself.
And I believe that was Feydeau We'll see if that's the case here.
So we come in and look there's Nick Sarah and John and no Feydeau.
And just to really test this.
Let's go ahead and try and sign in with Nick password 1 2 3 4 and Nick's not on the list but phyto is
this means that we now have access to everybody.
But the issue with this is you know let's say we are going to follow some people or not follow some
people.
Well we want to be able to tell parce about this and have it saved in the background so let's get back
to our parts dashboard here and under our user object we're going to be adding a new column.
So we don't want to add a new row here but we want to add new columns.
If you go all the way to the right you can click this add new column and what we're looking to add is
an array.
So if we scroll down here we have an option to add an array.
And this is going to tell us all the people that this particular user is following.
So if we keep an array of this if we wanted then see who that user is following and get those users
tweets.
We can handle that.
So we're going to go ahead and call this lower case is and then Capitol following make sure you have
no spaces there we want an array called is following.
All right.
So this should be added to all of our users here.
Then we want to go ahead and write the code in order to get this working.
So when someone checks a box or uncheck that box we should be making a note of that in parse server.
So let's get back to android studio.
So if somebody is going to check the box they want to add someone to their follower list.
So in order to do this we're going to say hey if they check the box this is a situation where they want
to add.
We're going to go get a Parsee user get current user dot add and we want to add for.
The key is following.
Right.
That's that new call that we made and what we're going to pass in that is the key.
And we're going to say whatever user it is which has users get at index because remember we're in the
side of this on click listeners so when they click on you know the item position of index to then you
know we can go grab that from the array we can pass that through and that's going to add them to that
array.
Now when we want to remove them from the array you would think would be just the opposite that we do
not remove.
But I don't know if it's a bug in parce code but it's become much more complicated than it was before.
So here's everything that we've got to do to make this work.
So the first thing is we've got to go get the list from the current user and we need to remove the user
that they are checking here.
Right.
This is in the unchecked situation they want to unfollowed.
So we're going to go get Parsee user get current user and we're going to get the list and we're going
to check out for is following.
All right.
And once we've done that we want to say hey let's go ahead and remove the users to get that position.
So it's kind of the same situation as last time but we're trying to now remove them from that list or
that array.
And so once we've done that what we're going to do is download that list here and so download I mean
we're going to move it into a new object and we're going to call this temp users and we're going to
say this is equal to capital parce users get current user dog get list.
And again we're going to pass and that key is following.
OK.
So this is going to take the list for the user that now has that one user removed put in this list called
tempt users then we need to wipe out the list completely from the current partial user.
This is where I was saying before this is kind of freaky that this is what we have to do now.
But we're going to get the current user and we're going to say remove it we want to remove with the
key is following.
OK.
Then once we have that in place the next thing that we want to do from here is we want to then put it
back into that particular space.
So we're going to open up the parse user one more time and we're going to say get current user.
And now we want to put that back in the same spot.
So the key is going to still be the same is following.
But now what we want to do is we want to add in that list that we created the temp users.
So we're going to go ahead and pass in Tempe users just like that.
So then regardless of whether we were adding a user or removing a user then we want to be able to save
this in the background so then we're going to say parse user Daut save in background or we've got to
go get the current user parse stock get current user dot save in background.
OK so go ahead and make that save.
Now with this it's important to note before we do anything we want to go to our parce dashboard here
we want to make sure for all of these is following that we have at least an initial array set up because
if it's no we're going to get all sort of errors so we've got to make sure we fill that up with an empty
array.
So with that in place let's go ahead and we will run this app gang and we will wait to see what do we
get in new user here.
Are we're going to log in as a user and then we're going to see if we can't make some changes here.
So wait for app to pop up for just a second here.
All right.
So here it comes in let's say I want to follow Fido so I'm going to hit that check when I go back refreshed
this page.
And for Nick here look at that.
Now he's following Fido.
It's in that list.
Let's say he also wants to add Sarah so he gets that.
Let's reload the page here.
And as we scroll over.
Oh my goodness.
Wouldn't you believe it.
There is Sarah.
So this is how we know that things are working.
So let's go ahead now and try and remove one of these users like let's say for example I don't want
to fall Fido anymore it's going to hit that checkbox.
And now if I reload this page.
Look that.
I'm only following Sarah.
So this is excellent This is telling us that hey we can now go in and determine who it is we want to
follow and not follow We're keeping track of that.
But the problem is if I were to reload this app it wouldn't detect that I'm following Sarah.
It would leave everything unchecked so we have to have a way to be able to account for that.
So we're going to go back to android studio here and we're going to scroll down to after we go and get
all the users and you know we add them into the users list and notify that the data set has changed.
Then this is where we want to loop through all the users and see hey is a current user following any
of these people.
If so let's go ahead and put a check by their name.
So we're going to set up this for loop.
Let's go ahead and get that there.
And the thing that we are looping through is the user's array.
So each time we go through there we're going to get a string which I'm going to call username and with
that once we have looped through we want to check and see if the person is following this individual.
So in order to see that we're going to go get the current user and then we're going to get the list
from them of who they are following.
That's the.
Is following key there.
And then once we have that in place we're going to do a dot contains and this is where we're going to
check and say hey do you follow someone with this particular username and this will either give us a
true or a false to say yes I follow this person or no I do not.
So with this information if they do follow a person we're going to say OK.
Time to update the list.
Few will say few.
Set item checked and unset item check there's two things that we got to pass in.
So first is the index of where it is that we want to set the check.
So we're going to go tap into our users a rate list and we're going to say give us the index of the
following user name and we'll pass in user name just like that.
And then we are going to set that equal to true.
So you could see it equal that true or false about whether you want the check.
But in this case if they are following someone we want that to be true.
So let's go ahead and run this now shall we.
So we should see that Nick is following Sarah.
So when he logs in Sarah should have the check mark that will be our mark for success.
OK.
And we open up and boom.
Look at that.
Sarah is being followed.
Let's really put it to the test.
We'll follow John and Fido and then unfollow Sarah.
OK will reload this page here to see if that's correct.
Now it's only John and Fido right.
John and Fido and will reload this one more time here from Android studio to see if this is the case
and opens up and look there is John and Fido.
So one more notch on this app we were able to successfully say that we want to follow her and follow
people and see that list.
We still got more to go but we're making great progress.