This video I'll show you how to install Android studio on Windows.
So if you've already got android studio or you're not on Windows just skip to the next lecture.
So just go to Google and search for Android studio download and you should find that the top result
is this one here.
So it's developed dot Android dot com slash studio Sastry index Drage TNL.
And this will take you to the beach see download the latest version of Android studio which at the time
of recording is 3.2 0.1.
So just click the green button to download Android studio agree to the terms and conditions and then
Android studio should start downloading.
It's a pretty big file.
So you might want to go off and get a quick cup of tea well done.
Excellent.
You can now click run.
So you open up the studio installation program you'll need to allow the app to make changes to your
device choose the installation folder.
I'd go for the default if you've got an older version it'll ask to overwrite it.
So just click yes.
You'll very likely need Android virtual devices to follow along with this course.
So keep that option selected and click next.
And again Jees the final installation options are to stick with all of the defaults and then let it
do its thing.
Once that's completed click next and finish it to start Android studio.
And then you'll be greeted with the set up wizard.
So we're not quite there yet.
But again we'll just stick to the very standard options.
So essentially just keep clicking next.
Install the default components click Finish and then you'll have another bit of a white wall it downloads
the necessary components to run.
And then we're done.
So I just click Finish and now we're ready to finally learn Android development which will start in
the next lecture.