Now we're going to look at variables and how we create them and how we can work with them in Java.
And indeed what a variable is.
So for each new lecture here I'm going to create a new hello world template.
So just by tapping try that and then get rid of my previous one and I'm going to save it straight away
so that it's clear what we're working on.
I'll call this variable's
that we get.
So you can see that it's already saving all of our programs that we've made and then really all we're
going to change for most of the next few lectures is the code inside the main method.
So if you've worked with different languages before you may be used to defining a variable with something
like the VAR command like you do in javascript for example.
But in Java it works differently.
Java is a strong typed language which means that every variable that you create has to be of a certain
type and once that variable has been created you can change its type.
So let's start with a fairly basic type an integer.
So it is short for integer which is a whole number.
So if I wanted to create an integer I just type it and then the name of the variable so I might call
it age for example.
And then the initial value of that variable.
So for example 34 and then semi-colon at the end of the line.
So this creates an integer or a whole number which has the name of age and the value 34.
And from there just in case you're slightly unclear on what a variable is it should be fairly straightforward.
A variable is something like this that we can change the value of.
So that this might just keep track of the age of our current use for example.
And that's all a variable is.
We did use them a couple of times in the previous section when we created for example the added text
to refer to the text field that we wanted to get the value of.
So we have used variables already.
So here's a quick challenge for you straight away.
Can you create an integer called favorite number.
Set it to your favorite number and then output it to the console.
Very simple.
Good luck.
All right.
I hope you manage that.
You should have just used it to create your integer and then favorite number.
You may or may not have spelled favorite like that.
I won't take marks off if you didn't put you in but favorite number with a small F and A capital and
would be generally we would describe the variable because we usually use a small first letter and then
a capital letter for every word after that.
That just makes it nice and easy to read.
So a favorite number of my favorite number is 7.
And again take marks if you chose a number other than seven.
Well then of course you are wrong.
And then we just want to display it in the log so we use the same command that we saw in the previous
video system.
Dot out dot print.
And then we just pop it straight in.
Favorite number.
There we go.
So let's start that and there it is.
So that's our first example of creating a variable and displaying it.
Now what if our favorite number happened to be seven point five.
The reason your favorite number can be a decimal.
Let's try running that and see what happens.
We've got an era possible loss of precision.
So what's going on there.
Well it's fairly straightforward.
I think we've created our favorite number as an integer which means a whole number and then we've set
it to seven point five which is not a whole number.
So we need to change the variable type to one that can accept a non whole number and the one that I
normally use is a double so named because it takes up double the memory of a standard floating point
number and a floating point number is just a decimal.
So a number that can be either a whole number or a decimal.
So when you want to use decimals I'd recommend using double like that.
And then let's just take a look.
Now that displays seven point five.
No problem at all.
So those are the two Meric variable types that you'll probably want to use either and if you want something
to be an integer.
So a number of users for example h that kind of thing and double if you think that your number might
end up being a decimal.
So something like a price or temperature before we go on to look at other variable types.
I just want to quickly turn your attention to a great Web site learn Java on line dot org.
You'll probably end up here if you do some googling and you want to find out a bit more information
about something.
But this particular page shows us what is known as the primitives in Java.
So they are a set of you could say basic variable types from which other variable types are built.
So you can see the ones that we've looked at already are int and double the others just to make you
aware of them.
We don't really use very much but we have a few other integer types so that we've got bite short which
are much smaller.
They only take out one byte or two bytes.
And there's an integer which takes up 4 bytes and then long which takes up 8 bytes so the number of
bytes here refers to how big the number can get.
Without causing an error in the program.
So if for example I want to check how big an int can be I would google something like it maximum size
Well maximum value let's say in Java something like that.
And I like to look at that third result there.
So in fact we've got the values for all of them there.
So the basic byte can be between minus 128 and 6:59 which is probably a bit small for most cases a short
integer goes from minus 32000 to 32000 which again is probably going to be OK in most cases but if your
a number of users gets higher and higher then you might well exceed that whereas for it it goes down
to minus 2 to the 31 which is about minus two billion and up to about 2 billion.
So that's probably going to be big enough for most families that you're dealing with in your programs.
But if it's not you can use a long which goes up to an even higher number.
So that's the difference between those types.
And then we've got two decimal numbers so float and double.
I'd recommend generally going for double and then we've got Charle which is just a character.
So any ABC etc. and then Boullion which is the next one that we're going to look at here which is just
true or false.
So these are the primitive types and all other types are made up from those.
So let's jump back and have a look at our billion and I'm just going to get rid of that.
So to create a billion we just type Boullion like that and then we might have something like am I male
and for me that would be true.
If you're interested the word Boullion is named after George Boole.
There is an English mathematician who did a lot of work in logic and so true or false is obviously fairly
central to that and that's where the word Boullion comes from.
So in your programs you could use a Boolean for is logged in or is active user or something like that.
Or dead or alive or dead.
For our ghosts example from the previous video.
So very quick challenge once again create a Boolean for something that you could imagine actually using
a Boolean for in a program and then display it in the logs.
Durford
all right nice and easy so.
Just like boolean and then I'm going to call it user likes pizza and we'll set that to be true.
It is true for this particular use app and then we'll just pop it in the console.
So system and then output methods and print line use user likes pizza.
So I mean go and start and we should get tree that we get.
So that's how we use booleans.
So so far we've got billions and numbers.
The final variable type that we're going to look at is strings which we've already seen before up here.
So a string is just a combination of characters really.
It's a very common variable type but it's not a primitive because it's made up of Charles characters.
So because it's not a primitive.
Instead of using a lowercase definition.
So before we use it is lowercase b and we've used lower cases for all our definitions so far.
We use a capital letter because it's not a primitive it's actually a class and classes are generally
defined with capital letters at the start.
So just like hello world there.
So string my name for example is Rob of course.
I think we've seen before that we don't type it like that.
We need to put quotes round a string whenever we use it.
Say my name is Rob.
And then let's print that to the console.
But this time we'll do something slightly different.
Dot dot dot printer line and then we could use.
My name is in quites than I want to put a space at the end of that.
And then we use plus to concatenate strings.
That means put them together basically.
So my name is and then we have my name and we might want to put a full stop on the end as well.
I would have let's just run that every day.
My name is Rob.
Fantastic.
So another quick challenge for you.
I want you to save your name and your age as variables and then output them to the console saying my
name is whatever your name is and I am your number of years years old.
Good luck.
All right.
I hope you manage that.
So let's create a string again we'll just call it my name robe.
Same as before.
And then we'll create an integer called H which is 34.
And then we just put that to the console.
So our system took out top print helène.
My name is
what's my name
and I am what all those spaces in H.
Is old closed the brackets semi-colon.
All right.
Let's take a look.
Just run that fantastic.
My name is Rob and I am 34 years old.
Something that some of you may have picked up on is that this age is not a string it's an integer and
yet the system has allowed us to bring it into this string without any problems.
That works because it's a primitive primitive variables can be put into strings like this without having
to convert them to strings whereas other variable types generally will need a conversion to a string
before you can display it or bring it into a string like we have done there.
OK so now we're familiar with the main variable types that we're going to be using.
So integers doubles strings and booleans.
Let's just see a few things that we can do with them rather than just set their value and display them
in the console.
So let's work with numbers first of all let's get rid of this and create a double.
And I'm just going to call it.
I for the moment and will set it to six point seven and then we'll have another double beat which will
be three point two so I can do all sorts of manipulation with these numbers really straightforwardly.
So let's put it straight in the console's system out towards print line and then let's say we want to
multiply those two together.
We use the asterisks so that shift 8 for me.
So I start a means eight times B and that will give us whatever six point seven times three point two
is there we get we can add them together of course.
Similarly say nine point nine and we could subtract seven point three from that
as well.
We'll work that out for us.
Now here we get an interesting result.
It's not quite 2.6 it's 226 loads of zeros and then a 5.
Now this is because a double is not a completely accurate variable type.
I'm not going to go into precisely why.
But essentially this is a binary So a set of zeros and ones which is an approximation of the decimal
number.
Now the reason that is is essentially because it's much faster for the computers to work with.
So if you round it to one or two decimal places to display to the user then it's always going to be
accurate enough for you but you should be aware that if you're working with doubles and then you display
them to the user at some point or you use them in some way you should bear in mind that you should round
them to the number of decimal places that you need.
So that's working with numbers.
There are of course a bunch of things you can do with strings as well.
I'm just going to show you one for now but we'll see a lot more throughout the course.
And the one I'm going to show you is how to get the length of the strings or the number of characters
in a string.
So let's create a string which I'll just call my string with a bunch of random characters in it.
There you go.
If I wanted to get the length of that string and I would
put it in the console's print line I would use my string dot length and then I would use a pair of parentheses.
That's because length here is a method and whenever we call a method we were instructed to do something
we have a pair of parentheses which sometimes will contain a variable that we want to pass to that particular
method.
But in this case we don't want to do that.
We just want my string Daut length and that will tell us the length of my string
so check that we get 16 characters in my string.
All right.
So that's how you create and manipulate variables in Java.
Of course we need a final challenge to put all of that together.
So fairly straightforwardly I want you to create two strings which will be equal to your first name
and your last name.
And then I want you to create an integer which sums the number of characters in your first name and
your second name and then a line that displays in the can so the number of characters in my full name
is and then that final value should be fairly straightforward with any luck.
Go for it.
All right I managed it.
So in my case I just want to have a string and I'll call it first name.
Is equal to.
And then we'll have another string.
Second name is equal to Percival
and then we'll create an integer which I'll call length and that's going to be equal to a first name
dot length plus second name dot length because you want to add the a c together and then finally we
want to output the result say system start out of print line.
The number of characters in my full name is and then will concatenate that with the variable length.
That should do it let's take a look.
Fantastic.
Which is in my full name is brilliant.
I hope you manage that in the next video.
We'll go on to another important variable type which is the type of array.
See you then.