Now that we've got out into the app set up on pass server it's time to create our logon screen and just
for variety's sake I'm going to do something a little differently this time with Uber or at least our
version of Uber.
There's no actual need for a user name and password.
We could consider it more or less a one time use app at least the ridable will come along and access
the app and then request a new bar and the driver will come and pick them up.
There's no actual need for a username and password there.
Obviously in the real app it is required for things like taking payments and remembering past locations
but to show you that you can have a social app using a cloud service without a log in.
I thought I'd show you how to do that here.
So this is the logon page.
I'd like you to recreate or make something better.
And we've got our logo at the top there.
And Driver This uses a switch to choose between right and driver.
And then when the user clicks get started it's at the moment just logs were directing as driver or rider.
It also uses the past server anonymous logging which works in a very very similar way to the logging
that we saw in the instagram section.
So I think you'll be able to figure that out.
But if not of course just follow along with me.
So best of luck if you go here because well
OK.
As always.
Well I'm going to begin by jumping over to Firefox and just quickly getting the uber logo to work with
say.
Just search for Uber Lego
for that nice white one that's a reasonable size for us.
Goes without saying that you shouldn't use the overlay.
In any real apps but it's fine if you're just testing things out.
So call it bulgur
and then we'll jump back over the Android studio and create a new
drawable directory.
And then back over to find our Windows Explorer to find the logo that you've downloaded.
So looks like it's lost the extensions so we'll just pop up here and go on the end there and then command
control Control-C to select it over to drawable command or control vi to pasted in.
All right.
Now I have main layout
and then we'll get rid of our text VI and we'll build our layout.
So start from the top with our image via
And then as we're in 2.2 will automatically pop up with a resource search and then we'll add you back
just like that and again change the height
teepees.
Yeah that was great.
OK then we'll bring in our switch to choose between
a driver and a writer.
And let's zoom in a little here.
So I'm going to get rid of the text there.
So I'm going to use two text fields because it's not exactly as if we're switching something on or off.
We're just choosing between two options.
So let's bring in a text view to the right there
and we'll just make sure it's nicely vertically centered every game.
So this is going to be
the drive the option and then we'll have another text.
To the left again let's drag it around.
And this is going to be
rider option.
Now in order to get those perfectly aligned it would likely be worth having a quick look at the XtremIO
and you can see here we've got a 12 pixel margin to the left of this one and a 14 pixel there.
So if I update that to 14 on both sides then we should be nice and symmetrical.
Great.
And then we just need a button
to
allow the user to get started.
So will give this and click method of get started.
And they only use your own interface element we're actually interested in is the switch here.
So I'll call it.
Use a type switch.
There we go.
All right so that's out loud.
Let's jump over to Main activity and we're going to want to be doing everything when that button is
clicked.
So we'll create a method called get started which will be called by a view button which we'll call you
and find out before we do our test run.
We'll just see if we can get the value of that switch.
So let's create a switch variable
which will link to this switch.
So we'll call it use a type switch.
And this is going to be I switch
we'll find it via its ID card or id or use the type switch.
And finance.
I'll just log switch Valley and the switch value is going to be use a type switch and then we want is
checked
and that's going to need to be converted to a string.
So let's Android Judaea suggest that for us and one other small thing as I mentioned I would like to
hide the action bar to give this more of a full screen feel.
So let's very quickly do that.
It's actually very easy to do.
What we do is get the support action bar and height it
so let's have a look.
We should now have
this lay out.
So our switch in the middle and then
rider and drive are nicely aligned either side of it.
I'll get started button on our logo.
And there we go.
So let's just check
currently the switch value is false.
We switch it on it becomes Churi etc..
And you notice the action bar was hidden there sort of got a nice full screen app.
The only thing is I think it's a little bit too dense.
So I'm just going to stretch things out a bit.
I'm not too worried about design in this course but it's a little bit too scrunched up for my liking.
So let's change this to 150 deep.
It's a bit of a big a logo.
And then let's move things down a little so it will change the margin top to here to 50 driver and right
we'll leave the same.
And then the margin top here will have 50 as well.
Might be slightly too much.
We'll make it 40 and 40 and we can live with that.
Exham So now we need to do the work on pass to set up our user.
As I mentioned we're going to be using anonymous users this time.
So let's start by checking to see whether or not the users logged in
so we use past user don't get current user if that's no
more try and lock the user in.
And we do this using pass anonymous utilities so utilities don't logon
and this is going to have I log in callback as it's anonymous.
We're not sending any details so we'll just do a check to see
if he is no
more log
in five anonymous logon successful
else log
anonymous log in fails.
So let's just check that out.
Ads it's an anonymous slogan.
Obviously we're not sending any details and Logan is essentially the same as signing up as well.
So we'll still be saving the users details on our device until they log out.
So we won't lose the information about whether they're a driver or rider or whatever their latest ride
is but we just saved the use of the hassle of entering a username and password.
So let's get a monitor up and running.
And there we go.
You can see Anonymous Logan successful.
And then just jump over to our data browser and for fresh that we should now see a use of there as well.
It's also probably worth switching off automatic user here because we are using anonymous user now which
is slightly different to automatic user and also get rid of that code saving the example object.
We don't need that happening every time
OK.
There we go.
So here's our user with a randomly generated user name.
All right so we are nearly done for this video we just need to save the settings of whether the user
is going to be a rider or a driver.
So that will be stored when they get started.
Button is pressed.
So let's take our past user get the current user and then put and I'll call it rider or driver.
And then we want to set it to a driver if the switch is true to the right and the rider.
If it's not
so let's set a string variable
use a type to be right by default.
And then if
use a type switch it is checked
then will change.
They use a type 2 driver and then here them we'll just put the user type there.
And then of course we're now ready to redirect to the next pager our app which we don't have yet.
So for now I'll just log
in
redirecting as
and then we'll but they use of type in there as well.
And we do also just want a check down here.
If we do have a current user
if they've already set up whether they're a rider or driver we don't want to ask them again.
So let's check to see if past user
get current user don't get and then rider or driver
if that's not now if it's right or driver
then we'll do the same thing say in FE and then redirecting as
time has passed use a don't get current user don't get rider or driver.
So in the next video one of the first things we'll do is create the new activity and will we direct
appropriately so the writers will need to be directed to a different activity to the drivers.
OK.
See that in action.
And there we go.
So I just bring up the log so we logged in successfully
and then if we click that we're redirecting as writer or redirecting as driver Exham.
So that's as far as we're going to go in this video we've got our logon screen all set up in the next
video will begin with the right activity which will essentially be a map showing the right location
and giving them the option to call and Oupa.