So in this lecture we're going to cover two different topics but they're all sort of under the same
Rella and it's about auto completing tasks for our user.
They're trying to fill in some information we want to make it that much easier for them.
So we're going to learn about the new autofill API that comes with Android API 26 point no.
And also we're going to learn about autocomplete with which came about I believe an API 22.
But you're going to see both and how you can use them in your app.
So let's go ahead and start a new Android project.
I'm just going to call this wado fun because we're working with both the autofill API and the autocomplete.
So let's just go ahead and name that.
Now what is important make sure you have API 26.
We want the latest and greatest here so that we can see what those new autofill API is look like.
And then we want an empty activity here and finish up so that I'll go out and create our project for
us.
So first off we are going to talk about how we can work with the autocomplete API I think that one's
really excellent basically the idea is you can take what is essentially an edit text and turn it into
an auto complete text and you can basically provide suggestions to users about what could go in there
and you get to decide what it is that you're going to suggest.
It's really just you create an array of strings and have it show up just like you would do inside of
a list view.
It's pretty straightforward that way.
So to kind of talk about this let's just sort of set up a situation here that maybe you know have an
app where you message your friends or something like that.
And so people when they compose a new message they're going to be typing in a friend's name and you
want to autocomplete it so they don't have to type out a friend's full name to get to them.
So if that's the case then we want to have a string array.
Maybe we'll just call it friends and maybe let's call it friends then or Fern's come on spelling and
then we'll go ahead and fill it in with some values so maybe we'll have Nick in there.
And it's arch rival Rick.
Better put that in double quotes.
Maybe you also have Sarah someone else here James.
And I'm also the kind of show you how this auto complete works we're going to put in.
I'm going to put it in a couple of names here so we're going to do Nina as one.
I'm also going to have Noel and the let's do another one.
This probably isn't a real name but I do need a because this is going to help with the example that
we're doing.
So we have this array of friends.
Right.
And like I said it's as simple as connecting well I guess before we do this let's make the auto complete
edit text and then we'll get to the step.
So let's go over to our main activity and we'll go ahead and.
Well so if we look inside of what we have right now there's just a simple text view and we want to first
get an edit text but then even then it's a special version of an edit text so we'll go ahead and select
that text for you and delete it.
Then if we go to the text category all the way down the bottom you can see there's this auto complete
text view so go ahead and just drag this out you can decide where you want this.
I'm going to have mine be a certain distance from the top and also a certain space from the left and
the right.
OK.
And with this I don't want to have any text in there at the beginning so I'm just going to go ahead
and empty that out.
And when I do that it looks like it shrinks.
So let's go ahead and make sure this goes all the way to the edge here.
There we go.
Well not all the way to the edge but at least a certain distance that you know I can type something
out.
So that looks pretty good.
Auto complete text view is kind of a lame idea but we'll just leave it at that and then let's go ahead
and get access to that so we'll say auto
complete text view which we'll just call.
Let's call the thing out a complete text field is equal to find view by ID are Id done although complete
text field.
All right.
With that in place like I said this is very much similar to when you want to fill up a list view.
So with this string of friends or array of friends then we want to go ahead and make an array adapter
so we're going to say array adapter of a bunch of strings which we'll just call array adapter is equal
to a new array adapter.
And we'll just pass this for the context then we'll do lower case Android are laying out Daut simple
list item 1 and we'll go ahead and pass and the friends are right there.
You know you've been doing enough android when you can pump out our DOT Android that are to lay out
that simple list item one like you just in your memory.
Oh yeah that's the thing that we need when we make a list for you.
All right.
So we get that array adapter and then really you're going to be blown away.
Here we just take this auto complete text for you right.
We just say set adapter just like that Cirus a set adapter and we pass in our array adapter.
Boom that is all we need.
So let's go ahead and run this so you can see what this looks like.
Again we are here working with the auto complete text view.
And then we're going to be talking about the autofill API framework.
However you'd like to phrase that.
So the basic idea is the SAP's going to open up and as we start typing out the name of a friend if we
start typing out with an R it's going to hopefully show us Rick and if we do an asshole she'll share
Sarah.
And then why have all these names because I wanted to show you if we you know do a and it it'll show
all the ends of the food you and I will that show you know Nick need a Neenah but not know well.
And then you know we can keep sort of move from there.
So let's go ahead and pull up for you later.
Come on Android Syria we believe there we go.
All right.
So here it comes.
And if we start typing inside if you're like I said we'll do the.
And I look at that.
There's all our names.
Let's try out.
Sarah if I do an essay Oh it shows Sarah.
That's pretty cool.
James try the J.
Boom he pops up and if you're wondering if you type one of these out like I like Nina it will fill it
in the rest of the way for us.
And these are just like a tech so you can go ahead and get the text that's from inside of there turn
into a string whatever it is that you want to do.
But you might have noticed something that I think is a little bit annoying here is that I'd like it
if I type out just the letter and it would show me all the ends or I type out and it would show me all
the arts.
But instead we have to type out you know at least two letters in order for it to show up.
But that is customizable.
And so the way to fix that is you take your auto complete text for you and you say set threshold.
So this is how many characters someone has to type in order to get you know essentially the suggestions
to pop up so if we set it to one that's going to say they only need to do one letter and we'll go ahead
and search.
And the basic idea behind this is you know maybe if you don't have a huge array that you're tapping
into with only one letter it's not going to be enough.
Like it just doesn't make sense but you know to at that point maybe it's good and maybe for your situation
you want them to type three four or five characters whatever it is but just know that that is customizable.
So here comes the app and now you'll see when I type and inside of here look at that.
Nick Neenah Well NaeNae and if I do and I and all the sudden AOL drops out.
Same thing now if I do like J it goes for James Sarah bill.
There it is.
OK.
So there's the autocomplete text you which I think is really great.
Now the next one is the autofill framework API whatever you want to call it.
So this is the ability to have an app fill in edit Tex in other people's apps and Web sites stuff like
that and you can only have one default app that does a set of time.
So 99 percent of the time it's going to be a password manager.
Android has very explicitly stated in their documentation.
If you're using this technology you're most likely a password manager which if you are a password manager
you're probably a pretty large scale operation.
And so there's not really a lot of relevance for us.
But the part of relevance that we have is if someone's password manager is going to work with our app
we have to be able to work with it and so there's a little work that we have to do on our end so that
apps that use this autofill API can then successfully work with our app and it's really simple anywhere
that you have an edit text you just have to go into the SML and add a new attribute inside of here.
So what we're looking for is the Android Auto fill hints.
OK.
So go ahead and select this.
And once you do this you basically what you're trying to do is tell the app you know what kind of information
you're looking for in this particular task.
So for example if we were looking for a user name of somebody we would type in all caps auto fill and
we want underscore can't underscore user name.
OK.
And there's all sorts of different strings that we can use here.
So you know there's auto fill hint email auto fill hint phone number.
I think there's a great list of these in fact if you just go ahead and copy this whole string and if
we opened up Safari for instance if we paste this then I'm pretty sure we can get the full list here.
So let's see the autofill framework.
So look there's another one autofill and password.
I mean that would be a really really big one if your password manager.
But the idea is you know whatever it is in your app that you're going to be using that you're old you
know put these here so that those apps can say hey someone's trying to fill out a username I'm going
to suggest this option and then essentially brings up a menu very similar to what we have here where
it says oh are you looking to add this.
So again from my perspective it's very unlikely that you're going to be making an app with the autofill
API to be like the password manager on someone's phone.
Maybe you are and if you are props to you but more than likely you want to do your best to anywhere
you have an edit text that you think could work with this auto fill that you do your part to support
that to make it easier for your users.
Well that's all I've got for you.
Hope you learned about these two things.
Both of them are just these small little tips that we can add to our app to make it that much easier
for our users.
I'm sure they'll really appreciate our work.