In this lecture I want to help our little dude make it so that he can start falling down with gravity
and moving around on the screen.
So this is where we're going to start introducing some physics into our game.
I know that sounds a little bit complicated at least it was for me the first time I started doing game
programming but it's really not that bad.
So the first thing that we want to set up is the gravity.
And so this is how quickly our little dude is going to fall.
So we're going to make a new float.
We're going to call gravity and you decide what you want this to be equal to.
I found something like zero point two is a good place.
But again it's going to be different for everybody.
There's also another float that we want to introduce here and this is the velocity.
So go ahead and bring in velocity.
You can set this equal to whatever you want.
But I think a good starting point is at zero not the Letter 0 0.
Now we go.
So with these two pieces in place we can now write the code to make it so that our guy starts falling
down through the sky.
And so first of all we're going to do is we are going to calculate our man's velocity.
So we're going to say velocity is equal to whatever velocity currently is plus gravity.
So kind of a simpler way to do this is we can just say hey plus equals gravity just like this.
All right.
So we're going to go ahead and add that on there and then we're going to introduce a new variable here
and this is going to be the man's y position.
So we need a way to represent this guy's position when he's going to start the game and then as he starts
falling you know that's slowly going to update over time.
So we're going to come up to the top.
We're going to make an event that we're going to call man y again represents where he's going to be
on the screen.
So with this man why initially when the game very first starts we want that to be equal to you know
half of the height divided by two.
So we're actually going to cut this and we'll go ahead and paste that right in there so we can just
do that off the get go and we'll go ahead and replace man.
Why.
They're excellent.
But then we're now going to have an opportunity to change what man y is going to be.
So we've already calculated what the velocity is.
Now we have to apply this to man y and we're going to say Hey man why there's going to be equal to minus
equal whatever velocity is.
So you'll notice the first time we come through velocity is zero gravity 0.2.
We're going to subtract like 0.2 not much.
But then the next time velocity is going to be 0.4 of them point you know six eight whatever and slowly
we're going to see man y start falling down to the ground.
And so with this we should see him falling.
Let's let's give it the Old Testament confirm that's what we've got.
So we'll get our emulator here.
Ready to go and coin man has stopped.
I believe it's probably because I'm not allowed to set this up there.
So I want to go ahead and put zero there not before I copy that.
And we'll come and say all right you are on create maybe this is a good place for us to say you know
what.
Very first time we were on this.
Man why you should be equal to the center of the screen.
OK.
So let's try that one more time with Hopefully no airs there.
So here comes our app opens up and look at that or a little dude's falling but you fell off the screen
and you have even if we clicked there's no way to get them to come back up.
So there's one thing I want to do first to make sure that he you know if he lands down on the ground
he should be running on the ground unless we're making them jump.
And so we just need to check when we're doing all these calculations if you know man wise in the zero
or less than zero position we need to you know keep it at zero.
So we're going to do a little statement here when we say if we're going to say if man why is less than
or equal to zero meaning he's you know at the bottom of the screen or somehow deep below we want to
set his man y to be equal to zero so that he always kind of stays at the bottom.
So if we go ahead and run this now you'll see he'll fall down but he'll stop there at the bottom.
We still got to figure out the jump situation but at least this will get him to the bottom and looking
at all sudden he stops and he's now just running on the ground.
So the next step for us is to make it so that he can jump now in order to do that.
What we're going to do here is we are going to do a little if statement is you know decide if he should
be jumping or not.
So I'm going to go ahead and put this more at the top here and this is going to be an if statement that
will teach us how to work with touch.
So GDX has this awesome if we do GDX dot input dot just touched.
This will be equal to true when someone just taps the screen in it you know recognizes that the next
time that loops run this will be true.
It will be equal to false after that.
So this is only true once.
And so this is our opportunity to you know have a negative number here.
So in this case we're going to say velocity is equal to negative 10.
So the idea with this is when we say velocity is equal to negative 10 as we come down here we're going
to say OK negative 10 plus equal gravity so now it's like you know negative nine point eight and then
we're going to do zero minus negative 9.8 which really adds 9.8.
So it makes him jump up and if he wasn't at zero would make him go even higher and higher.
So let's go ahead and run this.
I want you to see what this looks like for yourself.
And we'll will go ahead and wait a second here and look at that.
When I click here he jumps up how cool is that.
That is an excellent thing that we've got going here.
So we've got some beautiful beautiful movement.
All right.
So I know we didn't go too far in this one but I feel like Logically this is a good stopping point for
us in the next one.
We're going to tackle the big subject of how do make the coins in the bombs move across the screen so
we're going to get into all of that in the next lecture.