So I misspoke in the last lecture I said that this was going to be about four loops it's actually going
to be about lists and arrays so listen arrays in cotland pretty straightforward.
The most simple simple way to make them let's say I want to make a variable of my lucky numbers and
say var lucky numbers is going to be equal to you just type list of.
And you don't have to specify the type inside those angle brackets you could just say like 1 6 7 8 3.
You just have to separate the items by commas and then all of sudden you have a list.
Same thing if you want to do an array you just have to say array of like that.
And all of a sudden now you have an array of ints.
Now if you want to make an empty array and not specify the type you can say array of.
And then inside of the angle brackets you just have to say what's going to be in there for example I
might say you know this is going to be an array of ints if you want to see that.
Now with both arrays and lists you can't grow or shrink them.
So if you want to be able to do something like that you need a mutable list so you can say for example
mutable list of and provide something like a set of numbers here I'll just go ahead and put some in.
Then if you want to add onto these you can you can say lucky numbers add and specify.
You know that one you want it to go at a specific position.
So if I had like the number five I can say that this should go in at position zero or something like
that.
That's totally fine.
Or if you just want to straight up provide something in there you could just say I want to add the number
four.
That's it.
That's valid code.
Other functions that come with here.
Really if you just hit the dot you're going to see you can remove at.
You can replace things you can turn things into a set.
All sorts of stuff.
But again if you want to grab something out of an array or a list you just do square brackets after
the name of your list or array and then say you know I want something from position zero and if you
know we go ahead and do a print line of this let's go ahead and do this.
You should see us get back to the very first value which is a 1 and so we'll wait for that look there
is it is there and if I give it a position of 3 for example that should give us the very last item in
the list so the number 6 we'll see if that works.
And look there it is.
Now if you want to get the size of a list you just do dot size and it's going to give you back an int
shall we.
So we should see the number four come through here and look.
There it is.
So really that's the lowdown on lists an array.
Pretty straightforward.
Again there are some differences between lists in array.
If you really want to get technical into it but honestly in most cases it's not going to be a huge deal.
So you can use those almost interchangeably.
But again if you really want to be able to grow and shrink the size of the list you've got to have a
mutable list in order to do that.
OK so let me go ahead and give you a quick challenge here.
It's going to be really straightforward.
Make a list of your favorite movies.
That's it Jane.
So go ahead hip hop on the video and do that now.
OK.
So hopefully that went well should be pretty straightforward.
I'm mostly interested to see what your favorite movies are so please leave it as a comment it'd be interesting
to see.
So I'm going to make a variable.
Fav movies and in mine listing is a list of and I might put inside of here or something like sandlot.
And another one of my favorite movies is Emperor's New Groove.
I'm sure I didn't spell that correctly.
And another favorite of mine is probably fast and the Furious.
And again I'm going to spell that wrong.
But anyways there are some of my favorite movies hopefully your spelling is a little bit better than
mine.
One thing that I did want to mention really quickly is that if you want to specify the type of A-list
or an array you can do that by saying Here you do do for example Capitol list and then in the angle
brackets you say what's going to be inside of there.
So in this case it would be a string.
Say OK this is going to be a list of string objects if you ever need to specify the type of a list you
can do that by doing this.