So in the previous video we saw how we can fade images in and out in this video we're going to just
whip through a number of other animations that we can do just of which you caught a glimpse of in the
previous video.
So I'm just going to get rid of the
part is showing part because we get to do all our animations with Bart.
And let's start then by taking about imagery and animate and we'll look at first the translation
animations.
So I've got translations with x y and Zed there.
And you'll notice that we've got either translation X which translates to a particular value translate
by the way in this case just means move.
It's a mathematical term.
Or we can use translation x by.
So this would move it in the x direction by a certain number of the piece.
So let's try translation y by let's say we want to meet it 1000 d piece.
This will be a thousand deep down and again will have a duration of 2000 OK.
Let's have a look.
So this will mean that probably off the screen in a downward direction.
Which is something you might want to do if you want to get rid of an element from the screen.
Here we go.
But.
And off he goes Oh not quite off the screen so you want to go further maybe 2000 pixels or maybe more.
If you want to make sure he's off the screen regardless of the pixel size.
So he's a quick challenge for you then can you change this so that instead of disappearing down he disappears
to the left and he goes completely off the screen.
Give it a go.
All right.
Hopefully you manage that.
It's pretty simple.
We use a translation ex-spy and we want to beat him to the left so that's minus a thousand.
The plus direction is to the right.
And I think a thousand will be enough.
You might want to put more there just to be sure.
Here we go.
And off he goes.
Fantastic.
So that's translations or movements.
Let's try a rotation.
So again we've got rotation and rotation by and rotation in the x and y directions as well.
So let's start off with just a simple rotation and then we get the number of degrees that we want to
rotate about.
So let's turn him upside down 360 degrees is a full circle so 180 is a half circle.
And again we'll set the duration date a bit quicker this time.
So we'll do it in one second.
The lightning button to load that up super quick.
Zap him and there we go.
If you wanted him to spin around many times you could put a zero on the end of that and he'll now rotate
five times in the same one second.
So it'll get him spinning.
Very nice.
You could even combine the animations in any way you like.
So notice if after rotation we put say an alpha to zero we could fade him out and spin him at the same
time.
See that in action.
There we go.
And the funnel type I want to show you is a scale
and again we can scale to a specific value or by a specific value and we can do it in the x and y directions
as well.
So let's say we want to make it half size.
We scale x and 0.5 will scale y to no point five as well.
And then as usual set the duration to 1 second.
Now notice we've got a red squiggly line here.
That's because the scale x function just with all the animation functions that we've used expects a
float and by default if you use a decimal value it's a double and even though they're just different
types of numbers we do need to convert from one to the other.
So the scale x value accepts the correct type but there's a very easy way to do that.
If you want to convert a number to a float you just put an F after it.
So that wasn't necessary before because we had integer values whole numbers which didn't require the
math.
But when you've got decimals then you do need to convert it to a flat.
All right.
Let's take a look.
So that should shrink down.
To half size.
There we go.
So here's a quick challenge for you then.
What I'd like you to do is animate Bart into existence.
So we're going to start the app with a blank screen.
I want Bart to spin into action from the left.
So after the animation he should be full screen just like he was at the beginning of this app.
But I want him to come in from the left and spinning as soon as the app is opened.
All right.
A little challenge for you there.
Best of luck over.
OK type you managed it.
So the first thing that will need to change is the initial position of bot.
So the moment is of course position on the screen but we want him to be positioned to the left of the
screen.
Initially.
So let's change our constraint from 0 8.
To minus 1000.
All right.
How did you manage that.
As always lots of different ways to do it.
But you almost certainly had to write some code in the on method because we wanted this animation to
happen on the opening of the app.
So first off we want to move Bart off of the main screen.
So we can use our bot image.
So I just copy this down rather than type it again and then will animate him off the screen.
So we want to use a translation X by and or use the same minus a thousand as before.
If we wanted this to work on every device we might make that 2000 but a thousand will be fine for our
emulator.
Let's just have a quick check and make sure that makes Bart initially disappear.
And they would get.
So you can say no about that.
Just a quick note if you're a little uneasy about using animations here we're doing effectively an instant
animation because we're not setting a generation.
There is another way to do that which is perhaps more self-explanatory.
So we could just set the x coordinate for example to minus thousand and that would do effectively the
same thing but without an animation.
So I'm going to use set X but you can use the animate if you prefer that.
All right.
Now it's just a matter of bringing him in.
So let's use that image we might.
And then we want to translate by and we want 1000 pixels to the rights this time to bring him back in.
And we also want the rotation overtakes him ten times 3600 degrees in the space of two seconds.
All right.
So let's have a look.
We should now find that Bart spins in from the left.
There we go.
Excellent so you can use these animations either to make your apps more exciting or to add actual fluidity
and functionality to games in particular.
And that's what we're going to be doing in the next video where we'll be making our own version of Kinect
3.