Now it's time to build the final activity in our whatsapp clone the chat activity and this is actually
going to be fairly straightforward.
We're going to bring in a simple plain text field which will go the bottom of the screen and we'll be
full with and that will be where the user can post
their chat
so I'll call this chat at a text and then we're going to use a list view to display past chats.
So let's try again how list we want to align the list view with the chat edit text.
So I'm going to bring that in.
Like that's.
And then look at our list view just above our chat edit text and we'll call this jet stream.
There we go.
All right so we've got two jobs here.
We want the user to be able to send a chat and we want to be able to view all the past chats in the
last few.
So I come to think of it will also need a button
which you put in the bottom right them
which will be a send chat button.
Right.
So let's do the send chat part first.
And we'll do that with a public method called Send chat
and we're going to need to know the active user here.
So I'm going to define my active user
initially just as an empty string.
And now to get the chat content I'm going to need to know the content of the chat at it.
TEXT
So let's get that text or call it chat edit text.
That's going to be an edit text found by Thaiday resources dot ID dot chat text.
Then we can create a pause object
called message and this is going to be a new parse object with a class of message.
And for our messages are we going to need to keep track of is the sender the recipient and the message
itself.
So let's say there is say message don't put will have senda and that could be our current user so pass
user get current user to get username.
We're going to need the recipient
which is going to be the active user
and then we'll need the message
which will be added text.
Don't get text don't to strain.
And then we'll take a message.
Save it in the background with a new safe callback.
And then as long as there's no error
we'll just let the user know that that's been successful.
OK so far so simple let's give it a go.
So try and send Keston a message tap send and it's looking good.
Just make sure I that in Firefox will refresh the past dashboard.
And now we can see that message that
prelim send up Rob recipient Keston.
Well with that let's just add a quick response.
Say hi how's it going from Caston to rap.
Right.
So now we're going to need to display all of these messages.
We'll do that in the on create method.
So we'll need
an array list of strings to keep track of the messages.
I will also need an array adapter.
What Without list view.
So let's find the chat.
List v..
It's going to be LSV which we find by its id our ID chat list we
Melosa set up the Araya adapter.
Going it be a new array adapter.
Using this as the context Android are taught lay out dot simple list item one has they lay out and then
messages as the linked list.
Then because I'm feeling confident I'm going to go straight into the parse query
can be equal Pasch query on past objects this time which I'll call query
and then this is going to be a new parse query and querying the message class.
We created Ophir.
Now we want to do something very slightly different to what we've done before.
We want to do a double query because we're going to be looking for messages that are sent and received
by our user.
So we're looking for where the sender is equal to rob or the recipient is equal to rob and of course
the other way round.
If the sender is Rob we want to make sure the recipient is Keston So we're going to need two queries
to do that.
So I'm actually going to rename that query one and then we can see set query one
where the sender is equal to our current user so pass user get current user to get username
and we want the recipient
to be the active user the person that we're currently communicating with.
I've been going to create a second pass query
on Pozzo objects which I'll call query to which will be a new POS query.
Again on the message class and this time we want it the other way around so when the recipient
is equal to a
the current use of
and all say they send the
must be equal to the active user.
OK then we take these two queries and combine them into a single query.
When we do that by putting them into a list.
So this is going to be a list of pass queries and both the past queries I pass objects
Huckle this queries
and this is going to be a new list
on past queries containing POS objects you know just get in the wrong place that they're.
So then we take our queries and we add query 1 to it.
And then we add query to
and then finally we create our main query
in the usual way.
But this time we use past query
and you can see at the bottom that we've got dot all.
And then we put out a list of queries in and that's how in past you run or queries i.e. when we want
to check for one set of things being true or another set of things being true.
It's a little bit based but hopefully that makes sense.
And we want to order those by date so we'll take our query and order by descending.
And the thing we want to check for is they created out of date
that we gave.
So now we've got to have Querrey will find it in the background
with of course a new find Colback
then will check to make sure there's no error
and that we have some objects
and if that's the case we'll get through the
each of these is going to be pass objects which are core message
in objects and then we want to add them to our messages.
Frailest which recreates it up here.
There it is
and I'll actually start by clearing messages just in case.
And then we want to add them to messages but we do want a way to make it clear which ones are from us
and which ones are from the other user.
So obviously lots of ways you can do that.
I'm going to use a very simple way and just append a greater than sign at the beginning if it's from
the other use of.
So let's create a string not a string tokenizer just a string called message content and this will initially
be message don't get string and it's the message string where the message is contained
and then we'll just check to see if the sender I message get string
sender is not the current user.
So pass user get current user
get username
when in fact we should use as their strings equals
rather than the equal t.
There we go.
But we do want that not to be the case.
We'll put you on the front.
So if the senda is not our user then we'll add the greater than sign to the beginning of the story.
So I will just use message content equals
greater than sign and then message content.
There we go.
Then we'll append that to messages
and then when we're done so just message content.
I want to append and then when we finished we'll take our array adapter and notify that the data set
has changed
and there we go.
There's just one thing I think I've forgotten to add and that is I haven't actually applied the array
adapter to the checklist view.
So let's do that then we get.
All right.
So that's one of the more complex queries that we've done on paths.
But it's the only way to do or queries here.
You set up to individual queries and then combine them as a list.
And now we should be able to tap on Keston and see the messages that have been sent both ways.
Let's take a look.
And there we go.
So we can see both of those messages.
And probably worth noting that we've got the newest at the top there is generally considered best in
chat apps today the newest at the bottom.
So let's just change that the order by ascending.
All right.
So we're pretty much done.
The only thing I want to change is that when the user sends the message currently it's not added to
their chat so let's fix that.
Well save it for the save Colback if you want to make your app appear even faster.
You can always do it straight away there perhaps have some kind of symbol which updates when it's actually
been sent.
Just put it in the safe in background callback.
And all we need to do is add it to messages
and again we want to chat and text to get text got to straight and then update the array adapter to
notify it that it's been changed.
All right so let's check that out.
We should now find that when we send a message it appears almost immediately on the chat left.
And here we go.
So few that chat again.
There it is.
Reply.
Great thanks.
How are you.
Send and then it appears there when it's been successfully sent.
All right.
So pretty much they're the only slight thing is that we don't really want the message to still be there
in the box after we sent it.
So let's make it disappear
straight after we have sent it here.
So would just use jet and it takes a set text to empty.
And of course if we're going to do that we need to store the content of it before we use it down there.
So that's create a string
message content which reach out at it text don't get text
talk to string
and in fact we can make that up slightly more efficient.
By using message content there as well
and then here
we use message content again.
All right so a final check we should now find that our chat added text content disappears ready for
a new message.
When we've sent our message I can say once again over to this chat and let's ask her if she wants some
coffee.
And there we go.
So that's deleted content ready for a new message.
Terrific.
So we now have our what's at play with the basic functionality replicated.
Of course there's a huge amount we could add to this including sending things like images and videos
including Read receipts and a lot more.
But I'll leave that to you and I'll end my whatsapp clone here.
Congratulations on making it to the end of the developer part of this course.
Now we're going to move straight on and see how you can market those fantastic apps that you're going
to build using the skills that you've learned in this course.