All right in this lecture we are going to learn about alert dialog so this is the second Android concept
and I want you to learn before we dive into the Notes app.
And essentially what alert dialog does is it pops up to let the user select one of two options and allows
them to move forward.
It just sort of hey if you need to check on something maybe display an error to the user this can be
an effective way to do that.
So let's go ahead and start a new Android project what we're going to do is first learn about Alert
dialogs then we have a challenge for you.
So let's just go ahead and call this one alert demo.
Can't we just want defaults on everything here so we'll go ahead and get that set up.
So the basic idea with this first one is we're just going to create an alert dialog dialog that basically
says hey are you sure that you want to do this it's supposed to be like a dialogue that might be presented
when someone's you know open an app for the very first time or that they're about to do a save or they're
going to delete something right is time to confirm some sort of user action.
So it is mostly just a demo to make sure you understand what's going on and then we'll apply it later.
So let's give ourselves some space to type this is all done via code.
There's no visual part of this that needs to be done.
So let's go ahead and first just create a new alert dialog.
So we're going to create a new dialog.
And don't get those parentheses at the end there.
You want to do capital alert.
Capitol dialog dot we're going say capital builder just like this.
And inside of those parentheses you want to pass this because it's asking for a context and then you're
going to be amazed by this we're just going to keep an offering thing after thing where we keep setting
adding settings onto the alert dialog.
So for example the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to say you know this alert dialog
builder dot and then we want to set the icon so we'll say set icon and the way to get to you know a
list of icon IDs we're going to say lowercase Android dot capital are not draw all dot.
And then this is where there's going to be a lot of them so we want to go for I.S. underscore dialog
alert and you can see there's all sorts of different options here but we just want the alert.
This is kind of the the basic one to work with now because we're going to be getting a ton of these
different settings on this one dialog builder.
I recommend hitting enter each time you've got to add a new bullet point.
So after we have set the icon we want to do another bullet point and we're going to say Dot said title
this time.
Right.
So this is just going to be some string that says what it is that we want this to say.
So we'll have the say.
Are you sure.
Exclamation Point question mark we've got to make this as dramatic as possible.
And then with this we're also then going to set a message so with an alert dialog you're able to set
a title and a message that title sort of the big thing in bold and then you can add some more details
here if you'd like.
You don't have to include a message but this one will say do you definitely we want to do this.
And then maybe we'll save the exclamation point on this one just to the question mark.
So we've set the icon title message.
Then we have to set the positive and the negative buttons.
So first let's go ahead and set the positive buttons will say set positive button.
So this is the one that users will select if they're trying to say yes to something or continue.
So the reason the Android chose positive and negative buttons is that you know every apps going to have
different use cases for these alert dialogs.
But if you always puts the kind of affirmative the yes the positive thing with a positive button users
will kind of get used to stuff that's you know in the positive position versus the not.
Of course there's titles there but just sort of helps to keep those things in place.
But with this positive button.
Couple of things of looking for first.
It's looking for an eye as a string about what you want to say in this button.
In this case we'll say yes.
Right so this is the positive button we want to say yes there.
Next thing is we want to set in on click listener so to do this we're going to go ahead say a new space
Capitol dialogue and we want the dialogue interface on listeners so just go ahead and hit enter on that
and you can see I guess there's this huge chunk of code.
And basically what we're looking for inside of here is inside of this enclave that we can type anything
and this will be code that's run.
If someone chooses the yes option so it will go ahead and let's just for example make a toast with this
or say toaster make text we'll provide our capital main activity.
This as the context let's go ahead and put some sort of message and we'll say maybe like it's done to
say that you know they had to confirm this action so we went ahead and went through with it.
We'll do capital TOSed dot length short and we'll do a show on that and semi-colon tank.
So that was set everything up for the positive but we also want to do a dot set negative button.
So for this one we want to go ahead and provide again the string for this one will say no.
And then if you want to for that Arncliffe listener you can provide no which basically says hey if they
choose this one and we're not going to do anything we'll just say you know what comes out of the dialog
box and move forward.
So after you said the negative button really the last option here is you just have to say Dot show can't.
So again this was a whole lot of code to create this dialog box and show it.
But this is what we need in order to move forward.
So let's go ahead and hit run here.
And again I'm going to teach you the skill.
And then we're going to come combine this with what we learned about menu items make sure we've got
both these skills in our tool belt and then we'll move forward with making a fun little app.
So here comes the app open it up so look for this alert dialog to show up and look at that.
Are you sure.
And this you know I see dialog alert we could have chose different icons if we wanted to this one is
kind of the you know if something important is about to happen and you can kind of mess around with
those see which one you want and then you can see our message do you definitely want to do this and
there's the yes and the No.
So if we say yes then look we get that little toast that says It's it's done.
But if you run this one more time and instead said select No it's just going to simply not do anything
because we provide null for that click listener so we tap no on that one.
Nothing happens.
So the challenge that I have for you is I want you to create an app where the user can save a language
preference whether they want to use your app in English or they want to use it in Spanish and it doesn't
have to be English in Spanish.
Maybe you want it to be French and Japanese or Chinese and Guatemalan.
That's not a language that's a location regardless.
Anyways you know just the language preference app so I don't use English and Spanish and the idea is
that when the user opens the app for the very first time it's going to present them an alert dialog
and say Would you like to use English or Spanish in this app and you know they make their decision and
then once they've made their decision there should be a menu item here that if they select this they
can go choose English or Spanish and update their selection and when they update their selection either
the first time or through the menu item that should be saved inside of the shared preferences.
So the next time they open up it's like oh they told us once they want to use this app in Spanish.
Well you know be able to provide stuff in Spanish and whether they chose English or Spanish just show
it up inside of a text few here on the screen effect you can just use the hello world that comes with
a new app.
OK.
So go ahead create a new Android studio project go do that on your own.
Hit pause now.
All right.
So hopefully that went well for you.
Let's go ahead and move forward with this so we are going to create a new Android studio project.
So go ahead and pick this.
Now the name for this one.
I'm going to call it playing with language.
You spell this correctly language preferences.
There we go.
Pref Bruin's.
Man my spelling is atrocious.
It's embarrassing.
But we'll go ahead I'll just use the standards for all this moving forward.
OK.
Now once we got this in place remember the first thing that we want to do is we want to present an alert
dialog that again just says hey do you want to move forward in English or Spanish.
So you know we had just created all that code before this should go really quickly.
I would go do a copy and paste but it's going to take about the same time to just type it out anyways
so let's just go for gold here.
So we want a new alert dialog and on this we want to do a builder.
And with this will pass and this as the context and then we'll start doing our dog.
So first thing we've got to set the icon and so we'll go ahead and do Android dog our dog drawable dot
and let's go ahead and with this one.
Let's do I see Button speak now that will kind of help you know.
Talk about that we're you know working with languages here then we're going to go ahead and set the
title with this.
We're going to go ahead and say choose a language remember we just want to provide two options next.
Let's go ahead and set the message.
Well sort of reiterate what we had said before but will say which language would you like to use.
Questionmark excellent.
Next thing we've got to set a positive buttons or say set positive button with this.
We're going to have in this case the positive the English and the negative Spanish.
Now as for deciding which language goes where.
Totally up to you.
Maybe a more positive option or more popular option you put in the positive box but you know depending
on where you're going to be maybe Spanish is more popular than an English maybe German is more popular
than Japanese right.
But it probably doesn't matter too much in this situation.
So we're going to go ahead and put English in this one English.
So then we want to provide an enclave listeners who going to say new dialogue interface on click listener.
So the code that we want to run through here is essentially we want to set the language to English.
So let's just go ahead and say set English right now.
We're going to create a function that is going to handle that for both either language option.
But we just want that for now.
Let's go ahead and set the negative button.
So for this one will say Spanish and again we want a new dialogue interface on click listener and this
one we want to set Spanish just like that.
All right so we've got icon title message positive negative button.
Once all those are in place we simply want to do a show and we'll do our semi-colon there.
Now the question is you know how do we set the English and how do we set the Spanish like what kind
of code do we want to provide there.
Well we want to create a function that no matter what language you pass into it it will be able to save
that information.
So let's go ahead and just make a new function we'll say.
Public void and we'll call this maybe set language and in the parentheses.
We'll go ahead and provide it and say you know you should pass on a string that we'll call language
can go do our curly brackets on that which now means if we want to set English we just call set language
and we provide English right inside of there.
And if we want to do Spanish we can say Set Language and just provide Spanish right inside of their
tank.
So now that's appropriately calling this method.
Now we've got to write the code in order to make this all happen.
So we want to save this and shared preferences for say shared preferences lowercase shared preferences
equal to this get shared preferences and inside of here we're going to first pass the name of our app
paste that in there.
Then we're going to go ahead and provide one a comma there and we want to do context dot and we want
unmowed private for this one.
So we now have our shared preferences set up and then let's go ahead and put in the language that they
selected.
So this should be very simple just say shared preferences dot it and this is where we're going to put
a string inside of there.
Now what's going to be the name of this remember.
Remember just say something like language because we're just describing what it is that we're saving
language in my spelling that correctly looks fine to me.
But then as for the actual value let's pass in whatever came through in this language parameter soldiers
to say pass in language right there.
Once we've got that in place the next thing that we want to do is we want to update the text to which
then means we have to have access to the text view.
So let's go over here to our main activity and let's figure out the ID for this hello world text view.
It doesn't have one so let's go ahead and put that in.
All right so now that we've give it the name of text view we have to get access to that.
So we're going to say text view lowercase text use equal to find view by id Capitol our DOT ID dot text
view.
Boom.
Now we have access to that.
Then the next step for us is we want to set the text so we can say text view set text and we'll pass
inside of there whatever the languages that they selected.
So we'll just pass in language Okay.
So with that in place let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
Let's run this on the emulator.
That looks good.
Again app should open up.
It should present that dialog box or alert dialog and you know we can say English or Spanish or whichever
one we chose it should be Chez saved and shared preferences.
And also it should be showing up in the text view.
OK.
So go ahead and give this a second to load up here.
And look at that comes through which language you like to use.
I want to use Spanish in a vice like Spanish.
Don't do it.
Look it shows Spanish.
Now one thing that I would like to show here is that if we're going to be working with this app again
like let's say we close out of it and we open it back up we would like it to be able to show what we
chose last time.
And so in order to do this we've got to have access to our shared preferences so let's go ahead and
rather than having to type this code all the time I'm going to cut this piece and I'm going to bring
it up top as a prop..
And then whenever we are going to create the shared preferences Let's go ahead and just put this inside
of the create.
So I'm going to cut this code when it comes down to our on create and paste that code right in there
so it says OK you know we have the shared preferences we can now use it here but we can also use it
in this method as well.
So with that let's go ahead and pull out whatever language we got from shared preferences.
So let's make a new string called language and we are going to set this equal to our shared preferences
dot get string and the string that we're looking forward is the language and then we need to provide
a default just in case it doesn't come through and in that case you know we could just leave it blank.
I think it would be nice to leave something like air or so the user knows that something went wrong
here.
OK.
So that now gives us a language.
And with this we want to go ahead and do some sort of Estaban because if there's already been a language
selected inside of the shared preferences well then we don't want to go do this whole alert dialog box
like that would be annoying for the user.
Like right now if we go to our emulator and let's go ahead and close out of language preferences and
let's open it up let's see where's there's language preferences.
You can see even though we've already picked Spanish and it's saved in shared preferences.
You know we have to be presented that question again.
So we're going to go ahead and do an if statement and go put big curly brackets around all of this.
OK.
And the thing that we want to check and see is language that equals and we want to see if it's equal
to Capitol Hill air because remember that's going to be our default to come back if you know we weren't
successfully able to get something.
So if the language equals error that means that we want to you know go through this whole thing asking
them which one they would like to use.
And then you know that gives us the opportunity to then present a Else situation to say OK you know
if they weren't able to find this information then you know let's go ahead and set some things.
Now the ELSE situation.
Go ahead and provide that.
We want to update the text for you which right now we only have access to up there.
So let's go ahead and cut this text view paste it right up at the top.
And again we can still have this text view but we want to move this to our on creative method same place
where we're setting our shared preferences here.
So just go ahead and paste that.
That really makes this set languages method that much cleaner.
Go ahead and leave some space there.
But with that in place now in this situation you know if we already have language select them selected
will simply just say okay text view set text and we'll go ahead and pass in whatever language has been
selected.
Right.
In this case it would be whatever came out of shared preferences.
All right.
So with those things in place let's go ahead and just see if we run the app that it will show.
I believe we selected Spanish last time she should say Spanish when the app opens up.
This is from last time so doesn't really count.
But look app opens up and oh we're still asked Would you like to use Spanish or English to let's do
Spanish should shouldn't be showing this again.
So go ahead and X out of this and let's try opening it one more time.
So will go to our APs language preferences and we're still getting the box there so let's go ahead and
walk through this real quick.
So if the language that comes back from here is equal to error then we want to run the code here so
maybe it's not maybe I'm not I didn't spell this correctly so laying edge.
No it looks like it's correct.
Let's go ahead and do this.
I'm going to do some live debugging in front of you.
Let's go ahead and log whatever language is equal to so say the Lang and we'll just go ahead and type
out language to see what it is that we're working with
language.
Excellent.
Now let's go ahead and run this so this time when we run we want to make sure that we've got log cabin
up and running here.
And let's see here comes the app.
So it opens up.
And so the langue is equal to air.
So for some reason.
Now I know what it is.
Whenever we did the put string we forgot to do a dot apply there.
OK.
So I bet once we fix this that's going to be the case.
So sometimes that's what it takes doing a quick log and just sort of walking through the code there
to see what the problem is.
Let's see so if I said Spanish here I go ahead and I X out this app and we open it up one more time.
So like language preference like that it shows Spanish.
So the last piece of this app is we want to integrate the menu ability right.
If someone wants to go hit a menu and say oh I originally said Spanish I want to change English we should
give them that option.
So let's go ahead bring back out our side menu.
We have to create that menu directory.
So we want a new directory that will call a menu.
And while we have that many Slichter will say file new and we want a menu resource file.
So again we're going to call this underscore main menu and that's going to go in that menu directory.
So that's good.
Go ahead and hit OK there.
So now we have this main menu.
SML where we can set some stuff up let's go ahead and go to that text view of this.
So remember we want to put items inside of here so let's make a new item.
And with this item we're going to first set the title so we're going to say Android title is equal to
let's do English first English.
Here we go.
The next thing that we want to set here is the IDs are in Android.
Idea is equal to a plus side slash in let's say English right there.
That means that we can close up this item and we just want to create another item in case they want
to do Spanish so we'll go ahead and pass that in and change this space vanish and also change this idea
to say Spanish.
Here we go.
So let's go look at the design.
That looks beautiful.
It's always weird to me why it shows that eclipsed here.
But when we actually run the app that it doesn't because there's clearly enough space I don't know if
that's an android studio bug or whatnot but with these two things in place we just then have to go and
are you know proper menus here by menus I mean the proper methods for when someone select something
so the first thing is we have to create the menu.
So we're going to say on create options menu.
And again the idea here is we use that menu inflators So we're going to say menu inflator menu inflator
is equal to.
We want to do get menu inflator then with that we're going to go ahead and say All right we're going
to take this menu inflator and we're going to do dot inflate and we want to pass in our dot menu dot
main menu that's the name of the one that we created.
Now we're going to pass through this menu object just like that.
OK.
That's all it takes for that method.
And then for the next one here this is when someone selects an item menu so menu item rather we're going
to say on options items selected.
And remember again we do want to call this Super But we have to return either true or false.
You know saying whether or not we were able to successfully do this.
So in this situation we basically just want to check whether or not they set things equal to English
or to Spanish so let's do our switch like we did before.
Inside of here.
We want to switch on an item not get item ID.
So in one case where we say OK if it's equal to capital our DOT ID dot English.
OK.
If that's the case then what we want to do is we want to call our set language method and we're going
to go ahead and pass in English just like that and we're going to do a similar case for if they choose
capital or indeed Spanish and that situation will say set language we want to pass in Spanish.
OK.
Now you know we could go ahead and do the return true here and the return return true for that other
one in the that you know define a default and all that stuff but for right now I think it's best if
we just go ahead and say return true here like that and then we can still you know do our default just
in case something else comes through in which case we'd want to return false.
But I think this will save us a little bit of code by saying you know if it wasn't one of those two
then we want to run that.
Although guess what the problem with this one is that there could be a situation where this handles
all of the situations so I guess we will actually have to do that.
I tried to save us some code didn't really work out.
Not everything works OK.
So go ahead make sure we get proper spacing on all of this.
And let's go ahead and give our app a run.
So our app when it opens up this time now that we've you know selected Spanish It should show that appropriately
when it opens but we should have the option to switch it to English back to Spanish if we want to.
So here comes the app.
Look it shows Spanish but we now have this menu.
So if I select English here that it uses English and to make sure that this works let's go ahead and
hit the X on that and we will open up the app again and it should show English.
Boom.
It shows English.
OK.
So you're now in a perfect position to move forward on our notes app.
You learn about dialog's you learn about menu items and we've even taken the stuff we've learned about
storage and we've sort of meshed it all in here so we're in a great spot.
Now make notes app.
Let's dive into it.