All right.
Hello.
Welcome to the egg timer app.
I want to show you the finished product of where it is that we want to get.
So I want you to create an app that has a timer like this where you can just set a you know amount of
time for a short period maybe you know a minute 58 and you go in all sudden your timer is going to start
counting down and you can stop and you'll notice we got this grayed out so we can't go ahead and update
that but if we hit the stop button this will reset it back to 30 seconds and I'll show you if we bring
it down to a smaller amount of time I'm going to turn up the sound here.
We want to have some sort of alarm or something play when the timer finishes.
So yeah check that out.
Pretty cool.
So this is what I want you to create.
I'm going allow you to go ahead and do this on your own again and when you do things by yourself that's
where the real learning takes place of course I'll walk through how to complete it.
But I want you to have the opportunity to do this on your own.
Now as far as there's really two things you've got to go get before you do this and that's the picture
of an egg and some sort of sound that you want to play when the alarm ends.
So for the time or rather I just went ahead and searched egg on google images found this one on clip
art panda dot com so if you'd like to find one similar I'd just suggest going to Google Images also
for the air HOERR sound.
I found one on sound Bible dot com so you can go get these exact ones if you want to really I just recommend
googling to go find the proper you know image and sound and you can just go ahead right click save that
image for here on sound Bible you have to click the empty three button to go ahead and download that.
But that's how you get those.
And again I want you to eventually arrive at an app like this.
Try as much as you can on your own.
Then we'll come back.
I'll show you how I did it and maybe you'll learn from the differences between us.
Good luck.
All right.
Let's go ahead and get started here.
We want to create a new project for this egg timer.
I'm going to call my project appropriately egg timer and I'll just go ahead and do the defaults for
all these hit enter through there.
And then while this is setting up we have our air horn sound we have a image that we need to get.
So I've already got those downloaded there on my desktop.
You can see them but we need to appropriately get them into the project so the first one that we want
to add is the egg to our draw draw a fold or so we're going to right click here.
We're going to say reveal in Finder.
And with that we'll go ahead and take our egg.
We want to put images in there and we'll just drop the egg there.
OK and the next thing we want to do inside of Rez is we want to make a new directory.
I'm going to call this raw.
This is going to hold our audio file.
So right click on raw here and we'll say reveal and finder and then we'll go ahead and take our air
horn noise here and we'll go ahead and put it in raw go.
Now with both of these just to make sure we're up to date we're going to say synchronized rah.
We're also going to right click drawable say synchronize Yes synchronize selected files.
There we go.
OK.
So now that we have those two in place let's go ahead and work on the visual side of the app.
I feel like it's usually best when you're working on a project that's visually get it set up right and
then let's write all the code to make it magical and work.
So we'll go ahead and start on this main activity ourselves to room some room to work with here.
And the first thing that we want to do is we want to bring in the Sikh bar so see if we've got a seat
bar here I guess before we do that let's get rid of that text view that we had before and we'll go ahead
and bring in the Sikh bar and we want to have this thing stuck up to the top.
Let's go ahead and just do.
Maybe a margin of five.
We also want it connected to the sides here so let's maybe say you know on this side we wanted to have
you know five as well.
And on the right side again let's go ahead and do something like five.
Now with this we've got to make sure we select this and we'll fiddle around here till we get to extend.
Perfect.
So now we've got the Sikh bar which is in a good place.
Now the next step is we need to go ahead and get an image view so that we can show the egg their souls
go ahead and go to our images here.
There there's an image you will go ahead and bring that out.
All right.
So it wants to put something in there.
Let's go ahead and select that beautiful egg that we had before we cut those nice big eggs.
That's showing up and let's go ahead and connect it with what we've got so go up to the top.
We want it to be fairly close.
You know your numbers you can totally pick what you want these to be.
I'm kind of having a fun time with the number five here so let's go ahead and see what that looks like.
If we if we find that we don't like it we can always go ahead and change it.
So this is something you just got to kind of play around with and find what you think works best.
OK.
So we have the Sikh bar.
We have the egg.
Really the next thing for us is we need a label to be able to show a text for you rather.
How much time is left here.
And then we need a button so let's go ahead and go to our text.
We'll bring out a text for you here.
I think it might just be best if we have it centered maybe here inside of the egg so go ahead and just
say that this thing should be centered.
I forget with this you want to go ahead and right click here.
And we want to go as a center we'll start with horizontally and parent.
Right click and say center vertically imperent.
OK.
So we've got that at the center of the screen.
Let's start with some default text of maybe saying you know there's 30 seconds on the timer or something
like that but it's really really tiny right now like kind of hard to see.
Tiny so you can actually go here and change what you want this to look like.
I kind of just prefer going in and changing the raw size of this so go ahead and scroll down till we
get to the text attributes here so go ahead and find text size here.
And you know totally up to you.
Let's maybe see what something like 36 looks like that's a little bit bigger.
But you know we could even go bigger Let's just see for example what like 60 espie looks like.
Now that to me that looks pretty good.
Again your discretion you get to choose how that looks but looks pretty good there.
And really the last thing that we just need is the button.
OK.
So go ahead and grab our button here.
We're going to put it right below the text view.
And we want to make sure that we have a good connection here.
So let's go ahead and get back.
Need to hide all of our attributes here.
Here we go and we'll go ahead and just do our little up here that connects it automatically with the
timer above it and I think we're at a pretty good position so if you want to you can right click this
and say Center horizontally imperent that's just to make sure it stays in the center.
But that should be enough there we do want to change what the button says so we can change that to maybe
something like Go.
This is going to change throughout the course of the app depending on you know if the timer is going
or not but at least this is a good start here.
OK.
So apps looking pretty good.
Let's go ahead now work on the program back side of things.
Oh I almost forgot we need to set everything here so for example with the Sikh bar we have to give it
a proper ID so I'll say something like Taimur seek bar for the image view.
Yes.
So go ahead and just call this egg image view for this text view.
Go ahead and call this count down text view.
Excellent.
And yes go ahead and update all those references.
And then lastly for the button we'll call this something like Go button.
OK.
So we now finally got everything in place all the proper IDs are showing up here.
Now we can finally go do the programmatic stuff.
So before we do move forward I want to show we got a little bit of a lay out tiff here you can go ahead
and switch this back to portrait if you want.
And I somehow got arrived on a Nexus 10.
I think we had a Nexus 4 before.
So anyways that's how we can fix the way out of that stuff.
But let's go ahead and make it so that when we move the slider we can actually change this text for
you to show the appropriate time that we would want to go start the time around.
So a couple of things that we've got to do here.
The first of which is we've got to get access to the bar and we've got to get access to the text view.
So first let's go ahead and do CPR saying we're going to have a sick bar.
Let's just call the timer seek bar OK and this is going to be equal to fine view by ID.
We'll do our capital R ID dot and let's go back and see what we named this time or seek part that would
make sense.
And also a timer seek bar.
Excellent stuff.
We also need access to the text view.
So let's make a new text view that we are going to call Taimur text view and again we'll do fine view
by Dady our dot dot.
And let's see what we've got for the name here.
And we have countdown text view right count text view.
Excellent.
So now we have access to both these things and it looks like we'd need to import the stuff for text
view.
So so we type in actually let's just hit enter there and that'll add it to our imports.
All right so with that we need to go ahead and set some initial values for CGC bar.
So let's go ahead and get the timer seek bar first thing that we want to do is we want to set what the
max could possibly be for this and we want the max for this to be 10 minutes.
And if you know this is referring to the slider's referring to the number of seconds that we've got
going on we would want to make it so that the max would be 10 minutes 60 seconds in a minute.
That would be 600 seconds.
Here is what we want.
OK.
The other thing that we want to set with the Sikh is what the current progresses at start time.
So we're going to do set progress and let's just go ahead and do 30 seconds that's like our starting
position for the seat bar.
OK then with that whenever someone changes the CGC bar we want to be able to run some code so you know
we've done this a couple of times now you should have this no problem when you say on Seek bar change
listener again we'll do a new seek bar change listener Caig is a sees three awesome functions inside
of here so it's the progress changes the big one that we want to be working with here and the first
thing that we've kind of got to do is figure out you know if they are at 432 seconds like what does
that equate to in minutes in seconds.
Right because we don't want on our time here to just so show seconds like we want to show the minutes
and the seconds we wanted to be nice and organized there.
So in order to do that we can do a little bit of math here and to find the minutes we can create a new
event called minutes and the math that we're going to do here is we're simply going to take I which
is the number of seconds we're going to go ahead and divide that by 60.
OK.
And what that does is when it converts it into an end because you know maybe you know some number divided
by six is not going to be a whole number there's going to be a remainder thereby by saying that this
is going to be an aunt.
It's going to round it down to the next number which is going to show us the appropriate amount of minutes.
So then in order to find the seconds we can say OK enough seconds is equal to whatever it is that's
the total seconds minus this minutes time 60.
So we can say minutes times 60 just like that.
And so essentially right like if there was a hundred and 22 seconds there you know that would mean that
there would be two minutes.
And if we did two minutes time 60 that's 120 so 122 minus 120 means that there's two seconds left.
Now you could leave this like this.
Personally I like to put little parentheses around here to say I want to do this first then that.
I think because of order of operations that will happen automatically but I kind of like to put the
parentheses around.
It makes me remember OK we're doing minute's time 60 first and then we're doing this subtraction there.
OK.
The next thing that we want to do then is update the text view so we're going to go ahead and get our
timer text view.
We're going to say time or text view that said text.
And this is where we want to put our information so we want to have the minutes and then the seconds
right.
So let's go ahead and convert the minutes we're going to say integer dot to a string.
There we go.
We're going to pass in minutes.
Excellent.
So that will give us a string so let's add to the string a colon to separate the minutes and the seconds
then we're going to add onto this the second.
So again we'll say integer
integers.
There we go to string and we're going to go ahead and pass in the seconds right there.
So that will go ahead and convert everything that we need.
So let's go ahead and get this on our app looks like I'm going to have to get my device up and running
and I haven't had it started for this project.
Wall that is loading up there there is something that I want to talk about and that's that when we do
this conversion of the minutes to the seconds we're going to run into an issue and the issue is is that
for the seconds here like let's say for example you know we had 120 seconds on the countdown right so
120 divided by 60 that gives us two minutes and then you know 120 minus 120.
That means there's zero seconds.
Well when you do zero seconds and convert that to a string it's going to show like Two colon zero which
looks a little bit weird with time right like it's usually to call an 0 0 so there is a way around this
and it's by basically do an if statement to say hey you know we're working with you know zero seconds
we wanted to show double zeros.
So the way that we can fix this is by creating a new string.
For example we could call this the second string.
OK.
And with this we are going to go ahead and set this equal to do our proper integer conversion stuff.
Right so just like we've done before we're going to take this thing to string.
Go ahead and grab our seconds there.
Right.
But then this is where we want to do or if statements so we want to say if the go ahead get our parentheses
in here.
If the second string is equal to the number 0 just the singular number is zero.
This is where we'd want to you know sort of update that.
So that was two zeroes there.
So this is where we want to say OK second string we're going to go ahead and say that you are now equal
to zero zero.
So if it is the case that for example you know there's one second two seconds three seconds whatever.
This if statement never gets called in we can just go ahead and use the second string.
But if not you know we kind of have this year here to sort of protect against that so we can go ahead
and take the second string.
And rather than doing this integer conversion we can go ahead and delete that and paste it there.
Now you may be wondering do we want to do the same thing for the minutes right like do we want to show
like 0 0 for the minutes.
Well that's up to you.
I mean it's kind of a personal preference thing.
You can decide.
I think it's probably better without.
I kind of like this the single zero example.
But again up to you with how you want to work that.
So let's go ahead and see what we've got here.
Go ahead and run on this one more time should see our app pop up.
Hey here it comes.
Excellent song.
Go ahead.
Move the slider and look at that.
We get those awesome numbers.
And as you can see I think this is the earlier code where you know we were saying you know if it was
equal to zero you know go ahead and do that double thing right.
So this is what we want to prevent so that it doesn't say you know 10 colon and then a singular zero
there.
So now with this new code let's go ahead and save and then run this
right we should see improvement here.
Now on our app so let's go ahead and move that to the edge.
You can for some reason that is not working.
Let me go ahead and take a look why.
So I figured out what the issue is I forgot that was strings rather than doing the two equal signs.
We want to go ahead and actually do a dot equals when you're comparing string.
This is the better way to handle it.
So if we go ahead and make that change with our IF statement we'll go ahead and open up our app and
you'll notice.
Now when we go ahead and move this there we go we get that double nice double zero.
And again I think the singular zero looks good.
That's up to you about you know whether or not you think that's a good idea.
You can totally choose.
So with that we should probably update on the visual side here rather than doing the double zero on
this should go ahead and change it.
We have a single zero.
Just to kind of keep things all uniform.
All right let's go ahead and keep moving forward so the next thing that we want to do is we want to
actually integrate a timer into this so that we can have some counting down and we can update the timer
as things are going on.
So the first thing that we got to do is we've got to go ahead with our button so the button is going
to kind of be the place that we kick off the timer.
And so with this we have to provide some name for its on click method here.
And so we're going to go ahead and just call this something like let's say button clicked.
So we got that name there.
Let's go ahead back and up here at the top inside of our class but not inside of the uncreate function
there we are going to go ahead and create a new function function method and we're going to save public
void and we're going to call this one button click to the same name that we had before inside of here
is going to get a parameter of a view.
OK.
We'll go ahead and do our little curly brackets there and let's make sure we get the proper code implemented
we want Android view of you.
So go ahead and hit enter there and just to confirm that at least things are working.
We're going to go ahead and just do a quick log here.
So we'll say Lagat thing and we'll say something like button pressed.
Nice exclamation point.
OK.
So we'll go ahead out or a little semi-colon there.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure that our buttons working in order for that let's go ahead and get our log cat up and running.
And here we go showing up in the emulator now so go ahead and hit this button and look out.
We get the button pressed.
Nice.
Every time we click on that we get that showing up.
OK.
So that's good to know that we've got that showing up.
The next step for us is we want to go ahead and create a timer when the user hits that button.
So we're going to go ahead and create a new countdown timer.
Go ahead and hit enter on that.
And with this remember we want to go ahead and add you know how long we want it to run for.
And you know what the intervals are going to be so for now let's just go ahead and put in some big number.
That's one that's 10000 milliseconds so that'll be 10 seconds and we want this to go off like every
you know thousand milliseconds which is one second.
That's what we're looking for there or accidentally misplace this.
And in parentheses So we want to delete that.
Make sure that goes at the end here where we make a new count down timer and you know we've got our
nice curly brackets here and at the end of this we want to make sure we start it and put our semi-colon.
And then the last step for us is just to hover over here.
And then we can go ahead and implement our methods both the tick and the on finish.
So we'll go ahead and hit OK to that.
And now we can go ahead and actually write the code that's going to take in order for this all to happen.
So in regards to the on.
So every one second that goes by you know we want to know about what the current time is left and sort
of update that inside of the text view and if you think about it we already have all of that code down
here right where we take the time and we you know we turn this into minutes and then seconds that we
update this we do the special check to see for the double zero situation.
So let's go ahead and just sort of reuse this code.
We're going to make a new method here.
So outside let's go ahead and make a new method so we're going to see a public void and we want to go
ahead and call this one the update timer function.
Now we do have to go ahead and take in some sort of parameter here and so let's go ahead and take in
a function called seconds left.
OK.
And then we'll go ahead and do our curly brackets just like that.
So to start with let's remove the code from here put it inside of this new update timer function and
then call that here.
And then you know we'll sort of mix up or fix all the problems that we're going to get from that so
let's go ahead and cut that first paste it there then we're going to come down here and say update timer.
We're going to pass and I right which is the numbers of seconds that are left so this code now is fine.
There's no errors here but as you can notice we've got tons of issues left here.
So first let's take the seconds left and we're going to replace that with wherever we had seen previously.
So that's going to go in and fix those problems.
But then the timer text view that's another issue right because we had timer techs you being set up
here.
But we want to have access to it you know in other methods here so let's go ahead and delete this or
I'm going to copy this code here so that we can create the text view outside and then we'll just set
this as if it was already created in the will go to the top of the page here and say all right there's
going to be a new text view called timer.
And you'll notice I didn't bring along the final there.
That was code that Andrew to automatically added to me and when you have a final That means it can never
possibly change.
But when you have it as a property of your class you want it to be a little bit ambiguous and if you
do final you're going to get in there.
So that's why I got rid of that.
But you'll notice that gets rid of the air that we were having before.
And so now we have this really cool update timer function which here inside of her on tick method we
can go ahead and call update timer and then the only kind of math that we have to do here is we have
to take this L which is the number of milliseconds until the thing's all finished up and we've got to
divide that by a thousand so it turns into a second.
So we're going to take l and we're going to go ahead and divide that by 1000 and you'll see we get a
little bit of an air here and that's because we have a long and you know this function is looking for.
And so we have to pass this over and say hey go ahead and automatically convert this thing into an ant.
And when we do that we do get some working code here.
All right.
So before we go ahead and test this out I do want to go ahead and make sure that the finish code here
is working.
So let's go ahead and just log something here and we'll just say something like finished.
Time are all done.
OK.
And one more thing here is that before we had just put in some you know arbitrary amount of time when
in reality we actually want to go ahead use how much time as you know was a lot inside of the Sikh bar
because right now this would just do a 10 second countdown.
So rather than this we're going to go ahead and delete that.
And in order to get access to our time or seek part we're going to have to do a similar thing where
we're going to cut this code paste it up top so we can declare this as a.
So it can be accessed everywhere and will take this time or seek bar place that there.
And now we can go ahead and say OK time or seek bar get progress that's going to give us the number
of seconds that the user wanted to set.
And we just got to go ahead and multiply that by 1000 so then we're working with milliseconds.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run this.
See what it looks like in our app.
We'll go ahead and have log cat open here so we can see what's coming through for us so as we said before
we can kind of move this down just go ahead and see what it looks like when we do.
Nine seconds so look at that.
We get this cool countdown going here that's some awesome functionality.
Looking really really good.
But the one issue that we're going to have here is you'll see we got the timer all done.
But as we were going through on this timer let me go ahead and run this now.
Want to get to a shorter time you could see.
Well now that it's running we didn't see it but you could see like when there was six seconds left.
We'll see here in a second.
Right.
It doesn't look says 9:08 like would be good if it was 0 7 0 6 whatever.
Right like we would like to have that option for our tests there so we can fix it here with our IF statement
rather than just seen if this string is equal to zero.
What we can do is just say hey if there's just a single digit meaning that if it's nine or less than
we want to just automatically go in the head and add a zero on to it.
So the if statement now that we're going to check with say OK we're going to take the number of seconds
which isn't it.
And when I say if the number of seconds is less than or equal to nine so 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 we want
to place a zero in front of it.
So we're going to say the second string is now going to be equal to whatever the existing second string
was.
But just in front of that we are going to add a zero.
So go ahead and do that at our cool little plus button there.
And once that is in place let's go ahead and test our code.
Ok big moment here.
Here we go to the emulator.
So I'm going to bring this down and look at that we've got a nice timer so it's saying you know 0 3
0 6 and let's go ahead and hit go on this and we'll see log cat to see when that is finished and boom.
Look at that.
It says time are all done.
Now it's a little bit off if you've noticed this.
Let's go ahead and go back up to you know maybe something like nine seconds here.
I just want you to see once this hits zero that we don't exactly get the time or finished to show up
and we were hoping that it would.
Right so we hit zero.
And then it says time are all done.
And the reason for this happening is because with we when we get this timer I'm going to scroll to where
we've got this.
Let me get some space here.
OK.
So when we're setting the count countdown timers how long we want it to count for it right we say OK
if they want it to go for nine seconds nine seconds time a thousand that's nine thousand milliseconds.
And we're going to count down every one second.
Well the problem is is that by the time it takes to sort of run this code and come back instead of it
being 9000 milliseconds it's like eight thousand nine hundred fifty two or something like that.
And so it's just a little bit off.
So this is a tiny bit of a hack here but this is kind of the code that we need in order to make everything
work.
We're just going to add on a tenth of a second by saying hey take whatever time they wanted times a
thousand.
We're also going to add a hundred seconds there to sort of do this quick fix and make sure that everything's
all working there OK.
So let's go ahead and run our app one more time.
Can you see if this doesn't look a little bit better for us.
And once we've got this me moved down to some sort of time like six seconds cable go ahead and hit go
there.
Hard times coming down let me get Lague cat open.
I kind of missed our time in there.
Let's go ahead and try one more time.
So do like six seconds like this.
And it comes down and we hit zero and boom it says time are all done.
OK.
So we are in a pretty great spot.
Really all that's left for us is we've got to do a little bit more work with this button.
And we've also got to get that air horn in place.
We're also going to do some cool visual things.
But I mean we have the gist of a timer done so at least you know we've got that working for us.
All right so let's go ahead and write the code so that we can play the air horn noise when the timer
is all finished so rather than just doing the logging here we're going to go ahead and play a sound.
If you remember walking through this we need to create a new media player and was just go ahead and
call ours and player.
Now we're going to set this equal to a new media player and we want to do it to create.
We've got to pass this a couple of things so we need to pass a context and it can be tempting to do
this but that's going to refer to the timer that we're currently on.
So we actually do get application context and then needs to know what file it is that we're working
with.
So we're going to do our DOT RA.
Remember that's the name of our folder and then we're going to do dot air horn just like that.
So this creates the media player and it's amazing how simple Android is made this for us we just do
em player start and that is going to play our toys for us.
So let's go ahead and give this a run here the play button app opens up make sure I got a good amount
of sound here so you can see what's coming through.
So I'll bring this down slightly oh here comes the big countdown.
You're ready for this air horn.
Don't jump too much.
There it is.
OK.
So pretty cool.
All right.
We've got the sound functionality but the next thing for us is that while this timer is going so if
I go ahead and you know bring this up one is we want this button to then say stop and actually have
it stop the timer.
If that's what the user is looking for and we want to get rid of the CGC bar so that for example of
someone you know while this is counting down we don't want them to be able to move it it's going to
make all sorts of problems.
So let's go ahead and talk about how we can fix that.
So I think the first thing that we should fix is that if someone's going to hit the go button then we
should change the text of the button to say stop so that the user knows that they can go ahead and stop
that.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go to our code and downhere Excuse me up here when someone
has clicked this button there's a little bit of extra code that we want to run before we go ahead and
do all this countdown timer stuff.
So what we're going to do first is.
And there goes our horn.
Well that freaked me out.
I hit it twice so we have two horns.
That's why this code we're going to right now is going to make it so we can't have two horns go off
and we don't freak ourself out in the middle of stuff here.
But the first thing that we need to do is we need to make a boolean that you know tells us whether or
not the counter is active so we're going to go ahead and create a new boolean.
We're going to call this counter is active.
OK.
And we're just going to go ahead and set this initially equal to false.
Excellent.
And then what we're going to do here is when someone goes ahead and actually clicks the button we want
to do a few things so the first one is want to take this counter is active and set that equal to true
because we're saying OK you know someone is now starting up the timer.
We also want to go ahead and make it so that the Sikh bar can no longer be messed with so that the user
can't update that so we're going to say time or seek bar set enabled.
And we're going to set this equal to false.
So that can no longer be changed.
And then the last thing we're going to do is we're going to update the button which means then we have
to have access to the button.
So we're going to go ahead and create a new button and we'll just call this the go button and we'll
go ahead and set this up sort of create method say Go button is equal to fine view by ID if I remember
right we called it the go button.
Yep there we go.
Awesome.
Now that we have access to the skill button we can go ahead and change its text so will say Go button
that set text and we can go ahead and have that say Stop OK.
And I guess we use an exclamation point on the last one maybe we should do it here.
Both are very exciting things to make the timer go and stop.
All right.
So we've got all of that there.
Let's go ahead and just test it out see what it looks like.
And wait for our emulator here.
Pops up let me bring it down.
So I hit go here.
And now you can see it stop the you know seek bar here is disabled.
Awesome stuff.
But the issue is we can't stop anything.
In fact by just hitting a bunch of times and nine seconds we're going to get a jillion horns I'm going
to turn this down for a second because computers freaking out right now.
So that's kind of the next big thing for us to fix here.
So make it so that we can actually stop the countdown if that's going to be happening.
So the first thing that we want to do here is we want to do an if statement that says well checks whether
or not the counter is active.
So we're going to see if counter is active and we want to go ahead and say you know if this is true
we want to do something for God let's put our parentheses around that.
So if it is active This is where we you know would want to stop it and do all that stuff.
But the ELSE side of this is all the code that we already have for this.
I'm just going to go ahead and wrap that all in curly brackets nice Android studio tabbed everything
over for us.
That was great.
And now we need to sort of write all of the things that should be happening if someone wants to stop
the timer.
So the first thing that we want to do because someone's trying to stop this is we should probably update
our text view.
So let's take our time or text view and say that set text.
And let's just go ahead and get this back to the 0 30 position.
OK.
Along with that we should actually update the Sikh bar to get to that position so we're going to say
set progress and we'll go ahead and update that to be 30.
Excellent.
OK so we've kind of done the CGC bar in the text you I guess we should re-enable the seek bar so that
someone can actually work with that so we're going to say our timer seek bar that set enabled.
And now we want to go ahead and change that to be true.
Excellent.
The next thing that we do is we want to stop the counter that we have here.
So in order to do that we have to have access to this we're going to go ahead and cut this pace up above
and now take our countdown timer and say countdown timer is equal to this so then we can say all right
count down timer dot and then we're going to do cancel.
This will stop it from continuing any further.
We also want to update the button so that changes back to go.
So we'll go to our literally go to our go button and we're going to say set text and we're going to
change that to say go.
Exclamation point.
That looks good.
And with all of this they're really the last thing that we just need to do is we need to say OK.
Counter is active.
We want to go ahead and switch this now to actually be false so that we can sort of switch back and
forth between the two of them.
So hopefully we've got everything there.
Let's go ahead and test this out make sure that that's working for I mean there's a lot of stuff that
goes on for stopping a timer here but hopefully we got it all.
So let's go ahead and go down to a smaller time so here's 11 seconds.
Everything was disabled and I can go ahead and say stop.
And just like that this is now re-enabled you know the go buttons there again.
And I can actually you know go ahead and start this thing one more time.
Let's make sure that the horn is still going off.
I didn't hear it earlier.
I know I had the volume down but I successfully stopped it.
There we go we got the proper sound so really the last thing that we just got to fix is when the timer
runs out.
It's a little bit awkward now for the user to say oh OK now how do I start a new timers it's like stop
this one and then I'm back at 30.
And like you know like would be nice if we just sort of automatically reset it for the user once the
timer counted down.
So essentially what we want to do is we want to run all this code whenever the timer runs out.
So what we can do is just make yet again a another method here so public void and we'll just call this
reset timer.
OK.
And this method will just go ahead and copy all of this or cut rather and then will just go ahead and
simply call timer excuse me reset timer is the one that we want and we can call the same reset timer
whenever our timer actually finishes.
So you know we go ahead and we play the sound and then we also reset the timer.
So let's run this.
Make sure it's exactly what we were hoping for.
And here it comes let's go down to a smaller time so we can see that.
Here comes the egg done three to one.
We'll get that resets the timer for us you know we're back.
The user can move this around if they want to.
Excellent stuff.
So congrats on creating this egg timer app.
You know we kind of pulled an even more concepts that we've previous learned bunched them all together.
We're just going to keep doing that in this course so we're not completely done with timers yet you'll
see it come along here in just a second but still got more info for you so let's keep moving forward.