So like I said this is going to be a little bit tougher we're going to learn how to make the coins move
across the screen and I think technically you have the chops to get this done but you'll you'll notice
women work with game programming there's kind of some weird tips and tricks that we'll use along the
way.
So let's go ahead and stop this.
So we don't have that running the whole time that we're adding this new code here and we need to add
a lot of the top.
So basically what we're going to be doing is we're going to be creating a bunch of coin objects that
are going to be on the screen and we're going to have an array basically of these and they're just going
to show up do their thing.
And so what we want to do is that we're going to make an array list and we want this to be of integers.
I know this sounds a little bit crazy but follow me on this.
So we're going to make an array of Integer objects and we're going to set this equal to coin X with
an ass.
So this is all the coin X expositions so to speak to a new array l'Est nothing fancy there.
And then we're going to do the same thing for the y position.
So the coin Y so we can now track in two or raise the x's in the why's of these coins.
Next we need to make a texture for our coins.
We're going to go ahead and say text your coin.
Just simple as that we'll just stop right there.
And then the next thing that we need to make is something called a coin counts.
This is just going to be an integer and we'll call it coin count.
And this is going to help us to make sure that we have the proper spacing in between the coins.
So with all of this in place let's go ahead and move now to our create method where we're going to get
things set up.
So the first thing that we need to do is we need to set up the coin.
So we're going to say coin is equal to a new texture.
Simple enough right.
Needs to have the name of the image which I believe is just coin PMG.
Let's check that coin P G.
We are in a good spot.
So we'll go ahead and do our semi-colon there.
But other than that that's really all we had to get up and running for the coins.
But you'll notice now what we're going to have to do so because we're going to want to have multiple
coins going across the screen.
We're going to want to make a method to support that.
So we're going to make a new method here.
Public void make coin.
I mean this sounds like a business like model we're going to make Kornya you know.
But with this there's a couple of things that we want to do here.
So now the first one is we want to determine what the height of this coin is going to be because the
coins are going to float across the screen.
Screen left to right.
That's not an issue.
But you know we don't want coins always come in at the same spot like we want one down here than up
here and then in the middle and you know maybe back down and down then up and you know we want that
to all be random.
So in order for that to work we're going to make a new float that we are going to call the height.
When you say this height is equal to and we're now going to have to use some randomness so let's go
ahead and make a new random object and say are random random and inside of our create we'll set it up.
So I should do my complete there.
So random is equal to in New random.
Excellent.
So there's this awesome function with random where we can say random dot next float.
And this gives us a number between 0 and 1 is going to be some sort of decimal point right.
So we can multiply this times the height of the screen which we do that do that geed X dot graphics
dot get height.
And this allows us then to go some position if it's time zero it's going to go to the bottom of the
screen if it's you know point five will go to the middle screen if this is one that will go to the top
of the screen.
So it kind of chooses where the coin is going to go on the screen.
So now that we have that height Well then we can go ahead and say OK Mike coin wise I know where to
place you.
I'm gonna say coin wise.
Dot ad and I'm going to add a higher object and I've got to make sure that I convert it into an object
because it is a float.
So go ahead and do that conversion there.
Now for the coin X the coin X is going to be the same every single time.
So in this situation you just want to make sure it appears you know off of the screen.
So we simply going to say hey give the whole width of the screen so we're going to get access graphics
Doug get with that's all we need as far as the width.
So you're probably still a little bit lost.
Like OK we've decided a random y position for our coin and we've decided an exposition that is going
to be right off the screen.
But then how do we get all these coins to show up and that's where we're going to start getting our
hands dirty here.
So the first thing is we're going to use this in that we created coin count to make it so that only
ever you like 100 loops.
We have a coin show up.
So let's go ahead and have our player let's do the coins before our player.
So that way if he if there's a choice whether we call draw the coin or him first we should do the coin
then him so he peers appears above it.
So we're going to say if and when this statement when you say coin count is less than 100 you've seen
this before.
Down here right we're kind of doing the same sort of style a thing we're going to say OK coin count.
You should go ahead and up yourself.
So plus plus.
But if that's not the situation then I want you to say coin count should be zero equal to zero.
That is and that you should also make a coin.
So that's going to go ahead and add yet another coin.
So this you know every time we run through 100 times and say put another coin on the screen and then
it runs another have another hundred times Boop put another coin on the screen.
So after we've got that in place the next thing for us is we have to draw these coins.
So we're going to do a little for a loop because we don't know how many coins it is that we're going
to have.
So we'll do a little for loop here or we're going to say four.
And what we want to check inside of here is we're just going to do a classic I is equal to zero.
And we want to know and I is less than the coin and you can choose.
Taxes are wise size ok whatever you want.
And then I plus plus.
So we'll go ahead and do this so that now we can go ahead and do some drawing.
So first let's go ahead and draw on the coin we're going to say batch dot draw.
And we want to draw the coin texture that we already have.
And we know where the X and Y is supposed to be.
So we just have to simply say here coin X get at the position and same thing.
Coin wise get at the high position.
Simple as that.
OK.
So that's going to go ahead and draw it on the screen.
And so with this let's go ahead and just run this and see what happens.
OK.
So we're going to go ahead and run this let's check and see what it looks like on a device.
All right.
So we'll go ahead and do this.
The app opens up and you'll notice what the heck there there's no coins like there's no way for this
thing to suddenly suddenly move.
And the reason for this is we never anywhere in our code update the coin acts to say you know we want
it to move slowly to the left so that's why we're going to do a new line down below here where we're
going to say coin X's dot set in this situation and we want to update where we currently are at.
So we're going to say at position II and then we want to set it up to whatever it currently is just
minus 4.
So we're going to tap into the same array list and say Corozal extra get that position.
But then minus four.
So this will make it so that slowly over time we've got some coins moving on the screen moment of truth
here.
Let's go see what this looks like.
All right.
I mean later here we go.
There's our dude and there's a coin.
Look at that.
They are just flowing across the screen.
That's that's a side of beauty right there.
We just got these things going in all sorts of different directions.
OK.
So so far so good this is looking great.
The next thing that we want to add is we want to add bombs that show up every so often so I'm going
to present this as a challenge to you I want you to make it so that not every 100 counts more than that
that we have a bunch of bombs showing up on the screen will NOT a bunch only a couple but you are in
charge of that.
So go ahead and do that now.
All right.
So hopefully that worked out for you.
It's a lot of just copy and paste of what we did before.
So for example these four lines of code we got to do the same thing for our bombs.
So we're going to call this bomb x' we're to this bomb wise.
We're going to make a bomb texture and we're going to have a bomb count.
We're going to have to set up our bomb texture here so to say bomb is equal to a new texture where the
image is just bombed up TNG.
And then we're going to have to make our own make bomb function here.
Really.
I'm telling you it's a lot of the same copy paste so same thing where we just want to get a random position
but rather than adding to the coin wise we want to add to bomb wise and bomb exits.
OK.
So once we have those in place we're going to do basically the same two things that we saw here so maybe
let's just mark out here the comment.
This is for coins.
And we're now going to do this for bombs so we'll just copy and paste here.
I actually think we should have the coin show above the bomb so it makes it that much sneakier.
Right so that if a coin and a bomb appear at the same position you know sort of hard to see that so
I'm going to put that at top.
So we're now say all right if bomb count is less then maybe 250.
I will kind of be in between the coin so I guess never We'll have one on top of each other but we could
change that.
Go ahead.
Instead of make coin we want to make bomb.
Also we have to change these to be bomb count.
And this is well to be bomb count.
Good good good then for our for loop.
We want this to be for bomb x' then we're going to say go ahead and drop a bomb go get the bomb x' go
get the bomb.
Wise and then go ahead and update here on the bomb axes so that it slowly moving across the screen there.
OK.
So go ahead and run this and something this could be kind of fun maybe we'll make the bombs move faster
so we'll put those at 8 for example so that the coins are moving at one speed but also and these bombs
become a little bit more dangerous right because we can't you know they're coming quicker and maybe
they'll just sort of appear out of nowhere.
So here's our guy.
We got some coins.
Well they get that bomb out of nowhere or go in there and also.
Well you know I think that's pretty cool that that speed variable in there now might be too quick because
I think if you're in one position and you see a bomb coming like would you have enough time to respond.
I want to see if one comes my way.
No I haven't gotten any one in my space yet.
Come on.
You know you kind of get the point.
We could have a situation there that could be tough.
Now one last thing I want to talk about before we finish out here is you know right now our dude was
just running into coin after coin bomb after bomb and there was no consequences the score wasn't being
updated or anything.
And in order to do that to the side if our dude is running into a coin or a bomb we have to write some
code to dis Terman if there were some collision.
And in order to do that we have to add an extra little bit of physics into our app.
So what we're going to do is we're both the coins and the bombs that we're going to make a new array
list.
So up here with the coins first we're going to say array list.
And this time we're going to make it of type rectangles you haven't seen rectangles yet but these allow
us to add a shape to our objects.
So when you say rectangle and we're going to call this coin rectangles just like that and we're going
to say this is equal to a new array list.
All right.
Nothing new there.
But then what we're going to do as we move down here and we are creating our various coins.
We are going to want to draw essentially this physics Corning rectangle around the coin.
So after we do the proper class for bombs let's do this for coins.
So after we do the proper setting a little bit off to the left we're going to say coin rectangles and
we're going to say Dot to me here for and we're going to say BOM rectangles dot and we're going to add
a rectangle here and we're going to say new rectangle All right.
And we're going to set this up say bomb taxes go ahead and grab those.
And we want to do that get to figure out the position that we're in there.
OK.
So with the rectangle you have to say sort of the x and y of those.
So we're going to put in that first then we're going to do when I'm mixing this up with bombs and coin
so let's go ahead and do coin there.
Know I Do The Same thing with coin wise.
I'd get at a particular location.
OK.
So once we have those things in place we also just want to say how big it should be.
So this is where we're simply just going to say coin.
Get with.
And we're also just going to go ahead and say coin not yet.
Right now if your programming sense sort of went on the back of your neck and take a little bit you're
just like whoa whoa whoa.
Every time we go through this function that's already looping a million times and then we're going in
the for loop from there we're adding a bunch of things to the surveillance like that sounds really bad.
Yes it is.
But before we go into this release we are going to clear out everything inside of the coin rectangle
so going to say coin rectangles.
Clear.
And that way it is emptied out every time.
And we're going to do the same thing for bumps which I kept so intently doing here so I'm going to copy
this.
Same thing for Bom So let's go ahead and call this bomb rectangles now as we're going through here we
want to make sure we do a clear write up at the top but make sure that is now four bombs and then we
also want to do this last line of code where we are adding these rectangles.
So let's update this to be four bomb rectangles and we have bomb axes bomb wise and then we'll just
go ahead and get the bombs with the bombs.
Right.
All right.
So if we went and ran or app right now you wouldn't see anything different but we are going to have
an awesome situation down below where we can actually check and see if there was some sort of collision
and if there was a collision we're going to want to do something about it.
So first let's go ahead and write some code to see if our dude collides with a coin.
So for this we're going to do this after everything is drawn.
And I guess before we do this we have to make a geometric shape for our little dude so we're also going
to create something.
Well let's go up to the top here.
We are going to call this a rectangle.
We are going to call it man rectangle.
I know a little bit ridiculous with our names here.
Maybe man wasn't the best choice.
I don't know.
Seems fine to me.
But here inside of our create you're going to say man.
Rectangle is equal to a new rectangle.
Excellent.
And just go ahead and get that set up.
Now with that then when we go down we are going to draw out our guy.
Here it is.
We're going to set up the man rectangle So we're going to say man rectangle dot set and this is where
we want to figure out where the man is in his current position.
So we're just going to go ahead and get to the man exposition which we can get.
Oh well we know the man position his ex never changes.
In fact the best way to do that is just go ahead and grab this point decode right here.
Well go ahead and copy that right there.
But I was going to say the easy thing for us is we do know what his particular y position is going to
be.
So this is where we're just going to say Man why position is and then after we've done that we want
to specify what his height and width is going to be so this we can simply just say man with excuse me
get with an I'm not sure oh we have to provide something inside of there around a man's state.
I forgot that we had a man or a so to say get with an also.
Man the man's state to get height.
So with that information in place we now can go ahead and do this.
And I know we've done a whole lot of code here to get this stuff set up and I didn't want to do a set
here.
In fact when we create our new rectangle we should be doing this down below or in say an rectangle is
equal to a new rectangle.
And where we pass forward all that information.
So now that we have that in place let's just do an if statement to check and see if the man's colliding
with the coin.
So for to do that we have to go through all the coins so we're going to do a for loop to get through
all of our coins.
And so we'll just do our classic ant is equal to zero.
So long as it is less then and we want this to be the number of coin rectangles thought size
and we'll just go ahead and say I A-plus plus they don't get a semi-colon there.
Now with that in place we're going to do a really interesting if statement and we're just going to say
if we're going to check out here something called inters sector in terms sector go ahead and open that
up into sector dot overlaps this basically checks if two things are on top of each other.
So when I say overlaps are we going to pass in first the man rectangle and then we're also going to
pass the particular coin that we're looking at.
So we're going to say coin rectangles get us ever at position.
So this is going to compare the two things and see hey do either of these things overlap here.
So I figured out what the air here it's a nasty little one if we go up to the very top to our imports
here expand this out the rectangle that I imported was from Java ATWT which is not the rectangle that
we want.
So if we do that and now we try and enter in our rectangle we want to do the rectangle from GDX so make
sure that you have that and then that's going to get rid of the situation that we had down below.
So let's go ahead and log some information here.
It's a little bit different.
We're going to say GDX dot app dot log.
And this is going to allow us to say something like.
CONAN And we'll say college on exclamation point.
OK.
So let's go ahead and test this with our app.
We're going to have to have log cat running up beside us so that we can you know see if we're getting
the proper message when we run into those coins I'll give some space so we can see what's at the bottom
sort of float around.
Oh there's a coin here you go down and look at that said collision.
And if we go we can hit those coins to get collisions there come back down like we can collide with
that coin.
All sorts of cool stuff there.
All right.
So go ahead and stop that.
Now the next thing that we want to do with this like beautiful is just detect the bomb collisions.
So you know still lots of adject logic to add here but let's just go ahead at least get this you know
detecting if we're colliding with bombs which is probably something we should know about.
So go ahead and say bomb rectangles.
We'll see if man rectangle overlaps with bomb rectangles.
And in that case we're going to say bomb.
So let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure it works and then we'll move on to finishing the sap up.
We're getting really really close here.
But just a little bit more to go.
So sorry guys floating around if we get the coins let's open a blog cat we've got that we've got coins.
But let me hit that bottom.
Whoa.
Look at that.
You see the bomb collision Let's see if I can catch another one.
I just missed it.
Oh that's a direct hit.
Look at that.
OK.
So in the next one we'll go ahead and put all the polish on this app and then we'll be ready to rock
and roll.