All right.
So we're going to use the animation skills you've just learned and a lot of the other skills you learned
in the previous section to make a game that I call connect 3.
It has a lot to do with the game called tic tac toe.
But it's kind of mixed with Connect 4.
Let's see how it works when you tap on one of the blank areas in this grid.
A counter falls down from the top and it alternates between red and yellow.
And the aim of the game is to get three in a way.
So basically the same as tic tac toe.
But you have these counters that drop in from above.
Now the game is yellow versus red.
So hopefully you get the idea.
We can play as many times as we like.
And then when we've got three in a row that is either vertically horizontally or diagonally.
The phone will tell us who has one and give us the option to play again.
So there's not much that you haven't done before but it's the complexity of it and putting it all together
that will be the challenge.
There's a link to download the image resources for the background grid and the counters in the next
lecture.
So go and grab those or you can of course make or download your own if you prefer.
I'm going to give you a little hint to use the grid layout to lay out your counters and you might want
to investigate something called tags to keep track of which slots have been filled and whether they've
been filled with a yellow or red counter.
That's all I'm going to say for now of course if you have any problems just watch me in this video but
otherwise pause and give it a shot.
Best of luck.
All right.
Well I heard that when wealthy as I said that was a big boom to make single handedly say if you did
manage it congratulations.
If not.
Not to worry.
Let's see.
Could have done it.
So as usual we'll start with a new project I'll call it connect three.
Game
usual options.
We just need the one empty activity and then we'll start by bringing in our images.
So here we've got Guillot red and bored so I'm going to copy them.
You can just direct them in a few days and then we'll put them in the folder.
Little bit of patience is required.
Let's try that again.
There you go.
Great.
Now.
OK so let's start with our lay out
our board image that I'm using is a square and it's divided into nine sections three by three.
So we can use a grid to lay out
to do this for us.
I'll just bring it in.
There we go.
So now we've got great layout but I'll just add constraints for
and an ID.
Am I going to need to set the number of rows and columns.
So we want both of those to be three two or three ways.
And three columns
excellent.
Couple of other settings we can change while we're here.
We wanted to be a square.
So we've got the width as 3 6 8.
I'm going to set the height to be 3 6 8 as well and just make sure that's deep.
And I'm going to set the background image to be how bored.
There we go.
So we've now got a grid layout without Nice borders the background so we can start putting our counters
in place.
So let's add an image.
And you can see how great layout appears here.
I want this one to be top left so I'll just put it up there and we'll make them all right for the moment.
We'll have to change them programmatically anyway.
Excellent.
So those are top left.
Add another one.
I'm just going to copy and paste.
So I put that in there.
You can see it appears next to it.
And we're starting to see the great format now appearing.
Add a third and we get three in a row.
The fourth appears on the next try and then five
six seven eight nine.
Now we do have a few problems there.
As you can see.
So let's fix those.
Firstly I'm going to set the width and height
so that it fits nicely in the box.
So rather than wrapping content.
Let's try something like 100 deep.
That's not too bad actually I think with the right margins.
Well speaking of which let's set those although I'll just set the height to match as well.
So now we've got a width and height of hundred rupees.
And then the margin will probably have to set specific margins for each one but let's get this one position
nicely first.
We'll start off with 10.
And that looks pretty good to me.
And if you wanted to be super accurate you could do maybe a little bit better than that but that's centered
as we need to be filled out.
So let's redo our copy and pasting so that we get
cancers that appear in the right place OK say vertically That one looks good but I think we need to
see change the left margin
to maybe 15 teepees.
Let's have a look a touch more I think
is nice to get things as centered as possible.
Great.
So that one's looking good.
Let's update the IDs as we go.
So we'll start off with you one and then two three etc..
Paste in another one.
I think that's good although it looks a little bit off to the right to me.
Let's experiment a little bit
that all day
and now I'm going to be bold and copy all three of these in one go because I'm reasonably confident
that they will display nicely.
I think they definitely get horizontally vertically.
I could do with bringing them down a little bit.
So let's at starting with this one android
lay out in top
and let's try that on I think that looks good can see the advantage of doing it using Exham out here.
It's a lot quicker than it would be selecting them all and manually changing everything on the design
view.
OK.
All my staff copy those three and the last three again need to be moved down a little let's try 16
16 16.
Great.
And then seven eighths
and nine.
OK it looks good in the preview here but I think it's now time to
run out.
And just make sure that everything is displayed on the device itself or at least in the emulator as
we want it to be.
All right so we're looking good.
But of course we don't actually want the board to look like this initially wanted to be empty and we
want to drop the counter then when the use taps on one of these spaces.
So let's work with this particular counter and we'll start by just getting rid of the source completely
so the image view is still there but it doesn't have an image displayed on it.
What we want is when the user taps on this image for a counter to drop in from the top and a pair or
settle there at the bottom.
OK.
So to do that we're going to need to add an on click method for this image V.
Done that before.
So I'll call this drop in.
And then let's go and write the code for our method.
So we're used to this public void doesn't return anything coolit droppin and it's going to be called
by a few which will be the image view that was tapped on now for the first time we do actually want
to access this variable this time because we need to know which one was tapped or as we're going to
be calling the drop in method from all of these.
So what will they do is create a variable of type image V with a name counter.
And this is going to be equal to the image view that was tapped on the View but view is a view of course.
So we need to cast that to an image view just as we do with fine view by id and then we want to drop
the county in which is going to involve a few different steps.
So first of all I want to translate it outside of the screen or above the top of the screen so that
it can drop in say let's take a counter and we could animate this but as we did in the previous video
with set X I'm going to set translation X to minus 1000 should take it off the top of the screen maybe
we'll make that fifteen hundred just to be sure.
And then I'm going to set the image for it.
Now we did this way back in Section 1.
You may remember we take our imagery and we set the image resorts.
And in this case I'll use yellow just to make it look a bit different.
So resources Daut drawable and yellow.
So we've moved it off the screen.
We've set the image view image to the yellow counter image and now we're going to drop it back down
again.
So it will use counter to animate and we want to translate y by a thousand or fifteen hundred sorry
to bring it back down and we'll do this pretty quickly.
We'll see how it looks.
We might need to adjust it but I'll go for a third of a second.
See how that works.
All right so now when we run the app we should have a blank space bottom middle and when that blank
space is tapped on the yellow counter should appear from above and just before I run that you may have
noticed a small mistake there.
I want to set the translation.
Why.
Because I want it to appear above the screen not to the left of the screen.
All right.
Let's give that a gay.
So now I tap on the invisible counter and there it is.
That looks great.
Just a quick thought.
We could even do a bit of a rotation so it spins as it comes in.
That might be quite nice.
Let's have a quick look.
Just had a little bit of flab barely noticeable but I think I'll keep that in.
All right.
So let's now add that to the rest of our counters.
So first off we want to get rid of all the drawable reds.
What we can do then is use find to replace to do that all in one go.
So I want to replace what I've selected there and I'll replace it with the setting the own click method
to drop in because that's another change I want to make.
So I'm not holding them both in one step.
There we go.
So they've all got the on click method applied and they've all had their images removed.
So let's have a quick look.
We should not find that we can tap on all of those images and they will drop in from above.
Here we go.
William that is looking great.
OK.
A reasonable amount more to do next of course.
We don't want them to be yellow every time we want them to alternate in color so that the players can
take turns.
So let's make that happen.
I'm going to create a simple integer called active player which is going to be 0 for yellow and 1 for
red.
Now you could use a boolean here.
True or false.
And that would work fine but the integer has the advantage that if you want to extend the game at some
point to more than two players then that's relatively easy to do.
So I'm going to enable that extensibility by using integers but I'm just going to put a quick note here.
To make clear that 0 is yellow and one is red because there's no way that someone reading my code would
know that without trying it out.
All right.
And then when we drop the counter in we just need to check to see what the active player is.
So if the active player is 0 then we want to bring in a yellow counter.
And also we want to set the active player to 1.
So the red will go next
Otherwise the opposite is true.
And we want to set the county image to read and set the active player back to zero.
All right let's have a look.
We should now get
yellow and red counters alternating yellow or red yellow red yellow red.
Excellent.
OK.
So actually the game is now playable as it is but it's not very satisfying when you get three in a row
for the game not to point out that you've won.
So this is the tricky bit.
Really we need a way of keeping track of which color each image slot is and detect whether someone has
got three in a row or not.
So first of them we need a way of keeping track of what color each count is.
And to do that we'll need to have a way of referring to each of these ISIS.
And as always there are several ways to do that but one I'd like to introduce you to.
And I think it's a good solution.
Here is the tag we can add a tag to any view.
It's in the attributes and it can be anything you like.
But in this case we're just going to have a simple numbering system so it will start at zero.
And then one two three four five six seven eight you could start a 1 but I think I prefer starting at
zero.
In this case.
So you can see here we've just got the tag set.
Then
so it's a little bit laborious.
Let's just go through and set the tag for each one.
As I say there are other ways of establishing which image has been tapped but the tag is very flexible
and useful.
So with seeing how it works
you need that.
And number seven last of all right.
Excellent.
So how do we get the tag then we can do it simply by looking at counter and then get tagged simple.
So just to make sure that's working.
Let's do a quick log.
We grab the tag and then we'll just convert it to a string
so that we can log it.
So now we should see the tag in the logs
and there it is that 0 8 7 et cetera.
Excellent.
So now we've got the tags we need a way of keeping track of what you might call the game state that
is which of these are empty.
Which of them are yellow and which are red.
So I'm going to use an array for this and it's going to be an array of integers.
I'm going to call it game state.
And initially all of the spaces are of course empty.
So if 0 represents yellow and 1 represents red Let's use a two to represent empty.
So initially our game state is just going to be nine twos that's 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
There we go.
So let's have that to how Codex.
And then when the play drops in a new counter we just need to update the game state appropriately that
we can keep track of each spects.
So let's first create an integer value for our tapped counter we're going to get this from the tag.
So I again will use counter to get tag dot to string.
But this time we need it to be an integer.
So we'll use integer to pass it that we go.
And then we just update that with the value of active player.
If it's 0 it'll become zero.
That is yellow and one it will become one that is red.
So we'll set game state tapped counter to be equal to
active player.
Brilliant.
So now we've got an array to track our game state really our final significant step is to establish
whether a player has three in a way say along the top down the side and there aren't too many possibilities.
It's only the top or middle or bottom right or left column middle column right column or the two diagonals.
Those are the only ways that you can win by getting three of those.
So the way I'm going to encode this is to create an array of winning positions.
So this is going to be an array of arrays.
I'll call it winning positions.
Hopefully you'll see how it works fairly quickly.
So the top winning position is 0 1 and 2.
Those were the numbers or the tags that we gave to those positions.
So the first winning position is going to be 0 1 and 2.
The second position is going to be the middle way.
So is that 0 1 2 3 4 5 3 4 and 5
is our next winning position.
And then the bottom right is going to be 6 7 and 8
if you are following along you might want to pause the video and see if you can work out what the rest
of the winning positions are.
But I'll just carry on.
So we'll do the vertical ones now.
So this is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 0 3 6 is a winning position.
As is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 1 4 7 fact you might notice that that's the same as the previous one we just added
1 to each of them to move them to the right.
So we know the last one must be the 5 and 8.
So those are the vertical winning positions of the last two are just the diagonals.
So that 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
0 4 and 8 and finally this diagonal is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 2 4 6.
All right.
And then when we brought in the counter we now want to check against winning positions.
So its going to be really really complicated.
But stay with me.
We are going to need to loop through all of the winning positions and check to see if they've all got
the same value.
And in the game state that is and that they're not equal to 2 because if they're all empty that doesn't
mean that anyone's won.
So we're looking for where each of the winning positions is either a 1 or 0 3 and that they're all the
same.
You might want to take a moment to convince yourself of that when you have carry them.
So we'll do a loop.
So we're looping three winning positions and each of the values of winning position is an array of integers
which I'll call winning position.
And the thing we want to leap three is winning positions.
If you remember that from Section 3 and then for each winning position we want to check to see if game
States.
And then we want a winning position.
Zero there.
So that's the first value in winning position and we want to see if the value of that of the game state
of that position is equal to the value of the next part of the winning position say we want to see if
that's equal to the game state.
Of winning position one and we want game States winning position one
to be equal to a game States winning position to.
So if the first one is equal to the second one and the second one is equal to the third one then the
first one must be equal to the third one.
So we don't need to check that separately but we do need to make sure that none of them are equal to
2 because we want all of them to be either zeros or ones I either yellows or rates.
So let's just check.
Could be any one of them that's for a winning position.
Zero.
And make sure is not two.
We don't need to check the other ones because we know that if these two conditions are true than that
all the same.
So if one of them is not to and the other ones won't be to either.
So if these conditions are all met
then the main thing is someone has won.
So let's do a quick test.
For now we'll literally just say
someone has won because I've written quite a lot of them before we correct this to make it a useful
message.
Just make sure that it is working at all.
I haven't made a mistake somewhere in that.
So let's let yellow's win down the side.
Someone has won.
Fantastic.
Great.
So it seems to be detecting that nicely.
So let's do a quick check to work out who it is that's one so we can get that from the active player.
Although we do have to be quite careful here because notice we've already changed the active player
ready for the next guy.
So it's actually the opposite way round than how you'd expect.
So the active player is one then the winner is yellow.
So let's create a string called Winner a which is initially empty.
And here will set when it equals yellow.
Otherwise when it is red
have them we can just update this
to say when.
And then they've won.
All right let's just check that.
Make sure that is detecting the when it correctly and we'll do it a new one this time as well.
Agnelli excellent.
So yellow has one fantastic So we've created quite a complex set up there.
But it's a neat way of detecting the game state and working out who has one.
Now really could stop there but it's a little inelegant.
There are a few issues going on here and I'll show you a couple of them.
One is if we tap on space that already has a counter in it will be replaced by another counter which
is not in the rules you're not allowed to do that.
And another is we really shouldn't be allowed to continue to play after somebody has won the game.
So let's stop both of those things from happening.
We'll do them in order.
So first off before we do any of this we need to check to make sure that the counter this pin tapped
on doesn't already have a counter in it.
So let's get rid of that lock first of all
and let's add a check to see if game state of the tapped counter or space is equal to two.
And if that's the case then the space is empty.
So we can do all of this but if not then we essentially want to make that counter inactive.
We don't want it to do anything.
So we should now be able to play the game as usual but if we tap on a counter that is already that nothing
will happen.
So let's have a look.
If I tap on your light every time nothing new happens but I can still had
new counters.
No just check yep we can correctly detect a Radwin as well.
Great.
Now to Stop It.
Once somebody has one so we'll have
a boolean
I'll call it game active which is initially true
and when someone has one will say game active
to be false and will add a check up here.
Not only does the game state for the top count I have to be two but the game has to be active as well.
All right let's have a look.
The game should now finish and ceased to be interactive.
When
somebody wins
Hargeisa a yellow has won and you say I can't interact with it at all.
Fantastic.
So we're nearly there.
Just one more thing with the quality of this game people are going to want to play it again and again.
So they don't want to have to close the app down and open it again to start a new game.
So let's add the feature to give people the option.
To start a new game.
And I'm just going to put the option at the top here.
So well have just a small text.
The
which
will align to the top of the app and to and actually I think this is where oh give the winner rather
than a toast so that they can see it
permanently.
So we call it when a text fee and I actually mean it's
right up to the top that making it a little bit bigger say 20.
And then bring in about 20.
Not a lot of very but should just about be able to squeeze them in.
There we go.
And the button
will be sent to and aligned to the text view.
Here we go and I'll call this play again button
OK.
Say just while that's running and we can check that it all looks OK.
I'll add an on click method to the button which will be play again.
That's how I look.
Yep that looks good.
Of course we don't want it to display initially.
So let's set the visibility
of each of those two
invisible
Exham and then we want to bring them in when the winner is detected.
So let's find them using their IDs so we've first hour play again button
we find VBI I.D. I.D. don't play again button.
And similarly the next few
is when I text you.
This is going to be a text for you.
Find if you buy ID card or ID dot when a text fee.
First off we want to set the text of your text so we'll take the winner takes view and set the text
and we want to set it to the text that we put in the text before let's get rid of our taste.
We don't need any more.
And then we want to set the visibility of both to visible.
So play again button and we haven't done this before but you might be able to guess set visibility
to visible and it gives you the view class which is necessary for that.
In the predictor.
And similarly for when a text view
view dot visible.
All right.
So let's give that a try.
We should now find that when we win instead of the toast we'll see this play again button and the when
a text view will tell us who has won.
OK it's OK for Tiger to win.
Excellent.
There we go.
So yellow has one and then button the button really should say play a game
great.
So all that's left is to
write our play again method to set everything up so that the game can be played over and over again.
So as usual public void won't return anything.
Play a game called by a view which will be the button.
So let's think what things do we need to do.
First of all we need to make these invisible again
so all do a little bit of copying and pasting that just to save you watching me typing all that again.
So we find them by their IDs at this time.
We're going to set the visibility to invisible so that will make the messages message and the button
does appear.
We also want to set all of these image views back to empty again.
Now that's something we haven't done before.
So let's see if we can find a solution on Google.
We essentially want to loop through all of the image views which are all the items inside the grid view
and remove the image source.
So let's see if we can find something that I would search for something like Android loop.
There we go.
Think about Android loop through all objects in.
Lay out something like that hope that first one that even includes the great option for us.
Sounds very promising.
Let's have a look.
So it's a leap through the children essentially in the great Wii yet.
It's perfect for what we want.
Copy that over.
We will of course need to get a variable to link to the great layout.
We've already given it an idea of great lay out so we can use find view by ID
in the usual way resources said Id talk create layout then we can just replace it with grid layout and
similarly that
fantastic.
Just say that in this code they're referring to text views.
We want to work with Image views.
And just said that we're reasonably clear on what they are.
I'll call them Countess
and we want to cast that as an image.
It is this is a different method to the one up here so I can use the variable counter again and it won't
conflict because the scope of the variable is just inside the method it doesn't exist outside that method.
Right now we need to take our image view and remove the source from it which is another thing we haven't
done.
So let's take a look.
Android job that remove image view source remove the image from an image that looks pretty perfect.
Look at MTV and then set image drawable to null makes a lot of sense.
Let's give it a go.
So counter set image drawable to know great is that everything you buy should look good.
Now because we've reset all of these and we've removed that part our game state variables won't be correct.
So we'll just need to change most of these back to their defaults.
Dairymen we won't need to change his winning positions because that's fixed.
That doesn't change anyway so we want to change the game state back to a bunch of twos an empty board.
The active player is yellow again and game active is once again true.
All right.
Fingers crossed we did change a lot of things that had quite a lot of code so it could be a mistake.
But let's give it a shot and hope that everything works as desired.
OK.
So first of all let's get a read.
When Try out this diagonal excellence I read one play again which looks pretty promising
but nothing happens.
That's because see what I've done here I've actually created these variables once again inside the method.
I don't want to create them.
I want to update them.
I thought that was worth leaving in that particular area because it's an easy one to make.
And it brings to light another issue that we can't simply update all of the values of an array in this
way.
We'll have to do that using a loop.
You see we've got an error here.
We're not allowed to update an array in the same way that we define it.
Say that's just leap 3
all of the items in game state.
So we going to get up to game state
length
incrementing each time and we just want to set game state
to 2.
All right.
So let's try again.
With any luck that will now work as we need it to.
Hey guys so again Mulder Radwin
Oh God help it your life has won doesn't matter.
Let's play again.
And now it's looking good.
That's good.
Read when they should have had before.
Red has one.
Wonderful.
Great stuff.
So that was quite a complex game but hopefully you managed to figure most of that out yourself and at
least managed to follow along and see what we did particularly with the winning positions to work out
the game state and whether anyone has won.
Wonderful.
So I hope you enjoy that.
Now let's move on to the other two main topics of this section.
Audio and video.