So in this lecture we're going to learn more about this User class about how we can make new users sign
them in sign them up check to see if someone is logged in or not.
We're going to need that for our app to know you know what we need to show the user in the end so let's
go ahead and learn the basics and then we'll start building our Instagram app.
So let's go ahead and clear out enough space here and one thing before we dive into the nitty gritty
is I want to go over to the starter application on Java.
There's this line of code here that says parse user data enable automatic user so this can be if you
want to have an app that you don't have to require a log in but you still want to know some information
about how people use the app like get back analytics and whatnot.
This automatic user if you go back to the browser here you can see there's this been this user that's
been created they don't have an e-mail or a user name and they have a user name but it's just a random
string of numbers that don't have a password or anything like that.
But this has created for us because we have that checked.
So for our app now that we're adding our own user logon information let's go ahead and comment that
out and then we're going to come back to our main activity and start writing some log in code.
So now that we're here the first thing that we want to do is we want to create something called a parse
user.
So we're going to make a new parse user who will just call user and or this is just going to be equal
to a new parse user.
Now with this user there's two main things that you have to set and that's the username and password.
So first let's set the user set username.
And with this go ahead and pick something I might say something as simple as Nick and then we're going
to take our user and we need to set a password.
So these are the two main things that username and password.
So with a password maybe we'll just go ahead and do something as simple as mine pass with the capital
P there.
Then what we're going to do is because you know we want to simulate First how do you sign up a user
then we'll worry about the log and stuff.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to sign up a user so we're going to say user sign up and there's all sorts of different
options to sign up and background and whatnot.
But let's go ahead and do the sign up in background that has a callback.
So we're going to see a new sign up call back and use the auto complete there to get this.
And then when it's finished it will tell us whether or not that worked out.
So we'll do our IF statement with the error or excuse me the exception that comes through so I'll say
if this is equal to know then we know that everything was OK else.
This is where we do like in the print stack trace.
OK.
Now with this let's go ahead and just give ourselves a simple log.
If everything did work out and we'll just say something like sign up OK and maybe something like we
did it.
All right.
So with that in place let's go ahead and run this.
And again if this works out we should see a new user inside of the class here this table that is going
to have a user name of Nic.
So looks like we got things up and running Let's check log cat here it says we did it.
So that should hopefully mean we're successful.
Let's reload the page here and look at this says user name Nick.
The password is hidden so I guess maybe that last user did have a password it was just hidden there.
But look at that we were able to successfully create a user.
Now you may be wondering OK let's say someone comes into our app and they want to log in.
How do we handle that situation.
Well let's go ahead and comment this out.
Will do slash star star slash and let's write some logon codes so the above stuff was for the Sign-Up
up to some logon code.
So it's quite similar except we don't create a user object or anything first we just go straight to
the chase here where we say parse user dot and we do log in and we want to do our log in and background
but do the one where we can pass in the username and password and then also a callback.
So first let's pass it a user name so maybe let's do the one that we did earlier Nick and let's go ahead
and provide a password which we had as my pass and then we also need to do a new one.
Oh excuse me log in callback.
So this will tell us whether or not it was able to work.
And it also gives a sparse user which is pretty great.
So we're going to say if statement here check and make sure we have the user so if user is not equal
to nil meaning you know we were able to successfully get back the user then we can log out something
that says success like we logged in.
Right.
But ELTs If that doesn't work out then you know we want to say something like You know you don't print
Stracke stack trace you know we had some sort of air.
So let's go ahead and try this.
We should be able to see success if we use the correct name and password that we had set earlier here.
So let's go ahead and get log up and look at that we logged in so we know that that was successful Well
let's say we go ahead and add a wrong path right here like I take one of the S's off of my pass will
now we should see an exception.
We do something like a print stack trace so let's go ahead and try this out.
And when we get this boom look at that.
So invalid user name slash password.
So we know that something went wrong there.
OK.
Then finally the last thing that we want to do.
Go ahead and also comment this out is we want to talk about how we open the app we don't want to log
someone in we don't want to sign them up.
We just want to check and see if there's currently a logged in user and parse handles all the work if
somebody logs in they'll stay logged in until you log them out.
So we can simply just write an IF statement.
Where in our parentheses we say capital parse user dot get current user and we'll just see if this thing
is equal to no.
Because if it's equal to no we know that no one is logged in.
But if it's not equal and all that means we have a user that's logged in and we can move forward.
So when in fact let's go ahead and log out something that says signed in.
And what we're going to provide for the other string here is we're going to get this parse user get
current user and then we're going to say get user names or even get a printout what their username is.
And if we that doesn't work out then you know we are going to display some sort of information here.
And you know this might be the place where then you'd want to provide some code to say hey you know
you weren't currently signed in I should so the user or the log in functionality or the Sign-Up functionality.
So we'll say no luck I'm not signed in.
All right.
So let's go ahead and try this get Lague can open up here to check this out so we should get a successful
signed in and the user name because we've logged in before and if we go ahead and do this let's see
you look at that signed in Nick so that successfully worked.
But now let's say you know you want to log out.
How do you successfully log someone out of an app.
Well all you have to do is you just say capital parse user dot log out and that's it.
It's really that simple.
So let's go ahead and run this what should happen now is we'll log out.
Then when we do this check get current news will bring us back now which then should bring the message
to say no.
No luck I guess.
I said not luck but if we do this look it up not look not signed in with your new skills of learning
about the user how to manipulate parse data queries all that good stuff.
You are now ready to move forward on building the Instagram app.
So let's go take a stab at it in the next lecture.