All right in this lecture we're going to be diving into functions and functions are so great in Kotla
And I think they're just a dream to work with makes it very straightforward about what's going on.
So to create a function and Kollin all you have to do is type fun space give your function a name like
I'll make one that just says let's call hello.
And the idea is this is going to print out Hello world.
So you have to do some parentheses here eventually this is where some parameters are going to go.
But right now those two function with no parameters.
This function does not return anything.
And then anything that's inside the curly brackets gets run when the function is called.
So for example inside of here I'm going to say print line and I'm going to print out Hello world and
now I can call this function just like this.
Hello I could call it multiple times if I'd like to and each time that I call it it's going to run this
code.
So we should see Hello World printed out three times.
Look at that.
That's exactly what we get.
Now let's say we wanted our function to return some information.
Well what we do is we put a colon after the parentheses where the parameters are going to go and then
we say what type is going to be returned.
So in this case if I wanted to return a string I can do that.
So rather than saying print line hello world I am now going to simply return.
Hello world.
Just returned space.
That's how you return something.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to print line whatever hello world or excuse me hello function
gives back.
It should be kicking back a string so let's go ahead and run this and look at that.
It prints out Hello world.
That worked great.
Now if you want to pass parameters into a function you can do that by specifying specifying a name for
your parameter.
So I might say something like If I want to say hello to someone's call say name.
This is going to be of type string.
If I can spell string correctly and now I can say something like hello and I'm going to do some string
interpellation here and pass in name so that then means here inside of this function if I'm going to
spit back some information or if I have a function that requires a parameter that I need to put something
here.
So maybe I'll put like Nick right there.
So now when I read this code it should say Hello Nick and boom.
Look at that it does.
Now one cool thing that you can do is you can set sort of default parameters so that if someone doesn't
provide a value you can still move forward so I can say no name calling is going to be a string and
I could set this equal to.
Maybe like Rick by default so that someone could still call and tell AJ is freaking out on me here but
I can still call this function without passing a parameter now and what it will do by default is just
say hey if no one gave me a parameter I'll just use Rick as the default for this.
And if you want to accept multiple parameters you can do that you just say comma and then you know let's
say if you wanted to take another première like punk you ation if that's how you spell it.
Right so if someone wants to say hello with like an exclamation point or something like that you know
then we'll say all right then we're going to provide dollar sign punctuation.
So we would want to specify here that we are going to first give a name like Nick and then we're also
going to give Let's to a question mark just to be fun here.
So say hello Nick.
That's what this function should give us and look at that.
Hello Nick.
Now something cool with functions that you can do in KOPPLIN This is the sort of shorthand way of making
a function so I'd say I have kind of you know a dumb function that adds to numbers and I say fun.
Add numbers and it takes two parameters so it takes like number one which is an ant.
And it takes nothing to write which is an ant.
And I say you know what this thing at the end of the day should be returning an int value and I'll do
my curly brackets here and then I'll say you know return whatever number one plus two is just like this
like.
That's a valid function right.
Well you can also do this same function but in kind of a shorthand way and the shorthand way to do this
is you just say fun add numbers.
So I'm going to do the same name as this one in fact I'm just going to copy everything up to the parentheses
here.
So I'm just going to copy this sort of the exact same function and what we're going to do this time
is instead we're just going to say this is equal to.
And then we're just going to say Nahm one plus two.
And so let me go ahead and comment this out.
Also that's a fun little hot key if you select all the text and then hit command and then the forward
slash.
That's going to allow you to comment out stuff quickly but basically this is the quick hand way of saying
I'm going to return whatever number one plus numb to it.
So call it a smart enough one to determine OK number one plus two.
These are the name of the parameters that were just given and they're both.
And so they probably want to return and end in you know so it does that.
Returns it and it doesn't make us specify that this thing should kickback in it.
I mean we could if we wanted to say that this is going to return an int but it's a little bit over kill
here because in this case Kotla knows that this is a totally fine way to do this.
So my challenge for you.
Quite simple.
Make a function that takes a dog's name and age and prints a sentence about it.
Man my spelling is horrible sentence.
Who cares.
OK.
So go ahead.
Hit pause on the video and do this now.
It's embarrassing how bad I am at spelling here.
Basically all you had to do was make some function that gives back prints out some information about
dogs so I might call this one like dog info.
It's going to take in my case name as a string and it's going to take age as an ant and it's not going
to return anything because we're printing here and I'm going to have it do a print line where it says
something like Fido is seven years old and instead of saying Fido that's a dollar sign name instead
of doing seven.
That's where I'll say dollar sign.
H.
That's it.
So we are flying through and the next one we're going to kind of step things up a bit by talking about
classes and then we're going to dive into nullable.
So some good information come in here in the next one.