Now that the writers view is working more or less as I would want it it's time to make things work for
the drivers side of things.
So this is going to look like this.
We've got our starting page that we're used to.
So we're going to switch over to driver top get started and now we're given a list of nearby requests
so we know the driver's location and we're doing a request using past server to get nearby requests.
So if you have a look down the options available when you're writing your query you should find one
that enables you to find nearby objects and then when we tap them one of these.
So let's say we want to choose the point two miles one then you can see we're given both the driver's
location and the user's location and the driver has the option of accepting the request.
And if they do then that's updated on pass which will stop the existing navigation.
And it also redirects them to Google Maps so that they can see and be navigated to that location shouldn't
take a long time for this one.
And that's it.
So a few small new things in there.
We'll be doing a little bit of googling to figure out for example how to get Google maps directions
from your app as always give it a go yourself.
Hope it goes well.
Best of luck.
All right.
Here we got them.
I'm going to start with a new activity for our drivers to see all the active requests.
Our usual empty activity
call this view requests activity
every day.
And before we do too much with that
in the rider activity I'm going to add a small logout button so we'll pop this
towards the top right
to allow the user of course to log out
every OK.
So let's quickly into rider activity
say public void log out hold by the button view.
And then we just want the
log the user out using Parsees I don't logout and then redirect
to the main activity
the application context and main activity class is where we want them to go.
And then let's do that again.
So that will enable us to go back to our main activity and then let's update redirect activity.
So now if we're a writer We'll get to the right of activity but if we're a driver then we'll create
a new intent.
And this one will go to the view requests activity
that we can.
So now have to view requests is going to be a pretty simple activity it's just going to have a list
few
somewhere.
There it is
which will be a full screen
I'll call it request list fee and then set up our list fee
request list view.
This is going to be a list fee from fine view by ID card of ID dot request for you.
And in fact we're likely to need that from several locations.
So I'll define it up there.
And just create it here.
Similarly we'll need an array list
of strings which I'll call requests
and then initially will just
add a test to that array list and then set up our array adapter.
And created here.
A new array adapter using this as the context and then Android.
Don't lay out the simple list item one as the template and then requests as our array list.
And then finally we attach that to our requests list view.
And just before we run that I've just noticed that we're going to need to actually set up
a very last
there.
Otherwise we'll get a crash when we try and add to it.
OK.
So let's do a quick test.
We should now be able to log out of the right activity and then log back in as a driver and then we'll
see our test item there on the list view.
And here we go see you see we're currently logged in as a writer.
So we'll tap the new logout button which takes us back to the log in screen and now we can switch to
be a driver tap get started.
And this now takes us to the driver list for you.
Excellent.
I'm just going to update the title there.
To say nearby requests now to offer nearby requests to our drivers we need to know where they are.
So we're going to need all the GPS related code from the right activity.
I think I'll do a bit of copying and pasting here to save us typing it all out again.
So we've got our location manager and location listener
copy that Eva
paste and all of those
and then
we're not going to need the Google map but we will need location manager and location listener.
And we'll also need
the on request permission result method
to do something when the user has given us permission to use that location.
All right.
So obviously the update map method is not there I think I may have copied one too many closing parentheses
as well.
All right.
So instead of an update map method we're going to have an update list view method
again that will need a location
and will define it as public and void
as we go.
I think we need to change that.
I don't think
so the update list for your method is going to be much the same as what we did here.
But it will of course get the requests from
our past seven.
So first off just in case we've got any active requests already saved let's clear those.
And then we're going to run a query to get nearby requests so great.
I passed query on past objects calling query
and this is going to be.
I pass querido get query on
how request object that is.
This one hand
and we want requests that are near our current location.
So we need to get our current location
so we'll create a GOP point.
I'm going to call this job point location and then we use new
passaggio point
using location get latitude and location dot to get long Ajeet.
And I'm going to do just a very quick check here.
To make sure location is not.
Now we've done lots of checks earlier in the code so very much shouldn't be but it's a good idea to
check that just before you attempt to get the latitude and longitude just in case.
So now we want the take out query and we're looking for where near.
So this will allow us to put in a job point.
I would point location and it will find objects which are near our location and that will order them
by their closeness as well.
So I just need to check the name of record location here.
So we want where location
is near our driver's location and then I'm also going to limit the number of results.
I don't think we need more than 10.
It's likely that the driver will always choose the closest one anyway.
And then we kind of run our query so I find in background
with a new find callback and as usual check for error.
Now
and objects dot size being greater than zero.
So if we have some objects will leap through them.
So parse Object object in objects and then the information I want to actually show on the list is the
distance to the request from the users current location.
So let's
create distance and I'm going to have it in miles it will have distance in miles.
And then if we get the users current location says Geo point location you can see we've got these lovely
methods which are perfect for what we want so distance in miles too.
And then we just need to get the request location.
So that's going to be object to get and then location we will need to
cast that to a geo point and Vijaya point.
I mean I passed you up with.
There we go.
So that will get the distance in miles that will generally be a very accurate number though.
So I'm going to convert that to one decimal place.
Distance 1 DP and we can do that in Java using math dot round.
So there's no easy one decimal place method.
But if we round outdistance
multiply by 10 to the nearest number and then divide that by 10 that will effectively give us a number
to one decimal place.
I just need to cast that to a double.
So thinking about that if for example we've got a number which is one point three and then a load of
decimals if we multiply that by 10 we get thirteen point and then a lot of decimals.
If we then round that to the nearest whole number it's going to be 14 because it's thirteen point six
say 14.
And then if we divide that by 10 we get 1.4 which is the original number to 1 decimal place.
So that's how a person process of rounding to one decimal place in Java.
So then we just take our request and at that distance so distance 1 DP and of course we're going to
need to convert it to a string and we'll add
miles on the end.
OK.
And when that's done we're going to want to update the list.
So let's take our data and notify that the data set has changed.
And then in a Meave
the definition here to our own create method
and just to give them a message while it's loading.
I'm going to take our requests and clear it just in case and then I'm going to add
getting nearby requests.
OK so with any luck now we'll get the driver's location and then get a list of nearby requests in order
and will display the distance from those results.
One more very quick change I think will
add a quick no nearby requests if there aren't any.
So if object sizes not greater than zero or
will add are no active requests nearby and then maybe the array adapter to be updated down that.
All right.
So let's give that a try and Mullet's compiling.
I'm going to add a few more requests down here.
So I will add just a random user name
and then remind myself where the current location is on say 52 and minus no point 3 5
to fifty two point one minus no point 3 6
add another number to
and then fifty point zero one minus point three five five
try that again to a point zero or one minus no point 3 5 5 every gay couple more
fifty point zero or three minus no point
3 5 6.
Strange that it does that
it's Belem.
And so that gives us four.
That's probably enough to be working with.
Let's go and see it in action.
And here we go.
So you can see we've got one that bang on which is no surprise because we haven't moved since we created
that one.
And then the other ones that I created are a little bit further away.
Of course if I then update my longer you'd say man it's no point 3 5 that will update the request list.
Excellent.
So now we've got a list of requests.
Our next step is to be able to view the precise location of these requests so to do that we're going
to need new activity.
And this is going to be
another Google Maps activity
I'll call it the drive out location activity.
And you can see it's jumped to the Google Maps API to SML But we already have our key in there because
we put it in there when we created the previous Google Maps activity.
So we're going to want to jump to the driver location activity from the view requests activity.
We'll do that when they tap on one of the items in the table and I'm going to do that by passing the
driver's location and uses location to the driver location activity.
So we'll add this down in our own create method
and we would take our request list we set on him click listener with a new on item click his name and
now we're going to want to pass not only the users current location but the request location as well.
So we don't have a store currently for the request location so let's set that up we'll create an array
list.
And this is going to be of flights
for request latitudes because we can't send locations directly in intense
this is going to be a new list of flights.
And similarly
we'll have request longer cheat's
which will also be an array list of flights.
And then here as we're populating the last few We'll take request latitudes and add and we want to get
the latitude from the object location.
So I think what alday is rather then use that every time
I create a request location which is going to be that object that
and then we'll use that there as well.
Could even be very careful and check to see if request location is not know before adding it.
And then request location to get latitude and you've got a small issue there because it's a double.
Not a problem.
I think the easiest thing would be to update these two doubles
rather than flights
go and similarly request
Lagace.
Well at
the quest location don't get let me cheat.
And also while we're there let's not forget to clear
multi that just here after they find him backgrounders happened
Klaver Quest long cheats and also requests latitudes.
All right so back to our own item click listener.
We want to check that we can get the locations that we need to send.
So I'm going to check to see if request latitudes dot size is greater than.
And remember I is the number of the row that the user pressed on.
So if the user presses on the first row that will be I will be at zero.
So we want request latitudes to be at least 1 in size.
So it has to be greater than I.
And similarly request
non-achievers
and we're going to use the last known location as well.
So that's here.
So let's grab that's in fact we'll grab it here and then
a check to make sure that last line location is not no
and we need to do our check to make sure we have permission
all that they version is less than 23 i.e. We're pre marshmallow
may be gay and we want this to refer to the the activity.
So we won't view requests activity got this
fee.
So if all those are the case then we'll do the redirect.
So I will create our intent
and we want to redirect to drive location activity doc class and then we'll add how extras
say
we'll have it use the latitude and this is going to be in fact will it request latitude keep our naming
reason to be consistent.
And this is going to be requested latitudes get I
and then Same for request long achieved
Everquest long teased off get.
And we've already done a check to be sure that that exists.
Then we'll put the call dry the latitude
and this is going to be the last known location dot get latitude and finally the driver Lagace it will
be the last known occasion to get
longitude and then finally we'll start activity and run the intent OK.
And then for now
we'll just be a very quick recipient of that intent.
So we'll get the intent
and for now we'll just center it on the driver's location so we'll create a new lot to learn which will
be intent.
To get double extra
The double extra We want to get is the driver latitude
with a default value of 0.
Just in case something goes horribly wrong and we don't have a valley and another double extra driver
long achieved and again 0 will be the default
and we'll call this driver location
and we'll give it a title of your location.
Seem to have an issue either in view requests activity that we can.
I've missed a semi-colon or I've got an extra parenthesis easily.
OK.
So let's take a look.
We should now be redirected to the driver location activity which will then show us the driver's location
on a Google map.
Our next step then will be to show both the driver and the user's location on the map which will require
quite careful framing because we want to be sure that both markers are shown on the map.
So while that's compiling Let's have a quick jump over to Firefox and see if we can find a good way
to do that.
Not an easy problem to solve.
So let's take a look at something like Android Google map show two markers on map something like that.
Let's have a look and then we get that first result looks pretty good.
Zoom to show all the markets Stephanie what we want to see.
They've got 10 markets but that's OK.
So let's have a look at this we're calculating the bounds of all the markets.
So we're using a lot to learn bounds builder and then we're looping through what looks like an array
list of our markers and then we're generating some bounds from those.
Then we add in some padding and update the camera using those bounds.
Okay that looks pretty straightforward.
We'll try that out once we've tested that everything's working.
Over in our app and here we go here's our requests so let's tap on one of them and there we go.
So it's redirecting nicely and displaying correctly.
Obviously the Xoom isn't great but we'll fix that now anyway using this code
which we're going to use to make sure that both of the markers appear
in our map so I've selected all of that
let's get rid of anything that isn't Kate and I think well use animate Kemmerer
say bring is in OK.
So if we remember what's going on here we're creating a lot to learn Baum's object and we're doing that
from a list of markers.
So let's create this array list of Marcus which are all cool markers and it's going to be a new rightest.
So we haven't actually created a market before except when we're adding a marker here.
So we should be able to take markers and then add and then we just copy how Marka creation carried
from that.
But of course we will need to know the location
before we do that.
So now we've got the drive is location that's do the same thing.
But adding the request location
to do that we'll need to create a layer again for the request location.
So this is going to be a new lot to learn.
And again we're going to use content don't get double extra.
And I think I called it request latitude.
Let's just check yes say request latitude
0 just in case and that intent get double extra request not achieved with zero as the backup
OK.
So now we've got our array list of markers that added to the map then we're looping through those markers
and generating the bounds.
So a bit of padding.
I think let's go for 30 pixels from the edge and then we update the camera.
And so we no longer need our code to add those.
And I'll just change that.
It should work as Google map but have we as we've used and map everywhere else to refer to our Google
map we'll keep it there as well.
All right.
So before we run that there's another change I'm going to make that is to add a request button to the
bottom of
that screen and this time I'm not able to drag my button in directly.
So I'm going to show you a solution to that problem which is to essentially create a relative layout
to contain our map.
So we're going to copy the relative layout code from activity main and then go back to the driver location
and then paste that in before our fragment and then we'll close the relative layout
I'm going to set
all the paddings to zero DP So we get all the way to the edge of the screen
every k
will change the context to driver location activity.
OK so now our map is contained within the relatively out and we should be able to drag in our button
I would go and position it now where we like.
So I'm going to go for bottom center
I'm going to call accepte request button unclick is going to be accepte request
and the text will be accept request
and then
what we need to do is set up
and accept request method called by a view button and here we need to do a couple of things
we need to update the request over in pass so that we know that it's been accepted so it won't be accepted
by someone else.
And then we need to give the driver directions.
So let's do the first thing first in order to update the requests we're going to need to know which
request it is.
And that's something we haven't actually got yet.
So let's add that to the requests activity.
So I will add an extra and we'll have the user name.
And again this is something that we don't have yet.
So let's have this in here.
It's going to be on the list of strings
and then we'll add that down.
Here's a user names.
It's going to be at and them we'll use object to get string and the string is going to be the username.
So that is this object here.
OK.
So now we're going see past that as well so that's going to be user names gets.
And again we want the right one.
And I'll just do a check to make sure
there are enough usernames to go around.
So that should now pass on the usernames
that define our intent so we can get
wherever we need
and then we'll create a query
to find
the request.
It's going to be a pass query to get query on the request class
and we want to find where the user name
is equal to a
a pope that is in and we want intent to get string extra
and use a name
then we'll run a query.
With a new find Colback
check to say that he is no
and that we have an object
then we'll look through them.
Well they were very much expecting one hand
and we're going to update that object
with a driver use a and that driver user name will be our current user names I get current user talk
get username
and then
save in the background with a callback.
So a new safe callback.
And as long as he is know how final thing today is then to get directions to this new location.
Again that's something we haven't done before.
So if we can figure out how to do it.
So Android gets directions to location and I'll pop in Java just because if I didn't have Java it might
look like I wasn't making an app.
I was just seeing how to use Android itself.
So now that top result looks pretty good.
So looking at that one it actually looks like he's trying to draw the directions on the map which is
not what we want.
We want the actual driving directions on location change.
Not really.
This one looks better.
Launching Google maps directions via an intent.
That's definitely what we want today.
OK.
And there we go.
That looks pretty simple.
So we're creating an intent
then creating a you are right
which is a Google Maps you are right with what looks like the starting point and the finishing point
right there.
And then we're starting that activity.
It's done you are right OK.
So you put that on the next line so we can see all of it.
So then I'm going to call this something else.
So we don't confuse it with our previous intent.
And then we just need to get all of the values from our initial intent.
So it's going to be a bit messy.
But here we go.
So intent gets
double extra.
And this is going to be the starting point latitude so that they derive latitude
the zero just in case
and I'm going to copy that
and replace it that
is put back slashes in rather unhelpfully I don't need those backslashes.
There we go.
So now we want drive long achieved
and then we want
again without the backslash is
the request latitude.
And finally
in fact we didn't have anything after that.
So just the request
to
there we go.
So that should create the Google Maps you are l and then
we just start the activity to direct them to the writer.
All right let's have a look and see if that works.
And here we go.
So let's try.
The second result and see what we get.
And sadly we get a crash but let's not worry let's have a look and see what's gone wrong.
I've run
so error using new zealand bounds maps as can't be zero.
Most likely the layout has not yet occurred for the map view.
OK.
That's a shame because we're running this in the on map ready function so you might expect the map to
be ready but presumably it's not laid out yet.
So let's see our previous answer
and see if there's any help there.
Almost all methods require the map object to have passed the lab process.
You can wait for this to happen using the add on label layout listener right.
OK let's see if there's any greater assistance there.
So they've got that specific error that we found and they've got a solution to it.
But they said they couldn't use on global outlets.
So let's see here we go.
This is how to use global outlets.
So let's do it the proper way.
So I back over and we'll do this in on create
so we're accessing the relative layout
which we have but we haven't given an idea yet.
So let's get our relative lay out and give it an ID
I'll call it map relative lay out
there we go.
And then we're taking our map layout and adding and on global layout listener.
Here we go.
So that's where we write code to update
everything that we need.
So that should work fine.
I think I'll just define my intent a little bit earlier so that it can be accessed just in case we have
any problems with the map layouts.
All right let's give that a try.
As I've said before if you get a crash Don't panic just go in.
Look at the error message try and see what's going on.
If you really can't figure it out Googling the error message will normally get you the solution to the
problem.
Someone's probably been there before.
All right.
So let's try it again.
Point four miles.
And there we go.
So we get a nice animation and both of the markers are shown on the map.
And let's try the accept request button as well.
We'll open that with the maps app I'll change that to the default for this device as well.
And then except that's skip the sign in process for now.
And there you go.
You can see we've got the navigation there.
So you just tap start navigation and we get to go.
All right.
So we're pretty much there for the driver side of things now just a couple of small tweaks.
The first is you may have noticed that we had two markers of the same color which made it a little bit
unclear which one was which.
So you'll be nice to have different colored markers and see if we can figure out how to do that.
So Android map
change marker colors something like that.
I would say
so.
Go straight to the answer.
And that looks good.
So we change the icon default marker and then we change the color there.
I think that might actually be something that were done before.
But let's have that in.
So it will change
the color of
the request location to blue
OK.
And the other change that we need to make is now that we've got requests that have been accepted.
And to see that we'll need to do a full refresh here because we've got a new column.
We should find the yes that this request has a driver username and we don't want to show you those sort
of requests in the request list because they're already taken.
So let's add
to the query
take our query and we want to find where the driver username is undefined.
So for that we can use query dot where does NOT exist.
And the thing that we want not to exist is the driver use the name we wanted to be undefined.
There we go.
So let's have a quick look at that in action.
We should now find that we can only see three requests in the user list and also that when we view a
request we see the markers as different colors.
And here we go.
So first off we can't see that request that we're no longer interested in.
And secondly if we take a new request you can see we can now see both of those as different colors.
Although having done that I think I'm going to increase the padding slightly because there's still a
bit too close to the edge for my liking so let's just quickly change that
or change that to 60.
There we go.
So that's as far as we're going to go for the driver.
Now all that remains is to update the riders view so that they know that our drive is on the way and
we're going to tell them how far away the drive is as well.
We'll do that in the next video.