Hi everyone.
It's Kim Schmidt again.
In the last module,
we set up the relational data portion of this
course using Amazon CloudFormation.
We also populated an Amazon Aurora Relational Database,
connected to this database in the cloud remotely with a
third-party SQL client and ran some queries.
In this short module,
I'll cover some of the necessary and amazing details about AWS Glue,
so you'll be familiar with these concepts as we build our next CloudFormation
stack that creates the infrastructure for using AWS Glue,
Glue crawlers, Glue jobs, and the Glue Data Catalog.
Let's now look at how encryption and security are
implemented for AWS Glue in an S3 Data Lake.
You use AWS Identity and Access Management,
or IAM,
policies to assign permissions that determine who is allowed to
manage AWS Glue resources via usernames and passwords.
In addition to a username and password, you can also generate keys for each user.
You can use these keys when we you access AWS services
programmatically either through one of the several SDKs or by
using the AWS Command Line Interface, or CLI.
The SDK and CLI tools use the access keys to
cryptographically sign your request.
A service role is an IAM role that a service assumes to
perform actions in your account on your behalf.
When you set up some AWS service environments,
you must define a role for this service to assume.
This service role must include all of the permissions that are required for
the service to access the AWS resources that it needs to.
You use AWS Glue resource policies to control access
to the Glue Data Catalog resources.
Glue enables you to encrypt data, logs,
and bookmarks using keys that you manage with AWS Key Management Service,
or KMS.
You can configure ETL jobs and development endpoints to use AWS
KMS keys to write encrypted data at rest.
Additionally,
you can use AWS KMS keys to encrypt the logs generated by crawlers and ETL jobs,
as well as encrypt ETL job bookmarks.
With AWS Glue,
you can also encrypt the metadata stored in the data catalog
with keys that you manage with AWS KMS.
You can only connect to a JDBC data store with trusted Secure Socket Layer,
or SSL, connections.
You use the security features of your database engine to control who
can log into the databases on a database instance.
Let's now look at Glue's built-in transformations that
are available for ETL functionality.
Glue provides a set of built-in PySpark transformations
that you can use to process your data.
You can call these transformations from your ETL script.
Your data passes from transformation to transformation in DynamicFrames.
The DynamicFrame contains your data,
and you reference its schema to process your data.
Initially,
AWS Glue generates an ETL script that includes built-in transformations.
But you can edit this script to add sources, targets, and transformations.
You can customize the job processing environment by providing
arguments for your job and the generated script.
Use these tables for your own reference when authoring ETL scripts.
One built-in transformation that I'd like to point out is
in the bottom row of the top-left table,
Relationalize.
Let's dive deeper into what that means and when to use it.
The Glue Relationalize transform simplifies the ETL process
by converting nested JSON into columns that you can easily
import into relational databases.
Relationalize transforms the nested JSON into key value pairs at
the outer-most level of the JSON document.
Conceptually, you are flattening a hierarchical schema to a relational schema.
AWS Glue can perform this conversion for you on the fly.
Semi-structured data typically contains markup to
identify entities within the data.
It can have nested data structures with no fixed schema.
For example,
you might want to parse JSON data from an S3 source file to
Amazon Relational Database service tables.
Understanding how AWS Glue handles the differences between schemas
can help you understand the transformation process.
In a nutshell,
the conceptual diagram on this slide illustrates single value A
converts directly to a relational column.
The pair of values, B1 and B2, convert to two relational columns.
Structure C with children X and Y converts to two relational columns.
And array D converts to a relational column with a foreign key
that points to another relational table.
Along with a primary key,
the second relational table has columns that contain the
offset and value of the items in the array.
A classifier determines the schema of your data.
You can write a custom classifier and point to it from AWS Glue,
or you can use one of the many built-in classifiers.
Let's further explore the built-in classifiers.
Built-in classifiers are applied in a hierarchical manner.
Glue crawlers apply classifiers to the data as it scans it and adds the
schema metadata as tables to the Glue Data Catalog.
Here we see 22 Glue Data Catalogs built-in classifiers in the hierarchy
of which classifiers are tried first for every crawl.
First, Glue looks for any custom classifiers you may have written.
If Glue doesn't find a customer classifier that fits the
input data format with 100% certainty,
it invokes the built-in classifiers in the order shown in this slide.
Each classifier has a unique way of determining the
schema when a crawler crawls.
The build-in classifiers return a result to indicate whether the format
matches that gives a certainty of 1.0 or does not match,
giving a certainty of 0.0.
The first classifier that certainty of 1.0 provides the classification
string and schema for a metadata table in your data catalog.
In the next section, we'll cover Glue crawlers, Glue Data Catalogs, and Glue's databases and tables.