Hi guys, it's Kim Schmidt again.
In the last module,
we really got our hands dirty working with AWS Glue services in the AWS Console.
Although we've used Athena before, I haven't explained it yet.
That's what this module will do.
It will give you a comprehensive understanding and experience
using Amazon Athena in the AWS Console.
Parquet is an efficient columnar storage format that's very good
at compressing data and is used heavily in large-scale
distributed Spark deployments on big data.
Columnar storage formats have the following characteristics
that make them suitable for using with Athena.
It has compression by column,
with compression algorithms selected for the column data
type to save storage space in Amazon S3 and reduce disk
space in I/O during query processing.
Parquet and ORC have predicate pushdown,
which enables Athena queries to fetch only the blocks it needs,
improving query performance.
When an Athena query obtains specific column values from your data,
it uses statistics from data blocked predicates such as min/max values and
so on to determine whether to read or skip that block.
Parquet and ORC formats allow Athena to split the reading of data to multiple
readers and increase parallelism during its query processing.
Let's look at some of Athena's other benefits.
Athena is serverless, you don't need to worry about configuration,
software updates, failures,
or scaling your infrastructure as your datasets and number of users grow.
Athena automatically takes care of all of this for you.
Although Athena is ideal for quick ad hoc querying,
it can also handle complex analyses like large joins,
window functions, and analysis on arrays.
Athena is optimized for fast query performance.
With Athena,
it allows you to control access to your data by using AWS
Identity and Access Management policies,
access control lists, or ACLs, and Amazon S3 bucket policies,
and it can query encrypted data in S3 and write encrypted results to S3.
Athena allows you to partition your data on any column.
Partitions allow you to limit the amount of data each query scans,
leading to cost savings and faster performance.
You can specify your partitioning scheme using the partition
bi-clause in the CREATE TABLE statement.
Athena has native integration with Amazon QuickSight.
QuickSight is the first business-intelligent service with
pay-per-session pricing and produces machine-learning insights.
Athena integrates with Amazon S3 inventory and Amazon EC2 Systems Manager.
Amazon S3 inventory can provide CSV or ORC file output of
S3 bucket objects and their metadata on a scheduled basis
that's totally configurable.
It can be used as a ready-made input into a big
data job or workflow application.
AWS Systems Manager is a collection of capabilities for
configuring and managing EC2 instances, on-premises servers,
virtual machines, and other AWS resources at scale.
It provides a unified interface that allows you to easily centralize
operational data and automate tasks across your AWS resources. In the next section, I'll cover Amazon Athena's dual data catalogs.