Now that you have course prerequisites set up,
in this module entitled The State of Analytics in the AWS Cloud,
I'll briefly explain the concept of Amazon S3 data lakes,
introduce you to the relational database of choice for analytics,
Amazon Aurora,
and then introduce you to AWS Glue and Amazon Athena and
the business problems that they solve.
At this point in the course,
you'll need a fundamental understanding of what data lakes are.
A data lake is a centralized repository that allows you to store all
your structured and unstructured data at any scale.
You can store your data as is without having to first structure the data.
When you use Amazon S3 as the data lake storage platform,
you have a complete portfolio of data exploration,
reporting, analytics, machine learning, artificial intelligence,
and visualization tools to use on all your data.
A data lake makes data and the optimal analytics tools available
to more users across more lines of business,
which enables companies to get all of the business
insights they need whenever they need them.
I'm aware that you'll be learning about Amazon S3
object storage in this learning path,
but I wanted to quickly review why Amazon S3 is used as the
primary storage platform for a data lake.
In the next two slides,
I'll quickly discuss Amazon S3's benefits in so far as it relates
to being the perfect data lake storage platform.
S3 is an optimal foundation for a data lake because of
its virtually-unlimited scalability.
S3 is designed for the 11-nines of data durability because
it automatically creates and stores copies of all S3
objects across multiple systems.
This means your data is available when needed and protected against failures,
errors, and threats.
You can take advantage of the range of S3 storage classes,
moving to a less-expensive S3 class when certain criteria is met.
S3 lifecycle policies can be enabled so your data will
automatically transfer to a different storage class without
any changes to your application.
You can use Amazon S3 storage class analysis to discover data that should
move to a lower-cost storage class based on access patterns.
These last two benefits contribute to substantial cost savings.
There are many ways to transfer data into S3.
Amazon Macie is a security service that uses machine
learning to automatically discover, classify,
and protect sensitive data stored in S3.
It recognizes sensitive data like personally-identifiable information,
or PII, and intellectual property.
It's a fully-managed service that continually monitors data access
activity for anomalies and generates detailed alerts when it detects risk
of unauthorized access or inadvertent data leaks.
Amazon S3 has built-in security by design.
It protects data with an infrastructure designed for the
most data-sensitive organizations.
S3 provides a wide range of data management features,
giving flexibility at an object level while managing scale,
configuring access, enabling cost efficiencies,
and auditing data across an S3 data lake.
S3 data lakes have query-in-place services for big data analytics
like Amazon Athena and Amazon Redshift Spectrum.
S3 has event notifications delivered using Amazon Simple Queue Service,
or SQS, Amazon Simple Notification Service,
or SNS, or AWS Lambda.
It has data protection through versioning, cross-region replication, and more.
There's many ways to ensure your data is secure in S3,
like multifactor authentication, flexible access control mechanisms,
access logs, and multiple client and server-side encryption options.
Using S3 as a data lake store platform gives you access to
numerous AWS analytics applications, artificial intelligence services,
machine-learning services, and high-performance file systems.
This means you can run numerous workloads across your data lake without
additional data processing or transfers to other stores.
You can also bring your preferred third-party analytics and
machine-learning tools to your S3 data lake.
On this slide is a conceptual representation of most of AWS services
that you can use to build your analytical pipelines.
At the bottom are various ways to get your data into AWS.
Next in red are S3 data lake services,
in orange are the various database solutions,
analytical solutions,
and blockchain solutions AWS provides at this point in time.
And in blue are the business intelligence and
machine-learning services that AWS provides.
I'm not going to explain this slide because it's a lot to take in at this point.
I've included it in this presentation so that you can revisit this content
after the course when it'll make much more sense to you.
In the next section, I'll cover Amazon Aurora, the relational database of choice when it comes to analytics.