Hi.
It's Kim Schmidt again.
In the last module, I gave you a quick introduction to S3 data lakes,
Amazon Aurora Relational Database service,
I introduced you to Globomantics, a global provider of NBA trivia,
whose technology problems can be solved by using AWS Glue and Amazon Athena,
and I introduced you to AWS Glue and Amazon Athena and
explained the business problems that they solve.
In this module,
we'll begin to build our cloud infrastructure and set up other cloud
assets needed to work with AWS Glue and Amazon Athena.
We'll be populating a relational database since most of you
are familiar with relational databases, at the end of this module,
the Amazon Aurora database will be ready to be crawled to
create a table in the Glue data catalog to be used for
analytics with Amazon Athena.
For the sake of time,
we'll be using Amazon CloudFormation to set up the necessary
infrastructure for us throughout this course.
So what is Amazon CloudFormation?
CloudFormation is one of my favorite AWS services because
once you know how to use it correctly,
it monumentally reduces the time needed to create your infrastructure.
You don't need to individually create and configure AWS
resources and figure out what's dependent on what.
AWS CloudFormation handles all of that.
Using JSON on YAML,
you can describe all the necessary resources and
their properties in a text file.
You can use parameters,
which are input values you supply to the CloudFormation stack at runtime
to initiate some important parts of the infrastructure.
Once your template functions the way you want it to,
you deploy the template,
which provides infrastructure as code as a CloudFormation stack.
A stack is a collection of AWS resources that you manage as a single unit,
and once it's created, it lives in an Amazon S3 bucket.
You can create your own custom template in the AWS
CloudFormation Management Console, or through AWS APIs,
or through the AWS Command Line Interface.
You can declare output values that you can import
into other CloudFormation stacks.
Output values are returned in response to stack calls,
or they can be viewed in the console.
A common example would be to output the name of an S3 bucket for
a stack to make the bucket easier to find.
After you deploy your stack,
you'll want to ensure all resources are created as you coded them.
You'll need to open the folder you downloaded from my CloudLeader's
GitHub repository that contains the code-related course assets I
instructed you to do in the module about prerequisites.
We're going to use the AuroraStack.yml script to
create our Aurora CloudFormation stack.
Before we start the first demo, type into Google what's my ip.
You'll get a result that has a format similar to the red
fake IP address shown on this slide.
I obscured my IP address for security reasons.
The next section is a demo section where we'll build our first relational database infrastructure using Amazon CloudFormation.