Hi.
It's Kim Schmidt again.
In the last module, we went over AWS Glue in detail.
This module is primary a demo module,
where you're really going to get hands-on experience using AWS Glue.
This module's objectives, in order to teach you all about AWS Glue,
include the following,
we're going to upload a Python script that contains the
transformation code we'll use during an AWS Glue job that will
transform the data from MySQL to Parquet format,
so the data is ready for analysis at any time in the future.
We're going to create another CloudFormation stack.
This time we'll call it GlueStack,
that will configure and provision our AWS Glue infrastructure.
We're going to use two AWS Glue crawlers,
one will crawl the Amazon Aurora database we created earlier,
and populate the Glue Data Catalog with the MySQL data schema.
The second crawler will craw the output of the AWS Glue jobs
transformations that the Python script created.
The second crawler takes the Parquet-formatted data in our Amazon S3
processed zone bucket and populates the Glue Data Catalog with a new
table in Parquet format versus MySQL format,
and that also has the same join of the films and
films_category tables just like we did when we used a
third-party SQL client in a previous module.
The intent here is to show how much easier it is to use AWS
Glue to keep a central metadata repository with all your raw
data versus having to log in remotely.
Let the Glue crawlers perform their magic by crawling your
data and populating the Glue Data Catalog.
We're going to work with an AWS Glue job that performs the ETL
transformations using the Python script that we upload to Amazon S3.
We're going to make two separate entries in the Glue data catalog,
one from each crawler differentiated by prefixes to the table names.
And lastly,
we'll use the data in the S3 processed zone bucket that's in
Parquet format loaded into Amazon Athena,
and use standard SQL to run some queries.
In the next section, we'll be creating and configuring an S3 bucket to upload our Python script to.