There's two types of data catalogs that work with Amazon Athena.
I'll explain the differences in this section.
If you created databases and tables using Athena in a region
before AWS Glue was available in that region,
the metadata is stored in an Athena-managed data catalog,
which only Athena and Amazon Redshift Spectrum can access.
To use AWS Glue features together with Amazon Athena,
you must upgrade to the Glue Data Catalog.
Athena can only be used together with the AWS Glue Data
Catalog in regions where AWS Glue is available.
It's the preferred data catalog to use because it provides many benefits.
The update process is extremely straightforward and easily found by Googling it.
Once you've upgraded to use the Glue Data Catalog,
it provides the following benefits.
The Glue Data Catalog provides a unified metadata repository across a
variety of data sources and data formats with out-of-the-box integration
with many AWS Analytic and other services.
You're able to use Glue crawlers to automatically crawl your data sources,
identify data formats, and suggest schemas and transformations.
Crawlers can help automate table creation and automatic loading
of partitions that you can query using Athena.
Glue's ETL engine generates Python code that's customizable,
reusable, and portable.
After your ETL job is ready,
you can schedule it to run on Glue's fully-managed
scale-out Spark infrastructure.
Glue handles the provisioning, configuration,
and scaling of the resources required to run your ETL jobs.
In the next section, I'll cover Amazon Athena's SerDes data formats and compression formats.