One of the first builds we'll do is to create and populate
an Amazon Aurora relational database,
so we can have Glue crawlers crawl the database and populate
the Glue Data Catalog with the schema and statistics of our
Amazon Aurora relational database.
Amazon Aurora is a MySQL or PostgreSQL compatible relational database engine.
On this slide,
I'm lucky to introduce you to Amazon Aurora's service-oriented decoupled
architecture that's applied to a relational database engine.
When Andy Jassy,
AWS' CEO challenged his data team to recreate the
relational database in a world where AWS exists,
they took about half the database out of the process,
the logging and storage.
Caching is outside the database process as well.
Notice the green rectangle that includes caching with logging and storage.
By doing this, cache remains warm in the event of a database restart.
It lets you resume fully-loaded operations much faster.
Looking at the data plane on the left side of the diagram,
the database engine is tightly integrated with the
SSD-based new virtual storage layer, reducing write to the storage system,
minimizing lock contention,
and eliminating delays created by database processing threads.
On the lower-left side, you'll see there's automatic,
continual, and incremental backups happening all the time to Amazon S3.
On the right side,
you'll see that Amazon Aurora is integrated with some of the
premier Amazon services for control plane operations where
forwarding and routing decisions are made.
Here we have a closer look of how Amazon Aurora replicates your data across
three availability zones for security and fault tolerance.
You remember that AWS regions are separate geographic areas
that provide durability and fault tolerance from large-scale
disasters like earthquakes.
Each region has multiple isolated locations known as availability zones.
Availability zones provide durability and fault tolerance for more
localized problems that might come up like power outages.
Amazon RDS provides you the ability to place resources such as
instances and data in multiple locations.
Resources aren't replicated across AWS regions unless you do so specifically.
And so far as the availability zones are concerned,
there's always one primary instance, in this diagram,
it's labeled M, kind of like for master.
Master slave is referred to as the primary instance and read replicas.
In this example, the primary instance is in availability zone A,
and one Aurora replica is in availability zone B,
and two Aurora replicas reside in availability zone C.
Notice the cluster volume and the how the reads and writes are distributed
among the primary instance and all the replica instances.
There now is Aurora Serverless for MySQL, with PostgreSQL in preview.
It removes the complexity of managing database instances and capacity.
The database will automatically start up,
shutdown, and scale to match your application's needs.
It seamlessly scales compute and memory capacity as needed
with no disruption to client connections.
You pay only for the database resources you consume on a per-second basis.
You don't pay for the database instance unless it's actually running.
It's built on distributed fault tolerant self-healing Aurora storage
with six-way replication to protect against data loss.
It responds to your application loads automatically.
It scales capacity with no downtime, its multitenant proxy is highly available,
it scales the target so it has a warm buffer pool,
and it shuts down when not in use.
In the next section, I'll cover what AWS Glue is, what it does, and the business problems it solves.