Log into your AWS Console and navigate to the Amazon S3 Console.
What we're going to do is we're going to create a bucket
and upload the Python script to that.
So click on Create bucket.
If you created your Aurora stack in the US East Ohio region,
name your bucket like you see here, aurora-glue-etl-script-east2,
and the reason for doing this is because it's hardcoded in the YAML script,
which in practice isn't a good idea, but for this course,
just use the naming conventions that I suggest.
If you created your Aurora stack in US West 2 Oregon region,
just leave off the -east2.
Filter your S3 buckets b Date created so that your most
recently-created bucket appears on the top.
Click on it, and then click on Upload and Add files.
Click the sakila- etl.py script, and click Upload.
Once the object appears, click on it, and go to Properties,
and then click on metadata.
If you don't have any metadata in the Properties
folder of your S3 object Python script, you would add metadata,
but since I already have something there and it's the wrong value,
I'm going to select it and say Edit.
You can choose from quite a few different pre-populated keys that AWS provides,
but the value here is wrong, we want content type,
but we want the value to be binary/octet-stream,
and then click Save.
At this point, we have our S3 bucket configured properly,
and it contains the Python object sakila_etl.
We're ready to create the second CloudFormation script Glue script.
Before we do the next demo,
I thought it would be helpful to walk through the Python
script that we just uploaded to the S3 bucket,
so you fully understand the transformations that are going to be done and how you write scripts to do that.