Before we learn how to build Athena databases and tables,
there's a few more concepts to cover, such as SerDes,
data formats, and compression formats that are supported by Athena.
The formats listed on this slide are used by Athena for reading data.
I'll explain formats that Athena uses for writing data
when it runs CREATE TABLE AS queries, or CTAs,
in a subsequent slide.
Athena supports creating tables and querying data from CSV,
TSV, custom delimited, and JSON formats.
It also supports Hadoop-related formats like ORC,
Apache Avro, and Apache Parquet.
It also supports log data formats from Logstash,
AWS CloudTrail, and Apache Web Server logs.
SerDes stands for serializer deserializer.
Amazon Athena uses SerDes to interpret the data read from S3.
Athena supports several SerDes libraries for parsing data
from different data formats such as CSV,
JSON, Parquet, and ORC.
It's important to realize that it's the SerDes you specify
and the DDL that defines the table schema.
In other words,
the SerDes can override the DDL configuration that you
specify in Athena when you create your table.
This table summarizes the Data Format, the Description of the data format,
and the associated SerDe Types to use with each data type.
This should be a great reference as you're building out
your own Athena databases and tables.
The compression formats listed on this slide are used for CREATE TABLE queries.
SNAPPY is the default compression format for files in
the Parquet data storage format.
ZLIB is the default compression format for files in the ORC data storage format.
You can also use LZO and GZIP for data in CSV, TSV, and JSON.
Athena determines the compression type from the file extension.
CTAS queries are commonly used for the three reasons you
see in the colored squares on this slide.
The data format supported for the CTAS queries can use ORC,
Parquet, Avro, JSON, or text file. In the next section, I'll cover creating Amazon Athena databases and tables.