There are a few best practices to optimize your data for analysis.
Let's take a very short look at those now.
It's important to ingest data in its raw format before any transformations,
analyses, manipulations, or doing anything with it at all.
Once you have the raw data in S3,
you have to prepare the raw data for consumption.
When you do this,
the raw datasets in S3 become your immutable source of record
that you can always go back to if needed.
To use raw data,
you abstract out the complexities of how the data is stored through
the Glue Data Catalog and Athena SerDes are used to serialize and
desterilize the data for analyzing the data with Amazon Athena and
other analytics services.
In S3 data lakes, the datasets are curated,
meaning they're query optimized for consumption across a wide
range of analytics and machine-learning tools.
Optimizing the data means that the data is normalized,
partitioned, compressed, and optimized for storage.
Due to time constraints, I won't be able to dive into each of these individually,
but they're very important, and I encourage you to do so.
I'll just point out a couple of them in so far as cost savings are concerned.
Before I show you the cost savings that can be had when using best practices
of preparing your raw data for downstream consumption,
you need to know that Amazon Athena and many,
many other advanced analytics work most efficiently on
columnar data formats versus row format.
Columnar data formats most often used are Apache Parquet or Apache ORC.
Parquet is very good at compressing data and is used heavily in
large-scale distributed Spark deployments on big data.
Columnar storage formats have the following characteristics
that make them suitable for using with Athena.
It has compression by column,
with compression algorithms selected for the column data
type to save storage space in Amazon S3 and reduce disk
space in I/O during query processing.
Parquet and ORC have predicate pushdown,
which enables Athena queries to fetch only the blocks it needs,
improving query performance.
When an Athena query obtains specific column values from your data,
it uses statistics from data block predicates such as min/max values and
so on to determine whether to read or skip that block.
Parquet and ORC formats allow Athena to split the reading of data to multiple
readers and increase parallelism during its query processing.
Notice on this slide that by using Parquet format versus CSV format,
there's an 87% reduction in size on S3.
The speed of querying is 34 times faster.
That gives 99% less data to scan, and price wise,
you spend 99.7 % less by simply using Parquet format.
These are significant improvements.
Glue ETL supports partitions when working with
DynamicFrames or semi-structured data.
DynamicFrames represent a distributed collection of data
without requiring you to specify a schema.
Instead of reading the entire dataset and then filtering in a DynamicFrame,
you can apply a filter to prune unnecessary Amazon S3
partitions in Parquet and ORC formats directly on the
partition metadata in the data catalog, reducing processing time.
Crawlers not only infer file types and schemas,
they also automatically identify the partition structure of your
dataset when they populate the AWS Glue Data Catalog.
The resulting partition columns are available for querying in AWS
Glue ETL jobs or query engines like Amazon Athena.
By default, a DynamicFrame is not partitioned when it's written.
All of the output files are written at the top
level of the specified output path.
Until recently,
the only way to write a DynamicFrame into partitions was to
convert it to a Spark SQL data frame before writing.
DynamicFrames now support native partitioning using a
sequence of keys and using the partition keys option when
you write to other destinations.
Source data sometimes is already fully or partially
compressed to reduce storage and disk I/O,
thereby improving query performance, as well as taking less space to store.
The table on this slide conceptually illustrates the differences between
data stored in an uncompressed CSV format versus simply GZIP-ing the CSV
file versus storing the data in Parquet format.
The size on S3 is large for plain CSV format,
but for both the GZIP CSV and the Parquet formats have
reduced this size by one-quarter.
However, looking at the amount of data that has to be scanned,
GZIP CSV files only need one-quarter of the data
scanned versus plain CSV format, and when the data is stored in Parquet format,
that's one-quarter of the data that needs to be
scanned then for GZIP CSV format.
The reason for this is that Parquet format is columnar,
and as you can see, your costs are reduced as well as the size.
Glue storage optimization is achieved via S3 lifecycle policies,
where the data automatically transfers to a different storage
class without any changes to your apps.
In the Functionality column, the information represents frequency of access,
retrieval time, availability zones, and price at the time of making this slide.
If there's a plus sign after the cost,
that indicates that there are some stipulations,
so you'd need to look up what those are. In the next section, I'll cover versioning in the Glue Data Catalog.