In this section, we're going to review the resources,
outputs, and parameters from the GlueStack,
and look at some of the things we're going to do in the subsequent demo.
You saw this screen in the demo, this is the resources tab of the GlueStack.
And you saw this in the demo as well,
where it shows all of the outputs created by the GlueStack.
And lastly, you saw this in the demo as well, showing all the parameters.
The top-left screenshot shows the AWS Glue interface for databases,
and you can see our sakila database is there.
Moving to the right screenshot on the top,
we're looking at the sakila database,
and surrounded in purple at the bottom is a link to view
the tables just for the sakila database.
Looking at the lower screenshot, when you click on that link to view the tables,
the lower-right blue rectangle surrounds the words that reads you
don't have any tables defined in your data catalog,
add tables using a crawler, and that's just what we'll do.
The screenshots on this slide show the crawler details for both
crawlers that we're going to run in this module.
The primary differences are that the first crawler will scrape the Amazon
Aurora database and populate the sakiladb database with tables,
using a prefix of glue_ for every table,
whereas the second crawler will run,
will crawl the S3 destination bucket that holds the contents of the ETL job,
where the data is transformed into Parquet format and has a prefix of S3_.
The first crawler's data store is a JDBC data store.
The second crawler's data store is Amazon S3.
The first crawler's Include path is sakila/%,
and it will crawl everything under the Amazon Aurora sakila database,
whereas the second crawler's Include path is only going to
crawl one bucket underneath Amazon S3.
On this screen is a screenshot of the AWS Glue job,
GlueStack-aurora-etljob, that we'll be using the in the next demo.
Notice in the Glue Job interface the lower blue rectangle surrounds four tabs.
The first one is the History tab,
where it keeps track of all of the runs that the job has done.
The next tab is the Details tab where you can drill
down into the configuration details.
The next tab is the Script tab, where you can view and edit the ETL script.
And the last tab is the Metrics tab,
where you can look at all of the metrics for that particular job.
The next section is a demo section, where we're going to run our Glue crawler and run the Glue ETL job.