In this section,
we're going to have another demo where we'll run the
Glue crawler and the Glue ETL job.
What we'll be doing in this demo includes running our Glue crawler
on the Amazon Aurora sakila relational database,
review the table results in the AWS Glue database
sakiladb after the crawler runs, confirm the sakila data has tables in data,
then we'll run the Glue job to perform the ETL
transformations on the data in the Glue Data Catalog,
and then we'll look at the Amazon CloudWatch logs after the Glue job runs,
and then we'll look at our S3 bucket that we specified was
the target destination for the Glue job to put the results
of the transformations into.
Log into your AWS Management Console, and start typing glue.
When you see it, click on it.
In the database view of the Glue Console,
if we click on our sakiladb and then click on tables,
we don't have any tables there yet,
so let's go down to crawler and click the little
checkbox to the left of the Aurora crawler,
and then you have the option to run the crawler,
click that.
You can see that it's attempting to run the crawler by
reading the message at the top of the screen.
Now your message is that the crawler is running, and the Status is Starting.
If you click on the name of the crawler, the status here is Running.
It goes pretty quick,
so let's go back to the main console and just keep refreshing the page
until it's finished crawling the Aurora database.
And you can see now that it shows a status of 3 minutes elapsed,
and now you can see that the status is stopping.
The crawler status now says Ready, which means it's complete,
and if you read the message, it says 23 tables were created,
0 tables were updated, and right from here,
you can click on the sakiladb database link in the message,
which is a shortcut versus using the links in the left menu.
So let's click on it.
And look at that, we have data.
Toto, I don't think we're in Kansas anymore.
So we have the 23 tables in our sakila database right now,
which are the same tables that we saw when using the third-party SQL client.
The sakila database has the columns of Name of the tables,
the Database that they belong to, the Location,
the Classification, and Last updated, as well as a column for Deprecated.
The classification for all these tables are MySQL because they all came
from the Amazon Aurora MySQL relational database.
Let's click on one of these to view the table details.
When we click on film, we see the details about this particular table,
and notice you can edit the table from here,
delete the table, view properties, and edit the schema.
The main window is composed of separate sections,
it shows various properties, various statistics,
and it shows the schema of the table.
Now if any of these had nested tables underneath them,
it would be a link, and you could click on it to see the nested table.
Notice here you can View the properties of this particular table,
let's click on it.
In the Properties popup that comes up,
notice that it has the name of every column in the table,
it also has the location, the format, any SerDes,
and it used a default SerDes because we didn't specify one,
it has information about parameters and about the crawlers,
classification, and the type of table.
Now that we have our first entry into the Glue Data Catalog,
it's time to run our Glue job to perform ETL transformations.
Click on Jobs in the left Glue menu,
and when you see our GlueStack-aurora-etljob,
click on the checkbox next to its row.
From the Actions drop-down, choose Run job.
From here, you can choose to add more properties before the job is run,
but I'm just going to choose Run job.
You can see the message that reads the GlueStack-aurora-etljob is running.
Check the checkbox next to the job name again,
and you can see that this job has a status of Running.
Notice currently that it's running, and so far its Execution time is 16 seconds.
Keep clicking the Refresh button from time to time,
and right now the job Run status is Succeeded.
Let's look at the Amazon CloudWatch logs for this job run.
Look at all the free CloudWatch metrics that you get when you run AWS Glue jobs.
Each of these are expandable with more information,
and you can filter through here by words or by time,
and you can also do a custom filter.
Let's close this and go back to the Glue Console.
Now that the job is done, let's go to the S3 Management Console.
Filter by Date created,
and navigate to whatever the name was that you input into the
GlueStack as the S3 destination target bucket for the job to
put the processed data into.
Click on it.
What you're looking at are all of the partitions that the Glue ETL job created,
and notice they all have snappy compression,
and they're all in Parquet format.
So what we need to do now is create another crawler to crawl this target
data source and put the results in the Glue Data Catalog. In the next section, I'll summarize exactly what happened in this demo.