This section is about using partitions in Amazon Athena.
When you partition your data, what happens is the following,
the data files are separated by any column.
A common column to use for partitioning is by date.
The query only reads the data that it needs, drastically reducing query time.
In comparison to relational databases,
where a query has to iterate over all rows to find something small,
using partitions dramatically reduces the amount of data scanned,
and thus reduces cost.
Partitions are defined when you create tables.
Partitions can be thought of as virtual columns,
and partitioning works on both text and columnar data.
The table on this slide compares query runtimes between a
partitioned and a non-partitioned table.
Both tables contain 74 GB of data in an uncompressed text format.
The partition table is partitioned by the l_shipdate column,
and it has 2526 partitions.
Look at the amount of data scanned in the non-partitioned
table versus the partitioned table.
The runtime of partition data versus non-partitioned data resulted in
being 73 to 77% faster with a cost savings of 98 to 99%,
hence the importance of partitioning your data.
There are two scenarios for Athena partitions.
If the data is already partitioned in S3,
like you see in the top CREATE EXTERNAL TABLE statement,
the S3 location that is in the CREATE statement terminated with a backslash,
then Athena finds the partitioning using equal signs like you see in the
bottom of the top CREATE EXTERNAL TABLE statement.
When you give a DDL statement with the location of the parent folder,
the schema, and the name of the partitioned column,
Athena can query data in those subfolders.
If the data isn't partitioned in S3 like you see in the lower CREATE
EXTERNAL TABLE statement to partition the data,
you'd have to use ALTER_TABLE_ADD_PARTITION to add each partition manually,
then run the MSCK REPAIR_TABLE_COMMAND To detect partitions
and the data associated with the partitions.
In the next section, I'll cover monitoring and tracing Amazon Athena's ephemeral data.