Serverless architectures are application designs that include custom code,
run and managed ephemeral containers on a Functions as a Service,
or FaaS, platform.
You can't see data when it's working in memory,
so you need to look at write logs and other services
that provide viewing ephemeral data.
Ephemeral data only exists briefly and is transitory.
The data literally only exists in such a brief time that
it's impossible for humans to see.
In addition, ephemeral data are deleted usually immediately.
There are two AWS services and three ways to monitor
and trace Athena's ephemeral data.
You use Amazon CloudWatch for metrics and logs,
and you use Amazon X-Ray for tracing.
Traditionally, even for non-ephemeral data,
getting operational answers from logs is difficult for the
four main reasons you see on this slide.
Amazon CloudWatch makes log analytics easy.
It integrates natively with AWS services and
third-party solutions for ingress and egress.
What if CloudWatch could combine log management with analytics?
Well, I'd say wake me up, I'm dreaming, but it's true.
CloudWatch Logs Insights is an interactive,
fully-integrated,
and pay-as-you-go log analytics service through Amazon CloudWatch.
Amazon CloudWatch Logs Insights are easy to use.
It's a fully-managed interactive log query service.
It's really fast.
Most log queries return in seconds.
It's scalable, and it can ingest petabytes of logs.
It integrates metrics with logs, and you only pay for the log queries you run.
In addition to that,
Amazon CloudWatch Logs Insights is purpose built for log diving.
I just love that term, log diving.
And it has all the features that in the pink
rectangle at the bottom of the slide.
In today's distribute environments and with data that
only exists for milliseconds or less,
tracing all services that work together around the globe can be very difficult.
To properly trace these kinds of environments,
you must be able to discover multiple services,
get insights into individual operations,
see issues that are isolated within each service,
and be able to perform root cause analysis for individual specific issues.
So how does AWS X-Ray help resolve tracing in these
modern distributed applications?
Well there are four reasons shown on this slide,
but AWS X-Ray helps answer three critical questions,
how is my app doing, why is my app performing the way it is,
and who is impacted by the issues?
X-Ray gives you visibility into your downstream AWS services.
With AWS X-Ray,
you can create sub segments for your data access
layer to capture query performance.
You can build visibility into the performance of
database calls using AWS X-Ray APIs.
AWS X-Ray can uncover major flaws in implementations.
Using Amazon CloudWatch and AWS X-Ray together,
you have the insights that answer why unintended behaviors are taking place.
The next module covers how to AI and ML your apps and business processes and how to future proof your data.