So first, let us set up the problem.
Let us see where do those performance issues come from.
Let us consider this code very simple.
We are just creating an instance of the Person class using the classical Java
Reflection API pattern that we covered in a previous module.
How does this code work?
Well, if we deep dive in the code called by those methods,
we will discover this kind of thing.
There are security checks, a SecurityManager is looked for,
and if there is one, we have this checkMemberAccess method that is called.
And then later on, we have more security checks.
Here,
Reflection.ensureMemberAccess that will check if the caller is
allowed to use the Reflection API on the subject.
So every time you are calling a method from the Reflection API,
several security checks are conducted to check if your code is
allowed to access a class using Reflection.
And all those checks are checked again every time an access is made.
So if the same code is calling the same Reflection method again and again,
those security checks will be done again and again
just to return the same result.
This has been spotted quite a long time ago.
All those checks are costly, and they have a noticeable impact on performance.
In fact,
this is the main reason the Java Reflection API is considered as a slow API.
This issue has been spotted a long time ago,
and it took some time to fix it, mainly because security is at stake, and of course, you do not want to give all the rights possible to untrusted code.