What we really want to do is create an EntityManager class
that will receive using depending injection a JDBC
connection to a particular database.
And since this connection is created outside of this EntityManager,
this EntityManager will be able to talk to exchange data back
and forth with any kind of database server.
So on the other hand, we need a connection provider,
an object that will be able to create this JDBC connection.
From a technical point of view, we are going to use a factory method,
createConnection,
and annotate it with this Provides annotation that we are also going to
create that will tell the system that this method,
createConnection,
should be used to create the connection object this EntityManager needs.
So let us see the big picture of the organization of our system.
On one hand,
we have an EntityManager that needs a connection to a database to work.
On the other hand,
we have this ConnectionProvider object that is able
to create a database connection.
The EntityManager does not know anything about this ConnectionProvider,
and of course,
the ConnectionProvider does not know anything neither about this EntityManager.
So those two objects are completely separated.
They can live in two different modules of our application,
but then we need some kind of glue object that will use the
ConnectionProvider to create this database connection and
give it to the EntityManager.
So we need a third object, and we are going to call it a BeanManager,
that will be able to wire those two objects together.
BeanManager is the classical name for this kind of glue object that
is used in both CDI and the Spring framework.
So here is the pattern of code we are going to use.
First, we need to create this BeanManager.
We can do that using a factory method or any kind of method.
And then we are going to ask this BeanManager to create
an instance of EntityManager for us.
This BeanManager will instantiate this EntityManager the
ConnectionProvider and will inject the ConnectionProvider in
the write field of this EntityManager.
The BeanManager needs to create the connection object.
For that,
it needs to locate the write factory method annotated with the
@Provides annotation we also need to create,
but we know how to do that.
And then it will need to invoke that method to create the connection object.
So it needs to invoke a method using the Reflection API.
And this is a technical point we haven't covered yet,
so we are going to see that in a few minutes.
Once it will have created this database connection object,
it will need to set it to the EntityManager in the write field,
annotated with this @Inject annotation.
This is just setting a field to a given value, and we saw that in the previous modules.