How can you invoke a method using the Reflection API?
This is the last technical point we need to cover.
So let us take an example, this ConnectionProvider class.
It has a single method, createConnection,
that takes a uri String of characters as a parameter,
and that returns a connection object.
This createConnection method is an instance method
of the ConnectionProvider class.
It is not static,
so we need to invocate on an instance of this ConnectionProvider class.
First, we need to get the reference on this ConnectionProvider class,
and we covered that in the previous modules of this course.
Then we need to create an instance of this class using this
pattern that we covered in the previous modules.
Clss.getConstructor returns a reference on the empty
constructor on the ConnectionProvider class and
getInstance just invokes that constructor,
thus, returning an instance.
And then this is the new pattern.
We need to get a reference and a particular method
of the ConnectionProvider class.
For that, we call the getMethod on this class object,
pass the name of the method as a string of characters as a parameter.
And since a given method may be overloaded in a class,
you need to tell the getMethod which overload you need.
And for that,
you need to provide the set of parameters that this method is taking.
So here, you are interested in a method that takes just a string as a parameter,
so you just pass String.class as a parameter.
Invoking this method is done through the use of the invoke method.
This invoke method works as the set value or get
value method of the field class.
It first takes the object on which you want to invoke that method and
then the parameters you need to pass to that method.
So here,
we pass this ConnectionProvider object and then the uri of the
database we want to create a connection to.
In case this createConnection method is static,
the first argument of this invoke method is just null since you do
not need any object to invoke a static method. So this is the pattern we are going to use to create the connection.