But then there is a question.
What about the fact that the name field that we are setting is private?
If you are outside of the Person class,
you do not have access to the private elements of that class.
So the question is, is the Reflection API breaking encapsulation?
Is it giving you access to the private members of a class,
and in that way, bypassing all the security checks that can be done by the JVM.
In fact, the answer is a little subtle and is a yes and no.
If the given field is private and you call the previous code just like that,
then you will have an exception which is an
IllegalAccessException just because you are not allowed to read
a private field from outside of the Person class.
So no, the encapsulation is not broken, and yes,
there is a security check if you want to access a private
member to a class using Reflection.
But you have a method on the Field class, which is called setAccessible.
And if you pass true to this method,
you will not have this IllegalAccessException anymore.
Now the reason for that is a little subtle,
calling setAccessible true does not make a private field public.
If you call the getModifiers on that field and you
check if this field is private, indeed, it is still private.
What the setAccessible true call really does is that it
suppresses the access control on that field.
And if you do not want that,
if you want to prevent this kind of thing in your application,
you can set a security manager and configure it to prevent
people to be able to do this kind of thing.
So yes, there is still a security check,
and no, this API does not completely break encapsulation.
It just gives you a control access to the private
members of a class if you need it.
So what we need to do in the previous pattern is just add
this field.setAccessible true here, thus,
making possible to set the value to this private
field from outside the Person class.
And by the way, the same goes for the read pattern.
You have a field.getValue method pass the instance of the person as a parameter,
and it is going to read that field, that name field, and return the value of that field in an object that you can cast to a string.