Now that you have a method handle properly constructed on the field,
a method, or a constructor, how can you use it?
How can you use it to invoke a method or read a field?
This is what you are going to see now.
Invoking a method using a method handle is,
in fact, the same kind of thing as with an instance of method.
It uses the invoke method.
The first argument is the object on which you want to invoke that method,
the object that holds the invoke method,
and the following arguments, if any,
are just the arguments that this method is taking.
This method may take no argument, so in this case,
you will not add any argument to this invoke method call.
Let us see the patterns.
Suppose we have a Person class with a property name,
which is a string; private field name; and public method,
getName and setName.
First,
this MethodHandle is the MethodHandle on the getter method of this Person class.
So we can just invoke this method calling nameGetter.invoke,
pass the person as a parameter, and since the getter does not take any parameter,
it will return the name of that person by invoking the getName method.
And we can do the same with the nameSetter MethodHandle created
on the setName method of this Person class.
We invoke it by passing the person as the first parameter and the value, John, for instance, and a second parameter.