Hello, my name is Jose.
I'm a Java Champion and Java Rockstar.
I'm talking to you from Paris, and I'm very excited to present my new course,
Java Fundamentals: The Java Reflection API and Method Handles.
This course shows you how to discover the structure of classes at
runtime without knowing them at compile time.
You will learn how to create objects; how to set up their fields,
even private fields; how to invoke their methods; how to use annotations to add
metadata on class elements; and how to read them at runtime.
Method handles are also covered for improved performances.
I organized this course around two very important real-life use cases.
First,
you will create a simple object relational mapper on the model of Hibernate,
and second, a spring-like dependency injection framework.
Before you move on, be sure to be familiar with all these,
the Java language, a little bit of lambdas,
and the basics of SQL databases and JDBC.
The Reflection API is not an easy topic.
It is very technical.
And I can't wait to see the awesome tools and applications you will be writing after following this course.