Now we need to handle the rest of the fields,
and that is the field name and age in the case of our Person class.
We are going to need to iterate over the remaining columns.
So let us do it in that way.
We're going to create an index, a columnIndex,
starting from 0 up to the number of columns we need to handle.
Let me increment this columnIndex.
So we need to get the corresponding ColumnField.
This is the ColumnField.
We can query the metamodels to have that get columnIndex,
and the remaining of the pattern is kind of the same as
the pattern we used for the PrimaryKey.
So first, we need the type of this columnField.
Let us put this in a variable.
This is our fieldType, and of course, we need to get the field itself.
We have not created this method, so let me create it quickly.
This is just a getter on the field columnField.getField.
Let me put this in a variable,
and we are going to read that field using the Reflection API.
So since this is most probably a private field, I'm going to make it accessible.
And now I am going to read the value of that field for
the object we have as a parameter.
So field.get, pass the t object as a parameter, put this in a new variable.
This is the field value.
This get method is going to throw some more exceptions,
IllegalArgument, IllegalAccess.
And now that we have the type and the value,
we need to have an equivalent pattern as the one we used for the PrimaryKey.
That is,
we need to check the type of the field and call the
Write method from the statement object.
So if this fieldType is int,
which is the case for the age; then we want to call
statement.setInt ; pass the parameterIndex,
we are going to talk about it in a minute; and the value of the field,
which is value.
Now as we saw, the parameterIndexes for the PreparedStatement start with 1,
and the value 1 correspond to the PrimaryKey.
So the set of the columns starts at the parameter 2,
so here, we need to put columnIndex + 2.
And this setInt call corresponds to the age field of our Person object.
We also have a string field, so let us add else if fieldType == String.class,
and here,
I'm going to copy/paste this statement because the method I
need to call is the setString method.
I need to cast the value to an int.
Here, I need to cast the value to a String so that the code can compile properly.
And if you want to write a complete system,
then for the different columns,
you need to handle all the types recognized by this PreparedStatement object,
and all the types are all the primitive types,
the string type, and the different date types.
And now what we need to return is this statement object.
So here in the calling code,
we now have the proper statement object fully created with the right
SQL query and the parameters set as they need to be.
We need to throw some exceptions, IllegalArgument,
IllegalAccess, SQL, and of course,
we need to copy/paste this throws statement in the corresponding
method of the interface for things to compile properly.
Now our persist method is compiling properly,
the writing object here does not compile because we
need to add throws declaration,
and I'm going to throw exceptions here because I'm not interested in those exceptions, and this code should be able to run properly.