And now is the time to wrap up this module.
What did you learn in this module?
You saw the second most important Application of the Java Reflection API,
which is dependency injection.
You saw how to create objects using Reflection and the user factory method,
and you saw how to inject them as dependencies in other objects.
This is how all the dependency injection frameworks basically work,
Spring, CDI, Guice, just to name a few.
Of course those frameworks are doing much more sophisticated things,
but at the basis of it,
there is this dependency injection mechanism that
can be implemented in that way.
Well, that's it for this module.
Thank you for watching it.
I hope you found it interesting.
We have one last point to cover, very important, which talks about performances.
Starting with Java 7, we have a new API to conduct Reflection in the JDK,
which is called method handles.
Much more technical, but also, much more efficient.
So I hope to see you in the next and last module of this course about method handles.