Okay, now that's it for this module.
Let us make a quick wrap up.
So what did you learn in this module?
First,
you learned how to add annotations to fields and how to
create your own custom annotations.
This is a very powerful tool of the JDK,
and you should be using it in your application if you need it.
Then you saw how to read and write fields using the Reflection API and how to
filter those fields using the annotations you have created.
Now that you saw how to create this metamodel,
how to use it to annotate your JavaBeans,
and how to use the Reflection API to get this information,
I think it is time to try to write those objects to a database.
This is what you are going to see in the next module of this course, and I hope to meet you there in a minute.