Time to see all this in action.
Let us jump into the live coding part of this module.
What are you going to see in this part?
Well, we are going to create MethodHandles and VarHandles on a very simple case.
This MethodHandle API is very technical,
and it's very easy to write code that compiles,
but that does not execute properly.
So let us do that.
Let us see those patterns in action.
Let us now see this MethodHandle API in action,
and for that,
I have created another Person class here with two classical properties,
name and age, to constructor, the of method,
a toString method.
First thing I would like to show you is how to get this lookup object,
which is the entry point of this API.
This lookup object is just created like that, MethodHandles.Lookup.
Let me fix the import.
And this lookup object is the object that you want
to use all throughout this API.
Let us first create an instance of the Person class using MethodHandle.
For that, we need to create the MethodHandle on this empty constructor,
take this lookupmobject, call the findConstructor method on it.
The first argument is the class, so Person class,
and the second argument is a special object called a MethodType,
and we are going to call it emptyConstructorMethodtype.
We need to create this object.
We need to import this Person class.
Creating a MethodType is done through the user
factory method MethodType.methodType.
By convention, the constructor is set to return nothing.
So here,
we are going to pass as the first parameter void.class since the first
parameter of this MethodType factory method is the return type of the
method we want to get a reference on.
And since this is the empty constructor, it does not take any parameter.
This findConstructor will return a MethodHandle.
Let us call it emptyConstructor and just invocate emptyConstructor.invoke.
It doesn't take any argument and should return a
Person object that we need to cast, of course,
since this method, in fact, returns a plain object.
Let us print out the result,
and we can see that indeed we have created an empty instance of Person.
We can get a reference on the other constructor of
this class that takes a Person class, and this time,
we are going to change the MethodType we would be getting.
This is the constructor MethodType,
and the other constructor we created in the Person class takes
a string as a parameter and an int to change the MethodType to
match this other constructor.
And let me do the same here, create a second instance of person,
but this time calling the regular constructor,
passing James as the parameter and then age.
Let us say, 28.
Let us run this code, and this time,
we have invoked the other constructor of the Person class.
You need to be extra careful because if you put void with a capital V here,
it will also compile, but it will not work.
Here, the MethodHandle API will complain,
telling you that it does not recognize this MethodType as
the right MethodType you want to put. So the type we want to use here is the void with a small v and not a capital V.