Now what is going to happen if we want to create a MethodHandle
directly on the field name of this Person class?
Since the field is private, it should not work,
and we are going to see the exception we are going to get.
So the pattern is lookup findGetter,
and remember that this findGetter method name is a little confusing because
you may think that it returns a MethodHandle on the method,
and it's not the case.
It returns a MethodHandle directly on the field.
This field is defined on the Person class.
The name of the field is name, and the type of the field is String.class.
This is a MethodHandle, and I'm going to call it nameReader.
Now if I invoke nameReader on p2 expecting to get Linda as the return object,
so String name2 =, and I need to cast this to a string,
let me print out name2, you see that I've got an exception,
and this exception tells us that the member is private,
Person.name, and that we cannot read it using this reader.
MethodHandle does not give you access to the private members of a class.
It only gives you access to the public members of the class.
If you want to access the private members of a class,
you need another lookup object here.
We are going to create it using the pattern MethodHandles.privateLookupIn
Person class and pass the lookup object we already have.
This is going to give us a private lookup object.
Let me get rid of this In.
Invoke now this findGetter method using this privateLookup object.
And if I run this code,
you will see that indeed the nameReader is now able to
read the private fields of my class.
We can do a little checking.
We are going to add in this getName method here a message
just to check when is this method call.
Here, Get name invoked.
Let us just add this simple message and run this code again,
and you can see that indeed when I am invoking the getName method,
the message is displayed.
But through this nameReader object,
which is a MethodHandle on the field and not on the method,
then the method is not invoked.
It is really the direct read of the field that is done.
So here are the basic pattern of this MethodHandle API.
There's just one thing that may be confusing in this API,
every access you can get on any class element,
whether it is a field, a method, or constructor,
are done through this MethodHandle object.
Everything you get is a MethodHandle,
and you do not have any difference between a field,
a method, or whatever from a class.
This may be confusing,
so you need to be really extra careful when you manipulate this kind of
object because the type of the object you manipulate does not tell you what kind of element from a class you are really handling.