And now we need to do the same for the rest of the columns,
so let us use this pattern to generate a forEach loop.
We need to iterate over the metamodel.getColumns,
and the object returned is the ColumnField,
and we are going to call it ColumnField.
This is fine.
From this ColumnField, we can get the field directly.
This is how we created our metamodel.
This is the corresponding field of our object.
We need the type, so the columnField.getType.
This is the type, and we are going to call it columnType.
And we also need the name, columnField.getName, and this is the columnName.
Now here, we have two types of column,
integer for the age and string for the name.
So if the columnType is equal to int, then we are going to do something,
and if it is equal to String, then we are going to do something else.
I think that in both cases, we are going to need to set this field as accessible.
So let me put this code here.
Here,
the value of the field would be the resultSet.getInt and
pass the columnName as a parameter.
And in that case, it's going to be a String,
resultSet.getString of the columnName.
And in both cases, we are going to call field.set,
pass the object t as a parameter, and the value we just checked.
Now let me copy/paste this code here again.
So here, we are just handling two types of columnType, int and String.
If you have more types, of course, you will need to add some more code here.
And once this is done, we can return the object t,
which has been created as expected.
So, of course, this is not compiling properly because of the missing exception.
So let me add them in a declaration; the SQLException that we need
to add in the EntityManager there; and the buildInstance is going to
add a nice collection of exceptions, Instantiation,
IllegalAccess, IllegalArgument, InvocationTarget,
NoSuchMethod, and Security.
Let me just copy/paste this exception's declaration and paste it to
the interface just for the compiler to be happy.
So now, if we check the reading object here,
we should be able to read our object back from the base automatically.
I'm just going to copy/paste this code to display the people we have read,
go back to the H2 console, check that we indeed have the people in the base,
disconnect, run this code.
We were able to read back the objects from our database showing that our code is working properly.