The metamodel we have created so far works in a way where a given
field is mapped to a column of the same name.
If the field is id, then the column has to be id.
Let us change that and update our annotations in a way where I can pass
the name attributes here telling that this column,
for instance, should be named k_id, and this column should be named c_name,
for instance, and this one c_age.
It is possible indeed to attributes to annotations.
Adding attributes to an annotation is just a matter of adding an
abstract method in the corresponding interface.
Let us do that.
And now you can see that my primaryKey annotation is working correctly.
Let us do the same with this Column annotation.
Copy/paste the name method, and that's it.
Now how can we leverage this attribute?
Well, we have this getName method in the PrimaryKeyField class,
and, in fact,
this getName method should probably read the name
attribute from the corresponding annotation.
So let us add a field here, a PrimaryKeyField.
Let us call it PrimaryKey,
and this getName method should instead return primaryKey.name,
thus, reading the name from the annotation we are reading.
And of course, we can add this field, .getAnnotation PrimaryKey.class,
and this is going to be the primaryKey.
Let us do the same in the ColumnField.
Add a field of type Column.
Let us call it Column.
This field can be read directly from the field that is
passed to create this ColumnField object,
get Annotation, Column.
And now this getName method, instead of returning the field,
is going to return the column.name attribute that
has been set in the Person class.
So we now have a Person class supposed to be mapped to a Person
table in our database with the field k_id,
c_name, and c_age.
So let us create the corresponding table.
Connect to the H2 server, create table Person.
The name of the primary key is k_id.
We have c_age, which is an int, and c_name, which is varchar, let's say, 40.
Let us execute this code, and now the Person table has been recreated.
Let us see the content.
Of course, this table is empty.
Let us disconnect, run our WritingObjects once again,
and this code does not need to be change because,
in fact, the name of the column is read dynamically from the metamodel.
Let us run this code.
And indeed,
you can see that the four people we have created have
been properly returned to the database.
Let us check the content of the table,
and here are our four people written in the proper columns of the database.
Let us disconnect from here and test now the reading of those objects.
Once again, this code should not change, so let us run it.
And indeed, you can see that those people can be read back in the same way.
So this is one way of extending the system,
adding more metainformation in the annotations that can be read at
runtime by the metamodel and leveraged to add more functionalities to our basic object relational mapper.