You might think, hey,
cool, I'll just run both versions in a single code base and
annotate my methods with version headers.
There's just one catch.
Let's take a look at an entity class. With Spring Data, we don't have
to define every single method. By convention, Spring manages all of
those methods for us so we don't have to write and maintain all of the
CRUD methods for our objects.
Unfortunately,
there isn't a property like basePath that we can just define to
introduce custom headers, so you could break out everything and add
the header annotations yourself; however,
that's a lot of extra code to write and maintain, and isn't that why
we're using Spring Data REST in the first place, so we don't have to
write and maintain all of that boilerplate code? If you want to utilize a
custom header to determine which version of your API to run, the best way
to do that without giving up the simplicity of Spring Data REST is to let
your load balancer or proxy server handle it. Like we did in the previous
module, you can branch your code and build two different versions,
one for version 1 and one for version 2.
You'll then deploy those behind a load balancer, but instead of
checking the URI path for version information,
you'll define a rule to look for whatever custom HTTP header you
define and route calls based on the defined values you have set.
Using a custom header allows you to keep versioning information
out of the URI; however,
your clients will need to send the header information so that they get routed to the proper version.