In this section of the course we will learn about CSSA special effects now special effects is not an
official name.
I just made it up.
We could also call this section of the course non essential CSSA properties.
In this particular lesson we will learn about Bach's shadow.
So earlier in the course we learned how to add chateaus to text in this lesson.
We will learn how to add shadows to block level elements like a div or an article.
Here we are in the web browser viewing an example page.
And let's imagine that we want to add shadows to these four blue boxes.
So those elements are divs with a class of box A.
So we can simply tack on new CSSA properties within this rule.
So to add a shadow to an element we can use a properly named box shadow this property except for values
.
The first two values control the positioning of the shadow.
So the very first value controls the horizontal positioning or the horizontal offset of the shadow.
So I wanted to say two pixels from the real content.
The second value controls the vertical positioning or the vertical offset.
So if we include a larger value here the shadow will sit further down from the real content.
The third value controls the blur radius of the shadow.
So if we want the shadow to appear blurred you can include a larger value or if we want the shadow to
be razor sharp we can include 0 or 1 pixel.
So let's include an average value like five pixels.
And finally the fourth value controls the color of the shadow.
So let's begin with a black shadow.
So if I save and refresh we can see that the Shadows have been applied.
Now let's imagine that we actually wanted the shadow to not sit so far down from the original content
and instead be pushed more to the side horizontally.
So we can reduce the vertical offset value to two and we can increase the horizontal offset to 10.
Now by default these offset values push the shadow down into the right.
But if we wanted our shadow to be placed above or to the left of the original content we can use negative
values so negative 10 pixels for the horizontal offset will position the shadow to the left.
And if we use a negative value for the vertical offset it will be placed above the original content
.
However I prefer my chateaus to the bottom right of the content so I will remove these negative values
Now let's adjust the color of the shadow.
So currently we're using a hexadecimal color code but we can also use an RGA color to achieve transparency
with our shadows.
So for example black in RGBA is 0 0 0 and the fourth value control the transparency or the opacity.
So if I set this to point five you can see that the Shadows are transparent.
And if I lower this to point to five the shadows look a bit better.
Now I'm actually going to lower it to perhaps 15 percent or point 15.
Now I think they could afford to be even a bit more subtle but because I want the shadows to clearly
show up in this video recording I will leave them at 15 percent.
Let's change gears and talk a little bit more about the positioning of the shadows.
So we learned that the horizontal and vertical offset can push the shadow to the right or to the bottom
.
If we use negative values to the top or to the left but in all of those scenarios the shadow was always
on the outside of the original content or an outer shadow.
What if we want an inner shadow we can include the word inset within our box shadow value and if we
see even refresh we can see that that pushes the shadow to live within the content.
In design we typically call this an inner shadow.
Now let's imagine we wanted to combine this inner shadow effect with the regular shadow that we had
previously.
Now your first instinct might be to copy this line of code pasted simply remove the word inset but we
can see that that does not work.
So only the external or drop shadow is appearing.
And that's because this declaration comes last in the stylesheet.
So it simply overriding this declaration.
So if we want to combine our two shadows we need to combine them to live within one value or within
one declaration and we can do this with a comma.
So after we've defined this shadow we can include a comma and then let's just copy and paste this exact
same code and then we can apply the word inset to one of them.
So this is one shadow comma.
This is another châteaux.
So if we save and refresh we can see that we now have both shadows and we are free to adjust a particular
shadow and it won't affect the other one.
So they're independent of each other.
So if we want to adjust the inner châteaux to use a smaller horizontal and vertical offset and perhaps
raise the transparency or the opacity a bit we can do just that and it doesn't have any effect on the
external drop shadow.
So feel free to use commas to lay around as many different shadows as you need to create your desired
effect.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson we will learn how to add rounded corners
to our boxes.
I will see you in the next lesson