In this lesson we will learn about CSSA typography typography is the art of arranging type or text so
that it is easy to read and supports the overall design of a project.
By this point in the course you are fairly familiar with CSS we've seen properties like font size and
text align.
So you've had a small taste of manipulating text.
Well in this lesson we will learn about many more tools to style text in the exact way that we want
.
Let's get started in front of you is an example page.
And let's imagine that we want to change the overall font that the page uses.
We know from earlier lessons that we can use the font family property to define a font stack.
If a computer or device does not have the first font that we list it will fall back and use the next
font.
Now a key concept in the font stack is to make sure that the last item in your list is not a font in
and of itself but is instead a keyword.
So if a device does not have a home installed it will use this key word to use whatever system default
Sanskrit font it wants to use.
So one of the most common fonts stacks is to try and use Helvetica.
And if that's not available then we'll use Arial.
And if that's not available then we'll just let the browser use whatever system defaults San Siro font
it wants to use.
So if we save we can see that the web page is now using Helvetica.
Now let's imagine that we didn't want to use censor fonts and we instead wanted to use Sarah fonts.
So our first pick would probably be Georgia.
And if that wasn't available use Times New Roman.
And then if that's not available we'll let the browser choose whatever serifs system default font it
would like.
Now if you do not want to limit yourself to fonts that are installed on someone's device you can use
a technology named APH font face to use any font that you have license to use.
We will cover that in our next lesson.
But for now let's continue reviewing basic types graphy.
Moving on.
We know that we can control the size of text by using the font size property.
Now when it comes to values for this property we have many different units of measurement at our disposal
so we can use percentages or we can use pixels of 17 pixels or we can use keywords so we could say small
or medium.
Now there is no right or wrong method or unit of measurement.
They all have their own strengths and weaknesses but the key concept regardless of which route you choose
is that you define a baseline size on either your body or each human element so that it can trickle
down to every element on your page.
So for example if we set the body element to use 15 pixels we can see that that establishes a baseline
.
So that affects the entire page.
Now if we want it to affect the size of this heading it's an H 2 element in the main call them.
We can simply select that using CSSA.
And then we can provide a multiplier so we can say that relative to the baseline font size we want that
heading level 2 element to be 200 percent and perhaps we decide that paragraph text in the main column
should be just a small bit larger than the baseline so we can target that with this selector.
And then we can say font size 100 an 8 percent.
So just a little bit larger than the baseline.
Now again there is no right or wrong way to size your fonts but the key concept that almost every method
has in common is that you define a baseline size on one of the root elements of the page and then you
multiply or manipulate that baseline size on different elements throughout the page.
That's enough on font size for the moment.
Now let's review other CSSA properties to manage the boldness of text we can use the font weight property
.
So if we didn't want this Heading to be bold we can say bont way normal if we wanted the Heading to
be italic we can use a property named font style and provide a value of italic if we want to control
the space between each individual letter.
We can use a property named letter spacing and then we simply specified how much space we want between
each letter.
So if I say four pixels there is now four pixels of extra space between each letter on a similar note
if we want to control the spacing between each word there is a property named word spacing.
So if I say 10 pixels there's an extra 10 pixels between each word.
If we want to add a shadow to text we can use a property named text shadow this property except for
values.
The first value controls the horizontal offset of the chateau or in other words how far from the left
of the regular text the shadow text should sit the second volume controls the vertical offset of the
shadow.
The third value controls the blur radius.
If we include a zero The text will not be blurred at all.
And the fourth value controls the color of the shadow.
So I will include a hexadecimal color code for a medium grey.
So if we increase this third value the blur radius value to 3 pixels we can see the text is a bit blurred
.
And if we increase this quite a bit it's very blurred.
We can also use a R-GA color instead of a hexadecimal color code.
So I could use the code for black and then set the transparency to 50 percent.
And we can see if we get a similar effect.
Moving on if we wanted this header to use all capital letters without editing the T.
Now we can use a property named text transform and provide a value of uppercase.
The property also accepts a value of a lower case if we want Tex to have an underline we can use a property
named text decoration and provided a value of underline.
However you should not do this because in the context of web browsers and web pages we automatically
assume that underline means something is a link.
So I recommend not adding that to any elements other than links.
However if you wanted to remove the underline from a link we can simply target link elements on the
page and type in text decoration.
None.
And that will remove underlines from an element.
Now let's focus a bit on styling the paragraphs of our page.
We can control the way that text is aligned using the text align property.
So if we say right text will sit to the right center obviously center the text justify will create almost
a newspaper column effect where the text is perfectly spaced per line to create a hard and clean edge
on the right.
And obviously the default value for text line is left.
If you want to indent the beginning of a paragraph you can use a property named text indent.
Actually you can use this on any element not just a paragraph and then specify how much you would like
to end in.
Now I've saved arguably one of the most vital properties for last one of the most important parts of
typography is creating a vertical rhythm and a very important part of vertical rhythm is line spacing
or letting.
This refers to the space between each line of text.
Now in CSSA there is a property named line height.
So I give this a value of 1.5 you can see that there is extra space between each line.
Now obviously we can target individual elements so this rule targeting paragraphs in the main column
.
Or you can target the HVM our body elements so that this will trickle down to your entire page so that
you can establish a baseline line height.
If we include this here now we can see that even in our Sidebar in our heading everywhere the entire
page now has leading or a line height of 1.5.
We want to increase this a bit we can say 1.7.
It's up to you to choose a value that works with your design and will also provide excellent readability
for your users.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson.
We will learn how to not be limited by fonts that are installed on a user's device but instead unbought
the potential to use any font that you have the license to use.
I will see you in the next lesson.