If you've made it to this lesson it's safe to assume that you are now familiar with H.
TNL.
Well congratulations you've made it to the fun part of the Course.
This is where we learn about C S S S S stands for cascading style sheets and it's the way that we add
color and layout and style and design to our web pages.
In other words each TMF is how we describe our content.
CSSA is how we describe our presentation.
That's enough for an introduction.
I'm excited to get started because this is one of the most exciting parts of becoming a web developer
.
Your first taste of CSX.
So in front of you is an example page and let's immediately hop over to our text editor and let's learn
how to attach a bit of CSSA code to a web page.
Now we know that the content for a web page lives within the body element and we know that information
about the page is stored in the head element.
So currently we have the character set and the overall title of the page.
Let's include a new line of code in the head section to attach a bit of CSSA link.
We're going to link to another file with CSSA code will give you an attribute of raúl which stands for
relationship the relationship of what we're linking to is a stylesheet.
Hence the name Cascading Style Sheet.
And then we include an additional attribute named A-Trak.
And this is where we point to where the new CSSA file will live in the same folder as where the web
page lives indexed or HMO.
I'm going to create a new folder to stay organized and I'm going to name this new folder.
SS Now let's create a new file within this new CSSA folder new file in the CSSA folder and you could
name the file anything that you would like.
You just want to make sure that it ends with an extension of dot CSS.
So I'll name it screen.
So we now have a blank CSSA file.
Now back in index that HVM now we want to point to that file inside this Atra if attribute.
So we want to dig into the CSSA for them and then forward slash.
Once we're in the field there and then we'll type the name of the new CSSA file screen CSX.
Now we've successfully added a link to an empty stylesheet.
Let's hop over to that empty style sheet and write our first ever bit of CSSA code.
So we'll give ourselves a goal.
Our goal is that we want this text example Heading to be orange.
So enter a new blank file.
We will write each one curly brackets color orange.
So if I save refresh in the web browser Whyalla we can see the heading is orange.
So let's review the syntax that we just used to make that happen.
This entire bit of code is known as a CSSA rule the siestas rule begins with a selector.
In this case we used H-1 as our selector.
And this is simply letting the web browser know which element we want to select to begin styling.
So we selected the one element which lives here on the web page and it says example heading then within
the curly brackets we can specify how we want to style the element that we selected.
So color is a property and we're giving it a value of orange.
When we combine a property with a value it's known as a declaration and we can have as many declarations
in a siestas rule as we would like.
So if we want to center the text you can say text a line which is the property and then give it a value
of center.
So if I save and refresh I can see that that changes taking place.
Let's give ourselves another goal let's style the paragraph elements on the page to be green.
So that would include this element this element and this element.
So we hop over to our style sheet and we'll create a new rule.
The first step is a selector we want to select the p or paragraph elements.
Open up our curly brackets the properties color and we'll give it a value of green.
So this is our declaration.
We include a colon after the property and a semi-colon after the value.
So I'll save and refresh and we can see that the paragraphs are now green.
That's it for this lesson you've learned a great deal of new material so let's review.
We learned that a style sheet is a simple text file that anyone can create and then we simply link to
it from our HVM file in the head section.
We learn that style sheets are made up of different rules and a rule is made up of a selector and declarations
.
And we learned that a declaration is nothing more than a property and the value in our next lesson we
will learn that there are all sorts of different types of selectors.
So there are different ways to target very specific or unique elements on your page.
So we'll delve into the wide world of selectors in our next lesson and that should be a lot of fun.
I'll see you in the next lesson.