In this lesson we will learn how to create a table of data with HTL.
Let's imagine that we had a grocery list but instead of only keeping track of the name of the item.
Let's imagine that we also wanted to keep track of its price.
What aisle in the store is located on.
And also quantity how many we want of that particular item.
With all of these different details of the grocery items in mind it doesn't make sense to use a simple
bulleted list.
Instead it makes sense to create a table.
So our goal for this lesson is to create a table of our grocery list data so you can become familiar
with table syntax.
Let's get started.
The HTL code to begin creating a table is simply table within the table element.
We then use the TR element which stands for table row to create a row within the table row element.
We can then use TDD for table data to create columns.
So for example our first table data element or our first column will simply say bread.
The next column we will include the aisle that bread is located at in the store.
So we'll say that it's on aisle 2.
And the third column will include the price of bread.
So we will say that it costs $3.
And the fourth column will include the quantity so we only want one loaf of bread.
If I save and refresh in my web browser we can see the beginnings of a table.
All of the data associated with the bread item sits on a single row.
Let's try to add another item milk.
So we would create another row.
Each item receives its own table row and then within that table row element again will create Dee-Dee
elements which stand for table data.
So milk
what Isle's milk on we'll say that it's on aisle one.
How much does milk cost 250.
And we'll say that we want to milk eggs to small cartons of milk.
So if we save and refresh I can see a second row in our table.
It's very easy to track all the data across a single row.
However our table desperately needs some sort of labeling system.
It's not clear to the user what these numbers even stand for throughout the video.
We've mentioned that the first numbers associated with the IO the item is on and that the final number
at the end of the row is the quantity.
But we need a way of labeling that on screen and we can do that by creating a row at the top of the
table with table headers.
So within this table row instead of TD for table data we can create table cells or table columns by
using the th element table header.
So the first column is the item name.
The second column is the aisle that the item can be found on the third column is the price and the fourth
column is the quantity.
So if I save and refresh we can see that our table is now clearly labeled.
So let's review the syntax to create a table you use the very intuitively named table element.
Each row of the table is created by TR which stands for table row.
Within that we create table cells.
There are two types of table cells.
The first that we saw TDE is for data stands for table data.
The second type of table cell is th which stands for table header.
These two types allow us to differentiate between labels or headers and actual data in our table.
Now there are a few additional wrapper elements that will also allow us to differentiate between headers
and data.
It's considered best practice to wrap any header information in the table inside a key head element
.
So I will copy or excuse me cut and paste the row with our table headers into the head element.
It's also a best practice to include all of the tables actual data inside a T body element table body
.
So cut and paste our data rows to sit within the T body element.
Now if I save and refresh in the browser we don't see any visible change by using t head and t body
.
However using these elements is a good idea for two reasons.
Number one it gives us additional hooks to play with later on when we're familiar with CSSA or in other
words when we want to style the table.
And number two it increases the semantic richness of our code.
Before we close out this lesson on each team tables there's one final organizational element that I
want to bring to your attention in addition to t head and t body.
There's also t foot for table footer.
Now even if we placed table footer above table body it will still be displayed in the web browser below
the body content.
So let's create a row in our footer for example.
So within tief foot will create a row and within that row we'll create four columns the name of this
bottom footer row will be all.
So it's all items.
What aisle is it on.
Not applicable.
The next column is the price.
So that's five fifty.
And the fourth column is quantity again that is not applicable.
So now if we save and refresh we can see that the table footer row sits at the bottom even though in
the markup in our HVM melt it sits above the table body.
Now when older versions of HMO you were required to place the table footer above the table body in your
code but in the newest version of HMO it's ok to include the table footer or teep foot at the bottom
of your table.
On a side note this should probably read total instead of all.
So if we save and refresh we can see that nothing changes even though we moved the table footer to sit
at the end of our code that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
But first here's a quick review of the structure of a table at the highest level we have the table element
inside that we have either the T head t body or t foot element inside that we then have a row and then
within that row we have a table cell which is either a piece of data Tedi or a header.
Th or see you in the next lesson