In this lesson we will learn a bit more about C Ss selectors.
Now there are many different types of selectors but the big three that we will cover in this lesson
are type selectors descendant selectors and class selectors.
Let's begin with type selectors.
So here is the example page from our previous lesson and you'll remember that this is the CSSA that
we wrote.
So it turns out you are actually already familiar with type selectors a type selector is simply the
name of an element and it targets every element of that type on the page.
So for example when we created this rule the rule that makes all paragraph green this selector of P
is targeting every element on the page.
It's targeting this paragraph this paragraph and this paragraph.
That's a type selector.
It's the most basic type of selector that there is.
Let's move on to descendant selectors descendant selectors.
Let us tap into the power of the Russians stacking a model that H DML follows the way that elements
nest inside other elements.
So for example what if we only wanted to select or we only wanted the style paragraph elements that
are descendants or in other words that live inside the hetter element.
So if we only wanted to select this paragraph and we only wanted it to be green we could adjust the
selector for this rule to simply say header p.
So if I save and refresh You can see that now only this paragraph element is green.
So let's review how this descendant selector is working.
We start with Hetter.
So the web browser selects this header element then we include a space and P.
So the web browser then looks inside this element for any and all paragraph elements.
Now we can drill like this as many layers deep as we need to.
So let's imagine that we want the word slogan to be blue.
If the word slogan was wrapped in a span tag we could create a new rule in our CSSA file.
So first let's drill into the header element.
Then let's drill into the paragraph element and then we'll finally select the span element.
Color blue.
So if I save and refresh I can see that that word is blue.
So in a sense you can think of the descendant selector almost like a type selector but with a family
tree twist you can include names of ancestor elements until you finally drilled down to the particular
element that you want to style.
So we've seen type selectors we've seen descendant selectors.
Now let's take a look at class selectors.
Now in order to make this example clear I'm going to edit the H DML bit.
Let's imagine that instead of only having one main body paragraph we had at least three.
So copy and paste.
So we now have three paragraphs in the body section and let's imagine that for some reason we want this
second paragraph the middle paragraph to have a yellow background.
So how would we achieve that.
Well we can't use a type selector or a descendant selector because in terms of the HTML. There's nothing
unique about this second paragraph.
There's no way to distinguish it between the first or third paragraph.
So what we can do to target this middle paragraph is give it a class so in the HMO on that element we
can add an attribute named class and then we can give it any name that we'd like.
So I will call this class name highlight this class name is our key to selecting only this paragraph
element.
So in our CSSA we'll create a new rule that uses a class selector.
So in order to target a class you simply type a period and then the name of the class.
So highlight and then we can style it just like we would any other rule.
Background color yellow.
So if we save and refresh we can see that only the second paragraph has received that styling.
Another great thing about creating a class is that we now have this truly reusable block of code so
we can reuse this class anywhere in our h DML that we see fit.
So let's imagine there was a second sentence in the footer.
Let's add that really quickly and let's imagine that second sentence read.
All rights reserved.
If we wanted this new sentence to have a yellow background all we need to do is give it a class of highlight
so we can immediately see how useful it is to create classes that can be re-used.
Are different pages.
Now let's take things one step further.
Let's imagine that we decide if a paragraph or an element has a class of highlight and it's in the main
area of the page.
We want to have a yellow background.
But if a paragraph is in the footer element and has a class of highlight we instead want it to have
a light grey background where we can achieve just that by using a mix of descendant selectors in-class
selectors.
So we'll begin by selecting the footer element and then we'll dig into it and look for any element that
has a class of highlight and then we'll give it a background color of light grey.
So here we can see that we have one class receiving two different styles because of the power of descendant
selectors.
So depending on where that element lives we can stifle the same class differently that's going to conclude
this lesson to review we learned about type selectors which select all elements of a specific type.
On the page we learned about descendant selectors which let us follow a path of ancestry to select a
more particular element.
And finally we learned about class selectors which let us create reusable bits of code that we can apply
to any element.
Now there are far more than just three different types of CSSA selectors but there's no sense in trying
to memorize all of the different ways to select elements in one sitting.
We will learn about new selector methods as they become necessary but for the time being just these
three types will get us quite far in our next lesson we will learn what the word cascade is implying
in the phrase cascading style sheets.
I'll see you in the next lesson