In this lesson we will begin learning about the different types of inputs that are at our disposal when
we are creating forms in an earlier lesson we learned about the input type of text.
So if I save and refresh my browser you can see a basic text input but there's an old saying that when
the only tool you have is a hammer everything begins to look like a nail.
So while the text input definitely has its place it's not the right choice for every type of field.
So let's imagine that we're creating a form and we want to collect the user's email address.
There's a special type for that.
So let's set up a standard form we use the form element let's move our input to sit inside the form
element and remember that we want to have a label associated with any fields so label email need to
associate the label with the input.
So we'll give the label A for attribute of email.
We'll give this input an ID of email.
Now this is the important part for type instead of text.
We can actually include e-mail.
And then let's go ahead and also give the input A name of email.
And finally let's give this form a submit button input type equals submit value equals save.
So if I save and refresh we can see here is a 4.
It's labeled If I click on the label it automatically puts my cursor in this field.
Now if I type something that is not an e-mail address and click save.
Most modern web browsers will automatically try to validate the form data so you can see in Firefox
it's telling me please enter an email address.
This means that if we would have used text as the input type the form would have gladly submitted with
this value in this field.
But because we used the type of e-mail the form knows that there needs to be an email address in this
field or it won't accept the form submission.
Another advantage of using the email input type is that it greatly enhances the user experience for
touch screen users.
So if someone's using a touchscreen device and they tap on this field the on screen keyboard that displays
should include the at symbol in a fairly prominent location because it knows that this is an email input
and you're going to need the at symbol.
So if we contrast that with the onscreen keyboard that is displayed if this was a text field you might
need to click a symbol's button to toggle different onscreen keyboard layout in order to find that symbol
.
So in other words by choosing the correct input type for your field you're making the lives of touchscreen
users a bit simpler.
Now email isn't the only special input type.
Let's take a quick look at another one.
Let's imagine that we wanted to collect a user's telephone number with our form.
So we will include input with the type of tell for telephone.
Let's go ahead and give this input a label telephone.
Give it a four attribute with a value of telephone give the input an ID that matches that telephone
.
And finally let's give this input a name of telephone.
So now if I save and refresh my browser we won't see anything special because I'm using a desktop or
laptop computer.
But if we were using a touch screen device when we tap on this field the on screen keyboard would resemble
that of when you're dialing a telephone number so it would be very easy to enter a phone number.
Now in an effort to keep this lesson from becoming very repetitive I'm not going to go through every
single input type in front of you.
We've seen e-mail we've seen tell for telephone if you're creating a form and it feels like there really
should be a special type for that input.
Odds are there is.
So in the course materials for this lesson I will include a more exhaustive list of all of the different
input types.
But for now let's move on to something a bit different.
Up until this point the only type of field that we've seen is a text box about this size that can receive
a single line of input.
Well what if we want to allow our users to type an entire paragraph.
There's a different field for that.
So let's race this field and let's create a field where our users can type a message instead of input
.
There's an element name text area and unlike input we want to be sure to include the closing tag for
text area.
So let's go ahead and create a label for our textarea your message
give the label a four attribute with a value of your message will give the text area an ID your message
.
Now the text area element does not need a type attribute because it is its own unique element text area
And finally the name will be your message.
So now we save and refresh we can see that there is a much larger box than the traditional text input
that weve seen in earlier examples.
So now users can begin typing their custom message and if they hit enter or return on their keyboard
they can even go down to second and third and fourth and fifth lines.
So the text area element is how we receive a paragraph or actually multiple paragraphs of text and that
will conclude this particular lesson.
Let's review what we've learned.
We learned that there are different input types for receiving different types of data.
So if we're receiving a telephone number we should use a special type for that if we're receiving an
e-mail address we should use a special type for that.
And finally we learned that when we want to receive multiple lines of text we can use the text area
element in our next lesson we will learn that we don't always want our users to manually type in data
.
Sometimes we want them to choose between a pre-determined set of options.
I'll see you in the next lesson.