In this lesson we will learn how to use CSSA to position elements so that they overlap one another to
achieve this.
We will use a property that you have not seen in the course yet its name is position.
And in this lesson we will be learning about position relative and position absolute.
Our goal for this lesson is to recreate what you see in front of you now so we can see that there is
an image and then there is a caption layered on top of the image so we can see that the description
box has a semi-transparent black background and is overlapping the bottom part of the image.
In this lesson we will learn all the code necessary to recreate this from scratch so I'm going to hop
back over to this tab.
This page looked familiar.
And we're going to rewrite the code together in order to create this overlapping effect.
Let's get started.
Here we are in the text editor and the first thing that I'm going to do is simply add the image to the
page image element source will point the browser towards the file.
OK.
So here's the image we can see right away that the image is too wide for this main column.
So what we can do is write a bit of success that targets all images on the page and gives them a maximum
width of 100 percent and then we'll be sure to set the height to Otto.
So with that in place the image will automatically shrink to fit the main column next.
Let's add the paragraph of text that we want to overlap the image create a new paragraph and I'll simply
paste in a bit of text so you don't have to watch me type this out.
So if we refresh in the browser we can see here's the text.
Next let's add a few extra classes and elements in our HTL so that we have more hooks to target in our
CSSA code.
So I want to wrap both the image and the text inside a parent div and we'll give that idea of a class
of image banner
and then the text itself.
I think that should also be in a div so will give this div a class of banner description.
OK so now each team has these two additional hooks to target let's begin writing our SS or create a
comment to stay organized banner overlay.
So the first thing that we want to target is the div with the text and it has a class of bannered description
banner description.
I'm going to use a property that you have not seen until now position and I'm going to give it a value
of absolute.
Let's create another declaration with the property of bottom and we'll give it a value of zero.
Also create a declaration with a property of left and give it a value of zero.
So if I say even refresh pay attention to where this paragraph moves to.
So we can see that the position that this text is in now seems completely random but it's not.
If I scroll up to the very top of the page we can see that this text has positioned itself in the very
bottom left corner of the screen.
Now if I change this from bottom zero to top zero we can see the text moves up to the very top of the
screen.
Now if we wanted the text to sit 50 pixels from the very top we can simply change this from top 0 to
top 50 pixels and if we wanted to get from the left 50 pixels we can change this to left 50 pixels so
we can see the position.
Absolute lets us provide x and y coordinates or horizontal and vertical coordinates to position the
element in a very particular fashion.
However by doing this it also removes the content from the regular flow of the page.
This means that as far as every other element on the page is concerned this content no longer exists
.
So very quickly let's remove this code just to prove a point.
So we saw that by default this text sat underneath the image.
Now as soon as is positioned absolutely.
Watch how this text as soon as I refresh watch this text simply move up as if that text no longer exists
at all.
Now you may be wondering why would I ever use position absolute if it completely removes the content
from the flow of the page.
How is that every useful.
The answer is that nine times out of 10 in order for a position absolute to be useful it needs to be
used in conjunction with position relative.
So for example when we specified that this text should sit 50 pixels from the top and 50 pixels from
the left.
The question that we need to ask ourselves is 50 pixels from the left of what or 50 pixels from the
top of what.
Now by default the browser will use the Web browser window as our frame of reference for the top and
left values.
However an element that uses position absolute will search up its family tree or up its Russian stacking
doll model for the closest ancestor element that uses position relative.
And once it finds that element it will use it as its frame of reference for these values.
So we know that in our HMO there's bannered description element which is what is housing this text.
We know that it has a parent element of image banner.
So if I change image banner to use position relative watch what happens when we refresh this text is
now positioning itself 50 pixels from the top of the image banner and 50 pixels from the left of the
image banner.
Very quickly let's review the HTML structure that makes this possible.
This is the element that's being positioned Absolutely.
It searches up its family tree to find the nearest ancestor with a position relative which happens to
be Image banner.
So it then tries to position itself in relation to image banner.
So you'll remember that we wanted our description to sit at the bottom of the image.
So now it's as simple as changing this to bottom 0 and zero.
So now the text will sit in the bottom left corner of the image.
Now that our description text is positioned correctly.
Let's focus on styling it.
So you will remember that we wanted a semi transparent black background and we wanted the text to be
white.
So let's go ahead and give the text a color of white and let's begin by making the background black
.
So this is simply enough.
But we wanted a semi transparent black background.
Now up until this point in the course all of the colors that you've seen have been hexadecimal color
codes which means typically six characters and that is preceded by the pound sign.
However in order to get a semi transparent color we're going to use something named R.G. colors.
So the letters here stand for red green blue and alpha alpha.
In this context refers to Alpha transparency.
Now in the world of color theory we know that we can create any color by combining different amounts
of red green and blue.
So let's imagine that we wanted this text to have a completely not transparent red background or GBH
except for values.
The first is obviously are for red.
Now we can enter anywhere between 0 and 255 to decide how much red we want to mix into the color.
So we wanted to be completely red 2:55 is the highest value.
We don't want any green.
We don't want any blue and a for Alpha transparency.
We don't want it to be transparent at all.
So we enter 1 0.
It's completely transparent or invisible.
So this creates pure red.
Now if we wanted halfway transparent red we would change the A or alpha value to point five and if we
decided that's a bit too transparent we can simply bump this value up to perhaps point six 5.
So we can see the Reds a bit darker now and it's a bit harder to see through.
However we didn't want red We wanted a semi-transparent black background so to create black you simply
don't mix in any color.
So we've zeroed out red green and blue and we can see we now have a semi transparent black background
.
Our styling work is almost complete.
Now let's add a bit of padding around the text.
So within this same banner prescription rule will add padding.
Let's give it 15 pixels vertically and 25 pixels horizontally.
That looks a lot better.
Now there's one minor thing that I want to fix.
If we look very closely we can see that the bottom of our text box is not lining up perfectly with the
bottom of the image.
Our text box is about two or three pixels too low.
The reason this is happening is because the overall height of our image banner parent element is being
determined obviously by the size of the image and by default images are inline elements.
So this means when the browser tries to calculate the height it can use things like font size and line
height values and it's not as precise.
So we really want this image to be a block level element.
So in our CSS I'm going to target any image elements that live within image banner and then I will simply
tell them to be block level.
So if we refresh can see that the two elements are now perfectly aligned.
This means our goal for the lesson is complete.
We've stifled the elements however before I end the lesson there's a few more notes on position relative
that I want to share with you.
We learned that with elements that used position absolute we can provide a horizontal and vertical offset
position in the element.
Now we can do the same thing with elements that use position relative.
So if we say top 10 pixels left 10 pixels on our image banner container element we can see that it moves
down into the left 10 pixels.
So if an element uses position relative its frame of reference is it self or in other words this line
of code is saying position the element 10 pixels from the top of where it would normally sit.
And this can be incredibly useful because it allows us to manipulate the position of an element without
removing it from the natural flow of the page.
So for example let's remove these so the image box sits where it normally would.
And let's see if we want to push the image to the left by 40 pixels.
You can simply say left negative 40 pixels and there you have it.
Notice that it did not take the element out of the flow of the page.
This paragraph that sits below it is still acknowledging and respecting the space.
This element takes up.
However even though the other elements on the page are aware of this content they are not aware of its
offsets.
So for example if we give this Elman a top offset of 60 pixels you can see that it is now overlapping
this text.
So this paragraph of text does not know to move down 60 pixels to accommodate the offset of our image
box.
So let's go ahead and remove these two offsets so the image box sits where it normally would.
So we've learned that you can use offsets on position relative elements when you don't want to rock
the boat when you don't want to affect literally any other element on the page.
Now there is one final topic related to position relative that I want to discuss before closing out
the video.
And that is the battle of the overlaps.
So for example if elements have been positioned in a way that they are overlapping each other how do
we decide which element sits on top of the other or in other words which element is visible.
So very quickly let's experiment let's push our image box to the left by a hundred pixels so we can
see it now overlaps the sidebar.
Now the image box is on top of the sidebar because it's using position relative.
However if the sidebar was also using position relative
we will see that it's now on top because it comes later in the HTL.
Now here is our image box.
If we scroll down here the sidebar.
So the rule of thumb is if both elements are using position relative or position absolute whichever
element comes later in your HMO will be layered on top.
Now there is a way to override that behavior.
So even though sidebar comes last in the HVM Now if we wanted our image box to overlap the sidebar we
can use a property named z index.
So on the image Bynner element I will add a property named z index and I will give it a value of 10
.
We can see that this places the image box on top z index is essentially the stacking order of an element
whichever element has the larger z index value will be placed on top of the other element.
So if we went to our Sidebar and gave it a z index of 11 it would stack on top.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
There was a lot of material in this lesson.
So here's a quick review.
Position.
Absolute lets you remove an element from the natural flow of the page and instead position it in relation
to an ancestor element absolutely positioned elements will look for the closest ancestor element that
uses position relative and it will use that element as its frame of reference.
If the absolutely positioned element does not have any ancestors which use position relative it will
use the Web browser window as a whole as its frame of reference if multiple elements are overlapping
each other and you want to have fine grained control over which element stacks on top of the other.
You can use the z index property to establish a stacking order.
I will see you in the next lesson.