In this lesson we will learn about responsive web design when we say that a Web site is responsive.
It simply means that the Web site responds or adapts to the size and characteristics of the device that
is viewing the page.
So for example a responsive web site may use a to call them lay out if someone's using a traditional
desktop or laptop computer to view the page.
But if someone viewed the exact same web page using a small smartphone they would see a different layout
the page would reflowed to fit the smaller screen.
So things would collapse down to a single column perhaps the navigation menu would adjust.
Now in the modern era we are so accustomed to seeing Responsive Web sites that I think it might actually
be easier to explain responsive web design by showing you an example of a Web site that is not responsive
.
So let's imagine that we designed a web site with laptops and desktop computers in mind.
Now if we did not code the page to be responsive if we viewed the exact same page on our smartphone
the text would be so small that it would be impossible to read and we would have to do the annoying
task of pinch zooming in to read specific portions of the page and then scrolling in and pinch zooming
and repaint zooming.
I'm sure that you've come across websites like this before and I will assume that you did not find the
experience very enjoyable.
Most users if given the choice between a not responsive web site and a responsive web site will definitely
choose the responsive route.
It's much more usable for smaller screens.
Now for the remainder of this lesson we are going to roll up our sleeves and learn how to take a standard
web page and make it responsive so that it will work flawlessly for any sized device under the sun.
Let's get started.
Our recipe for a responsive website has only two ingredients at its core.
The first ingredient is a metal tag that we will add to the head section of our HTML code.
And the second ingredient is known as media queries which is a fancy way of saying that we can tell
our CSSA to only run in certain scenarios or for certain screen sizes.
So let's begin with the first ingredient in our recipe.
The metal tag.
Let's hop over to our text editor and edit the HTL now.
So here's the head section of our page.
We're going to create a new line.
Mehta Now the metal tag that we're interested in is named viewport viewport.
Refer to the Web browser window area the part of the screen that scrolls with web site content.
Now we are interested in adjusting the width of the viewport.
We want devices to be true to themselves.
So for example certain smartphones will try and pretend like they're bigger than they really are and
that's what creates the horrible situation where you visit a Web site on your smartphone and everything's
very zoomed out and microscopic.
And you have to pinch zoom in to read the text.
If a particular smartphone is only 320 pixels wide we don't want it to pretend that it's 960 pixels
wide by artificially scaling and zooming out.
We want it to truly act and behave as if it is only 320 pixels wide.
Be true to itself and then we as web designers can adjust our CSSA to fit the content to work within
that 320 pixels of width.
So our code is basically saying the width of the viewport should be equal to the device with the width
of the device and we can go one step further and say that the initial scale should be 1.
So when the device first loads our website it won't need to zoom out.
It won't need to zoom in.
It can simply use its natural size and its natural scale.
So to review this line of code is telling devices that they don't need to adapt to the Web site.
And instead it's putting the responsibility back on the Web site.
The Web site needs to respond and adapt to the size of the device.
Now let's head back over to our recipe.
We've taken care of our first ingredient the viewport with the metal tag and now the devices are using
their true screen size.
We've created an issue for ourselves that can only be solved by ingredient number two so for instance
here is our example lay out and this is how it appears on a laptop or a traditional desktop computer
.
And this is how it would have appeared on a smartphone if our Web site wasn't responsive.
The phone would have tried to zoom in scale out to fit this layout but because we told devices to use
their true screen size this is what the average smartphone user would see.
You will recall from earlier lessons that we use CSSA to create a to call them lay out our main column
should take up 66 percent of the width and our Sidebar should take up 34 percent of the width.
Now the arithmetic looks correct but it just doesn't work on such a small screen size a screen this
small should only use one column so the green side bar area should simply stack below the main column
area and both sections should use the full available width of the device.
However we don't want to sacrifice our to call them layout for devices that are large enough to display
it in an elegant fashion.
So we need a way to send different CSSA instructions to different sized devices and that is precisely
what media queries allow us to do.
Now let's not waste any time.
We're going to hop straight into the text editor.
This is a CSSA file.
And let's see our first media query in action at symbol media screen and parentheses Max with seven
hundred pixels.
Now any code that we placed between this curly bracket and this curly bracket will only be applied to
the page if the browser window is no larger than 700 pixels.
So this is our chance to send different style instructions to smaller screens so we establish that we
don't want 2 columns for small screens.
So we want to override these width and float properties for main area in sidebar.
So within our curly brackets for the media query we can simply say main area and sidebar.
So we're selecting those two HDMI elements and we're going to save width should be audio which will
use the full available width and for the float property.
None.
We don't want them to be floated.
Now if we save and refresh we can see there are two column layout it's still intact for larger screens
but if I start resizing my browser window once we cross the threshold of 700 pixels we will see these
properties take effect.
So I'm continuing to resize my browser and we hit the 700 pixel threshold and we can see that we now
have a single column layout and it looks like there's a bit of extra space on the right side of the
main column area that's coming from this padding right property.
So let's override that within our immediate query will select just the main area padding right.
Zero.
We can see that the main column now takes up the appropriate width.
So our layout looks great.
If a device is 700 pixels wide or in other words a small tablet.
But what if someone was using a smartphone.
When we're dealing with the screen this small the first thing that I want to address is the main horizontal
margins.
This is too large and that spacing is coming from the container divs that we have for each section.
Now in our C Ss we have told the divide the class of container to have 40 pixels of padding on the left
and right.
However for smaller screens we don't want that.
So even though that size works for a 700 pixel wide device it doesn't work for smartphones.
So we can simply create a media query media screen and Max with now instead of providing a threshold
of 700.
We can say Macs with 480 pixels and then any code between these two curly brackets will only be applied
if the device is 480 pixels wide or smaller.
So within this media query we can select the container class and say padding left should only be 20
pixels padding right should only be 20 pixels.
So we're overriding the value of 40 and setting it to 20.
So if I refresh we can see that the new margin's free up more space for the content.
Next let's reduce the vertical space that we see here.
I think that much space works for a larger device but once we get down to the mobile level it's too
much.
Now that speccing is coming from the content area div and we've told that to have 40 pixels of top padding
so we can create a media query to override that media screen and Max width we'll continue to use the
480 threshold will select the same class and then will simply override this value.
Padding top let's say 20 instead of 40 pixels much better.
So we would just add certain values for smaller screens.
What if there's content that we don't want to display at all.
For smaller screens to for example this yellow box reads this content is not absolutely vital and does
not need to display on mobile devices.
We can set up a media query to hide this content for smaller screens to enter h TNL we can see that
that content comes from this code.
It's a div with a class of info box.
Now we want to keep that styling intact for larger screens and larger devices but I'm going to add on
an additional class to this div named hide small.
And then we're going to create a new rule in our stylesheet that only target small screens or say medius
screen and Max with 480 pixels within this media query.
We're going to target that class that we just added to the HMO.
Hi Small
display.
None.
So now if we refresh we can see that for small screens the yellow box is gone.
But if we make our window larger than this threshold of 480 pixels wide the yellow boxes back.
This means we have a reusable class named Hydes small which we can add to any element on the page and
it will do the heavy lifting of hiding that content for small screens.
So let's say we want to hide this slogan in the header can simply add a class of Hydes small and let's
imagine that we don't need frequently asked questions or links in the navigation class hide small class
hides small if we save and refresh we can see that we're beginning to optimize the content for a smaller
screen.
Next let's redesign the way our Hetter navigation works.
Free screen this size we can simply display all of the links in one line.
Once the screen gets down to about 700 pixels I think we should style the link so that they have a bit
more vertical padding so that they're easier to tap with a touch screen device.
And we should also style them so that there's only three per line.
So to achieve this we'll hop over to our style sheet.
Here's the area of our style sheet that styling the navigation and we'll create a media query that targets
devices that are 700 pixels wide or smaller.
So first let's write the code that makes sure that there's only three links per line.
So we'll target the site nav element and we're looking specifically for the list items say and list
item will give it a width of 33 point 3 2 percent.
Again we usually want our percentages to add up to 100 percent.
So this should create 3 equal links per row.
Now our list items had a bit of margin right.
So we're going to remove that so that the arithmetic concerning the wit will work out perfectly if we
save and refresh we can see there are no three links per row.
Now that's increased the vertical padding for each link and also add back in the spacing between the
wings.
So we will target the link or anchor element
padding the links originally had 10 pixels of vertical padding.
So let's bump that up to 15 pixels and they no longer need any horizontal padding because we've already
taken care of the width.
Let's also add a bit of margin back in.
So say margin right five pixels margin bottom five pixels.
If we refresh.
You can see that the vertical height increased so that the links will be easier to tap.
And we've also added spacing around each link.
Now let's go ahead and make the links used text the line center.
That looks much better.
So are heading navigation links are now much easier to tap and interact with on a tablet.
However on a traditional smartphone you can see that the three per row is not working very well.
Now we can counteract this very easily with an additional media query.
So our first media query was targeting devices that are 700 pixels wide or smaller.
Now let's create a media query that selects only devices that are 480 pixels or smaller and instead
of using with 33 percent we will select the list items and give them a width of 50 percent.
So now only two Parow which is well-suited for the smartphone size.
With that change in place let's take a moment to reflect on how our Web site is responding to the size
of the device.
So this is obviously what users will see if they use a smartphone.
As we start to increase the size of the window or the device we see that once we cross this threshold
we then have three links per room and we're no longer hiding the yellow box content or the slogan in
the header.
And then once we hit this threshold you can see we are then no longer using a single call them lay out
and our navigation then sits all of the links on one line.
So we've created different layout experiences for different screen sizes all things to media queries
.
Now throughout this lesson we've only seen one type of media query.
They're all using Macs with and I don't want you to get the notion that responsive web design is simply
taking a Web site that's designed for large screens and retrofitting it to work for smaller screens
.
Yes that's the example that we looked at in this lesson but you can also build from the other direction
So really quickly let's try an experiment.
If someone's browser window is larger than thirteen hundred pixels wide let's increase the maximum width
of our container so that the content we use maybe this much space instead.
And let's also bump up the base font a bit.
So let's begin by increasing the max width of the container for really large screens.
So in our CSL we can see here is the baseline style for the container div we've already targeted it
with the media Acree for small screens but let's add in additional media query only for large screens
so media screen.
And instead of Max what we can use men with 1400 pixels.
So now any code between these curly brackets will only be applied if the browser window is 3300 pixels
or a larger container max width instead of 960.
Let's override that to a value of twelve hundred.
So now you can see that our browser window is very large and if we refresh the content uses more of
the available space.
So if I resize the browser window we can see that the threshold is crossed right there.
Let's also increase the baseline font size for really large browser windows in our code within this
same media query that's targeting large screens let's select the body element.
Now if we scroll up to the top of our stylesheet you can see that by default our baseline font size
is 15 pixels.
So in this new media query for large screens Let's target the body element and say the baseline font
size should be 17 instead of 15 pixels.
If we were fresh we can see all of the font bumps up to fit the larger screen.
So let's look at the threshold again.
This makes effective use of larger screens and it's all thanks to the men with media query.
Now there is no right or wrong way to build a responsive web site if you want to begin with smartphones
in mind and then ad men with media queries to accommodate larger and larger screens.
That approach is called mobile first.
You're using the mobile as your baseline.
This mobile first approach is gaining more traction every year because we see that more traffic continues
to come from smaller devices instead of traditional laptops and desktops.
However many developers myself included still prefer to design for a medium sized laptop at first and
then include media queries in either direction to accommodate different screen sizes.
Again there is no right or wrong approach.
What's important is that you are creating enjoyable and highly usable experiences for all of your users
regardless of which device they're using.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
I hope that you're hungry to learn more about responsive web design because in our next lesson we're
going to look at how to create a responsive grid.
Or in other words we will learn how to manage call them layouts that are more complex than what we saw
in this lesson.
Now before you hop into the next lesson I encourage you to experiment with what you learned in this
lesson.
Have fun and I will see you in the next lesson.