In this lesson we will learn how to apply rounded corners to our elements which would otherwise end
with perfect 90 degree corners.
Here we are in the web browser This is an example page.
And let's imagine that we want these blue boxes to have rounded corners.
The blue boxes are elements which have a class of box A.
So we can simply add new declarations within this rule to target the boxes to give them rounded corners
.
We can use a property named border radius.
Let's begin with the value of 10 pixels.
So if I save and refresh we can see that the four corners of the boxes are now rounded.
If we decide that they aren't round enough we can simply increase the value so we can bump this up from
10 to 25 pixels.
Now we do not have to have a perfectly uniform curves for all four corners.
So currently we're providing a single value for the border radius property but if we provide two values
10 pixels spaced 25 pixels the web browser will use the first value of 10 for the top left and bottom
right corners and we use the second value of 25 pixels for the top right and bottom left corners.
We can take things a step further and really have fine grained control by providing for values.
So let's imagine we wanted the top two corners to use 10 pixels and we wanted the bottom two corners
to use 25 pixels.
So this works in a clockwise fashion.
This is the top left value.
This is the top right value bottom right and bottom left.
So if we save and refresh we can see that the top two corners are using a 10 pixel radius and the bottom
two corners are using a 25 pixel radius.
Next I want to talk about the exact shape of our rounded corners.
So for simplicity let's set this back to simply 10 pixels around all four corners.
Now until now we've seen circular rounding but we can also create elliptical rounding.
So if we say 10 pixels forward slash 25 pixels we can see a different shape.
So let's dissect how this new code with a forward slash works.
The first value is the horizontal radius and the second value is the vertical radius for our rounding
.
So we can create unique shapes.
Let's imagine that we increase the horizontal to 40 and reduce the vertical to 15.
We can see that our rounded corner now uses 40 pixels horizontally to complete the curve and only 15
pixels vertically to complete the curve.
So that is an example of elliptical rounding.
I however prefer circular rounding.
So I will change this to simply 10 pixels.
Now speaking of the phrase circular I scroll down a bit we can see a square box with a great background
that reads I wish I was a circle.
So let's try an experiment.
This box has a class of box be assigned to it.
And in our style she can see a rule here that corresponds with that element for our experiment.
Let's see if we can use our border radius property to turn this square into a circle.
So in our style sheet we can see that this box B element is receiving a width of 200 pixels and a height
of 200 pixels.
And if we want it to be a circle that means the rounded corners should take up half of the available
width and height half of 200 pixels is obviously 100 pixels.
So if we save and refresh you can see the squares now a circle because the border radius is taking up
exactly half of the size of the element.
So our experiment is complete.
If we scroll down a bit we find an additional experiment.
So here is a dark grey box and it reads I wish I was an oval.
That element has a class of box.
See here is the corresponding rule.
So let's see if we can use the border radius property to turn this rectangle into an oval.
Now in our C Ss we can see that this element is receiving a width of 350 pixels and a height of 200
pixels.
Now we need to calculate a value for the border radius property and I think this is a job for elliptical
rounding not circular rounding because we need a rounded corner to take up more horizontal space than
vertical space.
Now we know to create elliptical rounding we can provide two values.
The first control is the horizontal.
So half of 350 is 175.
And then when it comes to the vertical size of our radius we know that the element is 200 pixels tall
so half of that is a hundred pixels.
So 175 forward slash 100 will create an elliptical rounding effect.
So if we save and refresh we have an oval.
So with just a bit of arithmetic we were able to create an oval and a circle with the border radius
property.
Now before we close out the lesson I'll let you in on a secret.
There's no need to perform that arithmetic.
Instead of finding the perfect half values we can simply provide a value of 50 percent and the browser
will take care of the rest so we can do the same thing for our circle as well.
Border radius 50 percent.
Now I recommend using 50 percent for a few reasons.
You don't need to perform any arithmetic and 2.
It keeps things flexible so that way even if in the future your width and height values of the element
change which will happen quite often if you're using responsive web design and media queries.
You won't need to reach crunch the numbers for your border radius value in order to create the circle
or oval effect and that will bring this lesson to a close.
So whether you're looking to create circles and ovals or simply soften the perfect 90 degree edges of
your boxes the border radius property is the tool for the job.
I encourage you to experiment creating your own corner effects and I will see you in the next lesson