In this lesson we will learn how to use C S S to add styling to our HTL forms.
Let's dive right in.
By looking at the finished product.
So on this example page we can see that here is a form we learned in the H TMLC section of this course
that forms are how we can receive input from users.
So for example a visitor of the Web site could click here to enter their email address test that test
dot com.
This field receives their password.
Perhaps they want to choose what screen they are initially presented with when they log in.
And then this button submits their input.
Now we are not going to actually submit the form data in this lesson.
This is not a course on HP or Ruby on Rails or server side javascript.
This is of course an HMO and C Ss So this lesson is simply about making forms look pretty.
Now we've been looking at an example of a form that is styled and we all know that looking at a finished
product isn't great educational but I wanted this to be on the same page.
So now let's switch over to the tab that we will be working on together and let out a collective sigh
of disappointment that this sorry state of affairs is how web browsers render forms by default.
I think most people will agree that hands down.
This is pretty year and feels easier to use than this but that's OK.
That's why web designers exist.
It's our job to whip this form into shape so that it looks like something people will actually want
to interact with.
And that's exactly what we're going to do in this lesson we're going to write all of the CSSA code together
.
Let's get started.
All right.
I want to begin by making this field and this field take up the full available with or in other words
I want each field to sit on its own row.
Now before we write the CSSA to select this element let's take a quick look at our age TNL.
So that first field uses a type of e-mail.
So now let's try to select this element in our CSA as a create a new comment to stay organized form
styles so we can see that that element is an input.
So I'll begin with a type selector input but we don't want to select all inputs on the page because
for example this checkbox is an input.
So we need to make our selector a bit more specific.
We only want to select inputs that use a type of email and now we can string together declarations and
create our styles.
So I want it to take up the full available with 100 percent to keep things as predictable as possible
.
I will also set display a block and because we set a whit of 100 percent I also want to set box sizing
to use border box.
So this way we can specify horizontal padding without our field becoming wider than 100 percent.
So Box sizing border box simply changes the way the browser calculates overall width values.
So this code will play together very nicely and very quickly let's also set a baseline height.
Let's try 40 pixels.
We are making progress.
This field now sits on its own row.
Next let's make sure that the styles that we just wrote also get applied to the password field.
So all we need to do is adjust our selector for this rule.
I'm going to copy this at a comma.
Paste the code back in and change email to password.
Now for this particular form those are the only types of inputs that I will need to select.
But in most projects you will probably want to be sure to also include input types of text number and
tell for telephone the alternative to using these attribute type selectors would be to simply create
a reusable class.
For example something like standard field and then adding that class to every input that you wanted
to style.
However these attribute type selectors allow us to not dirty up our HMO with unnecessary classes.
So this is my preferred way of doing things.
Next let's style the actual form parent element itself.
So let's give it a background color and a bit of padding.
So in our CSSA we want to select the parent form element.
Let's give it a background color of E.C which is a light gray.
Let's give it 30 pixels vertical padding and 40 pixels horizontal padding.
Excellent.
Next let's hide these labels for the email and password fields because we are using the placeholder
attribute on those two fields.
We can see that before we even enter any text in the field.
We are given a hint by the placeholder text so I know that I'm supposed to enter my email in this field
.
Which makes the traditional label element a bit redundant.
However we do not want to simply go into our age T.M. out and delete the label element.
We want it here for accessibility reasons and for fallback reasons and all sorts of reasons.
So what we're going to do instead is add a class to it.
I will use a name of hidden label you could use any class name that you would like.
Now let's construct a class or a rule in R C Ss for that name hidden label.
Now you want to be careful you don't want to simply say display none because certain screen reading
software will interpret display none as oh I will just ignore this content completely.
So we don't want this.
Instead we can use position absolute to pull the element out of the natural flow of the page and then
set its height to zero with zero set its overflow to hidden and even set its visibility to hidden.
So this way the label is hidden visually for most traditional browsers and devices but screen reading
devices will still be able to access the label and successfully associate it with this field.
So we're in good shape.
Now we just need to add that class to the password field.
So here is the label for the password field.
Let's give it a class of hidden label.
Excellent.
Now let's resume.
Fine tuning these two fields.
If we look closely we can see that these fields are using a different font family than the rest of our
page.
And this raises an important point.
The font that we set on our h TNL or body element that we expect to trickle down to the entire page
does not get trickled down to form elements so we need to specifically set that too.
In this room where we are selecting the inputs we need to re specify the font that we want to use of
font family I'm using to home with a fallback to the system sans serif and lets also set the size to
be normal so font size 100 percent perfect.
Now let's create a bit of vertical space between these two fields so we can apply margin bottom.
Try 15 pixels.
Great.
Now let's override the browser default border that is getting applied to these fields border one pixel
solid.
I always use a light gray CD.
It is a subtle border but it's there if you look closely.
Something to keep in mind is that we need to give users visual feedback letting them know which field
they are currently working with.
So lets you CSSA to add a green border around the field that is currently being used.
And lets also add an inline shadow.
We will need to create a new rule but I'm going to use these selectors as a baseline so I'm going to
copy.
Let's create a new rule.
Paste those in.
Now we've already selected these inputs in their default state but now we want to select them in their
focussed state so only when the users currently focusing on one of these inputs.
Do we want these new styles that we're going to write in just a second to be applied.
All right so we want to change the border to use a green color paste that in and we also wanted to add
an inline shadow so we can use the box Shatto property.
Include the inset keyword.
I want the shadow to be fairly small and subtle so two pixels horizontal and vertical offset the two
pixel blur.
Let's use a very transparent black value.
So by default our fields will look like this but when the user clicks or tabs to one you can see the
green border and the subtle shadow next let's style the sign in button.
We will circle back around to styling this select box in just a moment but for now let's give the sign
in button some attention.
So in our HMO we can see that the sign in button has a type of submit.
So in our CSSA let's create a new rule input with a type of submit.
So that's how we can select the sign in button.
Let's begin by making the button take up the full available with so some of these styles will be similar
to what we've already written for the first two fields.
But the exact combination isn't identical so it does warrant a new rule.
So with 100 percent let's go ahead and set.
Display to block use.
Box sizing border box.
Let's use a green background color paste in hexadecimal color code.
Let's make that text.
Use a color of white.
So let's see how that looks so far.
So immediately see that I want to add a bit of vertical padding and also let's add a custom border color
padding 10 pixels vertically.
Border one pixel solid and I'll use a slightly darker green I think it would look nice if the button
had slightly rounded corners.
So let's try.
Border radius 3 pixels.
It's subtle but I like it.
Also we see again that the font for the button is not using the default font that we've set for the
page.
So let's go adjust this rule that we set up earlier where we added font family in font size to all these
different types of selectors.
Let's actually cut those two lines and create a completely universal type selector for simply all inputs
.
So that way these styles will be applied to all of these types of inputs and inputs that have a type
of submit much better.
Next let's add a bit of margin bottom to this button and also create hover or focus styles for it.
Let's try Marjan bottom 10 pixels.
And also when someone hovers over the submit button or gives it focus by cycling to it with the tab
button on their keyboard we want to style it differently.
So input type submit when it's hovered.
And also when it has defocus we want to style it differently so I'm just going to paste in rules because
I don't want this video to become too long.
So now when we hover over the button you can see that it changes or if we start here and then use your
keyboard to tab you can see the styles change as well and all that I pasted in there was simply a new
border color and a new background color.
So not rocket science.
Now let's circle back to the dreaded select element.
The reason I used the word dreaded in this case is because we don't always have complete 100 percent
control over how the select element is styled.
But let's begin by giving it our best shot.
So in our CSSA let's tack on the select element at the end of our baseline styles for inputs.
Not bad.
Let's also be sure to include select in this rule that applies baseline font settings even better.
Now it seems that the select element is playing along quite nicely and you might be wondering why I
used the word dreaded.
Well we've only seen this page rendered in Mozilla Firefox as what we're currently viewing.
Let me pull this page up in Google Chrome.
So now we can see that the select element has rounded corners and even if we specifically select the
select element and say web ticket border radius zero and simply border radius zero Chrome will still
not remove the rounded corners.
And this is where things begin to get a bit crazy.
So at this point if you were completely determined to remove these darned rounded corners and Google
Chrome you could go perform a web search for How do I remove rounded corners and chrome on the select
element.
And you might discover that you can use a property named Web Kit appearance and provided a value of
None and we can see that that did the trick.
But I would encourage you to stop and look in the mirror and ask yourself what are you doing.
Do you really want to open this can of worms.
Do you really want to try and override the default behavior of every operating system and web browser
combination on the planet meaning certain form elements like the select element for example will appear
differently on Chrome for Windows than they may on Chrome for Mac.
And we also have opera Internet Explorer Chrome for Android a whole slew of other mobile browsers and
other mobile operating systems.
So every combo is going to have slightly different looking form inputs.
Some of them have their own proprietary properties that you will need to override and it can get very
messy and very time consuming very quickly.
Now for certain projects you don't need to worry so much about the appearance of your forms.
However certain projects have corporate agendas or corporate branding requirements and you will need
to heavily focus on the appearance of forms in the description for this lecture.
You will find links to popular pre-existing CSSA bundles that you can copy and paste into your project
which will take care of a lot of the cross-browser heavy lifting work for you.
Having said that let's end this lecture with a few final customisations which we can make quite easily
.
So in Firefox you will remember that when we click on one of these fields it lights up with a green
border and we created that style manually.
However over in Google Chrome when we click on a field and this happens in other browsers as well we
can see a blue outline or a blue glow and you will often want to remove this.
So to do that all we need to do in the room for our baseline inputs simply add a declaration outline
none.
So now in Crome the email and password fields do not have the outline neither does the select but the
submit button still does.
So be sure to include outline none there as well.
Perfect.
And finally let's imagine that we want to adjust the text that reads stay signed in to be smaller and
perhaps use a gray color.
Now in our HTL now we can see that that text lives in a span that has a class of checkbox text and I
want to take this opportunity to remind you that you can use whatever markup you need to within your
form.
Now obviously you should try to keep your age TNL as clean and as semantic as possible but if you need
a bit of extra style here in there feel free to use the span element.
And even though we didn't cover it in this lesson if you needed to create different columns within your
form Feel free to use divs to back to our specific example you want to target this text.
So let's just create a new rule check box text font size 85 percent color.
Let's try a medium gray that looks a lot better.
And that will bring this lesson on styling forms to close.
Again if you need a bit more horsepower in wrangling in some of those cross-browser differences be sure
to check out the description for this lesson.
I will include links to popular CSSA bundles that you can plug into your projects.
I encourage you to experiment with your own form designs have fun and I will see you in the next lesson
.