In this lesson we will learn how to make certain text appear important or emphasized Or to phrase things
in a less academic way.
We'll learn how to make text appear bold or italic.
This is a quick disclaimer that this lesson is perhaps a bit pedantic for a topic as simple as bold
and italics.
So if you want the quick answer you can simply wrap a strong element around text to make it bold and
you can wrap and E-M element around text to make it italic.
However if you'd like to learn more about the semantic reason behind why we do these things then by
all means go ahead and view the entire lesson.
Otherwise you are free to skip to the next lesson.
We will begin with an element named strong in front of you is a text editor and here is a sentence when
eating it is imperative that you chew so we've wrapped the word imperative in the HDMI element named
strong the strong element is a tool that we can use to give strong importance to a certain bit of text
.
Typically web browsers will render content inside the strong element in a bold typeface and indeed here
we are in a web browser and we can see that the word imperative is bold now to throw a quick wrench
in the lesson.
What if I let you know that there was an additional element in HTML named simply b.
So if I save and refresh we can see literally no change in the web browser which means the B tag which
stands for bold will also make text bold.
However even though I want you to be aware of the element I don't want you to ever use it.
So let's change this back to strong and let's briefly discuss why most web developers will encourage
you to use the strong tag instead of the tag.
The strong tag simply implies that its contents have strong importance.
Now while it's true that most web browsers by default will render strong in bold typeface the element
itself does not have an intrinsic relation to being bold.
So let's say for example a year from now we revisit this page and we decide that important words should
be normal font weight so not bold but instead should be read.
If we use the strong element it is very simple to use CSSA to target all strong elements and tell them
to be a certain color.
But if we used the BE tag that intrinsically implies that this context should be bold it's not implying
importance it's simply implying a presentational preference boldness.
So it would be a bit awkward to use CSSA to target the bold tag and tell it to not be bold.
So in an effort to keep content and semantic meaning separate from presentational preferences I recommend
using the strong tag.
Now let's move on to our next topic.
Making certain text italic.
So let's imagine that we have a new sentence which reads that cat did not like the dog.
And let's imagine that we want to emphasize the word not.
There is a tag or an element in h t animal named E. M. which stands for emphasis.
So if I save and refresh in the web browser we can see that the word not has been italicized.
Now the semantic meaning behind the E-M element is that a person reading this sentence or a bit of screen
reading software should pronounce the word differently.
The cat did not like the dog.
However there are instances where we want to make certain text italic but we do not want to add emphasis
to the word.
So let's imagine that we have another sentence which reads the word tree is typically used as a noun
.
In this case we want the word tree to be italic.
We do not want to add emphasis to the word we simply want to designate that we're not using the literal
meaning of the word tree but were instead referring to the technical properties of the word.
So in a case like this we can use the A element which stands for italic.
If we were fresh in the web browser we can see that the word tree has been italicized.
However for the same reason that I recommend you don't use the tag.
I will also recommend that you do not use the IDE tag if possible.
So for example the eye tag is a quick fix and it's adding nothing but presentational preference.
So instead we could use the DFA an element which stands for definition.
So if we save and refresh we can see that the word still remains italic sized.
And this indicates that we're dealing with the definition or the technical properties of the word.
But there are only so many elements in HTML and there will come a time when you don't have the perfect
element at your disposal.
In a case like that it's OK to use the element but ideally in a situation like that you should add an
attribute named class and then give the attribute a value for this particular use of the element.
So we're using this element to refer to a term but you could come up with any name that you would like
for this unique use case.
That way in the future we can use a language like CSSA to target all elements with a clause of term
and style them a certain way.
Also this is very helpful when translating a website from one language to another because certain languages
don't treat italics the same way that English does.
So to review we've learnt how to mark text as important which will also consequently make the text bold
by default.
And we've learned how to make text appear emphasized or italic.
Now there's one final point that I want to include Before we close out this video.
And that is if you have a web page with a significant amount of text.
Let's say two large paragraphs and you decide that you want all of this text to appear bold.
Not for any semantic reason but simply from a design perspective you like the way that bulled appears
.
Please do not do something like this.
Do not use the strong tag to make entire sections of your page bold unless you actually want to designate
that.
All of this text is important.
Also do not use the E-M tag to make all of your body text italic simply because you liked the way that
it looks.
Please please do not do this.
You will learn that there is a another language named C S S and that's where you can make design decisions
.
But HTML is where we make content description decisions.
So HVM else is not the place to be defining how entire sections of text should appear.
For design reasons I will see you in the next lesson.