In this lesson we will learn about two elements which add absolutely zero semantic meaning to our code
yet are still incredibly valuable for adding bits of additional structure to our pages here and there
.
These elements names are div and span.
First let's discuss the div element in earlier lessons we learned about elements named header footer
article and these elements are all intuitively named.
They have very specific job and purpose and they are used to break up the page into meaningful chunks
.
The div element is similar to these elements in that it is used to divide up the page into chunks.
However it has no semantic meaning it's not used only for headers it's not used only for footers it's
not used only for articles.
It's a very general purpose.
One size fits all.
Use it whenever you see fit type of element.
When there is no semantic element that will do the job.
We use the development as a fallback.
It's name div stands for division so it's really a one size fits all way to create a section or division
of content within your page.
The reason that we as web developers want our pages to be made up of so many different sections and
subsections is because it makes styling the pages with CSSA much easier.
Now we have not covered CSSA yet in this course but we know that CSSA is how we add style and layout
and presentational preferences to our pages.
So let me show you a quick example of when I would use a development in this example page that we've
seen in previous lessons.
So here is the first article and we remember that this section is in the header element and this section
is in the footer element but the actual content is not in a subsection.
So let's hop over to the code really quickly that's creating this content.
Here is where the article element begins.
Here is the header.
Here's the footer and here's the actual meat and potato content.
Now even though we have not learned CSSA yet so we have not learned how to add style or layout to our
pages.
You can imagine that a web developer might want to style the actual body content of the article differently
so perhaps that means adding a background color or adding extra space around it.
So this is where the development comes into play.
We can wrap this body content of the article in a div element so there's the Start Tag.
Here is the end tag and then we can give the div a class.
We use the class attribute and then we provide a name so I could name this anything that I'd like as
long as I don't include a space in the name so I'll name this date for this division article body.
No this has absolutely no semantic value.
We just invented this class named article body and in a perfect world we wouldn't have to use this in
a perfect world there would be an element named article body but there isn't.
So instead we used the div element when there is not a dedicated element to do the job or when we need
an additional container or hook or element for styling and layout purposes.
So we've covered div..
Now let's discuss Spanne.
If the development is a non semantic version of header footer and article these block level elements
that we can use to chunk up the page then span is a non semantic version of strong or e m.
So for example what if we wanted the word ipsum.
Here it is in the text editor.
Here it is in the browser.
What if we wanted this word within a paragraph to be styled a certain way.
Let's imagine that if some was the name of our company and for marketing or branding reasons we needed
it to be a particular color so we needed a way to differentiate it from the rest of the text in the
paragraph.
We've seen examples of inline elements in the past so we've seen strong but this carries semantic weight
with it.
This implies that this word has strong importance so we don't want to use this element because we don't
want that semantic meaning.
We're only coloring or styling this word for marketing reasons or branding reasons which means the end
tag which stands for adding emphasis also doesn't seem like the right tag.
We don't want to emphasize the word we simply want to target it so we can style it differently.
So that's where the span element comes into play.
It has no semantic meaning it's not implying anything about this word.
Then we can simply add a class to the element named brand color or any other name that we want to make
up and then we can target this word with SS at a later date and we can apply any styles that we would
need to add and that will conclude this lesson to review.
We learned about two elements div and Spain.
One is a block level element.
The other is an inline element and neither of them carry any semantic meaning for the moment.
You don't need to worry too much about these elements but I want them to be on your radar because eventually
down the road when you begin learning C Ss these elements will become important.
I'll see you in the next lesson