In this lesson we will learn about responsive grids.
We will begin by learning what a grid is and what it's used for then we will take a look at grids from
a responsive angle.
And finally we will learn how to write our own code to create a responsive grid from scratch.
Let's get started.
We will begin with a question what is a grid.
A grid is a tool that graphic designers use to make sure that their layouts follow a uniform and balanced
structure.
If you've ever looked in a magazine or newspaper or website or app and thought that everything was perfectly
laid out there's a good chance that whoever designed that product used a grid structure in front of
you is one of the world's most popular grids.
This is a 12 column grid.
Now let's imagine that you and I are designing a new Web site together.
This grid is our blank canvas.
So let's imagine that we want four columns in our website for four articles.
There are the four columns now visitors of our website won't see the red lines.
They will simply see the four columns the grids are the red lines are only there for us during the design
stages.
Now the reason the 12 call them grid is so common is because 12 is divisible by many useful numbers
.
So if we wanted four columns we can see each one of our columns takes up three red bars a red bar is
referred to as a column and the space between two red bars is referred to as a gutter.
A key concept is that we don't want to begin or end one of our Web site columns in a gutter.
We want our Web site content to cleanly align with the red bars or with the 12 columns of the grid layout
by respecting the gutters our layouts will have uniform margins and clean lines.
So if for example instead of four columns on our website we wanted three a bit of arithmetic tells us
that each one of our column should span four of the red bars if we wanted our website to have two columns
.
Obviously each should span six of the red bars obviously are different columns don't always have to
be equal to one another.
So if we wanted to follow the rule of thirds and have our main column take up two thirds of the space
and have a sidebar take up one third of this base we could use an 8 4 split of our 12 column grid.
Now the benefits of using grid might not be obvious until we realize that our Web site is made up of
multiple rows of columns.
And as a designer we don't want to be inventing new horizontal rhythms for each row using a grid helps
us establish one unified horizontal rhythm and stick with that rhythm throughout the entirety of our
layout.
And that goes a long way towards pleasing the human eye and making our layout feel cohesive.
So now that we've established what a grid is and why it might be a good idea to use one we need to discuss
how we can apply this notion of a grid to the modern day web browser.
So let's give ourselves a concrete goal to work towards.
I put together a few rough draft sketches of a layout that I would like to create.
So this is what the layout should look like at the desk top level.
The main column on the left we'll have four call outs or four sub columns and then it will have two
photographs the blue content on the side represents a side bar.
So this is a large desktop monitor.
Once we get down to the medium desktop monitor or the laptop I want the call outs in the main column
to sit two per row instead of four Parow like we had on the large desktop version.
Once we get down to a tablet we want to make the sidebar the blue area simply stacked below what used
to be the main column and the call outs and photographs will again set to Parow.
And once we get down to a smartphone everything should set one per row.
So single call them with the exception of the green which is two photographs.
So that's the response of lay out that I would like to achieve at the different screen sizes.
Now here we are in the web browser and this is a page that I've put together behind the scenes and it
has all of the content that we were just looking at in those rough draft sketches only there's been
zero layout applied.
So even though the content is here nothing's being floated we don't see any columns now behind the scenes
.
I've written CSSA that creates a responsive grid system.
Now what we are going to do together is wrap this content that's making up the page in certain divs
with specific class names in order to create the different layouts for different screen sizes that we
looked at earlier.
Now most responsive grid systems adopt a mobile first approach and the code that I set up is no different
.
So I'm going to resize my web browser to resemble that of a smartphone.
And we can see that our layout is actually almost already complete at the smartphone level because for
the most part we just want elements to sit one per row.
However we did one even at the Mobile level for these two photographs to sit side by side.
So in our text editor Heres the HMO and I will look for those two images here they are.
And here is the code that we will use to create the two columns for the two images we want to create
a row so I'll create a div with a class of row and within this div we want to create one day for each
column.
So we want to call names.
So I'll give this element a class of call for column and then I'll give it a second class of call ex-s
6.
Now I will explain this naming scheme in just a moment but for the time being if it doesn't make sense
that's perfectly OK.
Now we want to have these because we wanted one for each image.
So I'm going to copy and paste.
And then let's cut and paste each image into these newly created divs.
So if we save and refresh can see that the two images now sit side by side.
Now let's review this naming scheme.
Call stands for call them.
We'll circle back to excess in just a moment.
Six is relating to the 12 column grid.
So if we want two columns half of 12 is six.
Now regarding X as this stands for extra small.
So in my responsive grid system I refer to smartphones as extra small or access.
I refer to tablets as small or SM.
I refer to laptops as M.D or medium and I refer to large desktop monitors as LG or large.
Now we are using a mobile first approach so this means that because we targeted extra small call them
extra small six those two images will sit side by side one another no matter what size device our users
are using.
So our live is already complete for the smartphone device size.
Let's move on now to the tablet size if you recall our rough draft sketches.
The only difference between the smartphone layout and the tablet layer is that we wanted our call outs
to sit two per row.
Once we get to the tablet size.
So in our HMO we will find those boxes here they are.
So I will begin by creating a row div with a class of row.
Now within this row I'm going to create four different columns call for column and I'll give this element
an additional class of call them small which stands for tablet.
Now again we want these to sit too Preux.
So using the 12 column grid we'll use 6.
Now there are four of these call outs so I'll copy and paste this device so that there are four of them
.
Next I will scroll down a bit.
Here's the code that was used to create one of those blue boxes.
So I'll grab one of them.
Delete the others and then paste them in to each of these different four columns that we just set up
.
So if I save and refresh we can see that now at the tablet level.
These blue boxes are these call outs to Parow.
And if I resize my browser to resemble that of a smartphone you can see that they still only sit one
per row.
This is because we chose a class of call small six by targeting small classes styles will only be applied
to devices that are a certain size or larger.
So our layer is complete for the tablet size.
Now if you recall back to our rough draft sketches The only difference between the medium desktop and
the tablet version is that the medium desktop version should have a sidebar that sits on the right side
instead of stacking beneath the main content.
So in our HMO we all scroll towards the top and create a div with a class of row.
Now we're going to create two columns.
One we will say call medium eight.
And the second div will have a class of call and call medium four.
So this will be the main column and this will be the sidebar.
We're following the rule of thirds.
So in terms of our 12 column grid we're using an 8 4 split.
So now I'm simply going to cut and paste all of the main column content into this div and I'll cut and
paste all of the sidebar content into this div to the main column content starts here.
And ends here so I cut that pasted in here.
And the sidebar content begins here and ends here.
So cut and paste here.
So if I save and refresh we can see that we now have to call them out.
But if I shrink my window down to resemble a tablet you can see that again the sidebar stacks beneath
the main content.
This is because we chose a class of call and D for medium.
So these classes of call medium for a call medium eight will only be applied to the page if the device
is medium sized or larger.
Now if we think back to our rough draft sketches The only difference between the medium desktop and
large desktop layouts is that we want the call outs in the main column to sit for per row for large
desktop monitors.
So in the web browser I'm going to resize my browser to be quite large and then hop over to the HTL
search for the columns that are making up those boxes.
Here they are.
They have a class currently of column small 6.
So that means for tablet size and larger they should take up half the width.
We're going to add an additional class of call them large three.
If we think back to the 12 column grid to create four pieces of content Parow we know that 12 divided
by four is three.
And we only want this style to be applied to devices that are large.
So then I will add this new class to the additional 3 remaining columns.
So now if we save and refresh we can see that because my screen is considered large the call outs now
sit for Parow.
But if I resize my window back to a medium desktop size they sit two per row so we can see that these
two classes are working in harmony.
We can layer in different class names that are targeting different screen sizes to create the desired
layout.
So our responsive layout is now complete.
Now in the beginning of this lesson I promised that we would learn how to write code ourselves from
scratch.
And throughout this lesson we've only been looking at H T and now I wrote the CSSA that accompanies
these class names behind the scenes.
So now to keep my word I'm going to remove all of that CSSA.
And we are going to write it together.
So behind the scenes I just deleted all of the CSSA that was creating the responsive grid system that
was corresponding with the class names we were using.
And you can see this is what we're left with simple content that has no way out.
Nothing being floated.
There are no columns.
However all of our HTML is still intact.
So we still have rows and we still have columns and we still have our specific class name systems.
Now we just need to write the corresponding CSSA together that applies the correct with than float and
padding values to correspond with these names.
So let's get started.
Here we are in the style sheet and the first thing I'm going to do is to make sure that at the bottom
where we have our clear fix code instead of group I want to make sure that I can also simply add row
to a parent element and have it automatically clear its floated children.
So with the rope clear fix solution in place we can begin writing the actual logic to our grid system
.
So the first rule that I will create is call for column in our HMO.
You will remember that every call them received in base class of call as well as additional classes
to tell them how much space to take up for different devices.
But the base call class is important.
So we want all columns to be floated to the left.
Next let's write the code that selects the extra small half wit column.
So you will remember that we wanted the images to sit two per row even at the extra small smartphone
level.
So this seems like a logical place to begin and RCA says.
So if an element receives this class we want it to take up half of the available wit.
Now if an element doesn't receive any of the classes that we've specified so far we want them to take
up the full available width if we save and refresh.
We can see the two images now sit two per line.
However we are missing gutters or margins between our elements.
So if you think back to the original graphic of the 12 column grid with the red bars there were spacing
between each of the 12 red columns.
We refer to that as the gutter.
So to add that back into our code in the universal column rule it is applied to all columns.
We can say padding right.
Twenty pixels.
Box sizing borderer box.
That way the padding does not adjust the overall calculated width of the elements.
Now if we save and refresh you can see that our code added gutters to the right of each of our columns
.
However we don't need a gun or at the very end of our row we only need gutters in between columns so
to counteract this at a CSSA level what we can do is target the row element that houses our columns
.
So you'll see a div with a class of row is used every time we want to create a row of columns.
Now in our CSL we can target that and give it a margin write value of negative 20 pixels.
This is related to the padding that we just added.
So if we save and refresh we can see that we still maintain a gutter between the two columns but we
don't have extra gutter at the end of our row.
Excellent.
Now we simply need to make sure that our style sheet has all the possible values 1 through 11 to accommodate
the 12 column grid.
So 6 is obviously 50 percent of 12.
3 is obviously 25 percent of 12.
Now instead of you watching me perform this very basic arithmetic I'm simply going to paste in rules
for 1 through 11.
Now remember we're using the extra small or mobile size as our baseline.
So these rules do not need to be within immediate query.
We want these to be applied to every device under the sun.
However once we bump up from extra small to small we want those classes to only be applied to screens
of a certain size so we can use a media query to say only if a device is at least 768 pixels wide.
Should you then act on these classes that use the small prefix.
So we now have our access for extra small classes in place we have our SM for small classes in place
so that takes care of smartphones and tablets.
Now we need to take care of our medium size so we can create an additional media query a media screen
and men with 10 24 pixels.
So only if a device is at least 10 24 wide Do we wanted to honor these class names that use the M.D
or medium prefix.
And finally let's take care of our large classes so we'll create one final media query medius screen
and men with 12 eighty pixels.
So only if a device is at least this wide should it honor our class names that use the LG for larger
abbreviation.
So with all of this in place if we save and refresh and make our browser window larger you can see that
we hit the smaller tablet level and we have two call outs Parow.
We had the medium size you can see again we have the side bar.
And once we hit the large size we have the four call outs Parow very quickly you will remember that
we set the gutter to be 20 pixels which looks good at the small excuse me extra small size but I think
once we get up to the tablet or small size our gutters should be 40 pixels.
So to make that change or simply hop over to our stylesheet scroll up to our small classes live within
this media query or select the universal call class and say padding right should be 40 pixels instead
of 20.
Now remember to counteract that we need to address the parent row element and make sure that its margin
right value is a negative value that matches the padding.
We just set.
We save and refresh we can see the gutter is now larger for every size except the extra small mobile
level.
And that will bring this lesson to a close.
I realized there was a lot to soak in in this lesson you might need to watch it more than once.
And at the end of the day if you dont want to use a grid you dont have to.
But I wouldnt be doing my job if I didn't familiarize you with at least one grid system.
I encourage you to download the demo files for this lesson and experiment with the classes yourself
.
Creating your own unique layouts.
Have fun and I will see you in the next lesson.