Next let's add the pagination dots that indicate which slide you are currently viewing we head over
to our HTML.
We can simply create a new element within our cycle slideshow div that has a class of cycle hyphen pager
and the cycle 2 script will take care of all the heavy lifting.
So if I save and refresh we can now see three dots which represent the three slides if there were four
slides in our slideshow then cycle 2 would output four dots.
Let's begin by positioning this pager element to sit at the top of our slide show horizontally centered
.
So to do that it's head over to our style sheet.
So create a new four cycle pager.
I'm going to use position absolute I want to sit down about 20 pixels from the top and I will be sure
to assign it a large z index value so that it is not overlapped by the slides themselves.
So if we refresh there it is.
But remember I also wanted it to be horizontally centered so to achieve that I will make the cycle pager
element use the full available width and then I will tell it to use text align center much better.
Now let's focus on styling the dots themselves.
So if I right click on the dots and click inspect element you can see that there is a span for each
dot.
Now we didn't add the spans for each dot we simply created the empty cycle page element and cycle to
it dynamically inserting a span to represent each slide and we can see that cycle to also as a class
of cycle pager active to the door that represents the currently displayed slide.
Now we are interested in customizing the appearance of these dots.
So let's see what's actually in each one of these spans.
So it's a bullet.
I don't want the bullet to display.
So I'll show you a neat way to completely customize this in R C SS was created rule for site quoll pager
Spain.
So we're styling each one of the dots.
Now I don't want that actual bullet character to display.
So I'm going to use text indent negative nine thousand pixels.
Let's make sure that each dot or each span element is using inline block.
Let's make them a 10 pixel circle.
So with 10 pixels height 10 pixels and if we want to be a circle we simply set the border radius to
50 percent by default.
Let's make the dots white.
So background color white Let's add a bit of spacing horizontally between the dots.
So margin we use shorthand so 0 in 4.
So vertically we don't want to add any margin but horizontally so that means on the left and the right
size word for pixels lets out a property of cursor pointer so that they look like links when we hover
over them and let's see even refresh and see how things look.
So there are the dots.
However they aren't lighting up to display which one is the currently active slide.
So if we inspect them again you can see that the exact name of that class is cycle pager active.
So let's just create a special class or a special rule cycle pager site called pager active.
So if an element has that class instead of using white background we want to use a background of black
.
So now we can see that the first slide is displaying so the first dot is lit up.
And now the second and if we advance through these rapidly now the third.
So our work with the pagination is complete.
Now I promised earlier in the lesson that we would set up a call to action button in the text area.
So let's do that very quickly over in our HTML for our first slide.
Here it is.
The slide at the end of this paragraph element let's add a link
that says call to action.
You could insert any text that you would like but let's give this element a class of button.
Again you could choose any class name you like.
This is just what I'm choosing.
So then in our CSSA create a comment stay organized button a style.
So now we can create a style that looks like a button.
So I like to begin with a bit of padding.
Six pixels vertically 10 pixels horizontally.
Let's give it rounded edges.
So border radius 5 pixels lets make the font bold make it use all capitals text transform uppercase
.
Let's give it a blue background background color and I'm going to paste in a hexadecimal code for blue
lets make the text white.
So if we save and refresh there is our call to action button lets make the font a bit smaller so font
size 84 percent.
And lets also add a bit of margin left.
So its not super close to the standard text.
Whoops.
Margin left 10 pixels much better.
Let's add a quick hover style.
So when someone hovers over the call to action button it changes button a hover.
So let's switch the background color and text color when someone hovers over it.
So the background color will be white and the text color will be the blue value.
Excellent.
Now one quick feature that we should change about Cycle 2 is that if someone is hovering over the text
area or actually anywhere on a slide it shouldnt auto advance to the next slide because that can be
very frustrating.
Imagine a user was just about to click this call to action button and then the slideshow auto advanced
and they could no longer click it.
So all we need to do to fix that is head over to our HTML. Our cycle slideshow did the parent do we
can add an additional data attribute of data cycle pause on hover and provided a value of true.
Its that simple.
So Cycle 2 is incredibly flexible.
So now we can see that because I'm hovering over the slide and I'm getting ready to click on the call
to action button cycle 2 will never automatically advance to the next slide.
But as soon as I move my mouse off of the slideshow and wait a few seconds cycle to nose to advance
again.
Now the final feature of Cycle 2 that I want to highlight in this lesson is that it plays along very
nicely with responsive layouts.
Some slides show scripts lock you into a certain with their height but not cycle too.
So for example if I make the browser window smaller to resemble perhaps a smartphone factor we can see
that obviously our textarea takes up too much space but the slideshow itself still functions just like
we would expect.
So we can make this fully responsive quite easily on a smartphone.
I think all we need to change is that the text area instead of overlapping the image should simply sit
below the image.
So to do that I'm just going to head over to our style sheet find the slide text selector.
Here it is.
It's create a really quick media query media screen and Max with 767 pixels so actually anything that's
smaller than a tablet.
Slide text should no longer use position absolute just use position static.
So standard positioning and instead of having a semi transparent background just use solid black.
So if we refresh that looks a lot better for the smartphone form factor.
But if someone's using a larger device they still receive the classic overlay styling that we set up
and that's going to conclude this lesson.
Hopefully you've noticed that cycle 2 is incredibly flexible.
Now you can extrapolate what we've learned today to create any type of slideshow you can imagine.
So this is an example of how we can leverage javascript without writing javascript so we can let a solution
like cycle to handle the on the fly manipulation of the page and then leverage our own.
Each TMLC has the skills to fully customize things.
I encourage you to experiment and create your own unique layout and styles for a slide show and I will
see you in the next lesson.