In this lesson we will learn about the CSSA box model or in other words we will learn that every element
on a web page is essentially a rectangle or a box.
And the CSSA box model will let us understand that becoming a web designer really means learning how
to manipulate and decorate boxes in any way that you can imagine.
So let's get started.
Here's an example page that I've created for this lesson and we can see that it reads box a the HVM
of this page is nothing more than a div with a class of box.
So our goal for this lesson is to write bits of CSSA code to begin to understand the way their boxes
are formed to begin to understand the box model.
So the first thing we'll do is target that class.
So a period box A and the first task is to give it a background color background color light gray.
So this is something that we've seen in earlier lessons.
There's nothing amazing about this.
We've given the box a background color.
The next property might begin to explain the box model.
However padding 30 pixels so you can see that the content of the box this text box A and our HMO here
now sits 30 pixels from the top of the box where we can see the background color begins and it sits
30 pixels from the left of where the content begins.
Next let's give our box a border in our CSX border.
The first thing we do is decide how thick we want the border to be.
So let's say we want to be three pixels that we want it to be a solid straight line.
And we want it to be black.
So if we refresh we can see that the box now has a border.
No in order to continue learning about boxes I think it would be helpful if we had more than one box
on the page.
So in our HMO.
Let's create a second div and give it a class of box B and we include the text box B within the div
.
So if we refresh we can see that it has not received any styling yet.
So let's give it a bit of styling
box be background color orange.
So if we save and refresh we can see that that's in place.
Now let's imagine that we want to create space between these two boxes.
So currently we can see that they're pressed up against each other without any sort of space or margin
.
So that word that I just used margin is how we create space between these two boxes.
So let's target box a within this rule and we'll say margin bottom 20 pixels.
So if we save and refresh we can see that box 8 is now pushing down so that there's 20 pixels of margin
or space between it and the next box.
Now that we've seen padding border and Margene inaction you understand the basics are the fundamentals
of the box model.
So a box is nothing more than an area that takes up space on the web page to create space within the
inside of that box.
We use padding to draw an outline around the outer edge of that box.
We use border and then to push or create space around the outside of the box.
We use margin.
Now that you're familiar with the basics of the box model let's take things a step further and learn
how to control the width and height of boxes.
So in our CSS Let's imagine that we want the box a gray box to have a width of 200 pixels and a height
of a hundred and fifty pixels.
So if I save and refresh we can see that we have fine grained control over the dimensions the width
and height of the box.
So if we wanted this box to be a little bit wider you could increase its with from 200 to 250 pixels
.
And if we were fresh we see that it grows a little bit in with now the width and height properties become
especially interesting when we begin to understand how they pair and relate to the padding margin and
border properties.
So for example let's add identical width and height values to our second box box B to a face saving
refresh we can see that even though we gave it identical with height values it's not the same size and
shape as box A.
This is because we added padding and border to box A.
But you will notice that we did not add those properties to box B and padding and border are calculated
when the browser determines the final dimensions of an element.
So this box is not actually only 250 pixels wide it's also adding 30 pixels of padding on the left side
30 pixels of padding on the right side and then it's adding three pixels of border on each side.
So let's give ourselves a goal.
Let's imagine that we want to adjust the box B's with value so that in the browser it appears to have
an identical with as box A.
So in order to do that we'll need to do a bit of arithmetic.
So 250 plus 30 pixels of padding on the left brings us up to 80 plus 30 pixels of padding on the right
.
Brings us up to 310 plus three pixels of border on the left.
Brings us up to 313.
And then another three pixels of border on the right brings us up to 316.
So now if we save and refresh we can see that the boxes are identical in width.
However front end web developers have more important things to do than crunching numbers just to determine
the size of a box.
So while it's important that you're aware of the way that padding and border affect the true size of
an element you have a luxury of being a web developer in the modern era.
Now in the last several years there's a property that's arised that will make our lives very easy so
that property is box sizing boarder box.
So if I save and refresh watch what happens to box a.
It shrinks.
And now it quite literally is two hundred and fifty pixels wide.
So now on our box B we don't need to worry about the weird arithmetic of adding this plus padding Plus
border we can put this back to 250 pixels wide.
And because we used box sizing border box on the element that has padding and border the web browser
knows how to calculate the size of box A so that it actually is 250 pixels wide.
Now when I mentioned that box sizing border box is a luxury of the modern era.
All that means is that if someone is coming to your website and they're using a very outdated web browser
a web browser that hasn't been updated since 2008 or very early 2009 this property will not work.
And in that case their web browser will resort to using padding and border when calculating the overall
with value.
However this is not a lesson on cross-browser compatibility.
This is a lesson on the CSSA box model.
Now in later lessons in the course we will discuss how to handle site visitors that are using disgustingly
outdated web browsers.
But this is neither the time nor the place for that discussion.
For the time being I want you to stay focused on the box model.
So I want you to reflect on padding border margin and the way that we can create and manipulate boxes
because in our next lesson we are going to learn how to create a basic page layout with CSX.
In other words we will learn how to create a web page that actually looks like a typical web page with
different columns sitting next to each other side by side.
And I think it's going to be a lot of fun.
So I will see you in the next lesson.