In this lesson we will learn how to create full with backgrounds with fixed width interior content.
It's difficult to explain this effect with words.
So let's hop straight into a visual demonstration in front of you is the example lay out that we've
seen throughout the course and it features an overall container element with a white background that
all of our other content sits within.
Now I want you to contrast that with this lay out in this new example lay out we can see that the header
section has a green background and it's not being confined by any other element.
It's using up the full browser window width and even if I make my browser window larger we see that
the content itself doesn't use more space but the backgrounds of the sections fill the entire browser
window with.
So this is what I was describing earlier when I said full width backgrounds with fixed width interior
content.
This is a common layout technique that many of the world's most popular Web sites make use of.
So in this lesson we will be revisiting this old example lay out that you are familiar with and will
be adjusting the code so that it looks more like this layout which uses full width backgrounds.
Let's get started.
Our first step is to edit the H TNL for our page.
We can see that we have a div with the class of container that is housing all of the content on the
page and that's what's giving the page the white background that's horizontally centered within the
browser window.
So I'm simply going to delete that div there is the end tag.
There's the Start Tag.
And we can adjust the indentation of this content just to stay organized.
So now that we've removed that overall parent element we can see that the background color of our room
HVM element is shining through.
So in our C Ss we were assigned a background color to our overall page.
So now we need to assign background colors to each individual section.
So if we want our main content area to have a white background I can simply find that in the CSX background
color solid white and let's imagine that we want our Hetter to use a darker background color with white
text.
We can make that adjustment very quickly.
Header background color.
Paste in hexadecimal color code for a darker green.
Let's change the color of the text to be white.
We also need to adjust the color of the links in the header.
Here is the rule that targets the links or change the color to white.
And I can see a five or 10 pixel margin around all four edges of the page.
So to remove that we can simply target the body element of our page and be sure to remove any margin
or padding.
Excellent.
So we now have full with background sections.
The header uses dark green the content area uses white and if I make my browser window larger you can
see that they continue to use the full space of the web browser.
However this is very bad for readability because we can see that the content itself is also trying to
use the full window width and the human eye only wants to read so many words per line before it becomes
fatigued.
So we need a way to have fixed width interior content.
Now you will remember earlier in the lesson we removed the overall parent container div.
Well now we can add container divs for each individual section.
So for example in the header in our HTML we can cut all of the content that lives within the header
.
Remember this Hetter element is what's creating the dark green background.
And within this element we can create a div for the class of container and then I'll paste back in all
the content.
Now let's just see SS for a class of container.
The only properties that we will need are a maximum with.
I will use 940 pixels.
We want it to be horizontally centered so we can say margin.
0 auto.
And if I save and refresh we can see that the header element now has a fixed width for the interior
content.
So if we review our h DML structure the hetter element is what's creating the green background color
and we have not assigned any sort of with that element.
So it uses the full window with then with in the header element we wrapped it into your div with the
class of container.
And that directly houses all of our content and the container element is what has a width and is margin
auto to be horizontally centered.
So now we can apply that same container class inside our main content area that has a white background
.
So in our HVM now we see here is the content area div..
So I'm going to cut and paste all of its contents creating a new div with a class of container and then
paste back in the content.
So content area has a direct child of container and that will reuse this same rule.
So if I refresh our content area also has the same interior wit
and now no matter how large someone makes their browser window our background areas will fill up the
entire window and our actual content will have a nice clean uniform margin.
That's really all there is to this technique.
It's a very simple concept but it helps to see it put into action.
Now before we close out this lesson I want to bring up a bit of a side note.
The reason that I used Macs with instead of simply width on our container element is to make sure that
smaller screens also work well with their layout.
So for example if I make my web browser smaller than 940 pixels wide we can see that it does not force
horizontal scroll bars but instead the layout adapts.
However there's no spacing on the left and right sides of our layout.
So to fix that in our container element we can simply say padding left 40 pixels tatting right 40 pixels
.
So even if a screen or browser window is smaller than the max with we've set there will still be a nice
margin on the left and right.
That's going to conclude this lesson.
We are now one step closer to creating beautiful flexible layouts.
I will see you in the next lesson.