In this lesson we will learn how to create buttons which users can tap or click to reveal or hide certain
sections of content.
So let's jump straight to a visual example of this.
Let's look at the finished product.
So here is an example page and if I resize the browser to a word that resembles a smartphone you can
see that the navigation is gone and there's a menu link that we can click and we tap to click that the
menu is then revealed.
This is a great way to conserve precious screen real estate on smaller devices.
Mobile navigation menus are probably the most prominent example of this functionality.
You've probably seen many web sites that use this strategy.
Let's take a look at another example.
So on a laptop or a large tablet or a traditional computer we scroll down a bit we see there's a bit
of text.
So this section reads important text and this area reads full text.
So maybe this text isn't super important.
Now if we resize our browser down to a smartphone size you can see that the full text is gone.
So perhaps we decided that it wasn't important enough to show initially on a smartphone but you can
see that we have this link here that reads read full text.
Now this link was not present at the desktop or laptop size.
So you'll see there is no link.
But again the smartphone size if we click this link it reveals the full text.
And then you can see that it's phrasing changes to hide full text.
So if we click it again the extra text is hidden.
So that was a quick demo of the reveal and hide functionality.
But looking at a finished product isn't very educational.
So now let's hop over to a tab that doesn't have any of this functionality.
And let's work together to create this behavior.
So our recipe for creating the reveal and hide functionality has two ingredients.
First ingredient is a bit of custom HVM and CSX which we can write without a problem.
And the second ingredient is a javascript solution that we're going to plug into our page named declarative
toggle.
In this scenario javascript will handle the click or tap events and it will also add and remove the
right classes at the right moment to the right elements.
So let's get started.
Let's begin by adding the declarative toggle javascript file to our Web page.
So here is the javascript file declarative toggle.
You can find this in the description for this lesson or in the downloadable zip for the lecture.
So I'm going to move this file to live with the other web site files.
So here is my web site folder.
Here is the javascript folder.
So I'm going to move declarative toggle to live within the jazz folder.
Next let's actually include this file in the head section of our HMO to I'm just going to copy and paste
one of the existing script lines and all we need to change is the name of the file.
So our file still lives in the jazz folder and its name is declarative toggled that J.
Yes.
Excellent.
So with this one line of code we have leveraged javascript and now all we need to worry about is the
H DML and C Ss.
So let's give ourselves a goal let's imagine that we want to hide the navigation and include a link
in the header that reads menu.
Now let's begin by adding this behavior to all devices and screen sizes.
And then once we have everything functioning properly we can make it responsive by feeding the behavior
only to smaller devices.
So let's begin by heading to our HMO and adding the menu button.
So I will create a span within the span I will include the word menu.
Now the declarative toggle script is actively searching for elements on the page that have a data attribute
of data.
Toggle target.
Now this attribute is where we specify what should be revealed when we click on this element.
So this attribute accepts CSSA selectors.
So for example when we click on the menu element we want to reveal this nav element and navigation and
that element has a class of site nav.
So within this data attribute we can simply give it a value of DOT to represent a class and then site
now.
And finally as far as the H team is concerned we also want to add a class of toggle button to any declarative
toggle buttons that we create.
So that's it for the for HTML.
Now let's hop over to our C Ss create a new comment to stay organized reveal and hides styles.
Now are javascript solution of declarative toggle has a hands off approach meaning it lets CSSA do a
lot of the heavy lifting.
The talk with declarative script utilizes four classes.
They are toggle button toggle button visible toggle target hidden and toggle target expanded to very
quickly.
By default we want toggle buttons to be hidden so display none if the javascript file is loaded successfully
.
It will add a class of toggle button visible.
So then we want them to be display Block.
Next up toggle target hidden to our script will automatically add this class to elements that we want
to reveal.
So we want them to initially be hidden so display none.
And finally when we click on the button our script adds this class toggled target expanded to the target
element.
So we want it to be display block or visible.
So with this VSS in place if I save and refresh you can see the navigation is hidden.
We click on menu it's revealed and if we click menu again it's hidden.
Now let's take a look at how easy it is to make this behavior responsive.
So let's imagine that we only want this hide and reveal functionality for small screens.
All we need to do is head over to our CSSA and of these four new rules that we created.
The bottom three need to simply be wrapped in a media query so I will cut these into my clipboard and
let's create a media query so media screen and max width.
So I'm going to say anything smaller than a tablet and then I'm simply going to paste in the ss.
So now if I save and refresh we can see at the desktop level the traditional navigation is in place
.
But if we shrink the browser down to a phone here's the menu.
We can talk to the navigation we can hide the navigation again and even if we make our browser large
again it reverts back to the standard navigation.
Now we all know that practice makes perfect.
So let's try this functionality again on the full text example that we saw earlier.
So let's head over to our mail.
Here is the full text area.
So the first thing I'm going to do is wrap this content in a div so that we have some way of grasping
it.
So I'll cut this to my clipboard.
It's create a div named full text and then I'll paste the content back in.
Next let's add the read more button at the end of the important text paragraph.
So here.
So create a span now that will give it an attribute of data toggle target and we want to target this
full text div.
So a class of full text.
So Dot full text now within the span lets have it read.
Read the full text.
Let's also be sure to give the span a class of toggle button.
So if we save and refresh you can see that at the desktop level the link is not visible in the full
text is visible.
But if we make our browser window smaller the full text is not displayed but we see this option which
reads read the full text and if I click on that there is the full text.
So now let's make a few edits.
Let's style this span so that it actually looks like a link or a button.
So let's jump over to our C Ss and give that span a unique class.
So it already has a class of toggle button.
Let's give it a second class of read more.
So now if we hop over to our CSX we can create a special style for Read more.
So let's give it an underlined text decoration underline and let's make the color blue and we can even
provide a hover style.
So read more.
Let's remove the text decoration or remove the underlined text decoration.
None.
So now if we refresh.
It actually looks like something that we would want to click or tap.
Now I want to show you one final feature of declarative toggle so you will notice that when we click
on this it shows the full text.
But if we were to click on it again it hides the text so perhaps it would make sense that once it's
been clicked or tapped once this text should change.
So instead of saying read the full text it should say hide the full text so we can implement that very
easily over in our HTL mail on this spand button.
We can provide an additional data attribute named Data toggle text and this is where we can provide
that alternative text that reads hide the full text.
So if we save and refresh we tap this once content is displayed we can see the text changes to hide
the full text so the description of the button changes depending on what action it's actually performing
.
Now before we close out this lesson let's give ourselves one additional goal.
Let's imagine that we only want the hide and reveal functionality in the navigation for small screens
.
But what if we want the hide and real functionality on this full text even on larger screens.
Now when we originally structured our CSSA for the declarative toggle classes we placed them in immediate
media query which means unless a device is smaller than this breakpoint the device will more or less
just ignore our javascript solution.
So what if we want larger devices by default to ignore our javascript solution but in certain circumstances
so perhaps if the elements live within the main column then we do want larger devices to play along
.
All we need to do is copy the styles that live within the media query and paste them so that there is
a copy outside of the media query and then add on an additional class to these selectors to make them
a descendant selector.
So for example this main column of our website has a class of main area so we can create descendant
selectors and say only if these elements live within the main column.
Do we want large screens to play along with our javascript solution.
So now if I save and refresh it can see that we still have the traditional desktop navigation but down
here the full text is hidden and we can show and hide it at will.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
I hope that you can find interesting uses for this functionality in your pages and your web sites.
Perhaps you can get creative and adjust the media query break point and create all sorts of neat responsive
layouts with interesting bits of content to toggle.
So like always I encourage you to experiment and have fun and I will see you in the next lesson