In this lesson we will learn about C Ss animations because animations are inherently visual.
We are going to jump straight in to an example page.
Here we are in the web browser and I want you to pay attention to this key feature blue box.
When I reload the page.
So we noticed that it faded into view on page load but there's a bit more to it than that unlike a transition
.
I didn't have to hover over anything for that animation to occur.
And if we take a closer look.
So here is another page refresh we see that the box isn't simply transitioning from one vertical value
to another but instead we see a bounce like effect where the box drops down to its standard position
and then bounces up and down a bit.
Now behind the scenes I have adjusted this example page and when I refresh there will be four blue boxes
instead of only one.
So this is an effect that you have most likely seen on a Web site where the call outs are featured bits
of content fade into view one at a time.
CSSA animations make this simple to achieve.
And again unlike transition's the effect doesn't need to be triggered by a hover or a click.
It's simply an animation that can begin playing on page load.
Now in this lesson Our goal is to rewrite the code together to create the animation bounce effect.
We will also rewrite the code together that controls the timing of the four boxes so that they all don't
fade in at the exact same millisecond but instead are staggered one slightly after the other and finally
let me introduce you to one final bit of content on this example page to further whet your appetite
for CSSA animations.
So we can see there is a star and behind the scenes I just plugged in a bit of additional code so when
I refresh can see the star has a unique animation and it will continue cycling and repeating this animation
forever.
Now once we are done with the code for our blue boxes we will also learn how to animate the star in
this fashion.
I think its going to be a lot of fun.
So lets get started.
All right.
So behind the scenes I ripped out all of the code that was creating the animations and I also removed
the star and the extra three blue boxes.
So here we are at square one just a single featured blue box and lets work together to create the bounce
animation effect.
So in our CSSA file let's create a new comment section to stay organized.
We will begin by defining and naming our animation.
So to begin an animation we use the at symbol and type out keyframes space and then this is where we
get to choose a name.
So I will name this animation Faid bounce.
You could choose any name that you would like.
Now between these two curly brackets is where we include the code that makes up the animation.
So for now we are not applying this animation to any content on the page.
We are beginning by creating a standalone piece of code that can then later be reused and reapplied
to any content that we would like.
So within these curly brackets I will begin by saying that when the animation is 0 percent complete
or in other words when it has just begun we want the content to have an opacity of zero.
So we want it to be invisible and we want it to start out a bit higher on the page that it gives the
effect that its sliding and fading down into view.
So we use the transform property translate why negative 200 percent so it will be pushed up.
So this is how content should be styled when the animation is just getting ready to begin when the animation
is 0 percent complete.
Now when the animation is 100 percent complete So when the animation is finished we want the opacity
to be fully visible and we want it to be positioned vertically where it would normally sit.
So transform translate Why 0.
Now these two states on their own the zero percent state and the 100 percent state are not going to
create the bounce effect.
We will revisit this code in just a moment to work towards that bounce effect.
But for the time being we now have an animation named Faid bounce that we can apply to elements on the
page.
So we know that this box or this div this blue key feature one box has a class of box A.
So within the rule or selector for the box element we can now say animation name Faid bounce animation
duration.
One second.
And if we save and refresh we can see that our animation is taking place.
I'll bet it's not a bounce yet but the animation that we created named Faid bounce is indeed firing
on page load.
And because we set a duration of one second our keyframe rule is transitioning between 0 percent and
100 percent over the span of one second.
So if we increase this to three seconds I can see the animation plays out very slowly.
And that's not what we want.
So let's change the duration back to one second and let's focus our energy on the keyframes rule and
add intermediate states between 0 and 100 percent that will create the actual bounce effect.
So at 40 percent completion of the animation we actually want it to be fully visible and sit vertically
in its natural state.
So I will just copy and paste this line of code.
So we want the remaining 60 percent of the animation time to be about the bounce effect.
So lets say at about 55 percent completion of the animation we want to bounce up a little bit.
So this line of code positions the element back in its natural position.
So let's have a bounce up just about six pixels.
Now were not complete yet but let's save this and see what it looks like.
So we saw that the element bounced once.
Here's another refresh.
It bounces once and then it's done.
I think it would be nice if we added a second bounce that's only 3 pixels.
So to achieve that we can create a few more intermediate states.
So let's say at 70 percent completion of the animation we want it to be positioned back again in its
natural state.
And then at 85 percent completion we want it to bounce up 3 pixels from its natural state.
So if I save and refresh we see the bounce effect.
Here it is one more time in terms of vertical movement.
I think it looks great.
But in terms of opacity I feel like we're fading to 2:04 opacity too soon.
So I'm going to move this line of code from the 40 percent state down to the 70 percent state.
So that way it will take longer to transition to fully visible.
So here is the updated effect.
It's a subtle difference but I believe it's an improvement.
Now that our bounce animation is complete I'm going to head over to the H DML and add back in the other
three blue boxes.
So we see all four boxes once again.
However they bounce into view at exactly the same moment and we want them to be staggered.
So one slightly after the other by default in animation will play immediately on page load.
Now that behavior is fine for our first box but we need to add a delay for the other three boxes.
Now there is a property named animation delay that will let us achieve just that in our CSSA file.
We see that we were adding the animation properties to the box a rule.
Now all four of these blue boxes have a class of box A.
So if we want to add a delay to only the second box we need a unique selector besides box A.
Now we could dig into the H DML and manually add a class of second to this box and manually add a class
of third to this box and forth to this box.
But that's a bit old fashioned.
Instead let's simply make sure that the common ancestor element of all four boxes this did with the
class of row.
Let's make sure that it has a unique class boxes.
Now in our C Ss will target the parent div boxes and then we can write colon enth child to box.
So this selector will only select and target the second box.
Now we can use the animation delay property and provide a value of point five seconds.
So if we save and refresh we see that box is 1 3 and 4.
Animate immediately but box 2 waits point five seconds before animating.
So now all we need to do is duplicate this rule and select only the third box and tell it to wait a
full second and then let's also duplicate the rule and select only the fourth box and tell it to wait
1.5 seconds.
So now if we save and fresh we see that all four boxes are staggered or offset by point five seconds
.
However our effect still doesn't look quite right because we need our content to be invisible while
it's waiting to be animated in.
So we need to adjust our SS The base rule for box elements before the animation even occurs.
We want the capacity to be zero now because we are making the elements deep for opacity zero.
We need to use a special property named animation film mode and provide a value of forwards. This way
when the animation completes the web browser will use the hundred percent completion state as the permanent
values.
Without this property of animation film mode forwards once the animation completes it would then use
opacity 0 again.
So with this line of code and this line of code in place if we save and refresh we see that we have
successfully offset or staggered the timing of the animation for the 4 boxes.
Now before we move on to the rotating star animation task I want to let you in on a bit of a secret
.
We don't need to type out these three animation based properties on three separate lines.
We can use shorthand and use a property named animation and then provide all of these values on one
line feed bounce one second forwards so that simplifies all three of these lines into one line of shorthand
code.
So when we save and refresh there is absolutely no change.
Our code is just that much cleaner.
We know that practice makes perfect.
So we've experimented with CSSA animations on these four blue boxes.
Let's practice once again by trying to recreate the star animation that we saw earlier.
So in our HMO I'm going to paste in the code for the star.
So if I save and refresh can see here is the star.
Now I will point out that the image element has a class of star assigned to it.
And in our CSSA the only code that's currently in place are a few properties telling it to have a width
of 25 percent of the available space and to have a height that is proportionate to that width.
Now that we are on the same page let's go ahead and write the code to create an animation for the star
.
So in our C Ss at symbol keyframes and then we can name our animation I will call this slide spin.
You can name it anything that you would like curly brackets.
Let's start simple for now let's only worry about sliding the star horizontally to the far right edge
of the available space.
So we'll say at 100 percent completion of the animation we want to use the transform property translate
X that is horizontally and push the content 300 percent from the left.
So when we use a percentage value with the translate function the percentage value is in relation to
the size of the element that it's being applied to.
Or in other words 100 percent is the exact size of the star itself.
Now the reason we used 300 percent is because we know the star takes up perfectly one quarter of the
available space.
So by saying 300 percent we're telling the start to move over three times its own size.
So one two three.
So that way it's right edge will be perfectly aligned with the right edge of the available space.
So with this very simple animation code in place let's add the slide spin animation to the star class
.
So within the Star rule I will say animation slides been two seconds.
So if we save and refresh
we see that the animation completes but then it very roughly and abruptly resets back to the far left
.
So again we can use the property animation fill mode forwards so that when the animation completes the
star will simply stay on the right.
Now you will remember that in the beginning of the lesson we saw the star demo.
It didn't just play once and then stop it kept playing.
Now there's a property named animation iteration count.
And this controls how many times the animation will loop through itself.
So if I say to the animation will play twice and then stop.
Now if we wanted to loop on forever we can provide a value of infinite.
And as you might expect the animation will then loop through itself infinitely.
Now it looks a bit odd that the star animates to the right and then performs a hard reset to the left
immediately.
So what if we wanted the animation to backtrack itself.
So in reverse every other pass through the loop there is a property named animation direction.
And if we provide it a value of alternate we see that the star smoothly transitions to the right and
then smoothly backtracks on itself and plays the animation in reverse to get back to the left side.
So now that our animation smoothly slides to the far right and then back to the left and alternates
infinitely We simply need to add additional states within the keyframes rule to perform the rotating
and change and size scale that we saw earlier in the lesson with the star.
So when the animation is 50 percent complete Let's alter the scale of it transform scale point five
.
However because we are using the transform property which we were also using for the horizontal positioning
we need to include that the translate X should be 150 percent.
So that way when the animation is halfway complete we are positioning it halfway horizontally 150 is
half of 300.
So if we save and refresh you can see that the star shrinks in scale when its in the middle of the horizontal
space.
Now the only effect that we're missing is that we want to start to also rotate or spin when it's in
the middle of the horizontal space.
So let's create an other state at 75 percent completion through the animation.
We want the star to stop moving horizontally for a moment.
So we'll provide an identical horizontal translate x value.
So it stays in place.
But we want to rotate 180 degrees and we want to remain at a scale of point five.
Now we only want the star to appear as if it's rotating when it's in the middle of the horizontal space
.
So we want the change in rotation to be between this state and this state because the star is staying
in place horizontally now because we don't want there to be rotation between this day and this date
.
We will edit our final state to also say that it should also have a rotation of 180 degrees.
So now when we save and refresh you see that the star is using the exact same animation that we saw
in the very beginning demo of the lesson.
Now once again I'll let you in on a bit of a secret.
We can use short pand to say that the animation should use a name of slide spin duration of two seconds
.
It should loop through infinitely.
It should use a direction of alternate and it should use a film mode of forwards.
So with this line in place we can remove these lines and if we save even refresh we see the exact same
effect only it took up less lines of code.
So we've completed the two examples for this lesson.
The blue boxes and the star.
But before we close the lesson there's a very important note our animation code will run perfectly in
Firefox and recent versions of Internet Explorer.
But if we want this animation code to run in Google Chrome Apple Safari and the majority of smartphones
we need to adjust our code just a tiny bit.
Step one anywhere we define and name an animation using the app keyframes rule we need to copy the entire
animation rule pasted.
And then in the original first copy after the at symbol include hyphen Web Kit hyphen step to anywhere
we use any of the animation based properties.
So whether that's the short and animation or any of the other properties like animation duration or
animation iteration count any animation based property again copy the line of code pasted in on the
original line include hyphen Web Kit hyphen.
That's it.
If you perform those two steps on all of your animation based code your animations will run perfectly
in a centrally.
Every modern device and browser and that's going to bring this lesson to a close at this point you should
be familiar with the basics of CSSA animations.
Now we have only scratched the surface of what's possible.
And if you're hungry to learn more about animations and transformations.
Be sure to check the description for this lesson to find information inspiration regarding what else
is possible.
Have fun and I will see you in the next lesson.