In this lesson we will continue to leverage javascript without writing javascript to be more specific
.
We will create a photo gallery that uses a modal window.
Let's dive straight into a demo of our finished product.
So here we see a photo gallery and let's imagine that I'm interested in the bear photo.
If I click on the bear you can see that the rest of the page is blacked out.
And the bear is front and center in design we typically call this a modal window or just a motile for
short means that we are taking the user's attention away from the main application or our main web site
and we're presenting them with a new window.
So let's say I'm done admiring the hi rez photo of the bear.
Users can return to the main page by clicking anywhere in the blacked out area or if I open it again
you can see there is an X that user can click the particular modal solution that I'm using also features
.
Forward and back arrows.
So it's very easy to cycle through the gallery and you can even use the arrows on your keyboard to go
left and right.
We also see text in the bottom left corner of the modal window which reads image 6 out of 8.
And if we go back to the bear we can see that some images even have captions.
This is a large bear.
This is a caption for the strawberry photo.
Now that's enough staring at a finished product.
I'm going to hop over to a different tab.
Now in this tab there is no modal functionality in place we can see that the photos are not aligned
in a perfect grid.
This barebones page has nothing more than basic HDMI out and CSX.
So this is the page that we are going to work on together to recreate the photo gallery grid layout
in the modal window javascript functionality should be a lot of fun.
Let's get started.
Currently from an HD a male perspective.
Our page is nothing more than eight instances of the image element.
Now very quickly let's review our recipe for creating this gallery.
There are two ingredients.
Number one is a bit of custom HTL and CSSA which we can write on our own.
No problem.
And number two is a pre-existing javascript solution named lightbox which is created by the talented
low cash to car.
So let's begin with the first ingredient the custom h t m l and CSS and in particular let's start with
the HMO.
So currently these thumbnail images are just that they're an image they're not a link.
So we want something to happen when we click on one.
So to turn a thumbnail image into a link we simply wrap the image element within the element A for anchor
within the opening a tag we will use the 8 ref attribute to control what we're pointing to.
So we want each thumbnail image to link to the high resolution uncropped version of that image.
So for example in my website folder Here's the web page.
Here's the images folder.
We see that there are two strawberry images strawberry dash thumb and just strawberry obviously the
thumbnail is the one that's named dasht thumb.
Let me open these two images for you.
So here's the thumbnail.
And here is the high resolution version that we want to link to.
So back to the HTL now we've wrapped the element around strawberry thumb.
So now in the Atropos attribute we enter the name of the image we want to linked to.
So it lives in the images folder and its name is simply strawberry d.j pig.
So if I save and refresh we can see that now and I hover over strawberry.
It's a link.
And if I click it it takes us to the high rez version.
Now clearly this is not a modal window.
We have not even plugged in our javascript solution yet.
Our web page is simply linking us to a new page or in this case to a new image so you can see that the
you are Albar changed to point towards the high rez strawberry file.
So we would have to now click our web browser back button to get back to our Web page.
But that's OK because that means that even without Javascript the user experience here makes sense.
Users can click on the thumbnail to see the high rez version.
We want javascript to be the polish.
The extra shine on top of a Web site we don't want our Web site to be completely broken.
If javascript is not enabled in someone's device.
So currently we are in great shape.
Now we just need to go through the rest of the images and set up links like we did for the strawberry
image.
Now I'm not going to waste your time and have you watch me do that for all 8 images.
But we will repeat ourselves at least once more just in the name of practice.
So let's work on the doc image in my images folder.
Here is the thumbnail doc thumb.
Here is the high rez file doc.
So here they are you can see that this thumbnails much smaller than the full copy.
So in our HMO We just want to wrap this doc thumbnail inside an element.
Here is the closing tag in the opening tag.
Let's add the ATRA of attribute and point towards the high rez copy of the doc so it lives in the images
folder instead of doc thumb its name is simply Dawk.
So I'll save refresh.
Now we can click on Doc there's the high risk copy I mean click on back.
All right now because I do not want you to die of boredom I will pause the video and come back when
the remaining six images are linked up.
Welcome back.
So now all of the images are wrapped in links pointing towards their high resolution counterpart.
I'm not going to worry about CSSA for the moment.
So currently the images are not aligned in a perfect grid.
We can circle back to that in just a couple of moments.
But for now let's get down to the fun part.
The Javascript.
Or in other words the modal window behavior we are going to use the javascript solution named the light
box.
So you can perform a web search for light box it's by location to car.
I've downloaded the zip file for light box.
Here it is.
Now I'm going to extract the zip so the zip created a folder named lightbox and within that folder we're
going to drill down to the javascript folder.
And here's the file that I'm looking for light box Dot meant yes.
So I want to copy this file into my web site folder.
So back in our Web site folder.
Let's move up and out of the images folder.
Here's our Web page.
And let's move in to the js folder.
So currently the only file in here is Jquery.
So I'm going to move this new light box dot minJs file to live within our jazz folder.
And now we need to include this file in the head section of our Web page.
So over in our HTL I already have Jayco are included in the head section from a previous lesson.
You most likely will as well.
So we can simply duplicate that line in the new line change the file that we're looking for to light
box.
Jay is excellent but we are not done moving files around yet.
So in the folder that the Lightbox zip created there is also a CSSA folder and we are interested in
the Lightbox Scott CSSA file.
So I want to move that into our web sites CSSA folder.
So let's move.
Lightbox Yes that's perfect.
Now let's reference this in the head section of our HTL now.
So I will duplicate the line that we already have.
It's calling in our style sheet.
And then just change the name that the browser looking for lightbox does CSS.
Now with the Lightbox javascript and CSSA files in place we are one incredibly easy step away from having
modal behaviour.
So let's scroll down to our thumbnails.
Let's start with the strawberry image.
So on the A element I'm going to add a new attribute named Data light box and you can provide a value
of anything that you would like.
So I will use Galerie you could use gallery one gallery too.
You could use any word that you would like.
So again I will use gallery now when I save and refresh if I click on the strawberry image you can see
that it opens in a modal.
Now very quickly let's analyze what the javascript is doing.
So the script actively searches the page for any links that have an attribute of data lightbox and when
it finds those elements it hijacks the click or tap event instead of sending this to a new page to visit
this link or this image.
It dynamically pulls in the image in a modal window.
So this means we need to add the data box attribute to all of our thumbnail links.
So I will copy and paste.
Now I will point out that the value we assign to data lightbox controls which images are grouped together
.
So for example because our first two links both use the phrase gallery.
When I click on the strawberry we see this note that says image 1 of 2.
So if I click the right arrow on my keyboard image to have two.
However in our second link we provided a different value for data light box.
If we said image 2 or any other phrase the images will not be considered a group.
So now the right arrow on my keyboard does not do anything and we do not see the text telling us one
of two.
So on and so forth.
Now we want all of our images to be grouped together in a single series so we want to make sure that
all of our links use data like box with the value of gallery so behind the scenes I will add that to
all of our links.
Welcome back.
So with that attribute and value in place on all of our links if I click on one of our images you can
see the text that reads.
Image one of 8 and the arrows on my keyboard can be used to cycle through all 8 images.
However if we think back to the beginning of this lesson when I first showed the finished product you
will remember that there are supposed to be.
Forward and back arrows and also an X to close the modal.
Now all we need to do.
For those to be in place is head over to the folder that the light box zip created.
Look inside the EMG folder and copy over these four great images into our images folder.
Now it's important to point out that the Lightbox CSSA file is looking for these images in an EMG folder
.
But in our demo we've named our images folder images not just I m g.
So to fix this all we need to do in our text editor is open the Lightbox dot CSSA file and on the third
line of code we can already see an example of what we need to adjust instead of EMG this should read
images.
So I'm going to perform a find and replace on Mac.
This is usually accomplished by holding the command key and simultaneously pressing f if you're on Windows
you can hold down the control key and simultaneously press F.
So I want to find all instances of dot dot image and I want to replace it with dot dot images.
I will then click replace all save.
And now if we refresh and see the x is in place and if I cycle through the images we can see both the
forward and back arrows are in place.
Now there was one final lightbox attribute that I want to run by you before we work on customizing the
thumbnail grid with our own CSX.
So very quickly let's talk about how to add a caption for these images.
So let's imagine that we want to add a caption for the strawberry photo in our HTL.
Now we can simply add an additional attribute to the link element Deda title and we can pass it any
value we would like.
This is a strawberry.
So now when we open the model there is the caption for that image.
It's that simple.
So the modal window aspect of our gallery is complete before we close out this lesson.
Let's write a bit of CSSA to fine tune the grid of thumbnails.
So for example Let's hop back over to the finished product that we saw in the beginning of this lesson
.
You can see they're spaced out just right.
And when we hover over one the rest of the thumbnails are dimmed and shrunk a bit and the one that we're
hovering over is rotated in there's a shadow.
Now some could say that this looks cheesy or gimmicky.
I might even be one of the people that says that but I think this is a fun exercise to practice writing
CSS.
So let's hop back over to our tab that we're working on together and implement a bit of custom CSS.
The first thing that I will do is head over to the HTL mill and wrap all of our thumbnails in a div
that has a class of thumbnails.
So this way I have a unique class to target in our CSA is now in our style sheet create a bit of space
create a comment some nail styles and we're off to the races now before we write any CSSA Let's give
ourselves a goal.
I want there to be four thumbnails per row.
So in my style sheet I will create a rule that targets any element or link that lives inside the thumbnails
Div I will float them to the left and give them a width of 25 percent because 25 times 4 is 100 percent
.
So we will fit four on a row so that save here.
And because we used floats Let's go clear our floats.
So I'm going to add a class of group to the parent thumbnails element to this way it will clear the
floats of its children.
So if we refresh in the browser we see that the images are perfectly resized and repositioned to fit
for Parow.
Now if you're following along in order for your images to be able to resize dynamically you'll need
to make sure that your style sheet includes a bit of code for images.
So towards the top of my style sheet I have a rule that selects all images and gives them a max width
of 100 percent without code similar to this.
Your images will not be able to resize on the fly.
So with that public service announcement out of the way now let's focus on creating margin horizontally
between the thumbnails.
Now what may be a bit counterintuitive but I actually prefer to use padding instead of margin.
So padding right with say 15 pixels now on its own.
This will break the layout because 25 percent plus 15 pixels will result in more than 100 percent of
the available width.
But we can simply say box sizing border box and other 15 pixels will be subtracted from the 25 percent
with.
So that once again it will equal a perfect 100 percent.
And because we do not want there to be 15 pixels of padding right on the last column we can simply apply
a negative margin to the thumbnails container element margin right negative 15 pixels perfect.
Now let's also fine tune the vertical margin between the rows of images.
Let's begin by zeroing out this default spacing which is present because images are inline elements
by default.
So this means they can be affected by things like font size and line height.
To counteract this we can simply make them block level elements.
So now we see the vertical spacing is gone.
And now we can provide a very specific vertical margin.
So on our elements I would simply say margin bottom 15 pixels.
So now we have consistent spacing horizontally and vertically.
Now all that remains is to add a fun hover effect for individual images.
Let's hop over to our CSX.
I will create a new rule thumbnails image hover.
So when an image is hovered over let's rotate it a tiny bit clockwise.
And let's also give it a shadow transform.
Rotate 2 degrees give it a shadow box shadow.
I want the shadow to be visible on all four edges so I won't move horizontally of vertically but I will
control the spread to be 7 pixels and I will use a light black or a transparent black value.
So it's save see what that looks like.
I like it.
Now let's imagine that when we hover over one image we want all of the other images to fade out and
shrink a bit.
So to do that all we need to do is create a different rule and our style sheet select the thumbnails
parent div and say when it is hovered over select all images to lower their opacity.
And lets also reduce their scales or transform scale.
Let's try 92 percent point nine to now in our hover rule for the image that is actually being hovered
over.
Be sure to set it scale to native or default 1.
Let's also set its opacity to 1.
So now when we hover over one them now all of the others sit back a bit and let the Hubbard image steal
the show.
Now I would prefer that the rotation and the change in size happened smoothly instead of all at once
in one millisecond.
So to make the transition smooth.
All we need to do is target this baseline rule for the thumbnail images add a new declaration transition
.
All properties should take 200 milliseconds and to make it extra smooth.
Let's use the ease in out timing function much better and that will bring this lesson on creating a
photo gallery with a modal window to a close.
As always you can find a zip file of the finished product in the related files.
For this lecture I encourage you to experiment with your own photo galleries.
Have fun and I will see you in the next lesson.