Before we move on here's a quick review of what we've learned in the first section of this course.
Number one we've learned that HVM mail is incredibly ubiquitous.
It's everywhere.
Obviously every web page is made up of HMO.
But even beyond that once we start talking about device native apps on your smartphone or tablet.
Many of these apps have some sort of HTL rendering engine embedded in them.
So there are many times when you probably don't even realize you're viewing HVM content.
It's everywhere.
Number two we learned that web pages are made up of elements and creating an element is like making
a sandwich.
The first piece of bread is the Start Tag.
Then you include the peanut butter and jelly or the meat the content and then you include a second piece
of bread.
The closing tag number three we've learned that elements can nest or stack inside one another much like
the example of a set of Russian stacking dolls.
So to create a bullet list an HMO we take multiple list item like elements and we nest them inside an
unordered list element.
Number four we learned about document structure.
So we learned that all of our web pages have the root element of HTL and then inside that element we
have the head section and the body section in the body section where we include content while the head
section is where we include information about the page.
Finally number five we learned about HTML attributes.
We learned that we can assign attributes to certain age TNL elements to make them come alive.
In particular we learned how to use the ref attribute on the link element to make our link fully functional
.
And we discussed that in future lessons we'll learn how to use different attributes on other elements
Just a quick heads up that if you have a spare moment or two I would really appreciate it if you could
go and rate and review this course.
I hope you're enjoying the course and finding it helpful.
But even if you're not above all else an honest review is the best review.
And I would love for prospective students to be able to see honest impressions of the course.
That concludes this quick review for the first section of the course.
I'll see you in the next section.