In every course I create,
I always end up with some favorite module or clip I get to talk about.
Sometimes this is just because it's a fun subject,
and other times it's because I think it's a topic
where we all get the most benefit.
In this case, it's a bit of all of the above.
Everything you've learned so far leads up to the super exciting
topic that allows you to go out and create your own constructs
and expose them for others to reuse.
So in this module, here's what we'll do.
First, we'll spend a few minutes setting up a registry in npmjs.
Npmjs is free for public packages, just like GitHub,
in fact,
they're owned by GitHub now. There are a million tools out
there where you can set up your own registry running
privately in your own AWS account.
I won't show it because it's beyond the scope of this course,
but setting up a Verdaccio server on an EC2 instance
literally takes about 10 minutes.
They even have Docker images for setting it up,
so there really is no barrier to entry on running it in
ECS or another container registry.
Head over to verdaccio.org, and I promise you'll agree how easy it is.
In our case, we're going to use npmjs,
and I'll keep the packages public so you can build stacks
directly from my registry if you like.
Once we get our registry up and running,
we'll have a place to publish our new custom packages.
As I said,
it would be hard for me to build every single construct we have and still
make the demo app easy to deploy, so we're going to build and deploy a
static website S3‑bucket‑driven app that uses an S3 deployment and a
CloudFront distribution in front of it.
Once we get that published in our registry, we'll come back in
and build a brand‑new Static Website App stack where we'll use
our new custom construct. And, oh yeah, don't forget about testing.
While I could go build a full course on testing CDK applications,
I'll scratch the surface with tools out there such as Jest to
ensure your constructs behave as you would expect.
Alright, this is a fun one.
So let's get through a few quick slides and spend all of our time in
demos for the rest of the module. With a little bit of English slang
to hammer the point home, it ain't magic,
folks.
It's just an npm registry where you publish your code.
If you've never had any experience with setting up a registry,
just head over to docs.npmjs.com and read through the docs.
We'll be running a simple npm publish to get our code up into our registry.
Now the documents explain how to version your code,
how to set a profile, and how to connect to your registry.
I'll go through that quickly in the publish demo as well,
so you can see it in action.
And if you've ever wondered why every time we have to
install a CDK package you have to prepend it with
@aws‑cdk, this is where you'll learn it.
In short, packages referenced in this way are simply scoped packages,
and in this obvious example, they privately belong to Amazon.
Scoping allows you to create a suite of related packages that may have
the same name as another user without a conflict.
Unscoped packages are always public and private
packages are always scoped, however,
you can create scoped public packages as well.
Inevitably,
if you're going to get into the world of building constructs
as private packages for your organization,
as is how Globomantics will be, you'll logically be using
organizations with npmjs or npm Enterprise in some paid account
or potentially some other registry tool.
If you haven't grasped a good use case to talk to your boss about yet,
let's peek at a simple example.
Many organizations might use buckets that include the
highest level of security possible.
Perhaps this is used by Legal,
HR, Accounting or some other department that stores PII,
credit card numbers or some other scoped information.
In that case,
you could set its required parameters to be allowed by only a
select few pre‑created roles publicly blocked,
heavily logged, include a stronger retention policy for
data, versioned, and possibly set up or backed in multiple
regions or availability zones.
That's the simple basis for our Highly Secured
Bucket construct for our business.
I capitalized the letters, as we've turned it into a proper noun
referring to our business's custom construct used by all
appropriate secure or confidential affairs.
Pretty simple concept, right?
Hopefully it's clear that you can build just about anything
that you can dream up and you can share it accordingly with
your company or the world.
At this point, I think we've talked about it enough.
Let's jump forward to the next module and start getting our registry ready to host packages.