We can't rightfully wrap up a CDK course without talking about security.
Now don't get me wrong, this module isn't a primer in any way on IaM.
Roles, policies, grants,
and resource policy usage is all very clearly defined in the
security section of the well‑architected framework.
There are also many Pluralsight courses on security around AWS.
Instead,
in this module we're going to talk about best practices in the
context of aspects, a neat, newish feature in AWS that allows for
extreme flexibility in the world of governance.
The internet likely has thousands of pages and articles on
securing AWS accounts to any degree.
In fact, security is widely known as the highest priority for AWS.
In the shared security model they secure all the
underlying assets, as you likely know, while you,
the end user,
are responsible for your own logical security of your
systems and application layers. You can read Bibles on the
principle of least privilege.
If you aren't familiar with these principles I highly encourage you to study
up on them, as a responsible developer of CDK technology.
If we shift gears a bit and focus solely on principles of CDK
security we can apply most of the same logic. IaM concepts such as
roles and policies should be designed,
reviewed, and evaluated against the operational nature of your business.
Further,
they should be enforced by some governance process as CDK developers were able
to build assets simply by following these rules as created.
That shouldn't be any different than following any coding
convention process in regular application development.
Where we can make a bit of an impact is in the new world of aspects in the CDK.
Aspects allow us to build in logic to our constructs to ensure they follow
these rules as defined. If highly‑secured buckets need a seven‑year
retention policy we can write an aspect for that.
If website buckets are only allowed to be accessed by a CloudFront role
we can write an aspect for that as well. You can almost think of
aspects as a unit test around security around which we can build best practices into our CDK constructs.