So let's see how this works in practice.
There are a handful of techniques to achieve true dynamic
and reusable multi‑environment scenarios.
Depending on your environment, one or all of these methods may benefit you.
Achieving fully‑dynamic deployments means that any resource,
construct,
or stack can be deployed to any region dynamically as
dictated by pre‑conditioned metadata.
Besides dynamic geography,
these stacks can be set up to be as dynamic as you wish them to be.
As you've seen so far,
there always seems to be about a dozen different ways to do anything with AWS.
As I said in the last slide,
this is absolutely the case as well in setting up
environments for multi‑target deployments.
And in most cases, it's actually easier than you think.
In fact, many of these techniques aren't even really AWS specific.
If you've been connecting to AWS using the CDK so far,
you've certainly set up credentials for yourself and likely multiple profiles.
Profiles are the simplest way to deploy to multiple accounts or regions.
Since profiles are a relatively simple command line option,
I'm going to focus more on the dynamic coding techniques going forward.
The most rudimentary path forward here is to simply embed the
environmental metadata into the project itself.
As I showed in the last module,
you can also use the context key value store to house
environmental meta characteristics as well.
From there,
it's not uncommon for organizations to use heavy scripting logic through
bash or PowerShell to control the deployment logic.
Even a lambda could theoretically act as a controller for deployments.
When you're ready to just store all environment meta definitions in the cloud,
either for security reasons or just for convenience,
the SSN parameter store is a great option as well.
And finally,
any combination of these tools and methods can be employed to your enterprise.
How about an IT service management system like ServiceNow acting as a request
and fulfillment trigger for your environmental request,
using a sophisticated approval workflow or even the
AWS Service Catalog tool itself.
So let's start simple.
Let's start by embedding properties in code.
In this simple example,
we're storing the current environment to be a dev‑local environment
through the simple use of an object and a property.
And we're able to store all environment‑specific meta
characteristics accordingly for the environment designated.
Now I know what you're saying, this about as rigid as it can be.
Well, you're correct.
We'll start pulling these out in a second.
In this object,
we're storing all characteristics for dev‑local and dev‑integration accordingly.
Admittedly, you'd like to have hundreds more properties here,
but I've only used the account and EC2 characteristics
for each to keep the example simple.
Local‑dev will default to T2.Nano instances while
dev‑integration would use T2.Micro instances.
So now as we create our stacks, we're using simple logic‑based actions.
For local development environments,
we don't create a CDN as we do for dev‑integration.
Another nice feature of using a structured programming language here
is that we can overload the stack constructors and optionally pass in
what we need based on the logic we need.
In the example above,
we deploy dev‑local and dev‑integration to the same AWS account,
whereas in higher level environments such as test,
we may choose a different target.
Let's take this one a step further with context to make it a bit more usable.
So again, in this case,
we strip out the hard‑coded designation of the environment
and keep our environment data metaobjects.
However, in this case,
assuming that the environment value is either stored in
the context JSON file or it's passed in through the
context flag from the command line,
we can acquire the necessary environment without the in‑line hard coding Again,
if you're thinking here that you could just store all
the meta information and context, including the environment props,
you're correct.
I could take this one step further and strip this
out into the context JSON file.
You can imagine that you might not want to pass on all
these properties on the command line, either.
SSN's going to behave the same way, acting as a parameter store.
Let's move the environment data out of the local file and
into SSN and see how things change.
So I just went ahead and created eight parameters in the SSN parameter store.
In order to facilitate object‑like storage,
these are created in the form of hierarchies.
When you combine nodes in your head, you can see a picture of these objects.
While I'm not the biggest fan of this feature in the AWS Systems Manager,
as a large enterprise might amass 100,000 of these,
they're still searchable and thankfully sorted in alphabetical order.
Looking at the first one in the list,
I created a Default‑env parameter in the event that an
environment is not chosen during synthesis.
I set the value to dev‑local so any non‑designated apps would
default to the lowest common denominator.
From there,
I simulated our object we'd formally stored in code using a simple hierarchy.
These are the account regions used for dev‑integration environments,
as well as the default EC2 instance choices.
So now let's look at using a combination of SSN in context in our code.
First, I set the environment designation based on a passed‑in context value.
If for any reason it's incorrect or null,
I pull the default environment value out of the SSN
parameter you saw a second ago.
Naturally, in a real‑life scenario, you'd likely put more error checking in here,
but I'm trying to keep things simple for you.
At this point, we no longer need to store the multi‑environment property objects.
We're able to dynamically build the SSN parameter from the
environment and set the property values 100% dynamically.
Note that these will be tokens at synthesis time and then get
replaced at deployment time with real values.
And lastly,
we're able to use these values from context or SSN parameters as
we build our construct and stack definitions.
Think of how easy it is now to do something like store all your S3 buckets
in one region and your Cognito user pool in another.
At this point,
we haven't even discussed CI/CD or the ability to create a full
pipeline from dev all the way through to production.
That's coming up in the next clip,
so we'll wait to refactor our code a bit in the next module as we talk more about context and avoiding tight coupling in AWS.