Before we dive into the last module,
let's take a moment and apply a measure of aspects in our demo application.
Let's ensure that our website bucket is only accessible by the CloudFront role,
and that versioning is turned on for all CodeBuild asset buckets.
A required property for using buckets is CodeBuild sources.
To implement the aspect,
we simply build a class that implements the IAspect interface.
Then, inside the class definition,
we only need to implement the visitor function to create our aspect checker.
Admittedly,
sometimes the construct properties can get a little difficult to realize,
which is where the documentation becomes our best friend.
In this example,
we first pass our configuration property to an isResolvable method to
ensure that the resource exists, and then finally check that the
value of the property is set to enabled.
It's a bit verbose, to be sure,
but after you look up properties in the stack node and then assess their values,
it gets easier and easier.
And then finally, from within the stack class,
you just have to call the applyAspect method, instantiating a new
version of the class you just created. Execution of the aspect happens
during the prepare phase of the CDK lifecycle,
at which time the visit method is called.
See how it feels a bit like a unit test? Let's look at a more
complex example with website bucket aspect. Again,
we need to build a class that implements the IAspect
interface and defines the visitor function.
In this case,
we loop through a policy document of the bucket object and grab the statements.
In each statement,
we seek out the principle values associated with the statement.
From there,
we can perform just about anything we want to ensure our
bucket meets the standards we set forth.
We could ensure that the only action is an S3 get, and we
can ensure that the only principle value matches whatever
our CloudFront identity would be.
In this case,
I just typed a fictitious value for our identity. And finally, from
within our stack, our aspect will get executed.
Now you may have noticed in the last two examples, I
didn't check for the node object type,
which means that this is going to run against all
objects contained within the stack.
So we'd want to embed more logic to ensure that it runs for only the CFN bucket,
where the static website hosting feature is enabled.
Otherwise it would impact our other buckets. You could also create a single
bucket checker that includes all your bucket logic in one class.
So let's take a live look of these aspects in action.
If I go back to our construct file,
you can see that right here, I added two extra properties to the construct.
They're both optional.
I added a bucketVersioned boolean and a requireBucketEncryption boolean.
As I said, they're both optional,
so you don't have to version the buckets, and you
don't have to require encryption.
However, if you are going to use buckets for deployments for CodePipeline,
they do have to be versioned.
So I'm going to go ahead and turn this on once I get
back over to my stack application.
Now I've gone ahead and republished this to npmjs as version 2.0. So
let's switch back over to the stack app itself.
Now what I've done is created an aspects folder, which you
can see at the top left here. And inside that aspects
folder, I've created two classes.
The first class is called BucketVersioningChecker,
and if I scroll down a little bit, there's a BucketEncryptionChecker.
Now,
as we just discussed, both of these implement the CDK IAspect
interface, and both implement the visitor function. Now to take a
quick peek at this, the first thing I've done is made sure that
what we're looking at are buckets, and that this is not going to
run against anything else.
And then from there I have a simple bit of logic to go
through and implement the aspect.
The first thing I do is just make sure the version and configuration
exists and isn't null, and then I make sure to exclude the case where
the property is a token by using the Tokenization.isResolvable
method. And this will go ahead and skip over that situation where
that value is tokenized.
But suffice it to say, the main logic exists right here,
where it says,
node.versioningConfiguration.status is not equal to
Enabled. And if it's not enabled,
it goes ahead and uses the Annotations class, and creates an
error against the node that it's running against.
Now if I scroll down and look at the other aspect, now
here, instead of checking for versioning,
I'm just checking for bucket encryption, and similarly,
if bucket encryption is not turned on at all,
or the bucket is unencrypted,
the aspect is going to fail with the error of bucket encryption is not enabled.
So if I go back to my main application file and scroll down,
you can see that I turned bucket versioning off and bucket
encryption to off to trigger my aspects.
And at the bottom of this file, I apply the aspects to my app.
So if I run a cdk synth,
you can see that there are my two errors complaining that bucket
versioning and bucket encryption are both not enabled.
So let's go ahead and turn those on, re‑compile, and I'll go ahead
and clear this screen, just so you so you can see this a little
bit better. Now if we do a cdk synth, let's see what happens.
Now we can see that the application synthesized exactly
as we'd expected without any errors, So that's really all there is to it,
and you can go as deeply as you want in creating
aspects across your application.
So to check back in, Ellen and Josh have once again met with the architecture
and security groups at Globomantics, and after learning about Jest‑based
construct testing in the versatility of aspects,
they've documented a testing and governance strategy around all custom
constructs that are built. With as many developers as they have, they've
created a security mantra of embraced security at the developer level to
implement these policy checks before the constructs are ever deployed. In the
last module, I'm going to try and pique your interest into pressing forward
with CDK by showing you a super cool concept implementation of building C DK from a UI‑driven interface.