Now, I know what you're thinking.
Why are we talking about VPCs when there are none in our application?
Well, even though that's the case,
you'll very likely build a CDK application in the
future that does require a VPC.
To that end, I'm going to show another popular method for decoupling systems,
and that's to look up the VPC dynamically when creating
dependent objects such a subnets and EC2 instances.
We've already done this once, so let's take a look again in the context of a VPC.
If we need to find a VPC by querying an AWS environment,
we can use the popular fromLookup method.
Remember the fromStringParameterAttributes method I showed you
earlier creates tokens that are populated during synthesis and
replaced at deployment time.
From Lookup and valueFromLookup, which we just used,
populate real values during synthesis.
It makes sense, right?
These functions are physically looking up the value when the function is called.
If we have less information about the VPC we're looking for,
we can use the fromVpcAttributes method,
which is obviously more specific to a VPC.
The last parameter of this method takes a VpcAttributes object,
which we can query by several properties.
Let's see these in action.
Called context methods, they're quite simple to use,
but often highly overlooked.
It's just not that complicated to look up a VPC in an account,
and in most cases and in many scenarios,
the VPC and subnets are already going to exist,
especially in an environment like production.
We first check to see if the VPC is cached in the context store like this,
as you saw in the last module.
Then we can use one of the two methods in an attempt to look up the VPC,
in this case, with fromLookup like this.
The other method from VPC attributes is a bit more versatile and can allow
us to look up VPCs with a wider range of attributes.
Alternatively, we can use both in a turnery and look up a.VPC if the ID exists.
Otherwise, use the default VPC in the target account.
We could even take that turnery one step further and physically create a new VPC if both conditions fail.