Alright, now we're cooking.
Hopefully you've been able to follow along.
Now that we have a construct in our registry ready to be consumed, let's go see
how to use that construct in the creation of a new stack.
So in that regard,
let's go build a brand new CDK application that uses our
new construct from our construct library.
So before we go ahead and initialize another CDK
stack and start using our construct,
I noticed that there were a couple of things that we
needed to add to this before it was usable.
So if I scroll down just a little bit in our construct,
you can see that I went ahead and I actually added a
policy to that website bucket.
The version that we had had no policy,
so we were bound to get an access denied by simply accessing the bucket.
Now,
the other simple thing I did is I actually used the
project name in the name of the bucket,
and that's just to ensure that our bucket names are unique.
And the last thing that I did is I added a couple of
convenient outputs right here as well.
So as soon as this is done deploying, it would at least give you the
website bucket URL and the CDN URL for convenience.
So let's re‑compile this, and let's check the version we have right now.
I could open the package.json, or I could type npm version.
We're using version 0.6.0. So let's advance that to
0.7.0, and let's re‑publish that package.
And now that we've got version 0.7.0 published,
let's go ahead and initialize a new stack.
So I've created a directory called cdk s3‑static‑website.app,
and I want to go ahead and run a cdk init. So let's go ahead
and start working on our new app.
I'm going to create a properties object,
which we're going to inject into our new class.
Obviously, it's going to complain, because the interface doesn't exist there yet.
Let's go ahead and save that for now, and let's go ahead and create that
interface. And let's rename it to WebsiteAppStackProps,
and we're going to make those required in our class,
and now we're ready to create our construct.
So let's go ahead and pull in our cdk‑s3‑static‑website construct. And
now we're ready to go ahead and create the resource.
And now we know exactly what these properties are going to look like.
So for now, I'm just going to copy them straight out of the interface.
And now what I'll do is just go ahead and fix them up
really quickly. And we're almost there.
Everything should work fine in our class.
And if I run a tsc from here,
generally what happens is the test project that's created complains.
We'll go ahead and comment that out, and everything is
happy from a compilation standpoint.
So everything looks good at this point.
We know that our project name is going to be my static website.
We don't yet have an assets folder, and as a testament to that fact,
if I run a cdk ls, it's going to complain that the assets folder doesn't exist,
which it doesn't.
So inside the assets folder, we'll make an index.html, and we should be
ready to go at this point. So I don't need to re‑compile,
because all that I changed was the asset folder in the index file.
So let's run a cdk ls again at this point, and our interface just saved us.
We know that our website bucket can only have lowercase characters.
So let me go ahead and fix that.
That's why we create interfaces, and we should be good to go again.
Let's re‑compile, and we should be ready to list,
synthesize, and deploy at this point.
Let me clear that and run an ls again. All is right with the world, so let's
go ahead and deploy. And remember, the CDNs take about six or seven minutes
to deploy, so I'll go ahead and fast‑forward.
And with all things correct,
our cfn outputs should give us the link to our CDN URL, as
well as the link to our website bucket.
So we'll be right back.
And once it's done deploying, we get our convenient outputs that we can click on.
So if I click on the bucket URL itself, we can see that there is our index.html that we spent so much time on.