That was easy, right?
Creating stacks without dependencies is as simple as building
out individual disconnected constructs.
In the real world, resources have to talk to other resources.
Fortunately,
a lot of the techniques available for communicating between
stacks are techniques you would use in building everyday
TypeScript applications in the first place.
So let's refactor our first stack that'll include dependencies.
The CloudFront stack will require the bucket information
from which its web origin is represented.
Alright, so we have our To Do file open again.
So let's follow the same process for the CloudFront stack,
or the CdnStack in this case.
So I'm going to go ahead and create the stack file,
and then I'm going to go ahead and update the full‑stack application file.
So I've already created the folder and the TypeScript file,
so let's go ahead and do this same process,
and grab the source, and see what we've got.
So, already out of the gate,
I know that I am missing a property called CdnIndexDocument,
and that's okay, that's another property that we were interested in.
Let's go ahead and paste that in as an interface as well,
and then let's pass our CdnProps into the constructor. And now
let's change that toprops., and that's resolved.
But what you'll notice is that the CloudFront
distribution wants access to the websiteBucket.
Well, now we're running into a new situation.
The websiteBucket is another construct that came from our
S3Stack that's actually created on the fly.
So how do we deal with this?
This is something that's not even resolved until deployment time.
And further, if I go back into the full‑stack file and paste in that library,
and then we instantiate a CdnApplicationStack,
everything should be working, right?
Well, it's not, we know it's not, because when we go back over to the cdn file,
we know that we need some dynamic properties here.
So here's where we jump into the concept of interest.communication.
So let's stop and take a quick break and look through all
the methods by which you can actually pass needed
properties and data in between stacks.
There are quite literally more than half a dozen ways to
communicate between distributed resources in AWS,
and these translate well into CDK parlance.
In most cases,
these will resolve to ImportValue function calls in
the synthesized cloud assembly.
One of the most common ways to pass data from stack to stack is the
simple technique of passing properties along as parameters on the
constructor of the dependent stack.
You likely do this in all your coding today,
so this should be relatively elementary to you in practice.
Another technique I see a lot is to use the stack props of the
dependent object to send properties through.
This concept is somewhat similar to simple parameters, it
just gives you a little clearer picture of the needed
properties for each dependent stack.
When you simply have too many properties to pass,
passing the instantiated stack object is just fine.
Now, that can be a heavy payload for sure,
but in most cases we aren't talking about massive objects.
If you had a stack with 100 resources in it,
you might choose a different method of communication if the
dependent stack only needs a few properties.
Other nontraditional code techniques include context variables.
Context is essentially a name value pair keystore that can be used
throughout the entire application lifecycle.
You can build keys and values in the context JSON file,
and you can build the reference context in code.
In most cases, however,
context is used to cache information with the stack itself.
Then there's always existed the concept of environment variables.
Environment variables can be set and passed around
using the Definitely Typed module,
which is included in a cdk init via the process object.
Environment variables are a bit heavy to use to
simply communicate between stacks, however,
they are great choices when critical synthesize or deploy‑time
properties are needed across various resource types.
The demo application, for example,
uses environment variables to pass the Cognito user pool objects to
the buildspec used in the CodeBuild projects.
And last, but certainly not least,
the AWS Systems Manager includes a parameter store that can
store just about any attribute type you desire.
For fully dynamic deployments across dynamic regions,
you often need a global variable retrieved from some
place other than inside your code.
SSM parameters can also be set up as secure attributes.
As such,
they're a great candidate for any secure information needed during deployment.
Passing one‑off parameters as parameters is akin to Programming 101.
Using the stack constructor,
you can receive a value from the existing stack
declared as a public class member.
We declare our app and initial stack in the standard way,
assuming now that this stack exposes a public member.
We can then pass that value along in the creation of the dependent stack.
And as you'd expect,
the constructor is set up to receive this value and
use it as needed in the class.
Using stack properties is another clean way to pass
properties to the dependent stack.
We simply take advantage of the properties object passed into the
dependent class by combining the existing set of properties with any
new values using the spread operator like this.
Similar to the last view, we go ahead and create our app as usual.
Now I've created a few default dummy properties here as an object,
as you can see.
Now once our initial stack is created,
we can again pass our public member value along this
time through the stack properties.
Then in the dependent stack we can expose an interface
requiring the creation of any needed properties.
It's a very clean pattern that's easy to read,
and can help avoid long constructor signatures.
Using props in this way,
you also get to keep the constructor signature at its
baseline without adding additional parameters.
When you have too many parameters to bother reconciling and articulating,
you can pass the entire stack object to the dependent stack.
As I said earlier, the payload here can be high,
so you'd want to avoid passing a massive stack object to
a dependent stack out of laziness.
Just as before,
we'd simply create our stack and then pass it along to
the dependent stack constructor.
And, as you can guess,
the constructor is simply going to be set up to
receive the stack itself as a parameter.
Context is a highly misunderstood concept of the CDK world.
For the most part, it's generally not used for communicating between stacks,
but it certainly can be.
Context is generally used for setting and retrieving parameters from
the cachable context JSON file at synthesis time.
However, context can be set and retrieved with these methods.
Taking a simple example, I set a vpcid value to 123456 on Context,
and then I simply just receive it into a local vpc
variable with the tryGetContext method.
Environment variables are generally used for storing
and retrieving environmental data.
They're also very handy when values have to be passed across logical boundaries.
Environment variables aren't secure, but can be set and retrieved very easily.
In this simple code snippet, I set an environment variable,
MYVPC to the value of MyVPC.
I then retrieve it into a local vpcName variable.
Sure, you could use environment variables to pass data between stacks,
but that's generally not what they're used for.
To take what one might call system variables a step further,
AWS now has a Parameter Store in the Systems Manager.
SSM parameters are highly versatile and can be secured as desired,
such as for, say, a database root password.
They can also be read at either synthesis or deploy‑time,
depending on your needs.
To set a parameter, we simply set a new string parameter in the store.
Then to retrieve it, we use the fromStringParameterAttributes method like this.
Similar to environment variables,
SSM parameters are generally made for dynamic variable storage needs such
as regions or secure needs such as storing passwords.
You wouldn't really use SSM parameters in most cases
to pass simple data between stacks, however,
if you are deploying dependent stacks separately and
potentially in separate regions,
you can use the Parameter Store to grab needed global
variables at any time you need them.
So let's follow the new tasks in our To Do list.
At this point,
what we're going to do is use parameters between the two dependent stacks.
So the first thing we're going to need to do is expose the objects
from the source stack that we need, and in this case,
that's going to be the S3 buckets for the CDN.
After that, we just need to update the dependent constructor,
which in this case is the CdnStack constructor, to receive
the appropriate property at that point, which is the websiteBucket.
Then the last thing that we need to do is simply pass that
along when we instantiate the object.
So if I roll over and I look at the S3Stack,
the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to
expose the buckets as public properties.
So let me grab these and paste them in here. And now what
we're going to want to do is we're not going to want to
instantiate these. Instead,
we're going to want to use the private member variables.
So at that point,
we're all set on the S3Stack, so let me save that and move over to the CdnStack.
Now what we need is a parameter in the constructor to receive this value.
So I've created a websiteBucket as an S3 bucket in the
constructor, and I really don't have to change much because
that was the name of the property already.
So we're pretty much good to go here, so let me save that,
and then move over to the full‑stack file.
Now,
one thing I've done is I've created a useCdn property so that you can turn the
CDN on and off when you deploy. Now you can do this using Context or by some
other means, or you can just comment this out.
So now, instead of simply just instantiating the CdnStack as we did before,
I can use the props.cdn to conditionally instantiate the stack, and then I can
pass in the websiteBucket itself as the needed parameter.
So at this point, everything is good to go, and we could actually deploy.
Everything is wired up appropriately.
Now let's finish off the remaining four stacks by passing constructor
parameters for the LambdaStack, and then full‑stack objects as parameters
for the Cognito API Gateway in CodeAppStacks.
So now let's add a few items to our To Do list here. For a few of the
stacks, we're going to use the same technique we just did to pass
properties along through to the constructor. For a few of the other
stacks, we're going to pass entire stack objects.
So what we're going to need to do is update the dependent
stack constructors to make sure that they receive the
objects or the needed properties.
And then we're going to make sure that in the source classes we have public
members for sharing those properties. That says private,
it should say public.
And then from there, from our stack instantiation,
we want to make sure that we pass the appropriate properties or
complete stack objects through to the constructor we're
instantiating. So if I start back in the full‑stack file,
you can see that now I've created the other four stacks, and the LambdaStack
itself takes the goalsTable and dynamoDbRole as properties, so no full‑stack
here. And then Cognito doesn't have any parameters, but the ApiGatewayStack
takes the LambdaAppStack full‑stack object and the CognitoAppStack
full‑stack object as parameters.
And then finally,
the CodeAppStack takes all three of the other stacks as parameters.
So if I go over and I look at the code file, we can see that, quite simply,
all I'm doing is taking stack objects as
parameters, exactly as you would expect.
So now if I compile and run a cdk ls at this point,
you can see that we now have all stacks listed in our stack list.
And at this point now, if I deploy them all,
we'll get all full‑stacks deployed and connected together.
So these are not quite fully deployed yet, but if I go ahead
and flip over the CloudFormation console,
you can see now that each stack is being deployed independently,
which is exactly what we wanted.
Now that we're masters of distributed stack patterns and we have
a great start to a well‑designed application,
let's jump into the fun world of setting it all up to run in multiple environments.