Welcome to the machine learning half of the course.
It is now time to begin with the machine learning sections of the course this introduction section will
discuss a general introduction to machine learning theory in general and how sparks M-L lib library
works for machine learning.
In the machine learning half of this course most machine learning sections will have these following
points.
We'll have the suggested reading assignment based off a book called Introduction to statistical learning.
Then we'll have the basic theory lecture will all explain the basic theory for whatever machine learning
algorithm we happen to be working with.
Then we'll have a documentation walk through.
So I'll walk you through the actual documentation example for the code that aligns of whatever algorithm
we're learning.
Then I'll show you a more realistic custom code example.
So again I'll walk you through a more realistic version of custom code which works on another data set.
Then we'll have a consulting project and we'll discuss this later on.
But the consulting projects are going to be more open and looser where you're basically given some sort
of tasks to solve and you have the actual freedom to solve it in any way you want and then you have
the consulting project solutions where I will walk through a possible method to solve that particular
consulting project.
So again the consulting projects are looser there are more realistic projects to attempt with the skills
you just learned.
So what data set some background that a problem is described and you're free to solve it however you
want.
If you prefer a more guided approach to problems that's totally OK.
We have the custom code examples before each consulting project which walks you through an example.
Plus you could treat the consulting project solutions as an additional quote code along lecture.
So if you don't really have the learning style where you're faced with this kind of a loose open ended
problem and you want to just tackle it on your own you prefer for someone to guide you and code along.
Feel free to just skip the consulting project and go straight to the consulting project solutions as
an additional code along lecturer.
So really you have the flexibility there to learn in the way that works best for you.
And one more note because different students have different backgrounds in math.
We're going to try to keep the mathematics behind the machine learning algorithms light as far as what
we present in this course instead.
If you're actually interested in reading more about the actual math behind the algorithms we discuss
We're going to be using introduction to mystical learning by Gareth James as a companion book.
It's freely available online and will show you the links in the resources for it.
So students who want the mathematical theory should do the suggested reading assignment that will appear
for each machine learning section.
Otherwise if you're more interested in the actual practical implementation of these algorithms using
Python and Sparke you can just watch the introduction theory lecture for the fundamentals of the algorithm.
If you want to dive in more of the math feel free to do the suggested reading assignment.
So the first suggested reading assignment for this actual introduction to machine learning is to read
chapters 1 and 2 to gain a background understanding before continuing on to the rest of the machine
learning lectures.
So again check the resources for this lecture for an actual link to grab the introduction to mystical
learning book.
All right.
Now that we discussed how we approach machine learning in this course.
Let's take some time to actually discuss what machine learning is machine learning at its core is a
method of data analysis that automates analytical model building using algorithms that iterative we
learn from the data.
Machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly program where to
look.
And that's kind of the key idea.
You don't have to explicitly tell the actual algorithm what to do.
The algorithm it really learns from the data.
So what is machine learning is for.
It's used for a ton of applications.
Anything from fraud detection to predict the equipment failures e-mail spam filtering financial modeling
tech sentiment analysis recommendation engines so many applications.
So what does the actual machine learning process looks like.
Well this is actually a key to understanding machine learning.
So let's go through this sort of diagram of the machine learning process.
First you need to get your data from somewhere.
You can't do a machine learning algorithm if you don't have data.
So somehow you have to acquire data.
A lot of times if you're already working at a company where you just got a job at a new company they'll
actually have a ton of data will be stored in a sequel database a cxxviii file etc..
And luckily we already learned that Python and SPARC can read data from a wide variety of sources.
So once you've acquired that data sometimes usually you actually need to clean that data.
So if you have missing values you either need to fill them in or drop them.
Maybe you want to make some new features maybe have a date time column that we saw during the dates
and time stamps lecture and you actually just need the year etc. So that's kind of cleaning and managing
your data.
That's the next step.
Then once you've done that you're going to split your data and you get to split your data into a training
set and a test set.
There's also sometimes a three way split between training test and what's known as hold out.
But we'll explain that later on.
Right now we'll take the simpler approach of a training set and a testing set.
So we end up doing is you take your training set and you actually train your machine learning model
on that training set and then to actually evaluate how well your model performed.
You compare that train the model onto your test data.
The reason for this split is because your model was trained on the training data.
It's not really a fair evaluation to then say okay how well did it work with the training data.
Maybe you're trying to predict housing prices well you should work on some data that your algorithm
or your machine learning model has never actually seen before which is why we split it into test data.
Then you just do this process.
It's really until you figured out the best parameters for your machine learning model.
Once you have it ready to go you can then deploy that model onto brand new data.
Ok so now let's dive in a little more into different types of machine learning Spark's M-L lib library
is mainly designed for supervised and unsupervised learning tasks with most of the algorithms falling
under those two categories.
Let's discuss them in more detail and describe how they're different.
So we'll start of supervised learning supervised learning algorithms are trained using labeled examples
such as an input or the desired output is known.
For example a piece of equipment could have data points labeled either failed or are for runs.
So you have some sort of label.
Another example would be the housing price data.
You have various features of houses like how many rooms they have their location the amount of square
footage cetera and you have the actual label the price of the house.
So that's where supervised learning comes into play.
So that supervised learning algorithm receives a set of inputs along with the corresponding correct
outputs those labels and then the algorithm learns by comparing its actual output with correct outputs
to find errors that then modifies the model accordingly.
Through methods like classification regression prediction and gradient boosting supervised learning
uses patterns to predict the values of the label on additional unlabeled data.
So supervised learning is commonly used in applications where historical data predicts likely future
events.
So the main idea to go back to the housing example is you have a bunch of housing data you have all
these various features of houses and then you have the corresponding price they sold at.
So that's historical data.
And then once you've trained your model if you visit a new house that hasn't been sold it and you're
looking for the price to sell it.
You can use your model on this new unlabeled data but it was trained on label data that historical information.
So again for example it can anticipate when credit card transactions are likely to be fraudulent or
which insurance customer is likely to file a claim.
Or like I mentioned it can attempt to predict the price of a house based on different features for houses
for which we have historical price data.
So supervised learning a lot.
It's just historical data that's labeled.
And then you train your model on it and you're trying to predict for new unlabeled data that's going
to eventually come in.
So now let's discuss unsupervised learning.
So imagine they have all this historical data.
But it has no labels to begin with.
So you have these unsupervised learning against data that has no historical labels.
And the system isn't really told the quote unquote right answer such as the price of the house.
The algorithm must figure out what is being shown.
And the goal is to really explore the data and find some sort of structure within the data.
So as an example if you're dealing with customer data I can find the main attributes a separate customer
segments from each other.
Popular techniques include self-organizing maps nearest neighbor mapping Kamins clustering and singular
value decomposition.
One major issue with unsupervised learning is that it can be really difficult to evaluate the results
of an unsupervised learning model.
And the reason for that is because this data never had any labels to begin with.
She can't really compare to see how well you did because you're essentially trying to discover these
labels or try to cluster them in some way to find some sort of structure within the data.
Now this is a little confusing don't worry unsupervised learning can be a little hard to grasp at first
especially in just a theoretical conceptual argument.
When you actually see it in action and in this course will kind of deal with it.
With Kamins clustering it's going to make a lot more sense.
Ok some final thoughts on machine learning in general.
Machine Learning takes time to learn.
Be patient yourself and feel free to post to any forums and as a quick reference no one course can be
a reference for all machine learning topics.
So if you were looking for a particular algorithm it may or may not be in this course and also a particular
algorithm may or may not be even implemented in Python and Sparke.
So if you were looking for a particular algorithm and it's not in this course there is also the possibility
it's not even implemented in Python with SPARC So it was never available for you to begin with.
So keep that in mind.
However in this course we really are going to go over the major topics in major learning algorithms
that are available to you in Python and SPARC.
So you're pretty much going to get the wide view of what you can do with Python and Sparc and it's M-L
lib library.
Again I'm always happy to point you in the right direction for machine learning topics and that book
that we mentioned.
Introduction to learning is a really great base for you to begin your journey on discovering machine
learning.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to discuss the specifics of using Spark's M-L lib library and how it's a
little different than other Python machine learning libraries.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.