Hello everyone and welcome to the recommender systems section of the course we're going to learn how
to build a recommender system with SPARK in Python.
Now for this section the course there is no consulting project or documentation example for this section
because the actual ease of use of SPARC and recommender systems didn't really lend itself towards being
tested on.
I initially tried to create a consulting project but the real challenge behind creating a recommender
system where Sparc and Python falls outside the scope of SPARC in Python itself.
The challenge is getting the users getting them to submit feedback in a useful way.
Organizing your data and actually building an infrastructure that's outside what sparking in Python
do what SPARC is really good at is taking in that formatted data and then quickly building a recommender
system.
So the challenge is just getting that data and formatting it with everything that that entails actually
implementing the recommender system itself was sparked in Python is pretty straightforward which is
why there's no consulting project or even a documentation example.
So keep that in mind as we continue on through this course.
Now in case you are further interested in recommender systems and what we cover in this course I suggest
you take a look at this book recommender systems you can find that on Amazon.
It'll go into much more detail about the mathematics and general background behind that recommender
systems.
Also as a quick know fully developed and deployed recommendation systems can be complex and resource
intensive.
Even companies that you think really rely on recommendation systems like Netflix don't always get it
right on the first try even though they study this problem a lot they have a lot of resources and really
smart people working on this problem.
Netflix itself has switched from a star rating recommendation system to a simple thumbs up and thumbs
down.
And then some sort of percentage of how much they'll think you will enjoy this TV show or related movie.
So even these huge companies working on these really hard problems are still developing the best techniques.
So keep that in mind as we continue.
You'll usually want someone with previous experience implementing a production ready recommendation
system.
Ok so since full recommender systems require a heavy linear algebra background what we're going to try
to do is provide only a high level overview in this lecture.
Check out that book previously mentioned in the beginning of this lecture for a deeper look in the mathematics
behind this topic.
Now the two most common types are recommender systems are content based and collaborative filtering.
Otherwise known as C-f collaborative filtering produces recommendations based on the knowledge of users
attitudes towards items.
That is it uses what's known as the wisdom of the crowd to recommend items content based recommender
systems focus on the attributes of the items themselves and they give you recommendations based on the
similarity between those items.
In general collaborative filtering is more commonly used in content based systems because it usually
gives better results and it's actually relatively easy to understand from an overall implementation
perspective.
The algorithm has the ability to do feature learning on its own which means that it can start to learn
for itself what features to use.
These techniques aim to fill in the missing entries of what's known as a user item Association matrix
that is users on one axis of that matrix and then items on another axis where the meeting point for
the user in the item would be some sort of rating value sparked the M-L currently supports a model based
collaborative filtering in which users and products are described by a small set of latent factors that
can be used to predict missing entries.
Spark thought and Mel uses the alternating least squares or HLS algorithm to learn about these latent
factors.
Your data needs to be in a specific format to work of sparks HLS recommendation algorithm and that's
really kind of the hard part the easy part is just deploying the recommendation algorithm.
The hard part is getting your data into that specific format and getting enough of it so HLS is basically
a matrix factorization approach to implement a recommendation algorithm.
You decompose your large user item matrix into a lower missional user factors in item factors.
So to fully understand this model you actually need to have a strong background in linear algebra.
So check out the various resource links for more detail on HLS and how it works.
Let's try to give you an intuitive understanding of this all at least So when you actually approach
it of python and SPARC you have an idea of what it's doing in the background.
So let's imagine that we have three customers will just named this customers number one.
Number two number three and we also have some movies a b and c so we're kind of like Netflix just on
a super small scale.
And customers number one and number two really enjoy movies A and B.
And so they rate them five out of five stars.
And these customers number one and two also this like movie c they give it just a one star rating.
And now we have this new customer customer number three now Customer Number Three hasn't seen the movies
yet and wants to see movie A.
They really enjoy it.
So they give it a five star review.
So now as this movie service what's the new movie we should recommend on our platform movie B or movie
C.
Well based off a collaborative filtering model will recommend movie B because since users number one
and number two also enjoyed movie B and they enjoyed the movie similar to what customer three enjoyed.
And that's the basic idea behind collaborative filtering.
You use that wisdom of the crowd technique which I mean the intuitive level it makes sense if users
number one.
Number two enjoyed movie A and enjoyed movie B then it's likely that this new customer number three
who enjoys movie A will also likely enjoy a movie be now a content based system when it actually need
to take those users into account.
What it could do is just group movies together based on features like the length of the movie the genre
of the movie what actors are in the movie and then it will just group movies that are similar together
and just based off those groupings suggest movies that are similar in that group.
Often real recommendation systems can have combinations of both methods.
Now for this course we're going to do is leave further review of the Aeolus mathematics up to the student
and those resource links.
So let's get started in the next lecture by opening up a Jupiter notebook and creating a recommender
system based off the famous movie lines dataset.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.