Welcome to the Python crash course section will now have a quick crash course in Python and the Jupiter
note book system.
Before we continue let's discuss a few things to keep in mind.
If you already know enough pythons create functions for example maybe you've already taken one to make
courses on Python.
You can probably just skip this section you're already good to go.
If you need to review however stick around and go through these lectures.
If you're not sure if you know enough python that's no problem.
Just move forward through the curriculum and attempt the python crash course exercises that you can
find towards the end of this section if you can solve them.
Then you probably already know enough python to continue.
Now keep in mind this is meant to be a quick review.
Preferably you should already know how to program before enrolling in this course and hopefully you've
encountered some python in the past will only cover concepts to the level you need to know to use Python
with Sparke including Paice park.
Well so we won't cover every single concept in Python just enough that you can use Python with SPARC.
We'll use the Jupiter note book for this course so we're also going to be starting with a very quick
review of it.
Remember you don't have to use the Jupiter notebook if you prefer another ID or text editor.
The same code works for any environment.
So if Jupiter notebooks aren't your thing no problem.
Use any ID or text editor.
You prefer OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.