Hello everyone and welcome to the clustering section of the course we've seen how to deal with labeled
data.
But what about unlabelled data.
Often you'll find yourself trying to create groups from data instead of trying to predict classes or
continuous values.
This sort of problem is known as clustering.
You can think of it almost as an attempt to create labels.
You input some unlabeled data and the unsupervised learning algorithm returns back.
Possible clusters of the data.
This means you have data that only contains features and you want to see if there are patterns in the
data that would allow you to create groupings or clusters.
This is a key distinction from our previous supervised learning tasks where we had historical labelled
data.
Now we're going to try to do is have unlabeled data and attempt to discover possible labels through
clustering by the nature of this very problem.
It can be difficult to evaluate the groups or clusters for quote unquote correctness.
A large part of being able to interpret the clusters assigned comes down to domain knowledge.
So for example maybe have some customer data and then you clustered them into distinct groups.
It's going to be up to you and your domain knowledge to decide what those groups actually represent.
Sometimes this is really easy and other times it's really hard.
For example you can cluster tumors into two groups hoping to separate between benign tumors and malignant
tumors but there's no guarantee that the clusters will fall along those lines it will just be split
into the two most separable groups.
Also depending on the clustering algorithm it may be up to you to decide beforehand how many clusters
you expect to create a lot of clustering problems have no 100 percent correct approach or answer.
And that's just the nature of unsupervised learning in general.
Since you never had those labels to check against.
So let's continue on by discussing Kamins clustering a specific clustering algorithm which is unsupervised
learning so if you want more background and Kamins clustering and the mathematics behind it read Chapter
10 of an introduction to Siskel learning Kamins clustering is an unsupervised learning algorithm that
will attempt to group similar clusters together in your data.
So what do typical clustering problems actually look like.
You can cluster similar documents cluster customers based off their features do market segmentation
identify similar physical groups and much more the overall goal is to divide data into distinct groups
such that observations within each group are similar.
So we can see here on the left what an example of unlabeled data would look like if you plotted it on
two features one features our next one features on y Kamins clustering is going to attempt to cluster
that data into distinct groups so we can see on the right.
So you can see here is almost discovering those labels.
In this case we're represented by colors.
So the Kamins algorithm does the following steps.
You as the user have to choose a number of clusters k so you have to choose that before you actually
initiate the model.
That means you're going to have to use domain knowledge to choose a reasonable value then it's going
to randomly assigned each point to a cluster until clusters stop changing.
It's going to repeat the following for each cluster.
It's going to compute the cluster centroid by taking the mean vector of points in the cluster then it
will assign each data point to the cluster for which the centroid is the closest.
So let's actually see this in action on the very first panel on the top left.
We have our data.
It's unlabelled and it's totally ready to go for clustering.
Then we have Step 1.
In this case we've chosen to be equal to 3.
So we randomly assign each point to one of the groupings of k then we're going to do on our first iteration
which we'll call Step 2.
We randomly place the send choice on top of our data.
Then on iteration once that to be that's on that bottom row we assign the individual data points to
the actual grouping for the centroid they're closest to.
Then on iteration to that to a well we end up doing is moving those centroid to the average of all the
vectors from connecting from that data point to the actual centroid.
And then we keep repeating this result until the centroid stop moving and then eventually you have your
actual cluster groups.
So again choosing a value this is going to be pretty difficult decision.
Or maybe a really easy decision.
It really depends on the domain knowledge and what the data looks like depending on what K-Ville you
choose.
You may get various groupings and some of them may be obvious or intuitive choices and other ones may
be completely unclear.
Here you can see some similar data.
We have different values chosen.
Some of these look to be making sense.
Other ones don't look to make sense at all.
It really depends on what your data looks like.
So as I've mentioned before kind of the shadow of unsupervised learning algorithms is that there aren't
really easy answers.
And in this particular case there's no easy answer for choosing a best value without specific domain
knowledge.
One mathematical method you could use is called the elbow method.
So what you end up doing is you compute the sum of squared errors otherwise known as S S E for some
values of k for example KCSM two equals four KCl six etc..
The SCC that sum of squared error is defined as the sum of the squared distance between each member
of the cluster to its actual centroid then what you end up doing is you plot K against SSD and you will
see that the error decreases as K gets larger.
And this is because when the number of clusters increases.
They should be smaller so each distortion is going to be smaller as well.
The idea of the elbow method is to choose the K at which the SSD decreases abruptly.
So this for this is what's known as an elbow effect in the graph.
So you can see this in the following picture.
So here we can see we have the number of clusters chosen and the within group sum of squares.
And you can see that around 5 or 6 you get the abrupt drop so that's known as the Elbel method because
it kind of looks like the Elbel of an arm.
So that indicates that choosing around that point is a good value and hopefully also have domain knowledge
that helps drive that decision forward.
So as far as plotting Paice spark by itself doesn't support a plotting mechanism but could always use
collects to get back a Python object such as a list or an array.
And then you can plot the results with MAP lib or other Python visualization libraries.
OK so as far as the elbow method don't take that as a strict rule when choosing a k value.
As I keep mentioning a lot of it depends more on the context of the exact situation.
Otherwise known as domain knowledge.
So we'll try our best to get a feel for this with the examples in the consulting projects.
All right let's get started by walking through the documentation example for Kamins clustering.
I'll see you at the next lecture.