Hello everyone don't walk into the course overview the lecture.
I would like to welcome you to the course.
And in this lecture we're going to quickly cover some frequently asked questions and what you can expect
during the course even if you've taken other courses by me in the past.
Please don't skip this lecture it's really going to help you understand what the Course is about and
how to get help during the course.
And topics such as that.
So we're going to discuss a few things or really help you give the best possible course experience lectures
like this one these video lectures can be sped up to your liking.
Up to 2 x speed I usually talk at a pretty slow and deliberate pace.
So I would personally if I was watching this video lecture probably speeded up a bit too.
So feel free to do that whenever you want.
And they can also be viewed at higher quality.
Sometimes some browsers or some internet connections auto to a lower quality if you're having trouble
with that.
You can always just click on the settings icon it looks like a little gear at the bottom of the video
and change it to a higher quality.
All right.
Let's discuss some coarse basics.
Who is this course for and what does it cover.
So this course is really designed for someone with some sort of experience in programming doesn't need
to specifically be Python or spark in the past but you should have experience of some programming language
preferably Python.
But we do have the python crash course to kind of get you up to speed on that quickly.
And this course is for people that are interested in using SPARC in Python for analyzing big data.
If you're interested in just general data science machine learning with Python and you don't really
have a need for a really large data sets that is data sets in bigger than like 32 gigabytes and you're
just interested in basic data analysis machine learning visualization with data science and you're just
starting to get into it.
Check out my other course Python for data science and machine learning boot camp and take a look at
that curriculum.
It might be better suited for you.
This course is better suited for people that have may already gone through that course this python for
data science and machine learning boot camp.
So I just want to make sure that your expectations are set here on what you're going to experience in
this course.
So again this course is ideal for students who enrolled in that previous course or who already have
some sort of general knowledge with basic data analysis with Python or maybe some other programming
language.
It's designed to add spark and price spark to your professional resume.
So you already have some skills you want to level up with SPARK and Paice park.
So what this course is not we're not going to cover typical Python libraries such as some pie pandas
visualization sikat learn.
This course is really just for big data that those technologies themselves can't handle.
So at a certain point your data becomes so large that none pie panda sikat learned they can't deal with
it anymore.
You need to move on something like Sparke.
So that's what this course is about.
OK.
So again this course is for people looking to build skills in things like Paice marked data frames Sparke
2.0 working with very large data sets and things like Spark's to suffix.
Maybe you've heard of sparks streaming or.
An employer is asking for you to learn that.
We cover that sort of stuff in this course.
OK.
Hopefully that gives you an idea of the target audience.
But let's discuss a few more things before we get started.
We have various installation lectures for different ways of setting up PI SPARC but I don't want you
to feel obligated to use any of them specifically if you already have your own setup.
We're going to be using the Jupiter notebook system for video lectures.
But if you prefer that PI files with some sort of ID like pi charm or a text editor like sublime text
editor that's also no problem.
I've provided the PI files for you to follow along with.
So it's totally up to you whether you want to stick to the notebook system or use your own favorite
editor.
You have the py files to basically explore any options you want.
So speaking of these pie in these notebook files you can grab the notes as a zip file as a resource
in this lecture.
So as you're watching throughout the course you can click on check resources or you may see a little
pop up saying there are resources there'll be a zip file and that contains all the notes.
So in the FNQ lecture the installation overview.
And in this specific lecture you'll see the pop up for those zip files.
It's all the same zip files.
I just put them in several lectures for convenience.
So any of those will work.
You can just click on whichever one you're currently at is more convenient to you.
The slides shown in the course are also linked to as a resource in their respective lecture and they're
hosted as Google slides so you can just visit online to see any updates.
So I prefer hosting them as Google slides versus using a PDA.
That way if there's any changes I can easily edit them online and you can get the latest stuff by clicking
on that link.
All right.
Now let's discuss how to get help during the course.
So whenever you're working through the course and you get stuck on something or there's an error you
should always double check that your code matches the notes exactly.
If you follow the same set up procedure and you're running on the same version of Python that sparked
the I am in this video lecture you should have everything working.
If your code matches the notes exactly.
So definitely double check that that's the case.
I would say somewhere around 80 percent of all errors are just because there was a typo or something
didn't quite match up to the notes you maybe did something in a different order.
So definitely double check that your code matches those notes exactly.
If you're still having trouble with that you're pretty sure it matches the notes exactly.
Maybe even Aranda notes do a quick check on Stack Overflow for a fast answer.
A lot of times questions have already been answered on that Web site.
OK so let's say those two methods you're still getting those errors.
No problem.
You can check the course FNQ lecture.
Maybe your questions are already being answered there.
That's the very next lecture.
He still can't find there not a problem.
Search the Kewaunee forums of course to see if someone else has already asked your question and if you
still can't find it you check the queue.
You check the notes.
Everything looks good to you but you're still having that trouble again.
That's not a problem.
All you have to do is post a new question to the Kewney forums.
If you still can't resolve that issue given the previous methods and I and the other students are happy
to help out I'm on the forums everyday checking trying to help out helping you troubleshoot any errors
you may have.
So again the Kewney forums are where you should be focusing your questions.
After you check the notes and stack overflow.
All right let's quickly cover the course curriculum and what you can expect to learn throughout the
entire course.
So we're going to cover the following topics.
Kind of these are big overview topics will start with spark in the Big Data basics.
Give an overview of what it really is how it works etc. then we'll talk about setting up spark in various
ways.
You have basically 4 installation options and we'll talk about that later on through an installation
overview lecture.
Now we have a quick Python crash course and then we have the Python and SPARC 2.0 data frame section
where we discuss how to use data frames with the spark 2.00 syntax and Python and then will also have
a Paice Park Project exercise to kind of wrap up that section.
Then the second half the course really focuses on sparc machine learning.
So you get an introduction to machine learning what it is and you also get an introduction to how SPARC
works with machine learning in particular with its M-L lib library.
And then we'll discuss some particular machine learning topics like linear regression logistic regression
decision trees and random force and in things like gradient boosting trees and there we're going to
continue on to k means clustering recommender systems.
Natural Language Processing and then things like Sparke streaming which aren't exactly machine learning
but it is another facet of SPARC and we'll discuss streaming something locally and also doing a project
with Twitter.
So streaming tweets using Sparc and within all those topics that I just mentioned those larger sections
we also introduce other things like pipelines or cross-validation.
So some of these topics don't really merit their own particular section like pipelines.
Instead we introduce them with other topics.
So when we talk about natural language processing we'll also introduce pipeline's explain what they
are etc..
All right thank you so much for listening to all of that.
But it should make your course experience much smoother.
Having known all that information.
So one last thing before we continue on.
I just want to give you a huge thank you for enrolling in this course.
I truly appreciate it.
And I'm really going to try my best to make sure you have the best learning experience possible.
OK let's get started with learning one of the latest technologies which has sparked with Python.
I will see you at the next lecture.