Welcome back to the Jupiter book lecture.
In case you're new to Jupiter notebook systems in general this lecture will briefly cover the basics.
You can feel free to skip this lecture if you're already familiar of Jupiter notebooks.
I'm sure if you've already taken one of my other courses on Python or data science you already have
more than enough experience of Jupiter note books in general.
In case you're unfamiliar let's briefly go over the chapter notebooks.
Jupiter note books use a IPY and B which stands for Python notebook file format but they can be saved
to a dot Peewee file.
That way you can open them up with any ID or any sort of text editor that can even be saved to him.
And PDA formats you can't double click a IPY and be filed to open it in order to do that.
You need to do it through the command line.
So all you have to do is open up the terminal and type.
Jupiter notebook.
Then you'll have the Jupiter note book viewer and you can navigate to wherever your notebooks are stored.
You can always use C.D to navigate to the terminal beforehand OK.
Let's jump to a Jupiter notebook's discuss a few key features.
All right so once you type in Jupiter put into your terminal you should see something that looks like
this.
Now the files are folders that you see here are going to be different depending how you did this.
If you're running locally you should see something that says local host a etc..
If you're running this on maybe an Amazon easy to instance depending on installation instructions you
followed you'll have a big easy to line and then a.
Etc. but either way regardless of how you're actually doing this you should see a screen similar to
this one and you can see what folders look like what a typical notebook file looks like.
And here you'll see other files.
For example some info for file.
Now obviously the Jupiter note book can't really open this well so let's go over how you would create
a new notebook and a couple of special features that hopefully convince you that you better know books
are going to be really useful when learning something so you'll come over here to New.
You'll click on it and you can see here I can create a new text file a new folder the new terminal.
But more importantly a new notebook now underneath notebooks.
I have various options because I'm running this on my own local computer.
In this case I'm actually running this on a Mac not a full Ubuntu or a Linux based system but I've specialized
my notebook to have multiple languages so I have R and Skala available.
Most likely if you follow the instructions you'll have either just Python to Python 3 or you'll see
something that says like Python Khanda.
Or Python default as long as it says Python somewhere around there or Khanda somewhere around there.
That's totally fine.
So just click on that one and you can review the installation instructions for whatever system you're
working with.
And then that will start a new notebook now with this new book I want to show off just a couple of neat
features.
For example if you want to run code you have these cells so I can say two plus two or two plus one or
two and do shift enter and with the shift enteric and immediately see the output.
So that's going to make your learning process really nice when working the Jupiter books you have this
input and direct output.
What's also really nice is you can write little notes for yourself so you can change these to what's
known as a markdown cell.
So you just come up here change it from code to markdown and that changes the cell notice how it does
have that in anymore.
And then I can just write something like this is a markdown cell
notes for me and then I can do shift enter and notice what happens.
It's just regular tech.
So that's a way you can leave little notes for yourself and these markdown cells are prevalent throughout
the lecture notes.
That's basically my way of leaving little notes for you.
That explains a lot of the code and the support for markdown syntax.
So if that's something you're familiar with for example you can put in hash tags here.
That actually changes the size of the font.
Cetera.
So that's a general markdown text that really has nothing to do of course but if you know it it's available
free there and if you want to change the notebook title you just click here on untitled and then say
something like.
My first notebook cetera.
All right.
So that's really the basics of what you need to know for that Jupiter notebook.
A lot of this was already covered throughout the installation lectures so I'm sure a lot of this is
reviewed to you.
The last two things I want to mention before we end this lecture are two really powerful features of
the Jupiter notebook and that's getting documentation string help.
And the list of the methods available for an object.
So let's actually show you if I have an object X and it's going to be a string and then I run shift
enter it actually to find that I can type in X and I see the output of the string but strings have methods
available to them.
So I can say something like dots upper and then I uppercase the string.
Now you may be wondering well how the heck am I supposed to know all the methods available.
Well luckily Jupiter helps you out.
So if you have an object that's already been defined remember you have to run a cell in order to find
the object.
So X was defined appear and I ran the cell.
Now that is the that can say X dot and a hit tab onto my keyboard and I can see all the various methods
that are available to me here.
So lots of methods.
A lot of these you won't be using in fact most of them you won't be using but with tab you can see all
the ones that are available to you.
So you don't really need to memorize anything.
So that's something that's really nice about the Jupiter note book.
A lot of ideas already do this sort of thing.
But you put in a book does it as well.
And it's quite helpful that everything's happening right here in front of us.
We see the input and the output we see the tab all the methods.
It's really nice.
Now the other thing I want to show you is the ability to see documentation strings for functions themselves.
So if we use a built in functions such as some I can do shift tab after this to see the documentation
string.
So I see the docstring here and some description of what this function does returns the sum X cetera.
Now again the function needs to be defined in order to actually see the documentation string for it.
So if you're working with your own custom function make sure you actually run the self first.
That defines that function in order to see the documentation string later on.
All right.
So that's really all we need to know if you ever want any more help with Jupiter notebooks.
Just come over here and help.
And there's lots of useful things here such as the keyboard shortcuts which are kind of just discussing
as well as general notebook help.
More stuff on markdown case that interested you and a lot more stuff about certain libraries with Python
that you can use for data science in machine learning.
All right.
Jupiter notebooks are super popular in Python for data science ecosystem in general.
So I hope you learn to love them as well if they're not your thing.
No worries I understand.
But feel free to explore them.
Thanks.
I'll see you at the next lecture.