Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture we're going to be working through the documentation
example for k means clustering So pay close attention to how we don't need the actual label column which
makes sense because we're doing clustering which is an unsupervised learning algorithm.
Now the documentation's example is a bit peculiar in its choice of a data set.
They basically have a really small data set and they actually do provide you if the label columns which
are unnecessary.
So we're going to explain that along the way.
And hopefully our own custom code along will clarify things further in the next lecture.
But for now let's get started.
Open up a new Jupiter notebook and walk through the documentation's own example of Kamins clustering.
All right.
So I've started in you know book and as a quick note you can find all the code that I'm going to be
working through at this note book right here clustering code exampled IPY and B.
So let's get started.
First thing you have to do is actually start a Paice perk sessions will say Place perks equal import
Sparke session and then I will create a spark session so will say spark session builder name and I'll
call this cluster.
And then I will say Get or create.
So we will run that and then I'm actually going to import our model.
So we'll save from Paice sparked off.
And we have to provide what a family this belongs to.
And in this case this is a clustering algorithm.
So from here I can import Kamins then we'll upload the data set the data set.
I've already downloaded it for you and it's under the clustering folder under Sparke for machine learning.
But it's this kind of esoteric lib SVM format.
So when you say Sparke read that format lib SVM and then you'll say load and it's called Nico's just
tab autocomplete this sample case means data that text.
So I will run that the next thing I want to do is actually check up data set.
And this is kind of why it's a weird choice given that we're doing Kamins clustering.
But if you show the dataset it's actually just this it's six rows of data and it has both a label and
features.
So I'm not sure if they're trying to imply that there's six different clusters to be expected here.
The documentation example actually sets K equal to 2.
So that's something that's a little bit peculiar.
So just keep that in mind as we continue on throughout this project.
What I really want to do is prove to you that it only needs features because this is an unsupervised
learning algorithm.
So I will say final data is equal to this dataset and I'm going to select only the features column.
So I'm going to run that and then I'm going to show you the final data and the final data only has those
features.
So that's what we're going to be using just to basically prove to you what a more realistic scenario
would look like.
And then I'm going to create my model will say k means is equal to and it's k means.
And then you can call off this set K and this is where you can set your K value.
In this case a follow along to the documentation.
They set their K equal to 2 and then something else you can do is set a seed of value.
Now a seed value is just a seed value for a random number generator.
So remember back in the theory lecture where you actually start the centroid is randomly chosen.
Well you can do is a seed number here that way.
In case you want to come back to this experiment and make sure you have the same quote unquote random
setting that C number is going to provide the same set of random numbers every time.
As long as you have the same number here.
So if you want to follow along with me and make sure you get the exact same results set your speed equal
to 1.
So that's our Kamins model.
And now let's fit the model so we'll say model is equal to key means and I'm going to fit it to that
final data dataset so now we run that.
And while it's fitting notice that it had no problems so final data only contains features and has no
problem fitting that because it's an unsupervised learning algorithm.
If you try to do this on another dataset it would give you back an error saying it's looking for that
label.
So again means only needs features and you can even do shift tab here on this means and notice that
it only expects features call it has no label column input.
OK so let's continue on and actually try to evaluate our clustering algorithm.
So something we can do is check out the within set sum of squared errors.
So within set sum of squared errors or W S S S E.
And then I will say that's equal to.
And the way you do this is a little different than our evaluation metrics earlier but we do as you say
model dot compute cost.
And then you passen your data.
So we compute the cost of our actual dataset and you're passing in the whole thing you're not doing
any test train splits.
That doesn't make sense because we don't have labels.
We're just kind of dealing with the entire data set as is.
And then you can just prints the within some square errors or thinset some squirters.
So for us it happens to be 0.1 1:9 repeating.
And what we can actually do is check out the cluster centers.
So if we look at our final data one more time and the show this notice that we essentially had three
dimensions of features.
So we had this item and to pull this vector of items in the tuple and then another one.
And if we see here the first one is actually empty or nothing on the first or the second two of the
first row.
So we can end up doing is checking out the cluster centers and because we know we have essentially three
values in this tuple for the features we should expect the centers to be in three dimensions.
So in order to actually get the centers we can say create a new object called centers and model and
it's going to be cluster centers and this is a method so you have close princes there.
So if you end up typing out centers it will return back the actual centers.
In this case it returns back to centers at 9.1 9.1 and put it on is like x y z and then another one
is 0.1 0.1 0.1.
So what does that actually mean.
Well it means since we set K equal to 2 it computed that the actual centers are at these locations.
Now generally speaking especially if you're unfamiliar if the data set it's a little hard to actually
interpret the within set some of squared errors.
This number right here or even the Centers.
I mean we understand that this is some Center and some three of them mention all space.
But truly what we want to know is if I look at my final data and say that show I have essentially five
rows and what I really want to know is which group does each row belong to.
Essentially I want to know the label that I created for it.
And the way you do that is you call your model then say transform and you actually then pass in the
data.
And again we're not doing a test train split which makes sense because this is unsupervised learning.
We don't have any real labels to do the testing on.
So we just have to pass in all the data during the fitting process and we're going to pass and all the
data during the transformation process because this is unsupervised learning.
That's kind of part of the issues with it that it's difficult to know for sure how well your model actually
performed because since the very beginning we never knew the true label to compare it to.
Now there's definitely method such as I mentioned though within set some A-squared errors that try to
evaluate that especially try to evaluate if you chose the right k but let's run this now.
So actually let's set this as results and then if I check out results.
So notice now I can say show and now I have the actual prediction.
So this predicts that this is the first group.
So these first three rows belong to the first group and then these last three rows belong to the second
group.
Now let's run this again with a higher value.
So I'll set this K equal to 3 and let's run this again so we'll say Kamins is this Kamins fit to the
model or the final data I should say.
And if we compute the COS now we get a different within set some A-squared errors and it makes sense
that it goes down as you increase k then we're going to check out the cluster centers and note that
we now have three cluster centers and one of the clusters is slightly off.
The other one looks like it took the 9.1 group from earlier and split it into two and it kept the other
group the same.
So now pay attention here.
One of these groups should probably be remaining the same.
And another group will be split so we'll say results is modeled transform final data.
Run that again.
And what I'm going to do is check out the results.
So remember this first three were ones last three were zeros for one that again.
Well look what happened.
It looks like one of these groups stayed intact and it split off.
The other group now has two zeros and ones two which makes sense given that we saw one of the centers
is essentially split off from each other.
OK.
It's not always going to be that obvious especially if you have higher dimensions.
But in this case the data is pretty simple if just five rows.
Hopefully that makes sense if you have any questions on that explanation please feel free to post the
Kewaunee forms.
OK.
So this was a really small data set.
It was kind of strange in the fact that it provided labels for us already but we really didn't need
them.
And what we're going to do is in the next lecture look at a more realistic dataset.
In fact that's a real data set from UC Irvine machine learning repository.
So let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.