Hello everyone and welcome to the tree methods Kodo long lecture where we're going to be coding through
a custom example.
We're going to be doing is working through all three tree methods discussed and compare the results
on a college dataset.
The data has features of universities and that the universities are labeled either a private university
or a public university.
And we're going to use a different tree methods to attempt to label or build a model that can predict
whether a university based Office features is private or public.
Let's jump to a new notebook and get started.
OK here I am at a new notebook and the college data set that we're going to be working with is available
for you underneath the tree methods folder underneath SPARC for machine learning and it's called college.
SEE AS WE But before we get started with that.
Let's start a PI sparks session or a spark session I should say and then we'll import Spark's session
from Paice supercup sequel and we'll create Sparke is equal to spark session builder and give the app
name you can call it whatever you want I'll call it tree.
And then we will get or create this spark session.
Now the next thing you want to do is actually load in that training data.
So we them before since it's just a see every file.
I'll say read CXXVI and it's called college cxxviii and you can always use tab to autocomplete and affirm
that.
And we'll say in first game as true as well as Hetter to be true.
So once you've done that and once the data is loaded We're going to print schema just so we can get
an idea of what the data looks like.
Once you print to this schema you can see here the various columns and if you want definitions or descriptions
for each of these columns you can just check up the code along lecture and it has descriptions for each
of these.
But essentially what these are they're just features of the schools.
So you have the school name then you have whether or not it's private which is what we're going to be
trying to predict.
And there are a whole bunch of features about it.
Things such as the number of applications received the number of students enrolled.
What percentage of new students come from the top 10 percent of the high school class or the top 25
percent they see hear etc..
They are state tuition.
So if you want an example of what this actually looks like you can just say head one and then check
out the actual data itself.
So you can see here we have this first school.
Yes it's a private university.
The number of applications the percent of alumni who donate back to the school etc..
So what we're going to be doing is testing out the various tree methods on this.
So let's actually start formatting this data.
There's a lot of columns to format so we'll say from PI spark thought M-L thought feature import vector
assembler.
So I'm going to import that and then I'm also going to call for the columns themselves to save myself
some typing when I actually pass the feature columns into vector assembler.
So let's build this out now.
I will say assembler is equal to this vector assembler is within the past.
And then I need to grab the input columns so that is an empty list right now.
And I also want to grab the output column or just define the upper column as features.
So what we need is the actual features that we're going to be using and we're going to be using basically
everything below the school's name.
And whether or not it's private.
So everything from apps all the way to the graduation rate works for us.
I'm going to copy this and then pasted in here.
And let me make sure everything's balanced that should work for us.
Let's try this.
Run that.
Make sure it OK.
Any errors.
OK.
So far it's all looking good.
We'll continue on and actually create the output that we'll see output is equal to that assembler.
And then I will transform the data run that and you shouldn't get any errors there.
OK.
Now we want to deal with the private column.
So if you take a look at the actual output.
So if we come back up here remember that this private column is what we're trying to predict.
But right now we have the issue that it's a string.
It says either yes or no.
So we need to actually change that to a 0 or 1 because Spark's lib library can't deal for yes or no
directly.
So we'll come back down here and we're going to say from Paice park M-L that feature import a string
indexer and then run that and then we'll say indexer is indexer the input column I'm expecting just
says private and the output column I'm going to create will just be something very similar maybe private
index.
And then I want the output underscore fixed to be equal to that index or objects that fit and then I'm
going to fit the output and then transformed the outputs and do this all in one step.
If you want to you can actually split this up into two steps.
We've seen it split before and this is just what it looks like on the one step and you could also use
a pipeline if you wanted to if you had to do this for a lot more features for a very strong indexers
I'd definitely suggest a pipeline.
But if there's just one column just a single column you have to apply string index to it's OK to not
use a pipeline truly up to you.
And what pipelines are really for is if you're going to repeat your code a lot that's when you have
to really consider the pipeline right now.
This is kind of the code along so we're fine just doing it this way.
And then finally when I'm going to do is I have my output fixed.
Let's check what that looks like.
I'm going to say print the schema of this run that so I have school private schools a string if I scroll
way down I see features.
Great.
That's a vector that I created and then private index.
It's the double that it created.
So everything's looking good.
I really just need these two columns but you can pass them all.
We really wanted to.
And we're going to do is say my final data is equal to output fixed and then just those two columns
that I just mentioned features and then private index as a string private index.
So let's run that.
And now I want to split this into some training data and some test data.
So I will say final data call random split on it.
And as we've done before Elisha's to 0.7 0.3 run that.
So now we have our trained data on our test data and it's time to actually check out the different classification
methods I could use that tree classifier the Kriti boosted tree CROSSFIRE or the random forest classifier.
So since we're using the tree methods for classification I need to say Paice park M-L and then call
classification here.
Then I can call decision tree classifier.
I can also then call you start typing G-B there is a job classifier and then there's also a if you start
typing random.
I put this on a new line.
Whoops.
Let's put this in print sees that we can do multiple lines here.
And then the final one if we had this over is going to be called random forest classifier.
So let's run them forests classifier So let's run those.
Now you can use tree methods as I mentioned earlier for regression tasks.
So you could say from Paice park the M-L regression and then begin exploring some of these regression.
So if you start typing in random There is a fan the random forest repressor you could use.
And again the difference is as we note in the theory lecture these random forest classifiers or tree
method classifiers in general essentially are just voting for what class they think the actual sample
belongs to for aggressor.
If you have a bunch of trees versus just a single tree put the aggressor will do is all the trees will
give their estimate of what they think the continuous value should be.
And then you just average all of those and that's the random forest repressor right now we're just doing
classification classifications kind of easier to explore as far as evaluation just because it becomes
really clear what accuracy precision or recall mean how many got right.
How many you got wrong versus checking something out like the root mean squared error but either way
just keep in mind all of these can also be used for regression as long as they're available for you.
PI sparked the M-L that regression.
And let's actually show off how to use the pipeline a little more.
So we'll say import pipeline from Paice park that M-L.
OK.
So I'm going to create three different models here DTC.
That's going to stand for my decision tree classifier and it is going to have the label column of private
index.
And then my features column is going to be just called features and essentially these are all going
to be the same.
So I will say our FC is equal to my random forest classifier and I'm going to pass in the exact same
arguments so label column features column.
Copy those and then paste them in and then I'm also going to say PBT for gradient boosting trees.
That's going to be my whoops greedy and boosted classifier and then copy and paste that in and hopefully
by now it feels super familiar to you and you realize just how easy it is to swap classifiers are any
different models in and out using Python and Sparke.
So we want to train all of these models.
So I'll say DTC model is equal to DTC and I will fit this to my training data and I will do the exact
same thing for the rest of them.
So create the model object that's going to be fitted again to my training data.
One more will say G-B T-model
and this is our see fit to G-B Tina R-S.C. Scuse me TVT fit to the train data perfect school run all
those that may take a little bit of time because it's fitting three different models just in a single
cell.
You're going to let it run for just a little bit and we're going to do in the meantime is check out
the model comparison to the model comparison is going to look really similar to this.
We're essentially going to transform for all of the soul say DTC threads for predictions is equal to
DTC underscore a model and I'm going to then transform my test data and I'm going to do a similar thing
to the rest of them.
So let's just copy and paste this so we can add it in later on we say RAFC Freda's is equal to RAFC
and then paste the rest of that and then we'll do the same thing for a gradient boosted trees.
So make green tree predictions physical to Djibouti and then copy and paste the model.
So run that as well.
Again that may take a little bit of time.
The transform process however should be pretty quick.
The fitting is what takes a long time with models.
So now let's get some evaluation metrics and actually see how all of these did.
So I'll say from PI Sparke da M-L top evaluation we're going to import the binary classification evaluator
So once you've imported that binary classification evaluator I can create my evaluation object we'll
call this my and I'm actually going to call this my binary Eva.
All and then I will set this equal to an instance of that binary classification evaluator.
And if you shift tab remember the arguments are a raw prediction column and label column.
Right now my label column is not called label.
It's called private index.
So I want to clarify that.
I'll say a label column is the private index and we'll just go ahead and feed it that raw prediction
column.
That's fine.
And now it's time to evaluate each of these models so let's print out a little line for us all say DTC
for the decision tree classifier.
And then what I'm going to do is print out the result of my binary evil and then I will evaluate the
results of the actual predictions which was DTIC underscore Freda's.
So let's run this and see the results.
OK so this is the area under the curve zero point 0 9.
That's pretty good especially for a decision tree.
So that should already indicate that this particular dataset was highly separable especially if we're
getting such good performance off a single decision tree.
So you may see a little extra from the RAFC or the PBT.
We're also using the default so that's important to remember.
You may be able to juice a little more out of the random force and the gradient boost of trees let's
explore just so the default arguments or default parameters.
How will they do.
So I'll say no RAFC and I'm going to print again my binary evaluates but I'm going to call it.
On the other one so that's our See predictions run this.
OK.
So RAFC that's really quite good.
0.27.
So you can see here that using just the decision tree is not nearly as good as a random forest.
And honestly it should never really be any other way.
It makes sense that having a lot more trees to do the voting or choose the classification would work
better than just a single decision tree especially when we're doing the random splits so you should
always fecht re-inforce to outperform decision tree in almost every situation.
Now something to note before we hit the gradient boosted trees is that greeting boosted trees doesn't
actually have the default prediction or prediction column.
So let's take a look at what JPT Fred's actually looks like by saying.
Print schema offer this and you can see here only has the prediction column.
It doesn't have.
Unlike the other guys I call our spreads and then print this schema these days I actually have those
raw predictions and those probabilities.
So that means if I try to pass the predictions into my binary evil I'm going to get some errors.
So let's actually create another evaluator object that expects just a prediction column.
Remember we discussed earlier that binary classifier evaluator has no problem using that prediction
column instead of the raw prediction.
So I will grab this guy.
Copy it.
Paste it here and we'll say my Ameri evil and let's leave it to.
I am also going to add here is that the prediction column is where I should say this.
So remember we need to specify raw prediction column and instead of prediction we're going to specify
that it's just prediction.
And if you look at the documentation it specifies that that is ok to do OK.
So let's make sure those principles are balanced.
I'm a little zoomed in here.
So hopefully that runs well.
Okay perfect.
So there's my Barner Eve too.
So you can take in this prediction column and we're going to delete that and then prints Green a tree
and print out my binary eveil to evaluate these PBT predictions or Pretz.
Let's run that and we can see here this gradient boosting tree did not perform as well as RAFC and also
did not perform as well as the decision tree.
So that may be surprising to you.
And the reason for that is because we're the green and blue tree we actually didn't really edit any
of the default parameters and the default parameters that spark provides.
You may not be really good for your particular dataset.
So what you should do is when you actually create the model come back appear to GBG classifier.
And if you shift tab you'll notice that you have max depth Max bins and Max information gain a lot of
parameters here to mess around with.
So you should definitely check these out play around with them.
That's kind of an assignment to be left for you.
Can you deal with random force classifier and green Boosey tree classifiers to try to juice a little
more performance out of them especially if Ranum Court for us classifier if you look at the defaults
here the actual number of trees used isn't that high.
If you expand on this they will tell you that it's only 20 trees.
That's a pretty low number of trees.
It's for this particular case it's no problem but a lot of times people use up to 100 or 200 trees on
a tree in the forest again.
It really depends on your particular dataset and whether that number of trees makes sense but number
of trees 20.
Depending on how many entries you have that could be a pretty low number so might be fun to try to increase
the number of trees here and see if that helps out with a prediction.
So let's just actually do that right now since it's easy enough we'll see a number of trees and I'm
going to set the sequel to 150.
So let's run these again.
And we're not going to fit all the data.
Instead we're going to just fit around the force model run that.
So now that we have 150 trees toppling and it take quite a bit longer than it used to but that's OK.
Now I'm just going to do our F.C. predictions run that and then we'll say from Paice park that again
that should still be good.
And let's run these again.
So that's still 0.9 0 9.
And this is we're going to redo.
So this is with the 20 trees.
Let's see if Brina it's 150 trees increased accuracy and there we go.
So you can see here that already juiced up to 1 percent as the area under the curve.
Not bad especially since we just had to change the number of trees and the actual work we had to do
was actually just changing one line of code.
All right.
So we saw how affecting the parameters of the models can help increase performance but what else we
want to discuss is about our classification evaluators.
Right now we're doing binary classification so we imported the binary classification evaluator but fortunately
if you want to test things like accuracy precision or recall you can't grab those directly from a binary
classification evaluator but you can grab them from the multiclass classification evaluate it directly
and actually spark plays nicely.
Even if you're just doing binary class and you can use that as well.
So let me walk through how to do this and there's a more detailed example and the spark notes or the
notebook that goes with this lecture will say from Paice park the M-L that evaluation.
And we will import the multiclass classification evaluator.
So we'll run that and then let's create our will say this is an accuracy evaluator acq evil will take
multiclass classification evaluator specify that the label column is that private index column from
earlier and then that should actually be in the prediction column.
The shift tab here is by default prediction.
It's included in all of them so we'll just run that.
And then the next thing you're going to do is actually grab the accuracy.
So let's make sure that we're doing accuracy Fidus shift tab so the metric name right now is EF 1.
And I'm actually going to copy this and set it to be accuracy so it can specifically be set to accuracy
as a string.
And as you mentioned before we can check the documentation for all the metrics available.
So we will run that this time and then we're going to do is evaluate this again.
So let's evaluate something like the random forest will say random for us.
Accuracy is equal to this accuracy evaluator and evaluate on RAFC predictions.
So once that's been running we'll say our the accuracy and it's 94 percent accuracy.
And if you want to check other metrics you can always show us replace this metric name with the other
available metrics shown in the documentation.
As a quick side note you can check out the notebook for this particular lecture and I've gone through
and shown the accuracy of just using pure defaults on all three models and all super similar.
They all get about ninety one point five percent accuracy.
The one that has the highest accuracy just with the defaults is the radio industry.
But again that may come at the cost of good precision or good recall.
So definitely have a lot of fun with this.
I want to leave it as an optional assignment for you but I highly encourage you to just start playing
around the parameters in these kind of models.
It's really useful to see how changing certain parameters can affect the accuracy or performance of
the model itself.
And if you have questions on some of those parameters you can do the reading in an introduction to school
learning to find out more about each of those parameters actually does ok.
Hope you enjoyed this project.
Coming up next we're going to discuss actually your consulting project for this section of the course.
I'll see you there.