Welcome back to the Python crash course.
Let's get started with Part 1.
I'm going to hop over to a new Jupiter notebook to get started.
Let's start off our crash course with the very basics starting with numbers.
So Python has two main number of types that we're going to be working with.
It has integers which are just whole numbers or what is known as floating point numbers or floats which
is essentially just with decimals.
And if you ever want to check the type of any objects in Python you just use the type functions.
I can say type one.
I can see there it's an I.A. for integer or type of one point zero.
And since it has that decimal information it's a floating point number or a float.
Let's go through some very basic math with Python.
So all of this you would probably expect to work one plus one.
So that's addition multiplication is just an asterix 1 times 3 division is just a slash So 1 divided
by two.
If you wanted to exponents for example 2 to power four it's just two sets of Asterix.
We can see that 16.
The modulus operator or maade operator is just a percent sign as it is in various languages.
So for maade to brings back zero or remember the Mod operator in case you're unfamiliar with it it just
returns the remainder after the division.
So for divided by two says to those evenly into four just returns zero.
And for example I can do 5 mod 2.
That brings back 1 because 5 divided by 2 has a remainder of 1 and then quickly order of operations
is followed in Python.
So for example if I have two plus three times five plus five here it brings back 22.
But if I actually want the addition to happen before that multiplication I can specify a specific order
of operations of parentheses.
So here I'm going to say hey do the addition and then multiply them together.
So now I want to run the cell I get back 50 the basics of variable assignment are also quite simple
with Python.
Python prefers snake casing.
Meaning if you have multiple words inside a variable name you separate them out by underscores.
So this is just by convention there's no really strict rules on this.
But we'll talk about this later on as well.
But for instance I can say equal sign there there's a name of a variable so I can do this multiple times
so x is equal to 1.
Why is it to run that.
And then it can say something like X was y and there I get the variables.
OK so we talked about numbers and a variable assignment.
Let's quickly talk about strings so strings can be a single quote.
Or a double quote.
So there we see strings of both single and double quotes.
And for instance if he wanted to say something like I don't like that you could just wrap it all in
double quotes so I don't like that.
And notice now even though I have a single quote here because I'm wrapping the whole thing in double
quotes.
I don't get any sort of error.
If I had done this with single quotes then Python is getting confused because it doesn't know where
your actual string ends and starts.
It says Oh is this a string or is this whole thing the string.
So you can just mix up these quotes double versus single to actually make everything work correctly.
Now notice here I'm actually getting in an output cell the string if I want to actually display the
string I can print it which means I can do something like Prince Hello.
And notice the difference here between just saying print hello or hello.
If you're dealing with another idea you're going to be having to print your variables to see them during
the output for Jupiter notebook However a lot of times it displays the very last line in a cell.
So you can see here it's just displaying that string versus here in the top cell in 20.
It's actually printing out the strings.
Notice the difference here.
There's no quotes there's no outsell versus here when I'm just asking for the string back returns the
outsell Plus the string itself.
So that's printing.
The very basics of it.
Let's show you how to format prints which is essentially also known as string interpellation which is
a way to insert things into a string.
For example if I wanted to say something like.
My name is and then leave some sort of space there for me to input names.
I could do curly brackets and then off this string called the dot format method and then I'd just pass
in whatever I want to be there.
So for example put in Jose so will print this whole thing out.
So put this entire thing under print and I can see it says my name is Jose.
So this is known as doc format on a string or string interpellation for a general sense.
But it's a way to insert objects into a string and the curly brackets there indicate what's going to
be put in.
Now I can do this with multiple objects and the way can do that is by actually naming them or ordering
them.
So I'll say my name is blank and will say My number is.
And then we'll also have curly brackets there and then I'll pass in a second argument inside a format
and I'll put in something like 10.
But let's put it in as a string so we don't get any errors here.
OK so I say my name is Jose.
And then it says My number is 10.
So I'm passing in that string 10 and then putting in here.
Now if I don't pass that as a string and try to run this it also works.
But you should be careful that sometimes you make errors if you try to add stuff together inside the
string.
So I'm playing it safe passing that in as a string.
So that's a really common thing to do.
Another thing to do with format is to actually label these variables which you'll also see.
Let me show you a quick example of that.
So I'll say first it will pass and X and then say seconds and we'll pass in Y.
So look what happens when I actually say for these things x x x y y y.
This is just to make it kind of really obvious what's happening here.
Whoops I get a key error because I actually labeled a key so it expects a variable x to be in say format
and it will also expect some variable y to be inside that format.
So let's those in we'll say x is equal to this triple X and Y is equal to this triple y.
So running this again now it works so I see first triplex second triple.
So you might be wondering well what's the point of this.
Well now I don't need to worry about the order things are in format or I could use objects more than
just once.
For example I could just say why why.
Now when I read the cell says first why why second triple Y or I could reverse the order say Y is first
and then second is X running this I can see now I have a lot more control.
They actually naming these variables inside of the format.
So that's the basic use case there they're Let's move on to talk about lists so lists are also known
as arrays and other languages and the way they work in Python is actually quite simple.
All you have to do is use square brackets and you separate the different items inside of the list by
commas.
So here I have a list of numbers 1 2 3 but I could also have a list of strings such as a comma B comma
C.
So that's another list and I can even mix data types so I can say there's a number and there's a letter.
Run that and Python doesn't complain.
Now if action I want to grab objects from a list I can use indexing.
So show me how to do that or create an object called my list and set it equal to a list of letters.
So we'll say a b c now is a really quick note which you should never do is if you're typing a variable
name and you notice that it's suddenly highlighted for you then you're probably going to run into issues
there because this basically indicates that this is some sort of reserved keyword.
So if you notice that it's being highlighted then you're having an issue.
Now if you define your own function and you expect that sort of behavior then that's totally fine.
But notice here it's being highlighted.
So we're going to try to avoid using lists as a variable name which is a good call and let me zoom in
just a little more here so we can clearly see what's happening.
So I have my list.
Sequel to these A B and C. Let's say I want to grab the very first item in my list A.
I can just use an index call.
So we grab the name of the list add in square brackets and then indexing starts at zero.
So Phonogram the very first item that letter A I pass on a zero there and it returns the letter A.
I want to grab the very last letter.
See I had two options.
I could count over and say 0 1 2 and passen the number 2 and then get back to letter C or let's say
this was a super long list.
And I just wanted to grab the last letter but didn't actually want to count all the way through python
supports negative indexing meaning I can say OK starting from zero go backwards 1 which essentially
saying loop all the way around and grab negative 1.
And there we have C..
OK.
So that's the basics of indexing of a list.
If I ever want to change an item in the list I can index it and then set it equal to some new item.
So I'll say my list of zeros equal to you.
And if I run this I don't actually see any output.
So let's check if my list was actually changed by just asking for my list and a new cell.
And there it is.
I have new b c so that's the way you can define a new or re-assign an object in a list.
Now if I don't want to reassign an object in a list but in that add on to that list then all I have
to do is use the append method which appends a new item to a list.
So let's show that going to clear that cell.
Right now I have my list which is new B and C but I want to add a fourth item.
So I'll say append and then let's add the letter D to the end of the list.
So I run that I don't get anything back since the action is not actually returning anything but it is
affecting the list.
So if I asked for my list back I can see New B C and D.
I can also nest lists.
So I'm sure what I mean by that I can have my list is equal to and I'm basically creating a new list
here 1 2 and then the third item can actually be a new list.
For example 100 200.
So if I look at my list now I see I have a list inside of a list.
And you can do this as many times as you want.
However be reasonable.
You don't want to nest inside of a nest inside of monastic cetera.
But if you want to grab an item from this list for example let's say you want to grab 200 just by itself.
Well I know that this list completely is the third item.
So that's 0 1 2.
So I pass in two and I get back that list 100 200 and I can actually stack index calls meaning if I
want to grab 200 will that index zero index one.
So I just say this one shift enter and then I grab 200.
So that's a nested list and that's the way I can actually grab stuff from a nested list.
I can just stack these index calls.
So that's going to be useful if you're working with a Matrix or something that has two mentions.
Usually that's represented as a nested list.
So we'll see a little bit of this throughout the course but it won't be anything too crazy.
So that's the basics for all you really need to know about lists or arrays.
Again they're just a sequence of items or elements that are in order meaning you can index them with
a number.
Now let's talk about dictionaries also known as hash tables and other languages.
So dictionaries use this sort of notation.
I'll say these equal to curly braces and then they have a key which is always a string there and then
some sort of item.
So this is known as a key value pair.
So have key and then let's make a value one that we have a comma there and then we have key to colon
and then some second value.
So I run that and then if I want to access items from the dictionary I pass in the Keenum.
So I want to do is access values based off of their key.
So grab a key here key one that returns value 1 which makes sense.
And if I ask for key to that I get back value to.
So something to keep in mind that is sometimes confusing for beginners is that these hash tables or
dictionaries in Python they do not retain any order.
So unlike a list these guys don't retain any order.
So whatever order happens to be printed out.
So let's say I wanted to print out this dictionary.
It may not actually be in the order that you would expect.
So here I notice I get key to value to one value one even if I defined it one and then two.
So again dictionaries don't retain any order and that really has to do with the way a hash table works
which you don't actually need to understand for this course.
The basic idea is these are just key value pairs.
So instead of items being in a sequence they're matched up with key values as a pair.
So you can easily access items based off their key and this is a really great way to store things where
you need really quick access.
All right.
Let's move on to discuss booleans civilians are quite simple in Python.
It's just either true of a capital-T or false for capital F.
Not much more to it than that.
Now as a quick know a lot of programming languages Python included have what's known as truthy which
means if something is true or false see which essentially assigns some sort of truth or false behavior
to a lot of objects.
So for example if you're ever working with if statements which we'll discuss later on and you don't
really want a boolean.
You can also use numbers so zeros are treated as a false statement.
So if you say if 0 it happens to be false and ones are treated as a true statement.
So if one then it actually does something we don't see too much of that in the course but if we do see
it I'll make sure to let you know.
It's usually pretty obvious when you see it in actual coding but that's something I want you to be aware
of.
Now there's two more data structures I want to discuss that's tuples and sets.
Tuples are very much like a list.
There are a sequence of items and notice here that they're defined by using parentheses instead of these
square brackets that we saw earlier.
Now you might be wondering well why use a tuple versus a list will tuples are immutable.
Meaning you can't reassign the items inside of them.
So I have t of 0 and if I try to set this to new like I did for a list I will get a type error and it
says tuple object does not support item assignment.
So you want to use tuples when you want to make sure a user can't actually change anything inside of
this sequence.
So that's the use case of a tuple.
And then finally the last major data structure of Python is the set looks a lot like a dictionary except
there's no key value pairs.
It's just this sequence of items.
So a set is an unordered collection of unique elements.
So what does that mean.
It means since all the elements have to be unique if you add in multiple instances of an element inside
of this set it's going to reduce this to just the unique elements which is 1 2 and 3.
All right.
That's really all we need to know as far as the basic data structures and we'll constantly be reviewing
this sort of stuff as we continue on throughout the rest of the course.
And a lot of the syntax we'll be using is mainly to have sparked data frames so this is all you really
need to know.
Coming up next we'll discuss comparison operators logic operators and then how Python deals with if
LCF and L statements as well as certain loops like for loops and while loops.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.