Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on evaluating regression.
Let's take a quick break from our coding lecturers to discuss evaluating regression models.
Since we saw some evaluation metrics in the previous lecture but didn't really touch upon what they
actually stand for or what they mean and what we discuss in this lecture is not just for linear regression
but any model that attempts to predict continuous values and categorical values which is a classification
task.
So as you been studying machine learning you may have heard of some evaluation metrics like accuracy
or recall these sort of metrics aren't useful for regression problems because we need metrics designed
specifically for continuous values.
So let's go ahead and discuss some of the most common evaluation metrics for regression.
And this includes mean absolute error mean square error.
The root mean square error and R-squared values in R-squared values are exactly the evaluation metric.
It's more of a statistical property of your model.
And we'll talk about that towards the end of this lecture so we'll begin with the simplest one which
has mean absolute error otherwise known as an A.
This is just the mean of the absolute value of the errors.
So it's the easiest to understand because it's basically just the average error.
And this is what the equation looks like.
So let's break it down.
Starting from the left hand side we have one over N and then we have sigma from equals 1 all the way
to end which is just another way of saying take the sum and then divide it by N.
Now taking the sum of a array of numbers and then dividing it by the count of all those numbers is just
taking the average.
So essentially all the left hand side is saying is just take the average.
Now take the average of what.
So we go to the right hand side and we see we have absolute value bars and we're essentially just taking
the average of the true value minus the predicted value.
So what does this actually mean.
Well we're just trying to see what was or average error.
And the reason we have those absolute value bars is because of favoring aggression.
Fit line your prediction may be below or above the true value.
So you may be negative or you may be positive since we don't want the negatives to cancel out the positive
errors when we actually take the average we take the absolute value first.
So we basically have the average error.
So what would this actually look like in a more realistic scenario.
Well let's imagine again to our common continuous problem where we're trying to predict the possible
price of a house.
So your average error may be something like you're off by a hundred thousand dollars on average.
So it does mean absolute error.
Actually look like a realistic example.
Well let's imagine back to that classic problem of trying to predict housing prices based off the features
of the house.
So your mean absolute error may sound something like on average you're off by $100000 on the price of
a house.
So that's all the mean absolute area does it just tells you that on average how far off are you on the
House now in trying to improve on that we have the mean squared error.
So this is the mean of the squared errors.
So we still want to try to retain some sort of positive error.
So instead of taking the absolute value when we end up doing is we square it.
And the larger errors are noted more than with the mean absolute error making MSE more popular.
So what does that actually mean.
Well you can imagine that if you have a very large difference between your predictive value and your
true value then when you square it that difference is going to be essentially punished more you're going
to see the error even more when you take that average which is why MSEE is more popular because it takes
into account when you were off by a very large margin.
Now the issue with this are the units you're no longer in the same units as the why you were trying
to predict.
You are now in the units of squared or Y which isn't super helpful.
So we end up doing is we take the root mean absolute error.
So this is essentially the most popular because it takes into effect the actual squared error values.
So it still has that punishing effect on really large errors.
But it also has the nice value of being in the same units as wide.
Which is why we take a square root at the very end of all that.
So root mean absolute error.
Our MSEE is the most popular error metric for regression models.
However hopefully you should have an understanding now of all three of those error metrics and in different
cases some are really more useful than others are MSE is the most popular for the reasons I previously
stated.
Now let's discuss R-squared values.
This is also known as the coefficient of determination.
It's not quite in error metric because we saw from the previous era metrics it's more of just a statistical
measure of your regression model.
As a quick know by itself just knowing only the R-squared value won't really tell you the whole story
of how well your model is performing in a very basic sense.
It's just a measure of how much variance your model accounts for and it's always going to be between
0 and 1 or 0 percent to 100 percent.
So an example would be your model has a point nine value for our square meaning explains 90 percent
of the variance of the data.
There's also different ways of obtaining R-squared such as adjusted r squared and some are squared methods
can actually yield a negative R-squared value.
So keep that in mind as you kind of explore machine learning on your own and you see a negative R-squared
value they may have calculated it using a different metric and the Wikipedia page for R-squared value
has really nice details on the different methods that you can calculate R-squared.
Now a full analysis and explanation of interpreting R-Squared is outside the scope of this course.
But check out the resource links for more information on this topic.
What I really want you to know about R-squared.
It's basically just a measurement of how much variance your model explains.
There's different types of R-squared such as that just that are squared.
It's really useful when you want to compare models to each other but you take in mind that you should
compare models and adjust that are squared not a normal or square.
And there's a lot more to this.
It's not as straightforward as just saying oh I have a point nine R-squared value which means my model
is great.
There's more subtleties to it than that but that whole discussion is outside the scope of this course.
It would take a really long lecture to discuss all that.
So I put in resources here just some links for you to read.
In case you're interested in finding out more about those R-squared features.
All right.
So again keep in mind the R-squared can enhance your understanding of a model or help you compare models
but it shouldn't be your sole source for evaluating a model.
Now let's continue on to our code example.
We're going to walk you through a more realistic code example for use in linear regression with Python
and Sparke.
Thanks I'll see at the next lecture.