Welcome to the K means clustering consulting project you're beginning to become world famous due to
your machine learning skills and the technology startup in California needs your help.
It's time for you to go to San Francisco to help out this tech startup.
They've been recently hacked.
I need your help finding out about the hackers.
Luckily there are forensic engineers have grabbed valuable data about the hacks including information
like session time locations word permanent typing speed etc..
The forensic engineer relates to you what she's been able to figure out so far she has been able to
grab meta data of each session that the hackers use to connect to their servers and she has that data
with features here the following features in the data that you're going to be provided.
There is a session connection time feature which indicates how long that hacking session lasted in minutes.
There's the bytes transfer which is the number of megabytes transferred during the actual session from
the company computer to the hackers computer.
There is another feature called Kalli Tracys which is a binary feature indicating that the hacker was
using the Kallio Linux operating system.
There's another feature called service corrupted that's number of companies servers that were corrupted
during the attack.
Then there's pages corrupted which is the number of pages illegally accessed by the hackers.
Then the location feature column indicates the location the attack came from.
However the forensic engineer believes this is probably useless because the hackers were using virtual
private networks or VPN.
Finally there's the word permanent typing speed feature column which is the hackers estimated typing
speed based on session logs.
Now the technology firm has three potential hackers that perpetrated the attack on their list.
However they are certain of the first two hackers but aren't very sure if the third hacker was involved
or not.
And this is where they've requested your help and where K means clustering can come into play.
So they want you to help them figure out whether or not that third suspect had anything to do with the
attacks or was it just two hackers essentially.
Was it two hackers or three hackers.
It's probably not possible to know for sure but maybe what you've just learned about clustering can
help.
And there's one last key fact which is going to help you determine the answer.
The forensic engineer knows that the hackers trade off attacks meaning they should each have roughly
the same amount of attacks.
So for example if there were 100 total attacks on their servers then in a two hacker situation each
of the hackers should have about 50 hacks in a three hackers situation.
Each would have about 33 hack's the engineer believes this is the key element to solving this but doesn't
know how did the single wish this unlabeled data into groups of hackers.
Best of luck with this project.
It should be a fun one.
If you get stuck feel free to go straight to the solution lecture.
We're going to code along an example solution.
I hope you enjoy this consulting project.
I'll see you at the next lecture.