Welcome to the logistic regression consulting project you did such a great job in the previous consulting
project that we're starting to spread about your abilities.
You've been contacted by a top marketing agency to help them out with customer churn.
They flew you out to New York City or some of the best marketing agencies in the world are located what
they need you to do is help them out with predicting customer churn.
So this marketing agency has many customers that use their particular service that produces advertisements
for the clients or customer Web sites and they notice they have quite a bit of churn in clients and
they currently randomly assigned account managers for each client.
However they want you to create a machine learning model that will help predict which customers will
churn.
That is thought by their service so that they can correctly assign the customers most at risk to churn
an account manager.
Luckily they have some historical data and they want to know if you can help them out.
The basic idea is to create a classification algorithm that will help classify whether or not a customer
turned then the company can test this against incoming data for future customers to predict which customers
will turn and assign them an account manager.
The data is under customer underscore turned out C S V.
So let's quickly go over that data and what your main task is.
So this is what the customer churn data looks like and these are the various columns lets go over them.
You have the name column which is just the name of the person who is the latest contact at this client
company.
You have the age column which is the number of years the customer has been in business.
Then you have the total purchase which is the amount of the total adds purchased and then you have the
account manager column which has a binary column where 0 means they have no manager and one means they
have an account manager assigned to them.
So remember right now in this customer churn CXXVI training set you have this particular account manager
call them being randomly assigned.
And thats something they want to fix later on.
Then you have the years column which is the total years as a customer for this marketing agency.
You have the name sites column which is the number of Web sites that use this particular marketing agency's
service you have the onboard date which is a date that the name of the latest contact was on boarded
the location which is the client headquarter address.
And then the company name so the name of the client company and then you have the label column.
So the label column is this chern column 0 or 1 indicating whether the customer has turned.
So your goal is to create a model that can predict whether a customer will turn zero or one based off
the various features.
Now keep in mind a lot of those features were strings.
Some of them will be useful some of them won't be useful at all.
Hopefully you can use your intuition to decide which ones are useful and which ones are not.
Remember that the account manager is currently randomly assigned so it's likely that in that training
set of customer underscore terms that see CSP file the account manager column isn't going to be very
helpful because it's just a randomly assigned value.
As always you can treat this consulting project as a loosely guided exercise or skip ahead and treat
it as a code along project.
Best of luck.
All the information you need is in the notebook and there's also a solution book for this consulting
project.
We'll see if the next lecture where we walk through an example solution.