Welcome to the linear regression consulting project so we're going to set you loose on your first consulting
project you've been contracted by Hyundai heavy industries to help them build a predictive model for
some ships.
You've been flown out to their headquarters in South Korea.
Hyundai Heavy Industries is one of the world's largest manufacturers of large ships including cruise
liners.
They need your help to give them accurate estimates of how many crewmembers A ship will require.
They are currently selling ships with some new customers and want you to create a model in these it's
predict how many crewmembers the ships will need.
That way once they sell the ship to the customer they can accurately report it estimate of how many
crewmembers will be required for the new ship they provided you data with these features.
The ship's name the name of the cruise line the age of the ship the tonnage of the ship the number of
passengers the ship can hold the length of the ship the number of cabins on the ship the passenger density
that the ship can hold.
And then the number of crewmembers needed for that ship your job is to create a regression model that
will help predict how many crewmembers will be needed for future ships.
In other words use the features you think will be useful to predictive value inside the Crew column.
So if we come back here you have various features and you want to predict using those features.
The very last bottom value the number of crew members needed the client has also mentioned that they
have found that particular cruise lines will differ in acceptable crew accounts.
So it's most likely an important feature to include in your analysis the cruise line value is a string
however and we haven't covered exactly how to convert strings the numbers with Python and spark yet.
So I want you to see if you can discover how to use string indexer from the documentation.
Google around the documentation see if you can find how to use string indexer and see if you can apply
it to the cruise line column to help with your analysis.
As in any real world project there are no 100 percent correct answers here.
Just try your best to build a predictive model and that optional aspect of it is to figure out how to
use string indexer on your own.
We'll cover more formally in future lectures as well as a possible solution lecture.
Coming up next after this one again this is a pretty open consulting project.
Feel free to either try it out on your own or if it's more your style.
Go straight to the next lecture to the solutions to do a code along of an example solution for this
consulting project.
There can definitely be more than one way to create this model.
OK.
Best of luck with the project.
All the necessary information for the project can be found in the following files.
The linear regression consulting project that notebook has everything you need to know and the CSP file
that goes with this project is called cruise line info.
If you're looking for the solutions notebook it's called linear regression consulting project underscore
solutions and that's a notebook we're going to be walking through in the very next lecture.
Best of luck and approach.
This however is your style to either try it out on your own or to treat it as a code along with the
next lecture.