Welcome to this course it's really great to have you as a student in this course in discourse.
We're going to do something fun.
We're going to build an entire angular app from scratch now.
Yep we're going to build this one.
This is dangler Fitness Tracker app.
It features users sign up where we specify e-mail password our birth date feature by a date picker and
then of course also have to agree to the terms and conditions.
And then we can log in and start exercises we choose from a set of exercises that's actually fetched
from the server we started.
We can cancel it if we want and we can of course do all the past exercises and we can even falter and
sorties.
That's a lot of cool features combined.
And behind the scenes we'll be using angular material angular fire and firebase which is awesome cloud
database service with a real time database and will also use N-G are x angular is more advanced state
management system.
And of course by the end of discours We'll also deploy the app to a real server in case angler's something
you know but you are no expert in it yet.
I also get a brief refresher section on angular and discours so that you can get started with quickly
and refresh your angular knowledge.
So that's of course pretty amazing and I can't wait to dive into that with you.
Now who am I though who's teaching you.
My name is MSXML and smarts Mitla.
I'm a freelance web developer and 5 star rated instructor.
You're on to me.
I teach a broad range of topics and I created the best selling and best rated Anglo course here and
to me the complete guide now.
This course doesn't replace it.
Not even close.
You don't learn angler from scratch.
I only got a brief refresher.
But I will show you how to take that angle of knowledge and apply it to a real project.
I work with ular since it's been an early alpha stages.
So I guess I can tell you a lot about it.
And with that I think enough of the talking.
Let's dive into what this course has to offer.
And then let's dive right into building this app.