So what is angular angular is a javascript framework.
You build javascript client side.
So in the browser apps with it to be precise it uses typescript a javascript superset.
So the language we use is typescript.
It's it's a language very close to javascript.
A lot of the syntax is the same but it offers some extra features and in some cases the features look
similar but very in details.
We have things like classes properties decorator's interfaces.
These are all terms you don't need to know you will see them in this course but that is essentially
the language we use.
Now as I said we use angular this framework to build client side.
So browser side web apps running in the browser obviously served by a server initially but they're after
running fully in the browser does this a huge advantage that we can create so-called single page applications
where we only download one page from the server and thereafter everything is handled in the browser.
This feels and looks a lot like native mobile apps.
Things happen very fast because we don't need to wait for some of our responses or if we occasionally
do we need to wait.
We at least wait for a new page but we can show a spinner on the existing page while status fetched
in the background.
You will see this in this course.
This native mobile app like user experience is of course very pleasant.
We all laughed at and that is why we use frameworks like angular angular awls is a framework that's
highly scalable and offers a great performance.
That is why it's very popular and allows you to build big and very big apps and it's continuously developed
and supported by Google.
That's the company behind angular.
So we can expect for it to all be alive in two years from now.
Now did we know angular.
What are its core concepts.
The core concepts are components and of course that we have a single page.
So we only get one page from the server engaged him a file and a bunch of javascript files and there
after the entire page and what's on it will be managed.
Why are javascript which we of course can use to dynamically create and remove elements.
We don't write code for that on our own though.
Instead we instruct angler to do so by building so-called components.
Our whole web site is made up of components like a or component component a sidebar or a item component.
So we basically build a bunch of building blocks and tell angular how to glue them together and angular
will do the rendering part.
The communication part and all these fun pieces which we don't want to code on our own.
And if you think about web pages you of course can easily deconstruct them into components because we
always have re-acquiring elements on all these pages.
A component is just a template where we have HVM the code which is enhanced with some special angular
syntax like here where we have a click listener and output some content as well as bind to some image
property.
Additionally to the template components are always accompanied by a typescript.
So you could say a javascript file where we write some logic for the components.
For example what should happen up when I click.
And besides having components with features like that we also have a number of templates and ex-U.S.
quite a lot and that are so-called directives.
We use that in component templates but directives allow us to manipulate the content whereas click listeners
and content output instructions as you see them in the middle example only change in minor pieces of
the app with directives like energy for we can dynamically loop for our data and then render whole parts
of the page based on that.
These are the core features we get now.
These components of need to communicate to from there we get various tools property and event binding
for example but all the things which are called services and dead is angular in a very very very condensed
nutshell.
Now I will dive into these core features over the next lectures and briefly walk you through them to
give you a feeling about how that all works and how we use that.
But definitely take an entire angular course if you want to dive deeper.
This module won't replace an entire course.