Let's start building a demo angler app and for dead we need the angular C-L I the command line interface.
This is a tool that creates new angler projects for us and we need it because angular project is more
than just the age HTML page and ascript fall because we use strip and because a lot of optimisation
needs to go into such app as well as the fact that we need development server to test it.
We need a more complex set up with a more complex build workflow that uses third party packages for
all these optimizations and build steps and Selye gives us such a workflow out of the box on CLID I
thought angular dot I O U C DS insulations steps which you need to execute to get started with the Seelye
and create a new project for it to work.
You need NPM which is notes package manager so you should also install note J.S. from note JSE dot org.
Choose the latest words there or if you're facing issues with that.
The long term stability Worthen on the left now note is not only required because of its package manager
which it automatically installs which we used to manage to seal it and then alter the project dependencies
but we also need she asked for the development server which has managed by the Seelye and which we can
spin up with it.
This development server is required because just double clicking the nix HDMI file won't do the trick
because double clicking the file won't actually use HTP to surf the page and therefore some features
just won't work.
Hence you want to have a real testing environment to see the app as it will run on a real web server
and for that we need a real web server.
We don't have to code it on our own though.
The Selye has one but it needs node j s to run it.
So if they're all out of the way let's install the Seelye for dead.
You should navigate into your terminal or a command prompt tool on your operating system and then with
node j s and stold run NPM install dashi at angular Seelye.
Now on Mac and Linux you might need to add a pseudo in front of that to get the right permissions with
that command you download and install the latest Seelye word.
And this could take a couple of seconds and minutes and once it's done you can use a different set of
commands to create a single or apps.
And also to run this development server and so on.
Now the seal I will already say that offers more features than just project creation and DiVall open
server running.
You can also create these angler components into which will dive with it and you should really check
out seal either angular dot IO to learn more about it.
So now the installation finished let's create our first project then.
For that I never get it into the folder where I want to create the project.
I did this here in the terminal with the cd command and now we can run engine you.
My first angular project or whichever name you want to choose DNG command is available.
Since we installed DCL I-and the last step.
Now it will create a project folder with a bunch of configuration files and a very simple app to start
with.
And there's also no installs all the dependencies.
So all the built dependencies as well as dangler package itself it can take a couple of seconds or minutes
and I'll be back once it's finished once installation finished.
You should open the folder it created with your favorite web development ID or editor that could be
sublime.
Adam web storm or Visual Studio code of free ID which I will also use in this course here is the project.
Does the folder structure you'll have after creating a new angle or project.
We've got a bunch of conflict files on the root level here.
You don't really need to work with these and in the source folder you will find your angular app to
be precise in the app folder there.
This is where you find this strange component false.
And as I said components are a core part of angular.
So we will work with DS Deandra files.
Also don't have to be touched as often though in the next lecture.
I'll quickly walk you through how an angler app actually works and starts and then will dive into the
individual core features that you gotta know when working with angular.