We're almost done with the refresher.
There's one more thing I want to cover and that is routing routing simply means that our angler app
can have multiple pages even though only one page is sent from the server.
The other pages are really just simulated retreaded or renders the entire page to give the illusion
of having loaded a new page even though everything was done by javascript which is of course faster
than fetching a new page.
So for that I'll add one new component.
Let's name a D.
Home Guard component tot he has fall in there I'll export my home component class and we could have
used to Selye to create this.
I'll add my apt component decorator which should be imported from at angular core and to the decorator
I'll pass my template here.
I'll use an illustrative syntax with an inline template where you just pass a string to define what's
inside the template and I'll just add a one take in say the home component and this is of course only
useful for very simple templates.
You might see that I'm missing the Select are here.
The reason for this is that I don't even need a selector when using routing but more on that later.
Now if I add a new component I also have to declare it in my app modules.
So here already home component and I'll also add the import path to the home component.
I just edited it so that we have multiple pages.
The Products page and the home page to add routing.
I'll now add a new file and I'll name it.
Abeche routing module does.
Yes it is a common convention to put routing into its own module.
Technically this is not required but here follow that convention in that file.
First of all create a new module.
The app routing module and since this is just a normal module it needs debt at Monch decorator so I'll
simply add this year at ngi module.
This NGI module decorator should be imported from angular core.
So we need to add at angular coord at the top.
No end here.
I wanted to find my routes for that.
I'll try the new constant routes which is of type routes.
Now this is a type coming from the Anglo router package.
So we import routes from at angular slash router.
Now with that we have to define the routes and routes requires an array of javascript objects where
each object represents the configuration of one route a route always needs to have a path.
This is the part after the domain.
In your t u r l an empty Potthast just your Roueche route.
Then you need to define a number property.
The components that should be loaded when this path is reached and here for the root POV I want to load
the home component.
You also need to get the import here so the typescript can find it not set up a second route by adding
an additional javascript object and here let's say the POF is products don't add slash products just
products.
This will be reached under your domain dot com slash products here the component should be the products
component and you'll also need to add import to that.
With that we got a very simple routing configuration.
Now we just need to inform angler about it and we do that by using the router module.
It's also important from an angle or router.
It's added to the imports array of our energy module there.
I reach out to the router module and call the four route method on it.
It does is used to define the route routes of our application and we simply pass that routes array as
an argument.
That this isn't an extra module and every module works stand alone and doesn't spoil its information
to other modules.
We need to add another key here to the energy module definition which is exports.
This takes an array of all the features from that module like to router Marshall in this case that we
want to expose to other modules.
In our case we want to expose it to the app module and therefore to the entire app so that safety app
routing watch.
Now.
Now we need to go to the app module and import this app routing module we're exporting functionality
there but we can only use it if we import it in another module.
So here in the app module all go to the imports array and add the app routing module as well as the
import path up here.
So with that we import our own module from our own file and add it to the imports area here with that.
Engler is aware of our roads.
We now just need to tell it where to render them for dead to go into the app component and instead of
hard including the app products page will use a special element the router outlet.
Now router out that is t l element you could say its a directive coming from angular actually which
marks the place in your document where you want to render about content above or below that will not
be replaced by the router component.
This element here will say if I add my cool app at the top we will see this on all pages.
Thats of course great because you could add a header instead.
But this router out that will be replaced with whichever component we find in the routing module here
for the given route.
Now we just need to have a way of navigating around.
And for that I'll create a very simple header in the app component.
Your I'll add a link and not use the normal ref element but instead the router link directive that's
all the provided by.
And it takes an input which is pointing to the.
When I go for Slash nothing that would be the home page and if I duplicate this to go to the product's
page here that would be slash products and this will be appended to your domain.
Now with that we can save us and now we get the two links and if I click it you'll see I can switch
between the two parts of my application and that is routing in a nutshell.
As with all the other features there's way more to it.
And you definitely should take an angular course to learn more about it.
But this is the core you got to know we will use it in this course and I hope it's a bit clearer now.