In the last lecture I showed you how flexible X works in a very brief refresher.
Let's now remove the C S S code and the javascript code and lets you as a number package and stat does
flex layout package I was already mentioning it simply abstracts away.
Does CSA s style set up I showed you in the last lecture and you use convenient to use directives to
assign DCF as classes basically that's what's happening behind the scenes.
Additionally it gives you a responsive API which simply means that you can combine these directives
with certain responsive directive additions were you to find if a certain rule should only apply to
certain screen sizes.
We'll see this in action though.
First of all we need to install it.
You can click on using angular Selye here to see how to use that flex layout package.
And they're important.
You don't need to install the Seelye.
We got this.
You can start with the install flex layout step which is only about installing one package with NPM
install dangler flex layout package.
So let's copy that command and let's quit and serve for a second and run this command here NPM install
angular slash flex dash layout dash dash se say once this is done we need to import flex layout to end
you module to unlock all these directives.
So let's restart and serve already and let's go to the app module and let's add in order at the top.
Where I import does flex lay out module here.
So Flex layout module from angular flex layout like this we now add this to Wirtz year flex layout module
and now we can start using these directives.
Let's go back to the Sign-Up component age female file and let's make sure that this form is actually
positioned from top to bottom.
We could do this manually with the flex boxes as classes I showed you but let's use this package to
use these convenience directives Tuta for him which is my wrapping element and which therefore could
be the flex container.
I'll add F X lay out and actually set this to a value of Cullom.
If you don't set a value here you will use the default of rope.
But I want to position the elements from top to bottom.
So I need to set this to column.
Now we can also add another directive F X.
Lay out a line to define the alignment of the elements.
For now let's not use it then let's see how elements are aligned so I'll cut this and go back to the
running application.
And we see it's a line from top to bottom but they're stretching over to full width and they sit on
the very left on very big screens.
This is a really strange looking form.
So instead let's change this by first of all making sure that our foreign fields don't take the full
width for it at all.
Add a class to my wrapping section here and I could also use that as a chest to the form and I will
name this sign up form the name is up to you though in the C S S file and then defines I'm Stultz 40
sign up for M C is this class.
And for now a will simply set the width year to 300 pixels a with which will look good both on mobile
devices as well as desktop devices.
Now if I go back to the sign up form and save that to and we go back to the running application and
reload as you see now with a smaller What nice to center everything though.
And you learned how it works you add dead ethics layered a line directive to the same element where
you added eFax layout and now you can assign center.
This will target the main axis which in our case for Cullom is from top to bottom.
So now it's centered in the middle of from top to bottom.
What do you expect us to look like.
Well let's have a look.
It doesn't look the way we want.
And we can reloaded as often as we want because it's centered word actually and just doesn't help us
or we don't have a problem with that.
And if you're wondering why it's not centered in the middle of the page because the wrapping container
doesn't have a height of 100 percent so it only takes the height of the elements it contains.
Instead we need to center on the cross axis and we do this by adding a second center.
This will be assigned to the cross axis value and now it's centered a little bit for in the middle.
But the problem we face is that of course the sign up form the wrapping class year simply has the width
of three hundred pixels at the form sits inside of that.
So it's centered inside of these three hundred pixels which is not the behavior we want to fix this.
I will actually get rid of this sign up for class year and instead I can show you something else which
is pretty interesting to note.
You can directly target the component selectors of material design components all target map for field
as I could target a normal aged female element and get data with a 300 pixels.
And now the cool thing is this will now give it that with.
But Centra everything in the middle because the container now still takes 100 percent of the width.
And if we expect this on a mobile device you see it looks good there too.
And with that we get this centered and we get our first look at angular flex layout.
Now let's continue this road and let's continue working on this for him and add more than just the boring
input fields.