Time to continue on our sign up for.
We added.
Q inputs are two components actually we are more than that.
We are at the forum field and input component and I want to add more components but first of all let's
add a basic component a button so that we can submit this form and see how we can actually grab these
values and work with them.
Now the cool thing is these form field components your work with both the reactive forms approach and
the template driven one.
So you can use either of the two.
Let me show you how to use the template driven one year.
However it's exactly the same code you use in any other English app.
First of all let me quickly add a button as you might remember that's a normal button where you add
Matt.
And then for example rased button I will also add a color here which are set to primary and I'll add
submit as a text.
Now use that button you need to add something to the material module the mat but marginal needs to be
imported and added to imports and exports.
We already got this from the early example though.
So with that added If we go back to the application we see that button in the middle of the click it
submits the form which I don't want like this.
Now first of all let me get this partner type submit which is a good practice a good pattern.
And let's now make sure that we control is for Frue angular as you might know it by default on a form
which is not initialized with the re-active approach angle or use a template driven approach.
If we add a special import to the app module Do you know which import that is.
If you do go ahead and edit It's the form's module to unlock forms functionalities we need to import
this into our Engler app.
So I'm going to add import to the app module.
It's the form's module and it's coming from angular forms like this.
Now go to Raptor's forms module and I will add it to imports.
Now aler will detect our form and will automatically create object representation offered behind the
scenes.
The form isn't that useful though.
We need to register our inputs as controls to the angle of form and we do this by adding two things
when using the template driven approach.
At least we add energy model like this.
We could add with two way binding but this directive alone is enough to make angular aware of it.
And I don't want to use tway binding here.
One thing we have to add though is the name attribute where we give this control a name.
Here I'll name it email.
Now for the password.
All the add and model and give us a name of password now with that we got all these controls set up
now to make this forum submit a bill I will first of all give it a local reference by adding hash tag
and that the name of the reference like F and assigned us to Engy form.
It just gives us access to this automatically created object.
It then stores it in this f local reference which we can only use the template to get to some method
in our typescript file or bind DNG submit event which is made available by Engler and it will execute
on submit and pass this local reference F and you can name as whatever you want.
Now in the typescript file maps on the testing fall but in the typescript file here I can add on submit
and there will receive a form which will be of type ngi for him and you can add the import here which
should point to at angle of forums like this.
So we get this forum here and for now let's simply log it to the console like at.
Now with that we help button which will submit the form which will be catched by angular through and
you submit it which will trigger on submit and forewards the automatically created for.
Let's go back to our page and hit submit.
And indeed I greased this entry form here with all the fields.
You probably already know.
And if I enter an e-mail here like test at test dot com and testor and submit does well then we can
see that under value we get an object which has an or a password with our values.
Now that's nice but can't we do more with that.
Can we add validation.
Maybe show an error message and maybe show a hint.
Let's do all these things in the next lecture.