So over the last lectures we added our basic form.
We added validation hints and you'll learn how the angular material components.
Mostly the math for Imphal component when it comes to forms gives you a lot of out of the box working
functionalities to create beautiful forms which provide great user experiences.
Now let's add more form fields because of course you're not limited to just inputs.
If you have a look at the official angular material documentation under form controls you'll find things
like order completing inputs.
You can learn more about that here on that page of course.
And also the date picker and the checkbox to component.
I want to use for now.
Later we will also see the select input.
So let's start with the date picker the date picker is actually a bit of a more complex component but
still easy to use.
Let's have a look at its code here.
You see you typically use it by wrapping it in a map form field since you typically use it enough for
him and one to have things like the floating label one to have things like maybe hints and arrows.
You don't use a normal input with madded put which you connect to the date picker to output the date
picked by the user.
And then you have to the actual date picker component which consists of a toggle.
So a button that opens the date picker and then the date picker which is shown if you click the toggle.
Now one crucial part of the picture is that it also manages to date format.
So if it picked this date your it outputs this in this format and that's of course important for us
because we want to use a format that fits to the locale of our application.
Now you can learn more about the date picker here in this article of course some advanced use such as
how to restrict pick a date and so on.
And also about internationalization.
Now here you actually got a working internationalization out of the box and you can easily inject your
own data local into providers of your root module where you define which locale your app should use.
And this will control how the data is actually formatted automatically for you.
For this all to work there's one important part and that can be found here under choosing date implementation
and date format settings.
Now you can actually choose from different ways of how the data should be formatted and handled.
There you see we basically have to map native state module which is built into material angular material
where it only end USA supporters but which also has no dependencies.
Or you use them more powerful math moment date module where you have more support locales.
You can click this link to actually see more about that.
Here are all the locales that are supported but where you also have a separate dependency moment Chase
which is an external library you need to install in this case.
No I will go with the native date module but in the end all comes down to just importing this module
which will do in a second possibly then setting this data locale which will only work with momentary.
Because the native one only supports us and then automatically getting dates which are formatted for
the language you're using.
Now important you can also go as far as customizing the parts and display formats entirely.
It does it's highly wants though and not something I'll cover here but in the end you can essentially
write your own data that if you want.
However I will not do this here if you want though.
Here's an example in the code.
It shows you how to set this all up and how you could create your own date parser.
Before we go to add once though let's simply add a date picker shall we.
So to do so let's go back right to the start and let's have a look at this example.
Let's add a new date picker before this button here.
And let's add Matt for field as a wrapper.
So this component which gives us access to floating labels and so on.
Let's add our normal input here where I will add math input this directive to turn it into material
input that works nicely together with Matt for field and then lets also add a placeholder maybe choose
a date or maybe your birth date because let's say Dad is what I want to fetch your birth date like this
with that if we save this and we go back to our application we got this input which is a normal input
and no date picker.
It'll stay in normal input but our goal is to automatically populated with a date value we pick from
that date picker.
For that I will add a new component right below the input and that's the Matt date picker toggle that's
the button which opens the date picker.
You can see it here.
Now for this to work we need a date picker too.
And as you see the two interact by adding a four property binding to the toggle where we point to some
local reference which is assigned to the actual date picker.
So let's implement this pattern here too.
Let's add Matt date picker.
This is the actual date picker which is hidden initially.
Let's give it a local reference.
You can use any name you want.
And let's then bind the 4 property of the date picker toggle component and set it equal to this local
reference here.
Now if we save this it wouldn't run though the reason for this is very simple.
We haven't added an import to our material module so let's simply do that.
Let's add the Matt date picker module here.
Now let's add it to build imports and exports.
So here I'll add Matt Dave picker module split this up over multiple lines.
So here's Matt date picker module.
Add it to both imports and exports.
With that if we go back to our application I still get an error and the error is that no provider for
date adapter was found.
Now as I said there are two built in ones you can choose from but we have to choose at least one or
just one.
So here I'll use the native one.
So mapped native Dave module and this should now also be added to imports and exports so that the picker
can format the date automatically.
Now it redirect me to where it comes let me quickly go back to sign up and on this page we now get the
toggle button.
But if you click on it we get no associated input.
Well that makes sense because how Or should the date picker know where to enter to date.
We actually picked.
We want to intrude into dis input but it can't assume that it's the next input which is next to a toddler
or something like that.
We have to tell it explicitly of course and this is a good behavior.
Otherwise it might get really hard to control more complex forms to tell it dead it just does input.
We add a directive to this input which is matched date picker distractive stand alone doesn't work.
We need to bind to a property of that directive which is also called Matt.
Picker.
And as a side note this is important.
Matt Dave picker is directive coming from the Dave picker module.
It's not a property of input it's a directive and this directive happens to have a property named Max
date picker to which we bind with this syntax.
So now with that we can assign a value here and that should be the picker.
So this local reference with that to toggle is connected to the Speaker and his input is connected to
the value this pic or spits out.
We now save doesn't go back to our application and I click the toggle again.
Now it works and if I enter something it's kind of NTSA say it into our input but then it doesn't right.
This looks really actually the I Can the toggle is positioned right below the value simply because we
can configure this toggle and we can add Matt suffix to position this as a suffix at the end of the
input.
If we add this the toggle switches to the right.
And now this looks much better and we can choose a date.
Now let's say we want to restrict the range of dates the user can pick from because maybe we only want
to accept people that are at least 18 years old they shouldn't be able to pick a date dead would make
them younger than that.
How can we restrict the range.
Let's take a look.