In the last lecture we added the date picker and I simply reformatted to decode to make it easier to
read here not want to add validation.
I want to use or add a max date which ensures that the user can only pick a date that makes him at least
18 years old.
Q At dysfunctionality we can add the max property to the input.
This will add the max value validator and if we set this to a date this will automatically be recognized
by the date picker and taken into account.
So this should now be a date.
And let's actually use property binding so that we can bind to a property of our types of class all
named is Max state and I'll go to the typescript class.
This one here.
And at the max state property I binding to here too.
Now here I want to add a new date and this new date should ensure that a person has to be at least 18
years old.
That's actually initialize this all in the energy on init method Ursel just set max date here to find
initially but an engine in it and then said this Max state equal to new date.
But thereafter I want to set a max date call a set date on it to set it to a new date and there used
the old max date just to date is to day by the way.
So I'll use today and on today on the date which refers to today I'll get the full year.
Is a method.
No I can deduct 18 here to set my not date.
Excuse me my full year instead.
Q Two days a year minus 18 and this should actually give me a max date which is today 18 years ago.
Now max date is what I bind to the max property here and now if we save that all and I click on the
date picker you see it automatically jump back to January 2000 because I'm recording this on January
16th 2008 team and the first date I can pick or the oldest date actually is dead and they can't even
go to more recent months.
So this is awesome functionality which of course takes quite simple trick to build on your own which
is shipping with the match date picker.
So again an example off.
It's not just styling.
There's a lot of logic inside that angle a material component.
So now we can pick this and it will output the birth date here just fine of course with the same logic
as we said max date.
You could also set the mandate if you want to insure at at least a certain date has to be picked.
And this is how easy you can add validation to your date picker.
But even more than that how it automatically adjusts and only displays a certain range.
And this is the date picker and how we're going to use it in this project.
Now let's move on.
And in the next lecture.
Let's also add a checkbox.