In the last lecture we are at the site now.
But the issue is the height is very limited.
The reason for this is it's how H.T. email works.
If you don't define heights then it will only take the height it needs to wrap all content which in
this case is the tool bar.
Unwelcome works to fix this.
We need to change some stylings for this.
We should go into deep components C S S file and add stylings for Matt side Neph container which is
a container wrapping everything as well as MAP side nav content which is the container for the content
that is below Deeside Nath.
Both should be set to use height 100 percent.
You also want to do that for math science.
So for the actual side.
Besides that you should go to Stout's thought see assess and give the whole body of the document all
to a height of 100 percent so that the entire body takes the full height.
Even if the content inside of it doesn't require it.
With that if we reload application still doesn't work right.
The reason is the height alone isn't enough we also need to assign it to HQ mail so we can put it into
the first rule.
Now with that if we go back we can actually see that if I talk of the side in we know half the full
height which in my opinion looks much better.
Of course we have the issue that the side that only is as wide as required though so what we can do
is we can go back to the Yapp components CSSA fall and for the math side.
Now for the actual site navigation container not a container which also contains the content of the
page.
Just a side nav we can give it a whiff of let's say 250 pixels.
Now with that we'll use that which looks much better in my opinion.
So that's our side navigation.
Let's now work on the toolbar because Dad looks ready ugly.
First of all.
I don't want to have a dead button here.
I want to have all I can BOTTEN which shows the hamburger menu then I want to have the logo but some
distance in between would be nice and they all after I want to have my links which all should look differently.
Let's work on all these things.
Let's start with the button in the Afkham Hornet HTL fall where we have our tool bar for the button.
Let's give it the mad dash icon button directive or component selector to be precise.
Now we can't place ikan on the button and have it look good.
We do this by adding d Matt Iken component inside of the button.
Me quickly restructure this so that it looks a bit easier or is easier to read.
So this is our But no end in the Met.
I can here we can use the menu icon and you can always check this material.
I could page I mentioned earlier maybe use the name of all I can.
That looks like this hamburger menu.
We do that.
We see this Nye's button here.
That looks much better.
Now onto the links.
I'd rather have them look differently and it would be nice if they were sitting on the right of the
toolbar and not next to the logo.
How can we achieve that let's start with the stylin the components CSSA fall of first of all simply
style my anchor tax here.
Q hath no text decoration.
So it should not be underlined and to have a color of white let's say with that they already start looking
better.
But I went to a different style for links which I'm hovering over or which are active.
So which you clicking on there we could assign a color of let's say light gray maybe let's see how that
looks like if we do that and we hover over all I can.
Yeah we can see which one we're hovering on.
Now that's what I think but pushing them to the right was another thing I wanted to do.
And here we could take advantage of the fact that the tool bar uses flex blocks flex blocks as I showed
you in the very brief introduction distributes all elements along a main axis and the main axis depends
on the Flex direction.
Now for toolbar as you can probably guess it's row from left to right now to get the free links all
the way to the right.
We can actually do a couple of different things.
One is to give this div which contains the links DFA X flex property and safeness No by doing this alone
we won't see a difference.
But one thing did change if we inspect dealings we see they are in a container that takes the full A-Whale
with that what's different before it before we had a container that only took as much with as required
as it is the case for logo and the hamberger I can.
So now we have that container.
We could also give this Dev D F X layout directive to turn it into a flex container.
Yes.
An element can be both a flex container and a flex element at the same time.
Leave the set to the default of row but set f x.
Lay out a line equal to flex and for the main axis which is from left to right this will push them all
the way to the end of their container.
So now they're at the end of this header and alternative with Ben to not use this approach.
So let's remove that.
But to enter a number diff between the logo and the links here and give this the eFax flex directive
then this for take all the available remaining space and therefore this would not all be pushed all
the way to the right.
So this would have been an alternative.
Now I'm going to use the first approach because it shows more features of the Flex layout package but
what we can see is that the links are way too narrow.
Well to fix this I will add a unordered list here does also semantically better with list items where
each link sits inside a list item.
So let's quickly do that for all three.
Let's put the log into a list item and training into a list item and with that add it it'll actually
look horrible because now we have an unordered list here on the right to get rid of that.
What I will do is I'll turn to an ordered list into a f x layout so that this uses flex box to distribute
its elements.
Now from left to right now of course we should also change the styles though so give us a class of navigation
items maybe.
And let's go to the map component see a SS file and add navigation items here and does it sitting on
the order list so there I want to set the list style to nonne and remove all padding and margin this
might have with that we're back to where we were before but at least Snel semantically better.
Now the goal is to add some spacing between these list items and we're using flex layout here on the
wrapping container.
Now what I can do is I can also add F X lay out Gap again and set this to 10 pixels by doing that we
get some spacing between the different flex items and you don't even need to assign ethics flex to DS
list items that would ensure they take all the way to that space.
But I actually only want to have them take as much space as they need and not as much as they can.
So with that the navigation is finished for now.
Was a lot of work but now we can navigate between Sign up log in and well training where we got nothing.
No when clicking on Logo I want to go back.
That's one thing I'll add.
So here for the logo I'll add the anchor tag were the router link points to the main page.
Seems sensible to me.
And now with Dad it truly is finished.
Got the logo where we can go back.
We get the links and we get a side nav that's working.
Now obviously we need responsiveness.
We want to have these links inside the site Neph and we only want to have the hamburger icon on smaller
screens where we don't on the other hand don't want to have the header and where we all want to have
a truly responsive layout and not assumed in worship of the Web site.
So responsiveness is what we're working on next.