We add that the toolbar and the side.
Now it's time to make our website responsive.
And for that we can have a look at the flex layout package again.
Thus far we had a look at the static API with ethics lay out lay out a line gap and we also used epix
flex we didn't use order offset or align or fill because well you really need these you really need
to change the order.
But what I want to do now is I want to have a look at the responsive API.
This allows us to annotate all these directives with been working with with responsive directives like
X asked for on small devices or lower then small so to only apply something on very small devices so
annotate all the static API directives with these responsive directives to only apply them on certain
screens.
Let me show you what I mean in our example here we get if we go back to the stedding API for a second
we get these helper directives at the bottom ethics height and show which determines whether something
is winnable or not.
Now we could simply hide this entire block here on the toolbar on small or very small devices and hide
the menu button on bigger devices.
This way the site nav could only be open on smaller ones and toolbar navigation would only be shown
on bigger ones.
We can of course do this by adding ethics show and hide so we can go to the day if that wraps our navigation
items and add ethics height.
Now if I save this and I go back to my page it disappears.
The navigation is gone.
Now that's a first step.
I want to hide it only on small devices of course.
Now we can add this responsive API.
We can add a dot and now annotate this with any of the response of directives for example x x which
means only apply ethics high on very small screens and you can go back to documentation to see that
definition for this under responsive API.
You'll see that access simply applies does media query where it says only four screens to go up to 600
pixels.
The rule where this was added will apply.
So in our case only four screens up to five hundred ninety nine pixels.
They will be hidden or this layer will be hidden.
This navigation list.
So if we go back to our app we can absolutely see the menu here.
But if I switch to mobile mode it's gone.
And of course the same for different mobile phones.
Now this shows what I mean.
But we a.
We get no menu here but we got it here.
Now let's do the opposite for the button for the menu button.
I'm going to grab this and now on this day which wraps the button we can add it but of course you want
to hide that on everything but very small screens.
So we could say F X s m f x hide M D and all these classes you see here.
So we have to do that for large and extra large to ethics hide large ethics hide x l by doing this.
If we go back we see no menu button here.
And if I shrink the screen it's Stehr if we go to smaller devices.
Actually it appears at 1030 already because sumed in if I were to soome out again.
To my normal resolution then this would not appear and would only break at 600 pixels.
So all the 600 pixels and smaller we get this button.
Let me Sumant again though.
So this is our responsive set up here where we only get this menu bar on small screens.
Assigning to classes like this is a bit cumbersome.
Know what we could do is we could add F X show X s.
If we do this it's always visible though.
So this doesn't help us here.
Instead we can use a number a helper class.
We all get lower and greater than classes and we want to say this should be hidden.
So ethics height for everything which is greater then extra small does is referring to this helper class
here.
And with this set up we now get the same effect as before but with less code.
And now we got a responsive navigation here.
Still of course the side they have a separate empties.
So that is something I want to work on next.
And then we should all have a look at how we can actually split this app component up into smaller more
focused subcomponents.
Let's work on all these things over the next ELECTRESS.