We had it's taps and The Last Lecture.
Now I want to work on the new training now for the new training.
I actually want to use a cart.
Look now what do I mean with CART look.
Let's look at the official documentation they are under layout.
You find a cart component and you might notice look from a lot and lot and lot of web pages carts like
this or if you have a look at examples like this is a more complex card.
Of course you can view the source code of this code to the idea behind a card a simple you have a wrapper
for the entire card like Matt card.
In this case and then in the angular material you give a couple of subcomponents which you can nest
into the card if you want to get that out of the box nicely style title subtitle the general content
image that might be placed at the top and stretches to full with some action so some buttons at the
bottom which you can also see here and also a folder which you can optionally at all if that is optional.
It allows you to assign content to different places of your card but you can also start with a card
as simple as that.
Now here I won't take a super simple card.
We will build a card with the title a content and some actions and then want to have a card which essentially
says new training or something like that.
And where I don't have a form inside of it that allows me to select the training of what to do the exercise
I want to do.
And then an action so a button and which allows me to start that's trading now for that let's go back
to the code.
And let's at max dash cart as a component like this.
Now Matt card won't work because why we haven't imported it right.
So let's go to the material module again.
And they're at the top.
Let's import Matt Hart module.
This one and you know the game.
We also added two imports and we added two exports with Datsuns.
We import data.
The module we can use the card in the new trading component like that.
Now Matt card is a start but as I said I want to have a title some content and also some buttons.
What I also want to have is I want to restrict the width of this mat card so that it's not spanning
the full width on big screens but only on small screens.
Let's start simple let's add.
This is a card and see what this looks like.
If I save this and we go back to our application then we see the card here.
And you don't really see a card because it spans the full width so everything is white here.
Now as I just said for bigger screens I'd like to restrict the width.
We can easily do this.
Why is simply assigning eFax blanks and setting this to let's say 400 pixels.
We do that then we got a card which actually ends over here but which has one disadvantage.
The disadvantage is dead it's positioned all the way to the left.
We can fix this with flex box as you learn but to be able to position this we need to wrap it to that
container where we can use the eFax lay out directives.
So let's quickly add a section to your class new training.
We'll see if we needed.
And then I'll add my card in that section and cutis s.i at F X or lay out just like death row is OK
and ethics lay out a line should center it horizontally.
Now what do I need to enter here to center the card horizontally.
Do you know that
I need to enter center because the first value which we assigned to ethics lay out a line always centers
on the main axis.
If we don't override ethics layout to use Culham then the default set up is to use row and then the
main axis is from left to right.
So if we don't center on the main axis we center horizontally so that if we say if this we get a centered
card in the middle.
No that's all right.
This is nice.
We got a card.
Yea but it would be better if we also had a title more detailed content for example.
Drop down and some buttons.
So let's add such things to our card.
I will remove this as a card and instead add Matt card's title a component we can use inside of Matt
card also exposed by the Matt card module and in there we could add time to start a workout.
Whatever you want.
If I've saved this then we got this title on the card.
Now a title is nice but we want to have some content too.
So let's add Matt card content below the title.
This is where I later want to add my dropdown so that I can select which type of training I want to
take.
So I'll say select type of training for now.
And below that card content I'll add mat card actions and in here you add an action by simply adding
a normal button a normal button with Mat button.
Here like this.
Here you can give it any caption you want like start and the button can be of type submit as I will
later add for him.
But with that we essentially got our card finished.
If we go back and have a look at it does this how it would look like get the start button down there.
And this looks a bit ugly.
Odd traveler at a drop down here as I mentioned already.
So let's work on this and let's add a dropdown to select the type of exercise you want to do in the
next lecture.