Time to add some roud protection with that I mean that we can't reach the training route if we're not
affected basically.
And for that we can use a route guard.
Now I'll go to the off folder and add off guard dogs.
TS now export a Claassen here which all named off guard and this will actually be a normal typescript
class.
It will implement a certain interface though an interface which needs to be imported from at angular
router.
Now which interface is this.
It's the can activate interface.
So for this colossal Abdy implements keyword and then implement that can activate interface.
And this now forces me to add a can activate method in this method.
We actually get a couple of different arguments.
The first argument is the route we're trying to activate it's of type activated route snapshot which
you actually import from the router package.
So the same we used to import can activate
the second argument we receive here is the current routing state it's type routers state snapshot.
And does this also import that from the angular router packet and not from any other package.
So this method will be executed by angular in the US off guard whenever we well run into it and I will
show how we attach it to our route and a second the off guard is not complete though it needs to return
true or a promise that resolves to true or an observable that resolves to true.
So here I will return true for now.
Now that would be correct and it would always grant us access.
Now instead of course I want to check whether the user is offended.
So at d at injectable decorator here which needs to be imported from at angular CT
and I do add it such to they can inject the off service year because the off service is the part where
we find out where the user is offending get it or not.
So I'll inject the off service and for that you need to ensure that you do import the off service your.
Now with the officer who has him or that we can assign this hype here and inject it.
And now you're in can activate are actually not true but reach out to be of service and returned or
sort of my is off method we have in there now is off Meffert if you recall is this method down here
which records whoever user is set or not.
And it will not be said if the user is not affected.
So here we only return true and therefore it grant access to the route we wanted to load.
If is of is true now actually returning just that is not enough we have to do something if it's not
true because our wise routing will not be allowed to use we get stuck.
So I will check if dys returns true.
And if this is the case.
So if we make it into this check here I will return true otherwise though if this fails I want to redirect
the user.
So I'll inject the angular router here.
Which I also import from the angular router package and with that injected here I will call this router
and now navigate to slash log in that is where I want to redirect the user to.
If it tries to access the router was not being authenticated with that the guard the set up.
The question is how do we use it.
And the answer is we attach it to a route in our routing setup.
So in the app routing module here we get our training route which should be protected and we can protect
it by adding a new property to the route configuration which is called can activate and this is an array
of classes which all have to implement the can weird interface because angular will execute the can
activate method that interface forces us to implement for us.
So this method will be executed by angular and for single or two executed.
Well we have to add our Kinect with guard to diskette actuator array for this route where we want to
use it.
So here I will add my off guard and we need to add an inch or two off guard from the off that guard
file in the off folder.
And with that that route is now protected.
Now there is one tiny thing missing it's not obvious but the off guard.
Behind the scenes is treated as a service it's injected by angular.
Even though we don't injected angler dusters for us and for days to work we need to provide it.
Now normally we would provide a deep module but here we can provide the app routing module because it
will still actually be made available to the entire app.
But we only use it here in the routing section and we can make this really clear by adding providers
here.
So providers of guard.
And this is a rare exception.
You normally should provide in the app module or directly in a component but guards are fine to be provided
in the routing module.
Now with that we can go to our application and if I now try to access slash training here you see I
get redirected to slash log in if I do log in successfully though.
And I don't go to training.
I am allowed to access this.
I'm not redirected here.
So this is Route protection being added.
This was a lot of work on of education and so on and Portland but did I promise to also work on training
data and add angular material components that relies on data.
Well we'll work on this next.