We worked on a syndication Let's close this chapter for now.
We'll reopen it later once we add a server and let's work on the training now.
Now in training section we also of course should work with data we should store exercises done by the
user so that we can output them under past exercises.
So four days of first of all add a model next to my training component and I'll name it exercise not
the model that's the Fall name because in there I'm going to define how exercise should look like and
you're of course free to the finders in whichever way you want.
I'm going to expert a interface named exercise and exercise in my application should have an ID which
is of type string.
You could of course also make it of type number but I want to have a well human readable ID.
And in general have an idea that all that can consist of characters.
It should have a name of course which we understand something like crunches and so on duration because
not all exercises take equally long and that can be a number.
Let's say in seconds it's up to you how are you to find out calories burned if you make it over the
full duration.
That could also be a number or should be a number probably.
Now also if you finished or canceled the exercise a date so basically the date when you started it of
type date should be optional though because not all exercise is half that.
If we set up an exercise to populate our dropdown it's not going to have a date and you could create
a separate model but we can also mix it really nice and a state to state all is optional and this actually
is a type of assignments in Texas which you might not know you can assign a couple of possible values
as a type because I want to have a completed or canceled as a state so I'm accepting two strings or
now.
This should not be a colon.
But this pipe symbol so state deceiver a string of text completed a string with text.
Canceled may be spelled correctly though or.
Now this is my exercise Mandala which I want to use now.
I'll also need a service where we manage all exercises we know as well as our completed and canceled
exercises.
So for that I'm going to add a new fall next to this model we just created which will name training
service.
You could of course also name it.
Exercise starts here.
I'm going to export a class training service where I want to manage all the exercises we know as well
as all the exercise to be completed and so on.
I'll start with a property named away lable exercises which is of type exercise so make sure to import
dad from that model of fall we just created of type exercise.
Air raid though not a single one.
And here I want to create a couple of exercises we will start with.
So which are available in our app.
You can of course create your own exercises and find this to your needs.
Attached to this video you'll find this aere or these objects of predefined exercises with various durations
in seconds and the calories you burn during this duration.
So this is now the first thing we can use in conjunction with angular material in our new training component.
We hard code different training.
We have what we can now connect this to the way that all exercises of our training service.
Here's your challenge.
Try this on your own in the next lecture.
We'll do it together.