In the last lecture we injected our training service let's now connected to the new training start button.
Right now I image does training start event which I then consume in a training component but now I want
to do all of that through services for debt in the training service.
Let's first of all add a couple of properties.
The first one is the running exercise which is of type exercise.
This should store the exercise which the user selected if any.
With that we can now add start exercise method here which I want to call from the new training component
wouldn't be clicked the start button were a set exercise the user chose for dad all pass or all received
to select that idea which should be a string.
I will have to make sure that this is passed from the component and then I will find the exercise to
user selected.
So the selected exercise which will temporarily store this constant can be found in my A-Whale exercises
with the help of the find method where it will execute this arrow function on every element in the array
and return an object where I return true here in that arrow function.
I want to return true if the exercise ID.
So the exercise is currently looking at.
Again it will look at all exercises in that array.
If that's equal to the selected ID because then I know they selected ID matches the optic I'm currently
looking at.
You should return true because we found the optical one to find.
So ultimately this will give me the object the user selected.
And now all store does in running exercise I'll store my selected exercise in this property.
And yes we could skip this extra line.
We could also just set this running exercise equal to that.
So this running exercise equal to that would all be perfectly fine.
Now with that set up we're storing the exercise user selected in the service.
That is great but only part of what we wanted to do.
I still want to inform the training component about the select that exercise so that it can hide the
maktab group and show the current training and stat for that in the training component.
I'll have to get informed about Webroot use or picked new training or not.
So I want to set up this event driven approach here too just as we did it for authentication.
I guess this is another great place for you to practice this.
We get a certain event the user clicks the start button which you need to connect to your start exercise
method here and then you have to admit an event to which you subscribe and the training component to
change ongoing training.
True whenever Well it occurs.
Does this your challenge in the next lecture we'll do it together.