What are you successful.
Now let's try this out step by step in the training service.
I want to meet an event as I said before that I don't use DA or event emitter as you learn but you are
actually a subject so import
subject from our exchange as Slash subject like that.
I now want to create a new property here.
Maybe right at the top which I'll name exercise changed
which is a new subject that will eventually hold a payload of type exercise because I want to pass to
select that exercise to whoever is listening so that whoever's listening knows which exercise was chosen.
So exercise changed is now something I have to execute here in start exercise.
This exercise changed.
Next is the code that emits it.
And here I will actually return a new object where I distribute all the properties of this writing exercise
again for the simple reason that I don't want to return the same object I'm storing in the service.
Now I admit this I call next.
We can now subscribe to exercise changed and I want to subscribe in the training component in there.
I will therefore First of all already import subscription from our exchange subscription so that we
can also unsubscribe and therefore save memory.
I'll then add a new property.
The exercise subscription year which is of type A subscription
and now I want to set up a subscription in NZ on it.
Now for that I need to inject the training service so private training service of type training service
is what I am here and for that you also need to add an import at the top which points to your training
daat service file and pulls in the training service type.
And now with that object that in NZ on in it I can store it in my subscription and it is whatever gets
returned by the SUBSCRIBE method which I want to execute on training service exercise changed.
This will fire when ever we got a new exercise.
So here I actually get the exercise as a value instead of the SUBSCRIBE method and I want to do what
I actually don't care about the exercise.
But if it's not now then ongoing training should be set to true because of the exercise to select that
exercise is not null.
It means the user didn't pick one and that means were in the training.
So here I will set this ongoing training equal to true.
However I only want to do this if exercise is treated as truthy So if it is an object or something which
is not null or undefined if it is null or undefined then I want to set this ongoing training to false.
And of course you could also put this all into one line.
But I guess this is a bit more readable.
So now we're changing this whenever we're starting an exercise now in the training component template.
This means that I can remove the training start listener on the app.
New training component and inside the app new training component.
I can now go to On-Star training and no longer emit this method.
Instead I want to call this training service start exercise and important.
I need to pass the idea of the exercise which was chosen.
Now this is important how do I get this idea though.
I get this idea from a forum.
I have to create in this cart so that clicking this button actually submits the forum and we can read
the selected ID from the forum.
I will do this in the next lecture.
For now let me simply clean up this event emitter and remove the unnecessary event emitter and output
imports.
Now with that we get a broken app right now will fix it in the next lecture.
Let's add a forum to new training.