What does angle fire.
If we have firebase our angular app then angular fire acts as a bridge between these two things.
Actually we have of course more options than just using angle of fire since dad is a package that is
not made available by the firebase team but buys up our developers.
So it's not the official solution but of course an absolutely fine one to use.
I'm just stressing this to emphasize that you've got alternatives.
You can't for example use various rest.
API is provided by firebase does would allow you to use the angular H to the client to connect to firebase
store data fetch data authenticate users do all these things.
If you've gone through my angular Complete Guide course you saw the arrest API in action for the real
time database.
And we won't use that in this course.
We also can use the official firebase SDK which is a javascript package we can use in any javascript
project and that's of course also true for angular projects.
Again if you've gone from my complete guide course you saw DSK in action there we use that for the authentication
module but it will also not use that and discours Instead we'll use angular fire.
A third party package which actually also provides us all the features are a lot of the features the
STK the official SDK gives us.
But in a manner that embraces observables and nicely integrates into angular.
You can only use it in annular atts that's important you can't use it in other frameworks but there
it integrates really nicely and it makes using firebase a recess you will see the important part really
is that observable based nature which is absolutely in line with angler's strategy of all is using observable
wolds wherever possible.
Now for that we of course need to understand what observables and subscriptions and so on really are.
Now that is something I'll have a look at in the next lecture if you know everything about that.
Feel free to skip that lecture of course.