So in the last lectures I introduced you to angle of fire.
And we use some absorbable magic combined with snapshot changes to get exactly that data from our collection
that we need.
Now of course I want to take this a step further.
It's good that we can select this in the dropdown.
If we start a new exercise then we actually submit our exercise form and then that exercise for him.
We of course have that idea we selected.
So in the training service where we in the end have the method that gets executed in start exercise
we're getting that idea and we're trying to fetch fatuus from a whaleboat exercises that this will now
fail because a whaleboat exercise here is no longer relevant.
We can actually get rid of it because we're not directly fetching the exercises in our component.
Now to be honest it still would make sense to fetch it here in the service.
We should have our array of whaleboat exercises here so that we can still use statue to start the exercise
and get the completed exercise.
We should just initialize an update dead array with data coming from the database.
So what we might want to do is maybe rename get a whaleboat exercises to fetch available exercises and
take the logic from that new training component here and NGO in it and run this code here in our training
service.
So I'll cut it and go to the training service and executed here in fact available exercises now.
This TB is not a way bill because we haven't inject that angle of Firestorm into the service yet.
Let's do that and to inject something we need to add at injectable here.
Now injectable needs to be imported from any angle of course so make sure to add this import and once
it's added You can add a construct for your end and check the database which is just the angle of fire.
Store object which you import from a regular to fire store.
So now does this inject that.
Now this code works.
Now I want to populate my available exercises as I said.
So here I will now actually add subscribe and no longer use async pipe because I want to use this result
program medically and get my exercises which we can even explicitly declare from a type perspective
as an array of exercises because that is what we eventually get here.
Now in this erro function I can then set this a way that exercises equal to exercises.
So the exercises were getting back from Firestar And now we got it in the service.
The problem is that now we can no longer use it in our new training component though it is broken now.
And here we need these new exercises.
So how can we get them here to a good solution would be to simply emet an event whenever we receive
new exercises.
So here we could add exercises changed and set as equal to a new subject of type exercise array because
that is what we're emitting.
And we want to trigger this whenever we got new exercises.
So here right after we store them all call this exercise cesse changed.
And the next and emit and then Ray with all the available exercises I'm using a new array with the spread
operator to create a copy so that we don't pass the original array for mutability reasons.
So now we're emitting this now we can subscribe to this in new training.
So here in NJ and in it I want to do two things.
I'll reach out to the training service and call fetch available exercises like this.
This is there for always called when we go to a new training.
I also want to subscribe to this newly created subject.
So in a training service we got the exercises changed subject and I'll subscribe to it now since I subscribe
to a subject.
I also want to import subscriptions so that we can unsubscribe.
So I will import observable and subscription from our X..
J.S. your all then create my exercise subscription which is a type subscription and all store this subscription
and exercise subscription.
Now in the SUBSCRIBE method here I want to do something here I get my exercises and I simply want to
set this equal to this exercises in this component.
Now this exercise was set to an observable.
It's now set back to and well at a rate of exercise as it was earlier in this course.
We got our subscription.
We also should unsubscribe if the component is destroyed.
So let's add the on destroy interface here and also imports data from at a singular core and let's there
for all and now implement ngi on destroy and the new training component and said this exercise is subscription
or cole this exercise subscription unsubscribe whenever a disk is triggered we can buy away and also
removed the injection of the fire.
Store of the angler fires store service and remove that import.
Now we should get informed whenever he exercises change.
We store our exercises here and we initialize the fetching of exercises with this call in the new training
template.
We no longer need da sink pipe now because indice component there is no asynchronous code.
We just got an array of exercises and nothing else.
If we now save that and we lock back in
you'll still see these values after a short time.
So that is still working.