Let's work on authentication and for then I'm going to close the training section navigation section
and go to the off section obviously right now if we have a quick look in both log in and sign up we
simply call a method in the off service whenever we submit the form.
So it's the off service where we should do some work and firebase or angle or fire helps us with authentication
too.
Now I will inject something from the angle of fire package to get started that something has to be imported
first.
So import something from angular fire to slash off and that something is angular fire off like dead.
Now to make it work we need to add the all functionality to our app module though.
Thus far we only added the angular Firestar module.
We should also add the off module.
So let's duplicate this important change.
Fire store 2 off.
And then it's the angular fire of module.
This now has to be added to the imports array and the app module to unlock this functionality and ensure
that we can inject this object we're looking for.
So any of service let's now inject off.
You can get to any name you want which is a type angular fire that's important.
Now on this off object we can create a new user.
So here in register user let's no longer create a user like this let's instead reach out to.
Off and there SSD off functionality not a name and can be strange so-named this A.F. of four angular
fire off.
So this is the angle of fire of package.
And this now is the yeah kind of off functionality kind of strange that we have to it like this but
it is what it is.
And now we can call create user with email and password.
And there we should pass two arguments and well guess what email and password so we can pass off data
e-mail and all data password.
How convenient that our model has these two fields.
Now this returns us a promise where we can listen to the success case.
So result let's console larg result and where we can also handle potential errors that might occur like
maybe an e-mail address that's already taken.
So we can also for now simply console log the error or I only want to dispatch or call this off successfully.
If it does well did indeed go successfully.
So let's say if doesn't go back to our angular application and click on Sign-Up and let's try this out.
Let's take an e-mail address and some password that is at least six characters long.
And let's take a birth date and agree and submit and get an error.
They're given sign in provider is disabled for this firebase project well you actually need to turn
on authentication before it works.
So in your firebase console go to offend cation and click on set up sign in method and dare email and
password is the method we want to use which will still work email and password values on some firebase
server and you should simply turn this on and it's safe with that if you go back to your angular app
you cleared a console and hit submit again.
It now actually locks you in.
And we get this very cryptic success response which essentially means we were successful.
So this is working and we can confirm that it works by going back to authentication clicking on users
there.
And this is a user we just created through angular fire.
Now let's also implement user log in.
So if we're dead in the log in function our service we can use A.F. off and there of S. section so to
say.
And then it's signed in with email and password.
And there again we passed of data e-mail and of data password like this does again gives us a promise.
So we can have a success in their fail case and that will just copy the code from the sign up because
it's essentially the same.
And now let's try this out too.
Let's save this and go back to the angular application and on the logon screen.
Let me try.
Envelop credentials and I get an error.
Let me try the Velika ones and I get the success case.
Now I can also access training.
However one thing doesn't work.
The battery shows up but I can't go there.
Now the reason for this is that we no longer create a user object which we would store here and therefore
it is off which we use to check whether we are offended or not.
In our off guard will always return false because it doesn't find a user.
So this is actually working correctly.
We can fix this error with a little bit of refactoring that will implement in the next lecture.