Back in the firebase console Let's go back to fire story.
And they are under rules.
Let's work on security rules.
Right now everyone has access and we get a warning about this because we simply allow read and right
now I want to allow read and write it.
And we do this by adding a colon and then if if request off is not equal to null.
Now what does this strange syntax mean.
It means you should allow read and write access
the incoming request has an authenticated user deaths.
Basically the information hidden in that of property if that is not null.
So if the authentication status is not null which it would be if authentication fails then we should
get read and write access.
If I publish this I can go back to my app and log in.
And now you see
that I still can't access everything now isn't that strange because I personally would expect that an
error or because now we turned on protection on fire store so that unauthenticated users can't access
this and still it works.
Now you could of course argue yeah we did just log it right.
True but behind the scenes it actually requires us to send this token to fire store to work.
And it turns out that it automatically does this for us.
Angular fired does this for us if we use angle of fire to manage authentication too.
So just because we signed in with email and password meant that angle of fire or behind the scenes also
sports dead token which we received Madchester token.
As I mentioned when I showed you that slide and attaches it to outgoing requests so that we can work
with the database just as we did before.
But the major difference is that it's now protected that an authorized access is now not possible.
And I can prove this point with the unoffended can an access that's not allowed by temporarily disabling
our off guard so that we can access the training pages without being authentic data.
So I'd just returned TRUE in there only for a second.
And that will also go to my office service and connect this log out method to reach out to my angle
of fire of package to the off part and call sign out here.
This will get rid of the token and everything.
So let me quickly show this to you if I now save this and they go back to my app all still see all these
things and it's a bit broken so let me quickly log in here so that I am treated as locked in and hit.
Log out.
Now everything is clear.
And now we get an error or missing or insufficient permissions.
We get that because we've got an ongoing subscription.
And if I access the trading page now and we got the app therefore And I'm not offended that we also
get that error because we're not locked in.
So disproofs my point now I'll go back to the guard and reverse the code and we will have to do some
work regarding the log out to work correctly because even with the rewards code will face an issue.
If I do log in now then everything works but if I log out we still get that error and I don't want to
get that error.
So we'll work on that and we'll track all of state differently.
But the key takeaway is we got protection now and the whole behind the scenes stuff regarding our syndication
with the token and so on is managed for us.