Time to reorganize our code a bit more.
Let's take advantage of a feature provided by angle of fire.
We can listen to any changes in our authentication status.
So let's do that and to do that all add a new method call it in that of listener.
In there.
All of which are two angular fire off and there's this off state object.
This is actually an observable to which we can subscribe.
And it will emit an event when Evergrey authentication status changes.
So when we go from offene credit to unoffended hatred or the other way around.
Now in there we will receive a user object.
So ever that is NULL if we are unauthenticated or it is the currently locked in user.
So what we can do here is we can check if user which will only be true if the user is set.
So if we are affiliated in this case we can execute the code which we currently have in office successfully
so catch it from there and added here.
Else in the other case I want to execute the code I have in the log out function all the code.
Besides this sign out line here.
So here abuilding catch this code and put it into the else case.
So if we are switching to it indicated we will redirect and we will emit an event and all the set is
often equated to true.
Otherwise we'll cancel subscriptions imit and event never navigate to the log in screen and said is
authenticated to false with dad.
We can get rid of off successfully and log out.
Also Schrank we can remove D is successfully off successfully call here and just cancel log something
or do nothing at all if you want.
You can of course run any code you need.
And now we just have to make sure that it all listener is called the best time to call it of course
is when our app starts.
So lets go to our app component for this.
The cost is this the very first component that gets instantiated and lets simply implement the on in
it interface year which you need to import from angular court and which of course forces us to add DNG
on it.
Methot now in this method I wanted to call this method in my office service.
So what does I need to inject the office service of course.
So I'll provide you or not provide.
It's provided an app Marchal I'll simply inject you of the service by referring to my office service
type which you need to import here at the top.
And with it injected here in NZ on end it all reach out to all service and call my in it of Lisner method.
Now let's save this and try it out.
In theory we should now still be prevented from accessing training
this fails and we should still be able to log in and then be redirected.
Here we can still start our exercises and potentially cancel them and go to past exercises to see all
our exercises which we can still sort we can navigate around here and we can simply log out in which
case I should no longer be able to visit training that works.
So now we improved our application by making sure that we have one global offstage listener in the off
service which is initialized when our application starts and where we don't do whatever we have to do
for Medicaid or unsophisticated users.
And with that we got all the functionality in place that makes our application really amazing.