So in the last lecture we added error handling and showing a better error message.
Now I also want to show a spinner while we're waiting for the log in.
And additionally once we are locked in.
I also want to show a little spinner when we are on the new exercise page because there the available
options load very fast but are not there instantly.
So this is something I also want to ensure.
That's possible.
To achieve this we can look for a fitting component and the dare.
A progress spinner or a progress bar makes the most sense.
Now a progress bar might not be ideal here because a progress bar kind of indicates that we're submitting
large chunks of data in either direction.
So a progress spinner is what you see more often for these kinds of situations for logons or and so
on.
So therefore we want to have a spinner and now we want to have an indeterminate spinner if you want
to have an indeterminate spinner.
You could use the map progress spinner which we already used and set the mode to indeterminate or you
use the short cut mat spinner which is simply what you see here just that.
So we want to show this spinner while we're waiting for the log in.
And that means that in the log in component here we want to show it let's say instead of the button
so we could of course add this mat spinner down there.
Let me add it here and then go back to our application and log out.
Now we always see this better here.
So we have that spinner below the button.
I don't want to have a big load but I want to have it instead of the button of course.
So therefore we need to use NGF to control whether we showed a button or a spinner.
The question just is what is our condition and the condition is dead.
We did submit to form but haven't received a response yet so we have to manage that in the off service
there.
We do call our logging method and we start this log in process and we're done once we reach this or
to catch block because in the catch block we have an error but the submission still is done and we want
to start right before we execute this sign in with IIM-A and password method here.
So what I need is an additional event emitter that allows me to control the display of a splitter and
I will not control or create does eventa matter in the off service.
Instead I want to create a new shared folder and yep folder and in that shared folder all create my
you I thought Service Dot.
Yes file and you can of course named it differently.
I'm calling it like this because it controls global UI functionalities and they're all just export a
class which has the name UI service and that class will simply have my event emitter.
So there I will therefore import subject from our SJS and will then here create my loading state changed
event listener which is a new subject which wraps a boolean triplicated whether loading started or finished.
Let's say and now with that service created a one provided in the module.
So I'll go there and in the provider's array I'll admire you ice service for dad.
We also need to add an import at the top pointing to the shared folder and then you either service file
it with the service provided we can go back to the off service and now simply use that loading state.
Changed Lisner so any off service.
First of all inject DeWyze service bind it to a property named you a service maybe type is you guys
service and of course for Dad we all need to add an import import service from the shared folder and
then you Idylls service and we can now use that service in the log in the register method.
So here in logon our reach out to the ice service and I'll call the next method on the loading state
changed subject all set to true to indicate that we started loading and I'll also emit an event once
we're done here outside of two falls.
And as I said I'll also do the same and the catch block because we did fail but still we were successful
in submitting their request.
So we need to remove the splinter and show the button again and the same for registering here.
I'll also start by setting this to true.
And then and then block I want to stop everything and set the loading state to false.
With that we can now subscribe to that loading state changed listener and we want to do that in the
log in component.
So here are ULS and checked DeWyze service and bind it to a property named service for Dad's uter we
all need to add the import of course.
So when you log in component that is moving to the shared folder and importing from the user's file
injecting it in the constructor.
And with that object that we can add a new property is loading which initially is false and which we
now switch whenever we get a new loading state.
I therefore will subscribe to this loading state changed event emitter and that means I need to store
the subscription.
So I'll import subscription from our exchange Yes and it will create a new private property at the top
which will name loading Suppes which is just of type subscription.
Now an entry on an ad we can set up a subscription.
I can there bind to my loading Suppes and I do find this UI service loading state changed subscriber
which will fire whenever we trigger dis loading state changed as we do in the off service there I get
is is loading state so does Boullion which is either true or false.
And I want to set this is loading.
So this property I created a second ago to the value of its loading Sotoudeh value were emitting with
the subject.
And of course we have to unsubscribe in ngi on the stroy.
So let's implement on destroyed.
Make sure to also add an import which is coming from at angular coord and implement the energy on the
stroy method therefore so NGO and destroy they are I reach out to my loadings subscription and call
unsubscribe to prevent memory leaks.
With that we got our is loading state set and we can now use it in the template of the loading component.
And there finally we can bind the button with NGF to not is loading to only show it while we're not
loading and the spinner on the aberant should be shown whenever we are loading.
So when it is loading is true.
And with that let's see that an action for the log in screen.
Let's go back to our application.
Let's enter credentials.
And now you'll have to watch closely because fire is really fast.
But for a short duration you see the spinner.
Now let's do the same for the sign up page and I'll simply repeat the whole pattern there.
The Sign-Up component.
First of all inject you service and therefore your queue we need to add the import to the United Service.
And I plan on storing a subscription.
So I'll import subscription from our exchange Yes here too two and then I'll add two properties is loading
which is false and a private property.
My loading subscription which is of type subscription and then an entry on it all quickly assign my
loading subscription 2D subscription I get from the floating state changed subject in the ice service
where I also get is loading boolean and where a density is loading property of that component so this
one up here to the value of the emitted is loading Boullion and now of course I also implement on destroying
this method to prevent memory leaks from my loading subscription.
So for that we also have to import on the stroy from an angular core and implement DNG on destroy method
at the bottom.
Dan called this loading SEPs unsubscribe.
And with that we can go to the Templi of the sign up component and use that new as loading property.
You only show the button if youre not loading and to otherwise show the math spinner.
And here therefore we add NGF is loading.
So now for Sign-Up we should also see a spinner.
Let's also see this in action.
For data I need to log out first and go to the sign up page and I enter wrong credentials here and email
which is already used.
But I should still see the spinner and I do.
And it also disappears in the Arrow case which should show it.
So we're almost there.
One thing I want to do now.
I also want to add a spinner.
If we are logged in and waiting for the exercises to load here I don't want to show the dropdown and
the button unless there's a stun.
This is a great exercise for you.
Now it's a bit different because we don't use firebase authentication but firebase firestorm.
But the pattern should be the same.
So this is the next assignable diven.