So we implemented downloading functionality and we're controlling it entirely through our YOU eyes service.
Now we have another UI element that we implement that just a few minutes ago if we have a look at the
log in screen.
What about this snack bar which we're handling in the off service there were displaying this snack bar
a sodas message at the bottom.
Whenever we get an error.
No actually this is a UI element that we might also need from other places in the app.
So a good improvement of the app is to actually add a method to all you Ice Service which we may call
a show snack bar with a message and an action and a duration.
And where we now use that snack bar instead.
So now I'll add injectable to debt service which is imported from Anglo COOREY so that we can inject
dad Matt snack bar service which will inject by adding a snack bar in the constructor which is of type.
Matt.
Snack Bar which needs to be imported from ET angular material.
And now we can simply call this snack bar open and pass the message to the action.
And also my conflict here as an argument is not my conflict but an object where I set the duration to
the duration argument I'm getting here as the first argument of this method.
Now we have that reuseable show snack bar method which we can use from inside the off service.
There we already are injecting to you Ice Service so we can simply go to all instances where we use
this snack bar open which are these two in register and log in and there instead of calling this snack
bar open.
I will now call this you I service show snack bar where my message just the error message where the
action is still null and to durations 3000 like dead.
And then I can remove this snack bar open from the You Ice Service you're actually from the officer
of this year from the registry user Meffert and for log in it's just the same method.
A service show snack bar with the error message null as an action and three seconds.
And now I can remove the injection of Matt's snack bar from this service.
So this is now a tiny improvement which ensures staed in our application.
If I do log out I still get my error or a snack bar at the bottom if it fails.
But now we're controlling this in a central place too which makes it more reusable and spares the hassle
off injecting mat snack bar into all the places where we want to use it.
This also allows us to improve the error handling of other parts of the application.