This far in the module we applied multiple optical improvements.
Now we can work on the technical side and the technical side.
I mainly mean splitting up the app module.
It's OK we could leave it like this.
We don't have a super big app but we already have a lot of imports and declarations in the app module.
So it would make sense to split our application up into feature modules and maybe also add a core module.
Now let's see what makes sense.
We can certainly add feature modules we can add a feature module for a training feature and one for
you off feature.
So these two modules certainly make sense and they allow us to move the components which belong to a
certain feature into that module and therefore clean up the app module.
So let's start with that.
Let's start with a feature module 40 of part next to the off servers and off guard.
I'll add a ofter module that yes file I'll simply export a class here of module.
And this has turned into a module by adding the Ngee module decorator.
Now the Ngee module decorator needs to be imported and it is imported from at angular core.
So make sure to add this import at the top of your file import module from at angular core.
With that added We should add some while configurations are an object we passed to Engy module to Engy
module.
And here we have to add some declarations.
So the components we use in this module we might need to add some imports and we might need to add some
exports.
Now let's see what we need.
We don't add providers here because we actually should always provide your services in the app module
if you plan on using them.
Application wide or in general if you plan on using them as a singleton.
Once you can learn more about this in my complete guide course where I dive into modules in way greater
depth as I dive into all angular topics in way greater depth there.
So which declarations should we add to the of module now.
We have a look at the map module.
We certainly have to sign up component and the log in component that does not belong to the entire app
but to the of module to the feature.
So catch them from the declarations in the app module and I'll remove the imports.
And instead I go to the off module and add them two declarations here.
This means we all have to add the imports here.
So at the import to sign up component from the Sign-Up folder the sign up component file there and the
same for the log in component which is fetched from the log in folder and there from the log in component
file.
So that are my declarations which are relevant to the off module.
Now what about imports and exports.
Well in the app module we clearly have our angular material module which we import.
This one we also got routing and flex layout and the forms module and so on.
Now the important thing to keep in mind is that just because you import something into the airport all
this does not make it available in over modules even if these modules are kind of child modules to at
Marchal because you could think that since we created this off module that you simply imported so import
of modules from.
And now let's go to the off section and there import that of Marchal file and then you add all module
to the imports array of your app module like this.
If you do this it compiles successfully but your app will now actually break with a bunch of error messages.
We have a look at these error messages.
We essentially get messages like Engy form is unknown but also a couple of material components are unknown.
The reason for this is what I just said.
The things you import into your app Marchal are not passed down to the off module they're not exchanged
between modules.
Each module works standalone.
So what ever you need in the off module has to be added as an import there.
Most importantly that's for example the and module a module that gives us access to NGF and so on.
You imported from an angle or common now in the off module we have to sign up into loggin component
and into log in component.
We use the reactive form approach in the Sign-Up of component.
We use the template driven forms approach.
Now this means we also will need to add forms module and reactive forms module to our imports both it's
imported from at Angola forums and we also use material components from angular material.
That is why we also need to add the material module here.
So make sure to add this in order at the top and additionally entry and the import cere here to now
we go back.
This looks better but the styling is off.
The reason for this is that we also should import our flex lay out module this flex layout module here
because we use this flex layout positioning here and we don't get an error.
But still the directives will now not be recognized.
So let's add the flex lay out module which you import from angular flex layout out if you do that.
Now this looks much better if you have a look at the sign up and log and component.
Now if you're worried about increasing your Bunuel size by importing some modules both here in the off
module anti-particle this is not the case.
Angular manages this cleverly behind the scenes.
So the key takeaway is if you use something in a module you need to import there the things are not
exchanged between modules.
Now these adjustments also mean that we can get rid of the reactive forms module and the forms module
from the app module because we only use Fordham's here in our off module and also in part of the training
module once we created that.
But this will all become a future module.
So there's nothing Giddyap component where we would need this.
Speaking off that in the next lecture we'll create our training module and also restructure our app
for Daten.
So let's move on to this.