With lazy loading it I want to go to my training routing module.
So delays in loaded routing module and remove the off guard from here because if we use it here we have
one disadvantage if we use can actually wait here.
We check whether we are allowed to enter this component is training component after we lazy loaded the
whole module.
Now we can simply save that and don't download the module.
If we don't have access anyways so this is why checking it here is too late to have an optimal app at
least.
So I will remove the off guard.
Importante can activate key here on detraining routing module and go to the app routing module.
And here on this route on this lazy load route there is a special property can load which we can add.
It works like can activate but it runs before the bundle is loaded.
So here I am off guard and for this to work I need to go to my off guard file now here and actually
implement the can load interface.
It's imported from ET angular routers so let me add.
Can load here.
Now I have to add can load here and can load looks almost like connected way so I can copy that entire
code.
The differences.
It doesn't have that second argument just the first one.
We save this we get an error because the first one all has a different type it's of type route which
we should import from the router.
So just the route like this.
Now with that it successfully compiles and now we have the same checks.
We have the same check and both methods we're not using can activate anymore or we could remove that.
But I'll leave it here for completeness sake.
But now we have can load and we added this in the tray excuse me in the app routing module.
So now we're checking this if we're allowed to access this route you're still before we exit before
we entered.
But also before we load the bundle.
So if I log out I still can't access slash training as I can prove to you if I try to do that manually
I'm still redirector to log in and it still works on the other way around.
If I do log in but behind the scenes it will now only lazy load the package the training package.
If we actually are allowed to enter this.