Now to get started with NTR X I need to install a package and that package is called Engy are x slash
store.
I do install it by running NPM install dash dash save at Engy our X store.
Now this will give us all the functionality we need to implement is angular specific read X pattern
in our angler app we simply hit enter.
And those will now be downloaded added to the package Dodge's and file.
And of course added to our project went to the stern.
I can restart my development sir with Engy serve and continue working on this project.
Now as I mentioned on the slides when we are using NCR X we're talking about these reducers which will
in the end manipulate the store.
We have to store itself of course we have actions that we have these effects.
Now let's get there step by step.
Let's start simple by adding a story for this in my main folder next to my app module.
I'll add my app Daut reducer dot TS file.
Now the naming namings up to you.
I'll name it like this because it will house keep my main producer which will manipulate my main story
thereafter.
Now how does this maned reducer look like a producer is just a function.
It's a function which I'll export an old name it app reducer.
Now this function simply takes the old state as an input as well as the incoming action because remember
on the slide I said you dispatch actions to change the store.
You don't do it directly.
So the actual resistance reducer and is passed into it.
It this brings you through.
We do one simple thing.
We return a new state.
So the simplest possible reducer just returns the old state.
It doesn't therefore do too many useful things.
But this is one thing we can do.
Now typically you want to start with some state with an initial state.
So I will create a starting state and store it in a constant named initial state.
And this let's say is a javascript object where we want to manage is its loading state to start simple.
So this is currently managed new Ice Service with the loading state changed listener.
Let's now add a reducer and add is loading as a property which of course is a boolean.
And with let's say it's false initially what's its object so let's use a colon.
We can also gift is initial state or state for our application in general and interface.
So I will create a new interface here which all name state which I simply define as an object where
we have it's loading which is a boolean.
So this is not just a type definition you're not an object and just the type definition an initial state
will be of type state.
And here in AB reducer I'll get all giftie incoming state a default value of initial state so that we
start with the initial state in case this reducers execute the first time when we have no state yet.
So now we return the initial state in all cases.
Now we want to be able to change that state to change from is loading falls to is loading true.
So we will probably get an action that does trigger this change.
Therefore you typically use a switch case statement.
You switched the action type.
Know this is important actions which are dispatched must have a type property.
This is why we can safely assume that we'll get one.
I'll show you how to dispatch actions in a second.
So now we got our action type which I switch here and the first case is maybe dead.
We have to type start loading.
This is just a string all uppercase so that it's literally whistle and kind of looks like a constant.
Clearly to find value if this is the case I will return a new state a new object where is loading is
actually true.
And that's this immutable thing I was mentioning.
I'm not returning the old state where I switched is loading to true.
I'm returning a new state and my state only is object with one property which is why I return one object
with one property.
Here is loading set to true now.
Also handle the case that were stopping the loading.
In this case I want to return is loading false and I'll also add a default case in case some other action
hits this reducer here I will just return state without any changes.
So now this is our first producer handling some actions which we have never dispatched thus far but
will do so soon and changing our state.
Now with this simple set up we of course have to make angler aware of this reducer and tell it to create
a store that is actually manipulatable by debt reducer.
To do that I'll go to the app module and indie app module.
I now will set up my store module so in imports there I add store module which I need to import from
at Engy our X store.
So you're at the top I'll add import to store module from at ngi our X store.
The store module has a function for root where I have to pass my app reducer my main reducer.
So for that I'll import dat from my files so here I'll import from the app reduce or file and what import
is of course my app reducer function and this function is what I pass to for root.
To be precise I don't pass like this but I pass an object where I can map multiple Ribby reducers against
keys by which I can then access the state slices.
They manage like the producer right now is responsible for the entire state of course but you could
argue it's responsible for you.
I relate related state like it's loading.
So that is why.
Yep Marchal we could name this UI and assign app reducer function here.
Now we will refactored just later to have multiple reducers but does a good start.
So now we have that store initialized and we're using for root here to register our producer which can
now edit this story.
Now we need to do two things we need to be able to dispatch actions and we need to be able to listen
to changes so that in the end we all of course have kind of an event emitter pattern though with the
more clearly defined series of steps.
Let's start with the dispatching part where do we want to dispatch our loading action.
Well that is for example happening in the off service.
So when you offer service you want to get access to our store and therefore we need to inject it all
name it's stored and it will be of type story store needs to be imported from at Engy or ex store.
So this import here this one has to be at an import store from at NCR X story.
Now we can inject the store and the store actually is a generic type where we can define how it will
look like if we have a look at our app module.
The structure is in the end a store that consists of multiple slices.
Right now only one day you slice which in turn holds the state returned by the producer which follows
this interface this definition.
So that means that any off service we can define our type here as an object where we will have to state
from our app reducer so does state object here.
So I will simply export this interface and the producer and end of service I can now import everything
as from app.
And this is just a special Sunday export import export that things from a file and store it in a variable
under which I can then exit and conventioneers to name reducer related imports with a low lowercase
character at the start.
So from app which is coming from in the end just my average user file.
Now here I could import to reduce a function or dead state object.
So our store is of structure you will I.
And then from app state.
So this is the store we inject into the office service looks a bit complex but in the end it just gives
us access to the global store.
Now I want to dispatch an action whenever we start loading right.
Does What's the idea.
We can do this by going to any place where we set deal where we called you Ice Service thus far.
And there will not use to you service anymore but instead use the injected story.
And there we have a dispatch method we can call and there we do dispatch an action.
Now the action is always an object which remember what I said always has to have a type property.
So your type could be let's see which types we support in our producer start loading and stop loading.
So we want to start loading so let's grab this string here grab the entire string start loading is to
type.
I'm dispatching here.
Like that.
Now of course I also want to dispatch an action once we're done.
So here where I previously used mine is subject I will now call stop loading and I'll do the same of
course down here when I catch an error.
Now for the log in case I'll also dispatch.
Start loading enter ofter in the then block stop loading and in the catch block stopped loading.
So this is of course really similar to the approach we used before but now using that central store
so with that we're dispatching the action.
Now we also need to subscribe.
And we will subscribe in our components in the log In the sign up component.
So in there in the log in component let's create a subscription.
Therefore I need to check the store.
So in the log in component also bind to store property here and inject the store which is imported from
at Engy our X store like this.
This line needs to be added.
So with that I inject the store here and it's all the generic type here.
So let me also quickly import what I just imported in my off service so I'll import everything as from
app from.
And now let's go up to the app reducer here.
This file and then I can also define a type here to be an object where we have a UI slice which isn't
the end of type from App State.
So now we inject the store into the log in component.
And now we can easily use it by going to Engy on it and then accessing store and subscribing to it.
And there we get some data out which for now simply want to log.
So they can have a look at it.
Now let's see if our application still works in the server in the page which I can reload which is run
by the def server.
We get this value here which is an object which has this UI property which N.K. which in turns to stores
is loading.
That's looking good.
So isn't status the case we can simply do one thing now we can change the existing loading property
to be an observable for dad.
I need to import observable from our x J s so let's add the observable import observable as a generic
type and it will eventually hold a boolean here.
For that to be the case I will actually assign it here an engine in it.
And said this is loading.
And by the way it's a convention to use dollar signs at the end of the variable names which are controlled
by NTR x.
So this is loading.
Is that equal to this sport.
And now not subscribe because I don't want to subscribe here.
I want to do that from within the Templi with the async pipe but instead I'll add map here.
This map OPERATOR I need to import import this so import map from our exchange as Slash operators.
This allows me to transform the value because here I end the end get my state if you want and that is
an object with a UI property.
I'm only interested in the loading properties of that though.
So I want to return state.
You I is loading the value of that will be a boolean which in the end will be extracted.
So no comment out the loading subscription.
And I can therefore comment out Engy on the stroy.
We don't need to unsubscribe from NDR extort related things that just automatically I can remove the
on the stroy implementation import therefore.
And now we can use D is loading observable.
That it now is in the template.
And here at the azing pipe and of course changed the name to Etty dollar sign because I changed the
variable name the property name.
And now with that we see it works as before but now it's taking this local store into account and using
that observable based approach.