Who are still there time to continue with then John X the general pattern won't change anymore though
you learned about the store reducer actions selectors.
How we get values and how we dispatch values and that really is the main part.
Now I'll show you how to create more reducers for the different feature modules we have.
We already created one for the UI state.
Now I will just repeat this pattern for off and training.
Let's start with off.
So in the off area we get this off service next to it.
I'll add my off reducer.
TS file just as I created my producer and I will also create my of actions.
TS fall because you will have some actions like user is authenticated user id log out.
So with that we now can start working on this off reducer and we can actually have a look at UI producer
and copy the content from there into the off reducer to use this as a blueprint.
Of course we should import different actions.
We should import our off actions and we got on.
So this is an empty import right now.
The state will look differently if we have a look at the off service what is our authentication status.
In the end we just want to know are we authenticated or not.
That is the only thing we really care about.
The other parts like tokens and so on.
Thats managed by Angel or fire behind the scenes.
So we really only care about this.
So we got is authenticated as a state which also happens to be a bully and again but of course dont
be deceived.
This can be a string this can be a number.
This could be an object or an array.
You are not limited to booleans and we will see this once we create detraining state.
So this is the stage for all indication though and the initial state is to have its authenticated set
to False.
We then have our producer and our named is off reducer and we also get the initial state here.
The actions Well that is something we'll need to create an action file as we do have to do that for
our cases.
So let's do this let's move to the off actions.
There again we can have a look at the UI actions and copy to set up from there and move it over to the
off actions in there.
We got the action imported from NPR X store and then we can have a couple of different actions.
I guess one actually would make sense would be set authenticated and one that we could call set an authenticated
and authenticated.
This is all coming from the off reducers all renamed is to off.
And here I got set up.
They indicated and here I got said and indicated as I mentioned the exact values here don't really matter
said on of anti-cat it.
I guess it's a hardboard Somehow I don't get it.
So now we can create a clause which is named set or vindicated.
God I do have to type that.
That'll do.
And your type is set off indicated.
The second clause is set up set unauthenticated using Pascal OK's.
And here we use set unauthenticated as our type.
And now we export both are merged into a custom type which all name off actions.
Here we have every asset authenticated or we have set an authenticated.
This is now the off actions file and the off or we can now import from there.
We have our off actions and we get specifically set authenticated and set.
I don't indicate it's set.
I don't indicate it's that constant.
So do you actually get in the off reducer is a type of actions.
It's either starting starting or stopping it's resetting or unsetting.
So to say the user authentication and the first case is set off then decay that like this and here on
a Saturday is authenticated property to True.
The second case is set on authenticated.
And here I want to set is authenticated to false and devolved States always the state we got before.
Now I'll try to help method get is off.
Whereas simply state is offene catered for the same reason we did this new UI reducer to have easier
access to that.
So now we get our off reduce and of actions.
No we need to add it to our app reducers just as we did it for the UI reducer.
So any app reducer I'm going to import everything ass from off from the auth folder and there of course
our off reducer file.
And now we add both the state and the reducer itself.
So any state interface I'm going to edit off Sly's so that we can access all related state pieces which
points to from off state.
Excuse me.
This should be from all one word and in from off we should have a state.
So in the off reducers there should be a state export interface state.
I guess we have one yet I just need to add a semi-colon and indeed reducers map it no longer fits our
state because there is the off state missing.
So I will add the off key here which is coming from off and they're off reducer.
So now that's added here too.
Now we can also add more selectors.
The first one is d get off state selector which gives us direct access to the off slice.
And always keep in mind this is optional.
You could drill down manually by accessing the properties but it's easier if you do it like this.
So here it create a feature selector where access from off and state.
That's the type.
And that is what I will get when I access my of slice.
So this property here in my reducer map and in my state therefore And now we'll add a number select
or just as we did 40 you ii get is off we'll use the Create selector feature because now I don't want
to get access to the entire state slice but to a specific property in that slice and for that we use
create selector and here well first of all pass a reference to get off state.
So the feature select will be created a second ago and the second argument will then be coming from
the off reduce or file does get is off help or Mefford we defined in there and that is exactly the same
logic we used for the UI reducer.
So with that we got this all added to the app reducer.
Now we dont need to touch the app module.
Everything is fine there.
Now we can go to the places where we want to use Dadge reducer.
So that would be in the off related files of course were dispatching an action whenever we get back
to result from Register user.
So here we dispatch stop loading.
Now all that want to dispatch of course my action regarding the successful log in to be precise we don't
really need to do this here though.
Remember we got our off state listener.
This is where we also do the routing.
Actually it's here where we should now do that and where we should now trigger our action.
So first of all I'll import everything as of from my off actions file and with that I can dispatch actions
on my store.
Now the store still uses the global state of the app which now includes the off parts it is fine.
And now if they are I won't said this is authenticated and it won't trigger my off change here.
Instead I will call this store dispatch knew of set authenticated as to class name which I instantiate
and on the other and down there where we redirect to log in I will also not use my subject anymore but
instead dispatch set unauthenticated this class and it will not manage to get it property in this file
anymore.
I don't need the off change subject anymore which means I can remove the subject import up here.
This is all stuff I can get rid of in my is all helper method.
I will remove that because we've now managed this in ngi are x.
And with that we improved dieoff service and we're using NCR X to manage the state of our indication.
Now that's of course only worth something if we also take the values from there.
Right now we only dispatch but that broke our application because the parts of the app where we checked
for the user are being offended will now not work anymore.
For example our navigation there in the head header component we actually subscribe to off changes and
we did the same and decide neth we all were interested in that in our off guard of course.
All these things are now broken.
So let's fix this in the next lecture.