So how do material themes work material themes have 5 colors that you need to define which will then
be automatically assigned to certain parts of certain components.
So every component that's part of the angular material framework knows how to style itself or for some
components like a button you can overwrite it with the color property.
But all of that refers back to the underlying theme which defines the base styles.
So if you want to create such a theme you in the end need to do one simple thing you need to define
five colors.
Now these colors are so-called palettes and we started with a primary palette.
That's the most widely used color across all screens.
So do you based the main color on your app.
It's accompanied by an accent palette that's used to highlight content for interactive elements for
these floating buttons.
Things like that.
You also typically have a warrant palette so that is a color which is used to show warnings to really
draw attention.
And then you go to our palettes for text and general content.
One is the foreground palette which is used for text and icons.
And once the background palette which is for example used by default for the toolbar so a light background
color with that I don't mean white which is the background color of your page anyways but I mean if
an element has a subtle background this will be used.
So we need to find these five colors.
The question of course is where do we find it and how.
Let's take a closer look.