On material that Engler did I O you can click on Guy it's and then on theming angular material and there
you find a description of what a theme is and a link to the material design spec which shows you all
the colors you can choose from.
That's good for us.
We'll use that in a second.
And it also mentions how to build a theme here under defining a custom theme.
It's actually pretty simple.
So this is what I'll walk through together with you.
So let's start to start I'll close my app folder and I'll create a theme file or simply create here
next to styles of C S S I'll call it my field dot.
And now that's important SPSS because we're going to use sassier.
SAS is a superset of normal C S S and allows us to use special features.
It will be compiled down to normal C S S by DCL automatically and we use SAS for the theme creation
because we work with some variables so that the like them can generate a file that will define the different
styles for the different components automatically based on some input variables.
So in my field that is as sitting next to put files and maynt.
Yes.
And you can name this followed every want this file now needs to import something which we can see here
in our documentation.
It needs to import does it.
Angular material faming package you could say let's throw that into this.
S.c.s as follows.
Now with that package m ordered the next step is to include mat core.
Now this is a mix in and includes includes it into this file which simply makes a lot of content available
to us.
For example some variables.
SAS knows the variables which to find the angular material colorists.
And a lot of Ahmer functionalities that are needed to successfully create a styling file in the end.
Now the next step is to define our colors and themes.
So I'll copy that over into our file and explain it.
Here we define a bunch of variables we create variables with the dollar sign at the beginning.
We define variables for the primary excellent word colors and these variable names are totally up to
you.
The map Pelet function here is again provided by the theming package and it's essentially create such
a color palette.
These variables we use here are also defined by the package and they refer to the official color guide
here.
So here we got deep purple indigo blue pink.
These are just a nice names you see here.
So Indigo pink red always prefixed with a dollar sign Matt.
So you have to choose some of the colors you see here and you can add up to three shades for the default
lighter and the darker worsen which makes a lot of sense for the exent color since that's mostly used
on buttons and so on because these alternative shapes will be picked by angular material for example
for Hobert effects and so on.
If you don't define them all the effects will just take the default color.
So with that set up we got our free color set up the war palette is optional as you see here.
The devil would be red.
And with that added We now define our own light theme here.
Now that is done with the mad light theme or the matte dark theme function.
The function will simply style the elements differently.
The darkfield gives everything a darker background and zone light theme as well.
A light background.
So it is something you can do to choose a darker or lighter mode for your app.
You pass your free colors or at least to up to free to dysfunction.
And with that the only thing that's missing is that we actually call include So use include to run and
never built in mixin which is called angular Dasch material theme.
Now to this function you'll simply pastie theme you created and you stored in this variable.
So I'll pass this here and this will now not only create the theme but also load it this also means
that we should go to the Stout's see us as file and come and just feed them out because we don't need
two feed fighting with each other.
That of course also means that we need to ensure that this custom my Feme file gets loaded and for that
we go to the angular seal either Jason fall and besides loading the stuffs that CSSA fall which we now
also could remove.
I guess now we get some recode in there that will keep it.
But besides that will now also point to the my theme that s.c.s as fall and the seal eyes upwards.
S.c.s essence sace compilation out of the box.
With that we can quit DNG serve process and we have to do that so that the changes are picked up and
we rerun energies Earth and this will now build the project again and we'll build our s.c.s as fall.
Now for subsequent changes you don't have to restart.
I just did have to do that because I changed the Selye configuration to tape this fall into account
now once the compilation is finished we can go back to our application
and we don't see a real difference.
The reason for this is that the theme we find just uses the colors we use before.
So let's switch everything up.
Let's use a primary color of red and simply safe debt.
And now when the EP reloads you see we got a rat primary color everywhere.
And this is how simple it is to update and change and manipulate themes.
Now if you want to learn more about themes dive into the official guide I was showing you off from the
official docs but this is how you can work with teams and how you can make sure that your app looks
exactly the way you want it to look.