In order to see just where sprint planning fits into the overall Agile project,
let's start by walking through the Agile project lifecycle.
So we will examine the Agile project lifecycle in detail,
and as you will see, the Agile process groups are not phases,
but rather,
they are an integrated set of processes applied
iteratively throughout the project.
An Agile project is composed of the following: It begins with planning,
vision, and a roadmap,
followed by one or more releases and ending with the project retrospective.
So this is the entire Agile project from end to end.
Now let's look at the results of the planning activity.
Before we begin an Agile project, we need to do a few things.
When your project has a clear and compelling vision and roadmap,
prioritizing stories is easy, or at least easier,
for the entire project.
A clear vision and roadmap helps justify which stories to keep,
leave out, or better prioritize.
Also,
a clear vision provides a common grasp and understanding
of what's important to the project,
enabling a higher team morale and increases stakeholder trust.
This all matters as we drill down into release in sprint planning. Okay, onto the next process group, the release.