Sprint timeboxing is simply the length of elapsed time
of a single sprint or iteration.
In my observations over the years,
a typical sprint timebox is about two or three weeks.
Sprints can be potentially boxed in two ways.
Let's check those out now.
There are two basic types of release or sprint plans,
scope-boxed or timeboxed,
and these could apply to release plans and sprint plans alike.
A scope-boxed plan defines and determines the
features the team will build in advance,
but the date is uncertain.
With a timeboxed plan,
the specific features that the plan will include are uncertain,
but defines and determines the date in advance.
This is by far the most popular approach used.
Timeboxed plans, to me, are almost always better.
Now let's look at the benefits of timeboxed plans.
Scope management.
You can manage the amount of work, that is scope, that you can do.
Prioritization decisions.
You will need to influence people to make the challenging,
but important prioritization decisions.
This is important.
Customers or users typically want everything and yet do not
consider changing the budget or due dates.
Lower-cost stories.
This requires a team to identify the most cost-effective
stories and high-value stories as well,
which are most useful or valuable alternatives that will fit into the timebox.
Without a timebox, trust me,
your plan will include more low-value features that may
be forced in by your product owner.
Now that we understand estimation's value to sprint planning,
and what velocity is,
and how timeboxing can better manage scope and deliver value better,
we can dive into the details of release and sprint planning in the next section.
But first, a point of view.
Here's my point of view on estimation, velocity, and timeboxing.
Most people are not comfortable making estimates.
Since the process of making estimates is imprecise at best,
and as engineers we appreciate and live by our preciseness,
give them the support and trust they need to build and
improve their estimation skills.
Good estimation is a key component of agile planning.
Tracking your velocity is important so you can better predict the amount
of work you can accomplish over time in your sprints.
And always use timeboxing and not scope- boxing since
timeboxing drives higher value, lower cost stories.
Else, it is simply a dog pile on requirements.
You want to guide and manage your product owner into making
the best business decisions possible. Now let's move on to release planning.