Sprint Planning: Part 1.
Let's get after it.
First, a quick context check.
Remember,
a sprint begins with sprint planning and contains a series of daily work events,
followed by the sprint demo, review, and retrospective.
At a high level, here's the agile sprint planning flow.
In order to do sprint planning, you need the product owner,
Scrum Master of doing pre-scrum, the dev lead,
and the dev team.
But we'll feed into sprint planning maybe a couple of things.
Here I am showing that this sprint plan is for a sprint
within release 3 and its associated backlog.
If you are not using the release planning model,
you would have the remaining backlog as input into the sprint planning.
Next, the outcomes of the sprint planning are first,
the sprint plan,
which is focused on the next sprint within this release and also what backlog
candidates will be in the subsequent sprints in this release.
Next, refined user stories.
We may need further discussion on a user story to better understand it.
Next, refined estimates and priorities.
Based on those refined user stories and discussions,
we can improve the estimate and reset the priority we want to assign to it.
Lastly, sprint backlogs.
In this example,
we have three sprints and have determined which user
stories are assigned to which sprint.
Again,
this may change based on the outcomes of the sprint
demo review and retrospective.
So, in this example,
I am showing three planned sprints in this release and
the associated backlog for each.
Please note, for the next sprint planning,
let's say in two weeks,
we will only have sprint 2 and sprint 3 since sprint
1 of this release is complete.
Since we are using timeboxing in this example,
the schedule is set, and the scope is fluid.
Each sprint for this example is two weeks.
Typically, at this detail, resources or budget is straightforward.
If my team consists of five, including devs,
QAs, etc., then it would be easy to determine their labor costs. Okay, let's dive a little deeper into sprint planning step by step.