Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module,
Summarizing Key Learning Objectives through the course,
Developing Effective Agile Sprint Plans.
Let's review the three key modules of this course.
First, we will review key Agile, Scrum, and sprint terms,
definitions, roles, artifacts, and processes.
Next,
we will review all of the essential key points of planning sprints effectively.
Finally,
we will review how we handle the myriad of issues that
may affect and impede your plan, such as bugs,
staffing, spikes,
and incomplete work and what options you can apply to mitigate them.
Now let's review the module, Understanding the Agile Workflow.
Team participants in the Agile and Scrum world are the product owner,
the development team, and the Scrum Master or team leader.
The product owner may represent a line of business,
a steering committee, department,
or other segments of the user or customer communities.
The product owner needs to express the items clearly so that they are
understandable by the development team and prioritize them so the
development team knows what to work on next.
Dev teams are cross-functional, but working concurrently.
I want to emphasize this since in the traditional project model,
typically code is developed, then tested,
and then moved into preproduction environments as
separate teams and/or processes.
This team, the development team,
is working together concurrently throughout the development process.
In the Scrum world,
the Scrum Master is facilitating the adherence to the Scrum process,
and the team is self directed, that is without a team leader.
But what I have seen so often in the absence of a Scrum Master is a
team leader or tech leader that still provides the Agile/Scrum
process guidance along with team leadership.
Agile project planning outcomes are a clear vision and roadmap that
helps justify and guide which user stories are to keep,
leave out, or better prioritize.
That clear vision provides a common grasp and
understanding of what's important to the project,
enabling a higher team morale and increases stakeholder trust.
An Agile release is composed of the following: It begins with release planning,
followed by one or more iterations or sprints,
and ending with a release retrospective.
So this is the entire Agile release from end to end.
Iterations or sprints.
Remember, those are interchangeable terms,
and it's composed of the following pieces: An iteration
or sprint begins with sprint planning,
followed by one or more daily work activities,
and ending with a sprint retrospective, review,
and demo.
So this is the entire sprint, again, from end to end.
Daily work is composed of the following: It begins with a daily standup,
which includes daily work progress updates and actions.
Then it's followed by one or more daily work tasks and activities.
That's where the work is really getting done.
The development team is developing new and interesting software.
So this is daily work from end to end.
Remember, if you need an extra standup when things get tight or critical,
just have one.
Backlogs are the fuel driving Agile projects forward.
They are so important.
I want to impress on you that you need to ensure you
have a healthy backlog process,
which means having quality backlog items and a
quality backlog management process.
So hopefully this course has provided you with what you
need to know in order to do that.
User stories are a high-level definition of a requirement or feature.
User stories contain just enough information so that the developers can
produce a reasonable estimate of the effort to implement it.
User stories collectively will add up to be your backlog.
Sure,
there may be other things in your backlog that are
not characterized as a user story, but they'll mostly be stories.
Now we talked about adopting a user story template in order to write
consistently constructed stories and to also follow the INVEST model.
I make strong recommendations about that.
Use a template when writing user stories,
and use INVEST as a checklist to ensure that the user stories
have the fidelity and quality they need.
Last, SMART-based tasks.
There's a great technique for creating developer tasks,
and they map into the word SMART.
They are specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, and timeboxed.
So after you write your tasks,
use the SMART keywords as a checklist to ensure the highest
quality of your task descriptions as well.
So both INVEST and SMART are great little checklists to make sure the
work you're doing meets a certain quality level.
In the Planning Sprints Effectively module,
we did a deep dive into several very key topics.
The first, timeboxing.
Now timeboxing is a set length of time that's applied for all agile events,
such as the sprint itself, of course,
but also the daily standup and the sprint planning to name the most obvious.
Release planning.
Most people forget all about it and go right to sprint planning.
Release planning is a series of sprints that are contained within a release,
and a series of releases are contained within a project.
To develop a release plan, we take as input the product vision,
the product roadmap, and the product backlog,
and the output are releases, each with features or stories identified.
These would be our release goals and possibly target dates and budgets as well.
Don't forget about release planning.
Most people just jump right to sprints, and it's just a series of sprints.
Release planning gives you a great bird's- eye view,
and remember, executives like to see that high-level planning activity.
Next, sprint planning.
Now, within sprint planning, a key element is estimation,
and we learned that solid estimating skills are
critical to the Agile team's productivity,
reliability, and most importantly,
predictability of the sprint planning outcomes.
Velocity is the amount of work a team can produce in a single sprint.
Knowing your velocity helps you better predict the amount of
work you can commit to in your sprint planning.
Now, in your spring planning sessions, we will define the backlog,
estimate sprints, prioritize the backlog,
and use our known velocity to make sprint commitments.
Again, velocity,
very key and a great representation of what you've done in the past,
as well as what you could do in the future.
Daily scrums and work.
Daily scrums are an essential element of the dev team's daily activity.
Sharing what you have done since the last standup scrum,
what you plan to do today, and discuss any roadblocks or issues.
That's a biggie as well.
A lot of gold or great ideas come out of discussing roadblocks and issues.
Based on the complexity of the issues,
certainly follow-on meetings can be conducted of a
subset of the team to go resolve.
Now, daily work is when the dev team is excelling and producing results,
writing code, testing, and producing usable software.
That's where the rubber meets the road, of course.
And a really exciting part, of course,
of the whole spring process are the sprint demonstrations.
Now is the chance for the team to shine and show the
product owner the results of the sprint.
Here you are demonstrating your workable features to the product owner,
and, of course,
potential other user representatives that might be
part of the demonstration itself.
Reviews and retrospective.
Don't forget to do your reviews.
The sprint review is focused on improving the process that created the product,
and it's just the development team that usually
attends and not the product owner.
And a review may be 15 minutes or 20.
It doesn't take a lot of time,
but whatever you learn and can change will affect each and
every sprint and add to its success, productivity,
and higher quality.
Now, retrospectives are really just a team self-audit,
and you would discuss things like what went well?
What didn't?
Should we try new things in the next sprint?
Should we stop doing things that weren't working?
And things like that.
All these things, the retrospective and the reviews I just mentioned,
help bring the team closer together and bond better.
+ As we know, not everything will go perfectly right,
and we need to be prepared with options.
Now we had first discussed how to avoid problems early to better
ensure your sprints run smoothly and are able to complete the
user stories that you committed to.
So one of those ways is to nurture and support your product owner.
Do not neglect your product owner.
They may need some tender loving care.
They have a critical role in managing and prioritizing the backlog.
Help them in any way you can.
If they are successful, you will be successful.
So spend the extra time and effort, get to know them,
get to understand them, and even help them write the backlog.
Now you can use slack for technical debt.
Again, slack is time set aside for unanticipated activities.
Basically, you are setting aside time in reserve.
It is likely best used to reduce your technical debt,
but it could be used for, say, user stories take longer to develop.
Testing takes longer than you thought.
Always allow a little slack in there.
Your velocity will help you manage that just right.
Use spikes for control tests or experiments to provide information
and hopefully to clarify any technical issues by setting aside the
complexities of the production code.
Spikes are very small,
isolated experiments when you need to prove an approach to seek
additional information or prove some technical worthiness.
If you see several spikes coming up,
then set aside some additional slack to do those.
Now there may be many obstacles to your team's philosophy such as sick time,
vacation, people issues, and turnover.
Try to minimize these as best as you can.
It is proven though that teams that work consistently together
over time have more reliable velocities.
Dealing with problems.
You will have problems and issues.
This is simply part of the app dev world,
and you might try solving a problem by using your slack time,
maybe cancelling a spike,
and using that time or working a few more hours than normal.
As a last resort, you may need to reduce scope,
that is remove a user story in order to accomplish what you need to do within
the sprint timebox and then be able to deliver working,
functional software.
Okay, sometimes there's a thing called a lost sprint.
Now that should be very rare, but if this happens,
your biggest challenge will be informing the product owner and why
this is the best course of action and also shoring up any team morale
issues in your review and retrospective.
Again, lost sprints are rare.
Try the approach of reducing scope,
maybe reducing a lot of scope so you can at least deliver some working software.
Okay, lastly, partially done work.
Don't let the partial code become technical debt.
That will only cause more trouble downstream.
So consider removing partially completed stories from the code base
unless they will be part of the very next sprint.
So partially done work means you had to maybe reduce the scope
so some user stories will not be delivered,
but some of that code may be partially developed,
so you'll want to isolate that code and take it out or,
as a last resort, leave it in if you know for sure it'll be in your very next sprint.