SMART, like INVEST,
is a checklist of traits or characteristics to follow
as a guideline to write better, inconsistent tasks.
SMART is not for user stories, but for the task of a user story.
We are going to use task 3 from the last slide as our
sample task and compare it to the template.
The first is S for specific.
A task needs to be specific enough so that everyone can understand it.
It helps to keep other tasks from overlapping and also helps people to
understand either the tasks add up to the full story or not.
In this example, it seems specific enough, so check.
The next is M for measurable.
The key of measurable is actually simple.
Can we mark it as done?
The team needs to agree on what that means during task development,
but it should also include what the task is intended to do,
testing, and maybe with some refactoring within the timebox,
so check.
Next is A for achievable.
The task owner must be able to achieve, that is, complete the task.
It may be achievable, but isn't achievable within the timebox of the sprint?
If so, check.
If not, is it possible to decompose into more subtasks?
Next is R for relevant.
Every task must be relevant and contribute directly to this user story.
User stories are broken into tasks for the developer's benefit certainly,
but the product owner should still be able to presume that
each task can be justified and explained.
Once again, check.
Next is T for timeboxed.
A task should be limited to a specific duration.
And as you will see in the next module on sprint planning, in hours.
This doesn't need to be a formal estimate in hours or days,
but there must be an expectation so people know when they need to seek help.
If a task is harder than expected, then the team needs to split the task,
change players, or do something to help the task and story get done.
For this example, we think it'll fit, so check.
If you would like to know more about the SMART characteristics,
check out Bill Wake's writings.
Now for a point of view.
Now that we've covered several concepts,
processes, and building blocks, all of which are critical to sprint planning,
does it seem doable to you for your organization?
Let's go over a few key points.
Right people.
Having the right people with the right intentions and attitudes are important.
Agile/Scrum understanding.
Ensure that the team has a good understanding of the Agile philosophy,
Agile practices, and Scrum.
Epic and user story skills.
Most Agile projects are immediately off track by inadequate user stories,
so encourage your team to practice on some of your customer's
backlog items first as a practice drill.
Task breakdowns.
Developers usually do well here, but if they struggle,
that's a red flag that the user stories,
these are not well formed,
or the development team does not have the right technical skills,
so keep your eye out for that gap.
Teamwork.
The only way to accomplish this is through teamwork.
That might sound a bit cliched, but it's true.
Management support.
You will need management support, and not just in the beginning.
When pressure mounts on delivering software,
the management is usually the first to fold,
so beware.
Lastly, time to gel.
It will take a while for the team to gel and work as a well-oiled machine.
Please be patient. Now let's summarize this module.