Here is the summary of this module.
Agile foundation.
We learned there are four process groups.
The first is projects, which is the overall container of the Agile effort.
The second is releases, and projects have releases.
That is a project is made up of a series of product releases.
The third is iterations.
There are multiple iterations per release just as there
are multiple releases per project.
Also, in Scrum terminology, an iteration is known as a sprint.
And the fourth is daily work,
which is what the team does every day within an iteration or sprint.
Several days of work make up an iteration or sprint.
Next, Agile participants.
An Agile or Scrum team has three specific roles.
The fist is product owner,
who is the person responsible for managing the business requirements.
The product owner has a very key and critical role
of gathering the requirements, ordering or prioritizing the requirements,
and ascertaining the value of each to the business.
The next is the development team.
And because Agile/Scrum teams are cross- functional,
a development team includes testers, designers,
OPs engineers, or any other skills or capabilities required,
in addition to developers.
Lastly, in the Scrum world,
the Scrum Master role is added to facilitate the Scrum process itself.
In the absence of a Scrum Master, there may be a project manager,
leader, or technical lead fulfilling that role.
To me, the real heartbeat of Agile/Scrum projects is the sprint.
This is where most of the action, that is time,
resources, effort, are expended over the entire Agile project lifecycle.
Backlogs: Driving Agile projects forward.
Key to your success is that you need to ensure you
have a healthy backlog process,
which means having quality backlog items and a
quality backlog management process.
We discussed that the initial backlog may be fuzzy,
could be unclear, may even have multiple writing styles.
So in our planning meetings, we want to transform those stories into succinct,
and clear, and, if possible, using a single writing style.
User stories and INVEST.
We discussed that writing user stories follows the INVEST checklist,
and it yields better user stories.
Those traits are independent, negotiable,
valuable, estimable, small, and testable.
Using user story templates are important for three
reasons: Roles are in the first person,
templates help the product owner or the development team
more easily understand the user stories,
and lastly, templates help keep user stories concise and contained.
Leveraging SMART for writing better task descriptions.
We presented a checklist for you to use to validate the quality of your
task descriptions to ensure that they are specific,
measurable, achievable, relevant, and timeboxed.
In the next module, we'll be doing a deep dive into planning sprints effectively. See you there.