The Burnup Chart: Assessing your Sprint.
I am sure you've heard of the term burndown, but I like the term burnup instead.
Both forms of the burn chart would be fine to use.
It's just that burnup sounds better to me.
A burnup chart provides a bird's-eye view of the project's progress,
or the releases progress, and also, of course,
the sprint's progress.
Burnup shows the aggregation of completed story points over a period of time,
and burndown shows the remaining story points for a
sprint or release or project.
Why is burnup important?
It shows a quick and easy way to determine the health of the sprint,
that is, how well are we doing?
Metrics of the burnup are tied to the unit of measure for the sprint,
which may be, of course, story points, which I like,
could even be hours, or another metric you may be using.
So at the end of the sprint, the burnup value is the velocity of that sprint.
Let's see an example.
Many automated tools allow you to simply click and get to
see the burnup or down chart by sprint, release,
or full project.
Let's go through an example.
Here we are starting the sprint day one.
This sprint's backlog has three user stories: 7, 2, and 1.
The next column is the points, which total the 44 points,
and the third and last column called Done are all 0s since
this is the first day of the sprint.
Below, you will see a simple chart which summarizes our sprint,
and since we are just getting started, the burnup for week 1 and 2 are 0s,
and our sprint goal is 44.
Now we are in day five, or the end of the first week, of a two-week sprint.
We have completed user story 1, which is 10 story points,
so the total for the week is 10 completed points.
That would be represented in this chart.
Week 1 is 10 points.
Now we are on the last day, day 10, of the 2-week sprint.
We have completed user story 7, which is 22 points,
so the total for the sprint is 32 completed points.
That would be represented in this chart where week 1 is 10 points
and week 2 is the aggregate total of 32 points.
And let's see just what happened.
Our velocity for this sprint is 32 story points.
So we can see that our sprint goal was 44 points,
but our sprint result was only 32 points,
12 points shy.
No worries.
And here are some reasons why we may be short of our goal.
The team may be too aggressive.
The business domain may be complicated,
so it took more time to figure things out.
The team may be new to Agile and Scrum or just be new to each other.
That is the team may be Scrum experienced,
but just don't get to know each other.
What to do next?
Well, you might set your target to 32 points for the next sprint,
or I would set your target to the revised average velocity of the
release you are in or the last couple of releases.
Do your retrospective, see what improvements you could make.
And don't forget, your sprint cadence will vary,
and it's not perfect, and that is totally fine and normal. Now let's put all of this together with an example.