In this course, Developing Effective Agile Sprint Plans,
you will learn skills, approaches,
and techniques to advance your essential agile and sprint planning capabilities.
The sprint plan, and more importantly the process by which sprint plans are made,
is the key building block of an agile project.
This course will focus on sprint planning,
features and user stories, developer tasks,
backlogs, priorities, and estimates, burn down and velocity,
slack and spikes, daily scrums and daily work,
and lastly, sprint demos, review, and retrospectives.
Here is the course overview of the three core modules.
The first, Understanding the Agile Workflow.
We will quickly review key Agile, Scrum,
and sprint terms, definitions, roles, artifacts,
and processes to provide the basis for this course and cover the numerous
benefits of having a solid agile planning process and what those outcomes
and expectations of spring planning should be.
Next, Planning Sprints Effectively.
You will learn the activities regarding the product backlog,
user stories, sprit planning, sprint backlog,
the sprint itself, daily scrum or standup,
the potentially shippable product, and lastly,
the sprint review and retrospective.
Included will be management activities such as sprint status,
burndown, and developing velocities.
The third core module, Avoiding Problems and Making Mid-sprint Corrections.
Finally, this course will not only cover the happy path of the planning process,
but once this sprint is launched and is in flight,
we will explore how to handle the myriad of issues that may
affect and impede your plan such as bugs,
staffing, spikes, incomplete work, and what other options you may have to apply to mitigate them.