Hello and welcome to a new section in this simple chute's section, we are going to be making this the
simple through to game and we're going to learn about movement, movements, animation.
As you can see here, our character is a fully animated third person character.
We are going to be adding all sorts of enterprises to add movement system and the aiming system, an
animation on top of all of this.
We're gonna be adding a shooting mechanic.
Shooting with possible effects, et cetera, shooting.
And we're gonna have death.
I said we're going to kill off a guy with shooting mechanics and also have health for ourselves.
Finally, we're gonna have a win lose condition.
So if I get shot to pieces, the game's gonna notice that and it's going to restart the mental for and
display this handy message telling us what's going on.
The same happens if we managed to kill off all the enemies in the level we win and get a similar message.
Except it's greed.
So to recap, the project plan for the next series of 50 lectures also is going to be, first of all,
sorting out our player movement, then taking a bit of a deep dive into animation to make our third
person character look really cool.
We're going to then have some short sorts of shooting architecture and gun architecture discussions
to allow us to do that shooting.
Then we're going to have health and death happen for both us and the A.I. We're going to implement an
enemy A.I. using behavior trees and teach you how to make your own behavior tree nodes in C++.
And then we're going to implement a win lose condition using the game mode and access to the level to
detect whether all the enemies are dead and whether we are dead as well.
So that's a rough outline of the section where in some things we're going to be looping back to multiple
times.
But this is the main stuff we're aiming to cover.
So let's dive in and get our project set up.