Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we are going to be learning how to connect up an animation, swacked gameplay.
And we're going to get the speed of our character hooked up to the BLENDE space so that we can get this
effect.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
Okay, so we have got ourselves a bland space to integrate in to this.
A BP shooter character.
The first thing I'm gonna do is I'm going to go ahead and delete these two blends that we use as an
example of how the animation blueprints and graph works.
And instead, we're going to bring in from the asset browser in the bottom right.
The Blende space that we've just created, this B.
S underscore locomotion.
If you drag that in to your Annam graph, you'll see it brings in this little green node here and very
much like the other blende nodes and things like that, we've got ourselves and UNimposed that we can
drag into our outputs.
And if I compile, you can see it's just in our default space.
And then you can see this little visualization, which is quite handy of the little Blende space.
And we could go ahead and change the values in here statically or we could input some variables into
here.
Well, we're probably going to want to do the latter.
So I'm gonna go ahead and delete the two variables.
We've got the left and the forward because we know now that what we want is an angle which is going
to be a float.
So let's change that over to float.
And we're going to need a speed variable as well, which is also a float.
And we can patch those two in the speed variable into the speed and the angle into the angle.
And we go hit compile look at our animate preview editor and just tweak the values.
So first of all, the speed, let's bring the speed up a little bit.
Let's bring the speed up to about 30.
See what happens.
They go he starts to walk by, bring it up to 70.
He is getting closer to running.
I bring it to 100.
Not 10, 100.
Then he is full on running and then it can change the angle.
So at 90 degrees, he's going 90 to the right, minus 90 is going.
Mind going over to the left.
We can go somewhere in between.
So I can say 45 degrees.
You can see runs at a 45 degree angle and you can see the Blende space where he is trying to pick in
the plan space and what animations.
It's sort of blending between its blend between that forward animation and that 90 degrees.
Right.
Animation.
So that's cool.
We've got that going.
But as we know, this needs to be driven by our actual gameplay.
And why do we do that anyway?
Why don't we just have the animations, drive our gameplay saying, you know, we need to be moving
forward at such and such a pace?
Well, the reason for not doing that, the reason for not using the animation to drive gameplay is that
you often want your designer to be able to tweak all sorts of variables about your gameplay.
You want them to be able to say, okay, well, it doesn't feel right that this character is running
at this speed.
He needs to be running at this speed instead, and walking should be more at this speed.
So you don't want your animations to constrain the design and game, feel you want the animations to
come off the back of your game, feel and make it look good.
So during a design process, you might realize actually we need a faster running animation and that's
okay.
But you want to be able to change up the game first to get there rather than have to go and try and
record a different running animation or find a different running animation and then realize that actually
that didn't improve the feel of the game.
That's why I want to keep these two things as separate as possible.
There are times when things really must line up with the animations, but this is not one of them.
So there are exceptions to every rule.
So don't take this as a completely set in stone rule.
You'll definitely see instances of games that drive some features from the animation.
But generally speaking, we want to do it the other way round.
We want to say, what's the speed of the character in the game?
Let me go and update the speed of the animation rather than saying, what's the speed of the animation?
Let me update the speed of the character in the game.
With that said, how do we do this?
Basically, the mechanics of it are that this blueprint, this animation blueprint has an event graph
like other blueprints do, which means that it can have things like a tick event.
If I go over in to the event graph and have a look, we have got a couple of event nodes in here that
we can use to start from.
We've got this blueprint update animation.
If we come off of this every time it wants to update the animation, it's going to give us the execution
note and allow us to go ahead and grab some state.
So what we're going to do is every time this is called, we go and grab some say and notice here, it's
got this get porn owner that's saying go ahead and get the porn objects.
Let's remind ourselves, the porn in this case is a character character being a subclass of porn.
And it would be this BP shooter character.
Why would it be the BP issues character?
Well, let's see.
Because this character, if we select the MASH, go to the viewport, it's currently running just a
simple animation.
But what we want to do is change the animation mode over to use animation blueprints.
And we want to use that HBP shooter character.
So that is why this is the porn owner is using that animation blueprint.
So the blueprint now has a porn owner.
And so what we want to do in this update function, just to summarize, is we want to grab the information
from the porn about its movement.
We want to say, what's your speed?
What's the angle of your movement?
That's what we're going to calculate in this lecture.
We're just going to do the speed because it's the simplest to do.
The angle is going to require a little bit of manipulation with transforms, which we're gonna look
at in the next lecture.
So the note that we're going to want here is to get the velocity of our porn owner.
That gives us this vector here.
And then off the back of that vector, we want to find its magnitude or its length.
So we can drag off that vector search for the magnitude.
And that's been clever here.
And I've search for magnitude, but it's given me the function called vector length to clearly magnitude.
They've clocked that it's a synonym for vector length.
Why do we want to get the vector length rather than the vector itself?
Because we're looking for a float's, which is the speed vectors include the direction as well as the
speed, which we're gonna need to calculate the angle.
But it isn't what we need to calculate the speed.
So little mini challenge for you here.
Go ahead.
There aren't there isn't any other challenge in this lecture.
Go ahead and set the speed using this vector length.
And remember, if you need any execution pen, we're trying to do this on the blueprint update animations
that pause video and have a go.
Welcome back.
So the speed is what we want to set.
So if I drag that into the blueprint and hit set speed, you can see we've got an execution pin that
we need.
We're gonna get that from the blueprint update animation.
And we need the data pin, which is going to be the speed that comes from our vector length of getting
our velocity.
So we should be able to go ahead and save and compile that.
You can see that's reset the speed to zero.
Because now it's trying to set it from a porn owner.
That is not really there.
So what we're gonna want to do is actually go ahead and play in the world and see what we've got.
Okay.
This is much better.
We've got ourselves a porn that's staying static on the ground except for when I move, at which point
it is giving me some speed.
And if he is an analog input, such as a controller, you can see that by changing the analog input.
That sort of changed the speed.
We can change how fast this guy is moving.
Now, obviously, there are two problems here, the first one being that if I move off an angle, it's
just using the absolute speed.
So it's not adjusting their angle in our BLENDE space.
And so the animation looks wrong.
The other problem is that we're getting definitely some foot sliding here because the speed of our animation
is not matching the speed of the character in our game.
That's something that we will look at fixing in a following lecture as well.
Great stuff.
Hopefully you now understand how animations should hook up to gameplay using the animation blueprint.
And you should be able to go and apply that to your own game.
See you in the next lecture where we will be hooking up those angles.
So this movement looks a bit more natural.