Hello, welcome.
In this lecture, we are going to get our foot sliding in order.
As you can see now, if I am walking.
My feet are no longer sliding.
And if I'm running the same, I'm also not sliding.
So let's dive in and see how we can do this by calculating the speed of our animation's.
So let's try and fix this foot sliding issue, if I'm movings, especially visible at a slow walking
speed, you can see he's basically running across the ground.
Now, why is this happening?
The reason this is happening is that in at Blende Space Locomotion, we have got some speeds set up
here and these don't actually correspond to the speeds of our animations.
So what we're saying is that in gameplay we're moving at 100 centimeters.
A second is going to be playing this running animation.
And if this running animation is faster than 100 centimeters per second, you're going to get foot sliding.
Also, if it's slower, you're going to get foot sliding in both cases.
You'll get foot sliding.
So what we want to do is match up these axes to actually play the correct animation at the correct speed.
And then interpolate when we're at a different speed.
Obviously, this is going to mean that there is a limitation on our gameplay.
We can't go faster than our maximum animation will allow because we are unable to display that.
But if you did want to do that and you did once go faster, then you would have to get more animations
and so on.
But as I said, that allows our designer to change up the gameplay first and then we can go and hunt
for animations if it works.
So let's have a look at this run animation.
How can we calculate the speed of this run?
Animation is not automatically told to us by unreeled.
So there's a little bit of maths involved to get there.
Let's go and find the jog forward animation.
And we want the jog forward combat in particular.
Here it is.
And how do we go ahead and get this?
Let's just pause the playing at the animation.
What we want to see essentially is how fast one of these feet moves across the floor.
So from the point, it touches down to the point that is starting to leave the floor.
We want to know how fast it moved across the ground.
And that is the speed of animation to do that.
We are going to track the speed of the ankle bone.
So if I click into the world, you can see I should be able to select the foot underscore.
Ah, and that is our ankle bone.
And as we move across, you can see that it is moving the rotation.
But notice is not changing the location.
Why is that?
Because of the location shown here is a local rotation, that local location rather.
And that location is relative to the knee.
And it's not actually moving relative to the knee.
It's only rotating relative to the knee.
So that's why we are getting that.
If we switch over to the world location and go ahead a move now, you can definitely see that we are
getting movements in our location.
So we need to switch over to world for this calculation to work.
And then we wants to find two points.
The point at which we land, we are going to want to find out the Y value y the Y value, because that
is this axis here that we're looking at from left to right is the Y axis.
You can see it in the widget at the bottom left of your viewport.
So we're going to want to find the Y value when we hit the floor.
We're also gonna want to find the time at which we hit the floor, which is this second number in brackets
on our timeline.
The point one nine.
And we're going to then go and look and find the second time, which is where we're going to leave the
floor.
Find that time.
Find the Y value, and then we're going to apply this formula here.
Let me break it down.
The first thing is to calculate the foot speed.
We need to calculate the Y at the finish minus the Y at the start.
We want to divide that by the time at the finish divided by the time at the start.
So I'm going to work through this calculation with you or you're going to need is somewhere to capture
the numbers, such as a new notepad or I'm going to use a new text documents in Visual Studio Code,
just an untitled one.
I don't need to save it or anything.
And I'm going to open up a calculator on Windows.
It's just easier to do it on your computer because you can copy and paste into it.
And we're going to start finding some values.
First of all, we want to find where do we hit the floor about here, which is going to be a time nought
point one six.
That's type that in to our text documents, one point one six.
Go one six.
Like that.
And what's the Y value?
Best to capture it now because it's gonna be hard to find later.
It is.
Let's just go ahead and copy it.
It's hard to see my screen resolution.
Points something cool.
Now, that's the start.
Where is the finish?
Let's go and drag the foot across.
Around here is probably where we're leaving the ground and is conveniently point three note and the
Y is going to be a negative number now minus two eight point they get.
So let's apply our formula.
First of all, it's the finish that we want in there first, not the start.
Counterintuitively, we're going to subtract the start.
Like, that's gonna give us a negative number of.
That's how far we moved, 45 centimeters is how far that foot moved in one now.
Now, how long did it take for that to happen?
First of all, let's let's get that number down in our file and our text file and see how long it took.
Let's clear and start with the finish.
And then subtract the start gives us this number.
I don't get a copy which just control C on Windows without selecting anything, it just automatically
copies a number that slam.
And then we're going to want to work out what this is equal to.
So let's clear and start with the minus 45.
And divide.
By the point one for.
And that gives us this number right here.
Like that.
So this is telling us that ad jog speed is giving us a negative number because that's kind of going
backwards.
But the jog speed forwards essentially is going to be 325 approximately centimeters per second.
So that's what we're going to want to have in our BLENDE space.
So we now need to do the same thing for our walking animation.
So that's gonna be a challenge for you to calculate the walk speed as well as the run speed.
Find the walking animation that's relevant, probably the forward one, and apply the formula and do
it the same as we just did.
Finding the foot speed is why finish minus why start divided by T finish minus t start.
So pause the video and have a go and see what speed you come up with.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's go and find what is the correct thing here, we're going to want to find festival at Blende
Space and see what animation we were using just to jog our memories.
The Valley here is the r m b walk forward.
So let's find that R and B, walk forward.
Open that animation up and we should see that it's gonna be a much slower animation than the other one
and we're going to find our values.
So first of all, let's find the foot plant that's about here after the foot start moving is probably
the best place like that.
So that is let's go and add some new lines in here.
It's going to be points three, four like so and go and find the details of this foot bones, left foot
bone world.
We've already got selected and we're going to find its location.
That's it.
Why?
Then we go and move the foot back until we're almost leaving the ground, which is going to be at point.
Six, seven.
And the Y is going to be a negative 22 thing.
Hey, guys, moving the same distance sort of, but you can see that the time taken is much longer,
so it's going to be much slower.
Says Open up our calculator again.
And first of all, calculate the finish minus the starts, so finish, minus start.
Gives us this.
So, as you see, very similar distance, and probably if I'd select a different timestamps, it would
have been the same distance.
Then we're going to get the finished time so clear this finish time minus the start time.
Gives us a much longer time, almost twice as long.
So I'm assuming it's going to be almost twice as slow.
So let's clear and get.
At 42.
Divided by point three three.
Gives us, indeed, something that's more like minus.
Well, basically one hundred and thirty.
So copy that.
Interestingly, when it's the bigger form, it doesn't copy as easily.
They go.
So this is basically ass beat.
One hundred and thirty and three to five.
Now, how do we get this in to our BLENDE space?
That wasn't part of your challenge.
But we're going to do this now.
Let's open up our space location because these divisions aren't so easy for us to do that.
Well, the first thing is that we don't need to get things exactly 100 percent right.
But the second thing is that we can change the divisions or the number of divisions on our speed access.
So the way I'm going to do this is I'm going to have round these two values to approximately the nearest
50 and use 50 divisions.
So what we'd have here is this one's going to round up to 350.
This one's going to round up to 150.
And then what we can do is figure out how many divisions we need.
So 350 divided by 50 is going to give us seven.
So let's go to our speed.
Add in seven divisions.
Add the maximum axis value to be 350.
Like so.
And now what we should get is at the 350 mark.
We are going to be running when we're down at 150.
We are going to be walking.
So if we save and then anywhere in between, obviously it's going to interpolate as best it can.
Now, let's go ahead and play and see if that's helped fix our foot sliding.
Issueless.
Look down at the ground so we can see our feet.
As I am walking, you can see we've got far less if no foot sliding whatsoever as we run.
It's certainly no noticeable foot sliding now.
So I'm quite happy that we've successfully calculated a decent approximation for the speed of our animations.
And hopefully you can apply this to any animations that you use in the future if you're trying to put
them in a blend space or match them up to a foot movement.
So that concludes our little foray into animation for now.
I think we've got a good starting point for animation with a third person character.
The next thing that's really missing here is some gun architecture.
So we're going to look at how you architect guns for third person and first person shooters in the next
lecture.
See their.