Hello and welcome back.
So currently when we run our program we see that we print the sum and the products of our variables
to the terminal.
But it's not really in context at this stage.
If somebody was to play our game they wouldn't have a clue what these numbers mean they certainly wouldn't
know that these numbers represent the sum and the product of the code they have to enter.
So we're going to clean this up a bit before moving on.
We're going to start by inserting a new line above where we print the sum to the terminal.
And on this line we're going to call cout from the standard namespace and we're going to print out
a string.
We want to make it clear to the player that there are three numbers in the code so let's print out something
like that.
There are three numbers in the code and then we want to end the line so we can start a new line on the
terminal.
So we'll call end line from the standard namespace.
And on the line below where we print the sum we can insert some quotation marks before we type some
so we can print a string here and then we can use a two left angled brackets to print the sum afterwards
so we can now print the codes add up to and we could put a colon and a space to print some just after
a little space here.
So now if we compile our code and run Triple X we can see now that we have a hint that there are three
numbers in the code and the codes add up to nine
in my program.
So now it's your turn to finish these messages off.
I want you to clear up the next line.
Print a message about the product just like we've done with the sum and then why not take a screenshot
of your terminal and showcase your Triple X game.
So far in the community so pause here.
Fix up your messages and share your work in the community.
And then when you're ready we can carry on.
Okay, so here's my result I now print there are three numbers in the code the codes add up to and then I print
the sum and on the line beneath this I print the codes multiply to give and then I print the product.
I've also used this little plus symbol here just to make the hint stand out a little.
But this is totally optional.
And I also want to point out that I have a blank line before the hints get printed out in the terminal.
This is because I've used end line from the standard namespace in my code twice before we see out to
print the hints.
Okay great.
So this is much clearer for the player to understand.
Now before we move on we're going to be taking a look at how we've been naming our variables.
It's really important to give your variables good names in C++.
Variable names must begin with a letter or an underscore meaning variable names cannot start with a
number.
And in C++ we cannot use a reserved keyword for a variable name.
Key words are reserved to be used only by the C++ language.
And there's over 90 keywords in C++ that are reserved.
We've seen some of them already.
For example we can't name a variable const or int because they are reserved by the language.
Now I said it's important to give your variables good names. By doing this we can self documents our
code, self documenting code makes our code easier to read and understand by anybody who views it.
If we give a variable a good name we don't have to use a comment to describe and explain what it does.
And we always want to have this in mind when we name our variables and there's something else we should
point out here that relates to Unreal Engine 4.
We want to be conforming to Unreal's coding standard. In the coding standard documentation for Unreal
the naming conventions are listed.
It says that the first letter of each word in a name should be capitalized and we should avoid using
underscores between words.
So this is quite important.
We should start following these guidelines to prepare ourselves for Unreal. Unreal Engine 4 uses an upper
CamelCase naming convention meaning that the start of each word is capitalized which is different in
comparison to working with other game engines.
So we want to follow these guidelines when we name our variables. So we can be honest with ourselves
here A B and C aren't very good variable names and we've even had to add a comment to describe them
but we understand the pain now of having a bad variable names we've had to describe them with a comment.
But right now I want you to rename these variables to something more suitable. Rename your A, B, and C
variables to CodeA, CodeB, and CodeC then rename the sum and the product to CodeSum
And CodeProduct and make sure your CodeSum and CodeProduct variables are initialized with your new variable
names not just a, b, and c and make sure to follow
Unreal Engine 4's preferred naming convention use UpperCamelCase where you capitalize the first
letter of each word.
So by doing all of this is really going to help clear things up as we move forward.
So pause here to rename your variables and then we can wrap up this lesson.
Okay, so I've gone ahead and renamed my a, b, and c variables to CodeA, CodeB, and CodeC and I've renamed
the sum and the product variables to CodeSum and CodeProduct and we are initializing them with expressions
that add and multiply our CodeA,B, and C variables together and a more so now following Unreal Engine
4's naming convention where we capitalized the start of each words we're using the upper camel
case naming convention here.
Now there's a slight issue here because we've changed the name of the sum and the product variables
but we're still using them later on in our code and we haven't changed the name for them here yet.
So I'm going to back up the steps to my CodeSum and CodeProduct variables are just named sum and product.
And notice when we click on them it highlights and shows where they are used in our code and we can
right click on the variable and we can select change all occurrences.
And now if we start typing notice it's highlighted where our variables are and when we start typing
now it's going to rename the variable everywhere it is now file.
So sum is going to be CodeSum for me and we can do the same with product we can right click on it
and change all the occurrences for it and change it to CodeProduct.
Okay great.
So we're almost there.
We're going to wrap up this lesson by declaring a new variable towards the end of our main function.
We're going to declare an integer and it's going to be called PlayerGuess and we're not going to initialize
it here.
We're going to use a semicolon to end the line and in the next lesson we're going to use this variable
to store the player's guess that they enter into the terminal.
So we'll wrap this lesson up here and I'll see you in the next one.