Hello everybody and welcome to this lecture on binary space partitioning sounds pretty fancy but it
is pretty awesome because we're going to be able to mock up a level incredibly quickly.
Now this is great if you've got an idea and you want to see whether it works or in fact you want to
pass the level design onto an artist to make some awesome assets for it.
We're going to look at the various different brush types we can get and we can look at additive and
subtracting modelling the order matters mainly because of what I just talked about additive and subjective.
If you put something in later on we'll see that it won't work as expected at rebuilding needs something
that we've talked about with the lighting.
But rebuilding works would BSP as well and can fix some of the issues that we can have and it is highly
recommended that you work aligned to the grid.
It will be far more performance and also it will mean if you to swap things out with models that have
been made you know that they're going to fit without having to rejig the entire level.
Okay.
So let's hope over to unreal.
Okay so now that we're over an umbrella let's go ahead and start adding some of these BSP what are they.
How do we get to them.
So over on the left hand side if you go ahead and click geometry when that appears we will see that
we've got a series of brushes that we can use.
Let's zoom out a little in our 3D view here and I'm going to come up because some of these pieces are
quite big.
So you can drag in a box you can drag in a cone and you can drag in some curves there as you can see
how very quickly you could build up a level especially with these stairs and there's some straight stairs
here and some spiral stairs as well so before long you've got a level coming together really well.
Now with each of these BSP is they're configurable so we can change them in real time so I can select
this cone go over to the details scroll down and say well actually I want it to.
Here we go the brush settings got scroll down a little further on the on this one and we can go ahead
and increase the number of sites it will updates and we've got more detail geometry there.
Now if I'm going to say this now and I'm probably going to say it several times this is no substitute
to actually modelling geometry properly texturing et cetera.
Okay.
So we can add things to our scene day in day out and we have a little taste of there of the setting.
So if we go ahead and click back on the cone have a look there's quite a few set brush settings there.
The cube is going to have a few less because it's a simpler object.
Now you can change the dimensions of everything there and just like any of the mesh objects you can
click and drag a material directly onto the surface of these objects which is incredibly useful but
building up your level like this is not very good for performance.
We do have to watch out great for testing and making sure that the level flows well or it's the right
size and feels right.
But don't rely on BSD to create a final product.
It won't be very performance.
And as you'll see in a bit we can get quite complex with these BSD.
Now we can bake them down to a static mesh so at any point let's say this cube we were happy with it.
We go to the brush settings towards the bottom here we've got create a static mesh and if you did this
to all of your BSD in your scene then the aforementioned performance issues that you have by using BSD
essentially do go.
However of course the quality of your models will suffer by just being basic BSP shapes.
Now if we were going to do this I'll pop it in my model's folder and I would name it S.M. which stands
for static mesh as you might have guessed underscore that's me my maths out the way.
And in this case cube example or something along those lines because it's just a cube example we create
the static mesh.
Now that reminds me a bit of a Segway here.
I'm going to open up my content browser for a moment.
Now you may notice that when I went along and brought in my two by one door and frame they were actually
within one blend file.
So I exported them and both in the same esp FBI exe file.
Now in hindsight what I will now do in the future whenever I'm exporting models is that I will go ahead
and the two by one door and frame I will export them as separate objects want rather than relying on
the name of the file because that's why it's got this here.
So let's let's sort this out now and just be aware that if you ever do anything like this renaming them
in the content browser is fine it's going to rename them on the disk as well but it's not going to rename
my original models.
So I've got to remember to rename them elsewhere.
Not a problem in the case of this one objects but if this was a series of objects you'd quite easily
end up with something or many things out of sync with everything else not doorway doorframe.
Okay.
So I've got my all my objects.
They're named next come back from that little bit of a distraction there what else can we do.
Well let's get rid of these extra objects over added into my scenes.
I'm going to just highlight them and press delete the stairs over there.
Okay.
I'm going to create my a new instance of this stone material so I'm going to right click Create material
instance and I'm going to just call this wall for the moment.
It'll enable me to change the settings on it later on.
Now I can obviously click and drag and drop things on and you can see this is going to be a very tedious
process to do this cone.
Well I'm going to get rid of that cone because with that material selected when you go ahead and drag
and drop it in will you look at that it has the material applied to it's straight away which is incredibly
useful.
Now here is a great example of where the materials and its alignment on our on our objects here is just
not working out well it looks a mess.
And this is a prime example of really why you don't want to do anything like this just using you're
really going to need to use a 3D modeling program like blender in order to apply textures to a model
in a more meaningful manner.
Now saying that you can tweak all these textures and align them but that's a lot of hard work considering
what you're getting as the end result.
Okay so you can drag things in like that.
What else can we do with BSP experience just scratching the surface here.
Let's say we go ahead and grab a box and at the bottom of this list we've got subtract and we can change
the setting of anything that we drag into our scene that's just track this then pull it down so intersects
with our current and we can see here is a nice little hole in it so you can see you can actually make
some quite detailed geometry.
We start building these things up.
Let's have a look at the settings just there.
So we've got a subtracted brush that's all box shape.
Oh that's interesting.
So we can change it and have something else and you can see there's some other options in there as well.
We can change its actual size as well here which is incredibly useful.
We can play with Wolf thickness.
Okay well wall thickness won't really come into effect until you've ticked hollow when you tick on holiday.
Now we've got a wall thickness and if we set something like 40 so we can really see it we can see here
that it's got an inner and an outer wall which is pretty awesome I'm not sure I like the shape that's
going on there but if this was a bigger box technically we could make a room out of it and then just
cut a hole in the size using a subtracted method and we end up with a room if I'll show you that now
because that is not the way that we're going to go.
And in order to see my view just a little bit better.
Obviously I'm going to hide things and move them out of the way but in the top here we've got an option
top right of your editor window maximize our resources viewport if we click that little button there
we get this quad view which is incredibly useful for trying to work things out and move around so I
can move this around place it now.
Now go off front a side and the back can we can say oh no it's not front sorry no.
It says at the top left here we've got a back a right and a top view.
And obviously we can change that to a front view if we wanted to.
And we can move things around in the viewport just like we can the 3D view with the right mouse button.
So this is incredibly useful if we make let's say this box brush a thousand by a thousand.
There we go.
A wall thickness of 40.
That's fine.
And then we should be able to cover up our existing floor which we can do.
Perfect.
And let's set it to a additive brush.
Excellent.
So we now have a room there.
If we make it just a little bit taller let's make it maybe four metres tall.
So 400 we can then come along lift it up because it's going to be a nice high room.
Yep.
That looks good.
And then we can just grab another box.
I'm going to be rubbish at position it here but I can go in from the side pull that through and look
because it's subtracted brush.
Now if we go ahead and press play well let's stop that for a moment.
Let's make this full screen press build.
Now press play.
Look at that.
Now the floor is looking like a disco floor.
This is Z fighting.
And I've set it up deliberately so you can see it's at its worst you've probably seen this effect before
and it's because the surface that was already there our original floor that square floor that we had
and the new one that we've created are in exactly the same place.
So we can sort that out in the moment but here we go we've created a room.
Now I wouldn't create a room like this because it doesn't give us very much flexibility.
Yes we can.
That's just come out of it for the moment.
We can drag a different texture to the walls et cetera but if I go to build and then that will build
the lights in but if we look at the drop down first we can see we've got an option here to build geometry
all of this PSP that we've put in so far is geometry.
So when we go ahead and click the build button it doesn't just build the lighting like we've been playing
with so far it builds any geometry any B.S. piece as well.
So it's a slight optimization but what I'm expecting here is for our room obviously to get quite dark
because it's not got much light in the way of it's coming in but I expect it to not do the lighting
very accurately anyway.
I've always had problems with sealed geometry like this.
It's just not going to like it.
So it kind of works but then it doesn't and it's just not worth the hassle.
Now this particular Z fighting issue very easy to solve if you've got that site we've got the box brush
it's the entire room we could lift that up ever so slightly so we can just go to the z value of its
location and it's currently at 200.
If we just lifted it up to 220 or something like that it would be completely in the clear and not touching
this other bit here or we could lower that bit down.
It's entirely up to you when it comes about by would not construct the room like this.
I'd make it out the individual walls or even out of individual pieces itself.
Okay.
So we've added BSP sourcing in the brush types there we've subtracted.
We get things like this doorway really in the order does matter.
So if you put something down that's additive first and then put something that's subtracting it would
take away from it if you do it in the other order it won't do that.
So if we go ahead and let's say add in this attractive cube it's going to cut out of anything before
it.
So let's it's snapping here so let's cut another hole over here in the corner but then if we go ahead
and put a sphere next to it or did that appear and I've seen yet and make it over here in the brush
type settings an additive one and then drag it into that place we can see that it's not being removed.
Now if we were to go ahead and go to our order down in the details as an order here and say it was the
first thing that we created and we can see that's a bit of a mess how it's chopped everything up.
Not that great but of course you're probably not going to be putting together geometry like that very
often.
OK let's get rid of that let's get rid of our room let's get rid of our cone that we've got there.
I'm just gonna click Build so the final thing that I wants to go through with you.
Well there's two things really.
Okay so the first one is the fact that you can edit these brushes in a bit more detail so let's drag
a box in again.
It's gonna snap to the world of currently got my world snap settings set to 100.
Feel free to play with those.
I would suggest keeping them around that sort of level.
A hundred ten easy to move around.
In fact 50 is probably going to be a bit easier for doing these half grid squares at a time.
Let's change that to additive.
Okay.
I'm not liking that material applied there because I want to set up a wall.
And then in a few moments I'll get you to actually come along and design the rest of your room.
So I'm gonna select that box brush and delete it.
Look at this I've got two box brushes in my scene.
I can't see because the ones that take away.
So one of the things I would do here is just delete that and let's go ahead.
Right click Create a folder and call it building.
Because we're going to construct a building in a moment and we can put our pieces in there.
We can start by grabbing that the door and the door frame.
Notice their name hasn't changed from what we've changed our actual meshes to again.
Might be worth updating that might not entirely up to going to lift that up to the building so then
it's nested in there.
Just the bits of organization as we start building and we select my wall that I've created drag my box
in here.
Oh and change it to additive so we can set the scale of the face is just down here x y and z so we can
make it the entire length of this box by setting that to a thousand and then just dragging it roughly
to the right place.
There we go.
So definitely takes up all of that length and we can see that the Z fighting again.
So you just have to be aware of that and move ever so slightly.
That usually solves the issue.
Okay.
So we've got that there.
How about if we want to edit it and make it a slightly different shape.
What we can do that if we have a look at the very top instead of going to place things let's go all
the way over to geometry editing.
You may not be able to select a face.
I have been able to there.
If you cannot select an entire face we should be really easy to do by just clicking on it like so then
you've probably got transparency mode turned on so click away so you don't have any objects selected
and pressed T.
Now when I come back I will find that I cannot select any faces.
It's very easy to do that and I've been caught out with that so many times I press t at some point and
then I can't select an individual face which I now can when you can select a face you can actually change
the size of it very very quickly.
So this is brilliant.
If you don't know the exact size that you're looking for and I've squished these down to a single plane
I'm not sure if I can recover from this hotel.
Never mind let's drag a new one of these things in so it's very easy to drag them on top of one another.
I'd advise you don't do that.
There we go.
So we tracked anyone in go here.
We're on edit which is absolutely fine should be able to click a face here and move it to an appropriate
location.
Now this is the great thing about if you didn't know this was a thousand wide very easy to get it so
it matches like so.
And again you may need to try and edit the snapping settings at the top to make sure it fits perfectly
but it's not just the face we can go ahead here and grab an edge now an edge is one of the harder ones
to grab.
There we go.
And then I can push that back and we've got a wedge shape.
Pretty awesome but it's going to start distorting the textures if we're not careful.
But we can also grab individual vertices and move those around to really mess up the geometry.
Now we see at this point it doesn't know what to do with our textures we've completely destroyed any
hope of being able to map them and you can see here as well what we've done.
Even the basic default grid texture that appears and things absolutely ruined.
Here we go and put these war pieces on.
None of them are going to line up.
Now that may be fine for what you need but again this is the sort of thing that an external program
like Blender is going to be much better at sorting out.
We can select the face we can come in.
Oh here we go rotate rotate the texture.
Can we put an arbitrary amount in it.
Can we get it.
So it looks roughly right.
So that looks roughly Ryan's rotate that around.
No we're going to have to perhaps go 30 degrees all so close.
Let's try 15 now is going the other way so maybe you can see how this is just going to add up to a monumental
pain in the backside trying to get it right but it can be done to a certain extent but you'll be far
better going through an external program that does handle this natively rather than having texture because
this is a very simple object.
Imagine something that was a bit more complex it would be a real real nightmare.
Okay so the final thing here is just to remind you that this is not a replacement for proper geometry
by all means you can click on your object and in the details tab we go down to the brush settings we
can create that static mesh from it which is a step in the right direction but it's not ideal and you'll
probably be better off modelling it elsewhere might be okay for those distant objects that the player
never gets that close to and you just need something in your scene real quick is a great get out of
jail free card but it's not necessarily great for performance and leaving things as BSP does is a great
idea because you're able to manipulate and change things rapidly but then keeping them in the final
game that's something you want to try and avoid.
Now it's unlikely in our small level here that we're going to hit any performance issues so it's absolutely
fine to leave them as a BSP and not convert them to a static mesh but ideally you probably do want to
convert them to a static measure and you're happy with them and then replace them with better static
measures later on.
And the final thing that I want to look at before I present you with your challenge is and I'm going
to get rid of that for the moment when you're adding in your brushes like the box let's say and you've
decided by thinking about how you're putting your level together.
You have decided to set it at a certain size.
So we go ahead.
We come in here we say well the the war piece itself is going to be in the x direction so that's just
its width here.
We're going to have it set to 100.
No no no English size walls let's set it is 20 says 20 thinks 20 centimetres thick.
Let's say we're going to have it four metres high and there we go.
We've got a for me to high wall that's two meters long.
So if the pieces that you're producing outside for your game are roughly this size then you can set
it up in here and then later on you can swap it out with the real mesh that's going to go there.
So that's one way that you could do it.
Of course you could create your room by just putting the the side across completely.
And remember you've got this little button on the top right for alignment.
I do most of my stuff in here I'm quite comfortable in the 3D view ports.
So here for instance you can very quickly drag out a couple of wall sections by holding down out.
Remember you need to press down old as well.
Each time you want to make a copy.
You may end up with some seams.
I believe these are all seamless textures but you do run the risk of having some scenes where these
objects join but you can see there.
That's brilliant.
We've managed to get a war section built incredibly quickly and it's modular.
I can take that one out really quickly without having to worry about cutting a hole.
However what I may want to do instead is grab this to make a duplicates which we have been doing and
then cut a hole suitable for the door in it.
I'll let you explore how you want to set up be seen.
This one's a bit more involved and I'll say this time and time again there's never a right or wrong.
This could quite easily be a piece that is instead of 200 y just a thousand.
And there we go we can slap it right there.
It takes up and looks exactly the same.
And for all intents and purposes is absolutely fine as a war piece there.
And I will let you decide whether or not you're going to bake these things down to a static mesh at
the moment.
Remember if you do that you lose all edited ability the moment you bake it like that so that buttons
just at the bottom of our brush settings in the details create a static mesh and remember to name things
appropriately as well.
So no point in creating a static mesh and not putting that save the box brush where's the other one.
That's it.
Where is that all gone invisible.
Let's get rid of that.
Okay so we've got this one here.
It's part of the building.
Let's pop it in the building.
Do we leave it as Bob box brush six.
That's not very descriptive is it.
Probably rename that war room.
And of course you may want to be more descriptive with that and say four five six metre wall or whatever
its dimensions are.
That will really help.
Okay.
Wow.
That was a deep dive into the BSP system.
Lots to take in there.
And it's an incredible system in order to make your level quickly.
You can mock up a level incredibly quickly and you can add quite a bit of detail as well.
If you need to if you need to give your artist a better direction than then do is much better that way.
OK.
So we've been going quite a while learning all about BSD and in the following lecture you'll have a
challenge straight away to implement them.
See you shortly.