Hey and welcome to this lesson where we're going to learn how we can process user input in the terminal.
So we've been using cout throughout this section so far.
cout stands for "character output" when we call cout
we use these two left angled brackets to output whatever is to the right to the terminal as characters.
These left facing angled brackets are known as the insertion operator.
When we use cout and the insertion operator we are basically inserting characters to the output stream
which is then displayed on the terminal.
But now we're going to be taking a look at cin which stands for "character input".
It looks similar to how we've been using cout but the angled brackets go a different way.
Here we can see that the angled brackets go right.
They are facing inwards.
These are known as the extraction operator.
We use the extraction operator we've seen to extract characters from the input stream.
So when this line of code is executed the program will pause and wait until the player enters something
into the terminal when the player hits enter the input will be extracted from the input stream and
assigned to whatever is to the right of the extraction operator.
So this is how we can get the player to enter something into the terminal and store what they enter.
Then we can use this to see if they've made the correct guess or not.
And now I want you to make use of cin. At the end of the last lesson
we declared a variable called PlayerGuess. Insert a new line under where we declared the PlayerGuess
variable and call cin to extract the player's guess from the terminal to store it in our PlayerGuess variable
then print a message to the terminal that displays the guess the player just entered.
So pause here to have a good go at this and then we can explore this together.
Okay,
So I've added two lines of code.
I've added a line calling cin and I'm using the extraction operator to store the player's guess.
I then print a message to the player that says "you entered: " and then it will print the value of the variable
PlayerGuess.
So I've saved my work.
I've compiled my code and now let's take a look at running Triple X. So Triple X is running now and it's
now paused waiting until I enter my guests into the terminal.
So we already know the answer is 2 3 4, and when we enter this
it prints what we just entered and then our program finishes running.
So this seems okay but remember as a player we are trying to guess the three number code and the code
is split up into our variables CodeA, CodeB, and CodeC.
Now if we enter 234.
Well this would be the answer here is going to be treated as two hundred and thirty four.
Our guess isn't going to be treated as separate numbers.
So let's try entering 2 3 4 separated by spaces.
Now when we do this 2 is assigned to our PlayerGuess variable and anything after our spaces is ignored.
But we're giving in the right direction here.
We just need some more variables to help us store these other values.
So just like we have our variables CodeA, CodeB and CodeC we can declare variables for each guess
and then we can use cin on each of these.
So instead of declaring PlayerGuess we can remove this and we can declare GuessA, GuessB, and GuessC
but check this out.
We can actually declare all these variables on the same line.
We can type GuessA and then enter a comma and a space to declare GuessB and we can do the same for
GuessC, we can enter a comma and a space to declare GuessC then instead of calling cin on PlayerGuess
we can call it on GuessA and then on a new line beneath this we can call a cin on GuessB and then
on a new line beneath this we can call cin on GuessC then instead of printing PlayerGuess we can
print GuessA, GuessB, and GuessC to the terminal.
Now let's save our work and compile our code and run Triple X.
So it's now paused waiting for my input to assign a value to GuessA.
So if I type 2 and hit enter it then moves onto the next line and calls cin on GuessB.
So now if I enter 3 it then moves onto the next line and calls cin on GuessC so we can answer 4
and then it prints all the values of our variables at the end of this, but we don't have to enter these
numbers into the terminal on separate lines.
Let's run our program again and let's enter our numbers but separated by spaces so this still works and
runs through all the rest of our cin lines without even needing any more input.
Now it might seem like a bit of wizardry but there's a reason for this.
We enter 2 3 4 separated by some spaces.
When we call cin on guess a it will only extract the numbers up until it finds a space so it only extracts
two.
Then it moves onto the next line of code where we call cin on GuessB but instead of asking us for
more input it knows that there's something still left over from our previous input stream so it will
use what's left.
So 3 is extracted and assigned to GuessB but we still have something else remaining.
So when cin is called on GuessC instead of asking us for more input it will process what's left over
from before.
So basically your program will only ask for more input.
When cin is called if the input stream is empty.
Okay so we're almost there but there's something I want to make you aware of any character other than
a number assigned to an integer will be converted to a zero.
So for example if we entered 2 3 and X separated by spaces our number will be 2 3 0 because our
X gets converted to a zero but there's some more wizardry that happens here that we don't see once we
enter a character like x.
That isn't a number.
Yes it will convert the value to a zero that any lines of code that relates to cin after this won't
work again until we reset cin with a few lines of code.
So there's a lot of iffy stuff going on but we're really not going to dwell on this right now because
we won't be using cin and cout in Unreal and also our program ends after these lines of code runs so
it's not an immediate issue but we will be coming back to this later when we add some replayability
to our game. Now what I want you to take away from this is we want the players to enter numbers into
the terminal.
They can enter each number separately on different lines or they can enter the numbers on a single line.
But with each number separated with a space.
We don't want them to enter anything other than a number.
And we need to add a fix later for replayability.
Now I have a final challenge for you.
Before we wrap up this lesson I want you to declare a variable called GuessSum and initialize it with
the expression of GuessA,B, and C being added together.
Then I want you to declare a variable called GuessProduct and initialize it with the expression of
GuessA,B, and C being multiplied together.
So pause here.
Declare the sum and the product of the player guesses and then we can wrap up this lesson
okay.
So I hope you had a go at the challenge at the end of your main function.
You should be declaring two variables called GuessSum and GuessProduct and you should be initializing
GuessSum with an expression that adds GuessA, B and C together and you should be initializing GuessProduct
GuessProduct with an expression that multiplies these variables together.
Okay.
Awesome.
So at this point we don't even care about the individual GuessA,B, and C values.
We could just work with the product and the sum.
We don't need to let the player know the numbers they've entered over.
So let's remove the line where we print to the terminal.
The guesses that they've just made and then in the next lesson we're going to look at a way where we
can check if the players guesses are correct.
So once you're ready I'll see you in the next lesson.