Hello and welcome in this lecture, we are going to be spawning our rifle at runtime from our character
class in C++.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
OK, so we want to get our gun spawning as a child of the shooter character, the first point of call
is to be able to spawn that actor from within another actor.
We're gonna do this at runtime.
We're gonna do a begin play because that's the way you Carneys do when you spawning actors need to do
it at runtime.
And the way we're gonna do this is we're gonna get hold of the world first.
So get world and then we're going to call a function on get world.
By the way, world and level are synonyms.
So what we're actually doing here is we're going up to the level and saying, hey, level, can you
create as an actor because lact is essentially belong or live in a level.
So we're then we're saying, you know, spawn ACTA for me, please.
And this is a Sporn actor that takes a template.
You can say, I want this actor that I'm going sporn to be of type a gun.
And for that to work, we're going to need to have an include up here hash include for the gun to H.
And then we're going to take in an argument and the argument to spawn is actually can be a class type.
So by default it will go ahead and spawn the C++.
But here we want to spawn the blueprint child of this gun.
So we need to figure out what that's going to be.
That needs to be hooked up in blueprint.
Can't be hooked up here in C++ is not easily the best place to do it.
Is it blueprint?
So we're gonna do an O to go to the head of file for our shooter character and we're going to add in
a new property here.
To allow us to configure the class that we should be pointing to in order to spawn an act, which blueprint
class should we be spawning from this shooter character?
We're going to have it as an edit defaults only.
Why edit defaults?
Only because we don't want to be able to edit this at runtime, because it would give a false impression
that you can change what type of gun we're using at runtime, whereas Biggin plays already been called,
that gun's already been spawned.
And so it wouldn't actually update anything.
So we don't want to make it editable to give not give people a false impression of what can be done.
And then here we're going to use a macro called T sub class, of which you may or may not have come
across before.
And T subclass of is a template.
So we use these angle brackets again.
And we wanted to say a subclass of gun.
And basically what this means is that it allows blueprint's to restrict the classes that we can select
from to only the classes that are subclasses of the gun and C++ class.
Now, this isn't going to be a pointer because we're not pointing to an actual instance of the gun.
What we're getting here in this variable is a class itself.
In this case, it's a blueprint class, but it's still a class.
So what we're going to want to call this is the gun class just to make it super clear that this is not
actually the gun itself.
We do want another you property here to store the gun.
And that is going to be not an edit default.
So basically, we don't want to make this a visible property at all, but it's going to be an a gun
pointer.
See the difference?
One of them is t subclass of gun.
The old one is a gun pointer.
And this one is the actual gun.
That's once we've created an instance of the class.
That's where we're going to store it.
So let's go on over in to our shooter, see P and finish off this begin play where we are spawning things.
So we're gonna have gun equal to get World Spawn Act a gun.
And the argument are gonna pass in here is the gun class, which we're gonna be setting over a blueprint.
So let's go and try and compile this.
It may give us some arrows.
Let's see.
I have the message log open with the compile log.
And sure enough, we're getting some errors over here in the head file thing, undeclared identifier,
because we need to forward declare the gun.
So I'm just gonna do this at the top because in two places I'm going to say class.
A gun like so.
And just a reminder for declaring like this means that we can keep at compile times down by not including
too much in a heavy header files.
Let's try recompiling.
See.
Looks like that was the only error.
It's now compiled successfully.
Let's go ahead and hit play and see what happens.
Exit.
Have a look at our.
We basically want to have a look at the message lol, which I don't have open.
So let's go to window and developer tools and have a look at the output log and see if we have any errors
here.
Yes.
Spawn Act failed because no class was specified.
Sure.
No classes specified because we didn't configure it yet.
In Blueprint.
So this I'm gonna give as challenge to you to hook up the gun.
Find the property in our character blueprints.
Set it to the correct gun and test that it spawns.
Pulls a video and have a go.
Hey, welcome back.
So let's go over to our shooter character, BP, and find the property which should be on at the roots
or the class defaults, go into details and under shoot a character.
You can see we've got a rotation right here, which we have configured and we have got our gun class,
which is a dropdown which allows me to choose between the gun being the C++ gun.
And here's where a naming convention comes in handy.
The things prefixed with BP underscore are the blueprints.
So we want AB BP underscore a rifle.
Go ahead and select that.
Compile save.
Go over in to the scene and hit play.
Now, hopefully we have not got any errors about about spawning a gun.
The gun should have spawned.
Okay.
And to find out if it has we can f eight and have a look in the world.
Outliner.
If I make the world outline a little bit bigger, I can search for the BP underscore rifle.
Hurray!
We've got a BP and a school rifle.
The moment it's in the middle of nowhere and it's not correctly child it that's gonna be the subject
of the next lecture.
So I will see you there.