Okay everybody Welcome back.
So we're on to our challenge here where you get to create your Test level.
So the challenge is going to be to create your room.
I'm going to recommend using the BSP to do that.
And here are some specifications for you.
The walls must be three meters high.
Remember to organize your scene.
We've started making a fold I'd like you to continue making a folder and remember to name things as
you go later on.
Even though this is simple it's the time to solidify that if you leave it until later on when you've
got several objects in your scene.
It's going to be a real pain to try and work out what is what they might use to create a doorway that's
2 meters in height and one meter in width.
And you're going to place your door in that hole.
Now I'd like to be specific here as to what end of the room you should push your door.
Let's go over it and turn real.
Before I give you the challenge and this will help solve a potential issue you may have later on okay.
So let's just make the 3D Ed view just a bit better.
Okay.
So in this viewport if you click on your door right now and scroll up and your details tab to the transform
option take note of the rotation.
If it's not 0 0 and 0 looks like that might be zero point something like We get zero then make sure
it is because later on we will be rotating the door.
And if it's at 90 degrees already.
Initially when we start working with the code we'll be rotating it to 90 degrees.
So make sure that if you have a look at the axes that your door is in line with the x axis the red one
and perpendicular to the green axis.
And that would mean that basically anywhere along that y axis providing it's there you'll be absolutely
fine.
I would recommend as well when you create your hole for the doorway that you do it in such a way that
it's easy to make that hole.
So make sure you use something like the grid to align everything in its place.
Okay.
Polls over the year now make your level as simple or complex as you'd like.
If you're having lots of fun perhaps make another room to move into.
I'm not going to do that at this point but later on when I start putting my level together rather than
just the test level I will start thinking about other rooms that we're going to move into.
For the moment I'm just going to go for the one room I'm going to open the door and go out into the
void and remember just like we were talking about in the last lecture.
You don't have to make it as one wall you can make it as modular pieces that you stack together.
It's entirely up to you how you approach it.
So go ahead pause a video and give that a go
OK.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create my test level or should I say test room.
OK.
So I'm pretty much set with this wall piece here and there are a couple of ways that I could do this
I could go ahead grab this hole down out a move it's cross boom we've got the other wall very quickly
and then I could do the same again hold down ALT drag it to roughly the middle.
Pull it out this way I didn't have to do it in this order and then I'm going to rotate thrown by 90
degrees and if I've got my rough lining up Oh no I was so close look at that I'm out by a couple and
I wouldn't I would have that as well if I was in this view so this is the the benefits of using these
views is we can snap things together incredibly quickly now if we have a look at all not geometry here
it is intersecting we do have to be careful when things intersect especially if faces are on top of
one another this is absolutely fine for the type of work we're doing it really isn't worth the effort
of going into geometry editing selecting this face here let's make sure we've got the face selected
have a press.
There we go and just pulling it back and then go oh no that doesn't fit it properly needs to be ten
and then dragging it back there we go.
No no no no don't waste your time doing that just leave it as it is remember this is a test level and
even though it's lots of fun and I know the perfectionist in you is going to try and get things lined
up absolutely perfect do remember that this is in fact a test level to take it to a good degree of perfection
but not all the way there.
In fact I am going to do a bit of editing here and bring down the heights because I was not paying attention
when I duplicated this I've duplicated it and it's 400 in height Whoops.
So I'm going to come in here and said That's a 300 and I'm going to have to move things around a little
in a moment but that's that's no big deal there's only a couple two moves so hit this one here this
one and this one over here finally now one of the things with the lining everything to 100 meters or
50 hundred meters centimeters is that things aren't quite lining up here properly and I don't know whether
that's because my floor is funny I've just accepted its default position but it may be at a funny location.
Yes is it z equals 20 something the set is z equals zero.
That should allow me to set the location here
what does it need to be 150 by the looks of it.
So let's grab this one and type in 150.
Excellent.
I should be able to grab the other one as well.
Okay.
Brilliant.
So those are the four walls all sorted.
Now I could have them as static meshes.
I want to leave them editable for the moment.
Obviously this is quite a big room.
You'll often find that rooms especially in first person view are indeed bigger than they would be in
real life because otherwise it feels incredibly cramped like you can't move.
In fact this door is a real life door and it looks quite small.
It's not its is bigger than a lot of doors.
It's a metre wide and two meters tall.
I know the doors in my house are a lot less white than that but that doesn't look like I can fit through
it so it's just an illusion of the way that the first person camera works in games.
But I'm happy with how that is for the moment and this door.
I'm going to bring down to zero as well.
Excellent.
And then we've got our wall.
Now the question is Where am I going to place my dog could have it on an edge here.
Absolutely fine I could have it smack bang in the middle.
I'm going to choose smack bang in the middle and then we're going to have another wool piece going across.
Now there are a couple of ways that I could do this.
I've obviously elected at this point to make solid wall pieces like this rather than smaller modular
pieces.
That's absolutely fine if you've gone the other way.
Again no problem at all.
So that's moved across.
That looks really good.
But from the door doesn't go through yet.
So we need to make a door hole that is two meters high and one metre wide and we'll see we will have
some Z fights in because that is the exact size of the door.
So we might actually have to alter it to compete with that Z fighting that we will have.
So let's drag in a new box.
It should be a subtracting box.
So let's change it to 1.
And this is where we can set our settings appropriately so in the x direction we can see that's the
width here.
I'm going to set that to 100 for the moment and the depth.
Well that doesn't really matter at this point in time with where it is we can see our door needs repositioning
that's absolutely fine so that scrap the door and the door frame is almost worth putting them in their
own folder.
But anyway let's move into the wall ever so slightly so we can pop it there haha.
Here we go here's some Z fighting straight away.
Is there any at the top.
Yes there's some at the top and the side so I'm going to combat that straight away and we'll go to this
box brush.
I'm gonna bring it up I'm going to call it.
Cuts out.
That's essentially what it is.
And if we do anything here to make it higher and wider wider I'm gonna do higher.
I'm not because if I just make it bigger it's going to eat into the floor at the same time.
Actually it probably doesn't matter with how we've got things set up.
But I'd rather just extend it manually at the top in this particular case because the floor is not a
BSP but it could be in a game you're creating in the future.
So the X value here if I said that instead of 2 100 maybe 120 it then can expose all.
Yeah that's fine we can see here on the doorframe that there is enough space in fact it's about halfway
through.
That's really good.
And then I'm gonna go and edit geometry I think we can see that there is a shortcut shift and the numbers
so we can move backwards and forwards if we need to one two three four five perfect.
Now I can't see that at the moment so I'm gonna select it so I can click the top here and I'm going
to pull it up just by one unit which in this case will be 10 because of the snapping.
Okay.
And I think that will be absolutely fine.
The final thing here is more of an alignment.
And again I am being quite picky here.
I'm going to have to drop this down to five so it fits in between if I picked a different wall size
that should have been fine.
Is it coming out here.
Oh no that is exactly 20.
Mm hmm interesting.
So perhaps I need to make my doorway bigger in future yeah.
Okay.
I'm just gonna pull this out here and worry about the rest later because this wall is gonna have to
be slightly thinner.
In fact I am gonna make it slightly thinner.
What's it sets out at the moment 20.
Well let's make this one just 10 wide OK.
Now let's move our door back in to that.
So hopefully now that's even on both sides.
OK brilliant.
OK a bit of hacking there but that's absolutely fine.
The other question here is do we want a roof on our building.
I think yes.
Now you may not have put a roof on yours I appreciate that it wasn't actually part of the challenge.
It's just a couple of ways that we can do that.
We can grab the floor which is a static mesh actor that we've already created or we could just create
one a new one to fit this.
I'm going to go ahead and just practice the skills that we've learnt by dragging a new one in I'm not
going to give it any materials at the moment either.
That's deliberate and I'm going to set the size to 1000 1000 and the thickness not 200.
I'm just going to set it is 20 like everything else then I'm going to set its position to 0 0 and then
I think if we set it to 300 it'll mean the room is ever so slightly shorter than what we thought it
would be 3 meters because it would come down maybe 10.
But that is pretty good.
OK let's go ahead.
Save my level because I've been doing a lot of work there.
I'm going to click on build to make sure that all the lighting is built.
And of course we get our standard map lighting needs rebuilding.
Yep fine.
The geometry is now rebuilt the lighting is rebuilt and it should be pretty dark in here.
Now you will end up with a couple of issues when it comes to the corner here.
You can see that we've got almost looks like likely then we stare at it long enough the exposure settings
within here slowly bring it out is to try and give the fake illusion of eyes adjusting.
Now that's quite interesting you see because it does happen there and it doesn't happen in these corners.
It does happen slightly right down there.
Do you see that little bit appearing that I've just go straight through anyway.
So perhaps we can muck around with our geometry and make a line a little bit better.
But for the moment that's pretty well I want to say watertight but light tight now we can of course
add lights in and we'll be talking all about that in the next lecture.