Everyone, and welcome back in this lecture, we'll be seeing how we can implement dynamic delegates
to our projectile class.
This is an event that you can set to be called and respond to every time that this event is fired off.
Anything that we'll be listening to the event will then receive it and be able to take an action or
call their own function based on that event.
We can jump straight into this in our code, codifying in the constructor.
Just after we've created our projectile match, as this will be the component that will want to bind
to the existing function.
So to start, we do this by calling the function that we want to bind to on the projectile match, which
in this case will be the on component hit.
For every actor, class has sets of functions on them.
And one of those which is shared is the component hit function, which is registered.
Anytime a collision mesh on that class is registered.
This will be fired.
We don't want to assign at the ad dynamic binding.
With a context of this for the first argument and then our custom function that we want to be run whenever
the on component hit function is called.
So they are that dynamic is a macro that acts as a helper for calling the underscore internal underscore
a dynamic, which is the option will come up with the auto complete.
And also, we haven't created our own hit function yet, but we'll do that in just a moment.
So for now, we just kind of pre filling this in the knowledge we'll get to creating another function
very shortly before that we can dive into the on component hit function to finally function arguments
that it will be taking.
And I'm just going to.
Right.
Click on the function and select go to definition.
So now when we create our custom version of this and bind it to the delegates.
This works in a similar way to overwriting in a parent class function in that we still need to provide
all of the function arguments.
So we'll need all of these that we can see just here.
So if you have access to dive into the code files this way, then do feel free to copy them and use
them in a moment.
But to avoid mistakes as you need to be careful with which comma separate is left in.
I'll just go through one at the time and types of mike with you.
So back in the head of file in the private section, we want to make sure that this is a you function
as dynamic delegates needed to be declared as a you function within going to create our void function
named on a hit.
The first argument was the you primitive component pointer named hit component.
So the component which is being collided with then we have an act, a pointer named other actor.
So we've got the component which is being collided with and the other actor.
Which that component is hitting.
We then have a second that you primitive component pointer.
This time named other comp.
So this could be the specific component within the other actor that you've hit.
So, for instance, a lot of classes may be made up of kind of sub meshes or sub objects, and you can
find out exactly which components within the class you are colliding with.
And we want an effector named Normal Impulse.
And finally, a concert f hit result named Hit.
So these are two things which more to do with the force of which things being hit, the direction that
location can be returned from the hit results as well, as well as many, many other things.
But we're not going to need those levels of complexity.
But that argument still needs to be provided.
So if that were done, then use the C++ help to implement the new function.
And the first thing that we want to do in our own hit function is get a reference to the earning actor.
Which should be the porn that spawns the projectile, as we'll need this a little bit later.
We can do this by creating a temporary pointer to the actor class named my owner, which will be equal
to the return of the get owner function.
Next, we want to check.
This was successful and if not, then we can return straight from this function to avoid any errors.
So F isn't my own.
Then return.
If you've gotten past the stage, then we know that we have a valid reference to the owning porn.
And we can do some checks whether or not to apply damage to what we've just hit.
So first, we need to check that the other actor at this point is still valid.
And also that the other actor isn't equal to this just in case we have other nested components that
could also overlap a collision within the same class as our projectile.
And then finally checking that the other actor isn't equal to my partner just to avoid destroying the
porn that spawned the projectile.
So just a quick note, too, that all of this is available because of the declaration that we've made
in the porn based class.
When Spalding is saying that the site owner equals to this so that we're setting the owner to the actor
class.
That was.
I mean, I using that here, but I was all of those checks made with no narrowed down to confirm that
we've hit a valid actor that isn't ourselves or owning porn so we can now apply damage to whatever thing
we've just hit.
So we want to call the apply damage function, which is located in the U.
Gameplay Static's class.
So we'll just go back up and include that just above.
And of course, that's found in the Kismet Library.
Then back in the unhit function, we just want to use the game, play statics, apply damage.
So this is the first time that we've looked at these functions.
Let's dive into the definition of the function to see the arguments that this expecting.
So this function does exactly what you'd expect, given the name.
It hurts a specified actor or applies damage.
And the first arguments that we need are the damage actors.
So the other actor that we want to attempt to apply damage to, then we need to pass in a float for
the base amount of damage to be applied.
And then the next two arguments are quite interesting and can be somewhat confusing to begin.
So we have the event instigator, which is a type of a controller.
And then the damage causer, which is a type of a actor.
So the instigator is the being responsible for causing the damage.
And as this is a type of controller, this can be extended to the A.I. controlled porn as well as the
player controlled porn.
And this can be useful for checking things like the team or the legitimacy of damage to avoid things
like friendly fire and damage between different A.I. components or A.I. possessed classes.
Then the damage Coosa is the actual thing that caused the damage.
So as the comment shows here, this could be something like a grenade or in our case, that's going
to be the projectile itself.
And again, useful in cases that you might want to apply damage buffs or DB ups against grenades.
If a character has a grenade proof vest or something, then finally we have the damage type class,
which we have ready to describe the type of damage being applied.
Back in the projecto class, we can finish this function call by first providing the damage actor to
be the other actor that we're checking against.
The damage amount will be the value that we've already created named damage, and then to provide the
AI controller reference.
We know that the projectile won't have a controller as it's not a pawn is an actor class.
So instead we're going to reference the my own a variable and call the get instigate a controller function
that returns the controller of the given pawn.
It's the projectile hitting the other actor, causing the damage.
So the damage instigator will be a reference to this.
And then we've already set the damaged pipe in our editor, so we'll use our variable name to damage
type.
So quite a few things to fill in here, but we already had the reference to everything apart from the
controller.
So that wasn't too difficult.
And we'll be returning later to make the process look a little bit better regarding the gameplay.
So we'll just leave a comment in the section.
To that extent.
For now, though, we can finish off the function by cooling the destroy function to remove the projectile
from play.
And just to recap, this will be called every time at these static mesh component on hit function is
called or the on component hit function.
Sorry, but then able to use all of the arguments that function would take so that we have access to
things like the other actor, the hit results and other useful information.
And if we do a quick restart of the others and compile this, we can test some of this in action.
So after pressing play, if we go and fire some projectiles, we can see that they are all being destroyed
when they hit anything.
And this will stop a lot of these strange issues from occurring, like overlapping each other on spawn.
And just a quick visual recap whilst Walter in the editor.
If you're not familiar with the blueprints, the exact function of a binding two is just here in the
projectile blueprints.
So if we select the projectile match as that's the components function we've been binding to in C++,
we can scroll down to the collision section and we can see here the on component hit.
So this is a function that we can expose if we press the plus button and we can then see just how the
overrides that we've been using in our custom on the hit function in the projectile class.
So it was just a quick example of what we've been calling if you've been following along here.
Be sure to delete this note as we won't be running this in the graph.
We don't want this being classed as an override or forgetting to pass anything in here.