Hey and welcome to this lesson where we're going to start adding some replayability into TripleX.
Now currently when we play our game once it exits but by the end of this lesson we're going to be able
to continue playing after we complete the level.
So to get started with this we're going to be taking a look at a while loop.
It looks very similar to an if statement.
But here we are using the keyword while which is all lowercase.
And then we provide a condition within the parentheses just like how we do with an if statement.
But the difference here and the main idea behind the while loop is the compound statement we provide
will loop continuously while the condition is true.
So another way to think of this is that the code block will execute repeatedly until the condition is
not met.
For example if the condition is false.
Now we need to be careful here when working with while loops because you could end up in a situation
where you've unintentionally found yourself in an endless loop.
So there's something I want you to remember at any point while you are running your program you can
press control C to stop your program from running.
That we'll be taking a look at a situation where we need to do this shortly but we will fix this so
we won't have to kill the program again.
So right now I want you to pause here and implement a while loop into your main function and hard code
the condition as true for now and then add a code block for it that executes our play game function.
Then once you've done this we can continue and take a look at how this all works together
okay.
So I have implemented my while loop into my main function and I've hardcoded the condition as true to
repeat my play game function within this code block.
Now just to make it clear the while loop is going to start by executing play game our program will then
run through all of the code of play game.
And remember when we get to our cin line the program will pause and wait for input.
Then once the player enters the guess the program will continue running through the code of play game
and then once it gets to the end the while loop will call play game again and it will repeat every step.
Just as we've just seen.
So let's try this to save our work that's compile our code and let's run Triple X  .
The program runs if we enter the correct answer.
Notice that it repeats the game again.
But I have another issue here with regards to new lines.
My program is starting on the same line as the last string printed to the terminal to fix this.
I'm going to add the backslash and escape sequence at the start of our print introduction function where
we print our first string to the terminal.
But I'm also going to add another backslash end as well just to give it some more space.
Now if we press control C to stop our program from running because it's still waiting for input we can
break out the program.
We can compile our code again and then we can run Triple X and now if we enter two three four as the
correct answer we can see we have a bit more space between our messages here.
Another program repeats so I mentioned the endless loop.
This means that the code in our program will loop endlessly and there's no way it can stop and in some
cases it can cause our computer to crash and we can end up in an endless loop with Triple X.
If we end up using any character other than a number in the terminal.
So for example if I typed in 2 for X noticed that we've ended up in an endless loop.
So we want to press control C to jump out of this.
But let's add a real fix for this right now.
So this is happening because anytime whenever we call cin and then enter character other than a number
into the terminal it results in an error.
And any future attempts to call or use cin will fail and because we've used the while loop our play
game function just endlessly executes without pausing at our cin lines.
This is why we have the endless loop so to fix this.
We need to add some code in our while loop below our play game function.
We're not going to worry too much about the details we're going to add this line here.
That clears any errors in relation to input but we need to add another line too because if a player
enters a bad character it will still be left over in the input buffer.
Even after we clear the error away so we need to add this line here to to fix that.
I'm skipping over the details here because we're only going to need to do this once and we'll never
need to do this in Unreal.
But if you want to discuss these lines of code more in detail why not post in the community forum and
chat with your fellow students.
But for now I want you to pause here and look at these lines of code carefully.
Notice the periods here too and implement these lines into a while loop after play game is called
Okay
These lines of code fixed our endless loop issue.
Now if we save our work compile our code and run a Triple X and try entering any bad characters we can
see that the level just restarts and we can't go into this endless loop.
Even if we write Triple X here it still doesn't cause any endless loops.
Awesome stuff.
So remember we need to press control C to exit the program so we're going to switch gears now and take
a look at how we can make our play game function return some data.
Currently it returns no data.
That's why we use the keyword void.
But we wanted to return if the player has successfully completed the level, in order to do this.
We need to start working with booleans and we've technically already been using boolean.
So far we've been working with the conditions in our if statements and wild statements and we hardcoded
true or false and that's all a billion is is a value that is true or false.
Now before we take a look at our play game function we're going to start by declaring a new variable
in our while loop and this will be used to store if the player has completed the current level.
Remember when we declared our variables CodeA and GuessA variables like that they were integers.
But we're going to follow the same guidelines here.
We're going to start with a data type and for boolean we need to use a keyword bool, then we can enter
the variable name and we also want to conform to Unreal's coding standard here. In their documentation
they list that all boolean variable names must be prefixed with a lower case b.
So let's follow these guidelines and call our variable bLevelComplete and we're not going to initialize
this just yet.
So we can end this line with a semicolon.
Now I want you to change the type of data your play game function returns by changing the data type
for play game from void to bool.
So I want you to pause here to do this and then I want you to compile your code and see what happens.
Okay so I've changed the data type of play game from a void to bool.
Now if you've done this too you should notice that when you tried to compile the compiler tells us  that
there's an error, "play game must return a value."
Now remember that's our main function returns an integer so our play game function must return a boolean
and it must return a boolean that's every possible place where our function can end.
And in our play game function the function can end in two possible places it can end in over our if
or else statements.
So to return a boolean that tells us if the player has won the game or if they've completed the level
we can simply return true in our if statement.
And if the player has failed that level we can simply return false in our else statement.
Awesome.
So now our play game function handles playing our game and it returns.
If the player has completed the current level or not. So now because this function returns a boolean
we can initialize our level complete boolean variable with the results of our play game function.
So where we declare our variable bLevelComplete we can initialize it with the result of play game and
we can remove the line where we call play game just below. Amazing so we use the while loop to loop our
game and every time we play it it tells us if the player has completed that level or not and we'll go
to see why we're making our play game function return a boolean in the next lesson we'll be taking a
look at how we can increase the game's difficulty.
So when you're ready I'll see you in the next lesson.