Hello, everybody, and welcome back.
In this lecture, we're going to be able to play our game and it will give us some instructions on the
screen.
So we're gonna be able to write to our in-game terminal.
And not only that, if I click to use it press tab to enter the terminal, I just press enter to continue.
It clears the screen as well.
So we're starting to build the foundations of our in-game terminal.
Okay, so let's go ahead and just dissect what we have in front of us before we start adding our code.
At the very top, you'll see that we include the bull cow cartridge header file.
Now you can keep open the book cartridge pedophile if you want to.
I'm going to leave it there.
So when I switch between the two, I can just control and tab backwards and forwards between these two
files.
And that's gonna be more prominent later on when we start hopping between them.
Now, you may notice compared to our triple X game, we don't have a main function here.
And that's because Unreal handles that for us.
So in front of us here, we have two functions.
We have one called Biggin Play, and that will run when the game starts.
So this is where we could introduce the player to the game that we're playing.
We've then got another call here.
We want to leave this here.
Otherwise, our game will not work when we starts playing it.
So this is something we're going to leave here for everything else benefits and then our second function.
This is going to happen when the player hit sensors so they can type anything into the console.
But when they press enter, then whatever code we put within this function will execute.
So let us now type off first bits of code.
So on a new line underneath begin play.
Now, it really is important that your code goes underneath begin play.
If you don't put it under begin play, you will get weird errors.
What we want to do is print a line.
We're going to print a line to our terminal.
So if we start typing, you'll notice.
There we go.
It started auto filling.
The great thing about this is you can hit tab straightaway and it finishes off what we were typing.
Cause you have to be careful about this.
But this is a very quick way of auto completing your code.
But beware, when you're doing this, you may run into an issue where you end up auto completing something
you didn't want.
The next thing we need is a double brackets and then a semicolon to finish off at the end.
Now, print line currently has a red squiggle under it, if that's the case.
That's because at the moment we've not passed in a string.
Now this string happens to be empty, but it is accepted.
And we no longer have our red squiggles.
And what we can put here is Hiver, for instance.
Let's put an exclamation mark on the end.
Save our code.
Go over to the Unreal editor.
And before we do anything else, you're going to have to press.
Compile says, go ahead, hit, compile.
And that would take a few moments to do some here with a quick note from the future again.
I just want to say that in Visual Studio Code, sometimes you get false errors and they can look a little
bit like this.
However, if you go over into one reel and hit compile and there are no errors, that's absolutely fine.
That's just visual studio codes.
Intellisense and I put this in air quotes that is misfiring and telling you about errors that don't
really exist.
So always make sure you try, first of all, to hit the compile button before you investigate an error.
Once completes, we can play our game.
Now, I have seen a couple of bugs.
When we go ahead and play and now we go, it's worked.
I can see that straightaway.
It says hi there.
So the moment we've started playing our game and if we refer back to our code, begin play when the
game starts.
So the moment we press play, it's printing out.
So the user can see.
Hi there.
Occasionally I've had to press compile twice before it works.
That's just occasionally, but it is something to check.
Now, if we have a look at the next function on impact, we don't have any code there at the moment.
So if we go down to unreal and just click so well within the game, then press tab to access our in-game
terminal and then type something in and press enter.
Nothing happens.
That's what our code says.
And that was what we were expecting.
And that leads us nicely onto our challenge.
I'd like you to clear the terminal and do a few other things to welcome our player.
So, first of all, change our current high there to a Bull Cowl's welcome message, welcoming the player,
then print another line, asking the players, input something and press enter.
You can do that in one of two ways.
I'll leave you to figure out which way you're going to do it.
But again, there's no right or wrong when it comes to this.
And then finally in the on input function, cool, clear screen.
And what you will find is that then clears the terminal down.
Remember to save.
Remember to compile and then play your game.
Pause video now and give that a go.
Okay, everybody, welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and welcome the player to the game and then clear the screen after they've type something.
Kate, before I do anything else in here, I'm just going to stop the game from running.
There we go.
Let's go back over to our code.
So instead of saying hi there, we can say welcome to bull cows.
Now, we have a couple of options here.
We've got welcome to bull cows.
We could repeat this line like so and paste them in and then.
We can just change that to something else like press and to continue.
And then on the on input's function, we can clear screen so we can select it from there.
Remember, use semicolon at the end, otherwise our code won't run.
Notice that without it, by the way, we get a red squiggle.
And if we hover over it, it does tell us it expected a semicolon.
Now, as often is the case, it's not referring to line 14.
It's referring to line 13.
So we put a semicolon man on the end.
Absolutely fine.
Cause we're missing.
It's a function.
We also need our parentheses in there as well.
Let's go ahead, save that file and make sure it's working.
Over in into unreal click compile with our compile complete.
I'm gonna go Alton Pizza.
Play the game.
Welcome to Bull Cows.
Brilliant press.
Enter to continue.
That looks like it's working fine.
It's tapped to use the console and then we can type in anything.
Type in hello for instance.
And you'll notice that special characters like Exclamation Mark don't work on impulse.
But that's to say hello and brilliant.
It clears the screen.
In fact, that should work with anything.
So let's just go and play our game.
Click for mouse control press tab and then just press enter.
There we go.
It's clear the screen.
Perfect.
Now, before we go on, I just wanted to show you the other way that you could have done the code and
some of you might have done.
So we've got here press enter to continue.
Dot, dot, dot.
We could have popped it in like that.
And then this next one would print a new line.
Anyway, I'm just going to leave it there for the moment.
I'm going to save that.
Come back in and recompile when I go ahead and press play.
We get the same thing again.
Ah.
You see, it's got a gotcha in it straight away because there's a space between them.
If we have a look here in the code, there's a space just here that's included because it's literally
a space that's one of the characters within.
So you'd have to remove that to fix it.
Now, I don't like this type of code because much like your functions that you end up writing should
really only do one thing.
This print line function is doing two things.
It's both welcoming the player and giving them an instruction.
So my mind, it's much better to have these as separate functions.
This one's saying Welcome to Bull Cows is welcoming the player to the game.
This one is giving the player an instruction.
They're doing two separate things.
So they should be separate items are going to receive that's.
Go over into unreal.
Just stop the game, Mac, recompile it.
Make sure it works after changing things around.
And in general, I would very much recommend that when you made one change, especially early on, do
check that it's working as you'd expect it to.
After that one change, rather than trying to do a lot at once.
And there we go.
That's working exactly how I'd expect it to.
How are you guys getting on?
Did your code execute first time, just as you expected it to?
Or did you come across any Niko's.
Please share your discoveries over on the forum and I'll see you all in the next lecture.