Everyone, welcome back.
In this lecture, we'll be creating our health component, which will be a flexible class, allowing
us to record health undamaged for any actor or pawn that we place in the world, whilst will only be
applying this to our own classes for this game.
Something like our health component would be great for recording damage to props around the world.
If you wanted to align things like Biros Kraatz vehicles, all of those to take damage before exploding
or reacting in some way.
So before we create our health components, I just wanted to cover the difference between the actor
components and the sync components, as we've now been using both of these throughout the project.
And I know that you've already worked a lot with the Grabow actor component in the previous section.
So I've created two new blueprint classes between the lectures just to kind of visualize a few of the
concepts so you won't need these to follow along.
And I'll be removing them as soon as this example is over.
So I have my BP underscore scene and BP underscore actor for the class and the actor components respectively
inside of the pawn tank.
I've added both of these in the components section and we can see here that the BP underscore scene
is showing up here with many of the other components that we already have.
Whilst the BP underscore actor is kind of done here by itself and kind of lonely.
So both of these class types are very similar and that they can both be placed on actors, as we can
see here.
And the main difference is that the scene component is up in the top section and has a transform, meaning
that it can be moved around in the world and attached to other scene components, whereas the actor
component can be attached to only an actor and not other components.
And it also has no transform or representation or place in the world.
So if we take a quick look in the content browser and create a new blueprint, look for something like
these static mesh components as this is something we've already used in our classes.
And we can again take another look in to some of the inheritance and see that many of the components
that we are already using are just a child class of the same component type, which itself is a child
of the actor component.
So again, we can just see that all this really happening here is the sync component is inheriting everything
that the actor component has, such as being able to be placed on other actors in classes, and then
it's getting some of his own functionality, such as the recognition of world transforms and things
as part of its own class.
So with all of that information fresh in mind, your challenge is to use what I've already described
and consider which class would work best for our new health component.
If you don't already have an answer in mind.
Pause the video here and take a look at the class descriptions to see if that will help.
Okay, so the main thing that would be the deciding point here is that we would have very few arguments
that could be made for the health component to need a place in the world.
We're not going to be attaching this to the player's hand, for example.
We're not going to be placing this on other components.
So in this instance, I think it's going to make sense to make this a reusable, active component.
So choose to create a new C++ class and search for the active component type.
Nameless, one health component's.
And place it in a new folder named Component's.
As always, when that's open, we'll take our usual steps of removing the tick event as we're not going
to need this to update constantly over time.
And we'll take the second public section with it.
Then create a private section and create two float variables, one named default health, which are
set to one hundred and one named health, that I'll default to zero.
Then the default health will need a new property with the editor anywhere with you property complete,
the health variable will be updated purely in C++ and set based on the default health.
So we shouldn't need this to be exposed or have any new properties here.
And the final variable that we need is the reference to the game mode that we'll be using to pass a
message along later.
If the owner's health is lowered to zero, so we'll create a pointer to the A tank game mode base and
we'll name this one game mode ref.
And then, of course, at the top of this head, a fight we just need to include a full declaration
to this class by using Class A tank game mode base.
So to finish our declarations, we want to create a new protected function of type, avoid name to take
damage.
This will be another function that will be binding to an existing function in the class.
And this will be the any damage event on the owning pawn.
So for that reason, we're going to need the overwrites very similar to what we did with the on hit
function we created previously.
These overwrites are all very similar.
So I have these ready as they're all kind of similar types to the unhit overrides.
And again, these kind of explain themselves and what they do in the naming.
So we're going to need an active pointer named damage actor.
So the actor which is being damaged then will need a flight variable named damage.
So the amount of damage being passed into them followed by a contest.
You damage type.
Again, this will be a pointer.
And this one is named damage type.
So the type of damage being used.
Then a controller pointer named instigated by.
And then finally, another act pointer named damage caused.
So, again, very similar.
The overall instigator.
So the possessed porn or controller that was responsible for sending the damage and then the specific
actor which is causing the damage.
And again, because this is going to be a delegate.
We need to add a you function above this.
Then to finish getting this class ready, I'll take the usual steps to implement the function.
Then I'll delete the tech function and make sure to set the kind of a tech to be false.
As mentioned, we won't be using the tech functionality in this class as it will be another class,
which is kind of completely reactive to functions being called on it or those which has been assigned
to by the bindings with all of that done.
We have our class set up and ready to implement its new functionality.
We have quite a bit to do in this class.
I think we should have everything ready to implement the whole class in the next lecture without leaving
all of the comments to come back to.