Hello and welcome in this lecture, we're gonna be looking at spawning a muzzle flash so that when we
hit the trigger, we get a particle effect.
So let's dive in and see how we can do this.
From C++.
K. So we want some particle effects to spawn from the muzzle of a gun.
What's gonna be the best way to do this?
We are going to, first of all, have a look at what particle effects we've got available here.
I've taken the ones from the shoot a game.
Obviously, you can use any particle effects that you want.
You can find them on the asset store.
You can take them from example projects like I have ones go into the effects session asset packs, shoot
game effects and then look at particle systems, weapons, assault rifle.
And I'm looking for the muzzle one, at least initially.
And we want this assault rifle, M.F. and you should be able to see it's going to take a little bit
of time to get the shaders in here compiling.
But this is what essentially the muzzle flash looks like.
It looks like a muzzle flash.
So that's what we're going to be using and we're going to try and spawn this in C++ when we have the
trigger pulled.
So let's go over into our gun.
I'm gonna go to the guns GPP and instead of this log message of having been shot.
Not particularly useful.
We want to spawn a particle effect.
And to do this, we're going to be using a function from the gameplay static's dot h.
So let's go over to the gameplay static's dot h and have a look in here.
We want to spawn an emitter calling it spawner and emitter and you will see if we have a look at this.
That's what it is taking in is a world context object.
It's taking in a particle system which is the emitter template, as they're calling it, the location
rotation scale, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Or alternatively, I think you can make it attached so we can do a spawn emitter attached.
And this is going to try and attach it to a component so we can see that this takes in a scene component
to attach to.
Now, in this case, I think this is what we wanted.
Depends on the particle effect in question, but some particle effects are going to keep spawning particles
for a duration of time.
So you want those particles to keep coming out of the muzzle of the gun as the gun moves.
They might be creating some smoke, some stuff like that if you move your gun while you're shooting.
You want the particle effect to move with it.
So that's what we're going to be using.
Is this spawn emitter attached?
And as it says here, it's going to take in the emitter template and the scene components that we need
to attach to.
So those are the things that we most are going to be needing.
It also has this attach point name that's gonna be a socket.
So that's actually quite handy for us to know that we can attach it directly to the muzzle of a gun.
We don't need any kind of offsets.
So let's have a look at that if I go and open up my BP rifle.
We already know we've mentioned that this is a skeletal mesh.
So I'm going to go and find that rifle in the content browser and open up the rifle mesh.
And what you'll see over in the left, if you have the skeleton tree pain visible, then you're going
to see that we've got this rifle roots.
We've got the rifle magazine, which presumably can be swapped out or something, but we don't particularly
interested in that.
And then there's this muzzle flash socket.
So that's where we're going to spawn our muzzle flash.
If it didn't have or your mesh doesn't have this, then you can go ahead and add one, because we can
always add sockets in the way we've seen in previous lectures.
So let's have a go at spawning this.
The first thing we're going to need is one of these particle system references.
And the best way to do that, again, the best way that I know how is to create a new property and do
it in blueprint.
There are other ways you can do it by named references.
But I really don't like using named references.
They break easily if you rename stuff so much easier to do it in Blueprint where all of that is handled
for you.
Gonna make this a you property edit defaults or actually this could be edit anywhere.
Why?
Because if we were to change this during game play, which you might want to do if you're trying to
tweak things and say, well let's does this particle fact look better than this one, then this would
actually work.
The next time you shoot, a different particle effect would be created.
And then the type of this needs to be a new particle system pointer, which we're going to call our
muzzle flash like that.
And that's what we're going to be setting up over in blueprint's.
And let's go back in to our pull trigger method in the C++.
And we want to call it that you game play static's function.
So you game play Static's notes.
It's Knokke auto in here because I need hash include for this by hover over that game play static's.
You can see that it's under Engin classes kismet game play static.
So all we need to do is kismet game play, statics, dot h.
And we should have you game play static's to auto complete from.
And we want to spawn.
And this may or may not work because of the version that I'm in, in.
Unreal.
We want to spawn the ammeter attached.
And we want this muzzle flash right here.
And we want to attach it to a scene components in this case, we want to attach it to ag guns mesh and
we want to attach it to the appropriate sockets, which, again, I'll let you fill out is the if we
go over to the gun is the muzzle flash socket.
I'm going to copy it from there directly and just put a semicolon on the end of the line to top it off.
So this should work.
Let's go over and hit compile in the engine.
And once that's finished compiling, we can go over into our BP underscore rifle opened the full blueprint,
Ed..
I just prefer to deal with that and look at our let's see if we go to the root.
In fact, the actor itself or the class defaults, go to the details.
Pain.
You can see we've got this muzzle flash property, the new one, and we need to find a particle effect
in here.
I'm going to look for the key word muzzle.
Let's see.
Maybe muzzle was not the one we looking for.
It's assault rifle, M.F..
I think so.
Muzzle flashes that.
What is standing for, sir?
Assault rifle, M.F..
That's the one we want.
Compile and save that and we'll go over into our sandbox and play and see if shooting indeed launches
up our muzzle flash.
And you can see that it is continuously shooting at the moment.
So we do want it to just be a single muzzle flash.
So I think I'll actually choose a different muzzle flash.
I think I'll use the one from the Wraith asset pack, which we've got sniper and primary.
I'm going to choose the primary just because I am not wanted.
Create a rapid fire weapon.
That's a slightly different way of doing things.
Not not massively different.
Just more of a kind of once you're holding, you start the emitter and once you are finished with it,
you you want to close it down.
In our case, we've just won a launch that ammeter one time.
So we're going to do l.p again and see if we.
There we go.
Now we shoot.
We get a single flash of the muzzle.
And if everything is hunky dory, it seems to be attached nicely to the end of the gun as well.
As I move around, wherever I move around, whichever way I face the muzzle flashes in the right direction.
Cool.
Well, this is really starting to look more like a shooter game with particle effects.
So in the next lecture, we're gonna look at the first steps of ray tracing, which he'll be actually
to go and reach up to our character owner for some information.
I will see their.