Okay, everybody, welcome over into Unreal.
Now, a couple of things that I want to do before we get started.
Just having a look at my hierarchy, the world outliner over here.
I'd like to just name these things here a bit more appropriately.
So we got down like two and down like three.
Well, actually, this would also be down like two in this particular case.
It's good that we can name the same thing.
Therefore, we know they're part of the same object.
Now, I'm also going to rename my folder here and set it down lights down lights because it contains
both of them.
I'm just going to minimize the building.
There we go.
Awesome.
I don't think I'm gonna add any more to the building for the moment, but what we do need to add is
potentially another component.
Now, when you're adding test code to your scene and you're working on, let's say, a component that
you've already got in the world, like the world position, there's no harm in just adding a bit of
code to that and just seeing whether or not it works.
However, in this particular case, we've got something that does something distinctly different and
we know we're definitely going to need it.
So let's select hold door, go and add a component.
It's gonna be a new C++ component and it's gonna be an active component on the actor.
We're gonna call this open door and let's go ahead and click create class.
Now, there is something we need to consider when we are going to move something in our scene.
All of these static measures have an option on them.
And this is incredibly important.
If we don't go ahead and set it, you're gonna run into problems.
Your code will work perfectly, but you won't be able to see anything.
So let's make sure we've got our doors selected.
So we're looking at the static mesh components of our door that have also just clicked on that.
And let's bring this area up here so we can see just a little bit more.
And we've got three options under the transform section.
We've under mobility.
We've got static, stationary and movable.
Now, if we leave our door a static, it doesn't matter what we do.
No amount of code will move it.
And what we need it to be is a movable object.
Okay, so let's go ahead and set this back from movable to static for a moment and get the lights coming
through.
So I'm going to rotate my door, make sure it's selected and just rotate it.
This is what we're gonna be doing, encode in the moment and it will just snap to a particular value.
And let's go to our world direction or lights.
Here we go.
The light source.
And I believe I need to tweak the Y value and the Z value.
There we go.
So that's a there.
See if I can get our longer shadow.
There we go.
So it's really coming into the doorway.
Now I'm going to shut my door again.
Here we go.
And it looks pretty good there, doesn't it?
But at some point, we're going to need to bake our lighting again.
So let's go and just bake the lighting only.
So it's nice and quick.
Okay.
Now let's see what happens.
Oh, well, that's a that's a bit rubbish there, isn't it?
We have a look.
So it's it took a while, that update, but here we've got the light on the floor.
Looks good so far.
But when we open it, we kind of have a dynamic light there as well.
And we've got this shadow that shouldn't exist.
So this is something we don't want.
And this is an example of why we need to set this static mesh here too movable.
However, when we set, it's a movable.
It will update the rendering engine as well.
In that case, we're gonna have to build our lighting again as well.
And there we go.
Got a much better shape coming through Real-Time lighting like this is far more expensive.
And we can see here we've got a couple of issues with the lighting.
Again, that's something that you can sort out later on in when you start tweaking things.
But for a moment, that is good enough for our test purposes.
So let's make sure the door is actually shut.
Zero.
And I want to draw your attention to the rotation values if we hover over X, Y and Z.
We can see they've got different names roll.
Pitch.
And your.
And that's what we're going to be editing in code.
Now, the reason why I'm just bringing that up is not only the names, but they won't necessarily be
in the order X, Y, Z.
When we come to coding it, that's something to bear in mind.
It's very easy to think that.
Oh, Z.
Well, that's the last value in the three, so I just need to alter that.
Now you do have to pay attention because it won't always be in that order.
In the code.
So let's go ahead.
I'm going to right click on my open door component and open open door header file and oh, it's just
opened up on another screen.
Let's bring that down.
Ready to edit.
This is typically where we could add our members, our member variables, any functions that we're going
to use in this particular case.
I don't think we're gonna have anything just at the moment, but later on we will do.
So let's go straight over to the implementation.
Now, we can put everything at the moment in Biggin Place.
So when we click play, what will happen is the door rotate instantly to 90 degrees, hopefully, and
in which case I should also pre-war knew at this point.
Notice here that the door value, it's your value is already zero.
If you happen to have constructed your room and the door is already at 90 degrees or minus 90 degrees
is not really going to do anything.
It's just gonna flip around and stick at this angle.
In fact, what I would do here is I'm just gonna shut the door back up and then I'm going to take a
duplicate of the door and the door frame for reference ALZ drag popper over here.
I'm gonna rotate these by 90 degrees.
There we go.
And we'll see that when we execute our code.
When we press play that this storm will move.
This door won't just to highlight the issue going on there.
And that's something we'll fix up in an upcoming lecture.
Let's go back over to the code.
So we're about to use something called float's.
This will be the first time that we've used any floats.
And the way that we would declare it is with the keyword float.
Then we'd give it a name.
So my float in this particular case.
And then we would initialize it was some value.
Now, unreal is quite clever.
And it will do some implicit conversion.
So if you were to just type in 10 and leave it like that, that would work.
It would implicitly convert the integer 10 to a float.
If you were to go ten point zero, that's what's called a double, and it would again implicitly convert
it from that double into a float.
And if we put the F on the end, we are literally saying to the engine.
This is a float.
And you've got two ways in which you can write your float.
You can write it with the decimal place in there that you're working to.
So if it was ten point five.
Like so.
But if you had it just at 10, you wouldn't have to have the zero.
There you could also leave it like that.
So when we're talking about 90 degrees, we could actually set it like so and we're saying this is a
float, not an implicit conversions from any other number.
So we're being very specific there.
And whether or not you include that zero, there is entirely up to your code style.
You will look through the unreal docs and you'll see a lot of the time it's written like that.
However, if you're looking online, you may find someone has a code style that includes the zero there.
I think that I'm going to remove the zero not only for speed of typing, but also it matches the unreeled
box and I want to stay as close to those as possible.
We'll come back to that in a moment.
Now, we're we already know how we can go ahead and get an actor's location.
So if we try, let's say, gets actor rotation.
I've seen that as we've gone through before.
So we can get owner.
That's absolutely fine.
Now nothing's happening.
Oh, dear.
Can you remember why?
Yes, you're probably correct.
We've not included what we need to use.
So let's go to the top of our file here and hash include.
What do we need to include?
Well, it's going to be the game framework.
Forward slash actor, the H.
Okay, so now that that's included, what we should find is the Arrow operator.
She comes out here so we could get the actor location attorney on rotation.
There we go.
So this here.
What is it.
What is this.
Returning we hover over is going to give us an F rotator.
Okay, let's go over to the docs and have a look at how an F rotator is constructed.
Okay.
So here we go over in the F rotator in the documents that scroll down F rotator.
And here we go.
This is the struts that contains the pitch, yaw and roll.
We can see there a float, which is awesome.
And look, it's not in the order X, Y, Z is in the order.
If I remember correctly, Y is pitch.
Let's go have a look.
Hover over.
X is roll.
Why is pitch.
Z is your.
Okay.
So this starts Y, Z and then X.
So you do have to pay attention to how that's constructed.
OK, so we know that get at a rotation is going to return an F rotator.
And currently line 26 is just throwing that value away.
So let's store it somewhere.
Let's go and f rotate.
So I'm going to give myself a space there so it auto completes for me f rotates and I'm gonna call it
currents rotation because that's what it will be and we'll set it to whatever this returns.
And what we could do here is we could go current rotation dot.
Here we go.
We've got your if we scroll up roll impact.
So we're able to access the members of that struct, which is really useful.
Now, this is just all about getting the active rotation.
What we really want to do is set the active rotation.
So if we go ahead and went get owner, let's make sure this is available to us.
We'll get owner Brackett's arrow operator as Triceps Act rotation.
Here we go.
Awesome.
Now, what is that expecting?
So what is set at active rotation?
Expecting to be put into it.
Let's go have a look at the docs for set to rotation.
OK.
So over in the dots, we can see here, there are two types of construction.
It will be an F rotator or a quick Ternium on, which is another type of rotations, which I'm sure
will cover later on in the course.
So it's expecting F rotator to be put in there.
Okay.
So, for instance, here, we've already got an F rotator we can put in so we can put in our current
rotation.
Now, obviously, that's going to set it to what it currently is.
And your challenge will be to open it by 90 degrees.
OK, so your challenge is to get the door to open using code.
So create an F rotator with a your value of either 90 or minus 90 degrees.
And then once you've created that F rotator parser into the sect actor rotation in order to rotate our
door or anything, in fact, that we put those components on by even 90 or minus 90 degrees, possibly
an hour.
And give that a go.
Okay, everybody, welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and create our F rotator that will open up our door.
So there are a couple of ways in which we could do this.
We could go ahead and modify the value of the current rotation.
So if we come into here and get the current rotation dots your.
Let's spell that correctly, otherwise it won't work.
And we could change it to ninety point F.
And then we can pass the current rotation back in another way that you could potentially do this is
you could declare a new F rotator and initialize it at the same time so we could have an F rotator open
door, for instance, and then we could give it some value straight away.
Now, I have put an equal sign here, but it isn't actually necessary.
So I would open up our curly braces.
Now, if you have admitted that the equals sign here, you could just as easily use parentheses instead
of curly braces.
And we could go zero point F comma.
And here we go is is helping us here.
This is where we need our ninety point F comma and then zero point F again, because we don't need it
rotating elsewhere.
Okay, so we've constructed it.
Awesome.
Now let's see if the current rotation works.
And then we can swap out open door.
Now, we're not using this at the moment, so I will comment out that line and we're not using my floats
at all.
That was just an example.
Let's save our code, compile and see what happens.
OK, so I'll compile is complete.
Let's go ahead and press play.
And the door is open and noticed this door hasn't moved at all.
And the reason for that?
Well, with setting an absolute value of snapping the door instantly to a particular value.
Okay, so let's go back into our code and see if the other way of working it would be.
So efforts to open door.
And this is being explicit, but it is hard coding a value in.
So we might wants to be able to later on edit that.
That's something to bear in mind here, that these are hard coded values that the user can't change
very easily.
But we can change that later on.
So let's remove the current rotation from there.
Is this doing anything?
No, it's not doing anything.
In this instance and here we can pop in open door instead.
Let's go and save our work.
Back over into unreal hit compile.
With the compiler complete, let's hit play.
Now, I can already see that the doors open because of the shadow.
Excellent.
So there you go.
There are two different ways that you could accomplish this particular challenge.
One final thing I'm going to do here.
I'm going to have a look at my place starts and I keep wanting to look at that door, don't sigh.
So let's go ahead and move it.
Let's rotate it round so faces the door.
That looks good to me.
And we might want to just shift it back ever so slightly as well.
Hey, when we press play.
Yes.
Brilliant.
That's exactly what I wants to see.
And we've got some lighting to bridge be rebuilt here.
Now, I'm over the top at the moment.
I would say with my building of lighting by wants to do that's currently just to make sure that everything
is right in my scene.
Now, on a larger level, this can take tens of minutes to do so.
You don't necessarily want to overzealously click the build button all the time with a small level like
this when we're learning what our changes are doing.
It's a good idea, just like it's a good idea to compile our code on very small steps is a good idea
to do our lighting as well to make sure that what we're working on is what we expect it to look like
as well.
So that's it for this lecture.
We've got our doors snapping open to 90 degrees.
We've got an issue that it is just opening to 90 degrees, which means if we put any other doors in
our world at anything other than 90 zero degrees starting, they're not going to behave how we'd expect
them to.
And, of course, we'll sort that out in the lectures to come, and I'll see you all in the next lecture.