In this lecture, we'll continue from where we were in the health component and implement its functionality.
So first and the begin play, we want to set the current health value to be equal to the default health.
That's why we've exposed the default health value to the editor.
We can easily update this, test the values there, and it will be updated whenever we start the game
for easy testing.
We'll also need a reference to the tank game mode based class, as well as the use of some of the gameplay
static's functionalities at the top of the class.
That's going to include the tune tanks.
Tank game mode based on age and then the kismet.
Forward slash gameplay static's at thought age.
Then back into Biggin play function.
We want to fill our game mode RF variable, which will be equal to a cast of type a tank game mode base.
And this will use the You game play static's.
So, of course, this is getting the context of the current world and finding the current active game
mode in that world, cast that back to our A tank game mode base just to make sure we have a valid reference.
We can use this later.
Then we'll be using.
I would get ONA function to return a reference to the owning actor and we'll bind our take damage function
to the Ontake.
Any damage function in the same way that we did with our hit functionality previously in the projectile
class.
So to check the understanding of binding functions in C++.
Here's a quick challenge.
Will you use the Ontake any damage function in the owner reference to create a dynamic binding for our
take damage function?
If you get stuck here, take a look at the projectile class for a refresher as the syntax will be the
same.
Just swapping out the relevant functions.
Okay, so let's check that we have this implemented as intended.
I've already provided the first two steps, which is to use the only reference and use the on take any
damage function.
The next big headstart as we're using a dynamic binding.
So we'll use the dot at dynamic and then similar to our projectile implementation.
We're passing in the reference to this and binding the function to the address of our U.
Health component.
And the function take damage and that's it.
So now whenever the on take any damage function is called on our earning actor, the function in our
health component will also be called, which will be the take damage.
The final steps will be to implement.
I would take damage, functionality.
And this is going to be very simple, but I kind of love the simple flexibility of something like this.
And again, going back to the context of creating this for a small game injury, it will be the use
of components like this that really help speed up the development in a short period of time.
And that really allow you to get the most out of the time spent in the gym, as we'll see in just a
moment.
So the first thing that we want to do in our new function here is check the damage value being passed
in isn't equal to zero just because if that is the result, you're guessing there's likely an era of
input, meaning that we probably don't want to do anything here.
I've also chosen here to check that it isn't zero, rather than checking that it's more than zero,
as this will also allow us to extend this to use it as a kind of add health functionality rather than
just taking health away by passing in a negative value.
Which again, is going to be perfect.
If you wanted to add some kind of health, pickup's to your game later.
So the next if a non zero value is Pastan, we're going to set the health to its new value using the
F math clump function to clump the health to B the current health, minus the damage clumped between
zero point zero F and the default health value that we have.
So this is just to ensure that we cannot drop below zero or cheat the system and get above the default
or maximum health cap.
Also note that we need to specify has the point zero f to specify this as a flight value.
If we tried passing in an argument as just zero, we'd get an error that the F math could not deduce
the template argument of an integer type.
Okay.
So we now have our updated health value.
So all that's left to do is check if our owner is still alive.
So if the health is less than or equal to zero, then we can check that we have a valid reference to
our game mode.
If we do that, we want to cool the game mode ref actor died function.
And passing our owner as the argument that we have here.
Then in an EL statement, if we don't have a valid gay made reference, we're just going to create a
temporary log of type borning and print that we don't have a valid game reference in our health component.
And just a small recap here over a little bit of what's happening.
We're just checking that the health is less than or equal to zero.
Even though just above we have clumped this to be a minimum of zero for the health value.
This is partly out of kind of programming.
How about, I suppose, but also if something changes in the code above later on in development, it
will be nice to know just here that even F.T. Health does fall below zero.
That scenario will also be accounted for, captured and classed as a death state.
And this is just to account for things like other developers joining the team, maybe needing to change
something here and not quite looking through all of the code and accounting for that clump.
Removing it for whatever reason and then having things like that, like I said, not being captured
in this if statement.
Next, the keynote amongst you may have noticed we're not passing anything to our owner actor to let
them know that they've died, and that's purely due to the complexity of our game.
So we know we'll only be using this on two of the pawn types and both of them are kind of relevant to
the game flow via the game mode class.
So rather than passing off most Promesse, just once the game mode and one to the pawn classes, we
can just use our override here of the owner.
Let the game mode know that something has happened and one of the pawn classes was destroyed and then
a lighter game mode to process the results accordingly.
If you did want to expand this to things like having the props have health components, then you can
use the same kind of implementation to cool some sort of destroy function on the prop to play act,
the kind of effects relating to that destruction.
And then one final thing that we could do is return to our game mode class and just copy in another
under a log.
And change the text to something like a porn dyed.
If we then go back and compile this in the editor, we should be able to see all of this working.
So we'll be returning to the game mode a little bit later to implement the full functionality.
But this will at least now, at last, a test that things are registering damage are accounting for
the house.
Because if we remember back in the projecto class, we are already calling the applied damage function,
which will fire the any damage function on our POUM.
So the connection for applying and receiving damage is already in place.
So back in the ed, I have that compiled and we can go and see if we are getting our expected output
logs to make those tests, one that has finished compiling will first need to go to both of our classes,
the tank and the turret classes.
Navigate to the component section and add a new health component to them.
Be sure to check that the default health has a value assigned to it.
And with that done for both of the classes, we can then go and Pressplay and check the output log to
see the game mode updating when a pawn has its health drop below zero.
And that began.
We can see this is a working and printing.
The new log is firing a little bit more than it should because we currently don't have a check for whether
or not the pawn is ready dead.
So we can go back and we can pretty quickly fix this.
So what we're going to do is just her and the statement will add and or check to the end of this f check
to check if the health is less than or equal to zero, because, again, we can then be sure that we
won't be calling this function on anything which would be classed as a dead actor.
So we can compile this again and just double-Check that the message is only being called once purple.
So we can see that is triggering as expected.
It will stop once both of the Poons have had this function called once.
And set the health to anything zero or or less.
So we cannot be sure that we won't have any kind of strange things happening in the future, like pawns
being blown up or playing the death effects more than once if multiple projectiles hit too soon before
that removed.
So we now have our projectiles and our health system linked up and working so we can start going back
through and getting more of the gamefly in place.