Hey and welcome to this lesson where we are going to learn about function parameters.
So in the previous lesson we declared a boolean variable inside our while loop to store if the player
has successfully completed the level or not when they play the game.
Now why are we doing this.
What's the benefit here.
Well let's take a look.
Let's add a couple of new lines at the bottom of the while loop and let's write an if statement and I want
to show you a little trick here.
If you type if and press tab Visual Studio code will insert the rest of the statement for you ready
for you to enter the condition right away.
So remember a boolean is a true or false value so we can actually use our blevelComplete variable here
as the condition so we can just write the variable name which is blevelComplete and we can hit TAB
to start writing our code.
So just to refresh this here our while loop will now execute play game and store.
If the player completed the level inside our level complete variable we then fix any errors in regards
to input but now of this if statement we can check to see if the player completed the level if they
did we will want to increase the level difficulty before all the code loops again in the while loop.
So for now let's just leave a comment here to remind ourselves that we want to increase the level difficulty.
Now there's different ways that we can write some of our code and it will still have the same effect.
We can see that the code block for our if statement has its curly brace { starting next to the condition
that still works and sometimes you will see code written this way but most of the time in Unreal you'll
see it the way that we've been writing our code so far with the code block directly below this line.
And one thing to remember is that we don't need to put a semicolon ; after we provide the condition which
is usually a common mistake.
Okay.
Now we're going to go ahead and declare a variable that we can use as the level difficulty.
We're going to do this outside the while loop because we don't want to declare and initialize the variable
for each iteration of the while loop.
So let's insert a new line at the start of our main function and let's declare a new int variable
named LevelDifficulty and let's initialize it with the value of 1 okay so now we have a variable
that we can use for our level difficulty.
We want Triple X to become more difficult with each level.
If the player completes the level we then want to increase the level difficulty so let's remove this
comment.
And let's take a look at how we can increase our level difficulty variable to increase the difficulty
we can increment the variable by typing the plus symbol twice ++ and then we can type the variable name
LevelDiffculty and we can finish the line with a semicolon ;
So this is simply the same as saying take the value of level difficulty and increase it by 1.
So if we were playing the game and we were on level 4 and we completed the level we would increase it
by 1.
To state that we've made it to Level 5.
Okay so now if the player completes the level our level difficulty will increase.
So wouldn't it be cool if we printed the level difficulty in our introduction messages.
Well let's take a look at doing this.
Now I want to insert the level difficulty into my message just here.
So I'm just going to move the rest of my string here into the next string below just to give us a bit
more space on this line here and then we can output the value of our variable LevelDifficulty
Now let's save our work and let's compile our code.
Notice that we now get an error.
The compiler tells us that it doesn't know what level difficulty is even though we've declared it inside
our main function here.
This is because our level difficulty variable only has scope within the main function.
A variable declared inside a code block has scope.
So this could be applied to a variable inside a function or inside a code block for an if statement
or a while loop
For example a variable declared in a code block is local to where it's declared.
And this means that it cannot be accessed or used outside of its scope.
This is what I mean when I say this variable has scoped the main function.
It can't be used in any of our other functions.
So we need a way to pass our level difficulty variable from our main function into our print introduction
function.
So in order to do this we're going to be taking our first look at using parameters in our functions
creating parameters allows us to pass values into our functions.
We can create parameters within the parentheses ( ) of where we've defined our function so to create a parameter
for print introduction we first need to provide that data type which is going to be an int and we
can also name the parameter lessening the parameter difficulty so we can see here that is kind of similar
to declaring a variable and it kind of works like a local variable too instead of trying to print the
level difficulty variable from our main function to the terminal which we can't access.
We can now print the value of the parameter for our print introduction function.
We just need to type the name of the parameter just like we do with a variable.
So we're just gonna type <<Difficulty;
And I've just noticed that this should say you are a secret agent.
Breaking into a level and then a space then we print the difficulty.
So I'm just gonna type in level here and a space and we should also start the rest of a message with
a space to so now when we tried to compile our code.
The compiler is telling us that there is an error on line eleven print introduction does not take zero
arguments so this is telling us that we now need to pass a value into our PrintIntroduction( ); function
also known as passing an argument.
We do this within the parentheses so the value is an integer and we could just hard code any number
in here for now.
I'm just gonna use seven and now if we compile our code we no longer get an error.
And if we run our program now it now says you are a secret agent breaking into a level seven secure
server room cool so we're getting somewhere now but we want this to print the value of our level difficulty
variable from our main function.
So to do this we need to pass the variable into the PlayGame( ) function as an argument and then from
the PlayGame( ) function into our prints.
Introduction just where we've provided the seven here.
So I want you to do this next step.
Pause here and create a parameter for your PlayGame( ) function that is also an integer with the name
of difficulty.
Just like how we've done with print introduction
okay see your prints.
Introduction function should now have a parameter that is an int named Difficulty.
And your PlayGame function should have one too.
Now instead of passing the value of seven as an argument into your print introduction function we can
now pass the value of the play game difficulty parameter.
We can just remove 7 and replace it with the name of Difficulty.
So we're now feeding our Difficulty parameter from PlayGame( ) in as an argument into print introduction
and we can even see this when we click on Difficulty because it's highlighted.
Now let's try compiling and we could see that we get an error again and this time is telling us that
there's an error on line 51 and it is telling us that we need to pass an argument into PlayGame( ).
So remember we need to pass an int into here but instead of just passing a random value we can now
pass our LevelDifficulty variables straight into this.
So let's just type.
LevelDifficulty.
So just to clear up what's going on here we've declared LevelDifficulty.
We pass it into play game and then play game passes it into print introduction and then print introduction
prints the value out okay.
So now if we save our work and compile our code
and run our program we can now see it says you are a secret agent.
Breaking into a level one secure server room because the value of our LevelDifficulty is one.
Now if we enter the correct answer notice it now says we are breaking into a level two secure server
room.
This is because we increment the level difficulty if we complete the level.
So if we don't completely level the level doesn't change and it restarts and if we complete it again
it increases.
So if the player completes a level then we increase the level difficulty or service so we're almost
there with our TripleX game now.
We need to start looking into actually randomizing our code and making it harder with each level.
We also might want to add a maximum number of levels.
So we're good to start covering this over the next couple of lessons.
So when you're ready I'll see you in the next one.