Hello everybody and welcome.
In this section we're going to be creating a terminal based game called bulls and cows.
So let's go ahead and introduce the project.
The important thing here is we understand the game that we're going to create.
So we're all on a level playing field as we start during the creation of course.
If you want to take this off on your own direction.
Brilliant.
Go ahead do that.
Now it is a terminal game similar to the last one we created.
But this time is within Unreal which allows us to use Unreal specific C++.
Now this is important as we dive into Unreal.
We'll start to see that some of the syntax you need to use is slightly different from just regular C++.
OK.
So how does the game work.
It's a word guessing game but in order to make this an easier word guessing game is going to be guessed
the isogram an isogram is simply any word that doesn't have any repeating letters that limits
our selection of words and also enables us to give a bull or a cow.
What are those?
Well a letter in a guess and in the right place is a bull and a letter in a guess but in the wrong place
is a cow.
And of course if you guess a letter that isn't in our head and word you won't get any bulls or any cows
OK.
So let's talk about the mechanics of the game itself the hidden word is going to be pulled from a list
of words the game will let us know the number of lives that we have the player will make a guess.
You will lose a life if you get it wrong and display how many bulls and cows you got.
It may be zero if the correct word is guessed then the game is won.
And of course if you do not correctly guess the word and your lives have run out the game is over.
So let's have a look at that now in action okay.
So now we're over on our Unreal let's go ahead click the play button and see what happens.
So our first word here is action.
I've put this top line in here so I know what I'm supposed to be guessing here.
And it's a good way of debugging your code as well to make sure that the word you're trying to guess
is correct.
And of course the full game where we have that in place.
So we'll be guessing the six letter word and you have six lives.
You may have already guessed by reading that that these are linked together.
So let's see if we can generate a new word.
We got able now four letters four lives.
So we can adjust the amount of lives we have based upon the length of the hidden word.
Let's just stop and play that again.
And here we go we've got a five letter word.
So let's start guessing.
If I were to type in something that was too short we'll be able to prompt the player and remind them
of the conditions of a guess.
So let's go ahead and guess a five letter word that isn't an isogram so we can error check the
user's input which is a very important skill to obtain.
And of course you can decide whether you punish by docking a life at this point.
So let's start guessing something else.
Go above.
Look at that.
So we've got three balls.
If we remember about an above share A, B and O.
So let's say we thought that's our I guess itself the A, B and E were correct and we tried something like
abuse and we get down over here.
Oh well hang on.
We got one cow here so the difference there might be that the U is wrong so let's go back to here and
if we guessed correctly as you can see you in the game and you can press return to play again and then
it'll give us a new word and we can start guessing once again.
And here you can see four bulls and one cow because we've got the N in there just in the wrong place
so that's where a cow would come in and if we constantly guess incorrectly what we will end up with is
running out of lives
and at this point we tell the player they've run out of lives and tell them what the word was and also
prompt them to press return to play again.
Brilliant.
So that's the simple game that we're going to create.
It's going to be lots to learn during the section.
I'm really looking forward to seeing what you guys create with it as well.
So once you've taken this knowledge I'd really like to see you all modify the game to your own and we'll
be diving in first of all and learning about the interface and even making this level that you can see
in the background your own.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.