Hello and a warm welcome to the course.
My name is Ben, Ben Tristem. GameDev.tv founder and CEO. I originally designed and created this course
back in 2015 and it is being remastered during 2019.
We're going through the entire course rerecording it using Unreal Engine 4.22 or later and all the
latest design philosophies we have.
Furthermore we're going to be making the games more fun more visually appealing etc. So it's gonna be
a huge great remaster.
I'm asking for some help with that one person who helped us was Gavin also known on YouTube as
Tesla Dev Milroy.
He was a partner instructor with us in 2019.
He has created a great version of the Triple X game which is a new game for this remaster.
You'll see that in the course early on and then after that you'll be seeing Michael Bridges our senior
founding instructor, one of the... in fact the first instructor to work with me in GameDev.tv and he's also known
for his blender courses.
So they're the three phases you'll specifically see in this course.
There's a whole bunch of other faces behind the scenes but I won't confuse you with those people right
now.
So I want to share with you have to get the most from this course.
Firstly do all the challenges when you see them that's really important you'll see a challenge.
A little bit later in this video they are our way of making sure that you get actual practice because
you only really build a skill when you do something so please take the time to do the challenges.
Visit the Google slides their lives slide that gdev.tv/uc2slides that stands
for unreal course two slides then you can comment on the slides if you see any issues whatever so go
ahead and do that if you want it in general become an active community member also become a problem
solver try and get even better at solving problems during this course and stay positive and work hard
some bits of this will be difficult but things that are worth doing tend to be difficult so stick with
it it's gonna be cool.
All right so the first thing to say before we dive into any of the technical stuff is to make sure that
you understand you're not alone.
Don't struggle in silence.
Ask for help.
We have a world class community forum for a start.
Let's take a look at it.
This is our community forum it's at community.gamedev.tv you can access everything on this
without signing up.
Obviously if you want to post to the forum you're going to need to sign up but you can read
everything else everybody else has done without signing up.
And specifically the Unreal Courses section has three subsections you can talk issues where you share
and discuss and generally hang out.
You can ask if you've got a question that needs an answer then this is a good place to ask.
Because all the questions are tracked and we have Dan
Our student instructor in there looking for answers for you.
We also dive in occasionally as needed and then you have somewhere you can show off share screenshots
share code etc. So that's all structured like that inside the forum.
And when you post here once you've signed up or signed in you'll get the choice of whether you post
into talk ask or share.
All right.
So that's our community forum.
As I say you can talk ask or show when you do paste please use code formatting over in the forum.
So for example if you're asking a question and it is a technical question then either use a screenshot
like this which is a great example of a screenshot and if you're sharing code look for the code formatting
options in the forum.
Basically be a good community member.
Use code formatting make code readable include screenshots etc. but for instant help, if you need help
straight away there is our Discord server. If it's a simple problem that needs instant help come here.
I've given you an invite all these links are in the resources against this lecture.
We have several thousand people at just the right number or broken out nicely into different channels.
Give yourself a nice username I'm BenTristem.
I don't frequent it too often I go in once a week or so because there's so many, so many demands on my
time I can't be there any more often than that but if you go in there and mentioned me I'll eventually get
back to you.
And that's a good way of getting immediate answers to quick questions.
If you have a more nuanced question I suggest you post it onto the forum like this and then go and grab
the link for it and take it to our Discord live chat service so that you've done other people the service
of laying out your problem and thinking about it first.
The next place to show you is our GameDev.tv Unreal Course community on Facebook if you like Facebook.
This is great.
It's thriving.
Lots of people there willing to help you.
Friendly bunch of faces as you can see from the top here.
Then we have twitch.
We stream on Twitch occasionally and when we do it's good fun so you can follow us on Twitch.
We also have a YouTube channel which we use for various updates etc. So give us a subscribe over there
and then on a daily basis we use our Twitter channel at GameDev.tv on Twitter.
All right so they are most of our community places that you can go so why don't you go ahead and pause
the video.
This is the first challenge slide you can see on the screen now with the pause logo on it.
Join at least one community, it can be the community forum site that I showed you, the Discord live chat
server, The Unreal Facebook group, our Twitch channel, our YouTube channel, or GameDev.tv on Twitter and
all the links to these are in the lecture resources so go ahead pause the video join at least one community
now whatever you feel most comfortable with and I'll see you in a moment.
Awesome job.
Welcome back.
So please do do these challenges if you don't take action.
You're going to struggle later on in the course but I won't keep nagging you about that.
All right.
So how to ask good questions.
Very important when you do go over to a community site.
First off before you even ask anybody else please ask Google.
Just paste the exact error text into Google try and solve the problem yourself.
If you still need help then include the error that you're getting when you share the problem with any
code snippets or any error codes that you've got okay? Make it easy for other people to reproduce
the problem and understand the problem.
That's the key.
Make your description of the problem as short as possible but as long as necessary and also you know
what goes around comes around so please to answer other people's questions that will really help you
to understand how to ask a good question.
If you get into the habit of answering other people's questions as well you can really put yourself
in the question.
Answer is shoes.
So that's it.
A reminder that all these slides with this link below which is gdev.tv/uc2slides
And thank you for watching this video.
Next up we'll dive in and start getting everything installed and set up.