Okay, so to get started with this section, you want to download the starter project, provided the
project has been created in version four point twenty five.
So you'll need that version or above installed.
You can then extract and run the project just like any other unreal project you've worked with.
So inside of the tank game project, I've already set up some of the folder structures.
The input settings and created the default main map, as well as providing the audio and visual assets
that we'll need for the game.
This would just allow us to focus as much on implementing the logic in the classes as possible.
You might have also noticed that this project was created from an empty blueprint project, meaning
that we don't have or see any of the C++ directories or the classes in the project at the moment.
And this is because I find this to be a lot of the time kind of preferred approach to creating new C++
projects just because it avoids the engine, creating the default game mode class, which in most cases
doesn't follow the ideal naming convention or folder structure.
Now I know that in some of the previous sections you've seen how to delete classes from the project
and this can be a slightly long winded process.
So this is something that where possible we want to try and avoid having to go through that process.
So in the next lecture, we'll be looking at how we can turn a blueprint project into a C++ project
whilst also getting that full control over the project structure.
The naming conventions and things like that.
And just for those of you who may have noticed that my unreal engine editor interface is looking a little
bit different.
That's just because I've installed the minimal UI pack.
Now, this is a free download and you can find this by following this link.
And then on the get help page here, you just need to select the download option and follow the simple
four step installation process.
Just know, though, that even if you don't want to do this, that everything still appears in the same
location on the screen and it doesn't affect any of the processes that will be taking.