Hello and welcome to section 2 where we're going to start building our first game together in C++.
So this is going to be a simple number puzzle game that we're calling "Triple X" and it's called "Triple X"
because it's based around three unknown numbers.
You're going to be hacking into a computer lock of some sort.
And the idea of the game is to find a valid three number combination.
Now it starts pretty easy but it becomes much harder as you keep playing the game as it ramps up in
difficulty.
And you don't have to follow the exact same storyline as me here.
You have the opportunity to customize the story. If you want the story to reflect a fantasy setting,
then there's no problem create your own story as you follow along with me in this section.
So let's take a look at the game to get a clear idea of what we're going to be building.
So here's the game.
Here is Triple X. You're a secret agent.
Breaking into a level 2 server room your super hacker 2000 tells you the following information.
There's three numbers in the code and the codes multiply to give 18 and the codes add up to 8 as
the player we have to enter the three code numbers followed by an x.
So what three numbers multiply to give 18 and add up to 8.
Well I think it's "3 3 2" let's start with the addition here, 3 + 3  is 6 and 6 + 2 is 8.
So if we use those same numbers to multiply, 3 x 3 is 9 and 9 x 2 is 18.
So yeah the answer is 3...
3 2
And we need to follow the answer with an X and with the correct answer entered it tells us "congratulations
you're in.
Now hurry before anyone finds you" and we're immediately thrown into the next level we play the game
again.
But the levels change we're now in level 3 no longer level 2.
The difficulty has ramped up.
So this is the idea of Triple X if we were to give a wrong answer.
It's just going to give us a message saying "boom you've failed miserably and died horribly."
So why start with Triple X instead of hopping straight into Unreal.
Well we've chosen this game very carefully. It's going to teach you the basics of C++ syntax.
You're going to be learning all about variables and constants which is important foundational skills
and you're going to be creating your very own function for the first time that will take an argument.
You'll be using the hash include like we've already done in section one that we're going to be talking
about it in more detail because it's going to be heavily used inside Unreal.
And you'll also be learning about other programming structures such as the "if" and "while" statements.
So here's a quick peek at our code here.
Already we're seeing a lot of code that we're going to be writing in the section before jumping into
Unreal and trust me Unreal is going to be firing a lot of concepts out to you.
So we need to just get down and dirty with the basics before moving on to Unreal.
So why learn C++?
This project's being carefully selected to teach you all the right tools to help you get started without
being too complicated.
It's really going to set you up for the next section of this course.
Now the older version of this course didn't have this Triple X section and some students found the learning
journey just a bit too steep.
So it's really worth doing this section. Now by learning C++
you're going to be learning a superpower.
Now we would call any coding a superpower here at GameDev.tv
C++ is a super powerful language because it's both high level and low level.
It covers the very high level like object oriented programming that we'll be talking about in this course
but C++ also covers the very low level like getting into the details of the bits and bytes.
So it's a very broad language.
And by learning C++ you'll be joining a unique tribe of power users which is pretty awesome, right?
So finally and quite importantly one of the last reasons to learn C++ is that it's fun.
And it's also challenging.
Now if you think you know enough C++ and can create this game without even doing this section then go
right ahead and share your results in the community and move on to the next section.
But if you're a new user, you really don't want to hop into Unreal without doing the section.
So I'm going to leave you with this.
What's the story of your game.
Try and think of a unique story.
You don't have to follow the same idea as me.
We were breaking into a server.
And if you're stuck ask a kid.
They have quite vivid imaginations and you might be surprised.
And most of all enjoy sharing your stories in our community.
So that wraps up this video.
And in the next lesson Ben's going to be giving you an overview of the code in this game.
So once you're ready you'll be seeing Ben in the next lesson.