Hello everybody and welcome back.
I'd like to take a little bit of step back from coding for a few moments to discuss our game loop.
First of all what is a game loop.
Well it's the process that a player is going to go through and there will be multiple of these per game
that you end up creating in the future.
There are games relatively basic.
So there is just gonna be one core loop that the players can go through.
And I don't want to confuse a game loop with loops with in your code that's different.
And what's the player experiences from the moment they interact with our terminal within the book how
game is what our core game loop is going to be so why write it down in the first place why can't we
just get down to coding.
Well a lot of you will find that visualizing the process before you start your coding will help you
check your logic.
You may even change how you thought the game might run.
When do you take lives away when do you process the guests that they've put in knowing these things
and enables you to describe your intended behavior and also check that your code matches that intended
behavior.
It's very easy to write down a one flow and end up with something slightly different once you start
coding.
Now there's no right or wrong when it comes to this if the intended behavior works that's great but
you may end up having to go back to your flow chart that you end up creating or indeed modifying your
code again to reflect what you actually intended from the very beginning.
And it also helps define the scope of your game.
And by that I mean when your coding away and you think of a new idea.
Well it's not going to be on that flowchart so it's really going to have to make you think about whether
or not you want to include that in the game at which point you can go back to your flowchart and see
how putting that new behavior in is going to affect your code.
And with that I'd like to dive straight into your challenge.
I'd like you to write your basic loop.
Now there is going to be no right or wrong with this.
However I'm going to give you some things to consider see you line up pretty much with what I'm doing.
And so you can follow along of course.
So I'd like you to go ahead and sketch the most basic game loop you can come up with.
And by that I mean literally grab a pen and paper or use a flowchart tool if that's something you're
used to.
It doesn't matter how you do it.
It's that you get the idea behind the loop.
The first time I did this I scribbled it down in a notebook.
I then formalized it later on and here are a couple of things to think about to get you going.
We're going to have to start the game.
We're going to have to set the hidden word.
We're going to have the prompt for a guess.
We're going to have to receive the gas we're going to have to wait for user inputs of course and then
is the guest correct.
And have they won or lost.
So you can see this is a very simple loop that we're trying to construct here.
We're not worrying about lives.
We're not worried about multiple different hidden words or anything along those lines.
So go ahead pause video now and give that a go
OK.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and look at my basic game loop.
You can compare it to yours as well see how similarly you managed to create its sir.
Here we go.
The first thing we're going to do is print the welcome message.
This is going to introduce the player to the game is going to give them instructions on how to play
etc. etc..
The next thing we need to do is set the hidden word.
Now at the moment and in the next couple of lectures we'll make it hard coded and in the future we will
pick that word randomly from a list of ISO Grams remember.
This isn't Isaac Graham guessing game and then we're going to prompt the user to guess the word.
So this is going to be quite difficult because it could be any one of thousands of words but then we've
got this hourglass symbol that simply means we're waiting for the user input.
And once they have given us the inputs we can assess it.
So is it correct.
That's all we care about at the moment.
Yes or no.
If the answer is yes they win the game.
If the answer is no they lose the game.
So this is pretty much as simple as this structure can get is a very basic game and there's only one
life.
So you better get it right or you lose.
And with our basic loops we're going to be able to start coding now for this very simple game.
Then later on we can expand on it.
So remember to show your basic loops over in the forum and I'll see you in the next lecture.