Everyone, and welcome back in this lecture will be creating and displaying our start and end widgets
to the screen to encapsulate the flow of gameplay.
We need to start off in our BP underscore game mode based blueprint in the event graph.
We can get rid of the begin play.
And the event tech as we won't be using those.
What we want to do instead is override our functions from the C++ parent class.
We can do this by going to the function section, highlighting the function text to get the override
option and then clicking that button when it appears.
If we then drop this down, we can see all of the inherited functions to override and the two that we're
interested in fall under the tank.
Game mode category, which are the custom functions that we've created in our own class.
So if we start by selecting the game starts and then go back and also select the game over function,
these will then be implemented into the event graph as event notes.
So because we've defined these as a blueprint implementable, we don't have a parent function to implement
or call the override on.
So we won't need to add the call to parent function here.
If you've seen that used before.
So what we want to do here is to create our widgets as soon as these functions are called in the C++
counterpart class.
As this was the intention to get everything like that running in our blueprint.
So to create a widget we call the create widget function.
That's taken a parameter here of the type of widget that we want to pass in.
So for our game start function, this will be the WBB underscore game start.
And this only creates the widget.
So it kind of makes the object exist in the context of the current world to make actually show on screen.
We need to take the returning widget reference here and call the ad to viewport function.
Also remember that we've set up those SACEUR functions in our widget blueprint.
So we need to pass in a value for the start delay.
So because we have a reference to the exact widget type.
This way we can pull from the return value again and call the set start delay function within that class.
We can provide the amount of time that we want the game start countdown to take.
And then we're going to want to ensure that this is called before the widget is being displayed to avoid
any kind of visual jolts in the widget elements being updated after they've been kind of placed on the
screen.
Have also gone ahead and added some reworked notes here.
So you can see me doing that in the background.
Just keep things a little bit tidier.
And if you're not familiar with this, the easiest way to get Re-route notes, you can search for them
if you wanted.
But if you really have some wires available or you need to do is double click on The Wire where you
would like a reboot note to be placed, and then you can kind of move these around so that we don't
have so many wires going through each other.
So for the start, time alone, it looks as though we haven't created a value to use for this section
just yet.
So would just prefer this with a hard set value of two seconds just to test things and make sure that
they're working.
We can then copy the create widget note and paste that just below.
I've used control w here to get the copy paste in a single command.
Then we just need to replace the widget reference with the game and widget.
Again, we're gonna want to call the function that will update the text before displaying the widget.
So this is controlling the display of showing whether the player has won or lost the game.
So pulling from the return node will cool the set play player.
One function from the WBB underscore game and class and pass the player one from our game mode function.
Call into the set.
Play at one function with a couple more rewrite notes.
Just keep things again.
Slightly tidier and easy to maintain with an ad at the widget to the screen.
By pulling from the re-route pen and calling the ad to viewport function.
So this when I display both the widgets during the gameplay as we already have everything set up to
account for them.
So if we press play, we can go ahead and test this.
So we can see her there.
Everything seems to have worked.
If we destroy the enemy Tarrant's, then we are greeted with the wind state widget.
Then if I play again, we can see that the loose state is also working if we like the target to deplete
our health.
The only real problem here is that nothing is actually changing for the player.
So the tank is not being hidden and we can still move about freely.
It almost feels as though nothing actually happened.
So let's just go back to our C++ class and make some of those changes to start addressing at least a
few of these issues in this lecture.
So the first thing we want to do is go to our game mode class in the protected section here.
We can add a new variable for use in our blueprint class, which will control the countdown duration.
We just saw that we're missing.
So I'll give you a small challenge here.
Create a new protected variable of type int 32 named start delay.
Also provide the new property to ensure that changes can be made in the default class as the game mode
doesn't exist until the game starts.
So instance, use in game mode doesn't usually very useful.
Besides, if you know you're going to be updating something during the game that be working after the
event begin, players being called also make it readable in blueprint's and then provide a category
named game loop.
Okay, so hopefully you have that we will start by creating the Integer 32 named Start Didley, which
I'll set to a default value of three.
And making it edit devotes only.
Providing the blueprint read-only specify.
And then giving it a category, name of game loop.
So all very standard stuff, but I just wanted to try wording the process a little bit differently to
see if the concepts in general and I'm making sense, rather than focusing on the exact steps that we've
taken in the past for the U.
Properties before compiling then and checking some of our changes, I'm also going to go to our pawn
tank code file and just make it change.
That will be removing later.
But I wanted to provide a visual example to aid the description I provided in some of the previous lectures.
So down in the 100 destruction function, I'm going to add a cool to destroy the pawn.
Very similar to what we have in the turret class.
And this will help us visualize exactly when we've lost the game.
But also for anybody who hasn't seen the jumpy camera transition I mentioned when a controlled pawn
is destroyed.
This will let you know what to look out for in your own projects.
So let's be sure to save all of that.
Go back to the editor and recompile.
The first thing then when we're back in the game mode class, we cannot get our start delay variable
and pass that straight into the start widget function.
This leads us to and I very quickly change how long the current line period will take.
So you can play around with some values here to get a start to count on time that you like.
I'm going to settle for these three seconds here.
And then press play.
I'm just going to go over to the turret.
We're ready now that we can enter the wind state.
So I'll let the turret win here so that we can test our loose state.
And we can see that the text is now updating correctly.
We get thrown quite sharply to the scene at defo camera, which is the result we're trying to avoid
by creating our custom handle destruction logic for the player later.
But this is what I meant by that kind of jumpy camera movement from one camera to another.
If you completely destroying a pawn and we look at how and why we can get around that a little bit later,
this will require a player controller, which will be a topic that we cover in future lectures.