This lecture is a kind of additional topic that I wanted to cover on debugging.
And at this stage, you won't actually be experiencing the same error that I'm going to be showing,
which is in my code.
But hopefully this will prove as a useful kind of insight to debugging an issue when you've made what
is quite a simple layer to make in the code that doesn't actually cause any errors or warnings.
But it does stop the project from running or responding as you had intended or expected.
This was the result of me making a really simple mistake in my prototype project and just not noticing
it as I went through and continued expanding whilst annoying small issues like this one that we're about
to discover can be really useful for learning how to track down weird, unexpected behavior as we're
not getting a fatal crash or pretty much any response at all.
So let's go ahead, find out what I did and see if you can spot this along the way.
So the problem that I had was that regardless of what I set the health to in the tank class, and I
think it was for the entire class as well, I always seemed to be getting destroyed almost as soon as
I was pressing play.
I have some recordings of this as well.
And I had an idea of what this might have been.
I'm not going to show you is the kind of process that I took to debug through this, because this is
one of those things where I'd look to the code for quite so long that what could have been quite an
obvious mistake didn't really stand right to me.
Because you get to a stage when when you're just reading through code, you kind of skim things almost
like a book.
I suppose what you're looking for most serious errors, then what was the actual problem at the end?
So back in the code file, you can kind of follow along.
Like I said, your code is going to be slightly different here, which is fine.
I have a challenge for you right off the bat here, and that is to place an unreal log in the take damage
function and print out a message, including the amount of health remaining.
So this was the first step that I took.
So I'm just gonna get you to do that as your challenge for this lecture.
And what you should be doing before you post video is just considering the best place to insert the
log as well as the log type.
And remembering how to display the health value is kind of appended to that log.
So post video now and give that one to go.
Okay, so we already know how to log values to the output using the UEE underscore log.
The main thing that we want to consider is the place in which we want to put this.
And in this case, we know that the health, as I've described, was being successfully updated.
At least it was always being taken away and the tank and the tarps were being destroyed.
So the most useful place we're not checking whether this is taking Healthway.
We're checking high.
The health is being taken away.
So I think the most useful place for this is going to be just after the health value is being updated
so we can see what value is being changed each time we're hit.
I'm going to make this a log temp and of type warning, and then I'm just going to add a string.
How followed by Double Kerlan and then a percentage F, which is our indicator that we're expecting
a flight value to be passed in as part of the final thing to print.
Then finally, outside of this.
Followed by a comma will pass in our health value.
So let's go back to the editor and compile this and I'll see what's happening in my original kind of
prototype project.
So with that compiled, this is kind of confirming part of my suspicion that we're taking damage.
As soon as the game launches.
And then once more to take off the final bit of health after the targets to second fire.
Right.
Cool down.
So this is because way back when I was creating this, I'd set the timer controlling the turrets fire.
Right.
To not have an initial delay.
And that's fine.
That will work perfectly fine.
It's just that I also expected the plan to start just slight side of the detection radius.
So this issue would have been fixed by moving the player away from the turret, which is something that
I was going to do in the.
Kind of level pass anyway.
But that does confirm, at the very least, that we are taking two hits before being destroyed.
So the calculation, the math and everything like that seems to be working fine.
So let's go back into the health component code and see why the health isn't being updated.
In the adisa, which seems to be the main problem we have here.
So we can cut the log from the take damage function as we've solved that part already.
And then we're gonna move up to where we're setting the P for health.
And this is the bit which is going to look different for you.
And some of you might have really seen this when we were brushing through the code file and have noticed
what the issue is.
But we'll debug this all the same so you can see firsthand what the problem was.
And again, this should make it hopefully more readily available in memory.
If you make a similar mistake in your project and you are not sure at the time how to fix it.
This you might not need to follow along with because the print strings be completely different for you
and me as when we've gone through this in the lectures.
I've obviously put this in the correct place, but the problem here is I'm making a dynamic variable
update in the class constructor, which is a mistake that I missed, as I said, during the initial
implementation.
So if I paste the UNRRA log after assessing the health value and see what's happening, if you wanted
to, you could set yours in the beginning play and see how yours is being called differently.
So again, back in the editor with that compiled and ready to go back in the tank, I'm going to change
the health to something much higher so that we know that we should be expecting to take way more than
two hits.
I've gone for 1000 points of health and then back in the output log.
We can see that each time that we've made a change that would have called the constructor.
This has still only been set.
It's been called, but it's only being set to one hundred, which is the value that offsets the default
health to be when declaring it to avoid a no value in the header then because we've now gone past the
construction stage.
Even if I press play, this isn't going to be updated.
And you can see that we'll take two hits and we'll lose our one hundred health and die.
So back in the code fall, as I said, you should have if you following along with your unrelaxed,
then you'll see that you have different results to what's being printed.
And back in the code for the fix to this and the correct approach whenever setting a variable in this
way is just to make sure that we put that in the beginning play function.
So all variable initialization like this should be done outside of the constructor.
No.
One to make a point of this, it can be very easy, especially when you're making a lot of components
and you using the create default sub object of function as we have so many times.
You must, I suppose, get a little bit and go on like an auto programmer mode where you just start
putting everything that you're initializing into the construct.
And I think that's what I did here.
And I think that's also was very easy to overlook because at a glance, you know, that you've initialized
so many things in the constructor that doesn't jump at you as an arrow straight away.
And that's why I kind of had to debug back through things like this to find the arrow.
So just to show the different results.
So with my code and I'm in the correct place, I won't need the log any longer.
So I'm going to remove that.
Just recompile this one last time.
No Pressplay to show the final results, which is really going to be what you have anyway.
So as you can see here, I can leave the tank where it is and take a lot more hits as the health is
not being correctly updated from the default health value because that is now on the Biggin place.
So all of these are being initialized properly, which means that we can easily change and update this
in the editor to get the to try different values and things for our health values.
So this was just a quick aside from the project that was just a little bit more in debugging.
And I thought that was quite useful because it's a very kind of realistic scenario actually happens
to me, rather than trying to make up a debugging scenario just for a lecture.
So I wanted to keep that one here.
But with that fixed in my existing project, when I'm ready to move on to the next topics and start
finalizing our game.