Hello and welcome in this lecture, we're going to be hooking up our health system to the animation
blueprint so that I can shoot this character until he dies.
Let's dive in and see how that works.
So you want this boolean in the animation blueprints to be set automatically from our gameplay.
And if we go through to our event graph and have a look how this is currently working, other properties
like this, such as get velocity, get active, transform, we're going to the pawn and we're doing
a get function on it every time we want to update animation.
So we want to kind of follow along in this model where we're going to go and get whether or not our
player is dead.
So to do that, we need to expose some functionality, some callable function from our C++.
So let's go over to the C++ and have a look.
What is there?
So we've could create a public function, but that doesn't necessarily make it accessible to do the
accessibility.
We need to have a new function which makes it visible to blueprint's and unrolls head Ital system.
But we've got to go one step further than just having it as a new function.
So we start with the you function macro, but we want to make it blueprint callable.
So that is the option that we can use.
Blueprint callable.
However, there is another option that overrides Blueprint.
Callable, rather implies that it's blueprint callable and that is Blueprint Pure.
Now we'll see the difference between Blueprint Pure and Blueprint callable in just a second.
But just know that if you use Blueprint Pure, it is doing the same as Blueprint Callable and then some.
So it's doing a little bit more than Blueprint callable.
And then what we want is a function that returns boolean that says whether or not this character is
dead.
That is going to be useful for us to know.
And then finally, we want this to be a concert member function.
Now, why does it want to be concert?
Because when we call this function, we don't expect it to change any of the states of Ashu to character.
So we can safely say that this should be a concert function.
And in actual fact, concert and blueprint pure often go together because Blueprint Pure means that
if we go over in it to any blueprint, we can have a look at some pure notes.
This one here get transformed.
That's a pure note.
Get velocity is a pure note.
Set speed is not a pure note.
Can you see what might be linking these together?
What about these?
Makes this not pure.
And this one pure?
Well, generally speaking, it's the fact that there's an execution pen.
A pure node is one that doesn't have an execution pen.
And it's usually safe to say that something doesn't have an execution pen when it doesn't have any impact
on the thing that it's calling only on its result.
Essentially, this means that no matter how many times we call this function, it's going to always
output the same result.
It's always going to have the same effect on the program.
It is a pure function.
It doesn't change anything when it is called.
So it's kind of the same as concert, although it's a little bit stronger, because what it's saying
is not just that it doesn't change anything here on the shoot character, but it doesn't change anything
global, any state anywhere.
Full stop.
The only input.
The only effect it has is in the outputs that it produces.
So that's why we're choosing to make this blueprint pure.
It removes the need for an execution pin, which makes it much nicer in blueprint.
And it also just expresses the fact that we aren't making any changes to the state of our game when
we call this function.
So let's go ahead and try to create an implementation for this, in fact, to leave the implementation
up to you as a challenge.
And we're gonna go over and hook this up in an IM graph sorry, in that event graph of the animation
blueprint.
So we're gonna do this by having a new set here.
We want to set the is dead boolean variable at the end and we want to get the pawn owner and we want
to cast that because it needs to be a shooter character in order to have this is dead property.
So we want to cast it, too.
And in this case, I want to cast it to the C++ shooter character because I don't need to go all the
way down to saying it's definitely a blueprint version of this, because this new function actually
exists on the C++ level.
So we're gonna go ahead and cast.
If we succeed in cast, we're going to be setting the is dead property.
Let me just put in some redirect nodes here to make our blueprint just a little bit nicer looking like.
So and then what we want to do is using this shooter a character reference.
Now that we've cast it to a chute's character, we know that it should have this is dead property,
so we should be able to do that.
Once you've compiled and got it working, you can get this is dead property and set it here.
So it's time for your challenge to calculate if we are dead or not.
So return the correct boolean out of our is dead function.
That's the first step.
You might want to use some inequalities with our health variable for that.
And then hook up our variable.
The dead is dead variable in the animation blueprint we've got just short of doing that were just needed.
We just basically a compiler way from getting that done.
Pause the video and get that sorted.
OK, welcome back.
So let's go over to the code, first of all.
So this fairly straightforwardly, I'm going to return an expression that returns a boolean.
So we want to say, is the health less than or equal to zero, in which case we are indeed dead?
That's about as simple as a an expression function can get.
So let's go ahead and build that.
And once that has compiled, we can go over into one real and hook it up.
So dragging off the as shoe to character, we arg node, we're going to have a shooter character reference
here.
So we want to do is dead gives us this is dead function.
You can see it has no execution pin because it is pure.
Then we take this boolean off of that and hook it up to it is dead favorable.
And now if we go ahead and play, we should actually be able to kill off.
That character in the world will shoot at him until his health goes down to zero.
And there you go.
The animation has successfully killed him off.