In this lecture, we're going to return to our tank class and complete the implementation of what happens
when the base class handle destruction function is called to begin, we'll need some new properties
in our tank pedophile first in the private section.
We're going to create a boolean named B is player alive, which we'll use to stop the movement being
tracked.
If the player has been killed and also as a variable later for the turret class to check against whether
it should be firing at the player or not.
I'll also initialize this when we create it to be true, to ensure that we always start the game with
the player being classed as alive, the way that we'll be using this boolean variable for the Taat class.
We have a couple of ways.
So the first option would be to make the boolean public so that external classes have the immediate
access to the variable as long as they have a reference to the class.
However, where possible, we want to keep our variables as secure as possible to stop other classes
being able to accidently set or override the variable details.
So instead, we're going to make use of our public section and create a get a function of type boolean
named Gett is player alive and then implement this with our C++ helper inside of this function.
Or we're going to do is return our new B is player alive value.
And this will align with the function to be called outside of the class by the TARP class or any other
class that may need to know the state of the player, whilst also ensuring that the actual variable
itself is not accessible and therefore classed as a class a variable, meaning that we cannot make any
accidental changes to this variable from outside of the class, which generally makes it a little bit
harder to track where the body is being set and what's happening to it.
Next, we can flesh out our hundred destruction function.
So the first thing that we want to do is set our new B is player a variable to folks.
We want to handle the last two points that we've considered before, and that is to hide the tank from
view and stop further input from being handled.
We can do this with two standard actor functions.
The first that we use is the set actor hidden in-game and set this to be true.
And then we're also going to set to take an able to be false.
So this will hide any of the visual components on the actor and also set the tech functionality to stop
running.
So this is useful because it will have C save us a little bit of performance.
When the player isn't being used and it's also going to stop the movement anyway, because that is where
we have the movement functionality being run to actually drive the movements and the rotation logic.
Then to finish off the tank destruction functionality, we can jump straight over to the target class
and immediately use this new alife boolean functionality.
So your challenge here will be to use what we've been implementing in the tank class, add a check somewhere
in the check fire condition function and stop the turret from firing if the player is classed as that.
So this challenge has multiple layers.
Think of where you could place the check and then also ensure that you can use a function cool from
another class as the argument.
As always, go ahead and post video while starting to give this one to go.
Okay, so we have a number of options of where we could do our conditional check here.
Like with anything in programming, there's usually no right option for this use case, though.
I'm just going to borrow the existing F check that we already have to ensure that we return.
Straight out of the function.
If the player has died, then we just need to cool.
The public gets a function that we've just implemented and we already have the reference to our player
pool.
So this will just be a pawn get is alive.
So for this, we're just going to say or if play a pawn get is a life that and that will be our F check.
Although this is currently a positive based condition.
So we're going to want to add the not condition before this.
So if we just read this f check now as kind of standard text, wouldn't I be saying if there isn't a
player POUM or if the player isn't alive, then return?
And I think that's a pretty clean way to implement this.
And it means that we know that we're always going to return out of this function if the important factors
for firing at the player haven't been met.
But those changes made, we can I hop back over to the editor and test our new functionality.
So I have the two tests that I wanted to check for here.
The first was just to ensure that being destroyed would stop me from being able to make additional movement
and also remove the visualizations of the pawn.
And the second time I had my finger being helped down on the move forward direction whilst I was being
destroyed.
And we can see that we haven't no continued movement or momentum after the destruction.
And of course, the main thing here is that the camera knight doesn't jump back to a new position because
we're still keeping the camera.
That's still what we're viewing through.
We've just hidden and stopped the movement so that we don't get the unfortunate kind of default.
Pollner response is when destroying them from the level.