Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we're going to be setting up the basics in place for our A.I. getting started on the
whole A.I. process, which is going to be quite a series of lectures.
So we're starting with a revision of A.I. controllers and blueprints.
Let's dive in and see what we're revising.
So let's check back in with our project plan at the moment.
We have done player movements, animation, shooting, health and death.
So far, those things are pretty much covered.
We're going to look next at a very big chunk, which is going to be the enemy A.I..
So let's get started.
The first thing we always need to do with A.I. is to have an A.I. controller.
So we're gonna go over and create a C++ one that I'm going to challenge you to create the blueprint
subclass and hook it up as the default for the pawn.
So we're going to go to add new create a new C++ class in here and then we're going to go down and look
for if there is an AI controller in here.
I'm not sure if there is something to show or classes and look for the A.I. controller.
And we're going to use that as a base class.
Go ahead and rename it to something like Chuter, A.I. controller and go and create that class.
And once that's gone ahead and generated and recompile, it may take a little while in your system.
You should end up with a C++ class like this.
Now, that's pretty much all I'm going to do because the rest you should be able to remember some of
it yourself.
We done a lot of this in the previous section already.
So let's see if you can do it.
So here's a challenge to create a blueprint child.
You're going to have to first create the child class.
Then set it as the A.I. for our blueprint character.
You may or may not remember, but that has to go.
You go into your blueprint for that character.
The first person should, while the third person shooter character and you can set the A.I. that should
automatically possess these characters when they're placed in the world and then test the actors.
I'll create to test that the A.I. controller actors are created by basically UN possessing, doing their
fate and having a look in your world outliner to see if those actors are present.
Pause video and have a go.
Hey, welcome back.
So first of all, we're gonna create a blueprint.
Child class here.
So I'm going to do that by going to add new blueprint class and I'm going to make it a child of the
shooter, A.I. controller.
And then I'm gonna call it the BP underscore Chuter A.I. controller I and get the capitalization right.
Like so and then we want to make that the defo A.I. for our BP Chuter characters.
I'm going to open up the BP chute's character and dock it to the main window.
And then I'm going to go to the class defaults details.
And in here, we should have, under the porn settings, the A.I. control class, which we want to switch
over to the BP underscore Chuter A.I. controller so I can click all save.
Okay, do all of that and go Olt P to play and then F eight to D possess and have my mouse back and
look in the world outliner.
We should be looking for a shooter A.I..
And here we go.
The BP shooter, A.I. controller is being created for that character we put in the world.
If you are to put more characters in the world, there would be more A.I. controllers being created.
And do watch out.
That is the blueprint version being created because we want any of the modifications that we make in
Blueprint to be showing up in our game, basically.
Cool.
So we've just gone through a quick revision of how we typically set up A.I. controllers.
And next, that show will be actually making that A.I. controller do something.
Basically aiming at our player.
So you then.