Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we're going to be working on a focus.
So that is some built in functionality, in unreeled that we can use to make sure that our A.I. characters
follow us around the world, are able to aim at us no matter where we go.
Let's dive in and see how focused works.
So I currently doesn't really do very much, and I think a first starting point for it to do anything
would be for it to turn and face towards our player.
Now, to do this, where we can use some built in functionality of the A.I., which is setting a focal
point.
So if you have a look at the A.I. control dot h and look for set focus, there's a couple of relevant
methods here.
One is set focal points.
The other is set focus.
And the one just below that is clear focus.
So the idea here is that you can tell the A.I. controller that it should be trying to focus either on
a particular point or it should be trying to focus on a particular actor.
If you choose the latter, if you choose to focus on an actor, then what's going to happen is as that
actor moves, you're going to keep focusing on that actor.
Whereas if he chose to focus on a particular point, you would keep focusing on that point.
But if that point was the location of an actor, when the actor moves, that point does not get updated.
So typically, focal points are for things that are fixed in the world, actors for things that move
around.
That kind of makes sense.
And then we have this clear focus function down here, which tells us that we should stop focusing on
something.
So that's how it works.
You set focus, you clearer focus.
Now, there is this priority variable in here which we are going to come to a little bit.
But the idea here is you've got different levels of priority.
We've got this enum here, which by default on set focus and set focal point is set to gameplay.
If we go and have a look at the definition of that enum, you can see there is a default move and gameplay
and they're basically listed in the order of priority.
So game play will have the highest priority if he said something is gameplay.
That's what it's going to look at.
If gameplay isn't set because you cleared the gameplay priority, then it's going to look where it's
going.
And if it's not moving anywhere, then it's going to just look at the default priority, which might
just be some wear off in the distance.
So if you've got a guard, there's got a patrolling behavior, he'll default to looking to where he's
next moving to.
Once he gets there, you could set a default point for him to look at.
So I don't know, maybe he's looking at the entry way to his particular zone.
Something like that.
Anyway, this is what the priorities are all about.
As I say, we weren't have to be using them too much because we're mostly going to be using this gameplay
functionality to say that, hey, there's something interesting going on over there.
There's the player.
So let's go ahead and look at him.
So the first thing we're gonna do is we're going to implement to begin play on our A.I. controller so
that we can set the focus on begin play.
That's just going to be to show us how this function works.
So begin play, as we've probably seen before, it's a protected function.
So we need to create a protected section and then we want our virtual void begin play again to put the
override keyword just for safety here.
And then we're going to go ahead and create implementation over in the C++ and we're going to want to
call to super begin play because that's always good practice, because otherwise things in blueprints
go wrong.
If you forget to do this, you can have a problem with blueprints.
After you've created a big begin play, make sure you check that you're calling to super.
And then at this point, what we want to do is get hold of the porn actor and set the focus to it to
get hold of a porn actor.
We can use a function from the gameplay static's header, which if you hover over their source, search
in control.
Pete.
Fine gameplay static's.
You can find that this is under the kismet forward slash gameplay static's.
So it will go back over to the shooter A.I. Controller CVP and include that.
So hash include and then it's going to be kismet forward slash gameplay static's.
And then we should be able to do our new gameplay static's and use a function from within here which
I find very useful is the get player porn which is gainst return as a point to play a porn.
And it does that by taking in a world context object and the play index.
In our case we're going to find the zero player.
So let's say you get play a porn and do a get world and then we're going to look for index zero and
we're gonna save this into a variable.
A porn.
Which is going to be the player porn like say, that's what we want to focus on.
So it's challenge time for you to set the focus.
Use the play, a pawn that we've just got using our game, play static's function, call set focus and
test it out in the world to see if you move around our different A.I. characters.
Will they follow you?
Will their gaze follow pause video and find out?
Okay, welcome back.
So hopefully it wasn't too difficult.
We need to call set focus because that focus is on a parent.
We don't have to find any pointers here.
We do set focus and what we got here, we just need to put in the actor, basically, because the priority
is already got a default of being set to the game play, which is what we wanted anyway.
So we can just passin in play a pawn and that should be who we focus on.
So let's go ahead and build.
And once that's done, let's hop over to Unreal and play.
For some reason, I still have this pesky spawn point here.
Let's go ahead and delete that and make sure we're spawning near our A.I. character.
Here we go.
Let's go and have a look, a little walk around this A.I. carrots.
And instantly I can see that he is turning to face my porn wherever my porn leads.
So that is the beginnings of some A.I. in place.
I know it's not much, but we're going to work on that, getting this even deeper in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.