In this lecture, then we'll be converting our blueprint project into a C++ project.
And this is something which is super simple to do.
And we even have a few different approaches that we can take depending on your preference.
So the first would be to click the add new button in the content browser and select new C++ class.
We can also just right click anywhere inside of the content browser window and again select new C++
class, or we can just navigate to the file dropdown and again select new C++ class.
So any of these options work and will open up the class creation options.
We're going to start by creating our base class for the player to control so that we can get the tank
moving around and interacting with the world as soon as possible.
This is gonna be the perfect time to take a quick pause and consider which would be the best type of
parent class to fit our requirements.
So from the example of the finished project that I've shown at the start of this section, we can really
see that we're creating a type of vehicle class, which means we probably won't need the complexity
which is included with the character class, such as running and jumping and things like that as we
go for a very Arcady feel to the game.
I also know that we're not going to need to take into consideration things like acceleration gear changes
and suspension.
So that means that the vehicle class would once again be slightly overkill for the requirements.
So for those of you unfamiliar with the class structures in the Unreal Engine, from reading the descriptions
just here, it might suggest that either a pawn or an actor could work for the base class, as both
of these can be placed or spawned in the world.
The main important detail between the two of these, though, is captured just here, and that is that
the pawn is a type of actor that can be possessed and receive input from a controller.
And a controller in this situation is essentially saying player.
So to get a better understanding of what this means, if we take the show, all classes option at the
top of the window will see all of the classes in the engine in order of their hierarchy.
So again, I know this has been covered in the previous action in the inheritance topics.
I won't go into too much detail here.
What we can see, though, is that everything derives from the object class.
And then if we drop down the actor class, we can find that below that we have the pawn class.
If we then drop down the PWN class, we can see all of the other types of controllable classes.
What's most important here is that the actor is going to be the lowest level of object that can be placed
in the world.
And then the pawn is the lowest level of control, all actor that you can either possess as a player
or an A.I. controller.
So for our project, we want as much kind of control and brains over the controllable class as possible
while still allowing it to be possessed by a controller, which means that we're going to want to choose
the pawn class.
So the final thing will just be the naming of our class.
And remember that I said that this will be our base class, meaning that in a similar way that we've
seen that the pawn derives from an actor will be driving our tank pawn and our turret pawn from this
pawn based class.
So go ahead and name the new class.
I would recommend Pawn Base and at the end of the path that string that you can see just here, type
in porns.
This is going to automatically give us a file structure when this is created and it's going to put the
pawn based class into a new folder called Porns.
And as our project is going to be using a lot of different classes, it's gonna be useful to start putting
them into their own folder structures.
This is definitely to help a lot more later.
Now, also worth noting is that in recent versions of Unreal, at least version four point twenty four
and four point twenty five, there's a current issue in the system which is gonna cause us some errors
in the future classes that we create.
So this is gonna give us a great opportunity to look at how we can fix those issues as well.
I'd recommend leaving everything else as it is, specifically making sure not to click the public or
private buttons and then just select the create class button.
So I let that compile and open that up in Vegas code, which will set us up nicely for the next lecture.