All right.
Let's look at the general structure of C++ and we're going to use the code that we're going to write
together in this section as an example.
Now look I only want to focus on this at a 50,000 foot view level if you like at the moment.
Let's just zoom in to that bit in the corner there.
That is the overview that we're not even going to get a read.
So the point is to have an idea of the structure of the code at this sort of literally fuzzy level for
this point.
What we can tell at this level is various attributes of the code.
We can see without actually being to read the detail that there's a bunch of purple include statements
at the top that is including other people's code that we're going to need to write to the terminal before
we even get into our code.
So that's what you're seeing at the top. Then the next thing that we see inside our code is the idea
that the play game with difficulty method that we've written ourself is at the top before the main function.
So we're having to write it before we can use it.
All right.
So there's a big lump there everything inside a given function is indented.
So there's two loads of things that are indented in here.
One of the things that is indented is everything inside the main function.
And the other thing that is indented a few spaces in is everything inside the function that we're going
to write together play that game at difficulty.
Right.
So that's the other thing we can see on a very big picture view.
The other thing that we can see is that we are using indentation when we have things like while and
if statements.
Now we're going to find out exactly what they are.
As we go through the section these are things that control the flow of execution it's saying while something
is happening do this and the indentation helps your eye see what code gets executed when the same with
these things called if statements if some particular condition is true then do this otherwise do something
else.
Right.
So to recap at a 50,000 foot view we can see that we have other people's code included at the top that
this piece of code has two functions you can see that by the indentation and the fact they're only basically
two things apart from the includes that are not indented.
That shows you there are two functions overall.
In our case the main function is at the bottom and then the function that we write is above functions
just a grouping of lines of code will find out all about all of that in just in just a moment in the
next upcoming videos everything inside of functions indented everything inside a control structure like
a while or if his indented the other thing that I'd like you to pay attention to is the fact that the
system is color coding things for us very differently where we have comments this is code that is not
designed to be read by the computer purely for us humans and we use them very sparingly for reasons
we'll talk about later they're in green strings text that we've put in if you like call the magic words
it's just text that we've decided to display to the user for example that's tending to come out in Orange
in this system and then keywords that the system is recognizing is coming out in blue or yellow depending
on the particular type of keyword and then other other things that we have declared ourselves and are
using may come I am white so I won't be precise about what all these different colors mean at this stage
because the amount of terminology that it would bombard you with would be not good but I just want you
to know that the color codes actually mean something and strictly means something that's telling you
something about how the code is structured and you'll start to absorb and realize what this means as
we go through the section.
So really that's all I want to do in this short video is just give you a 50,000 foot overview
of the code now what I want you to do is a bit of a challenges to to go into the community and try and
explain what you think just the main function does.
Now this is a weird challenge for this stage it's like "well I haven't taught you any C++ yet, why?"
Well it doesn't matter how much or how little you know about C++ here.
The purpose really is twofold.
Firstly I'd really want you to be brave enough to go and say well I don't know or I haven't got a clue
or I think this does this maybe it sets a difficulty and then I don't really understand this "while" thing.
However you you put it out there the really valuable thing is the second point which is that you're
going to record in history how much you knew about C++ at the start of this section and then at the
end of the section I'm going to ask you to do a similar exercise and you could look back to your previous
comment and see just how far you've come.
So this is an optional exercise if you don't feel comfortable doing this just don't do it but if you
do feel comfortable go ahead and do it and then after the pause I am going to come back and just explain
in my words what this does.
OK
all right.
Welcome back.
So not going into the rest of the code.
I'm just going to talk about the main function what does it do at a at a high level.
So yes we set ourselves a difficulty level we saying we start the game at a difficulty level of two
and that we're going to stop playing the game when the difficulty gets as high as five.
That's what ten rob a 10.
As I've highlighted.
Now this control structure here this while says while the difficulty or the current difficulty is less
than or equal to the maximum difficulty so the difficulty was two or three or four or five or six or
even 10.
Then we keep doing this thing in here that is indented as we talked about.
OK.
So what do we do all the time that the difficulty is between two and 10 inclusive.
Well we play the game at that difficulty.
This is hiding all the details of how you play the game all the stuff up here.
We can actually collapse down in Visual Studio code.
Obviously you won't have any this code on your screen yet the whole purpose of the section is to write
this code in fact it's the meat of this as you can see there's 43 lines of code or 40.
How many roughly 43 lines of code in play game at difficulty.
That's the meat of it but from a top level view what we're doing is we're playing the game at that difficulty
level.
We are clearing the screen and ignoring the user input and then we are incrementing, this is a code for
how you increase the difficulty by one and then we're going round again.
So we just keep going round and round this little loop of four lines from line 56 to line 59
in circles until it's no longer the case that the difficulty is less than or equal to the maximum difficulty.
And when the difficulty gets to 11 we spit out the bottom and he goes "Wow you're a master hacker" you've
basically beaten the game.
And then that return zero which we've seen before which is of exiting the program and off we go.
All right.
So this is just provided you with a 50,000 foot overview of how code looks how this outline view might
get you some idea as to how it looks.
And I fully expect this code to be completely fuzzy to you at the moment.
You remember how image is used to load on the internet when modems were very slow they would go very
fuzzy to start with and then they get sharper and sharper and sharper as the information came through.
That's very different to learning it kind of like this line by line by line learning from fuzzy to Sharp
is really powerful because you get to see the bigger picture first.
That's what I'm trying to do with you here.
I'm just trying to say this has some structure.
It has some color just recognize that from the beginning and now moving forward we're going to start
going into the very details and writing the actual lines of code.
At least you've got some context to hang this information on.
Another way of looking at it is we're doing a jigsaw puzzle.
This is the outside of the jigsaw first.
Then we go and try and find all the pieces.
All right.
Enough from me on this.
Let's dive in and start actually writing code in the next video.