They're going gonna be a few finishing touches that we can add to our game to make this really feel
like a final small full featured Jamm entry.
And that's what we're gonna be doing in this lecture.
The first very small thing I've noticed is that our projectile is moving through the air in a very kind
of rigid flat way.
It's being launched without any rotation and then flying through the air with accounting for velocity.
To show you a better idea of what I mean, I'm just going to remove the particle system from the projectile
so that we can see it in motion and also slow the velocity so that we can see it moving for a little
bit longer on screen.
And I'll be resetting these changes in a moment.
So don't feel that you need to follow these two steps.
So hopefully you can see from the demonstration in the background, the projectile kind of falls out
of the barrel and then just very rigidly moves to the floor.
And we can really easily improve this with one simple change on the projectile movement component.
So let's go back to the projectile, select the projectile movement component, and we just want to
take the rotation follows velocity option.
And the name here really describes what this is doing.
So I'm not gonna go into detail on that.
But with the speed and everything set back to how it was, we can see here that we get a kind of nice
arc to the path of the projectile now.
So I'm going to put the projectile particle system back on.
And that has fixed that one.
The next thing is that we're currently making the tart's face towards the mouse cursor and we can improve
this, too.
So let's go over to the player, control the blueprint klutz.
And as the controller is in charge of the cursor visibility, we can also change how it's visualized
here as well.
So if we go to the default, Mosko struck down and pick something a little bit more combat themed,
like the cross-hair option that we have here, and then we go another very small change.
But just another quick look at a bit more of what the player controller can do.
And also, neither curse just feels a little bit less default and a little bit more themed.
So one of the bigger things I've noticed is that we can actually drive through walls and other points.
And this is likely because we have all of the porn's default collision set to overlap rather than block
check.
So let's return to the classes and we'll check that again.
So all we should need to do is change this to block all on the collision setup and then we'll do the
same for the pawn Taric class as well.
And again, we've got a very small, quick change here, but this feels much better as this reacts a
lot more high, the player would expect it to.
And then the final thing, and this is definitely something that you can expand on, but that is to
set the level.
So I've created a very small map here with some simple rules just to act as dividers between the targets.
This was intended to allow multiple targets to be used when testing, while also allowing the player
some wiggle room to kind of move around and avoid the shots by hiding behind these walls.
So now that we have something resembling a small game ready to play from start to finish and with a
win lose stakes, we're going to want to share our end product with other people.
So we'll go through the steps needed to package the project, ready to play or hand to a friend or family
member to test three or again for a game of entry ready to submit to the platform of your choice.
Before actually packaging anything, we have a few different things that we can check and update in
the projects setting settings, so the most important of these is going to be in the maps and mode section.
We want to change the default map that the user will be brought into when they launch the game.
So we can see that we have two options here.
And before uploading and sharing the kind of starter project I had already set the default Edita map
or the Start-Up map to be the main map that I've created.
And this just means that whenever you open the project from the epic launcher or by running the You
Project file, we'll be greeted with the main map.
And this just saves us from opening at each time that we start.
Then in a similar way, the game default map is currently set to the entry map, which is the default
empty map generated by the engine.
And the game map is the level that will be loaded when the packaged project is run.
So this means that at the moment, if we gave this to somebody to play, they'd be stuck in an empty
demo map.
So we're gonna want to change this to also be our main map.
Then everything else here is fine as it is.
We can just leave the maps and a moat section and scroll down to the platform section and select windows,
which I'll be demonstrating how to build four.
So we get some pretty interesting options here.
And these are very simple things.
But again, in kind of terms of full developed games or just a game jam injury, things like this can
make your games done that little bit looking a little bit more as though you've gone through the whole
process, adding these splash screens and the lone Tricon just makes your entry standout is a more unique
and refined experience.
And the main benefit has all of these can be customized to fit the same aesthetic or style is your game.
So everything feels like one more kind of complete package.
Now, I don't have any assets here to change these, but do feel free to jump into a Tudi up package
of your choice and come up with some cool designs to swap these out with.
And just in case you're wondering, you can get the desired sizes of the images by highlighting the
elements.
So if you ever forget how big the meant to be, you can just find out what the default icon sizes are
just here.
Okay, so that was just more of a look at the options you can get.
We've made the important changes to our map so we can go back to the main tab.
And from here, if you go to these settings, you can also change some of your project quality settings.
I'll be leaving Meinert Cinematic.
Do note that if you start checking and changing things here, that this can cause the project shaders
to recomposed.
If you don't have time to wait for however long your your system takes to recompile shaders.
Don't go changing too much right now.
So again, just wanted to let you know, though, that that option is there.
But with everything set, we can go and package our project.
We need to this from the file menu, go down to package projects and then select the Windows 64 bit
option.
Now, before this final step, you can also choose your build type between debug game development and
shipping.
So these control how much of the engine specific content is included, such as debug symbols, which
will be included in the debug game option so you can still run through and debug your code this way
or the more stripped out and performance option is the development belt.
But it still retains some of the engine content, such as console commands and some games even released
with this.
I remember playing Ike on the PS4 and I realized that we could actually still run a lot of the unreal
specific debug commands to get some of the stats from the games and stuff.
That was pretty fun to find out.
And then we've got the shipping option, which will take a little bit longer to build.
It's the most performance friendly option, stripped out everything from the unreal systems to us and
only containing the things you need purely to run your game.
So you'll lose things like console commands and stuff like that.
And this is the option usually used for the kind of final gold disc development build release.
For this example, though, I'm just going to leave this as development.
It's the default option and just very easy to work with for our needs.
So let's click to package to Windows.
You're going to need to choose a folder to package the project to and then click the select folder button
to start the process.
So I've packaged mine to the desktop and when everything is ready, you can go to your Windows.
No edit a folder, which generally you're gonna want to rename straight away.
So I'm just going to change this to Toon tanks then inside of the folder.
You just want to launch the application file, which will take us into our main map and we can begin
playing.
And here just to mention as well, a quick step back to the map settings.
When you've got things like the game main map, you'd usually set that something like an animated splash
screen that you might want to introduce to the player when they first load up the game, which would
then transition to the main menu or just go straight to the main menu and let the player then transition
into the level select or however your game set up.
So just an example for this, because we only have the one map going straight to gameplay makes sense,
but in larger kind of more scope like games.
That's how you would use the game default map and the editor default map and the other city for maps
are really handy for when you want to swap the level that you're working on.
So if you know that you're going to be changing focus, you've completed level one and you're gonna
be changing focus and working solely on level two for a while, then you can change your edit a default
map to level two so that every time you close and open the project, that will be the map you immediately
brought into.
OK.
So with all of that done, we've now wrapped up the project in its entirety.
We have the full gameplay loop.
We've looked at some the concepts of inheritance and reusability of classes.
And then also not just making things functional and leaving them.
We've went back and added a Polish pass as well to see how we can make some really simple changes to
our core mechanics or just to add some flat to the mechanics that were already there.
So we're going to exit out of this section and I'm going to leave you with a mega challenge of a sort.
So these are just some things that you can go through.
And I think all of the stuff that we've covered in the section should allow you to easily tackle a lot
of these tasks they'll be providing.
And if you want to do all of them, you can, of course, pick and choose the ones which best suit your
interests.
But there's going to be a nice way to build upon the project that we've just created.
So the first thing would be to add some more level design, maybe bring in your own props or even follow
the kind of aesthetics that I've gone with and just create some extra sections and bring in the use
of more enemies and think of ways that you could make the game play or the level just a little bit more
interesting.
What we had for our development purposes.
So the next thing is a little bit more of a code task, and that would be to add a score system.
So we've already seen the use of blueprint quotable events.
We've seen a way that we can still pass information from our C++ class to our blueprint classes controlling
the widgets.
So you could add something into the game mode, parent class to start tracking the score of individual
targets and then pass that down in a similar way that we're calling a start timer to begin.
You could do this a similar thing to update the amount of score the player has and track this through
the gameplay.
Now, something that kind of goes hand in hand with this would be to create some new enemy types.
So maybe trying to create a new C++ anime porn type in the same way that we've got our porn tank and
our porn at Tarique class.
And then the blueprint derived classes of those or even just make a simple blueprint variant of the
porn star class.
If you were to incorporate a score system into these, then you could set different scores for each
of your different anime porn types.
And on top of this, we've really exposed variables, slight change, things like giving them different
health values, different fire rates, and visualize them with different matches.
So do go ahead and give those a go.
The important thing is, once you've started creating your own take on the projects that I've provided,
start sharing them with the community, get some feedback from other students and definitely look at
helping each other out with the changes that you're you're going through in the projects and see if
you can share any hints and tips between the different new ideas that you'll be coming up with.