Hello everybody and welcome back.
Let's go ahead and see what we're aiming for for this lecture.
So in the last lecture we couldn't escape through this door because it's shut too quickly.
However what we can do is implement a delay and I think there's a delay of two seconds in this particular
example.
So one two.
And the doors were shut.
And obviously that will give us plenty of opportunity to escape the room.
And of course this interestingly gives us the opportunity to also lock someone out of an area.
So if you wanted to gate someone in your gain.
So when they passed through there's now no way of reopening that door from this side.
So that's quite an important gameplay decision if you're making it if you want people to go back through
this door.
They now have no means.
You've got to think about that quite carefully okay.
So in this lecture is really about play tuning our game and being able to configure it.
So if you've got a room that's larger or smaller we'll be able to cater for it.
So we'll be using get world get time seconds.
We're going to be using that so we know how much time has passed and therefore we can actually make
the door open and hold there and then shut again when we need it.
Now this is going to make our game highly play tunable because it's going to enable us to just configure
it however we want.
And of course we can expose that to the editor as well.
We don't even have to go back into the code once that's set.
Now I think I mentioned this in the last lecture so I put it on the slide now so I have to do it.
I don't put a spotlight in that corner to just provide some performance that there's something interesting
over there.
And of course we're going to be play testing to ensure that the game is as annoying as it needs to be
in order to be a challenge for the player.
OK everybody welcome over interface code.
Now what I need to do first of all is just go through the function that will going to be looking at
here.
So we're looking at gets world and then gets world time.
If I remember correctly get gets time in seconds.
Excellent.
So what is that's returning.
That's returning a float which is good.
That means we can take it from another floats in order to do the calculation we need to do your returns
in the time in seconds since the world is brought up for play is stopped when the game is paused.
So is dilated and cramped.
Okay.
So that's really good we can use that in order to count from where we are.
So we can use it to make a timer.
So that means that in here we can say when the door was opened and in fact here we can say something
like door last open because this is going to enable you to open the door and shut it again.
It needs to reset the time.
So the door last opened equals when the door was opened.
Will be the time in seconds which is fine.
And then further down here there's going to be another if statement.
But basically if the door has been open longer than X seconds then closed the door and that will keep
it open for the length of time that we need.
So there are a couple of variables that we need.
Okay.
So we definitely need the float door last open I think this longer than X seconds can be a door delay
or door closed the something like that for longer than the door closed.
Okay.
So we need to make sure that those two variables are available let's go into the header file and I'll
just pop them at the bottom here we're going to have two floats two floats.
There we go.
We're going to have this one here the door last opened and we're going to have the door closed the lay
as well.
And then our last float will be the door closed the lei and we can set that.
Let's give it an initial value of two seconds.
That's 20 seconds.
There we go.
And of course the door last Open will be set within the implementation itself.
Oh this is Mike from the future.
Unfortunately leaving the door last opened without it being initialized is going to cause us a problem.
This will be undefined behavior unless the player and you'll see later on unless the player themselves
starts within the trigger volume then it just won't half of value.
And that can result in undefined behavior because whatever that variable has in its memory address will
be what's assigned.
So I thought it was going to be assigned but it's only assigned if the player starts in the trigger
volume.
So in this particular case I made a mistake there.
And I'll come back to it later.
Slap on the wrist and I'll fix it in a bit.
So for the moment initialize your door last opened to any value zero is absolutely fine.
Remember this is what you're going to need in order to do your calculation.
In fact I'll give you a helping hand just here.
And we'll set the door last opened to that value.
That is what we need in that particular place so the door last opened is whatever the time is in the
world that I give it a stamp then and then we can start counting from then.
And if it's been open longer than the door closed delay then we can close the door.
Now of course that'll be when we're no longer in the trigger zone the trigger volume itself that's when
it will switch down to the else statement down here.
Okay.
Time for your challenge.
Casey your challenge is to go ahead and write some simple time in code.
We've just got to fill in that remaining if statements and get the doors closing after a two second
delay.
Now of course you can change that.
That's the initial thing.
Make sure it stays open for two seconds and then you'll need to play test to ensure that you can't escape.
So see what values you can use so that you can escape and then dial it back until it's just you just
can't get to the door in time.
I know we almost had it before that was a pure coincidence of how everything worked out but play tests
that you can't escape and that will lead us on to needing something else in the scene in order to escape.
OK.
PULLS A video now and give it a go OK everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and delay the doors closing.
OK.
So it really comes down to this potential if statement here.
So we want to say if something then shut the door so this bits of code can go in here.
That's that's crucial there.
Now what do we need so we need to say if the current time take away when the door was last open is greater
than the door closed the delay that we've set up here we've already got two equals two seconds then
we want it's closed the door.
Okay because this door last Open is being updated every frame.
That's the important thing that is always going to be equal initially until it's not for at least two
seconds.
So we're going to get the world and then we're going to gets time seconds again.
Now we could stall that we could we could store this as the current time.
That would be absolutely fine.
So if you wanted to do that then by all means go ahead and then you wouldn't have to tie pin get well
get time seconds every time.
If I had to type it once more I would probably do that.
So if the world gets home seconds at the current time minus the door last open so if it is greater than
the door closed the light.
There we go.
I was wondering if I'd call it that I was thinking I was going to have to hop over here and find out
what it was called.
Okay so let's save that.
Oh we got a bit of funny white space here.
So let's do a tiny bit of tidying as well.
Obviously if you've got funny white space over your document go ahead clean it up as you go entirely
up to you.
And I'm going to just remove this extra bit of white space there.
Okay.
Save my file.
Now I've got some pretty code but it's a functional code.
Let's go find out okay.
So let's go ahead and compile.
Fingers crossed.
Oh I've got a failed pile all during my tidy up I think I've been a bit overzealous at the top here.
Yeah.
Have deleted the quotation mark.
OK no problem.
It's sometimes you know it's good to read these error messages to work out what have I done.
Oh dear silly me right.
It should be all okay now.
Brilliant.
Let's go ahead and press play.
Excellent as back up into the corner.
That looks good.
And one two.
And off it goes.
So when it's fully open obviously at the moment I can get all the way out.
So I need to change those figures to to play Tests but I also want to add in a tiny bit of a fortnight
in the corner.
So might as well do that now going to get my lights drag a spotlight into the corner.
I'm going to go to the four views here by clicking in the top right there so I can just line this a
little bit better with the world Okay where is our torch.
There it is.
Torch.
Spotlight.
It's definitely over the center there gets it over the center here as well.
That looks good.
Now we're gonna go down to the details for it and narrow that cone that cone is far too wide at the
moment so the intensity is fine in a cone angle out Kurt Angle let's bring that in and really focus
in in the cone angle.
Not too fast with that to be honest.
There we go.
Does that push the outer cone angle.
Yes it has.
Fair enough.
There we go.
We've got some performance in the corner of the room and I'm going to adjust my timing now and also
I'm going to have the doors open and shut.
Just a little quicker so that the timing makes a bit more sense.
Let's go back over into our code and the first thing I want to do is have the door slammed shut.
Essentially I'm going to increase that all the way to two.
Then if they extra zero there and the door opening I think I still do want them opening relatively slow
but maybe just a little bit faster there.
Okay.
So now that I've got that what else do I want to do.
I want to change the actual delay itself.
Let's delay it for half a second and see if that's going to give us what we need.
Cause every time you do this you're going to need to compile let's maximize here and might as well build
the lighting as well remember building the lighting only is going to be quicker than building everything
of course.
And once that's done we won't have the error message.
Compiling is complete and we can press play.
So.
Oh look for something in the corner.
We go and stand in it.
The doors open which is really good.
Look they slam really well so let's see if we can get out.
Well that was close.
If we can try again.
It really needs to be felt like it.
You could make it you can make it.
Ah that's really close I think I've got the right values there.
I like the way it slams shut.
Oh that was really close.
So I think there is a chance that you could possibly escape but I think we've I've actually made to
tune it first time relatively well.
Now you may think oh of course you've done Mike because you've got the fingers written down.
Nope.
I just guessed that I bought it thought two seconds was slightly too long.
I thought a second would also be too long.
Half a second gives us that little bit of delay there.
And I like the difference between them opening slowly it's like they're teasing you.
Come on then go through and then you start going and they slam shut on you.
That's exactly the frustration you want to feel like if I can't get through like that how else am I
going to get through.
Of course we're going to have to add something to our scene soon so we can place it in that volume so
we can escape.
Now what values did you end up with.
Did you do a different opening and shock value like me so it slammed shut but teased when it opened
to share your values over in the discussions and I'll see you well in the next lecture.