Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture we're going to look at the increment and decrement
operator since we're about to deprecate the lives every time we get an answer wrong.
So a predicament like a plus plus lives or minus minus lives.
You can see that the decrement or increment operator is before our variable.
If we do it as a post decrement the plus plus or minus minus operator is after our variable.
Now most of the time you probably pre decrement because it makes the most sense logically.
However there are times when you may want to post decrement what's the main difference between the two
then.
Well first of all I'll show you in theory and then we'll go and do it in practice.
Before I ask you to implement lives so pre we'll do the operation.
So in this case adding 1 or subtracting 1 from the value of lives and reference the results.
So if lives was one and you add one to it.
So plus plus lives you end up with two lives.
And that makes the most sense when you're talking about lives.
So we'll be using the predicament when it comes to the challenge.
However post that comment or increment takes a copy increments the value but returns the copy from before.
So if lives was one it would return one but we'll have incremented the variable lives so that the next
time it's used it will be to and there are cases where you might very well need to do that.
So let's go over into the s code and start playing with increments and decrement okay.
So over MVS code I think the first thing I will do is I will start writing some new code at the top
here.
But before I do anything else and get a comment out the game logic we currently have and that's so we
can just play with increments and decrement by themselves.
So let's say that we've got an integer that is called a and we assign it a value of 1.
We then want to go ahead and print out to our terminal and we will need the text macro here.
So text and then we're going to need our text and we're going to need the percentage I.
And the argument that we're going to pass in is simply the variable a.
And of course the semicolon on the end let's check and make sure that works.
And then we can stop playing with a variable and see what we get.
Okay let's go ahead and play our game.
Now what I'm expecting is the moments that I press enter.
We get a value which is a and nothing else.
So that's the exact behavior that I want.
Let's go back over to V.S. code and start playing with these operators.
The first thing we can do here is simply go plus plus a.
Now this is a pre increment so we should get the answer to out.
Let's save our code and run and see what we get.
Let's play our game press enter.
We get the value too.
Brilliant.
Okay.
So let's instead of pre incrementing it.
How about we post increment it.
What would we expect then when we go ahead and print this out.
Well I'm expecting to as well says go ahead compile our game go ahead and press play.
And then when we press center we get the value too.
So that's expected behavior at the moment.
Now how about if we start saying well what happens if we have a new integer called B and we assign it's
a plus plus what are you expecting B to be.
So let's print out a then let's printout B as well as a percentage I because it's an integer and then
comma B let's see what that's like when we run the code.
So when we press enter we get the value too and we get the value 1.
Now that's interesting isn't it.
Let's go back to our code and this is exactly what I was saying at the beginning that when we have a
post increment it returns the original value.
Yes it will still increment a by 1.
Hence a becomes too but B is 1.
So let's remove the comment there.
How about if we have this as a pre decrement instead what will happen then give it some thought okay
let's go ahead and see if you were right.
Now in this particular case we'll be expecting for both the values to be the same because we have modified
the value with the predicament so you can see straight away that if you're not careful with whether
you're pre or post that or incrementing you can end up with code that can end up being confusing and
giving you back undesired behavior.
Now you can even typing code like this.
So if we set another integer declare an integer C and we're going to go plus plus plus plus a and then
finish off that.
So what do you think is going to happen here.
Well first of all let's make sure we can see the result by putting in the format specified and then
including the variable.
So we're going to go plus plus plus plus a.
So what are we going to have as the value of a.
So let's save go over into unreal compile and see what we get.
OK.
We get 4 2 and 4.
Is that what you thought we would get.
Let's have a look at our code and work out what's happened there.
So we've initially got a value of 1.
We then increment that to 2 and then we increment it again twice.
So we end up with four.
And the value of a whilst it was set to two at this point it is now set to four.
Now in general I would say don't do this.
And of course you may ask well what would you do instead.
Well I would do the following if you did want to increment something by 2.
You could say a plus equals to that would be a much better way of writing that.
Let's just check for that evaluates to the same thing don't forget your semicolon.
So we've got our semicolon there are almost missed.
That's okay so we've got percentage up since.
So what is going to happen here.
So we initially have a value of one.
We're going to add one to it.
So now a is going to be two when we print it out.
Then we add two to a again.
So that's going to be for two and four.
But then we go and add another two.
This is much clearer it's a read rather than counting pluses all the time.
So now a is going to be six.
So we should get six two four and six.
Let's go check that now save our work go over into unreal and compile our code careless press play 6
2 4 and 6 perfect.
So it's doing exactly what we think it's going to do but it is rather confusing.
So it's important to write your code so it's readable.
This is much better than this let's just declare a nother integer.
We're going to call this one a and we're going to set it's a plus plus instead let's make sure we can
see it when we go ahead and print out.
Okay so what are we going to get here.
Let's let's run through the codes a is set to 1.
We're then going to increment it by 1.
So now a is set to 2 and B is set to 2 as well.
That's fine.
Then C is going to increments a by 2 and return a value of 4 in this case.
So a is now for C is also for D is going to be incremented by 2 so it's exactly the same as this line
above but it's going to be clearer to read.
So D will take on a value of 6.
I will then take on a value of 6 as well and then finally we've got this and we are post incrementing.
If you remember well that's going to do it's going to return a copy of what it was prior to being incremented
so e will be 6 but a will now be set to 7.
So that's a great example of perhaps when you want something incrementing every time you do something.
But the value to be the value that was there originally.
So let's go ahead run a code and make sure it's got that desired behavior as compile and we should get
out 7 2 4 6 and 6.
Let's go ahead.
Press play when it's ready.
Mary go.
Perfect.
The behavior is working as I expected.
Okay so here is your challenge to implement lives make lives equal to the hidden word length because
at the moment it's just set to 4 and we want it to really vary depending on the length of the hidden
word.
I'll add a nice level of difficulty to lives and then I'd like to show the number of lives at the beginning
of the game.
So when you say all you've got to get a five letter word you have five lives and take a life.
When the player guesses incorrectly.
So once they've made an incorrect guess then you simply take a life and let them know that they've lost
their life as well.
Once you've done that check if lives are greater than zero.
If not you're going to have the end game.
Otherwise of course you will just continue playing bowls of the year now and give that a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and implement lives.
OK everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead and nuke the code that I've just put in.
It's not relevant to our game and let's go ahead and uncommon at all of that lots.
Okay.
So we've got the game running through we've got the lives let's go ahead and set them to the hidden
word length to begin with.
We'll use the dot operator to do that.
So now we've got a hidden word sets a number of lives.
That's fine.
Okay so with our live set to the hidden word length we might as well say you have so many lives that
we could do this in various ways.
I'm going to show I had it here or not.
I'm going to add it as a new line so we'll print line and then we'll go.
Text will need to text macro and then we're going to pop in lives.
That's important.
So here we're going to go percentage I as the format specify and then say you have this many lives.
There we go.
That's good.
Apart from I've put this in the wrong place.
Easily done.
Comma lives.
Make sure we've got enough spacing in there.
And there we go.
Sprint you have that number of lives.
Should test that.
First of all I am a big fan of testing your code as you go.
I'm obviously reading from a script it makes it a lot easier to do.
But do check your code regularly.
Don't just do a load of edits and find out that it doesn't work.
So you have five lives typing your guess and press enter to continue.
OK.
So in this particular case I'm going to do a little bit of editing to that.
You have five lives full stop typing your guess.
And then on the new line I'm just going to go press and continue that will read much better.
I don't need to go back and check that that works.
I'll be fine.
And I'm also going to remove my Random Capitalization.
OK so that's fine.
Now to implement the life being taken away.
So if the game is over we're going to clear the screen and set up the game again that's fine.
Otherwise we're checking the player I guess.
So if it's correct we're going to say that you've won the game and then end the game and the end game
is going to say it's going to set the game over to true and it's going to say press and to play again
and that will clear down the screens will go all the way back here clear the screen that sets up a game.
So that's good.
Now else this is our only failure at the moment.
So what we're going to do here is say else Okay the first thing we need to do here is lives minus minus
or minus minus lives.
That's important.
So before we do anything else we need to take a life.
And then we can make some assessments.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm going to say give the lives themselves greater than zero.
We shall do the following.
But instead of all of this we can kind of say this again but instead of that we are going to go print
line text macro and we're going to pass in lives here is the arguments and say sorry.
Try guessing again.
You have percentage I lives remaining.
Now this is probably going to go off.
Sorry.
Try again and then say you have your lives remaining on a new line.
OK that's good so far.
OK put a semicolon on the end of that.
That's all fine.
So we've got some extra stuff here.
I'm going to go ahead and delete this junk here for the moment because then we're talking about else.
So if the lives are greater than zero do this check and then we come back out for the moment and we're
going to say else we shall mean that we've run out of lives we can print out to the terminal using a
text macro machine printout.
You have no lives left and then we can end the game.
OK.
That looks good to me.
I think we're missing one final thing just saying here.
You've lost the life.
So once again print line I want to put a semicolon on the end.
Blast them that text lost a life.
Not sure if I got too many exclamation marks in here.
Let's go and try our code
okay.
Let's click play.
Let's see what happens when we typing cakes.
We've won one present to play again.
That's good behavior.
We type something else in that looks quite odd that says you have lost and I definitely have removed
that from my code.
I wonder what is calls that the hidden word is five characters last press Enter to play again.
K..
That was not desired behavior.
Let's just check our code.
We've lost the life if lives are greater than zero.
So let's look for the string here you have lost.
That doesn't seem that doesn't seem right to me.
So if I was hoping you have lost.
There are no results.
So I think this is an example of a real being funny is not picking up the right thing no matter how
many times I compile here.
We seem to have a little bit of a bug.
Let's just try it once more and see if it exhibits the same behavior and then we'll load up our project
again and hopefully that will sort it out.
So let's go ahead
is working now odd behavior.
Make sure if you do experience odd behavior it does exactly what you expect it to.
Finally how confusing was that.
It certainly was for me trying to debug that.
It was only when I noticed it had a string in it.
I did not recognize I hadn't type that in a while.
So let's just play it again.
That's typing cake's we have one.
If I typed in something we've lost the life you have four tries remaining.
Now he's not saying that.
One two three four five.
Will give lost life because that's an invalid guest.
We've also tied up that issue where if we typed something in that was five characters it also failed.
And I'm going to win the game because I like winning.
Okay.
The one thing that I notice here is we don't get our debug line on the next run through if we need to
do it on cakes.
We have one that's fine.
We can lose a life.
Sorry.
Try guessing again you have four lives remaining.
That's the exact behavior that I want.
Sorry try guessing you have four lives remaining at the moment we're losing a life regardless of whether
we type in the right number of characters or not.
Let's just make sure that we've got the right number of tries as well.
One two three four five.
You have no life left Pleasants plague.
And if I type in cakes here it doesn't do everything.
So we've got the desired behavior that we want.
Brilliant and one final thing to tidy up our code and 10 points to you.
If you manage to do this if we have a look back at our code we've got minus minus lives.
And then we go ahead and print out lives.
Well what we can do is just deprecate the life there instead.
Nice and neat.
Hey.
So then we can go ahead and delete that line entirely.
Save our work and we should find that the same thing happens without any issue.
Let's make sure we compile our work.
And incidentally if you do find your compilers aren't working do shut unreal down and reopen it again
and that's press play and what we should find now is it still does art deprecation for us and our code
looks a lot neater much more concise.
The only thing that I will want to change over time is that I don't want the docker life.
If someone types in too few characters but that's for another day.
How did you guys get on our game is really coming to life now that we've actually got some lives.
Pun intended.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.