Hello and welcome and this lecture.
We are going to be looking at having some choice in our behavior trees such that I can have our enemy
run towards me.
And if he loses sight of me, he comes to my last known location doing basically two behaviors, a chase
and then an investigate behavior.
Let's dive in and see how it's achievable using behavior trees.
So while this patrolling behavior is very instructive, it's not really the kind of behavior that we
want to implement, what we'd rather have is something along the following lines when we can see the
player, we go and move as close to them as we possibly can.
And when the player goes out of sight, then we try and move to the last known location of the player
to find them.
And once we have exhausted that option, maybe we go back to a different location or maybe just stay
there for now.
So how can we achieve this?
Well, at the moment, we've got no way of achieving this with a sequence of actions.
We need to make a choice based on the data that we have available.
We need to choose between whether we can see the player or whether we can't, whether we've got a last
known player, location or not, that sort of thing.
So to do this, we need a new type of node in the behavior tree called a selective note.
So if we.
Right.
Click and look at our composites, one of the options there is the selector.
Now, the selector, as opposed to the sequence runs thusly.
If you have a bunch of task underneath a selector, it is going to run until the first one succeeds.
And basically it's expecting all of them to fail until one of them succeeds.
Now, the sequence did the opposite.
It runs all of them until one of them fails.
So why is that useful?
Why is it useful that the selector runs one of them and still one of them succeeds?
Because basically we want it to choose the first option that is viable.
Now, the way we're gonna do this is not by actually running tasks underneath the selector, but running
sequences underneath the selector.
So at the root level, we're going to be doing a select a node.
And then beneath that, let's just move this sequence aside and create other sequences.
We're going to have one sequence over here.
And what we can do is we can actually rename the sequence from being sequence to something like Chase,
and then we can add in another sequence here, which is going to be along of the lines of investigate.
And these are basically add to behaviors that we want to be able to choose between.
And in order to make them fail, we can add things to nodes called decorator's.
So if you.
Right, click on a node and go add decorator.
You can see here there's a bunch of options here.
And they basically change the way this node works.
Then they can do that in a number of ways.
For example, we've got this conditional loop which allows you to loop through all the actions again
in the sequence as many times as this conditional is correct.
We've got other things here, like a cone check, which is about visibility and other such lovely things.
We got just a pure loop, got a time limit.
So this can only we can only stay inside this sequence for a certain amount of time.
Basically, lots of things that modify the behavior of this sequence.
But the one that we are interested in is the blackboard, because this is a blackboard condition.
And as you can see from the writing underneath it, the default is something along the lines of is this
self actor set?
And if this is not set, then automatically this node and everything underneath it will fail.
Which means that our selector will go on to option two, which is investigate.
So in this case, we actually want to change this up.
We want to change how this works.
So our player location, we want this to be such that it is only set when the player is visible.
And then we want to add in a new variable here.
Again, a vector, which is going to be the last known player location.
And the last known play location when the player is visible is going to be the same.
But once the player becomes invisible, the player location gets unset.
And the last known player location is where we're going to want to go.
So we can do this by going to our blackboard base condition and just changing it to being the query
to be yes is set.
But the thing that we want to be is set is the player location.
So if the play location is set, then we're going to give Chase and we're going to give chase by doing
basically just a move, too.
And we're going to move to the player location.
Like, so now we're not doing much else under this sequence.
So in actual fact, you could put this blackboard condition directly on the move to.
But because we might wants to other things such as shooting, I'm going to leave it as a sequence for
now.
Then we've got this investigate.
Investigate is basically also going to move to.
But it's going to move to instead of moving to the player location.
It's going to move to the last known player location.
And you can see we don't have a condition on that because this falls through.
If this condition fails, one important thing to note about these Blackbaud conditions is that by default,
once we have made the decision to start executing this node, we're not going to re-evaluate that.
So if for some reason we lose sight of the player while we're moving to that player's location, we're
going to keep trying to get there.
So if we wanted to be able to abort the execution of this note, then there's an option for that.
If you go to the flow control, there's notify observers and there is underneath that observer aborts
at the moment set to none.
But you can select from a couple of options and you can set it to self.
So this is saying if this condition suddenly becomes false, then stop whatever you're doing and re-evaluate
your selector and see, maybe we now need to do the investigate note.
The other option here is lower priority and you can see that it's changed.
What's highlighted here.
It's saying if suddenly this Blackbaud condition became true, stop whatever else we were doing and
start executing this chase condition.
And then the final option is both.
And this is the one that we want.
Basically, it's saying that this Blackbaud based condition, if it becomes true, we start executing
the sequence immediately.
If it becomes false, we stop executing it immediately or stop executing whatever else was going on.
We just basically want to always go and do whatever path is dictated by this Blackbaud condition.
So hope that makes sense that the observer aborts stop things in action, otherwise it will wait until
the action is finished before re-evaluating.
So really now we want to go ahead and implement our last known place location and play a location,
because at the moment, if we go over to our C++ and give ourselves a little bit more room, then you
can see that we're only setting this play location in begin play.
Ideally, we'd be doing this every time we have line of sight to our play porn so we can actually uncommented
our line of sight code here.
And we probably wants a uncommented the ELT's code as well.
But we're not, in this case, going to be clearing focus and stopping movement directly.
I can go ahead and remove these entirely.
That's not the way we're doing things at the moment.
Instead, what we want to be doing if I remove the code is we want to be in here setting the playout
location.
We also want to be setting the last known location there.
And in ELT's, we want to clear the player location.
Now, to do that, we have got a function available to us, which is instead of the set value as vector.
If we go ahead and open our Blackbaud component dot h.
There is a clear value.
And this just takes the F name.
Doesn't need to take a type or anything or because we're just completely erasing whatever was in that
variable.
So here I got a challenge for you to fill out our tick set the two variables.
When Linus sites basically fill out this first bit of the if statement and then clear the player location
when we have the ELT.
So when we lose line of sight, we don't have a player location anymore.
Reduce the speed of the enemy that's in the world so that you can get away from him more easily.
And then check the functionality.
Check that you're able to hide behind a corner and that he goes to the last known location to try and
find you post a video and have a go at this.
Okay, welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
First of all, we're setting the play location.
I'm going to move that out of begin play and move it here instead.
So going to set the player location to we need to be getting the play a pawn here and take again.
So I'll uncommented that line and then we're doing exactly the same thing, exactly the same line of
code for our last known player location here.
So let's go to our blackboard and just make sure we copy it so we get exactly the same name.
And then we just want to clear.
That's the final thing, is to clear our play location here.
So it's gonna be clear value and it's going to take this at Tex.
Player location as the value that we're trying to clear at the end.
And we can go ahead and compile and see if this works.
While compile was successful, the other thing I said to do to make our debugging easier was to select
the enemy and we can go and change their speed by going down to their movement components and finding
the walking and finding their speed.
So, Max, walk speed is 600 here.
Let's set it down to two 400 so we can easily get away from them.
They're going to walk a bit slow and go ahead and play.
They are walking towards us slowly.
We can run away.
We hide behind a corner and here they go.
Come looking for us each time.
But hopefully if we hide behind two corners, they won't be able to find us.
So I hide their hide here, hide here.
And he's gonna go and investigate at the last known location.
You see, he's just poked his head round the corner, but then he's stuck there because he doesn't know
what to do.
And if we were to go and have a look at our behavior tree and just put this over to one side and the
game to the other and give myself a little bit of room, then if we have a look at the behavior tree,
we can see it's kind of jazzing around here because it can't do either of them.
It's trying to move to the last known location that's succeeding.
So it's getting a bit stuck here.
But if I come into view, you can see he's moving towards me.
If he loses sight of me, then he goes over to the investigate condition, so loses sight.
He's going to investigate.
And then he comes and sees me.
And then he goes back to chasing me.
So this behavior is actually working.
Now we're able to do a choice between trying to chase and trying to investigate based on this Blackbaud
behavior.
Let's just change the name of this blackboard to behavior here.
Two can see player questionmark.
So that's going to be much easier to read.
Now we've got this selector can see the play.
Then we should chase.
Otherwise, we should investigate and we can delete this sequence over here because that is no longer
in use.
So hopefully now you've got a bit of a better understanding of how behavior trees can be linked together
to create choice and sequence and put lots of tasks together to make more complex behaviors really easily
in the next lecture.
We're going to be looking at how we can make our own custom tasks in C++ so that we can get some shooting
action.
I'll see you in the next video.