Hello everybody and welcome back.
Now before we get on to actually creating our function that's going to loop through these strings.
I want to talk about const functions because this is an ideal time to actually touch them.
Now by using const you protect yourself.
It means constant and it means that you're making a promise that whatever you're doing within your function
that it will not edit or alter the member variables.
So in general if a function doesn't change any member variables of the class make it a constant by using
the keyword contest.
And I'll show you where that goes in a few moments.
And it also has the added benefit that your idea will end up with red squiggles everywhere.
And it makes sure your functions aren't going to modify your classes when you don't intend them to.
Now there is a get out clause.
There's a keyword called mutable.
We'll cover that later on in the course.
And also as I've been saying constantly so far is also referred to as a contest function so whether
you call a contest member function or a contest function they're both the same thing.
OK.
So before we go over into V.S. code a couple of things to cover with const functions.
First of all they cannot call non const functions.
So if you states that your function is const it's not going to alter any of the member variables of
the class.
You can't go ahead and call a function that would do and then const objects can only call const functions.
This is important it adds consistency and safety to your code.
And you'll get lots of chance to practice const as we progressed through the course okay.
So before we actually have a look at how our functions themselves let's go all the way up and have a
look at the first instance because const has been here since the very beginning.
So it's time to start unraveling what this means.
Things like this are often easier to read from right to left than they are moving forward.
And what this literally means is that this is a reference to a string whose contents will not be changed.
Now we have a look at how functions themselves.
But while before we do that let's have a look at these member variables here.
So over in the header file we've got three member variables declared which basically means that we cannot
make any function count that is altering these.
So we have a look at our code itself which starts with these two here that begin play and on input Well
neither of these can be const functions for a start.
The setup of the game if we scroll down here it alters all three of our member variables.
So we definitely can't have that.
This is an example here of where you cannot make a function count that then goes ahead and calls non
const functions.
So here the next one as well on input we definitely can't do let's carry on down the setup of the game.
Absolutely not.
End Game.
No we cannot do that.
It changes the states.
The big game over this is an interesting one here.
We've got the process guess function now.
At first glance it could almost be made contact and we could indeed make it const.
Apart from this whole lives thing here.
So what we could do is perhaps take all of this out.
This section of code here these first three checks before we decrement the life put that into a concept
function because none of this alters any member variable.
So we could do that.
I think it's better at the moment to just leave it in line for simplicity.
There is such a thing as over engineering your code and this is a relatively straightforward game.
And since this is all about processing the gas and what happens during the process of the gas then I
think keeping it all in one place is a good idea.
But if you want the extra challenge to move that into its own function then go ahead and do that.
Now if we go down to our final one the one that we're working on at the moment and this is why it's
a good time to start covering contest at this time is we're not touching any of the member variables.
We're taking a word in and we're assessing it and then we're feeding back the results straight into
here where we go and check if it's a nice gram or not.
So that means that we can make this concept.
So why do we put this const keyword.
Well simply here we put it on the end and the moment we put that keyword on there we're going to get
a red squiggle.
It's not declared so we've only made the definition contest at the moment and it is possible to have
const and non const versions of your functions which can get confusing.
But we'll leave that there for the moment.
Go to the header file.
So then we've got the is ice ground function here.
We go to the end of it and also add in the keyword count there and save our file.
We will then find that this itself the red squiggle disappears because we have declared a contest function
is Isaac gram and then we're defining it down here.
Perfect.
So there's not really a challenge to go along with this lecture other than the ongoing challenge to
make sure that when you're working with functions that do not alter your member variable make sure you
add concept to it.
In fact there's a very good resource that I'll add to the lecture resources that is called const correctness.
Now as a beginner this is going to be a bit confusing.
It's one of these things that doesn't make much sense in C you get into bigger code bases where it becomes
almost essential to make sure that something funky isn't going to go on in the background.
So make sure from the very beginning you practice this very good practice of protecting yourself because
otherwise it will come back to bite you later on.
So that's it for this lecture.
Simple one they're adding the cons keyword to the end of our function and we're good to go and I'll
see you all in the next lecture.