Hello and welcome and this lecture, we're gonna be looking at hooking up our character movement so
that we can move forward, strafe and look around our world, the classics of moving around in a first
person or third person shooter.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So continuing along in the vein of trying to get our character movement working, we are, first of
all, going to want to bind some input.
But we're also going to know want to know what to bind that input to.
Fortunately, when it comes to characters, there's a lot of simplifying stuff going on for us, after
all.
Unreal really is an engine that's optimized for making things like shooter games, character games.
And let's have a look at some of the movement functions are already provided for us by the character
actor class, not just the character movement component, but also the character actor class provides
these and often passes a lot of this onto the character movement component and on Cirilli.
So let's see what movement functions we're gonna be dealing with.
First of all, there is going to be add movement input, add movement input basically takes a vector
and tells you which direction you gonna move in.
So if it's a forward vector, you move forward.
If it's a backwards vector, you move backwards, if it right vct move right and so on.
And the size of the vector is going to determine how fast you move in that direction.
The next thing is we've got ad controller pitch in input.
So that's about looking up and down, which is obviously very useful.
When you've got your mouse, you want to be looking up and down by moving your mouse up and down.
Then there's ad controller, your input, which is going left and right.
And finally there is a jump function, which is just that maybe you hit the spacebar and you jump.
So with these things in mind, what we want to go ahead and do is create some bindings in our character
actor class that's bind some input or some inputs on your keyboard, your mouse, your controller to
these functions so we can do a few and then we're gonna do a challenge to do the rest.
So let's go over to Visual Studio Code, and I'm in my shooter character Dot H.
And we noticed that we've got already here the set up a player input component function.
This is where we need to bind our inputs.
I'm gonna hit alt o to go over to the C++ and find where we've got that set up.
So the first thing is it gives us this play input component that we want to bind with.
If you remember, this is the way we do it.
We have a player input component.
Here's the Arrow operator and we then do a bind function here.
So it's either a bind access or it's going to be a bind action depending on whether it's a discrete
actions such as jump or whether it is an action as a value, such as looking up and down or moving.
Moving doesn't with a key, but moving does when you have something like a controller.
So really, to take a step even further back, we need to go ahead and set up these actions and axes
in our project setting.
So let's go back over into one real go to settings, project settings, and then I'm going to dock this
down so we can see it very clearly and we're going to go to the input section.
So engine input and set up some axes, mappings and some action mappings.
So the ones I'm going to deal with right off the bat are the axes mappings for we're going to have,
first of all, a move forward.
And we're going to have also a look up, Nahrawan.
We don't have a move forward and a move backwards because we can just do that with negative scale.
So, for example, I want to set up my W key to be my move forward.
So that is scale one.
But if I want my esky to be my move back, I can still use move forward, but give it the scale of minus
one.
Just a quick reminder for you.
Same with look up.
I'm going to be using the mouse for this.
Will can cover controller input in the next lecture.
We're going to use the mouse.
Why?
Now remember.
Why is the one that goes up and down rather than left and right?
Because it's kind of a bit taller, isn't it?
A Y is a little bit of a taller letter than an X.
That's how I remember it anyway.
So Mouse Y is up and down.
And then we'll have to tweak with the scale, see whether it's going in the right direction.
But basically, this will give us negative values if we're going down and positive values if we're going
up.
So we may need to tweak we'll look up to see whether this is going to go in the right direction.
But you get the idea we can either invert the scale or not, depending on the type of input that's coming
in here.
So once we've got the axis name, we can go back into the C++.
We're going to bind it using the text macro and the text of the axis name.
Then we need to say who we're going to call the function on and what function we're going to call.
We currently don't have a function that we want to call.
So I'm going to go and create a new private function over in my C++ header file.
And it is going to be a void function that is going to be called move forward.
And it's going to take the float, which is going to be the axis value.
Finish off with a semicolon and go little tricky little extension here that helps me implement these
things a little bit quicker by doing control shift P and.
If I type in create implementation, it goes ahead and create site implementation for me in the C++
file.
Really nice and easy.
The name of that extension if I go over.
I always forget the names of my extensions, so I'll go and have a look for what it might be.
Yes, it's this little doozy here.
The C++ helper, if you go ahead and install this one for your Vyas code, it just allows you to do
that sort of thing, which is very nice.
Very handy.
So this is the function that we want to set it up to call.
So, first of all, we say this, this is the target.
The current object is the target for this function.
Then we go ahead and put in the issue to the fully qualified function.
H's character, Chalong Kolon, move forward.
And that should bind us to this function.
And then finally, what we want to do is pass that access value on to the function that we actually
want to call, which is a parent function.
So we don't have to do anything.
We can just do add movement.
Input.
Like so.
So because this is the move forward method, we want to have the forward vector of the actor.
So the way we do that is we can do a get actor forward vector like so.
And then we want it to be forwards in the amount that our axis value gives us so we can multiply by
the axis value.
And that's going to give us the right result.
So we're going to have the forward vector multiplied by the axis.
Value his one.
Go forward.
If it's minus one, a forward vector becomes a backwards vector.
And we're going backwards with just this one function.
So that's set us up with at.
Move forward.
Great.
The next thing is to bind for our look up.
So let's go.
And Koppio, we'd like to copy these string references so that I don't make a mistake and do a look
up.
And instead of binding to move forward, let's go back to the head of file and create something new.
It's going to be look up.
And again, a float axis value.
Like, say.
And if I do control Sheriff P and do create implementation, goes ahead and saves me a little bit of
time, and this time, instead of doing ad movement inputs, we want to use one of those other functions
that we had at our disposal.
Namely, the ad controller pitch input because want to pitch up basically.
So this time we can do ad controller.
Pitch input and pass indirectly the access value.
Now the a bit more experienced C++ programmers among you might say, hey, this function basically does
nothing.
It is just calling some other function with the same parameter.
So it's not really doing very much.
And you would be right.
So what we could do is we could do the a shooter character look up.
So we could call the function that was defined on this class.
The a shooter character.
Or we could say, well, there's ad control.
Pitch inputs that we could just call that are readily, couldn't we?
So if we use at 12 to find out where that's defined and you go and navigate to it, you can see that
it is being defined in actually porn.
Dot h.
So if you scroll up, you can see here all the way up here somewhere.
We're going to find a class.
This could even just search for class space, something like that.
And here we've got a porn is the class.
So let's go back to the shooter character and what we can try and just make this a little bit shorter
by saying instead, let's do a porn Kolon Kolon ad controller pitch input so that it automatically just
directly calls that parent function rather than having to go via our own function.
This is a valid way to do as well, but it's just not necessary.
So I'm going to comment it out so that you can refer to it and see it if you wants to do it that way.
But I would recommend doing it slightly shorter routes like so.
Oh, and trying to compile it.
I noticed that instead of calling BINDE Access, as I had been wanting to do, I've been doing binde
action.
So you've probably been screaming at your screen the whole time.
Let's go ahead and build that again.
By the way, I'm doing that with a control shift B and selecting the build option.
That is the simple shooter.
Ed Wynn, 64 development build just a quicker way for me than going over and hitting the compile button.
I'll look and I can't get my syntax right today, of course, we need to use the ampersand in front
of this function to say basically that we want to get the pointer.
We want to use the ampersand in front of these functions to actually have the correct syntax here.
OK.
So after I corrected those two very common errors, one being that I'd got the wrong function call and
the other being that I had gone ampersand in front the functions I'm trying to use.
Let's go over into one real and see whether this is actually working.
If I go ahead and hit play and use a W key in the ASCII, you can see I can move forward and backwards.
It's amazing.
And with the mouse I can look up and down but is feeling inverted at the moment to my movements.
So I'm just gonna go over to the product settings and hit minus one in there and go ahead and hit play.
And now if I go up and down, it feels correct.
Notice that I'm actually spawning in two different locations.
That's because I have to play a starts.
When I put the second one in, I didn't realize there was already one in the level, which is why I'm
sometimes spawning here, sometimes spawning in a different location.
You might find the same thing.
So it is challenge time.
Let's get you guys binding your move.
My rights and your look rights so that we've got full control of our movements.
So repeats the process that I've just done in the lecture.
For both of these two and you've probably been following along, if not, you can go in and watch to
revise.
And also, I'd like you to attempt the jump function as well.
If you're feeling brave, pause video and have a go.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
First of all, we're repeating the above steps forward.
Move forward and look up.
So we're gonna be having move, right?
And we're gonna be having a sort of look up.
We're gonna be have a look.
Right.
And we can go ahead and copy these to set up our axes in the project's settings.
So add another couple of axes mappings.
The first one gonna be move.
Right.
Which I'm going to map to the key, a four left.
So that's going to be the minus one is going to be minus one because we've actually left the opposite.
Right.
And D is going to be four going right now.
Obviously, you can add in the Arrow Keys here as well.
I'm just not doing that save time.
But you can go ahead and do the same thing.
You can just add more keys here, as many keys as you like to map to that single axis.
Look, right.
We're going to use the mouse x.
And I think one should be sufficient rather than minus one, we.
I don't think we have to invert this one.
And then what we're gonna do is we're gonna bind this slightly differently.
So I'm going to go out o to go and create ourselves a move.
Right.
Function here.
Now, you might be wondering, why are we doing this differently, why is move right?
Why we're not just calling straight add movement input.
The difference is here we're doing a bit of calculation.
We're adding in this multiplication by a vector, which is adding a bit of information and justifying
the existence for this function.
So this time, instead of getting the act of forward, we want to get the actor right vector like.
So multiply it by the axis value.
And then we want to be calling instead of move forward.
Want to be calling.
Move right now for look.
Right.
Instead of adding the controller pitch.
Input.
We want to be doing the your inputs.
Remember, roll pitch and you're from airplanes.
You can look it up on Wikipedia.
If you're not sure which one is which.
And go ahead and build that one.
Hopefully this time I haven't got the syntax wrong.
Let's dive over to the editor and hit play.
And they go, I can look all the way around me, that's looking good.
I can strafe left and right.
I can go forward and backwards.
So the thing left for us is jump just gonna be an action mapping rather than an axis because it's a
discrete action.
Kind, I call it jump and copy it.
Go over.
It's a visual studio code.
And just close down my compile window and here I'm going to instead of binding an axis.
You've got it.
I'm going to be binding a action bind.
Action.
Simple as that.
I'm going to start off still with the text here.
Of jump.
But the thing that is different with axes, as you probably remember.
Is we need to use this syntax.
I inputs events, which just an enum, which means that it basically can take a number of these different
options, double click, press release, et cetera.
We're going to want to jump on press like.
So.
So that's i.e. underscore prest.
And then once we know that, we can go ahead and do the same this and then we want to be calling to
jump.
Now, where is jump defined?
Is it in the pool?
Let's have a look.
No.
But it might be in the character.
So I'm going to do a control P and look for character dot h.
Open that up and just have a look through here.
See if they have a jump function defined in here, jump and then open brackets often is a good way to
look for functions within the header files.
Sure enough, we have got that function.
You can see the documentation.
I often like to use that source code directly rather than looking at any documentation files.
I just find it sometimes a lot quicker to access, especially when you have access to control P in visual
studio code.
So what we need to do is instead of going pawn Kolon, Kolon, we need to do a character, Carol, on
Kolon.
So it is going to be ampersand, a character Kolon color on this is because that's the class is defined
on.
We can't go looking at the hierarchy when we're doing this Kolon Kolon operator and then this guy is
just going to jump.
So character Kalanchoe on Jump.
And don't forget that I need a semicolon on the other line.
Go ahead and build and see where the raible to jump now.
Well, the build worked out correctly.
Let's go over to the sandbox level, hit play and try and jump.
I don't have any key bound, so that might hamper me at the space in as the key that I want for jump.
And go ahead and hit play.
Yay!
I'm able to jump up and down and move through the air and move around.
Fantastic.
So we've learned how to bind our axes and actions where we haven't learnt it.
We have revised it, but we've seen what we want to bind to in a character in order to get that classic
character jumping, strafing, moving and looking with your camera that we all know and love from our
shooters.
The next lecture will look at the nuances required for moving with a controller as well as a keyboard
and a mouse.