Hello everybody and welcome back in this lecture.
We're gonna have a closer look at looping in C++ now the broadly speaking there are four different types
of looping and in this lecture we're going to cover three of them in detail and just mention the other
one and we might look at that later on in the section and certainly later on in the course.
So the while loop itself is one variance and then we have a do while which we will see is like an inverse
of the while loop.
Now a for loop is another option so those are the three that we're going to look at in this lecture.
And one interesting thing is that a four and a while loop are essentially the same type of loop.
However they are written differently and also they tend to be used differently as well depending on
what type of loop you're running through a do while loop has a slightly different execution flow we'll
have a brief look at that and the other one the fourth one that we're not going to dive into details
in this lecture is a range based for loop which is typically shortened to range for.
So first of all the while loop so a while loop and all of these loops are very much like an if statement
they'll have a condition.
And once that condition is true they can execute the code within our curly braces.
So whilst the condition is true we could be counting a number whilst i is less than 10 let's say we
can execute a certain code and we can also increment or decrement that particular variable that we've
got counting up.
Now while loops will always check fact condition first.
So if that condition is false that code within the curly braces will not be executed.
Use these when the amount of loops is unknown so we'll unlikely to use them in this particular example
that we're working on our game here because we know exactly how many iterations we're going to do it
will be the length of the hidden word all the input minus one for instance.
Okay.
So let's have a look at the for loop next a for loop would be written out like this.
We've got an initialization so we might set a counter to 0 or maybe to 10.
It depends what you're trying to achieve.
And then we have our condition.
So whilst that condition is true the code is going to be executed.
And then like I was saying at the beginning of the counters at 10 perhaps you're going to count down.
So whilst we can increment we can also decrement as well.
And it doesn't always have to be by 1.
It does depend on what you're trying to accomplish in the code certainly in our examples coming up.
We'll just be doing it by 1.
Now use these when you know how many times the loop will be run.
And we have a pretty good idea of how many times the loop will be run.
In the case of our words the do while loop we won't go into that in too much detail here.
But basically it's like a while loop.
But the code to be executed will be executed first regardless of the condition.
So there are certain examples where you will want your code to be executed at least once and then of
course whilst the condition is true it will continue doing that.
But if the condition ended up being false basis it won't run it anymore so we'll execute it at least
once.
That's a big difference between the two.
So let's go dive over into v as code and start playing with our loops.
Okay.
Welcome over into V.S. code.
Now let's have a look at where we can place our test code.
I'm gonna do in setup up game again.
I'm not going to delete this block of code here that's going to be useful for later on during your challenge
when we actually start thinking about how to access elements of an array.
But first of all let's do the basics of a while loop.
Okay so let's start typing if we go while and then press tab we can set up our condition.
Now I'm going to say why I is less than 10.
Now you may be asking okay why Lesson 10 why why are we picking that word this is just an example of
We're counting up to let's say 10 elements of an array.
Now the issue here of course is you may say well why is it less than 10 and not less than or equal to
10.
Well remember when we're accessing the first element of the array is in fact 0.
So we're going to count up to nine.
And when it hits 10 when the counter hits 10 the code will no longer execute.
So here for instance to test this I can print out to our terminal so we can actually see what's going
on.
It's a print line.
It will need to be in the text macro.
There we go.
And what are we printing out here.
That's actually printout so formats specify I.
And then print out I.
Now the problem here of course is we've got a red squiggles and and it's saying Well let's remember
a semicolon.
It's saying here if we hover over this undefined we need to say what I is now I is going to be an integer.
It's counting up so in 32 I equals zero because we're starting at the first elements of an array.
In this particular instance.
So there we go.
But what would this do if we just ran our code.
There's no need to launch our game and test this we can logically go through this.
So I is equal to zero while I is less than 10 which it currently is great.
We're going to print out whatever I happens to be.
Okay but we're not doing anything to.
I.
So this will just be one of those infinite loops.
It's just going to continue printing out zeros in this particular case.
OK.
So we can hear incremented I plus plus or semicolon.
And now it's going to change the value to one.
It's going to assessor is I still less than 10.
Yes.
So I'll print out one print out to print out three until it gets to Nine it will print out nine it'll
increment it will come back up to the condition I is now 10 and that's it.
This code here within our curly braces will stop being executed.
Now let's look at the same code.
But this time in a for loop so first of all this is where we initialize something.
So in this case and in 32 I equals zero.
So whilst I is less than 10 and then we increment and then we can take what we were doing before and
pop it straight in there.
If we save that now both of these bits of code do EXACTLY the same thing.
And this is what I mean by a for loop being better for a known count.
You can see here this is nice.
This is only for lines of code.
This one is a lot more cumbersome.
I would say so I would use a while loop when you don't really know how many times you're going to iterate
round a loop.
Okay.
So before we move on to your challenge I want to cover a do loop really quickly let us in this case
also run the same sort of code.
So whilst I less than 10 which is good.
What are we going to do.
Well we're going to print out the same thing here.
Now what we haven't done is we haven't given I a value.
So let's go into 32 I equals zero.
So in this particular case this will do exactly the same as everything else is done.
Apart from we also need to go here.
I plus plus.
So it's always going to execute this first then it will say whilst it's less than that.
So this this is an interesting one there are a couple of things that we can do and play with this particular
do while loop.
We do need our semicolon.
OK.
So let's have one final look at how do while loop we know if it set to 10 it will print out 10 because
it will run through and execute the code at least once.
However if we set this to zero do you think you will also still print out 10 or will it stop at 9.
Well let's run through it.
But maybe with a smaller number than 10 let's just go for two in fact I'm going to change all of the
tens too because when we run it in the moment just to check everything works how we expect it to over
it in our game it's going to be a bit cumbersome if everything goes off of our in-game terminal.
So let's have a look here.
Let's run through the codes.
I is set to zero and we're going to do this and we print out zero and then we increment I while I is
less than 2.
Ok so I is now one we print how the value of one and then increment incremented six now two while I's
than 2.
No it will stop.
So all of these should printout 0 1 0 1 0 1 providing we.
Now go ahead and change the variable names so let's go ahead and change these eyes.
Now if I hold down control I can select multiple eyes at the same time.
Really useful because I can place the cursor there.
I can delete that.
And because we're dealing with unreal remember you need a capitalization on your variables to meet the
code standard.
So let's do these eyes as well.
We've got those ones there.
I must switch that out to a J for this particular instance.
So we can run our code real quick.
Let's go ahead and save compile our code.
Hopefully all is well with it.
Excellent.
With everything compiled we press it we get 0 1 0 1 0 1.
Perfect.
OK.
So we've had a bit of a diver over into loops and the various ways they can be put together.
And now it's time for your challenge Okay so this challenge is really just the beginnings of making
sure we can go through our head in word and print out those characters.
We will then build upon that to assess the letters against one another.
So what I'd like you to do is basically print out each character of both our hidden word and our inputs
on a new line in our in-game terminal sets the number of iteration to the words length and test them
one at a time.
Now what I would recommend that you do because you could quite easily do this in multiple ways.
I'm going to guide you down the path of using the is I as a Graham function for this code and then passing
in the hidden word and input elsewhere into the is I saw Graham function in order to execute and print
out both the hidden word and the inputs.
Remember to test them one that's a time to make sure that it's working first of all before you dive
into deep pause the video now and give that a go.
Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and print how each character of both our hidden word and our inputs okay.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is just clean up our code.
I don't need all those loop examples.
Let's save the work.
Now the first thing I'm going to do we're going to call is Isaac ram.
The beauty of this is we're already calling it for the inputs.
So we have a look up here.
The input is being passed into processed gas and then when we get here the gas itself which is the same
string coming through is being passed into is Isaac gram so providing that this is code which means
that the hidden word length is right and it's not the hidden word that has been guessed.
We should get it repeating out whatever we've got.
So we'll test that one first and then we'll call it from another place for the hidden word itself.
So we know we're going to be using a for loop.
I'm going to set a initial condition integer.
Now I could just leave it as I however I want to set it to something else like index.
So you've got index there whilst the index is less than.
Now even though we're doing the the inputs here we're not typing in inputs because this function has
no idea what inputs is it's completely out of scope.
However what it does have a notion of Is word so you can put the word dot length now the reason why
we're doing this if you remember is the elements that say element three of the array is the fourth letter.
So that's absolutely fine.
So won't go any larger than one minus the length of the word essentially which is great that's exactly
what we wanted to do and we're going to increment index by one every time so it will go through every
single letter of our word.
Now what do we want to do.
Well we want to print it out.
So if we go print line text macro and plop in there a character so percent it's safe as the format specified
and then we need to tell it what character that is.
So that will be the word we know that's the variable we're using we'll open up our square brackets here.
The square brackets in this form are called the subscript operator.
In this particular case we're going to have to pass in a value there.
We've already got the value we're using it as index.
So this is a great example of when we're using a variable rather than a magic number in that.
And that's what we wanted to try and get with all of our code.
Excellent.
So that's all we need to do at this particular point if I save my file here go over into bulls and cows
and compile my code.
What we should do is hopefully get it working when we press play.
It won't do anything initially but we'll have to type in something that is the right length and it should
repeat it out on each individual line.
So if I go and go quiet for instance it repeats.
That's how if I do bakes it will do that.
Perfect.
Our code is working as we would expect it to.
Okay.
Now the other part of the challenge was to also do the hidden word itself.
Now the hidden word is set all the way up parents set up game.
Now it doesn't really matter where in our code we decide to call is Isiah Graham to run that but we
could do it here.
That would be absolutely fine.
So we called is Isiah Graham spell it correctly.
Is Isiah Graham.
There we go.
And pass in here the hidden word
what we should find is that when we run our game and we will need to compile first it will print out
the hidden word character by character on each individual line and then the other bits that we did.
Well that should work as well.
Excellent it's finished compiling a.
There we go.
We print it out cake's line by line and our other bits of code should be working absolutely fine.
So then how did you guys get on.
I hope you managed to conquer loops loops are incredibly useful and used all the time.
So getting a handle on them nice and early is really important.
I hope you've had lots of fun playing with a full load.
We going to build on that to create a more complex form that's going to be checking letters against
one another and that will be in the next video.
Please share your work.
Any questions ask over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.