Hello and welcome.
In this lecture, we're gonna be creating a killer all game mode, which is going to be just one of
the possible game modes that we can create due to having a virtual pawn killed method that could be
called on any of the game modes that we want.
Let's dive in and see how we're going to implement this virtual method.
So we would like our game to be able to end.
What does it mean for a game to end?
It means that we go into some sort of state where we are the one or we've lost.
We inform the player using some UI.
We give them the option to maybe restart and play again, something along those lines.
Now, the classes involved with this typically are a game mode.
The game mode is responsible for deciding rules about the game, such as who won and who lost.
And for that, we're going to need to know who is being killed so we can have this virtual method here
called Pawn Killed, which will be called from our shooter pawn when it dies, whether or not it is
the A.I. or is the player that is doing the dying.
And furthermore, I want to add a little complication here, which is that we'll have different game
modes derived from our main shooter game mode.
They will implement that game mode.
That's what the arrow means here.
It's often a little bit counterintuitive the way the arrow goes, but KMEL game mode inherits from the
shooter game mode and it overrides pawn killed in order to count up and decide differently on the rules
of the game.
So that's why I want to put a virtual pawn killed method over in the parent shooter game mode and then
implement or override it again in the kill or game mode, which is going to be the game that we're implementing
for ourselves.
And you might choose to do different game modes where maybe you just want to kill a certain amount of
the enemies in the level rather than all of them or something along those lines.
Maybe a capture the flag, something different.
But basically, what's going to happen is the shooter porn is going to find the game mode.
That's got the type shooter gay mode and is going to call it's porn killed.
And then depending on whatever implementation there's actually there, it's going to go through to the
implementation via the override.
Now, another complication here is that our UI logic and restarting logic is really something that should
happen in the player controller UI generally being the purview of the player rather than something global
like the game mode.
This is especially true in games that are multiplayer because the game mode doesn't actually exist on
the players machine.
Only exists on the server.
So any UI stuff should be going on in the player controller.
That's a complication we don't need to worry about because this is not a multiplayer game, but it's
still good to use the classes for what they're expected to be used for in general.
So the player controller at the actual root play controller class has a virtual method called game has
ended specifically for this purpose.
So that's the game mode can call this method and we can implement it in our own shooter play controller
to do UI, restarting all that sort of stuff, but will need to be calling it from our game mode when
we have decided that the game is over.
So we'll call the virtual game has ended on the root player controller and then because that root player
controller is actually a shooter, player controller will end up diverting back and calling.
This game has ended.
So it seems like a circuitous route.
We're gonna be calling from our shooter pawn via the shooter game mode to the KMEL game mode, to the
player controller, to the shooter player controller.
But this allows us lots of flexibility in terms of saying, well, we can mix and match different play
controllers.
That will show you why in different ways and different levels, we can mix and match different game
modes that are going to work in different ways.
And that's the reason for me architecting it in this way.
It's a little bit overkill for our project, but it shows you how this could extend to other projects
with capture the flag game modes and different sorts of play controller.
So let's have a go at implementing it.
We're gonna go and first of all, find a route in game mode.
There's already one created because I started from a C++ project.
We've got this simple shooter game mode base.
And what I want to do here is create a public function which is going to return void and it's going
to be porn killed and we're gonna have to pass in the porn that was killed here.
So it's going to be a porn star called porn killed like so.
And then at the beginning, we're gonna make this a virtual method and we're gonna go ahead and create
a basic implementation, essentially does nothing in here.
Then we're going to create a subclass so new C++ class going to show all classes and we're going to
look for at shooter, simple shooter game mode base as our base class.
And we're gonna call this the kill em all game mode like so and go ahead and create that class.
Then when that has compiled, I want to just switch over for a second and go to our shooter character
C.p.
And you can see in here we've got our is dead in the take damage method.
Now if this is dead, well I want to be doing is getting hold of our game mode and calling the pawn
killed.
So the way we do this is we start with calling to get world in order to get the game mode.
Then it gets off game mode.
And then what we want to do is for this game mode to be of the correct type, which is the simple,
the root one.
The simple shooter game mode that allows us to then switch out this character, use it with different
game modes such as capture the flag game modes.
So the way we can do this, we can use the angle brackets right in the get auth game mode right here.
And we're gonna do a simple shooter game mode and we're going to need to include that top.
So hash include simple shooter game mode base.
Go.
So I didn't quite get the whole class name right?
I think so.
It's going to be a simple shooter game mode base.
That's why we're trying to get.
And we can go ahead and store that in a variable pointer.
Call it the game mode.
And then what we want to do is on this new line, we probably want to check that we have got this and
it's not a null pointer.
So game mode is not equal to a null pointer.
And then if it is not equal to an all points, that is where when a call game mode arrow pawn killed
and the pawn killed.
Is this like so?
So now the game mode is aware of a pawn having been killed.
Little mini challenge for you to override the kill them all game mode so that you can log out when the
pawn is killed and set that as the default game mode in your map.
Okay.
So hopefully had a go at that little mini challenge.
We're going to go ahead and implement.
So I'm going to do this by copying the public section of our simple shooter game mode base.
That's hard to keep track of all these things.
Then we're going to go over to our kill them all game mode base, which inherits from it.
And we're going to paste in the virtual method and we're gonna add the override keyword to make sure
that we're overriding this method correctly.
Then I'm going to create an implementation over in the C++ for our KMEL game mode base.
This is where we should be getting that log message.
And just to be super careful, we know there's nothing in the implementation, but you never know.
Things might change later on and we might get bit in the bomb.
So we want to do a porn killed.
Super porn killed with the porn killed.
Makes sense.
And then we want to do a you log in here basically saying that a porn was killed and we can see if that
works by going over into and real and compiling, then going to the blueprints item on the toolbar and
selecting in the projects settings that our default game mode.
We want to be if we select game mode based class, we want it to be the KMEL based game mode, basically
go ahead and do that.
In fact, that's not quite what we want to do if we go and select.
We wanted it actually to be a blueprint child of that.
And we've already got a blueprint child that has a lot of things set up.
So let's do a reparenting job.
Then we'll go to the roots.
We'll find the BP shooter game mode, which we've got here.
We're gonna rename this BP Kill or game mode, and then we can open that up.
Dock the window, open the full blueprint.
Ed, go to the class settings and change the parent to the KMEL game mode, C++, basically.
And that way we should be running the correct code if we go to our message to output log and hit play
and then kill off a character.
We have a problem.
Does not appear to have the right set up.
So if we go back to class defaults and change up the default porn class to being the BP shooter, a
character that should be correct.
Save and compile just in case it got that wrong.
And then check my blueprints dropdown here.
It's still it's the KMEL game mode.
The C++ one.
So actually want to choose the blueprint one in here and go ahead and hit play.
Now we've got our porn.
We can go ahead and kill this guy and you can see that a porn was killed is printed log message.
So that is working fantastically.
And the next lecture we're gonna be looking at, the second part of this, which is calling game has
ended when we actually do want to end the game.
And to be able to restart from there on.
So I will see you in that lecture.