In this lecture, we are going to be putting together a player controller that will receive information
that the game has ended.
From the game mode and will create this restarting behavior that after five seconds reloads the level
after the player has died.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So when the game is indeed over, we need to notify at player controller.
And we also need to have a player controller in our C++ so that we can implement the behavior of allowing
us to restart the level and such.
So the first thing to do is it when this point is killed, first of all, we're just logging indiscriminantly.
We do want to check whether or not the game is over.
Now, there are two scenarios.
One is where we win and one is where we lose.
The lose is the first one I'm going to tackle because it's easiest if the pawn killed is the player
you lose.
That's it.
You might choose to have multiple lives it with different iterations of this game mode.
But I'm not going to be doing that.
I'm just gonna have a single life.
If you die, game over.
You might want to restart.
So how do we check if this pawn is a player controller?
Well, that's pretty straightforward.
We can just do a cast so we can do a cast to a player controller.
And for the pawn killed.
And then if this is not null.
So let's take the pointer.
A player controller pointer.
Call it the player controller and store the results of that pointer in here.
And we're going to say basically, if this is not.
No.
So if the player controller is not a null pointer, then we know that it's the player that's died.
And that is game over for the player.
So what we want to do is call on that player controller method.
We've already hinted at the fact that there is a game has ended method.
Let's have a look at this.
If we do control P and have a look at the player controller to H.
And we can look for a game has ended.
You can see, sure enough, there is a virtual method here called game has ended.
And you can see there is an end game focus.
What actor should we focus on in the end game?
By default, this is no point and that's probably what we're going to use.
And then we're gonna say, is this the winner?
Basically, you've got to let the player control and know whether or not they have won.
And that's very straightforward, say, in this case.
No, they haven't.
So we're going to do a play controller.
Arrow game has ended.
Then I'm going to put no points for the end game focus because we don't really need that feature.
And then is winner, it's just simply going to be false.
This is not the winning play controller because it's the one that just died.
So it's time for a little bit of a challenge for you to implement.
Game has ended in a play.
Controller.
That means we need to create a C++ play controller.
Great.
It's a blueprint subclass sporn, that blueprint subclass by default from our game mode.
And then you want to go ahead and override.
The game has ended and put a log message in there to check that we are indeed getting that game has
ended at the right time.
Pause video and have a go.
Hey, welcome back.
So step one, create that C++ play controller, create a new C++ class, then go and look for, let's
see, play controller.
Next, we're gonna call this the shooter, player, controller.
Go ahead and create that class.
Once that's done, we want to go over to our blueprints and creates a blueprint class that is based
off of it.
So we want the shooter, player, controller as the base.
It's like that.
And we're gonna call it BP underscore shooter, player, controller.
This is not currently really needed, but later down the line, we're going to want to hook up some
UI assets to this play controller.
So we'll have it there.
Ready.
Then we're gonna get to the BP KMEL game mode and dock that in because we want to change the default
player controller class from the player controller to our BP.
Underscore Chuter player controller.
Cool.
Then we want to override.
Our game has ended.
So let's see if we go to the player control or h.
We can see that this is in the public section.
Here's the signature.
Let's copy it.
Go over into Ashu to play controller dot h.
And create public.
To that virtual void game has ended.
Cool.
And we've got to override already because that was clearly being overridden from somewhere to.
And then what we can do is we can go ahead and implement it.
Control shift P.
We want to call to super remember.
And we want to game has ended.
So.
And we want to pass in the end game focus and the B is winner.
And then we want to log.
So you log.
He's my macro there.
We have finished.
It's going to be the log.
Message coming out at the end.
So let's compile and see whether that's working.
Going to get to the output log.
Hit play.
Go and get killed, basically.
Health is slow going down.
And then we should see a message.
Are we getting the message?
No.
So let's have a look.
What's the play controller here?
BP.
Underscore.
Shoot.
Player control appears to be the correct one.
We've got our override game has ended.
Now here I spot a bug.
Now, that is something that some of you may have noticed and I've been shouting at the screen about
is that here we have got our player controller that we are casting to.
And I'm getting that confused with the player's actual porn.
So what we want to do here is we want to say get the controller of the porn that was killed so porn
killed DOT, get controller error to arrogate controller.
And then we want to cast that to the player controller.
And if that is now OK, that should work.
So let's go ahead and try that out.
Go ahead and hit play.
Casscells killed again.
And this time, we also don't get any message.
And this time it's for a subtle reason.
That is because we're detaching from the controller before we call this porn killed.
So when it tries to get the controlling porn, that's actually null.
There is no controlling porn anymore.
So we need to do this notification just before we do.
The detaching from the controller includes moving up the line that gets hold of our game mode.
I didn't think that would matter.
But now that I actually think about it.
Yes, of course it does.
So let's go over in it to our level and play.
Let's go and get shot at.
And once that is done, you can see that we have finished gets printed as we want.
So we had a few hiccups along the way.
Not your fault if he didn't get that in the challenge.
You've done everything else right up to that point.
That is great.
So hopefully maybe you had a go at debugging that.
But don't worry if you got stuck on those things.
The final thing I wanted to do here is to actually restart the game on a timer.
Now, the way we can do this is fairly straightforward because the player controller to H actually has
a restart method.
So if we go and have a look at this, it should be a restart level.
That's the one that we want to be calling and we want to do this on a timer.
So we've used timers before to do repeating stuff, but we can also use it just to delay an action by
a certain amount.
So I'm going to go to the shoot to play controller Dot H.
And create a private U property in here.
Private can be you property, which is edits anywhere.
Float, there is going to be the restart delay.
You can see why we need a blueprint base for this already.
I'm going to give it a five second delay.
Then I'm gonna go over into the C++ and we're going to want to do a get timer.
Well, timer manager.
And then we can do on that.
Then we need to include.
So hash include.
And it's going to be the timer manager dot h.
Then we should be able to use the dot operator because the return type here is a reference.
And we're going to do a set timer.
And in here we need to pass in a timer handle.
So in the private section, that's going create one.
This could be an F timer handle.
I'll call it the restart timer like.
So then that is going to be the handle that we pass into our set timer.
The next thing we need on the fifth signature here is actually to have the object that we want to cool
on, which is just gonna be this.
And then there's going to be, I think should be just the method itself.
So we can do that by doing ampersand.
And then it's actually the method, the restart level method, which we want to call on.
That was defined on the a player controller.
So a player controller.
Colon, colon, restart level, and then we just need to pass in the delay, which we have already defined
as the restart delay.
So do that, put a semicolon on the end there.
And hopefully we should get ourselves restarting after five seconds.
Now, got to make the testing a little bit easier by opening up our rifle and making it just a little
bit more lethal.
So I'm going to go to the defaults, do the damage at 50.
So we'll get killed with two shots, go and hit play.
Get ourselves killed quickly.
And then after five seconds, hopefully we should restart the level we restart and we're back in the
level, so our timer is working as we expect.
Now, obviously, there's not much indication that the level this is going to happen.
So we're going to look at UI in the next lecture's.
I'll see you there.