Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to log out to the console for the moment what our ray coming from us our
reach out into the world is intersecting with.
So we've got our cube and our cone.
And as I walk up to them if you pay attention to the log Well we get close enough.
We've got a line trace here.
We've intersected with the cube and we go to the cone we get the same thing there but nothing will happen
with any of the other objects that are not set.
As we talked about in the previous lecture with the four simulator physics turned on and the collision
object type set of physics body let's dive over into unreal OK.
So I said on real actually MVS code let's do a tiny bit of tidying up here and we'll get rid of the
logging that we've been doing we'll be doing some different logs in a bit.
When we log out to test I'm going to keep that line but just put it further down because we're going
to log out that's going to be your end challenge to lock out anything that we're intersecting with with
our ray cast.
So we're going to have to recast out to a certain distance which we've already defined up here.
So it's going to be quite straightforward to start building up the beginning bits of our cast.
And then there are some new concepts that we've got to go through now when we're right casting.
This we'll be in the world.
So the first thing we want to do is get the world.
So we're in our level and then we need to use the line trace single by object.
So line trace single by objects.
I've done it before.
It's top of my list.
You may have to type more letters and now comes the interesting part there's lots to go through here.
Let's go through it one by one.
So the first thing we've got here is s hit results and then we can see it's a reference and it's an
out parameter as well.
So how do we deal with this.
Well let's go ahead and create an F hit result because we don't have one at the moment for it to be
stored in F hit results and we should just call it hit for the moment now because it is an out parameter.
We can just type in our macro to highlight the fathers and our parameter and then we've got the hits
variable name.
Okay.
Now unfortunately the auto completes is having a moment I don't want a semicolon.
I do apologize.
That's a comma.
There we go.
And then we get the auto complete.
Right.
The constant vector starts Well currently we're using the player viewpoint location which is the center
of the fault pawn essentially.
So that is just the player view points a location that's the right one comma.
What's the end point.
Well we've already defined that as well.
That's the line trace and that we've been working with now of course because these two things are linked
to the debug line that we've already drawn in our scene on line 47.
That means that if we change any of the settings like the reach we'll get a visual representation with
our draw debug line.
And of course our code with how far we are actually interacting with the world will also be the same
right.
The next thing here.
This is where it starts to get a bit interesting.
So you've got an F collision object query parameters.
Okay let's start typing that since the F collision query parameter is that right.
Object query param so it's important here there's a lot of things with similar names.
So let's carry on typing here until we get the one that we want.
Object query parameters.
Okay let's open up parentheses here.
Let's have a look at the different signatures here so we get one that takes in nothing.
And I believe the one that we're actually looking for will be something to do with collections object
collisions i.e. collision query channel.
This is the one.
Now if you remember in the last lecture let's go over into our real in fact.
If we go ahead and select an object like this we have the object type as a physics body that's what
we're talking about here.
The collision channel which channel is its own.
So we've got physics body then let's see if we can go and use it.
So e collision channel.
Now if we hover over each collision channel we can see that is an enum and in order to access any members
of an enum you use two colons next to one another.
And then we've got a load of options I can already see physics body is there but if we starts searching
it's right there for us.
Okay.
The next one.
Now this has nothing to do the object query parameters we're not querying which object but this is just
the parameters for the collision query itself.
So before get world let's go ahead and create our f collision.
Now be careful there's many options here it's the query parameters that we want and what should we call
it let's call it trace paradigms I think or something along those lines.
So nice and clear what is is and what we're using it for let's open up our brackets and I'll put my
semicolon on the end straight away and I'm also gonna do that down here as well.
OK so what are we going to put in there.
Well there's no auto fill coming up on this.
So let's go and have a look at this online.
Okay.
It's a structure that defines parameters passed into the collision function.
That seems pretty clear.
Now we may have to include hash include collision query parameters.
I think we're covered.
I think it's a subset of something else we've already included.
Here we go here's the interesting one here of the constructors that we can use now looking at it I think
it's this third one down that we're going to have a look.
So let's drill a little deeper into it.
Yes yes.
This is the one.
So we have the name.
So in trace tag are we using tags in order to query whether we've collided with something.
No we're not we're actually using the e collision channel sets of physics body in order to assess whether
it's a valid object for collision.
So the next one hairball in trace complex what does that mean.
Well let's go over to unravel quickly so it's a basic question Are we viewing the world like s with
all of our simple collisions or are we viewing it with the visibility collision.
Now as I was saying if you were trying to reach through the door you'd have to have this set to true.
So are you using the complex collisions.
The answer of course is going to be no we don't want any complex objects.
So we've got something with wings on it.
We don't want it make to make it any more difficult for the player to interact with the objects than
it needs to be.
Unless of course it's a dexterity challenge.
And then finally what do we need to ignore other any actors we need to ignore.
And if we have a look at ourselves in the world let's go ahead and press play checks ourselves from
the scene.
We won't be able to see in this view and we get old and fall and go back.
So because our ray cast at the moment originates from with in the sphere itself.
If I can just clip through there we go as he starts inside of the first object that we actually hit
is ourselves.
So we need to make sure that we ignore ourselves.
Otherwise we won't be able to pick up anything in our world.
Okay.
So let's go back to our code here.
So we're looking for a couple of things.
The first one was is there any f nine.
Now we can't leave these blank.
We still have to start filling them in but we can leave the value itself blank when we get there.
So we need our text macro.
Can't do that.
So text macro but we leave it blank in there.
So that's our first parameter.
Let's go to our second one.
I've gone to father and that was whether or not we were using the complex.
Aha.
Look I started to give us the various constructors that we could have.
But we know that this is going to be false.
We don't want to use the complex.
And the final one here is is there anything that we should ignore yes we need to ignore us and we are
the owner the grabber is on us.
So we can just get ona now providing I've got enough parentheses that should be working and now we can
use that down here.
Now there is a red squiggle here.
Have we got enough.
No we've not got enough parentheses around this bit here first.
OK that's good.
And we've got too many at the end.
It can be very difficult to keep track of all these parentheses.
Okay so now we've set up our trace parameters.
We can then put that in here as well so.
Trace parameters.
Is there anything else.
No I think that's it.
So we don't need the extra whitespace on the bottom.
Wow.
That was quite a bit to go through but we've got everything set up now ready to report back and log
out what we're actually able to go out and reach or rather intersect with in our world.
Okay.
It's time for your challenge.
So what I'd like you to do is log the actor that is hit.
So get an actor star from hit perform and get name on this actor.
Now forget name I believe will return an F string and of course then you can log that to the console
and finally test that it works because shortly we'll actually be picking it up and this will confirm
that when we're intersecting with a particular object that will be able to be picked up and you might
want to protect yourself from a null pointer as well.
So you could say if the actor is hit then log out that will help protect you from having any normal
pointers come up.
Okay.
So Paul's video now and log the actor hit OK everybody welcome back.
Let's go back over into v s code.
OK.
So logging out to test that's fine.
Let's see what it hits first and then do the rest.
OK.
So if we go hit and hover over it we can see that it's not a pointer so we can use the dot operator.
And we've got a couple of options here one of which should be get actor excellent in our parentheses
and finish that off.
Now we're not doing anything with that yet but let's hover over and see what this is returning.
It's returning an actor star hit results.
Okay so that's good because that means we know what is what the type is that we're going to assign.
So a actor star remember that and we can call this the actor that was hit.
Now let's just call the actor hit.
Okay so now if we hit anything it should be stored as actor hit which is great.
And because this is in the tech component that will update every single frame if we are hitting an actor
that meets the criteria that we have set then it will be logged into the log.
Of course we do need to log it in a moment.
So to protect ourselves we are going to use an if statement.
So if actor hits then we're going to do something.
So we're going to do a a log.
It's going to be log temp as always.
Now I'm going to log this as an error just search a different color for once obviously later on we won't
be so flippant with the colors we're using.
I'm just fed up seeing a sea of yellow at the moment.
I'd like to see something red an error.
And what do we want to say.
Well this is going to be in our text macro and we're going to say that's our line trace has it percentage.
Yes.
That's good.
Now whatever is because it's an F string you log is going to have us the reference sets and then act
to hit an actor hits is a pointer.
So let's see what we can access with the arrow operator so we can get the world that it's in.
How about getting its name.
Does it have a name.
Let's bring this up a pen name.
We don't stick a name to it.
While there are quite a few here and there it is.
Get name and that returns.
These are parentheses that returns are f string which is exactly what we want.
So the line trace has hit and then it will give us the name.
Okay.
All being well let's go ahead and save our file and go back over it some real and compile it stop play
press compile.
Okay.
The compiles complete.
Let's go ahead and press play.
K cube hit.
Excellent.
Let's read as we expect cone.
So I think we're going to have to have this just a little bit longer.
I feel like we're having to get a bit too close to these objects to touch them.
Now that's just the viewpoint itself but all the size of these objects.
I mean that is quite a big box so perhaps it would fill a lot of your view up.
OK.
Brilliant.
So we've got our recasting our line trace or working.
How are you guys getting on.
Share your experiences over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.