Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We're going to be refactoring our pull trigger so that it's ready for us to add more code into at the
moment it was getting really out of hands who are going to refactored it to a small function like this.
That's really much more straightforward to read.
Let's dive in and see how to do this refactor.
OK.
So we want to put some sound into our game and the place we're gonna be doing this is in the gun when
we're shooting.
That's the first port of call.
I think an ice kind of shot sound and impact sound would be great.
The only problem is when I came back to our pull trigger function, I noticed that it has got outlandishly
large.
It doesn't fit on one of my screens.
It's also a little bit hard to read and understand where we'd be putting this functionality.
So while we take the effort to actually understand what the functionality is here, maybe it's worth
doing a quick refactored or pulling out some of this stuff into other methods so that it's not so hard
to read.
Now, if you go and have a look at this code and try and figure out what the basic things that it's
doing, then you'll see that a large chunk of this is actually just set up for our line.
Trace this whole chunk from line 28 down to 43.
And what are we doing?
Well, we're getting the owner pawn.
Then we're checking it.
They're getting the owner's controller.
Then we're getting the viewport from that.
Then we're getting the end location based on the max range.
And then we're passing in some hit parameters to ignore stuff.
All of this is just set up for our line trace.
So why don't we extract that out into its own function here, going to create a new private function
down right at the bottom.
After our variables, it is going to be bool return because we wants to essentially replace this call
here that returns success with one that just gives us the hit result out as well.
So we're going to do this as something like to call a gun trace function and it's going to have some
out parameters here.
Namely, one of them is going to be the hit result.
So hit result ampersand to make hits a reference.
And because it's not a constant reference, we know it's an out parameter.
We call this the hit.
And actually, there may be another one that we need here.
Namely, I can see that we've got the rotation is coming out of this chunk of code.
And in actual fact, we're negating that rotation.
So what we're really interested in is the shot direction.
So maybe that's what we need to go for.
So I'm going to create an F vector out parameter.
So effecta ampersand and it's going to be the shot direction.
These are the two outputs that are going to come from at gun trace.
Now, let's go ahead and create the implementation here.
And what we want to do is essentially just copy all of this code into their.
See how it goes.
And we also want to be checking this shot direction.
Take that out there and stick it in just before the end, or maybe just here after we've got our player
viewport.
We can set that the shot direction needs to be equal to the negative, the rotation.
But it's important to note here that actually we want to be setting not a local variable.
So if you put the type here, it's going to be setting a local shot direction.
We want to delete that so that it is setting the shot direction in the out parameters, which actually
means that it's setting the shot direction that we're going to be passing in in the function that calls
it.
Same goes for the hits.
We need to remove this local hit so that the hits being passed into line trace single by channel is
the hit that was passed into gun trace.
And then finally, is there anything else this is to do line which is now not needed?
And also this be success?
Well, we just need to be returning.
Be the result of the line tracing by channel.
That is going to be whether or not I can trace has succeeded.
So we have succeeded in making this indentation a little bit less.
We can fit it all on one screen now.
And it's a little bit easier to understand that, yes, all of this is related to getting a gun trace.
We can go up to Anggun CBP and we can now set our success up here.
So you'll be success.
We're going to need to set as the gun trace and we need to pass in some our parameters here.
Still need to declare those somewhere if hit result.
It's going to be one of them.
It's just gonna hit and the other one was gonna be an F factor called shot direction.
And those are gonna be passed in.
So we're gonna have the hit first, then the shot direction.
And then semicolon at the end there.
So that's going to make that just a little bit easier.
However, I'm noting we also need the owner controller.
And I don't want the gun trace to be responsible for the owner controller or forgetting the owner control.
That doesn't sound like it's the responsibility of a gun trace to do that.
It sounds okay for it to get a hit.
It sounds okay for it's get a shot direction.
But I'm going to draw the line at getting the owner controller.
So for that, I'm going to put it in.
Put all of this code into another function, which both of them can call.
So that's going to be a function there.
Tounes returns a controller.
Star.
And we're going to call it the get ONA controller, and we can make that a concert as we know, it's
not going meant to change any of the variables on ag gun class.
Let's create that implementation.
Just bring in the implementation from gun trace.
Fix up any indentation if necessary.
And we're going to go ahead and simply return the owner.
Control says no need to do a null check here.
That null check we do need to do in the function that is using it.
So we'll bring that up that we also don't need to set a variable in here.
We can just go ahead and return.
So it's going to be fairly straightforward, I get owner A.
But not completely.
And then we're going to set the variable in gun trace.
So owner control is going to be get owner controller.
Like, so.
Which we then do a no return to null early return and gun trace, which, by the way, it needs to return
a boolean because gun trace is returning a boolean.
So we can go ahead and return false here, because if we can't get an owner controller, we can't do
a gun trace.
Therefore, we can't possibly hit anything.
And then we also need that owner controller further up.
Where we have our hit actor, we're doing this take damage, and basically what we want to do here is
get the owner controller right in here inside our hate act.
So if we've hit an actor, we get the owner controller again.
Now, I know there's a little bit of gun traces calling get in a controller.
And then we're doing it again if we hit an actor.
But that's only going to happen every time we hit an actor.
So I don't mind having that recalculated twice because it's just going to make the code that little
bit more readable without having to store variables in state that could get out of sync.
So there you go.
We now got the owner controller that we need for take damage and our pull trigger is looking much better.
So that's it for this lecture.
Quick one.
Just refactoring our pull trigger so that we've got a good base to work from in the next lecture.
We'll see that.
Oh, and it looks like I made a little bit of a booboo here and they get owner controller.
If you try and compiler, it won't do anything because this return value is not actually returning a
pointer.
So we want to return null pointer in this case straight away.
Basically, we can't get a pawn, then we can't get a controller.
So we return null pointer.