Hello everybody and welcome back.
We are going to have a look at our first function that we can use on tier res.
Now it is very similar to the DOT early in function the length function that we've been using with our
f strings.
It returns the number of elements within the array itself.
And here's an example if we were to look at our words dot num it would produce a number.
Now be a good idea if we could go ahead and print that out.
So let's go and do that now.
Okay so first of all what I want to do is include something that I've missed before.
We do need to make sure that if for some reason this is called more than once it's going to cause us
an issue.
So we do need to make sure that we've got pregnant once at the top of our head and word list pedophile.
Otherwise if we were to use it in multiple places it could potentially cause us issues.
There's also a bit here to tie the up as well in our implementation.
I don't think we're using a lot of comments that we had before.
Now in the hidden word less we got a series of words within this array and it would be useful to know
when we start filtering them out whether they are Eissa grams and we don't want them to be.
And the different length words they were actually making a difference.
So let's go ahead and make a little bit of code using the DOT num function so we know how many words
are actually in this list.
Now it said a thousand when I copied and paste this.
Let's say it's true.
Let's go over to our implementation.
And as I said I'm going to tidy up some of the commenting here that is just not necessary.
And this here is another example of that's where we were playing around with characters.
In fact that was our first reach into arrays have gone sideways slightly yet.
So the code is all okay.
So that's nice and tidy and to save that.
And I think a great place is going to be at the very beginning of the game we print out what the hidden
word is.
Well let's also printout here the number of different words that we've got to pick from.
So this is going to be our print line function.
And of course we are going to need text macro once again the number of possible words is and then we're
going to use percentage I as our format specified.
And then we need to feed something into that now because our hidden word list is included.
It is exactly the same as copying and pasting this or cutting and pasting this into the top of this
code.
And what that basically means is we are aware within our implementation file of what this words is.
It is a constant series so we can reference it in here.
So where are we.
Number of possible words is so we can type in here words dot n new M and close brackets and we can see
there fortunately it does return us the number of elements in the array.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
And then finally we need our semicolon on the end.
Let's go ahead and rumble cow and see what we get.
Hey brilliant let's compile our code excellent with the compiler complete this press play.
Excellent.
Now it is exactly what we were expecting.
Okay.
So armed with this knowledge or really quick challenge with you to test everything that we've learned
up to this point and just making sure you can access different elements of an array because that's going
to be really useful coming up.
Okay.
So this is hopefully going to be a pretty straightforward challenge for you.
I'd like you to write a for loop that simply prints out the first five words from our words t array
video now and give that to go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and printout these first five words OK.
So back over in our file Howard going to add my full stop here just for my own sake and my own sanity.
And now the for loop that we need to do now in this particular case.
We're not going to use words numb as the as the count two points but we do need to count up.
So let's declare an integer called index.
And I really do like using the word index it really helps us focus on what we're counting in this particular
case.
Now it's very tempting here to start typing in words but no it's not that difficult.
We're saying it's just less than five.
We're counting up the first five elements of the array and when we reach index five we're talking about
the sixth.
So as long as it's less than old or indeed here we can go not equal to five as well.
You will see these sorts of things written in various ways and sometimes as a fundamental reason others
it's just the style you want to do.
And that's absolutely fine.
It does the same thing.
However one thing to be aware of here is if you're incrementing by more than one in a loop having not
equal to a certain number may cause you issues.
Think of the case where you have perhaps incrementing by two every time.
If you're on for a new increment by two you're on six it's not equal to five so the loop will continue
something to be aware of for future loops where you will find that the less than is probably a better
choice so for our code down here we're going to print line and then our text macro as always.
And what what are we going to put in there.
Here where we're going to go percentage s as our format specifies.
Now what are we going to put here.
It may be tempting to type out words which is correct and then we're talking about the indices that
we're looking at in this case.
It's just going to be the same as the index we're on.
But this won't work in itself it won't work with the semicolon.
Remember we need to reference it just like the hidden word here because we're talking about a string.
So let's make sure we're doing that.
And when we go ahead and save our work we can hop over to the game and compile go ahead and click on
compile wait a few moments.
Okay with that complete here's the moment of truth for when you click play.
Excellent.
So we're now printing out the first five elements of our possible words.
And I've also got my full stop on the end there just for my own sanity.
Brilliant.
So did you manage to print out the first five elements of our words array and did you remember to D
reference.
I know some of you would have forgotten that as we go through but there we go we know that we can now
get an element of the array and print it out that's really good.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.