The end result was a lecture.
Well we'll be able to move around our scene we'll be able to press and really saw a grabber.
But when we actually intersects with an object we'll be able to pick up.
We don't get a load of line traces hit filling up our log anymore.
It only happens when we press our grabber.
And only when it's within reach as well.
So the cone as well is going to be quite exciting because we're getting so close and after we've done
this we can actually attach the physics handle that we want the physics handle component sorry and actually
pick up these objects.
Awesome.
See you in that Hello everybody and welcome to reducing code in hot loops.
Now this might be a bit of a long one we're going to dive in to some refactoring.
We're going to dive into the disciplined art of refactoring now a hot loop is code that calls often
so our tech component is a good example that updates every single frame so any bit of code that you
put in there is going to execute on every frame and if you're not careful that can slow your game down.
Beware of code that you know will be called a lot.
Does it need to be called every frame.
These are things to think about even though the game appears to be working.
It's good to be aware of this and you really want to make it clear what happens every take.
So when we have a look at what's in there it should be super clear what is actually happening.
So we're going to refactor our code not only for speed but also get it ready for the physics handle.
So by the end of it the game will pretty much be the same as it was before just in a much better position
ready for our physics handle.
And that's the basis of refactoring so dive on over into the s code.
OK.
So let's get ready to refactor this.
And as always I think we should start in the header file.
Now the header file should be quite clear what's going on in the implementation when we read this.
We may have to add additional comments but let's go through it bit by bit.
So this public section here of our header file this bit here and this bit further down here.
In fact we could tidy this up just a little if we have public here in public here.
It can get a bit confusing so let's go ahead and move this protected area just beneath and I'm going
to need a little bit of extra whitespace there just to separate them out.
So that's nice and clear that these two items are in the public domain.
That's how a grab and release functions would also be better put into the public area so you could consider
that we've got an input controller somewhere else.
That's hard.
Grab a class registers with and then it would be the job of the player controller of the input controller
to call the grabber and say hey grabber we need to pick something up.
But for the moment we're going to keep it all nice and neat inside the grabber class itself.
And it basically comes down to an ideology sometimes it's better to separate things out.
But whilst our code is nice and simple we don't want to make it too complicated at this early stage.
So the API itself is essentially nothing there is nothing that we can do from the outside the reach
and the grab and release are all controlled from within the class itself.
So I'm happy with everything here at the moment.
Let's go over into the implementation will save up first and go over into the implementation and take
a look here.
Let's go all the way to the top.
OK so let's have a look at the constructor.
So this area at the top here we can delete lines 17 and 16 they're just dead white space.
It does need to take every frame.
That's absolutely fine.
That's an extra bit of whitespace here.
So refactoring is not only reorganizing your code but also just cleaning in SA.
I'm sure I've forgotten something as we go down here for I know we have.
So I need to tidy that up as well as we go.
OK.
So let's go down to the begin play now the moment we've gotten rid of the grabber reporting for duty.
That's fine.
And so the first thing we're doing here is checking for the physics handle component.
So we have this lump of code here from line 24 or rather 23 to 32.
That can be pulled out into its own function.
So it's a lot easier to read.
So what would we call this function before we go move the code.
What would you call it.
I would say it was to find the physics handle.
So let's call it that find physics handle.
So we would call that function and obviously it doesn't exist just yet.
Now I am going to just go ahead and grab that slot there.
Go back into our header file and this is going to be a the next function that we need to declare.
So find physics handle it's not going to return anything it's just going to run a set of code.
Okay then for readability down here we would have void you grabber and the scope operator find physics
handle we don't have the semicolon on the end we open up our curly braces and that is we're going to
put this lump of code I'm going to use ult and the down arrow to just move it to the appropriate location
and then there's going to probably be a tiny bit of whitespace to clear up either side.
Oh did I just move the.
Yes I just moved the cool down there as well.
So that's a lot easier to read find physics handle we don't really need to know what that's doing when
we're reading the code it should just be nice and clear that Oh it goes and finds the physics handle
how that's implemented of course you can come down and look if you want but if it does what it needs
to do that's fine we can move on now at this point in time we've moved code around I'm confident that
it would still work however I would strongly suggest every time you make a refactor especially when
you go ahead and do what I've just done with creating a new function that we save the file because it
should be working at the moment touch wood and then go over to unreal and make sure the behavior is
still what you'd expect it to be.
Okay so let's compile.
Okay.
So with the compile complete I'm going to open up the output log first of all I'm going to clear it
so I can see what's going on and then I'm going to press play sphere.
Old book of how.
We've got everything working here.
Oh but we don't have our message coming through okay.
Let's go back into the project now.
I think I'm being silly.
I think I'm looking for a bit of code because we did say if the ink put component.
Yes maybe it wasn't attached.
I've removed the business as input component not found I forgot I did that whoops because we didn't
need it.
That's absolutely fine.
As the game is working as I'd expect and the next thing to look at is this input component.
Okay so let's have refactor this out as well.
Let's think about what we're going to call it first.
This is going to be something along the lines of set up the input component so set up.
I don't need the word the setup inputs component so it's nice and clear what's going on.
Let's go over into our head to file.
I'm going to copy that.
So I've got to exact.
So here we are going to save it it's void it's not returning anything and set up input component.
Okay so it does set up input component require a comment against it.
I think it's quite clear as to what this is doing.
Let's go through this just once.
So grabbing Yep releasing.
Yeah finding the physics handle.
Yeah set up input component.
I think that's very clear what they're doing.
If there was any ambiguity or if there was a special case of something I'd certainly introduce a comment
or two there but that is pretty much self documenting.
Let's just save that and go back over into our implementation.
Now's the chance that it's underneath the begin play.
We can start defining some stuff so let's go ahead.
Void because it's not returning anything as normal.
Is gonna be the U grabber scope operator setup in input component and let's go ahead and grab this bits
of code here.
Line 26 to 31 in my case.
Move it down to the appropriate location.
Okay so now begin play is so simple is going to find the physics handle and set up the input component.
That's exactly what we want to see.
And of course now we've done that.
Let's go over to unreal.
I'm going to practice what I preach here.
Hit compile.
Make sure your game works.
You've just moved around a chunk of code.
Let's make sure we've not moved a semicolon somewhere or forgotten one or something.
I am on the wrong side of some brackets.
These are all things that if you did a load of code changes all of a sudden you won't know what the
mistake was that you've made so that is brilliant.
That's exactly what I want to see.
The game is working.
We can even bring open the output log.
So when we press play we can see everything is still working as we would expect it to.
Nice let us continue.
Now some of you may have experienced this already but MVS code you have these little dropdown arrows
that they are invisible unless you move your cursor towards the actual numbers.
The line numbers down the left hand side.
Now what you can do if you need to is make things a lot easier to read and you can squish them all up
into one another.
So you know this is going to set up the income input component we can leave it there.
Physics handle if we're happy with the code in there we can just bring it up like that and it makes
your code a lot easier to step through and then you just have to reveal it if you need to.
Now currently I leave everything open because it's very easy for you guys not to notice.
I've got one shut and wonder where the bits of code is.
If it's all there when I'm typing through etc. You can see what else is around it.
And one of the things that you can do here for instance as well is if this needs a bit more explaining
like the check for physics handle component.
I mean it is pretty self documented but it's not mentioning a component up there.
What we can do is go ahead line 39 here.
If we move it just above our function then when we minimize it we actually see what it's about as well.
And of course because that's no longer in line that can come down like that.
Okay so let's move down here to grab.
Now grab may or may not be the right word.
Don't be scared to change the name of things if necessary.
In this particular case I think we'll stick with grab.
It could be attempted grab.
It could be or you might have a completely different name for it but I'm going to leave it as grab for
the moment.
However the grep function is not just going to say that we pressed the right key it's going to do something
else so let's let's pseudocode what we need to do next.
We go going to try and reach any actors we have a physics body collision channels set.
That's basically what we're looking for after we've done that.
What's the next thing we're going to do.
Well if we hit something then attach the physics handle and then we could say to do attach a physics
handle.
Okay.
And when we go down to release it's going to be very similar.
We'll still lock out.
That's the grabber has been released so we can see that.
And so here another to do will be to remove.
Release the physics handle literally letting it go which is great.
Now we don't know how to do that yet but we'll get there okay.
The next thing that we're getting into now is the tic component.
So this is our hot loop everything that's within this tic component function.
Well it's going to be run on every single frame.
So we better make sure that is exactly what we want to do.
So we've actually got quite a bit going on in here.
But if we break it down to what the tic functions should really be doing what we want to do here is
save that if the physics handle the thing that we can that we can attach to an object is attached then
we want to basically go ahead and move the object we are holding.
So what does the rest of this code do and can we take it out of the tech component.
Well a redundant question because yes we can.
Now it's entirely up to you.
Let's go through here.
So let's go through the code first and then decide where we're going to put things.
So the first thing we're doing here is getting the player's viewpoint.
Then we draw a line from the player showing the reach.
Now this is a nice sort of debug function but I think we're happy enough now that this is not adding
to our code.
So now you can decide to keep it in anger and make my code simpler by removing it.
It was a great way of visualizing what we were doing with our recast.
However we don't actually need it currently.
Now of course you can use that sort of thing later on to project something into your world if you need
to.
And then we have our raid cast out.
This is the real meat of it rather than the projection earlier.
And then we see what it hits.
So can we fact refactor some of this out.
Well if we have a look at the grab itself what happens when we grab.
Well when we press that button that would be the time to get the player's location the rotation and
recasting out into the world.
We don't need to do it on every frame.
We just need to do it when the player wants to pick something up.
We need to see how are we close enough to pick something up so we will recast out at that point.
So another to do up here is to only recast when he is pressed.
I think I think that's fine for the moment and we can combine that with the line below only recast and
see if we reach okay.
So the next thing that we need to do is work out what's going on down here.
Now we can break it up into small chunks into large chunks.
It really doesn't matter but it doesn't want to be running on every single frame.
What we need is it's a run whenever the buttons pushed which is up here.
If a physics handle is attached move the thing.
Get the player's viewpoint.
So we really want here.
The first physics body within reach.
So when we Ray cast out what's the first one so we know that it goes and get something.
So get first physics body because that's what we're looking at.
And then in reach is a good enough name for me because it says exactly what we're looking for.
And that pretty much sums up what the rest of the code down here ends up doing.
But it does return something as well.
So it's not going to be a void.
Now before we go ahead and define it let's go into the header file and declare it.
So this one's going to be explained.
So this is going to return.
Now what is it going to return that's bounce back over here for a second.
See what it hits.
Well listen I had to hit get active so that's how we're identifying it.
So is this how we get the F hit results.
So that's what it's going to return is going to return the first actor within reach with a physics body
with a physics body.
So this is going to be an F hits results.
Is it going to come up.
There we go to go up.
So if it results is its type that it returns and then get first physics body in reach and we don't want
it changing what it ends up being hit by in that one frame that we're assessing it.
So it's going to be a contest function.
OK.
So let's go back over into our implementation now we can go ahead and say it's an F hit results that
comes up of course and then we're going to go you grab it because we need to fully qualify it.
The scope operator and then we're going to get the first physics body in reach.
OK.
So let's go ahead up here and copy from the player's viewpoint all the way down to locking out test.
Well I'm going to cut that and paste it down here.
Could also use the ult and arrow keys.
So now the tic component reads really easily.
Now line trace and has a red squiggle over it.
And I've noticed that I can't see it anywhere.
So when I was moving out the debug line trace I believe I inadvertently deleted a line of code I want.
Now I don't want to undo everything and go all the way back.
However because I use source control what I can do is go to get hub.
This is having so useful thing about source control and I've gone to the commit that I made in the last
lecture accesses a memory layout.
And if we come down I can search for line trace.
There it is.
I can get line seventy one there.
I can even click and copy the line and then I can bring it into the appropriate location again wishes
here.
Now if I save that that's to sort out line trace.
And now there's another issue here.
We've got a red squiggle under here.
You remember if you have a contact function its signature has to be the same in both places.
So we can sort that's out.
And we've asked it to return an F hit results which is fine so we can return hit.
I don't think we need logging out to test anymore so the final thing here is to return hit and cross
our fingers because we've just moved a big chunk of code and I inadvertently deleted something.
So both files are saved.
Let's go over into real.
Go ahead and hit compile cross our fingers.
No I'm sure we'll be absolutely fine here.
Compile is complete.
Let's go ahead press play.
Now we won't have our green line anymore.
That's absolutely fine I'm going to escape after that for the moment go to the output log and press
play again.
Now if we look around our scene line traces hit a cube hit the cone.
That's fine.
And I can press and release my grabber.
Excellent.
And when we go over here our doors are opening and shutting so everything appears to be working exactly
how it did before.
Phew.
Okay.
So a few final things here let's go back to our code and let's go to where we are grabbing.
So where are we grabbing up here.
So only Ray when the key is pressed so this is where we can go ahead and call our guests first physics
body in reach because that's exactly what we want to do and we go ahead and grab something Let's try
that compiles complete let's press play.
Okay grab a pressed and the line traces hit.
Now that's happening all the time still which suggests there's still something within our tick function.
So get first physics body and reach while it's doing that every time.
So this time we can turn that off because we've moved up to grab.
Which is a much better place for it.
Now if we compile and press play what we should find is that grab a release and press and if we grab
it's hit the cube.
Two excellent and it's hit the cone.
Two even better.
That's exactly what we want it do.
So it's hitting nothing.
It's hitting the cube.
It sits in the cone.
Excellent.
It's coming together really well now.
Okay brilliant.
That's the exact behavior that we want to see.
So we've now got a much better code base here to continue working from the only real messy thing left
is this big lump of code at the bottom.
It's a function that seems to do multiple things.
So we may end up breaking it up a little bit more when it comes to the physics handler components.
So we've come to the end of this lecture.
Now we have pretty much made no progress when it comes to functionality within the game.
However with the optimization and the much cleaner code we can build upon this so much better than if
we had left it how it was.
And that's the power of doing some refactoring.
So that's it for this lecture and I'll see you all in the next one.