Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we're going to have an introduction re look at references.
Now it's just going to be the very basics and will reinforce our knowledge in the next section.
So basically the premise that we're going to go for for here is why copy when you don't need to.
At the moment we're passing around all of our variables by value which does mean that he's taking a
copy of that and then using it's within the function itself.
We'll look at our implementation in a moment but we don't need to copy it every time we make a copy.
We're actually passing it by value.
That's what it's called.
And there are reasons why you will want to do that.
But it's such a waste when you don't need a copy especially when it comes to strings and things like
a raise they take up a lot of space.
So taking an unnecessary copy is a real waste of our resources.
Okay.
So instead we can look at the originating data directly.
This is called passing by reference and we will see that it affects multiple areas of our code already
so we can have a big performance boost with our simple code.
Now students will often get in a muddle with pointers and references.
But as I said don't worry about that.
We're going to be diving into pointers and references in more detail in the next section.
So we have a couple of key points to cover before we dive into the implementation the symbol that we
are using is the ampersand.
Now what a reference is is it simply an address in memory.
It's like a postal code or a ZIP code taking you to a specific location within the memory.
And one thing to bear in mind is the ampersand can have other meanings so you have to use it in quite
a specific way.
One of the things with the reference is it must be initialized.
You have to refer to something you cannot have an unfinished realized reference.
And we'll also look at the fact that you cannot reassign a reference.
Once you've assigned it to something it will stay assigned to that point in memory.
Welcome over to our implementation.
Let's first of all just have a quick look at a reference that's been sat here all this time.
And finally we've gotten around to talking about it.
This here is basically saying our input is a reference and it's a constant reference.
This is important so we're not copying what the person has typed in constantly.
And then we have a const meaning that that is a promise that that input will not change which is very
important because if the players input changes even if it's accidental with encoding it would ruin the
game we wouldn't be able to track it at this point.
And I was also thinking that this would probably be better being called player inputs makes a lot more
sense.
Okay.
So this is a constant reference to player inputs.
But how do References work.
Well let's go ahead here and play with them.
Begin play.
Now I'm not going to be using Pascal case here since we're gonna be deleting this in a few moments anyway
just as a bit of test code.
So first of all it starts off with a couple of integers that we can play with.
Let's have ints 32 a equaling zero and let's also have an int 32 let's have it be and have equal 5.
So that's pretty standard stuff we've initialized A and B with two values.
In general it's a good idea to initialize things unless you got a good reason why not.
So then we can have an int 32 because it does have to have a type then our Ampersand followed by what
we're going to call it.
I'm going to call a reference to a SO ref a I want to set it equal to a.
Now let's just have a quick talk about syntax here.
We've got our.
If we hover over here we can see that the ampersand is on the other side.
In fact none of this whitespace here matters you can have it in any formatting you want.
However this is the real standard formatting so we will keep it aligned to that.
Finally before we actually start playing with these and working out what happens if you try and reassign
things let's go ahead and print line
text and then what should we have in here.
Let's have a B and C being printed out.
So a equals format specify I.
Because it's an integer.
B equals format specified again.
And then finally ref a equals and another formats specify.
I.
There we go.
And then here we're going to need a b and ref a Okay so that's a nice little block of code let's see
what happens over an unreal.
Let's compile our code.
Excellent.
So here we can clearly see that referencing a gives the value back from what's at a.
Which is useful.
I equals zero and b equals five.
Okay let's do something that I've said you cannot do.
Which is something you can do which is reassign it but we'll see the impact that that can have.
If high ref a equals b what do you think happens well in this particular case.
I will allow you to copy and paste code.
That is exactly the same as the line above.
So what's going to happen.
I.
Well we changed ref a to b so surely referee now points a b so B and ref a will now be five.
Is that what you're thinking.
Well I can tell you straight away that's not what's going to happen because we cannot reassign it.
So what you've really done by saying RAF a equals b is you've also changed the value of a at the same
time.
Let's go see that in action.
Okay.
So you can see the danger when you start reassigning things you're actually changing something you didn't
realize you might be changing there's a lot of danger in that which is why we use the constant keyword
because the moment we say that this is a constant reference to something even though we don't get a
red squiggle down here when we try and compile our code it will fail.
It will say you can't do that.
You've made a promise that you're not going to change it and you've gone ahead and tried to change it.
So there we go the compilers fail.
That's what we were expecting.
And if we read down here we've got.
There we go.
Rafa's declared a contest.
You can't change it.
Why are you trying to change it but how can we go ahead and use them in our functions like this when
we're passing by reference.
Well let's go have a look at what we've currently got.
So we've got our input coming through and then the process gets the player input itself and that's it's
passed in.
That's absolutely fine because we can see it's a constant f string reference to player inputs at the
moment.
That's absolutely fine.
So let's go down to where we've got processed gas processed gas that's not a constant reference anymore
that's now a copy of the reference which is not what we want.
That's just an F string.
It's pretty lightweight compared to a T array full of f strings but unless it's a simple value like
an integer or a float or a boolean you do want to pass these things by reference specifically by const
reference those smaller items because they can exist on the CPE registers.
They can actually be slower to reference them.
It can be quite complex.
But don't worry about that when you're passing these type of things that contain things like f strings
contain characters arrays can contain different types and later on I'm sure we'll touch t maps all those
sorts of things you should pass around by const reference so how do we go ahead and do this.
Well are we going to change that guess.
The answer is going to be no we don't want to change that guess at all.
It would interrupt the game so we pass it in like this and that's absolutely fine.
But now when we go ahead have I deleted the error up here now I'm going to comment that's out for the
moment I'm going to show you here there's going to be another issue when we go ahead and compile this
time we're going to see that our definition doesn't match any declarations that we've made if we show
this here first parameter memory declaration does not match the definition what does that mean.
Well we've got an F string in the concept string.
If we go ahead and look at our header file process scarce notice here this isn't const and it's not
a reference either.
So essentially you had another process guess function that had been defined that was different from
this one being declared.
So you ended up with that error in place.
You do have to declare exactly what you were defining later on.
So that's that done.
Let's have a look.
Is there anything further down here that we can sort out so during the process guess once again the
is Isaac Graham is used and we pass in the guess which is absolutely fine but just like before if we
go down to this is Isaac Graham we're taking a copy of that word that we're assessing.
That's no good.
We're taking a copy of it.
Why do why are we taking a copy when we can just look at the original word.
So once again and we're not going to change it either.
So it needs to be const and it's a constant reference.
There we go.
And this t array down here.
Well that is going to be super expensive if we had an array of maybe a million words.
We can certainly guarantee that it would slow down.
Unreal having to process its and it doesn't have to be an array of words you could have an array of
actors in your scene copying them all the time you're going to run out a memory very very quickly.
But this is going to be our challenge.
Let's see what you have to do okay.
So your challenge is to rewrite the get valid words function to take in the original word list by reference
now all that any other functions that you can pass values in by reference rather than by value.
And finally is the parameter you are passing in const now.
Little clue here.
The answer's pretty much going to be yes.
Most of the time when you're passing around values you do want to make it const otherwise it can be
mutated which can cause issues.
So go ahead.
With there now and give that a go
okay.
Everybody welcome back.
Let's go ahead now and rewrite.
I'll get valid words function to taking the original word list by reference.
OK so the first thing I'm going to do here is actually go over to my head of file because we changed
that is Isaac Graham and did not make that a const f string reference.
There we go.
So that will now work.
The other thing here to bear in mind of course is the word concept can be placed in different places
depending on what it is.
Remember if it's after the function declaration it's simply a promise that we're not going to change
any of these member variables in our code okay.
So let's work on the T or write a string here.
So we've got to get valid words it's going to be a concert I'm sure you're fine with that.
And then it's going to be a reference so we can just place that there straight away.
Now we don't need to have these two words here at all either we can remove those and they're pretty
much ignored.
However in saying that it makes it more readable.
I know when I look at this it's almost like self documentation what's being passed in at this point.
I don't know what's being passed in there and this is going to be a word list I think has come over
and have a look here word list so here we can see get valid words what's being passed in there.
Oh it is a world list could be a world list.
Is that sort of thing.
So it's a word list so let's go ahead here.
Over in the implementation and we need here a concept f string reference and the reference does go there.
We hover over here.
We can just confirm that this word list is now being passed in as a concept reference and then we're
returning valid words which this is exactly what we want.
Now let's go through the rest of our code and just make sure there's nothing else that we can be passing
in by reference.
In fact let's look at the header.
So we only really have two other functions in our game at the moment sets up an end game and neither
of those taking any parameters at all.
Therefore we don't need to worry about whether or not anything is being passed in by a reference or
not.
So that's absolutely fine of course let's save our work go over into unreal compile the code cross our
fingers that we've not Mr. semicolon somewhere when we press play of course I'm going to clear up the
mess at the top there with our demonstration but welcome to ball Coulson word it's cakes.
So what we should find here is we can type in something and we lose.
We need to type in the right length and we go for lives left.
And so if I type in cakes so the game should basically play as it does normally.
Excellent.
Do you see anything at in play there.
Doesn't get calculated every single time we play the game.
Brilliant.
Now let me go clear up that code.
How did you guys get on.
Did you manage to put in your concert reference.
It's incredibly important to keep this up.
It means that your code is going to be much easier to interpret later on and we'll see in an upcoming
lecture not the next one but I think the one after why this is important when we start talking about
out parameters well that's something for a couple of lectures time being passing things in as a reference.
Make sure it's a constant reference unless there's a very good reason which you'll find out in a couple
of lectures time for it not to be.
So I'm going to remove these lines they have no value in our game at the moment other than demonstration
perfect.
How did you guys get on.
Show you work over in the discussions and I'll see you all in the next lecture.