Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture we are going to talk about struggles.
Now what is a struct.
Well it's short for a structure.
It's somewhere where we can store stuff a struct is a user defined data type so we're already used to
using in 32 F strings etc. Well a struct is our own data type so that's so that gives us a hint there
of how we're going to use drugs.
Now strokes are somewhere to store data possibly of different types if necessary so you could store
integers in there you could store a string in there and it can be a way of pre determining how much
memory part of your code is going to take up.
Now by default that data is public.
So in classes everything was private instructs.
Everything is public.
Now you will notice some similarity with classes and other than that default visibility.
There are functionally the same however semantically we use them in different ways okay.
So before we dive over into V.S. code let's look at how we would declare our struct we would typically
do this let's say in our header file.
So we would use the keyword struct and then we have a prefix on our struct name.
So in this particular case with unreal we have the F prefix we would then open our curly braces and
then we would give a type and a member.
So this could be an integer named a and we could even initialize it at this point as well.
And then you can have other members in your struct as well.
Then we would close off our curly brace.
And of course remember that semicolon so enough as the fairy.
Let's dive over into V.S. code.
Okay.
So overinvest code there are a couple of things that I want to do.
The first one is off line.
I was reviewing my code and I've got these strange spaces that I've decided to add in before we increment
the ball count and the cow counts I'm just going to get rid of those I don't know what possessed me
I'm going to get rid of these comments just here as well.
Okay.
That's that code tidied up.
Now we need to go over to our header file to create our struct.
So we're going to type in the keyword struct.
S t r u c c and then we need to give it a name.
It's going to be prefixed with F and I'm going to call this the bull cow counts and then we need to
open up our curly braces and I'm gonna immediately put my semicolon on the end.
Otherwise I'm going to forget to do it.
I know that because of experience.
Okay.
So the next thing we need to do is give this some members so the bulls and cows are basically going
to be integers.
So in 32 bulls and then and it's 32 cows now at this point we can leave them on initialized and in some
cases that might be desirable and we can assign them when we actually instantiate our struct within
the implementation.
However for safety let's initialize them with a value of zero.
I cannot see at any point bulls and cows ever being anything other than zero when you start a game.
So this will protect us from other initialized values we should just play havoc and then we go we've
essentially created our struct.
So how do we go ahead and use it.
Well let's go over into our bull cow can't shoot C++ file and then under begin play let's go ahead and
instantiate our struct.
So very much like you can go in 30 to give its a name and then assign it a value.
We can do exactly the same thing with our struct.
Now our struct already has initial values so we can just go f bool cow counts and then give it a name
like counts and then that's it.
We now have an instance of our struct that we can gain access to those member variables.
How do we gain access will remember that both of these are public by default.
So in here we can use the dot operator to access them by going count dot balls or count dot cows.
And that is the same as having those integers there.
So what we can do here is a little bit of fun we can play around with it so we can print line so we
can actually see the values here takes macro and then let's go bulls equals and then the integer format
specified and then cows equals again the integer format specified.
And then what do we put in here.
Well if we go count dot balls that's the same as just putting an integer in there we hover over we can
see it is an integer which is great and we can then go count dot cows if we go ahead and save that once
we've got our semicolon on the end go over into unreal and compile when we press play.
What we should expect to see is bulls equals zero and cows equals zero Okay let's press play.
Okay.
There we go at the top there we can see bulls and cows both equal to zero.
Okay let's dive back over to our code okay.
So let's say we wanted to initialize the bulls and cows to a different value before we started.
We can do that at this point.
We can open up some curly braces.
Not square ones.
There we go and sets our member variables 2 and 3.
Now when I go ahead save compile my code and press play.
We can now see that the bulls and cows have been set to 2 and 3.
Now we can change it in another way as well and let us through this on a line underneath we can access
bulls and just to sign it there and then we can reprint out this line again and what we should see is
the value has been changed from 2 to 9 and of course we need the s on the end of their okay with the
compiler completely as press play and there we go exactly what we expect to see now the bulls is 9 Okay
so we pretty much have the basics of structure under our belts.
It's now time for your challenge okay see your challenge is to rewrite your code to use a struct for
counting the bulls and cows rather than using these out parameters.
And remember you will need to return something from get bull cows polls of the year now and give us
a go Okay everybody Welcome back.
Let's dive on over into as code and rewrite our code so we can use a struct for counting those bulls
and cows.
Okay so the first thing I'm going to do here is get rid of our test code at the very top it's not going
to be of any use to us.
The next thing I'm going to do is go over into my head of file and have a look at this function.
Now we are going to remove the out parameters so let's go ahead and do that and think about does anything
else change is going to remain a constant function.
It's not changing any of our member variables and we don't want to modify the guess that's absolutely
fine.
So at the moment it's returning nothing.
But what do we need it to return.
We needed to return a struct.
We need it to return our new Type R F Falcao count.
So if I delete a void and go f bool Cal count there we go.
So that's the first part done let's go over into the implementation and fix this up.
Now as I'm going down the code at some point we call the ball.
Here we go online 88 so we're no longer passing in the bulls and cows so we can get rid of that and
the thirty 32 here bulls and cows we don't need that declaration either.
Okay let's carry on down.
I think I'm capturing things as we go so we don't need these two out parameters here and this void becomes
an F bull cow count.
Excellent.
Now because our bulls and cows are already initialized to 0 all we have to do here is have the F boop
cow counts as our type.
And then let's name it count as we did before and that is automatically set to zero then we need to
go ahead and increment the bulls and cows.
So here we can just do both counts.
Well in this case we're going to do count dot bulls plus plus.
And then finally count dolts cows plus plus.
Okay that's great.
So what's happening here is we're instantiating our struct.
We have then bulls and cows set to zero.
We incrementing them with the appropriate bulls and cows and then we're throwing away that data.
So the final thing we need to do here I believe is return.
What do we need to return.
Well we need to return our counts and now we need to do something with that in order to get the data
out because at the moment if we go back up where we have gets bull cows that expression is evaluating
to the struct.
So here is where we can instance our struct again.
And in this case I'm going to call it school and we can set it equal to that struct and then all we
need to do is where we're printing out the bulls and cows is go score dot bulls.
And this is just luck here and score on dot cows.
Fortunately their names have never changed.
Now all being well I think that will all work unless I figure on a semicolon somewhere.
Okay let's go into unreal and test that okay.
Let's play our game.
Okay so everything appears to be working so far let's go and type our word in backwards and we should
find here with a five letter word.
We're going to get one ball.
The W and then for cows.
Perfect.
And our count is going down and if we go whoa per we're getting closer.
And then of course if we gave power we've won the game.
Perfect.
Our code is complete.
That's fantastic.
And that completes our basic game.
How did you guys get on please share your work over in the discussions if you've made any modifications
to the game I'd love to see it and I'll see you all in the next lecture.