Hello everybody and welcome.
This is the penultimate lecture so instead of just wrapping up the section what I thought it would be
a great time to do is inspire you to take your code just that little bit further at the moment.
We have a functional game but there are a couple of features that you may want to add to your game.
Perhaps you've got some suggestions if you do please do place those suggestions over on the forum.
It'd be great to see what else you guys want to do with this game and what I'd like you to do now is
really push yourself and try to implement on your own.
A couple of additional features for your game.
It doesn't matter what they are but I'd like to try and do that.
There is no failing at this point.
It's the act of taking the knowledge you've got and actually going through the process of trying to
implement it.
Now what you can do of course is discuss us with the features that you want to implement.
So go over to the forum share your idea where you want to take it go whoops I happened to be stuck at
this particular point I've tried these things.
Well that's a perfect way of improving your knowledge the one way that you'll be able to improve is
constantly applying the knowledge that you've learned.
That's why we put these challenges in every and almost every lecture anyway so thank you for staying
on the journey with us so far.
I'm really looking forward to see how you adapt your games as well.
So please do share your ideas and annual final outputs over in the discussions and I'll see you all
in the next lecture.