Hello everybody and welcome back.
In this lecture I want to show you an error and potentially how to fix it.
So occasionally when you launch an Unreal project especially like this you may end up with an error
message like this in the game module whatever it is you're working on could not be loaded.
There may be an issue.
Now if this does happen one of the solutions to solving such an issue is this will crash now is going to
your binaries folder within your project and deleting it.
What that will enable us to do now is Unreal.
will rebuild those binaries so it will take a little bit longer for Bull Cow Games to open as we can see
here.
We got this message again.
We click on yes and it will start to build the projects again for us.
So that's a quick tip for you.
I've had this issue a couple of times as I've been moving about machines perhaps something got corrupted
during the transfer but you can rebuild that binaries file and as we say it doesn't take that long at
all.
And we're back into the game so as a quick tip for you if you ever come across that error message.
That's one of the ways of how to solve it.
And I'll see you all in the next lecture.