Hello and welcome to this lecture.
We are going to be getting a third person camera set up like so so that when we back into a wall, it
is going to keep at character in view and not disappear within the wall.
Let's dive in and see how this can be achieved in Unreal.
All righty, then, a third person camera.
How we gonna do this?
Let's go and do this in Blueprint, because there's really no point doing this in C++.
It's all configuration.
It's really much easier to do with some components in blueprint.
So let's go to the BP, shoot a character, open the full blueprint editors so we can see the viewport
so we can see all of the components over on the left.
And what we can do is add in a little bit of a camera component.
So go to add components camera.
And the easiest way to get a third person view is and something we probably already knew.
Just move this camera out and over the right shoulder, left shoulder, whichever way you want to move
it back and you can go ahead and have a play.
And that's gonna be a third person view.
Simple as.
But things are not going to be that simple for a start.
You can see that I control rotation isn't entirely working.
It can't go up and down.
And but also, if I back into a wall, you can see that I'm looking through the wall.
That's no good, is it?
So let's try and see if we can make this a little bit better.
Now, Unreal has a component for this that makes using cameras in this way a lot, lot better.
But before we do that, I want us to go to the camera components and fix that rotation problem so you
can get the camera options and check the porn use control rotation.
And what that's gonna do is it's going to rotate the camera using the control rotation.
Let's go ahead and hit play and see if that works.
Yes, it does rotate, but unfortunately it rotates around the camera.
That's not a very third personally.
Look, you tend to expect it to rotate around that kind of point over the shoulder here so that you
can always keep that character within view.
Okay, enough teasing.
What we want here is the spring arm components.
Just let the capsule component go to add component, because I want this to be a child of the camera
component.
Add a spring arm in here.
For some reason, Unreal is focused on trying to put these components in my character's crotch.
Now let's go to the camera and make the camera a child of the spring arm and against just reset its
location and try and transform location under the details pain so that when we select the spring arm,
you can see that the camera goes on the end of the spring arm.
And then what I'm going to do is you could move the camera, but I'll show you why in a second.
That's not a good idea.
We're going to move the spring arm instead.
And because the camera's child to the spring arm, it's moving with it.
We're gonna move that, too.
So there's this point just to the right of my character's mesh, the right of his shoulder, and that's
what the camera is going to try and look at.
So if we go ahead and hit play now and move, the movement is still not quite right.
But we should have fewer problems with the walls.
You can see that now.
I can back into a wall and my camera doesn't go through the wall.
That is the functioning of the spring arm itself.
So, you know, when I went into camera and I set the U.S.
Porn control rotation checked that we actually want to uncheck because it's not the camera that we want
to rotate, but rather the spring arm.
Because you can see if I use my rotation widget Tonkinese E to switch over to my rotation, which it
if I were to rotate the spring arm, you can see that I'd get the right sorts of rotation.
It wouldn't be just the camera looking up and down, because if I select the camera rotate that you
can see the camera just looking up and down, which is the behavior we were seeing.
We want it pivoting around that spring arm.
So what we can do is we can select spring arm and go to use portion control rotation on the spring arm
itself.
Now, if we hit play and we move around, you can see.
Yes, that is much more like it.
That is third person camera at its finest.
And you can see that we are able to move into walls and that is no problem whatsoever.
So like you to run a little experiment as part of your learning here, we're going to try and figure
out why not move the camera?
Why do we move the spring arm and not the cameras?
Get a third person view.
So try moving the camera, not the spring on and see what happens.
See if you can figure out why I did that.
Those videos have a go.
Kay, welcome back.
So let's give this a shot.
I have got to just go ahead and put our spring arm back in its original location just by resetting it
and taking the camera, instead using the movement widgets and bringing that up into a higher location
over, up and to the left.
So spring on.
You can see the little red lines pointing back here.
The camera's up there.
And so the left go ahead and hit play in this configuration.
Let's see if we can figure out.
Well, seems to be mostly working the same, doesn't it?
Let's go and have a look.
Go near an edge of something.
And see if we can figure out what's going wrong.
There you go.
That is exactly an example of why we moved the spring on.
Now, what's going on here is that that little red line of the spring on this one here that was in the
clear when we went through this doorway.
It was kind of going through here.
So it was going through the hallway just fine.
The red line was clear.
The camera wasn't clear.
The camera was up somewhere inside the wall.
So what we want to have happen is that this red line needs to be wherever we need to clear the view
for the camera.
And that's why we want the camera to always be looking down the red line.
So if we reset it and go and have a look at our spring arm, you can see that now the red lines kind
of pointing, firing out the camera to the point of interest, which, as we said, unreeled got a bit
of a interesting point of interest.
And in this case, it should be just above the shoulder like this.
And that's the point that we're going to want to go and get the camera to focus in on as much as possible.
Now, this does have an interesting point, which is that we want to if we wanted to say, rotate this
spring on, you can't simply just go ahead and rotate the spring on.
That doesn't work.
It seems to once go straight out backwards.
And the reason for this is it's in the settings of the spring arm itself.
You can see that there is this socket offset, target offset and spring arm length.
So the length is telling us how long that length is.
That's kind of makes sense.
But if you want to do a rotation type of thing, then you can use the offsets as no real kind of rotation
going on here, but rather we're just kind of moving that camera over using the offsets.
And then if you wanted to rotate the camera, too, you could rotate the camera independently so that
if it was pointing more in towards the player like so.
And because we've still got that red line set up in the right way, if the camera's going to work,
it's going to keep our visibility clear towards the player as much as is physically possible.
Now, I'm just gonna go ahead and tweet this more to my liking.
So I'm going to move it a little bit closer to the shoulder here, because I if I got the camera coming
in, I want it to almost be looking down the barrel of the gun.
But then I don't want any rotation on the camera itself.
I find that it's not really necessary.
But I do want to have a bit of a spring arm offset so that we can get that camera looking over slightly
more to the right when we are not near a wall.
And as we get near a wall, it's going to look closer and closer to the player's shoulder.
Let's play that, see how that feels.
So that's looking like I'm a bit too far over to the right here.
Let's bring it in again.
Think about maybe 60 units would be good.
Like, so just have a nice round number gonna hit play and you can see that's kind of in the right sort
of spot for a third person view, in my opinion.
And if I go up against the wall, you can see it kind of brings me closer into the shoulder so I can
still keep an eye on my character, are probably going to have a gun barrel.
This might need some more tweaking later on when we've got our animations in place.
We actually want to be looking down the gun barrel when we zoom in.
That's fine.
We don't need to do that just yet.
OK.
So hopefully you have got now a working knowledge of the spring arm and camera and how we can use those
two components together to create a third person camera.
Now, all that brings out the fact that animations are not there is just standing in a static, a pose.
So in the next lecture, we're gonna look at adding in those skeletal animations.
See that?