Hello and welcome back to this lesson where we're going to learn how to output some texts to the terminal.
Now this is something we're going to be doing a lot in our TripleX game but in order to do this we
first need to include a library with our program that's going to allow us to actually write and output
the text to the terminal.
Now a library is basically a collection of code that is written by other programmers that we can use.
So how do we get started here.
Well we're going to start by writing a preprocessor directive in our file.
Now this may seem like a very scary term here.
If you're hearing it for the first time but don't be afraid because this is very easy to understand
a print processor directive is simply an instruction to the compiler.
We're going to be instructing the compiler to include a library of code before it goes ahead and compiles
the rest of our code.
So it's pretty straightforward.
Now we're going to be inserting our pre processor directive at the start of our file so it's processed
before any of the other code in our file is compiled the hash # symbol is used to represent a preprocessor
directive in our code.
So what's the line of code.
We're going to be writing at the start of our file.
Well let's just take a look.
It's #include<iostream
So it's just one short line of code.
Now let's break this down #include is the pre-processing directive here so we can see that the directive
is to include something that's within these angled brackets.
We're instructing the compiler to include a library called iostream.
This is also known as a Header file.
So a Header file is a file that contains code and we'll be using Header files a lot when we switch over
to Unreal engine in this course.
Now notice we don't have a semicolon ; on the end of this line of code pre-process directives do not need
to end with a semicolon ;
So to summarize here we are instructing the compiler to copy the contents of the iostream Header file
into our code before it goes ahead and compiles the rest of our code.
And right now I want you to pause here and add hash #include<iostream to the first line of your file
as this is going to help us with our next line of code.
So pause here to do this before we move on.
So here's my file with hash #.
#Include<iostream added onto the first line.
Now notice I've inserted a blank line before my main function and this is just to improve the readability
of my code.
I'm not just making this up either you traditionally see other code written out the same way as this
as it's very readable.
I'm just following a coding standard.
Now we've included the iostream Header file and this is going to allow us to write what's known as an
output stream to the console which is our terminal here in VS code.
So I will go now is just simply print out hello world to this terminal when our program executes.
We'll break down what's going on in the moment but for now I want you to follow along with me here.
Let's add a new line into the main function body on this line.
We're going to write std: :cout <<
and another space
then we're going to add some quotation std: :cout << " " marks here and our message that will be printed out to the terminal
is going to be within these quotation marks.
We're going to print "Hello, World!"
We're going to finish this line off with a semicolon ; before we break this down.
Let's save our file and let's compile our code and let's run the program Hello everybody.
It's Mike from the future.
I know some of you especially new to coding are having a few issues here because it goes through quite
quickly but don't worry you're not alone.
And hopefully this will help you on your journey.
And I will be appearing majorly from the next section onwards.
So the compiling stage here is when we go cl triplex.cpp
Then afterwards we need to run what we've just compiled.
Now it's easy to miss this here in front of us where we've got triplex and we go ahead and run the
file by typing in triplex.exe it comes up really quickly here we go.
Awesome.
We've now printed hello world to the terminal.
So in order for our program to print Hello World to the terminal we've had to include the iostream
header file and also type out the strange looking code here.
So let's break this down.
So we start this line off by typing std which is short for standard.
Now this is a namespace a namespace is simply used to prevent name conflicts in our code just like we
can tell the difference between two people by their surnames and namespace allows us to avoid the conflict
of code being named the same way.
It allows us to tell the difference and we access the namespace by using these two colons :: here.
These are known as a scope operator when we insert the scope.
Operator next to the std namespace we are telling the compiler to check for code inside the namespace
and we're calling Cout from the namespace.
This allows us to write a basic output stream to the console.
This is what allows us to write to the terminal in VS code.
So following from this we insert these two angled brackets << that allows us to output whatever is to the
right of them to the terminal where outputting Some text here within these quotation marks.
This is known as a string a string is a sequence of characters.
So "Hello, World!" is our string here and we finish off this line with a semicolon ;
This whole line is known as an expression statement.
ok so for our line of code.
There's quite a lot of concepts to grasp here but don't dwell on this too much.
Just know that we can use this line of code to output some text to the terminal and we can use all of
this to create some welcome messages to TripleX
So let's think in the terms of our game now.
In my main function I'm going to print out you're a secret a agent breaking into a secure server room
on one line but then on a new line beneath this I'm going to print out something like you need to enter
the correct codes to continue.
Now I want you to do something similar here but apply your own story from the theme of your own game.
If you're more comfortable you can always follow along with me.
But then after you do this save your file compile your code and run your program to see what happens.
So pause here to try this now and then we could take a look at this together
okay.
So I have my two statements in my main function to output the messages for the start of my game I've
saved my work I've compiled my code and now I'm going to run triplex now when we do this.
Notice that our messages are all printed out onto one single line.
So this is because the compiler is feeding out our strings as one whole line into the terminal.
We need to instruct the compiler to insert a new line somehow between our strings.
Now there's different ways that we can do this that we will see for out the section but I'm going to
show you a way that relates back to our namespace.
I'm going to add in a new line underneath my first message.
We're going to call cout again but the std namespace also contains a function we can call that instructs
the compiler to end the line so we can start feeding in a new one.
So let's call the std namespace again and access it with the scope operator.
And now we can enter endl short for end line we can finish the line off of a semicolon ;
And now if we save our work and compile our code again and run the program we can see now that our strings
are printed onto separate lines into the terminal.
Okay awesome.
Now we took a look at whitespace in the previous lesson.
I mentioned that there's an exception where the compiler does not ignore whitespace.
So before moving onto the next lesson I just want to make you aware of this.
We can see that our strings that are being printed out on the terminal have our spaces included in them.
So looking at our string that we print out we can see that the compiler is not ignoring the white space
between it
Okay I just wanted to make you aware of that case that wraps up this lesson.
We now know how we can print out strings to the terminal and how we can also feed new lines.
Now when you're ready I'll see you in the next lesson.