Okay, so in this lecture, we're going to tackle the process of bringing our tank class to life by
implementing the movement, I'm rotation input bindings into the code.
By the end of the lecture, we should have some of the very basic kind of movements implemented, allowing
us to move around and rotate like this.
Just as a quick reminder that the project comes with the input bindings prefilled and we'll be focusing
on the move forward and turn bindings.
So keep these names and input mappings in mind as these will be referred to encode a few times before
getting into the code.
I just wanted to take a moment as well to consider the desired outcomes and the steps needed to get
there.
So a couple of things that I know is because we're doing the movement in our PWN class rather than the
character class, which is something you'll be looking at in future sections.
The character class has functionalities which will allow you to kind of automatically receive input
and the engine will do a lot of that logic and calculation for you in the POUM class.
It's a little bit different.
We need to do all of this ourselves.
And we're just trying to get a better understanding of adding location offsets and things like that
by using this POUM class because it's a simplified class.
So for that reason, we're gonna be using the add actor local offset for the movement and add actor
local rotation for the rotation of the tank.
So no documentation here.
We can see that there are going to be a number of variables that we can pass in to the allocated local
offset function.
And I think we should only be needing to focus on the F vector, the Delta location.
So the direction essentially that we want to be moving and the sweep boolean, which I'll discuss a
little bit more when we're going through the implementation.
Then for the add actor local rotation, this is actually very similar.
And this is going to allow us to provide rotation and again, a sweeping boolean check that is actually
a second override option that we can use for this and we'll be using this in our code.
And the only difference here is that this will be using a quaternion rather than the F rotated rotation.
We're gonna be using an F quat, also known as a quaternion.
Now, we're not gonna be using the full functionality of quaternions.
You can see her if you wanted to go to this documentation.
It has a lot of kind of pre-built maths functionality provided for the engine.
But in short, to quaternions are just a way to represent 3D orientation whilst avoiding bugs and strange
results that are sometimes encountered when using oilor rotations.
So one of the most common issues is something called a gimbel lock.
And this occurs when two of the three standard rotation axes are parallel in alignment.
And this will do things like locking the irritation of a desired direction.
So quaternions are fairly standard.
No system in maths.
They're regularly used in most, if not all of the modern game engines now.
So they're definitely something that you'll be getting familiar with over time at working with different
engines.
And like I said, they do provide a lot of additional functionality, but we're just going to be looking
at the kind of very surface level stuff at this time, just as a small side challenge.
What I'd recommend doing is just take a moment to research a little in two things like Jinbo Locking.
There's gonna be some pretty funny examples, which I probably can't show her due to copyright.
But especially if you look for Jimbo locking games, you'll see some really interesting things taking
effects such as sports games, where players next will suddenly start turning around in on themselves
like some kind of demonic animation going on.
Back on topic, though, quaternions are definitely a little bit overkill for our tank rotation, because,
like I said, they usually used to stop Gimbel locking, which is something that takes effect when multiple
directions are being rotated around.
And our tank is actually only using rotation around one axis, which is going to be the Z or up in the
world, for our example.
But I did want to show its use because this will commonly pop up in online examples.
If you look at how to add rotation to something, we will also be seeing the use of the standard rotator
a little bit later on in the section when we're adding rotation to the turrets that very much interchangeable.
Again, especially if you doing something as simplistic as this where we're only going to be utilizing
one of the axes to rotate around.
But this is just so you can see how to implement both of them into your code files.
So that was just a quick aside, the back into the tank Hadifa.
We're going to need two method variables to start with that will be using between a couple of different
functions, which is why we'll be declaring these in our head a file.
The first of these will be representing the effecta or the direction of movement.
So in the documentation, this was for our Delta location.
For this, though, I think we'll create the new factor.
And when name hours move direction, as that name just makes a little bit more sense, when we're looking
back over this next, then we know that we're also going to be doing our rotation and this takes in
the F Quaternion or the Aquitania.
And again, this was previously named in the documentation down rotation, but we'll just set this to
be called rotation direction.
Again, a little bit more readable when we come back.
Then for our functions, we're going to be separating the illogic out in two four different functions.
Two for the rotation, two for the movement.
And this is partly for kind of code readability so that we can really specify what each function is
doing.
But it's also going to allow us a little bit of extra freedom, how we update the movement, arm rotation
logic in our code, specifically the order in which that code.
And again, we'll see that in action in just a moment.
First, we'll create a void function named calculate to move input, and that would take in a single
flight variable named value.
And this will be the function that will be bound to our movement input function.
So the actual axes of the button being pressed by the player and the flight value is needed to handle
the axis value that's being returned.
So this will be based on the direction being pressed.
So W would be forward and that would be a value of one.
S will be minus one.
And that'll be backwards.
If using analog input then that could be a value between zero and one or zero and minus one, depending
on how far the analog stick is being tilted then going to do something very similar for the rotation.
So we'll create a new void function named to calculate rotate input.
And this is also going to take a flight named Value.
Again, just for the axis binding.
Then we'll create two simple Voit functions, one named move and one named to rotate.
So these will be the functions that will actually run on the event, tick and move in a direction and
rotate in a direction based on the calculations made in the calculate functions.
To implement these, I'm just going to use a shortcut from an extension named C++ Helper.
And this will automatically create the functions in our code while to use the shortcuts.
You can just select the end of the function you'd like implemented and press control shift and P together
then from the dropdown or the options list if you haven't used this before.
Find and select the create implementation from the options.
So doing it this way has just created the single function back in the head.
A file.
The one that I had selected at the end of the line.
And I just wanted to show you that we can also use the O to select because we've declared a few different
functions at once with all of the lines selected using the select method.
You can then press again control shift in P, and if you choose the implement option this time you will
create multiple functions at once.
So the next thing is that we want our calculate functions to be run constantly based on the input from
the player.
So we do this by using our input bindings inside of the set player input component function.
To do this, we use the player input component.
We call the BINDE access function and we bind this to move forward.
This is the part I mentioned where Move Forward is the name of the binding that we've set in the project
settings.
So make sure that this is spelt exactly the same way with impasse in a world context reference of this
and the function that we want to be called.
Whenever this is pressed or processed because this is an access, this is another thing to remember
that this is always being updated.
Kind of like a tick of its own.
So if nothing's being pressed, this is still being called.
But a value of zero is being returned or passed in to the function whereby to to assign it to.
So to actually bind it to that function, we'll get the address of our APEN tank.
That's where the function we want to call is located and that function will pass in the calculate move
input.
So we're going to do pretty much exactly the same thing for our rotation, this time with the player
input component.
We can use the blind access.
This one needs to be blind to the turn inputs again from the project's settings passing in a world context
of this.
And again, the address of the APEN tank.
But this time it will be bound to the function, calculate, rotate input.
And that line means that this will constantly be updating those functions.
They are now fully bound to our movement inputs.
So if we address the movement function, first of all, as this will be a nice kind of simple warm up
task.
So in the calculate move input function, we now have the flight value being provided, which will be
our input direction.
We can then use this to fill out our move direction, vector value.
So for this we say that the move direction will be equal to a new F vector, creating a new blank vector
force.
And the first thing we want is our value, which in this case also means the forward or backwards direction
being pressed by the player.
We are going to use this and multiply this by something to control the movement speed in the pawn.
So rather than creating a magic number here for testing, let's just go straight back into the head
of file and we'll expose this variable for use later.
So just above the functions, I'm going to create a new float named Move Speed and Prefill.
This was something that feels reasonable.
I'm also going to do the same for our turn speeds as we'll need a similar calculation for that.
So I'll name another float rotate speed.
I don't give this a for value of one hundred back in the code file.
We can now multiply our value by our move speed.
And finally, we want to ensure the movement is frame rate independent.
So it gets our world context using get world.
And then we'll multiply this by the delta time seconds.
So as it is at the moment, we've just assigned a float as a new vector.
So this isn't going to work.
And as we're only intending to move the tank in the forward direction based on the way that the play
is rotating.
And we know that in Unroll X is the forward axis.
We can finish off our move.
Direction vector.
By filling that into the X value festival and then finishing this off with comma zero comma.
So on the Y and Z axis, we will be applying no movement whatsoever.
So this is of C, meaning that we're not going to be strafing or moving vertically up and down.
Next for our calculate rotate input.
I'm going to break this one down to keep it a little bit easier to read as we'll need a couple of conversions
going on here.
So it's a start.
We'll create a temporary flight variable named rotate amount, which will be equal to our value.
So, again, this is the direction or the rotational direction that the player is pressing.
Multiplied by the rotate speed.
And then also multiplied again by the Delta times in seconds, which we can get from the world context
using the get world function.
We can now use this value to fill a temporary effort later that we're going to create named rotation.
This will be equal to a new effort later.
From experience, I know that we're going to want to rotate around the U.
Which in the editor would be these at Axis on the rotation field.
So we'll just locate that in the override list here.
So this shows us that we want to fill in the pitch and the row with zero so as not to add any rotation
here.
And then you will be our rotation value.
And we've done all of this so that we now have a value to fill in our rotation directions.
So I would just say that rotation direction equals a new F quat.
And that will process these values in our rotation value that we've just created.
Then with all of this done, this is kind of the heavy lifting out of the way.
And like I've said, kind of placed in their own functions.
We can only move over to the move and rotate functions.
And these are going to be much easier due to how we've separated this code.
So for the move function, we want to use the add actor local offset that we saw earlier and just passed
in the movie direction that we've calculated above.
And then also passing the argument to do a sweep check.
So if you're not familiar with what the sweep option does, this is just asking whether collisions should
be checked when the actor or the pawn in this case is moving.
So if we said this to folks, we could then potentially do things like phasing through walls or floors.
We'll be doing the same thing for our rotate function.
But this time using an ad actor, local rotation function, passing in our rotation direction.
And again, also confirming that we want the sweep check to be true just to avoid having things like
rotation, allowing us to do some weird phasing in glitching situations.
Finally, we just want to implement these, as I kind of touched on earlier.
This will be done in our tick function.
So in here, we're going to cool our move and rotate functions so that this is being constantly updated.
Now, I'm going to choose to call the rotate function first.
And this is one of the reasons I've set up this way is that I find it just feels a little bit better
to have the kind of instant knowledge of the movement direction or the direction you should be moving
in before allowing the movement to take place.
It's worth noting that you could simply just move the ADAC to offset and rotation in to that calculated
kind of function counterpart just like so and reduce the number of functions.
However, because the axis bindings are constantly being cooled and returning zero, if nothing is pressed,
that means that would be fine.
It wouldn't make us move or rotate woman or pressing anything.
But it does mean that we don't have any kind of control in which order they're being processed or updated.
This is why I'd just like to extract these in to their own functions and explicitly call the rotation
value to be processed before any movement is applied.
So I'm just going to control that back a few steps here to put things back in place.
And a little bit later in the section when we have things compiled and working properly, as well as
setting up the full kind of movement and rotation speed as you'd like.
I'd recommend coming back here and swapping the move and rotate functions.
Right, just to see which feels better as this can be a very kind of subjective thing.
And based on people's expectations of how the tanks move.
I've just noticed that when creating the new rotation value, I set it to use the rotation as the value
when they should be using the rotate of mine, which is the variable that we've calculated just above.
So if that changed and everything implemented there, I'm just going to load the editor back up and
compile these changes.
They're going to want to go into our tank class and at the moment we've inherited this class from the
pawn base, which doesn't have the camera and input setup.
So to update this, we can go to the class settings and overhear where you can see the parent class.
Change this from pwn base to pawn that tank.
You may have just noticed to the left hand side, the spring arm and the camera component have now appeared
in the component section because everything else was a universal component.
We've not had to change any of the hierarchy or anything.
We haven't lost any of the mesh or collider settings that we had made earlier back in the map.
If you haven't got one ready dragon, a BP underscore a porn tank into the world.
Then select your new tank and navigate to the auto possess player and change that from disabled to zero.
So in a single player game, this will always default to the first and only play controller and then
that will grab possession of the pawn.
When you press play with that done, if we press play, we can then test our tank movement.
So this is definitely working.
However, our player movement and rotation is a little bit slow and the camera is not really in the
ideal location.
So these are going to be some things for us to address and fix in the future lectures.
At the moment, we don't have any kind of ideal way to change the movement or rotation speeds without
going back and recompiling everything after doing multiple tests in our code file.
So we're gonna be looking at how we can improve that workflow as well.
But for now, we have the base implementation, which was our mango here.