Hello, everyone.
So in this series of learning how to make projects in Java today, we are going to make this wonderful
application, which is totally based on our purpose of increasing your productivity.
So after completing this project, not even we will learn our Java concepts, but definitely this application
is going to help us to enhance our productivity on our daily basis.
So on your screens you can see the opening window of this application.
So firstly come to the title, so build our time management app.
So in this project we are going to build a time management application.
So what do you think?
Like what comes in your mind when I say the word time management?
So I like to think about two aspects of what actually time management is.
That is a management for everything.
Like we manage our job, we manage our house, we manage our daily stuff, the groceries in our kitchen,
and we manage everything that things should like look in a proper way that whenever we need it, it
comes up to us without any complexity.
So what comes in your mind when you talk about time management?
So our time is definitely not a thing.
It is basically we can say the framework of duration.
We can say that that there is some duration and we call it as time.
So that is the time.
That is afternoon time.
That is evening time and definitely the night time.
So how can we manage that time?
Like suppose we have some goals to fulfill on our specific day.
Then how can we manage the time according to the task we are like aspiring to do so.
We have to set the goals correctly in a manner that the time should not be wasted and it should be optimized.
Basically, it means that we can do maximum number of tasks in minimum number of time.
So this is what time management is in which we can perform maximum number of tasks in optimal time.
So optimal duration we can say that.
So in this application we are focusing on the concepts of Java, of course, but what is the outcome
of this application?
So in this application we will be building a full fledged time management tool which will help us to
set our tasks and our timer attached to that task.
Basically, we have to decide that up to what time we have to complete that specific task and also we
can attach a deadline for our tasks.
Suppose we want to do a specific task till 3 p.m. today, then we have to set that.
Yes, we can start this task at 11 a.m. and we have to complete this task at 3 p.m. or today only.
So in that manner this application is going to enable us to do so.
It is going to help us to set a goal to perform on a specific day, a timer which is going to contain
that duration.
Till then, the task should be performed and on the completion time it will be like running continuously.
So this is the setting of task window.
Or once you hit this continue button, the timer will come up automatically and a timer will run.
That is, you have to complete this task in a definite, definite timeframe.
So yes, in that decided timeframe, you have to complete this a busy and definite timeframe for this
task basically.
So coming to the home page of this application.
How you can see that we have made this application using Java string.
So there is a frame inside which all the components are enclosed.
So it is containing a title task line.
Task management made is.
So we are like managing our tasks with respect to time that it should be done in a minimum duration,
the optimal duration, and we can save that time and do some more productive work in that time.
So basically we are increasing our productivity with help of this application and most importantly,
we are organizing our lives that yes, in this time we have to do this chorus and in this time we have
to do this course and accordingly table we have made for our multiple number of tasks to be performed
in a day.
So also we can decide breaks between tasks.
Suppose we have to do a work from 12 noon to 2 p.m., then we can like decide at lunch break for half
an hour or so so we can set the other task from 2:30 p.m. to 4:30 p.m..
So yes, basically this is allowing us to show that breaks between tasks that yes, this is our time
to relax.
We can relax in this time, have our food or whatever, the nap, short nap we want to take between
tasks.
So this is a we can say that full fledged application which will definitely increase our productivity
and also help us to like relieve between the tasks.
So yes, organizing is done.
Taking break between tasks is also managed and also we can plan our future goals also inside this.
So on the homepage of this application that is like a goal task planner helps you to increase our productivity
by focusing on individual tasks one at a time.
So yes, this is a goal for this time management application we are going to make that it helps us to
increase our productivity by focusing on an individual task at a time.
So suppose we want to do multiple tasks in a definite timeframe then that is like definitely going to
mess up everything and we will end up in completing none of them.
So we can only decide one task at a time.
And then after completing that one task, then only we can switch to the other tasks.
So yes, this is a main goal of this application.
We will see further what is actually happening here.
So that is an image on the homepage which is like showing our clock and all the plans, whether it is
thinking, planning, managing.
And so yes, basically this image is giving us an idea about what actually time management is like going
to teach us.
Also there are two buttons on the homepage are start now button and a help page.
So the start button is going to open the interface where we can organize our tasks.
And there is a help page which is basically the telling the goals of this application.
And about page you will be navigated to when you hit this help page button and yes, we will see what
actually this help page is.
So on hitting the start now button this window opens up again.
There is a title and there is a text field and a like a side to the text field there is a continue button.
Once you like hit like enter to and hit this continue button, then automatically these two text field
are paired with a timer text field.
We can say that all of these will remain empty in the beginning.
This is the interface after entering to her and hitting the continue button.
But initially on hitting the start button, only this text field and the continue button will appear
on the screen.
We will see that how actually things are working in the next part.
But this is just a slide which is showing that this task arranging window is how it is looking.
So yeah, so on selecting tool from here and hitting continue.
We can align two tasks in a row.
We can set a definite time frame for that specific task and similarly for the other one.
So suppose I have said 9 p.m. to 10 p.m. for this task, ABC and this task basically I have set 2 a.m.
to 3 a.m..
So on hitting this content button.
So suppose these are the two tasks we are aspiring to complete by 3 a.m. today.
So yes, this is the only thing we are listing here and on hitting continue.
We will navigate it to this window, what this window is.
So here we are having a timer.
That colour font.
We can say that at the time.
I will run in this part and this is we can call it a timeline.
So this timeline is a frame with a black background and we can say that a number line and that number
line is like containing a clock from 12 to 12.
So this 12 to 12 is the daytime and this 12 to 12 is the nighttime.
Basically, we have 24 hours in a day and we are arranging our task, the goals which we have to fulfill
by that day inside this timeline.
So suppose we have set 2 a.m. to three M for BCB.
So here it is, Blue Color Day and our hair also it is blue color.
Similarly for ABC, we have set 9 p.m. to 10 p.m..
So this is the nighttime, the like starting of the day from 12 at night and this is the time after
the like afternoon.
We can say that after 12 noon this is the time till 12:00 night.
So here, here we are changing our ABC in this timeframe and we are setting this BCD in this timeframe.
So this is how the task that we have added inside the like this rose we can say that the text we are
aligned in this timeline accordingly.
The time which we have set and also this time is running here.
So suppose that we have to start our task ABC So the ABC we have to start from 9 p.m. to 10 p.m..
Then suppose we are currently at the we can say that one hour, 25 minutes ahead of this 9 p.m..
So this ABC is 9 p.m..
So suppose we are here right now like this is the time we are at present.
So this is showing a time on that.
What is the time left for us to start that task?
ABC which is in this purple coloured frame, and once that time will like finish then on getting this
done with ABC button window will open, which will show that you have saved one hour, 25 minutes.
So suppose I have completed this ABC Bay like before this 9 p.m. to 10 p.m. as I have nothing to do.
Then I want to complete that task earlier.
Then if I complete that task the one hour, 25 minutes ahead of this 9 p.m., then I'm hitting this
done with ABC.
This window will open.
You have saved one hour, 25 minutes here.
You can see that a plane window will open with just a text containing that.
How much time we have saved our wasted.
Now suppose that we complete our task after 10 p.m..
Then this window will show that you have wasted that specific time, which is extra.
Now, this is the help page we were talking about.
This is simply telling the goals of this application and not hitting this back to home button.
We can navigate back to our like home page.
Now what are the specifications of the project?
We have already discussed that it is a Java string timeline like interface which helps us to prevent
our procrastination, complete our tasks in a fixed amount of time and we do not have to waste any extra
time.
So yes, this is like managing everything from setting a goal, prioritizing tasks that which are tasks
to do for us to this task to do next.
And also taking a break between tasks here, you can see that we can take breaks between the tasks and
this white color number line will show the amount of break we are taking between any two specific tasks.
Now, whenever a task is completed, then done button is coming out of that timeline with a message
of time seven times 15, which we have already encountered here that year.
So once we hit this done button, then our window will appear, which will come or take us out from
the timeline and tell us that what is the actual time we have saved or wasted now?
What are the concepts we are going to learn after the completion of this project?
So we will be using object oriented programming in Java for the light programming section of this application.
We are going to make a Java application from scratch.
We will be creating a new project in the ID and then coding it one by one to understand each of the
functionalities in detail.
Now we are going to use string and frameworks in an extensive manner, so such that we are going to
use simple date format, array, list, calendar, basic stroke and action listener and are many more
of them.
We will encounter this in the next part where we will start the coding section.
Also, we will learn how java timer and calendar functions are working inside the application.
How we are attaching the.
Inside the application as we know that everything we are doing inside this application is around times
and dates and yes, we are saving time, definitely.
So at that time it is going to be the main part of this application are definitely also we will be learning
about classes and object.
So if there is object oriented programming, then there is nothing without classes, objects, method
calling functions and all of them.
So yes, classes and objects are also going to be like the main part inside the coding section of this
application.
And yes, we will start the coding section after taking a quick look at the application that how it
is working.
So see you in the next part.