So our project title is Java EE Library System.
So we are going to build an E library system with some login methods for students.
And I'd also like for Librarian to create one EE library, which includes some been part or some JSP
part also.
So we are mainly focused on EE library management with Java.
So you can develop with another languages.
Also like Python, we have Django, then Flask also.
Then we have PHP also.
But while we are deploying with Java because it's really fast, again, it's easy to handle and with
GBK and Java Servlet it's very useful.
Like they created web thing different and for the back end thing different.
So we can define both things very significantly.
So our project title is Java EE Library System.
So this project is based on GDB C Java Database Connection.
JSP Java Servlet pages.
Java servlet which used to create some database connection with the JSP and all the things and with
the server deployment.
So JSP, I'm going to tell how it will work, but let us see what is our requirements and all about
our system, server system.
Project AIM is basically develop a web app using Java for E-library platform.
With the help of java servlet, JSP and gdb c.
So I'm not controlling your server part because server is finalised for deployment and everything.
You can use different deployment servers for the local hosting.
I'm showing your glossary server, but for on online web deployments, you can use different platforms
like Heroku app.
Also use this or you can use Google Cloud platform also to deploy your server or so Heroku needs PostgreSQL
for their deployment, but I'm using here Oracle database.
You can easily shift to PostgreSQL.
All the queries are same and all the things are same.
So steps of our development is basically project setup.
Understanding different tools, we are going to use JSP Basics, basics of database, java, servlet
and database connection and deployment on the server.
So before proceeding with our further system and everything, let us explain how we can set up.
Let us understand how we can set up our project.
So I'm using here ID as primary ID NetBeans, which is very popular and open source.
I'm closing this panel also.
So this is my previous project.
Let us create a new project.
Go to file here.
New project.
Once this is done.
I need to add.
More things.
Likewise, you can see here a new projecting.
I have to add this.
My new project, as you're going to see.
So go to Java Web here, Java and Web application, click next.
Then I'm giving the name as E.
B.
As you can see, Eli.
Let me maximize this part.
Okay.
Hope you can see this.
No.
Okay.
Then I'm going to click next.
Choose your your glasses server.
I'm using e-bay next.
I don't want to use anything here.
Look, finish.
So it will take time to load everything.
So.
Now you can see it.
My, this is my old.
Forget about it.
Ignore about this.
So E-library is my main project here.
So let me add some libraries here first.
As you can see, these are added libraries, but I want to add some jar folder here.
So let me add one jar folder.
So what is the jar folder?
Basically is nothing.
But I'm going to add or jar folder here.
Java X, I want to n so this database, I will tell you about that part.
Also, let me add my Java X if you are JDK 1.8 is not consistent java x file it will you error while
deploying everything.
So go to 1.8.
I'm using this.
I'm going to library.
Or.
So first find out where you store your Java X files.
So it should be du jour XDR this eliminating it absolute but.
So now my file is added.
As you can see.
If I didn't know.
Oh, so.
Let me do this.
So this is my index road estimate.
So consider this as index only.
Nothing more.
But let me tell you something more about this.
So what is the index rotation?
There is a loading page.
So if you want to check your system is running or not, click here.
Then go to clean and build.
If your window is not opening your output window, go to window.
You can use control for weather also, but I'm using your button.
You can down here because like this.
You can see this is deploying.
So let us run this project.
So this is for first time.
So I'm just running this for first time.
Check everything is running or not.
I'm going to use here some default bootstrap templates.
Also some default CSS and JSP files.
Also not default JS files, JavaScript files and HTML cases.
These are some already created templates.
So I don't want to focus on that part.
I just want to focus on Java part here.
So I'm going to use that.
So let's see.
Our project is running or not.
So it will take time actually for running.
2 to 3 minutes it will take.
So.
Now you can see my project is running and it's going to do right to content.
So this is nothing.
But you just wrote here.
So my deployment is running.
I'm going to close this all things and I'm going to close my browser also because we haven't written
anything.
So in the next tutorial I will tell you how we can deploy this, but before that let us learn which
tools we are going to use and what is the significance of these tools?
So as I told you, we are going to use JSP.
Java solid and GBK.
So our application requirements is basically some more important part.
So.
What is this?
Basically so.
We are going to use some school statements, we are going to use some log in statements and everything.
So let us see what we are going to do.
So our application requirements is the Java program to display web content.
Java program.
You should have some basic concepts of school.
Also, you should know about the this.
I'm not going to explain each and every tag here in each HTML.
I'm using your bootstrap for a better view.
So we need one website, two admin login as admin or log in as a student admin librarian part.
Here I am considering admin administration actions like add a book something student should have a register
and log in book submit anything that part related to library.
I'm going to tell you that further then JDK 1.8 we need.
ID am going to use NetBeans.
You can use any ID, Java EE, Virgin Enterprise Edition Version eight Oracle or my skilled database
server or Tomcat Server.
Remember for the server deployment, you should check both.
If your port is 88 and if it's already occupied by my SQL Server or Oracle database server, you have
to change the glass server either, or you have to change the Oracle database.
Also, my recommendation is to change the last server port because it's easy and Oracle to maintain
the Oracle database with 88 port always if HTTP is not port basically.
So it will be helpful.
So let's see what is basically Java servlet.
So if you know the Java servlet parts earlier, it is going to vary.
So Java Solid is an API that provides many interfaces and classes.
So, so let's access the interfaces and classes both.
So it is primary technology to build and create a web application on the servlet.
Different steps are used now spring then hibernate also providing.
So servlet is an interface that must be implemented for the creating on any servlet.
So servlet is access interface for creating any web or anything.
And so that is a class that extends the capabilities of servers, responds to the incoming request and
etc. things.
Now what is solid is with a component that deployed on the server part.
So as I told you, HTML is a client part or we can say it is network part while deploying all the things.
But the Java solids are mainly deployed and that page is Java pages are stored in the server part.
So in this example, our system is only a client and server access both.
But but consider there are two computers or you can say tremendous huge network of some school or university
and though all the servers.
Or we can say all the clients connected to the one server.
So for all e library management system, the main logic in the servlet or main Java logic is storing
the server side only, so it will access the request and response for every server for that purpose.
So like adn book and etc. things for all.
Logical, logical thinking.
So this is all about the sole servers.
So servers are mainly so lets are mainly running on server, which depends on the request and response
from the client.
So firstly, client request server for something information like I want to fetch the data from this
database or I want to put this into the database.
So this is all kinds of request responses generated at the runtime like in the server.
If request is given server, we'll do something and a response will be generated.
So that response can be data that book is added to the database that part or request can be.
You can see that book part is book is issued for that that student.
So these are all about how the server returning.
So why servlet we are using here.
So you can use normal things.
Also CGI which is basically returning all or anything C or C++ or languages.
But why we are not using this because it creates some processes.
We can say CGI, common gateway interface, it creates processes.
So it's exe as a multi processing.
So server are limited for some amount of processes more than then processes.
Consider one server which computing capacity is only considering 100 processes.
So one client put one each.
Or we can say one client put file request.
So that request converts into the process and that process comes through the server.
So for each client, if is creating file and or server can handle only 100.
So it's very difficult.
Only 20 clients can be used.
But in the servlet parts, what's happening?
Java itself creates servlet or requests into trading.
So trading consists more number of processes.
Also trading includes some trade lock.
Also then we have known that trading have some own time complexity things.
So it will be very easy for server to handle that processes step by step.
So now you are clear with why we are using servlet.
So main part is over jsp but java.
So links are used here to create database connection and everything.
So there are requests dispatching sublets.
As I told you, there are a thing like request dispatcher in JSP.
Remember J.C. does not consistently request dispatcher because dispatcher is for is providing some interfaces
facility for dispatching request from one source to another source like one email to another email one
servlet to another servlet.
So it consists forward and include methods forward for forwarding that including means including the
same.
But so these are all about these things.
So you understand throughout this diagram.
So it is very easy to consider this.
All part.
So this is all about solid.
So solid countries.
Three important parts is HTML.
CSS is just for frontend java solid program with backend part and logical method.
Backend means basically connecting frontend to the database.
So we need some Java logic like put this parameter to this row, put this second parameter to second
row like that.
We want to write a logic.
Logic is very easy and there are some default useful statements we are going to use here.
Web XML to control for web.
So now we know that HTML one index html is added or which is put to the.
Index dot Java, which is basically Java servlet, but we know that.
But our ID or our web flow doesn't know that.
We have to add that.
So control flow whereby we check for the control flow of our web, everything and we borrowed XML basically
and it will check which linking part is linked to that particular part.
If not, it will add some dependencies also.
So web xml will take care of all the connection and everything.
So for their part, we are going to learn how we can create JSP, how we can set up our project.
So in the next days I'm going to tell our project part and with the index HTML development.
And our fully developed solid.