Hello, everyone.
So in this series of learning making projects in Java today, we are going to make a new project in
core Java.
So on your screens you are seeing a layout of this application.
Basically, this is the interface of the application we are going to meet.
So this application is headed as the snake.
Ofelia Feed the snake.
So I hope by listening to the title you must have.
Yes.
Must have built a rough insight about what we are going to make today.
So this is basically a game made in Java code.
In this game we have to feed the snake and make it grow longer and longer.
The game continues until you feed the snake without hitting any obstacle.
So let me give a quick introduction about the application we are going to make today.
So in this we have a player.
Suppose the user is the player and going to play this game in his or her text.
So the player is going to control a dot, a square or any object like in this we have an apple.
Yes, this is the apple from which we are going to feed thusly.
So this object is inside this border plane and we have to feed this three dotted snake with this.
Now, then the snake will move forward.
And if this object, which is an apple, it will leave a trail behind.
Like if the snake will eat this apple, a more dot will be added to the body of snake, and later this
object will shift to any other place in the frame.
So we are going to build this main window and once the snake hits, any obstacle like the wall is an
obstacle.
The snake itself is an obstacle here.
So when the snake hits this, this, this or this four side window or itself, then the pop up will
appear saying that the game is over.
In another common scheme, a snake has a specific length, so there is a moving tail, a fixed number
of units away from head.
Like suppose there are three units.
And the last part is the tail.
So after eating this apple, the snake will grow a tail behind its head and it will continue until the
game is continued and not over.
The player loses and the game is over.
So this pop up will appear when the obstacle is hidden and the game is finished.
So I hope you understood this game.
If you are nineties kid, you must have played this game in your keypad phones.
And by making this game will make you nostalgic about playing this game in your head in your childhood.
So let's get a quick idea about what are the specifications of this project.
We are going to make today.
So talking about the specifications of the project, as I already told you, there will be a player
which will control the dot with the help of his or her keyboard.
So your keyboard has four navigation buttons up, arrow down, arrow, left arrow and right down.
So the player will control the snake with the help of these four buttons only.
So that dot square object where suppose that we have an apple here is inside the border plain and we
have to make the snake with the help of our keyboard to eat that apple object inside the frame.
So as the snake moves forward, it leaves a trail behind resembling a moving snake.
Basically, there are images which the snake this consist of, but it will look like there is a moving
snake and eating the apple and going.
But no, we are just adding images after the tail and again and again until the game is not over, the
player loses when the snake runs into the screen border obstacle or itself.
So if the snake hits the screen border.
And if like.
Suppose.
The snakeheads, this border, screen border or itself.
Then the game gamble over.
So everybody is of hope, willing to make this project on their own.
So before starting to make how this project is, let us gain a quick idea about what are the concepts
we are going to learn by making this application.
So what will you learn?
Heading off this slide.
So before making any project, we must wonder what we are going to learn by making this project.
What are the concepts that I will gain in my mind after making the project which I am going to start?
So you are no wrong.
We must think that what actually is this project actually going to help me to?
Not share my knowledge in Java or any other language in which a project is going to be made.
So let us start the concepts which we are going to learn in the project.
So the first point is object oriented programming in Java.
So what is object oriented programming in Java?
So basically OPS in Java organizes a program around the various objects and well-defined interfaces.
And these concepts aim to implement some real world entities in the program.
Ahead of having object oriented programming in real entities.
There are also many features of OBS in Java we are going to use in this project like inheritance, hiding,
polymorphism and etc. in the programming section which you will see later.
Apart from object oriented programming, what are the other factors we are going to learn by making
this project?
So after the completion of this project, you will be able to make an amazing application using just
core Java libraries, not any complex libraries, but just simply core Java libraries.
Thus make Ofelia feel the snake game is built using core Java AWP and string libraries and packages,
so the app is built above AWP and swing only.
Let us take a quick look at what AWP and Swing are.
AWP and Swing are used to develop window based applications in Java.
AWP is an abstract window toolkit that provides various component classes like label, button text,
etc. to show window components on the screen.
All the classes are the part of Java dot AWP package, which we will see in the programming section
later.
On the other hand, Swing is the part of Java foundational classes that is built on the top of AWP and
written entirely in Java.
Like suppose there is interference of any other language, then we have to learn that part also.
But no, that's not the thing.
The project is just made in Java and the library which we are going to use, are also made in Java only.
So my talking about the birth of learning how to make this project.
There is a main feature which I am going to tell you about now.
So we are going to make this game from scratch, like we have to write the code, make the project from
the beginning in our compilers, and write each function component classes, methods one by one with
explaining what this part is doing and what that part is doing and everything.
We are not going to leave a single point while making this project, and this is the main part of learning
this project.
So building such an interesting game of your own from scratch.
Yes.
You are hurting me, right?
This interesting game we are going to make from scratch.
Also, the classes and objects are the main part of object oriented programming in Java where there
is oops, there is nothing without classes and object.
So yes, apart from all the things, the classes and objects are also being used while making this project.
So I hope you all are excited to start making this project with your own.
So come on, let's switch into the coding section and start the coding part and learn how to make function
components, classes, libraries and package with our own.
See you in the next part.