Hello, everyone.
So in the series of learning how to make projects in Java today, we are going to learn one more project
within Java.
The title of this project is Not and Classes and this is basically an interesting game made in Java.
So we will be learning how to make this application from scratch.
Like we will be writing the code.
We will be like handling the functionalities behind everything.
So on your screen you can see that this is the interface of the application.
Like when the application will run, then this interface will open.
This interface will open after some tasks performing.
But the first window which will be open is this one where I am revolving my cursor.
So this is the homepage of the application.
This is a resizable window.
Like we can maximize it or minimize it so we can like criticize it as we want.
And also the other part of this application is that you will be learning how to make project in Java.
Like you will be learning the concepts of a language and also you will be like making something very
interesting, like making something very interesting while learning something makes the work more involving
more amazing.
Like suppose you are making something that after making you can enjoy playing it.
Like this is a game, an interesting game.
I hope you all must have went through this game in your childhood where we used to make classes, we
used to make O's and the player with three consecutive consecutive.
Exes are the Eagles, Vince.
So I hope most of the like us are aware about this game.
So now we are going to make this application with ourselves.
And in Java, of course.
So I hope you went through the interface of this application.
When we will open the application, this window will open.
This contains a total three nine and 2226.
Okay.
So in total there are 15 blocks are title bar containing the Java coffee icon and these three options
of minimizing and canceling the place like escaping the application.
Also, we have a dedicated button in the frame for exiting the application.
You can do this with this also and this button also.
We have a dedicated button for resetting the game.
Like suppose for the possibility of winning any of any player becomes impossible.
Then we can reset the game and start playing the game over and over.
So this application is responsive, like we can play this in any size.
I will show this in the working of application part that how this is responsive.
I will resize the application and show you that it will like set itself according to the size of the
screen.
Also, there are two players player, sex, score and player all the score and the player who wins scores
are updated like you can play infinite number of times.
Those player winning score will be updated in this block and for zero as well.
Now some more functionalities are like suppose player X or player wins.
So like as soon as three of the rows matches like whether diagonally or horizontally automatically the
pop up the offer dialog box appears and this message shown up that player opens or if player X will
win, it will show that player x wins and you have to click on okay to exit this dialog box and to start
playing the next chance again.
So this dialog box is also a functionality added in the application window.
Like in the programming part, there is a separate dedicated code section for this or dialog box.
Similarly, suppose if we want to exit the game like like we have all the chances place and our decision
came that this final player is winning.
Or suppose we want to exit the application so we can click on this exit button and the dialog box in
the similar way of the winning method for exiting message.
Also there is a confirm dialog box will appear with a yes and or no option.
So suppose if you click this exit button mistakenly so in the confirmation dialog box you can click
no.
And again the game will resume.
Also, if you purposely click this exit button, then you can click yes to exit the game like the game
window will be escape and the game will be closed.
Now let us take a quick look at the specification of this project.
So this is a game for two players.
Like we have a player X and player row and between these two only the battle is going on that who will
win.
So this is a two player game and who takes turns marking the spaces in a three by three grid with X
or you?
So we had the three by three then this is the grid.
These three, these three, the three either horizontally or vertically or diagonally.
Any player comes in like consecutive way that specific player will win that game.
Also, the player who succeeds in placing three of their mouths in horizontal, like I said, the three
horizontal, vertical or diagonal like in a row, then that specific player will win and it is a solid
game.
So yes, you may be wondering that how the computer knows that the three rows are complete and this
is the case for winning this game.
So we have already made the algorithm like this that if the three specific places are filled with a
single color like cross or zero, so if the horizontal or vertical or diagonal becomes same, then we
have to like show the dialog box that that specific player wins the game.
So we will be looking at the application program and then we will figure out that how it is an already
solid game with a force to draw, assuming the best play from both players.
So we have like taking the inputs from the players and there is already decided that if three comes
in a row then we have to show that yes, you want like whether it be X or whether it be zero.
Now we have went through the specifications of the project, the interface of the project.
Right, how it is going to look on that window.
Now, you all may be wondering that what actually we are going to learn while making this project and
it is a very natural question that we are making a game, we are making a game in Java itself.
So what are the concepts of Java we will be learning while the making of this game, this project in
core Java.
So the first and foremost thing we are going to learn is object oriented programming.
In Java, object oriented programming is the best like method of making any project in Java.
We should prefer making projects using this open concept only like it makes the coding part very easy,
convenient and user friendly.
Like we have to write like a bit of code and we can use it again and again.
The reusability factor is the most like exciting feature of object oriented programming and fascinated
me the most.
And like this took me to this object oriented programming thing in Java.
So yes, there are many other features in object oriented programming.
We have classes and objects inside object oriented programming and objects are, we all know real world
entities so we can handle the real world data with this.
Oops.
So yes, we have extensively used the string and AWG frameworks while making this project.
We have used the J frame j buttons, j menu, bar item, and so many of string components are going
to be used by making up this project.
So it's going to be interesting learning that how this game could be made, but simply using some already
declared components in the library, whether it be swing or AWP, we just have to simply import with
a one line code like import Java, dot, AWP and string, and every component inside the string and
AWP will be imported and we can use it wherever we want to use it in the code.
So apart from these things, we are going to actually learn, of course our game tutorial.
So you must be have heard about this that like a game development team is very complex and we have to
learn.
So many languages in order to make a actually working game.
But the speciality of this project that we are going to make a game like this and this is made in core
Java itself.
Of course it is an interesting game and it may like involve many complex like involving like many complex
packages, libraries, extension and it could be anything.
But no, we are just using core Java for writing the program and with a simple Java programming language,
you can make this project.
You do not have to learn anything else, any like backend library, any other language like packages.
We just have to learn how to write code in Java and then we can jump into learning this project.
So this is the most interesting feature while making this project.
We are also going to learn functionalities of a to play a game.
Like there are various types of games, a single player game A to play a game or a multiplayer game.
So in this we are going to learn that how to tackle functionalities of a two player game.
We have to set functions like in this manner that if like this thing happens, like if suppose X comes
in a row, whether it is horizontal, diagonal or vertical, then we have to update the score of that
specific player.
And like the second player score will remain same.
That will be noted.
So we are going to write loops, conditions inside Java so that we can tackle this to play our game
by maintaining the scores in that manner.
The game is happening like the game is taking place.
So I hope you all have gained a rough idea about this project and must be like we all are having a nature
that if we hear about something interesting, we develop our inquisitiveness inside us to learn how
to make that specific thing which fascinated us.
So I hope that you all are excited about learning how to make this project from scratch as we are going
to start making things from scratch by creating a new project in the compiler and then like initializing
classes, initializing functions and everything inside it, like all the objects, methods and everything.
So let us take a quick look at the working of the application and then start the coding path.
Let how to start coding for this project.
So see you in the next part with the other functionalities of this project.
Thank you.