Hello, everyone.
In that series of learning how to make projects in Java.
Today we are going to start learning a new project that TA in Java.
So the name of the project is Food Ordering System.
So this is an application, a GI application made in Java and it is headed as a food ordering system.
So this is the like interface of the application.
You can see it on your screens that the frame contains like several fields which asks for a selection
of size, select which type of beverage you want to order, and there are some radio buttons from which
we have to select that.
What we want to order like that is the input field which asks for how many glasses we want, like a
quantity of these items we have to enter here in numeric form so that the our system like calculates
how many glasses you have to order and according to it, what will be the prices of the whole card.
So this is going to be the home page of the application.
Like when the window opens, this interface will be visible to the user.
Now after with this dropdown button like Select Size is the name of the label and inside which there
is a dropdown asking for the size of the item which we want to order.
So there are three options here small, medium and large.
So we have to select one of them from these three, after which we have to select the type of beverage
like we want to order.
So currently we are showing four options mentioned as juice, water, tea, coffee and like we can change
it according to our convenience.
When we are making the application, it's upon us that what we want to keep in the like radio button
options.
So below this there is a yes ahead.
You can see I have entered five and this will be the quantity of water I want to add to the cart.
So there are two buttons and an order.
So on clicking the add button the like a checkbox will appear like not a checkbox, but a dialog box
will appear asking for eyes.
Like if I want to add eyes to the beverage, I want to order.
So if I wish to arise, I have to click yes in this dialog box.
And if not, then I have to click no.
So when I will click yes, then automatically the card will be updated with a glass of water.
Like here we have five glasses of water, medium size of glasses, and also adults eyes will be added
to our glasses.
Okay.
So we have total yes, five medium glasses of water with eyes and it will appear on the screen so that
you can see that what actually you have added to the cart and what actually you have ordered.
So in this there are two buttons on hold called as ADD and order.
So on clicking and the item will be added to the cart and you can select other options from the menu.
Also that I suppose you want two things to order, so you can order this by using cart and once you
have like completed all the selections you want to make, you have to click on this order button.
So in the next slide we can see that yes, we have order option and on clicking order option, a message
appears like it is also a dialog box containing the like total some of our order that we have ordered
for.
So five medium glasses of water with eyes and this is the price we have to pay.
So 5 million glasses of water with ice costs 12.5 like what is the currency?
You can set it according to your own.
And these two buttons functions in a totally different way.
This add button helps us to add items to our cart and then again like gives us the options to select
more items from the menu.
And then again add it to CART.
And once we finalize our ordering, then we can click on this order button.
Then this message dialog box will appear, start showing us that of what we have actually finalizing
to order and once we will click okay then another dialog box will appear which showing a message of
you should pay 12.5 and whatever the currency is.
So yes, they are on clicking this.
Okay, finally your order will be completed and you will again like visit the same homepage like this.
So on finalizing the order you can like complete everything.
So this was the basic like idea of the application.
Now next we will look up to what are the specifications of the project which we are going to make today.
So this is basically a food ordering system.
So we are going to manage everything about the food ordering system.
We can add items to the cart to attach add ons to it like we have seen that we were attaching eyes to
water.
Also we can confirm our order or once we have finished like selecting the items and the cart is full,
then we have to check out.
Then we will click on the order button.
Also at the last on the completion of the order, the pop up will appear like a dialog box.
So again we have already seen which will ask for what is the money to be paid by the like user and the
final amount to be paid will be also displayed in on clicking.
Okay, a separate a separate dialog box will appear and the final amount of money which we have to pay
for whatever we have ordered.
So these are the specifications of the project like the food ordering system which we are going to make
today.
So now you may be wondering that on making this project there should be something concept based like
logic, which we will learn after completion of this project, like on successful completion of this
project.
And the project will be working fine.
Everything will be like with no box, there will be no exceptions.
Then what are the like?
Things which we will logics concept, we will be learning on completion of the project and you are no
wrong.
So this question will naturally arise in your mind that what will you learn on making this project?
On learning the concepts of this project?
So this project is made in Java.
This is basically a Java GUI application which will have a test window interface.
We will be like operating this application on our desktops and the interface will open and in a separate
window the app will have us like Icon.
We have icons in our desktop.
Similarly, this app will have an icon and icon and that will open a separate window of the application
and then we will be performing the tasks involved with this application.
Okay.
So the concepts which we are going to learn on completion of this project is object oriented programming
in Java.
So this project is based on object oriented programming.
Okay.
So objects are real world entities, which are we like?
We have to handle real world and real world data.
Real world objects are going to be handled by making this project.
That is a difference in object oriented programming and the conventional process oriented programming
that we do not have any methods of tackling real world entities.
But in object oriented programming, we have that facility that we can tackle everything about real
world entities.
So yes, we are going to learn the object oriented programming concept and handle all the real world
entities.
Also, we are going to be building a Java application, so of course we will learn a lot about Java
programming language.
Java is a very interesting programming language.
We all know that.
That's why we are here and learning how to make applications in Java.
So this is the first benefit that Java is a language where we can make like real world application,
real like this applications are applicable in our daily lives.
So Java is that beneficial with the help.
Eight celebrities we had mentioned, two of them had swing and AWP frameworks.
So in this application there will be extensive use of swing and AWP frameworks.
So these two are basically like toolkits in which we are going to like put up things and then add functionality
to everything.
Like suppose that it will be offline.
So the frame is going to contain a panel and inside the panel we will be really having our input fields,
buttons and like yes, the dropdown box and everything like the dialog box will was appearing asking
for yes, no.
So once we will be checking out.
So everything is enclosed inside a toolkit and that toolkit is provided to us with the mercy of these
libraries we call Spring and AWP.
AWP stands for Abstract Window Toolkit, and this helps us in making the UI application like best window
interface applications are made using these spring and AWP frameworks.
So yes, these are beneficial to the like learners who aspire to develop applications in Java.
Also, we will be learning a Java food ordering system which is like no wonder we have we are making
a food ordering system so we will learn how to make a food ordering system in Java as well.
And classes and objects are going to be extensively used inside this application.
So if there are object oriented programming, there will be classes and objects for sure and there is
no wonder.
And so like everything we are going to learn while making this application is listed here, we will
be learning a lot of things after the completion of this project.
We will be like with a full mind concepts of object oriented programming, showing any frameworks like
giving us like what we can say that a teaser like the teaser to Swing and AWP is a frame, a text button,
a menu bar.
And there are so many components of these packages which we are going to embed in our application and
then see how easy it becomes to put up things by just importing a simple component of these library
and things make them so simple that we do not have to light a write up plenty of code to fix things.
We just have to simply add a single line statement like import this and everything is going to like
already import it to your project and just you have to call it again and again and everything will work
properly fine without any complexities.
So yes, I hope you have gained our like a rough idea about what actually we are going to make today.
This is a food ordering system with a functional functionality attached with these buttons and order
and we have to select these options from here.
Also, we will be asked for the items, we will be asked for size, we will be asked for quantities
we want to order.
And then we have to add things to the cart.
If we want to add more things, or we can simply press this order button to checkout from this cart.
On clicking this order, we will be like shown a message that what actually we have ordered.
This is a sort of confirmation and also at last you will be shown what actually you have to pay.
So, yes, this exactly.
It was.
Now, in the next part, we will be learning what how this application works actually.
And then the prototype to the code, which we are going to write in order to make this application.
So save in the next part with the complete project tutorial.
Yes.
So see you then.