Our project is Java COVID 19 cases tracker system.
So we are going to develop an Web interface or web application for tracking the cases all over the world
of COVID 19.
So during this pandemic scenario, we have seen there are huge data analysis part in COVID tracking
system.
So we are going to create some data visualization or we can set data set part with some spring framework,
and we are going to find some formal and visible solution for this.
So COVID 19 crisis ecosystem we are going to build using Java.
So this Java project is based on core Java Java spring framework and servlet pattern.
So I'm not going to beat core servlet concepts here.
I'm using some servlet concepts here.
So our full system is based on Java Spring framework.
I'm going to teach the Java Spring framework from the scratch.
I'm going to explain Java code syntax each and everything.
So our project is Java COVID 19 tracker system, and we are going to build some data representation
part in our frontend using Java framework.
I'm using here dataset part default dataset, but I'm not creating my own data set here.
I'm using data set default on available on the Internet.
You can use such similar data sets also.
So this is one of the useful application or we can say one of the useful data representation application
in current pandemic.
We can find all the cases we can find or append, or we can say ascending list, descending list of
each and everything.
So this is all about how we are going to develop our project.
So let us see what is our project aim first.
So our project AIM is to develop wave applications from the ecosystem of COVID 19 cases.
So we are going to develop one wave application for this purpose, and we are going to use your spring
framework.
Those types of development are six.
Basically.
First is project setup, how we are going to set up our project.
Second is understanding different tools we are going to use there.
What is the dependency design, etc.?
What are the XML files and all the things here?
Some Java basic concepts.
Davos Spring Framework, Java Solid Concepts.
I'm not going to use core solid part here.
I'm just considering solid as some syntax Java Web interfaces, how the web interfaces are made in Java,
Java PHI, etc..
So this is all about how the steps of our development.
So our project aim is to develop the reputation.
Application requirements.
Java Basic Knowledge If you should have some Java basic knowledge regarding the syntax speech and etc..
I'm not going to explain from the scratch of Java, but I'm going to tell you for some simple cases.
Java spin framework and not going with syntax this part or deep part of the Java string.
But you should know the Java spinning, but otherwise I'm going to explain also here.
Then Java web development how the web application developed in Java in regarding to the servlet part,
what is the front end, back end each and everything.
Then tools required.
Here is JDK, this Java development kit that brings ID, which is basically intelligent idea, which
is very useful platform to create such Java applications.
I'm going to use your ultimate edition, but you can choose Community Edition also.
Then Spring Initialized, which is basically web interface to initialize your project.
So this is it about how we can go with this?
So I'm going to specify the Java basic concepts also here.
But before that, you should remember some Java basics in taxes.
I'm just telling you the Java basic concepts here.
So Java is made up of three parts other than other languages like Python or C.
There are no parts in their languages that are just compilers or interpreters which are compiling the
higher language language to the machine level language and you are printing the output or you are developing
your project.
But Java is made up of three parts.
Firstly, JVM, which is Java Virtual Machine.
Why?
I'm telling you this because JVM is our runtime server.
We can say for this purpose.
So we are going to fetch data from one thing on available on internet which is lively, updated within
one day or two days.
So these are our data sets and what we are going to do, we are going to load it in the server pattern.
We are going to represent using Java Spring framework.
So Java virtual machine is a not physically existent machine.
It is virtual machine.
It provides runtime environment in which Java bytecode executed.
It also runs programs in other languages but compiled in Java by.
So basically it's Morse code, which is very important in the server part server and part it verifies
the codes, which is basically the compiler error or something, which is detects, executes code and
provides the entire environment.
Why I'm telling you the same thing is if you are getting runtime error, no need to check your web application
code or etc. You have to check your basic code, java code.
So these are the things you are going to use here.
So other than this jihadi jihadis Java runtime environment, which you set off tools, libraries, graph
files, etc., and Java application programs.
It is implementation of JVM.
We can say for the implementation purpose we need backend as a jihadi for the JVM.
Again, this is physically exist.
So these are some libraries.
Java files are files in Java.
JDK, JDK Java Development Kit, which contains Git Plus JVM.
So Jari Plus mixed JDK.
Also, it contains Java compiler, which is basically compiling purpose and which is basically you are
downloading the JDK only from the website.
I'm using your Java JDK 16th version, but then you are downloading that part is basically JDK.
So there are C version, standard edition versions, Enterprise Edition versions available on Java.
So these are the basic things.
So let us see pictorial representation of this game is this basically the oval shape is basically virtual
machine which loads the bytecode and all the things are virtual like all the ram, all the things are
virtual.
So it's access our virtual server for our purposes by creating this application and executing all the
code's state of libraries, Java file, some other files like documentation, etc., etc. Content content
makes great job contents, JVM and all these things.
JDK contains some Java files other than these, given all the things some Java compilers also are there.
There are some dependencies in Greek also.
So all the things makes JDK, JVM plus GIRI and Java compiler.
So the downloaded file is basically just JDK and your installing that.
So if you are not installed, JDK try to download latest JDK, which is 16th version, also give the
path name and etc. You can check your path also of your thing and you can check the Java version also
using Java version command in your CMD.
So I checked and I'm using 16 version.
So this is it.
We are going to do so.
I'm going to tell you some Java methods and classes later.
But let us see how we can initialize our project first.
So let me go to the Chrome.
Your web browser, any web browser, you have to go, then go to this start dot, spring dot.
So this is basically the spring initialize and we can say spring initializing project.
So you can check the documentation, etc..
So currently they are using 1.5 to 2.0.
So this is basically on 2.2.
Currently.
Also you can check here Springwood versions.
This is basically latest version and these are the snapshots.
So these are not the stable virgins.
You can check this is the stable version, 2.5.3.
Then my project, we are going to use your memory.
So in Java there are three or four frameworks already deployed.
So other than I'm taking the web application, I'm going with core Java, part code Java are basically
based on three or four applications.
Popular are three and my main and gradle.
So this basically condensed some web apps of late gbk JSP is also there and best framework also.
But my brain is more advanced part of and which contains spring hibernate.
Of all the things or in that part I will tell you what is hibernate and gbk basically gbk is basically
connecting part hibernate.
You can initialize the commands database directly in the java files.
No need to extract that part.
So these are the main things and Gradle is basically for the mobile app development, etc..
So language is over Java tools, language java.
No need to choose this code or go with Java with this.
Now we are going to mention this code.
I'm going.
Minchin as.
COVID.
So artefact name is again.
Well, we.
But I like this name.
Is this then?
Name is COVID 19.
Kisses.
Record.
Package name is this.
Remember I'm using Java 16 and click here 16 Virgin Java file image.
So we need to require some add some dependencies.
Also click add dependencies part.
So hope you can see this part.
All the things.
Let me add Webb part, which is Spring Webb.
We need to deploy our application using supreme efficiency.
So beautiful thing offspring.
You never required any server server part here.
Apache Tomcat is the default embedded container which deploys on the internet and you will get the output.
So these are the default server in the spring web.
Then let me add Tim Lee.
Which is basically Java template engine for the server and standalone environments, which is basically
HTML5 engine, which allows the HTML to correctly deploys on the browser and as a static prototype if
it's so dynamic.
Also spring and spring or we can say check also Springwood DevTools live, reload, restart.
I need to use that part so these things I need to request.
So Spring Web, Tim Live and Springwood.
Other than this you can add that also for the chat bot and etc..
So you can check there.
I'm not using your any restful API because our HTML file will be loaded to the spring only, so no restful
API is required here.
So Java maven this.
Keep as it is this and generate.
Once you generate this, you can see the file is downloaded, which is basically the file and later
we are going to open it in our ID.
But before that proceeding to our project, let us see the Java Basic Concept concepts first.
So first it's Java methods and classes.
So everything in a java is made up of classes and objects.
If you have seen our program in Java, again, it's class and method.
So while writing any program, printing any output or if you are making any arithmetic program, you
need to require classes and methods.
So everything in Java is associated with classes and methods.
Without classes and methods, you cannot write any Java program which is basically purely invalid Java
program.
What example?
In real life, cars are objects.
Sarah.
Sarah Having some attributes like weight color.
Methods are dry.
You break.
Stop.
Etc. open.
The door are also can be method.
So these are the things like in Java.
So methods are just the logic behind that part.
So classes is like object constructor or blueprint blueprint for object.
So car is the object.
So but we can create a one class as a vehicle.
Similarly, we can put in that vehicle motorbike.
Also, another object car is an object truck is an or another object.
So class is the basically the object constructor and object is basically to use that call the class
or use that class or to execute particular class.
An object and called instance of classes without object.
We cannot call classes except the class in a similar class or classes subclasses part or if the class
is inherited that part.
So the inheritance concept without an inheritance concept, we cannot use classes without any objects.
Methods are declared within the classes.
It contains the whole code of particular functions.
Methods contains return values, basic pairs also.
So basically methods are basic the logical thinking of logical part.
We can see logical block of classes, method, contents, all the logic of the whole process.
And object of class is created, we can easily use that methods with the objects which something types
like object methods, etc. in the java and you can definitely use that objects and classes and methods.
Again, main methods is the default method in Java.
If you are using public static void means seen with arguments which returns always strings.
It is main method which is default method in Java to run any program in Java.
So this is the first thing which loads on JVM.
So while writing the code, we are going to write some logic in main method only or we are going to
call that logic in method to run the program.
So this is about the Java methods and classes.
But what is this thing thing here?
So let us see.
What is the spring framework here is.
So if you know, in the python or in any other languages, there are some default frameworks to deploy
on the way as a python has Django and flask.
Similarly in Java in 2003, spring framework is created, which is basically basic framework in Java,
but there are several steps of development be taken and spring framework is now very popular in Java
to deploy any web application.
Second thing, it's long term stability.
And third thing is it's very easy to use.
So there are some advantages of the framework.
Also, I'm going to deal with this.
So spring framework is a lightweight framework, we can say, and you can start as a framework of frameworks.
So there are different frameworks in Java as to hibernate types to be GCF.
So.
And these are some popular frameworks in Java.
So spring frameworks includes all the frameworks and they made some robust framework for that.
So no need to require Hibernate or Scrooge again and again we can use spring framework directly.
This is my web MVC framework, which has several modules like IOC, then database injection also there.
Then dependency injection also there.
So these are some default cases framework you can set as a structure where we find a solution of various
technical problems.
So in spring framework, we can use database, then hibernate part, then JSP part, servlet part.
Also you can use.
So these are the some default spring frameworks.
So in three further videos, I'm going with some steps of development and how we are going to develop
our project.
So first initialize your project using spring, initialize the use that constraints and use that ID.