So our project has a store billing system which is developed by using Java programming language.
In this video we will be talking about the introduction of this project.
Overview of the project.
The main objective of the store billing system is to manage the details of seller's cashiers, products
and sales.
It manages all the information about products, stocks, etc..
The project project is built at both administrative and end user and also does both the admin and user
are guaranteed the access of the backend database.
The purpose of this project is to build an application program to reduce the manual work for managing
product sales.
Contents.
Introduction Requirements, Project Setup and components.
Introduction of the project is top billing system is a software based application is a desktop based
application.
This app enables the customer to perform the basic sale and purchase operation.
The system provides the access to the admin to create an account of cashier and product or to stock
manage sales of products.
The cashier can access this application for waiving the sale details and perform the operations on account
as per the requirements.
Requirements for this project.
Hardware requirement a processor clock speed of 1.7 gigahertz system powers of 64 bit monitor, LCD
monitor or any laptop, a standard keyboard, compatible mouse or any touchpad software requirements.
Windows ten A microsoft Maya SQL Server frontend is developed by using Java code swing with the help
of NetBeans IDE and backend is developed by using MySQL to store the database.
Set up of the project.
First of all, install MySQL if not installed at first, then we will create a database in my SQL named
as SBS, which is the abbreviation of a stored billing system.
Then we will be creating three tables named as a stock sale and user.
After that, we will insert values of sale table, so we will be inserting values of sale table.
Then we have to install NetBeans IDE if not install.
Or you can also use any supporting IDs as well for the Java development.
Then we will create a new project named as a store billing system and start coding our Java classes.
Components of the project will be our database named as SBS.
Some Java files named as ADD Cashier Add Product Admin Panel DB Abbreviation of database delete cashier
delete product generate invoice, log in sale and few more classes will be there a package inside which
all these classes.
So there will be a package named as a store inside which all these classes with inside libraries will
be used.
My SQL Java Connector, which will help us to connect our project with our MySQL database and JDK 17,
which will be a development kit to develop this project.
That's all in the introduction video.