Our project is Java online system.
So we are going to create one which platform for university level basic or you can create with for students
and teachers in audio you can consider like that.
So we are going to create one online quiz system with the back end in return in the Java.
So it's very useful to understand these parts.
So Java project, this project is based on GBK, JSP, Java servlet and server deployment.
So I'm considering only the back end part I mentioned here GBK JSP Java servlet and server deployment
I'm going to consider there.
So we are going to create an online quiz system at a university level which using a JSP as a main backend
with the help of Java Servlet, also we are going to use we are going to connect with the database and
we are going to finally deploy on the server.
So I'm going to consider here only the and we project here there are different libraries inside written
on Java or different approaches inside Java.
Like you can use Gradle, you can go with Mavin also.
So these are some famous frameworks inside Java Spring also is there, but I'm going to consider only
the end project because it's a very simple, basic and easier to understand than other frameworks.
Even though it's very basic thing, but it is a very helpful and essential or I can say effective platform
and project to create some online ecosystem from the scratch.
So before proceeding with the project, I'm going to tell you you should have some basic knowledge about
Java classes methods, then about some knowledge of Java servlet and basic connection.
But this is all about the back end part.
In the further part, I'm going to do how we can create frontend and everything.
So let us see how we can create or we can proceed with our project.
So our project is basically develop a way of using Java for quiz platform at a university level, events
or examination with the help of Java Servlet, JSP, GBC.
So Java Servlet JSP GBC are the main backends part of our project, but.
These are main part I'm considering.
Are this is basically our project team steps off our development is first is project set up we are going
to set up our project.
Then understanding what we are going to use your different tools, we are going to use your some ID,
then JDK and some sort of work part also.
So we are going to understand how basically they are going to work here then.
JSP Basics.
You should know about JSP Basics.
I am not going to tell.
Like you should learn totally from this, but you should know some basic part of JSP then basics of
databases like my scalar oracle you can use here.
So how we can create database, then creation of table, then invoking and inserting inside that table.
So basic knowledge about database, relational database and considering here java servlet and gdb connection
you should know basic part of Java.
So development engine connection and deployment on the server.
So this is these are the some steps of our development.
But before that I'm going to tell how we are proceeding with the project.
So before proceeding this object, we should know about the basic outline.
So we have only two users here, which is basically first is teachers and other are students.
So teachers are basically admin roles and considering who has a right to change questions, then see
the student leads and then publish some results and etc. etc..
Second thing, which are basically student students are going to attempt their quiz.
They can see their marks and some results.
So you can create some advanced things like bleach apply for recheck, then teacher will get notifications
or remark.
The question for that like the question answer is wrong.
So I'm considering here only the CQ level or multiple choice questions here because handling multiple
choice questions with the JSP is very easier.
Or we can specify and we can get precise marking system inside that.
For advanced things.
You can create some long questions, like brief questions or two or three line questions.
You can add insert that, but it takes more time to deploy with the server or deploy with the database.
And according to that, you have to change the relational database and relational tables also inside
the database.
So application requirements.
I'm going to drill post Java program.
We need to display all the web contents inside the Java program.
So these are the Java programs only, but with the servlet and some JSP are also then Java program basic
knowledge you should have Java program basic knowledge like classes methods, the parameters attributes.
What is the public and difference between public and private?
Then we are going to create static things here.
Then basic concepts of skill DSP basics.
I'm going to tell the DSP basics inside this also, but if you know the basics, the understanding of
this, this project is become very easier to understand this then for these all out the back end.
But what about the front end part for the front end part, I'm going to use your HTML CSS basically
with the help of bootstrap.
Also, I'm going to create here beta.
So consider this, I'm not going to develop HTML and this frontend from the scratch, I'm going to use
some readymade CSS files available on the internet or I already created for the different projects.
Plus, I'm going to use some remote bootstrap programs which are already freely available on bootstrap
platform to deploy on our front end part.
Because creating from scratch, it's very difficult for due to time constraint.
Also, we are not focusing on the front end part of our project.
We are more focused on our back end part and developing the Java program for the system with database
connection also.
So we are considering here both our to use cases admin and students admin, not basically teachers.
I'm considering here as a day as an admin of our website or VP.
So there should be to log in for teachers also and students also student has to first register and then
go admin can and I have some privileges to change their parts and everything.
For admin or teachers we have to do some administrative actions like add questions, then search for
students, etc. etc. For students they have to give options like register, log in with submit and students
which are basically non administrative actions on these platforms.
If you see I have seen some quiz platforms online, you can choose front end of that also and you can
develop your own platform according to that.
So tools we are going to require is JDK 1.8.
So I'm considering here only JDK 1.8, which provides Java eight E Virgin Enterprise Edition version
for the Web dev deployment.
So this is very old, I'm considering, but it's very effective and it's work finally with without any
bugs or errors.
So I'm considering this JDK only then ID, I'm going to use your NetBeans.
You can choose any other famous IDE like eclipse intel idea you can consider, but creating with the
NetBeans is very easy as I'm going to use JDK 1.8 Java E Version eight is very useful for the web deployment.
Oracle Out of my skill database, you can choose both as your databases, but I'm going with Oracle.
You can choose my SQL, but you have to specify all things inside my skills.
So Oracle using Oracle is very easy.
You can choose a glass free server for deployment or Tomcat server for deployment.
Remember inside the Tomcat server you can change your http port, etc. etc. things.
But remember Tomcat server is Tomcat server only supports Java E version seven.
According to that, ERP changed everything.
So Tomcat Server, I'm going to use glass v server, but I told you how.
I will tell also how we can change our port and etc. inside this.
And for the oracle, I'm going for the database.
I'm going to use your Oracle database only you can easily download it from the official website, Oracle
19 C 18 C version.
So this is all about the application requirements of our project.
So these are some basic things we require for our project before proceeding with the project.
Let us see how we can.
Set up a little project first.
So as you can see, I already created everything.
But I will tell you from the scratch.
So let us see how we can create it from the scratch.
So go to the file first and create a new project.
Regardless of you have created any other project.
Go to file.
Create a new project.
Then go to the Java.
And you can see there are different applications like Java Maven, which is basically very advanced
thing for the Java, but different projects you can create with Java.
But I'm going to get going with and.
Then you can see the various options here.
Java effects, then Java Web to consider web and click next.
Then use the project name, then project location and project folder.
You can choose this also, but I'm not going to choose this part because it will automatically create
one library file also the next there.
Then before proceeding you are to specify the service and settings.
So I'm using your hourglass feature basically with Java eight.
If you don't download it, it click and then it will show you the downloading page for that and you
can create some context, but it will change according to your project next and create calendar here
finish.
I'm not going to click here finish because I already created one project for that purpose due to time
constraint.
So you can see in HTML it's very basic in HTML.
I already created one another in HTML for my purpose.
So you can see created already in the HTML pages, pages here.
So once you download it, you can go to our tools here and you can choose the server part.
So you can see this is a class B server I choose with these for http port.
In your case, htp port is might be a different for your purpose.
Once you go to the this part, you can see the one dialog box opens when you click the server part there.
So you can see the report is basically 8080 for your case.
But I will tell you how we can change that for.
So let us see how we can change that.
So first, go to your glass server platform, basically.
So it basically for the Windows system so you can go to your CDB users and go to your default name,
then go to the class, switch server, then go to the glass fish or that config file there and go to
the domains, then your default domain, then go to the config and check for the.
Domain.
XML file and open it with your default code editor or default script.
You can also use notepad also, so we are going to change that a little bit.
Search for your default.
Or basically your default port is AT&amp;T.
In my case, I already changed to 2002.
So you can see one line there.
Network listener.
I will show you once again.
I will show you inside that thing.
So.
The default thing is your code editor and change that to.
Oh, your your in your case, you can change it to the different thing.
Also.
Like I already changed it to the 2002.
As you can see.
As you can see, I already change it to the.
2000.
To put in your case, it should be 8080.
Change it to 32,000.
So this is a very important step for this purpose.
It should be located inside the domain of XML only.
So this is very important step for creating or basically creating basic outline for our project.
So let us see how we can go through this.
Also, this is a basic GSP program we are going to create here.
So before proceeding the project, I'm going to tell you some
more part about how we can create this so you can choose this index or HTML.
So inside this is very basic.
I am choosing for some bootstrap and equity programs here already.
So these are some remote files.
If you look at this part, you can see in the remote files of our project also, these are the loaded
CSS, everything.
So this is the navigation bar and everything I choose.
Then I use this image.
Then I put this welcome to our platform online examination system with some information with basic based
on Java project I created, then I created one I container and everything.
So these are some basic things I use here.
So to use these things, what you are going to do is very simple thing you are going to create.
Just inside your project.
If you are using NetBeans ID go to online, then quiz that project folder, then go to the web and you
can see the web and index HTML.
So just copy, paste these all things and you're going to use your CSS, then bootstrap.
Then I'm going to main not meant to Node.js for CSS ergs, but then some logos part here.
So this is all about how we can proceed with our project for the time constraint.
I already created this index dot HTML with admin login and student login.
You can change it to the teachers.
Log in here also and next and everything.
So in the next tutorials I'm going to tell you how we can create with admin log in, JSP student log
in there JSP also.
So let us see how we can deploy this.
Just click here clean and build.
Once it is done, click run here.
So it takes.
A few minutes to reply on your default.
Or a project or a program, and it will take time to load everything because I'm using some web based
images.
So it will take time.
So as you can see, you can see welcome to our portal online system.
And this is so this is basically loading page for this animation.
I'm considering only these like you can see these animations, then this animation also here for I'm
using your bootstrap program here.
So as you can see, I can change these images also to different things as you can see.
So this is our basic loading.
Part of our JSP part.
In the next videos or next tutorials, I'm going to tell you how we are going to produce student log
in page then admin log in with the help of JSP.