So next class which we have to create a supplier class.
Here we will take the soccer player and that player according with the cursor.
So here what I will do.
Mostly clear class extends the actor class here.
And the next thing which we need so here we need a public constructor first.
Player and it should take the input y and into x coordinates.
Under that we will take super apparent class holding on.
I will pass x comma y here and make.
My third initial player.
I'm done.
This will set the image of our soccer player first.
So here I have to create and set the image of our player.
So here I will write image icon.
Icon equal to a new image.
I couldn't.
And under that I will give the part of my image.
CRC Resources, which has the name so combined that Bianchi and no image image is equal to icon.
Get image.
Get image and learn.
Next thing we have to set the image here.
So.
So we have centered our image.
Now we have to move the player.
That is so cool.
So to move matter moves the object inside the world.
So here I have the end x and the end y argument here on the right and the x equal to x and plus x here
in the y.
Equal to y.
Y plus y.
Say the x the x here, set the Y with the D line here and then next thing.
Okay, so this part is done.
We already set and take the coordinates of our movement and this will move our object inside the world
here.
Next thing which we have to create is a baggage or Java class here.