Here.
I have the class for the baggage object.
This object is movable.
So it also has a move method which we have created previously in the player class here.
So it also contain that matter.
So firstly, it should extend the actor class here.
Because I mean based glacier.
Here.
I have the constructor.
Okay.
So under that, we will create.
My provider.
Initial baggage, name, baggage.
I don't know.
We have to write the body of this method, so that is what we have to do.
We will firstly set our image icon.
Icon is equal to.
Okay.
So we need the new image icon.
And said depart to Assad see the comma baggage that B and she.
Now after that we have to write I am she is equal to I could not get image right the image also and.
Okay.
Now we have to take matter of movement also.
So here I will write public void means give the parameter of the x comma into y.
Under this I will write into the x equal to same body of the player class which we have created in that.
So same thing in divide here y and the class y here.
Now this set x
give the parameter to the x here set y gives it parameter with the DVI.
So here.
This is the class for the baggage object.
This object is movable.
So here we have the move method also.