So here we will create the area class.
It is the object on which we try to please the packages here.
So it should extend our mean that is actor class first.
Under that we have to create its constructor.
So here I will create a matter initial area and then we will create that method first.
Now what do we have to do?
Firstly, same thing.
We have to set the image icon here.
So just simply write image icon on.
Give the part authority resources or not be unclear.
Right.
Image.
Image is equal to I can not get image here and simply said the image also.
And so this is our area class.
It is the object on which we try to please the packages.
And now the next and the last part which we have to do is to create the so called one third Java.
This will be our main class, which will give our output on the window.