So in the first part I discussed about cryptography and different techniques.
So let us keep it aside.
I can say cryptography that is more focus on why we are using Java.
So again, I'm focusing on Gvm and JDK instead of if you know, there are not very like research languages
like Python also create virtual environment, but Gvm is virtual machine so we can perform different
cryptography techniques on each and we can check that part.
But JVM is basically Java virtual machine.
It's not physically exist.
Java is made up of different parts.
JVM, Guardian, JDK, JDK is basically Java development kit.
It consists of Jad and JVM physically exist is the implementation of JVM its runtime environment.
There are different libraries, Java files, there are different programs in that, but JVM never existed
on your system.
It is just a virtual environment or virtual machine which loads calls, verifies calls, executes calls
on its own.
So that's a very powerful thing in Java, like there is a virtual machine, so we never required about
trades and those parts.
Our system configuration never limits Java programs.
So that's very important.
Then this is basic thing, JDK, Java structure, this is my JVM, if I consider it like this.
So in this and so this is basically Venn diagram you can like so just like this journey and we are gvm
here and there are sets of libraries and different things here.
So now let me tell you, what is the cryptography thing?
Yes.
Okay.
So before going to.
For their part, let me tell some.
Right.
Cryptography.
And what is the cryptography in the market?
You can.
There are different things like bitcoin is like that's cryptocurrency.
If you know, the U.S. thinks Bitcoin also, there are Dogecoin also.
That's a cryptocurrency.
So crypto is not about money currency.
Cryptography is just basically the technique to hide the text so high the plaintext.
So let me, as I told you, a B is doing the stuffs, sending the data to the outside world.
There are a lot of lot of tricks available.
These articles are.
These are my attackers which always want to penetrate to this system or these systems or any data.
They want to steal these information always.
But and we are very talented.
Or we can say intelligent persons.
They are talking in code language also.
Always.
They are talking in code language.
Or always, which No.
Four known that code language is known for a and so that's a similar thing in cryptography.
But.
What is great is sending this message.
So this is my message.
With some key.
So this is circle is my just key sending to this being knows this is the key to encrypt the data b is
also having this data or we can say key to encrypt that my this part this is the my data.
This is my key.
But.
No one knows this is the key because there is no meaning for that key.
There is no meaning for that data.
So that's the encryption thing is happening here.
So now A and B charts are safe.
So in previous part I told you what is the basic things?
Like what is the semantic semantic use basically for the encryption and the decryption?
These saying these same for the encryption and decryption.
So I will tell you what is the inscription?
Inscription is this basically plaintext ciphertext?
Ciphertext is basically no one can read that message.
There is no meaning for that.
We can read that message, but there is no meaning for that text.
There are some symbols.
Also, we can include some streaks, anything, data in that we can add space.
So that's a thing for the decryption and encryption.
If key is same, then it's known as symmetric key.
Then what is the asymmetric?
If there is a symmetric thing, there should be symmetric thing.
What is the ultimate thing?
Why?
Sending a data to be a creates two keys.
One is public.
Another one is private.
For the encryption of data when it's public and other is private to send the data.
So what a is doing.
He's doing all he's encrypting the data using.
Encrypting the data using this public key.
Okay.
Encrypting data with this public key.
This is my public key.
And sending this key would be also to decrypt that data.
But why be sending some data to a.
It is decrypting that data to his private.
So as you can say that there is a lot of lot of security in this and there are different techniques
like signature in hashing.
Different things happen here or in this data.
So let me move to some important part.
So what is the cryptography thing here?
Let me tell you.
Cryptography is a study of different techniques to secure data from unauthorized entry.
So cryptography is not always related to encryption on anything.
It's a technique to secure data from unauthorized entity.
And anything you want to say in computer science, we try to develop strategies and practices to protecting
sensitive data.
Now, if you have checked WhatsApp, all they are saying end to end encrypted that what it means your
chatting is not stored as a common text or your voice is not stored as a common text.
It's encrypted.
So most of cryptography involves very advanced mathematical functions used to or used for securing data.
Why?
We request advanced things?
Because attackers are always changing their strategies.
They are always trying to penetrate the system.
So we require a very advanced functions, mathematical functions for these purposes.
The sole purpose of algorithms to develop cryptography is hide data from attacker or middlemen.
In this article we are going to understood this part and everything.
So you may take the cryptography things and we are going to do that stuff.
So this is the plaintext.
I played one key.
Which encryption algorithm.
Ciphertext generated decryption algorithm only pin test is generated.
So what is this imp things I'm going to tell you.
plainText is basically your original message or data that is hidden from view through of cryptography
or encryption algorithm.
Ciphertext is basically your output of encryption, which is not readable, like in previous thing I
created.
DB That's the ciphertext key is a piece of data or collected pair of data.
Well input with plain text.
Encryption of ciphertext is basically just encrypting and decrypting the data.
If you put in that part, you will get or you will understand the plaintext for that purposes.
And so it is a random piece of data which is added to the hashing function.
So I will tell you what is the hash here?
Hash is nothing, but you have to create some map of arbitrary size of data or bytes in that data,
in that main data to create some mathematical functions or create some mathematical attributes for that
purposes.
So there are different encryption algorithms to pull these RSA inside of encryption standards to Phish
Blowfish idea MD for you Mac Sha 256 is most like hashing functions of 256 bits bitcoin is using SHA
256 is very higher level algorithms also they are using.
So these are the purposes of a and asymmetric encryption.
As I told you, public private key was created and they are shared to this.
So mostly the cryptocurrencies are using all symmetric, but for the simpler purposes I'm deploying
the simple NIR, which is basically no.
Well semantically.
So now.
Let us create two or three things here which are very useful and let us see how we can set up our project.
So for the project setup, it's very easy.
You can you have to go to your ID.
And choose your own.
You can choose anything.
I'm not forcing anyone to stick to only one ID.
There is a reason for that because that's not really everyone's part.
Then I'm going with In Danger Area.
If you want to proceed with this, you may proceed with this.
So open your own eyes.
It will take some time to open.
But meanwhile, let me refresh your things.
plainText is basically just original message or data which is hidden due to from cryptographic encryption
algorithms then.
There is one.
Another thing is ciphertext, which is input and output of encryption.
And GHI is a piece of data and salt is another piece of data which is added to the hashing function.
And I will tell you what is the hashing later because it will not understand directly using this part.
We have to check for different purposes there.
So you need to create a new project in your own ID.
So what I'm going to do is.
I'm going to create my new project in my ID, so let me open my ID sometimes take two 3 minutes to to
my system configuration.
Meanwhile, let us see what is Java class.
And so everything in Java is associated with classes and objects along with attributes and thoughts.
Considering the real life example, car is an object which has some attributes such as weight, colours,
etc. etc. but
God is also having a constructor or blueprint of creating objects in class.
All does some user defined attributes to pass values or inputs.
Objects are used to create classes which are already created and invoke.
So that's it about how we are going to this and these some information about Java classes.
So class is a blueprint for object, as I told you already.
And class is something to store different functions methods in one block of code and this is the syntax
for reclaiming the classes.
So in the next part and how we can deploy it and how we can run our code in the next part.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.