So in previous tutorial I told you how I created this part.
And now what I'm going to tell you, I'm going to create here this part I already created.
And in this JSP, JSP is just the front end.
So let us see how we can create this front end.
So let me mention some HTML here because it's page.
So as you can see, ID will automatically move to that part.
Then let me create one style here.
So I will copy this part and I will tell you what is the significance of this.
Because I'm mentioning this directly.
I'm not going with direct path here, which is to mention.
I'm mentioning stylesheet here.
Okay.
Now.
So this is my stylesheet.
If you want to add title here, let me add title bar.
Caitlyn Jenner, basically.
Show me.
Right.
Let's move to add.
So these are the colored thing I'm adding and this is just a stylesheet.
The main part starts after this.
So let us see what is the body I'm going to use here?
So let me add a body tag here, because all the things are inside only body part, not your anything
part.
So I'm just adding this part.
Then I need one form.
Then I needed a form to create a one post action to to field, then some carry forward field.
Everything I'm going to add here form.
So let me add some
clues, but let me add some more attributes here.
Form is basically contain contents action.
Male client.
Limited.
Post this post.
So ignore this mail line because it's showing me the typo error.
Then let me add some form actions here and I will tell you what is the form actions these teams here.
So I already created this part.
So I will tell you what is the significance of these actions.
So this is the same thing.
Or we can say styling part.
I will tell you there are some arrows also showing my client these things.
So I will tell you what is this thing?
So this email client and what I'm doing here is here is started speaking.
So I'm accessing the request dot attribute message part first so as my HP to bring the message here
or we can say putting the message here.
Now table is started inside the form tag first is email to put the email whom I want to send that email
part email to part then subject holding part that takes subject and placeholder.
So then I'm adding some text area to comma six for email body, then directed with some input type type
submit.
And I mentioned here value.
So I will tell you what I'm going to do here.
So these are the all things of GSP.
As you can see, this tag is again GSP.
Time for printing message and creating some value of submit.
This part of it just basically I'm going to create one class inside this.
So these are the old things and I will tell you we are going to invoke in GSP class also and how I'm
accessing this part, I will tell you later.
But these are the all things I use here.
So this is it for the GSP part, and I'm accessing the button and I'm setting its value.
Value is basically just what method I'm going to use here.
It's the this mail client that OPI slash which is the use here operation go.
So I will tell you what is the significance of this in the later part.
But first let us see what is the basically functionally going inside created what what is the solid
part here.
So if you know front end and back end of the way pages.
So I'm creating your dynamic page.
It's not static, it's not showing only the information I had typed there.
I'm going to create some responsive thing here, like clicking on that go button.
It will send the mail and everything I'm going to use here.
So this is not only the static thing, I'm going to create some dynamic thing for that purpose.
I need to back it back in this just basic logic as estimated as having not exactly programming language,
these are some frontend languages or we can say scripting language or for the visualization part, these
are not exactly like they can not add some.
There are not mathematical symbols in that also.
So for that API part or for that purpose, I need a new language.
So here I'm using Java.
So what is the Java servlet java.
So it is technology to create web application.
So let's use an API which provides the interfaces and classes to connect the HTML and some backend service
or backend database, anything you can do.
So so it is an access both interface and classes.
So it is an interface must be implemented by creating any solid.
So you have to create the one servlet and according to that you need to create interface.
But servlet is also access class to having some capabilities of servers which responds for incoming
request.
So if you know how the servlet working or how the Internet's working, it's basically on request in
response.
When the client gives the response and it will give the response and everything requests.
So these are how the network works.
So, so links are important part in this.
Not only this object, there are different things also known like some Java scripting things, so and
so Python also is used for that purpose.
So these are the different things we can use.
So servlet is an web component that deploy on server to create and dynamic web page.
So here is the solid part actually how creates this is the client and this is the server part and for
this purpose it will request the server responsive generated and the runtime and connection to the client.
So how this works, actually it's depend on your server side.
So my server so program deploys on the server and client will receive only the GSP pages or in this
case.
So I'm deploying on the local server.
But if you want to deploy an online server, you can use anything, a cloud or anything you can use.
Then here request dispatcher in servlet.
So what is the request?
DISPATCHER Request.
DISPATCHER The interface provides a facility of dispatching any requests.
So basically if you want to check any link directly from the Java like you could submit button and do
you want to like you want to find some another page, you want to go to another page for that purpose.
We are using request dispatcher method here.
So we are using here two methods forward method include method.
So as I told you and that request method in.
Great attribute it just basically for that forward part also is my java is solid as you can see.
That's my main dependency.
So this is the forward method and forward is for forwarding that good and including that including the
same port.
Then let me tell you.
So that important part is HTML, CSS as frontend Java program as backend and web XML for the control
flow.
But here I'm using XML and web XML.
There are two different things here.
Com is for properties and web for the control flow for whole web.
So let me move to the ID now and let me create one client, which is basically male client.
So as you can see here, I am mentioning my client as male client.
Male client.
So let me complete this part.
Then what I'm going to do, go to this Java.
I'm going to create here one package.
So why I'm developing another packages because it's very important for us concepts.
You can create different packages and you can use that later.
So let me create one package here.
I'm mentioning as so in this mail package, I'm going to create one Java class name as male friend.
So this is it.
And it's not just what I'm going to do is I just want to invoke that or I just want to import that.
So far, the importing is very simple.
Just go to this.
Let me show you how I'm doing all this.
Okay.
So I am importing this.
Let me capitalize this.
Because everywhere I capitalized mean.
Let me.
Refactor here and rename here as.
Mean, see?
So what we're going to see now.
Okay.
I create another thing here.
Get me delete this.
And the Queen would disappear because I changed the name.
Naming is very important here.
I just want to create male seat not male because it's client notes.
Misspelled that.
How can I make sure it is done?
Let me mention your mail.
Still not the mail sealed.
And later I am going to create that open method.
I will tell you what is the thing.
So this is it.
I'm going to do so before proceeding with this.
Let me add some XML file here, which is basically very useful dependency.
I'm going to add here.
So let me add one dependency.
Which is basically Java meal.
Dependency.
1417 version.
So let me tell you how I am going to do is go to any dependency in that part.
I'm going to this part.
Let me paste this.
So this is the main dependency.
You can check from the Internet and just hit this and it will resolving dependencies, it will dissolve
it automatically.
Then I'm going to add another dependency which is basically Java X GBE, which is basically for the
dependency purposes.
Let me add this and let me sing this again so it will sync the dependencies automatically.
So Java X mail is for the mail purpose for creating any mail application.
So instead of downloading library or we can see Java Jar files, I can deploy this and this is the latest
version.
You can directly download this.
So this is for mail.
And let me just.
These buildings are just.
And let us create some mail in part here.
So in the mail client, what I'm going to do is.
Let me extend it to the.
Be solely part.
It needs to be solved.
So as you can see, just I added this and it will automatically let me do one thing, some good stuff.
So no worries about importing labels.
Oh again, I'm adding some annotations here.
So adding annotations is very useful while developing this.
In all Java a solid lot.
Annotations, dot stuff.
And what I'm going to add this here is web solid, not some simple web solid.
In this episode solid.
What I'm going to mention is here is this male.
See.
Even so, it will be helpful for me to.
Mention that this is a male client with Soviet.
So I'm going to create your one serial version, which is very crucial for creating any mailing part.
So private.
Again static.
I will tell you why it is static.
Final.
Or it should be long because I'm treating her seriously, but I genuinely.
She doesn't use it anymore.
And.
So I created this part.
Then create.
Let me create one public static.
Final.
And here is the part of Whoopi.
Go.
Is equal to.
I'm mentioning at the same.
So if you go to this park now, you can check your operation is now successful.
So let me go to the client again.
Then let me create one constructor here.
Let me mention.
He means it again.
This is my constructor, and I'm not imagining I'm adding the super here.
Super duper.
Create auto generated constructor.
This is just auto generated.
You can use old insert also you to create anything here.
You can see constructor.
So constructor already exists.
So you can create auto generated constructor or you can choose your constructor just to pass your everything
here, like HTTP and everything.
So hope you understand this part.
In further part, I'm going to create application with some dubious methods and everything.
Hope you understand this part.
And in further part I will tell you the JSP basics and SMTP V6 also, which is basically simple email
transport protocol.