So here is our MySQL command line client and the required notepad file.
So let's write the password first.
I will be writing my password of my SQL.
So I have validated the password.
Then the notepad file says that execute these queries one by one in your MySQL console.
The first query creates the database with name as AMS.
So I have already created the database and inserted the values so that not much of the time should be
taken in this value in this video.
So I will just do just to show you, I will create another database with the name as a amms one because
I have already created the database with the name Amms.
So let's copy this from notepad here and here.
Control Tesla.
I'll be editing it as a CMS one because same database can't be created twice.
So I will be creating create database ams one hidden.
So this is showing.
Okay, one refactored.
Now we have to use the database.
So using ams control plus c.
We have to edit AMS one.
Database chains.
Now we have to create tables.
So first table is a cancellation table which will hold all the cancellation record of the table.
So it's controlled.
Let's see.
So it says create table name.
Table name will be cancellation.
First column will be P and R number.
Second will be cancellation.
Number third is cancellation date and fourth is flight code for which flight ticket has been cancelled.
So let's hit enter set showing query.
Okay.
Zero rules affected.
Now let's create.
Another table here it is showing create table flight.
So let's copy that query to create table flight.
And pasting it here.
So this query will create a table flight.
With columns like F Code F name, flight code, flight name and its source.
Or you can say.
Starting station or location and destination.
That will be the final location where the flight will land.
So let's get into that.
Showing that database has a table has been created.
Query is zero rows affected.
Now let's create another table from our notepad file.
Another table is.
We have created the flight table now.
First database.
Use database.
Create the table.
We have created the table cancellation.
Created the table file.
And now we will create the table login for the login of the admin.
So copy this query.
Wasting it here.
So this query will create a table named as log in with the first column as username type of a string
and the size of 22nd as password type of work, which will work similarly like a strings in programming
languages and.
Size is 20.
Then let's attend into.
So it is showing that table has been created and with zero rules.
Then we have to create a table with a name as passenger.
So let's copy the passenger table query from here.
Copy this query.
So we have pasted the query.
Let's see.
Creating the table name as passenger.
Attribute has been our number.
Then there is an address.
Then there is the nationality of the passenger passenger name, passenger gender, passenger phone number,
passport number, and then the flight code for which the passenger will be travelling.
That's the table passenger.
Let's hit enter.
So table passenger has been created successfully.
Remember that I have already created and inserted the value.
So I will be just showing after the creation of this table so that you can create on your own.
Now let's create the table.
Next table is paytm payment table.
So let's copy this.
Based it.
So this query is showing like create table namespace.
Attribute Size.
Piano Number.
Phone number.
Check number.
Card number.
Amount paid date of the payment.
So these are the columns of the attributes.
Let's press enter.
So it is showing that the table has been created named as payment.
Now we have to create a table of reservation type.
So let's copy that as well from the notepad file.
And pasted her.
So the square will create a table named as a reservation with attributes.
Panel number Ticket ID Flight Code Journey, Date Journey, Time Source and destination.
Now let's get into so the reservation table has been created.
Now, the last table is a sector table which will use for the flights control plus.
Based here.
So all the tables has been created now, but I have already created the database with the original name
that is AMS.
But this is the virtual database which I have created to for you to understand how the tables will be
created.
So let me show you that database, which I have created.
So I will be changing the database from here to use AMS because I have already created that.
So it shows the database change.
Now I will show you the tables in this database show.
Tables.
So tables in EMS are the same, which I have just created for the virtuality.
Cancellation Flight Login Passenger Payment, Payment Reservation and sector.
Now let me show you the details, which I have added in my database, which I have created.
Values I have inserted.
So for that I will be writing query likes select as strict from.
For stimulus cancellation.
Cancellation.
So this is the cancellation record.
There is one record because I have checked for once by running my project as well.
So for that, the one record has been added.
We will be showing by cancelling more tickets than the record will be reflecting in this database as
well.
Second one, let's check for the flight.
Selector strip from flight.
Flight table.
So here it is.
So I have added these file flights.
There are five flights and source and destination of all.
Let's check for the log in.
Uh, log in.
What is there in the log in table?
So in long table there is only one username and password that is admin and password as one, two, three,
four which using which we will be logging in to our desktop based application.
The other table is passenger payment, reservation and sector.
So let's look at the passenger table.
Sarcastic gastric from passenger.
So here's the passenger table.
Let me.
So that you can see clearly.
Here is the passenger table two passenger I waited for to check that the project is working efficiently
or not.
After that passenger there is will be a payment table as well.
Yeah, payment, reservation and sector.
Let's check the payment table.
Payment table.
So there is a one payment added also.
And after payment, there will be a reservation table.
The reservation table check what's there in the reservation.
So I have added five reservations already in my table, which will be used to when we will be going
to run this project at the last video.
For the complete run.
The last will be sector table, which will be used for the flights.
So let's have a look on that sector.
So sector table contains this information.
Now I will be moving on to our ID.
So let's have a look how the database is.
This database is connecting with our project, which is a common class of.
Our first forward, this project that is an airline management system.
So let's have a look on that.
So here is our ID.
That is a NetBeans ID.
I am using 12.6 thousand of this ID for that I have using JDK 17, which is compatible with it.
There is an address to Exemplar File which we'll be using for the format tables in this project and
the MySQL Connector, which will help us to load the drivers, which will help us to connect with our
database so that we can manage the trip and update information in our database.
So there is a so first package airline inside which we have our classes and I can insert which we have
our images.
So let's have a look at the first file.
So it is defined inside the package airline.
We have imported the Java aspect package which will help us to use necessary methods and drivers to
connect with our database.
We have defined the class cone instance variable of type connection and stance, a level of type statement
inside the non parameter as constructor of the class.
We have defined the cache block and inside the trie cache block.
Inside the trip log we have class stored for name on my SQL driver.
This will help us to load the drivers, which will be connecting our program with the database.
So here the connection.
Variable in is initialized as driver manager don't get connection.
First argument is the location of a database, so that is GBK, MySQL and AMS.
And the second is the root, which is the username.
And the third argument is the password.
So my password is my square.
My square.
One, two, three.
Generally the default password and the username will be same as wrote root in a small case letter.
So if you don't have changed your MySQL command line password so that will be same as are odd.
So you will have to change that here to connect with your database.
Now statement variable we have initialize c create a statement using the connection instance and created
the statement instance which will be creating the statement and executing query further in our programs
and classes inside the cache block.
We have handled the exception by printing it out if any exception occurs.