In previous things, what we created, we created one gameplay class with exchangeable panel and which
is going to use some key listener and action action listener.
So we will create that part.
But and we are assuming we are, we will create one map functions later.
So now this is done.
But within this game gameplay there is should be key listener also.
So key listener is basically the keyboard listener you can say.
And let me mention this only directly.
So this will be used for direct reference of add key listener, then set focus focus level for
focusing the boolean part and which is always true.
If we want to focus our lives for like that should be fixed.
These are not keys changing part.
So let me mention this then said focus traveller wanting travel keys travel please for traveling the
teams and enable not these.
I need to mention this enabled.
And let me mention as false, because at the start of game, I don't want to create that part.
And in this let me mention timer is equal to.
New.
Would.
Billy.
On Mondays.
So this will incorporate Andy and.
Ingenious download.
Not.
Start.
So.
And let me mention this is not in this timer.
This is this should be in x dot swing dot timer part.
Always.
So now you can check.
It's not.
Remember, in Java, there are two things kinds of timer timing.
One is for util purpose, which is console purpose.
Another is for you purpose, which is Java.
So before that, I'm using I'm using Java Util because Java directly took that part, but now I'm using
this.
So this will remove all the parts.
Now I need to create one paint method to create any paint things here.
So let me mention one method.
Public void paint with one parameter graphics.
Which is AWG method graphics.
G.
And inside this let me create method part and I forgot to close the parenthesis.
So now let us mention these things.
So background.
Let me create first background.
G dot set color.
I'm going to set color here.
Now, you can remember always color, but I'm using your black directly.
Color or black.
So that's a blue thing.
And you can mention like this also black.
For the giving the color.
Then G thought I need to create, feel, reflect and react things so I am going to feel which is basically
rectangular thing.
One comma.
Six nine.
Two.
Come on, let me mention height for you.
Nine.
Two.
So this is the thing which is blackout thing.
Which is.
I'm going to create then.
Drawing.
Matt.
Matt also thinks I'm going to create a map draw, draw, I'm going to create.
And that's a function with another thing.
So we will create that later.
But.
Which is basically graphics 2D, which is a W thing, graphics 2D with G.
And that's it.
We will create my little pod.
So that map things, my paintings get map and set map things we are going to create later then borders.
Let us mention border dot set color.
And for the border.
Or let us.
Let me mention colored art.
Yellow.
So there are default things you can use or you can use hexadecimal codes for your purpose also.
That's all what I'm using here.
My reaction is again simple zero zero comma 3592.
So these are the border things I'm going to do and.
Let me copy this part again and again.
And let me mention what I'm going to do is I'm just going to change some parts for lower and higher
parts.
So let me say.
So this will be the side part.
692 while deploying this you will understand what these these things I'm going to mention zero then
three and five.
And so this is the purpose part.
But these things are acting as the lower borders of my circle, which is avoiding to get that ball out
of that function.
Now.
Let me mention scores for scoring purposes here.
G dot set color again.
Let me mention here.
Wait.
Let us check whether that is right or not.
So you can check your like there are different colors also.
So let me mention here white as it is.
Then let me mention dot set font because font is very important here.
Font in this point I'm mentioning serif, which is very common for and it's system enabled.
So no need to.
Work with this font.
Dot bold.
And let me mention this.
This 25.
And let me mention one thing here.
I created these things, but I forgot to create a new font method.
So.
Okay.
So this will now act as a fun thing.
And I need to mention one thing.
I forgot one thing, drawstring, which is just not deploying anything.
So.
Instead of graphics 2d animation.
Drawstrings directly at.
With two, 3 to 4 things.
So these things.
Interior part plus course I'm going to mention your score and let me mention for you.
Mine become a third of their assets.
So this will act as a store scores.
Now let us create two or three things here.
One is paddle and another is ball.
Because I created models and everything, but I haven't created any paddle or ball things.
So we will create that.
For paddle paddle design.
I'm going to great now.
Paddle is basically that basic or.
Stage four jumping the ball purpose so that sit.
CALLER And for this, I'm going to set colorize.
Color dot green so you can check your different things.
So.
GREENE I'm going to mention.
GREENE.
And God.
Again.
Rick Stengel, I need to mention now, what is these things player x which is default things, which
is our player that paddle I'm going to move so that's a player and now the ball design and need to mention.
So now again I'm going to mention.
Your local only football and get dot.
Now that's a rectangle.
Now, I need to mention one thing here.
So I mention one thing, then position.
I need to mention ball position.
X comma.
Ball position.
Position.
Why?
Omar 20 over 20.
So that's a height and width, height and width of these things.
And then we will create two or three things later, which is when you win a game, the total breaks
and the basic logic behind this, we will see in our next part.
Hope you understand.
Thank you for this.