In previous part, I mentioned the functional requirements of our block block system, connect global
block system, and I told you how we are going to perform each and every here with functional requirements,
application requirements.
So in this part, I'm going to mention what I'm going to perform here, which is basically servlet,
JSP, part GBC connection each and every here.
So stay connected with this and let us see what is our.
So Java solid.
So if you know what is the back end part of web frontend is basically what you are looking here, which
is HTML and CSS.
But consider there is one form in your web page and you are writing that form if you want, submit it.
You got that your data is stored now.
So what is the data is stored.
So it will go to the database and it is entered in that database.
Now, the thing is, you are writing in the form of HTML.
So how your name is fetched and how it's stored in the database, because database is always a skill
file.
Or you can check for the CSV file generator, which is basically command separated files.
So these are more different contents as can consider as a structure.
Each and everything is very different.
Like a skill are some skill statements like create table adding insert.
So these are very simple, but you are writing in HTML is very complicated.
So each entry is in consider as a table or you can form as a parameters.
And our Java could handle that, fetch that parameter and put it in that database.
So it's basically like request and response system in Java in the servlet part.
So.
So that is the technology which is used to create web application.
Again.
So it is an API that provides interface and class.
So what is the thing is the interface and class.
If you know the Java basics classes are structures of objects and interfaces.
You can see instance of classes.
So these are more different concepts, but so it's performance interfaces and classes.
So that's the power of solid.
So let is an interface that must be implemented for creating a solid.
Or you can say there is a solid part which can perform the servlet actions each and every time.
But also servlet is a class also as is performed as a class with some default libraries that are the
capabilities to serve off servers as a name.
So servlet, it's deployed on the server part only.
Extends the capabilities of the servers and responds to the AI, or we can say responds to the incoming
requests.
So what is the request and response?
I will tell you why you are searching on google.com for cars.
When you are searching cars on the google dot com, you request the server.
Show me the information about cars.
Cars.
Basically cars like motor vehicles.
So you are asking for the request.
So now server should respond with that particular page or consider there is or four car list you will
want to show you.
So server fails that for current list and it will respond to your server.
So this is very complex thing as a world wide web is extended more.
It's become very complicated.
Very complicated.
But request and response is very helpful for deploying your web application because web application
performs some dedicated actions like my in my case it is performed the block system.
But for the other application, consider as a library management, they are some different actions.
So for particularly that we need to write code to perform such actions.
So it can respond to any requests.
So while we are proceeding with Java Solid, there are many other options.
You can you see C++ per languages also, but you can use JavaScript which is very popular while writing
such cases.
So, so it is a web component that deployed on the server and create dynamic pages.
So one advantage of Java solid what we can say it's deployed on the server but no need to deploy on
the client but to extend your abilities with some web applications.
So this is it about how we are performing the Java solid.
So let's see, really presentation of Java servlet.
This is my client.
I'm sending request server will generate one response at a runtime and it will be respond to the client
that response.
So it can be some copy of document, it can be a data, it can image anything you can provide.
But we can see server can provide.
So there are different things, requests dispatched in.
So but before that, I just want to mention that while deploying on the sub servlet what is the beautiful
thing is it will be handled to the trade part, trading part.
So consider there are 100 clients you just searching in your blog.
Consider my blog system only simultaneously.
100 client using this my system.
So sometimes due to the my server is not very strong.
I'm using some low level server or you can say low cost server for the deployment of my application
purpose too, because I don't want to waste that much money on that part.
Consider as an owner of this blog system, I just implemented the server port on the lower end.
If I use some other technologies I need to mention multi trading part.
You because it will not handle.
Definitely I need to mention multithreading.
Otherwise it will handle some clients with the different processes.
And as my server is very low end server, it will it cannot handle that many requests.
So instead of that, I can use Java servlet which will have ability to create multi threads.
What is a multi trading?
Trading is a process process divided into the different different small processes is known as a trades,
and multi trading is like handling many processes at a time so it can divide joining the client as one
process.
It can be divided.
So several trades and it can be used as my application to run an application.
But beautiful thing is I can handle more request using multi trading in Java so let other than any thing
or any other platform.
So request dispatcher is basically that interfaces or we can say interfaces of java servlet dispatch
the request to another resource from another resource, basically just proceeding from one page to other
page.
It may be HTP, HTML, servlet, JSP, you can use anything here.
So for what it is just basically forwarding and including just basically the including the same file
inside your team or you can say inside the same page you can see.
So this is the forward, forward method, as I told you, and you can use this.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to use some default things here, like some CSS file.
All State and state ceases to declare on my server part.
Then I'm going to use some libraries part also here because.
To deploy such cases.
I need to.
Mention it from.
What we can say, and I don't want to create it from scratch.
So I'm going to use some default CSS part here.
So let me add such files.
If you're seeing my this left side, you can see I'm currently adding this and what I'm going to do.
Let me close this because it will deploy it again and again as a GP, but it will deploy it again and
again.
Let me add one further HTML also here.
I will tell you what is the full HTML value?
It will do the beautiful super part here, which is basically nothing but is just padding part we can
see in our file.
So let me add such files then images and libraries.
I'm going to add some.
So you can hit enter directly these images.
These images are nothing but some web images only.
As you can see, there are some web images which I lose here as my background part some.
On what we can see Linkin Park each and thing.
Then some Beijing part with pause and each and everything I'm going to use here.
So that's how I'm going to do here.
Once this is done.
You can check these files.
So sometimes there may be error in.
These cases.
Yeah.
So let me check.
What is the area?
Okay.
So.
So there is no deadline.
Okay, so this is my just everything here I mentioned is my thesis.
So this is the digital testament.
Let me delete this part because I will mention you what I'm going to do here.
So let me add in the protesting saying this is not just.
Tinker.
I'm going to add here.
So let me show you.
There is too much of padding here I used while writing this, so nothing.
But this is W3 awkward web or HTML page because I'm using here Ajax.
I will tell you what is the AJAX is basically a synchronous thing I'm going to use here.
Then some keywords, description and title as a test I will change it to.
Let me follow this thing at least.
So I will tell you what is these things?
I just added script here and all the things your style dot cases.
So let me first deploy this part.
Clean and build.
Will this successful conflict multiply this on this mine server part?
So now my thing is let me show you how this is looking.
So if you are adding my part, only you can check.
I created each and everything post to register each and everything log in form.
So these are the some default things I used your you can use your your thing and I mentioned some things
your tutorials each and everything you can check here and I'm using this part but let me.
Jake for this purpose.
So this is all about who I am mentioning everything here.
So in further part, what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention some important things here.
So.
It is that football team.
So you can check this out.
Also loaded.
So this is it.
Who I'm going to mention.
But before this, let me tell you.
What I'm going to do here.
Let me switch to the PPD part.
So this request or dispatcher, as I told you.
What is the thing here?
Request.
DISPATCHER.
You can check here as.
What is the basic thing I'm going to mention here?
As requested.
Dispatch reason, I think.
But you can check here as.
This is the thing what I'm going to mention here or.
Nyquist.
That DOT dispatcher is very helpful thing while developing this forward is for the forwarding method
and the thing I'm mentioning here is just for putting that part while writing this.
So.
Let me go to this part again.
So these is my server.
I'm using this connect globe and privacy trumps.
I added just our address.
Nothing, but I just added images here.
You can use your more responsive things here also and you can check this.
So this is nothing.
But I just added images.
Just forgot about this because I'm adding some default text here.
I just don't want to put much more efforts on this so you can use your log in from you can check your
recent discoveries, your latest news you can check here.
So that's it.
I'm going to mention this is just in this part and I just for the listing purposes, I just added this
can change it to the later part also here.
So in further part, I'm going to tell you how I'm going to put this each and everything.
So that's it about this, the deployment of index dot HTML part.
So for that part, let us see how I'm going to mention and this is the full statement as I told you
so it is nothing, but I just created and didn't lose this.
Okay, so this is the output and you can check my output is not random also.
So that's it about how I'm going to deploy this.