So here I have my project by the name Minesweeper Gaming Java.
Here this game consists of two classes board and a minesweeper and a saucy package.
This one.
And now we have 30 images underwater as RC slash resources directory this.
So these images we will be using in our project or the program.
So what we have to do first we have to define.
Okay.
So here first we have to define the constant used in our game.
So let's start with that.
We will write private final and.
Give the name as the no images and.
Settle down.
13.
We know the constraints.
We will take it as in the case in our interest here.
And another one constraint which we need is a private.
Finally.
And that will be the cell size set to the 15.
I don't know.
There are 13 images used in the scheme.
A cell can be surrounded by a maximum of eight miles.
So we need numbers 1 to 8.
We need images for an empty cell, a mind, a colored cell, a model cell.
And finally, finally, for a lonely cell, the size of each of the images is 1515.
So for that, we need another constants.
And we will write primate final end.
And write it code for sale here and initialize it to the ten here.
We need another one which we will name as a private final end mark for sale and third to the ten.
Here's another one which we need private final int and that will be the empty shell here.
And set this 2 to 0.
That's well done.
No, we need a minefield is in order.
Okay.
So minefield is an array of numbers.
For example, zero donates an empty cell.
Number ten is used for a cell cover as well as for a mark.
Using constants improves readability of the code.
So we need another things here.
We will try it here.
I will write private final and give it the name mindset and set it to the line.
Know what we need.
The mindset represents a cell that contains a mine, so we have to write private, final int and write
it as a code mine cell which really equal to the mine cell.
And it added to the cover for sell.
Here.
Another one constant variable which we need is the private final end.
It will be me as the modeled mine cell and it will be equal to the gold mine cell added to the mark
for cell.
Here.
So it's done.
Now what we have to do.
Okay.
So now the code mindset is used for a field that is code and contains a mine, the mog the mine cell.
This one is a coal mine cell that was marked by the user.
So now we need to determine whether to draw mine a mine over a mark or a wrongly mark.
So for that, we have to define the variables.
So here we will write, try with final in, and here we need to mine.
Okay.
So we will name it as the draw mine here and set it to the nine here.
Another one which we need is a private final and we need it.
Draw over here.
Set it to the ten.
Another one which would need to be made final in the 12 millimetres draw mark and set it to the levels
last one between we in the private final and name it and the wrong marker and it will set with that.
Okay.
So we have these constraints which will determine whether to draw mine a mine colour and a mark and
only mob cell.
Now which next thing which we need.
Okay.
So we have the minefield in our game which has the 40 hidden mines.
For that, we need another variable and another variable for the 16 rules and the 16 columns and the
field.
So there are 226 cells together in a minefield.
So for that, we need another retrievals and retrieval, right?
Primate.
And it will be the final in animate and stuff.
And mine's here and set it to 40.
For the hidden minds here we will write private.
I noted in Mehmet also Andrew Shearer set it to 16 last one which we need is a private final end and
calls here and set it to the.
Do you?
So here.
What do we have or do we have?
We have the minefield in our game has 40 hidden mines.
So there are 16 rows and 16 columns in the field.
So there are 226 holes together in the minefield.
No.
Next thing which we need is board width and height.
So let's take before that.
What we need, we need.
Okay.
So firstly for the board width and the board height.
So here we will right
here, even right.
Private, and it will be the final end limit as the board.
Right here, we really call to the end calls multiplied by cell size.
And it will be plus one.
Next thing, we truly need private finance in need and support right here, which is equal to the end.
ROSE And it will be multiplied by cell size.
Okay.
It will be up with the one.
I'm done.
Now we need an area of the field.
The field is an area of numbers.
So what we will write.
We will write private and only by the name field.
The field is an area of numbers.
Each cell in the field has a specific number.
For instance, a mine cell has number nine.
A cell number two means it is a two, two minus.
The numbers are added.
For example, a cover mine has a number 19 nine for the mine and ten for the cell cover and so on.
So what we need, we need another thing which will be, as the private boolean in this endgame variable,
determines whether we are in the game or the game is over, next thing which we need.
Okay.
So the next thing which we need is the private and numerate as the mines left here.
So the mine's left variable, the number of mines to be marked left.
So this is done and now we need an array of images to store the images so we will take image.
I am here.
I'm done.
So firstly we have to import image.
Oh, this is John.
Now what we have to do, we will need private.
Okay, we are done.
Now the next another thing which we have to do, we have to load our images into the image.
The images are named here 0.1 not being G now the last will be the 12 being.
These are in numbers.
So we have to store and load our images into the image area.