So here we will create our project by the name Rock, Paper, Scissors.
So here I have my project by the Rock Paper Scissors, in which I have created a package with the name
images in which we have a paper rock and a scissor I can image in the form of being in the format.
PNG and another package.
I have a rock paper, scissors under which I have created this a frame form by the name game frame here.
So here we have a frame.
Now, simply, we take a panel, drag here and enlarge this panel here.
And now go to the properties here.
Please.
We need to set a border of darkness for.
Okay.
We give it a color also.
You take some?
That's all right, then.
Close.
Here it is.
This is done.
And now what we need?
We need a label here.
This one.
For the mean flirting.
It will be us versus the computer.
So I will take all label and simply control plus.
And.
Okay.
Delete the spanner.
We don't need this control closed here.
We have another label here.
Simply adjust these levels.
So then.
So here.
Done.
We have created our labels and simply.
Expect after.
Firstly, take another panel here.
Sorry.
We need all nipples, not panel.
So here we will set a label.
Need another label here?
Here.
Take this label.
I need a.
The league would have to set first shift this.
Shiftless.
Not just here.
But here.
Okay.
So for this now added text and simply put the hyphen here and here simply added text on.
Four zero.
MILLER zero one.
We have to do this like these three labels and go to the properties and enlarge the font size, put
it to 24 to bold and so set close down.
Firstly.
Near the horizontal alignment to the sun center.
Close.
Here on me we have to enlarge for 2448.
Okay, then.
36 tone notes.
Here.
Take another Naples.
Good care.
And another level is here.
Here we will write.
You are this computer.
Computer, simply select both this level.
Change the font size here.
Make it bold.
The.
King.
Those.
Horizontal alignment center close.
Large this.
Read this text here.
Okay.
Now we need another three levels where we put out rock, paper, scissors, images.
So here, take this label.
So you okay?
We need to just adjust all these.
Here.
The rules that all these two.
You're done.
No need to set these labels here.
Simply put, the control policy.
Put this label here.
Control plenty and put this label here.
Simply, I detect clear text clear and text clear.
So here we have.
All five labels for the image part.
So now we have to give the variable names also.
So.
Firstly like this Julie will change.
Variable name.
No score.
We have to write you.
You wince and the next level change with name and portrait computer once.
The grandparents now we need.
Okay.
So.
This labour change is the third one.
Change really will mean.
To your score.
This one for change variable name to computer score.
So this one is done.
No.
We have to change the variable of this tree so we will set it to.
First one is for Chile and we need rock purposes.
Okay.
So the first one is rock.
Julie will nine will be sent to the Liverpool nine Rock.
The
last one will be the scissor.
Here we have a little variable names and what you like.
So simply go here and run this file.
Okay.
Now, let's say maybe.
Yeah.
Something wrong?
Okay.
So this part is done and now we simply see our.
Yeah.
So it's running and of course it's going good and we have our way out here.
So now we have to create borders for these square blocks where we have set the images.
So let's see that part.