My project by the name simple browser.
Here the folder is RC Domain and the junk.
Under this we will create a new package by the name sample browser and then click fresh.
In this package, we will create our class by the name, browser, browser or Java.
So here I get my class.
Firstly, we will extend in the class application from which we will get our properties on the Java
effects.
So here and we have to import this also imposed on Java.
Now firstly, what we will do, we will override the method which really we don't like before it starts
the primary.
Speech and prose exception
key although.
All right.
Unimplemented, immature.
I got this one already generated.
Now we will write our code.
First we will do the tapping and continue tapping here this one
afterwards we will do the tap start said taps closing policy.
You know, maybe I have.
Certainly.
Yeah.
Now what?
We will give the values.
We will do the tapping or tap closing policy.
Not all taps.
No.
Will make another class.
This is a one.
Firstly, make one thing.
Also we include a new class as well.
And start.
What to do?
Yeah, the main class.
Our main class?
After this.
Key.
No.
Hood Public.
Yeah, right.
So the public yeah.
So extending it mean trim and she's smart simple one now in the browser dot main and here this one.
Okay so.
Here?
Yes.
We have to drill now or we will do we will create a new class and new single page and then finish.
Now in this class.
Firstly, we will create our variables.
No, see, we will try the private view.
You know, another one is the private Indian.
Indian.
And afterwards we will clean the private
text.
Feel as though you are in text field, which we will need.
And what are the rules?
We will see that.
So we have to import this also.
Here, I will import all these things.
Now done.
Now, afterwards, we will do one thing.
Also, we will make the constructor also.
The single page.
And under this we will make a method initial page and we will keep it blank and give its body afterwards.
Right.
So what we will do in this matter, we will give the all functionality of our initial page.
What we will do?
What will it open?
So now from here onwards, fill.
Right.
Those few equal to Newman view.
The Sun and the.
In just a second here.
The small one.
Sorry.
Not right.
Easily some.
Yeah, this one.
No.
Look back in June and then write down you.
This one not get attention right now.
Of course, we need one more thing that is private.
The box.
This one name returns to the box.
So here we will do one thing.
Also out of the box.
Sorry.
This Reebok sequel to new Reeboks.
This one.
And afterwards we will take the edge box also.
These are the horizontal and vertical boxes.
In some problems this actually controls.
Ball.
Yeah.
Control Smoke.
Sequel to New Box.
The soon afterwards, we will do we will call our text field.
This one is called the new.
Fixed field.
Hmm.
Okay.
Starting this one, your text field.
And then afterwards, we will give us the we will give to you first the load you are in.
And then we will take the example of the two http colon backslash one dot com
colon more happened.
Okay.
We will create this matter after all.
And now you are all text filled or sent text.
This one.
And give them a clue here.
Also htp or non backslash?
Not con, no.
Here we will write our progress bar.
We will create the progress.
This one we need this one to name it as the bar, the p, the equal to new progress over here.
And what we will do, the pr dot we will give it the right property.
So pre this one pre revert property and we will bind this one bind with the vertical locks as well.
So we start here also in the root property.
So this one, the only property, the property and afterwards when the user interacts, the link changes.
So we have to update the text field with the new link also.
Now we will create our new functions.
So here what we will do and the user interacts and the link changes.
We will update the text field.
With the new link.
So here what we do is called love engine, not location.
This location property.
And call the listener method.
This.
You know what we will do?
We will give it stoke value.
The values are firstly the new and new change listener.
You know, change this one change listener.
But we have to convert it to string also.
So you okay?
I'd give it as a string.
Not the TV, but we will write you a string.
What happened?
You change listener.
Okay.
Here.
You got the override marker.
Public void change.
Observable value.
So here.
What we will do.
We will take the text field which we have created and give the set text value in the string.
And here we will write the new value.
This one done here we have created our and the colon.
So all things are done.
Know what to do after forwards.
Now we have updated the text field with the new link.
So also we have to update the progress for our progress while it is loading.
So here what we will do, we will update our.
Okay, firstly, right, we have to update the progress bars progress
while the web page is loading this.
So here we will create a rhythm in Jakarta called fibrinogen node get load worker.
I think the load worker and afterwards we will call the work done property and then the listener thing
listener.
And then here we will also get the new changes not.
And now here we will give our number property, not the string, and write the number.
So here it will give us the overwriting method as well, this one.
And here we will write about properties.
So what we will need.
Firstly, we have to call the P bar our progress bar and give it a set visible and here we will go over
by default through value first.
Cool.
Then we will call the Beamer, of course, again, and then we will set the progress here.
And we will write the new value and it will begin to double.
So we will write the double value, and here it's done.
And now we have to build the conditions.
If the progress is equal to 100 excited to false and then it will give zero.
So we will try it with the we will take the loop.
Then we have to give the condition so we will use P but not get progress.
Yeah.
The sun that progress is equal to 100.
So you take the parentheses and write the p bar not set visible.
And here we will give the false, of course.
And after we set it to E but not set progress.
Set progress.
And here we get the zero.
And it's done.
And all these things are done.
It needs a colon, of course.
And here we have done our things.
Now what we will do, we have to give the actions.
What what will our buttons will do when we action on?
So we have to run first.
No, I think it has to be complete.
So what we will do, we will create the buttons.
So you are in text field.
I'm not set on action.
Sit on this one and write.
You know you are in parentheses.
When you are, it is loading.
No.
You are in.
And.
Something.
Okay.
This one, the Lord you are.
And then we will call the URL text field or get text in a string form.
And.
And what happened here?
Okay.
We will create our method afterwards.
And it's done here.
And after this thing, what we need to back in the forward button also.
Firstly, back we created a bridge.
We will source something.
We have to go back.
Also, we have seen in our browser there was the option to go back and the forward and the reload option.
So we will create a three buttons.
Firstly, we will create the back button and name it as the back button.
We will use the camel case here.
So back button equals to new button to start back.
Or you can also give the images as well.
If we only.
But I'm simply writing the back here and here back button and set on action the event handler which
we are using and here we go.
It's action back which we will create it.
Here I am using this function and we will create its body afterwards.
And now what we need, we have created the back button as well.
So now what?
We need a new button to forward.
We have created the back.
Now we need the forward button.
Always remember the camel case, of course.
And then new button name returns forward, this one clone.
And then we set its action also to forward button not set on action on here what I do, created or not
done.
And right here we will do one thing also here we make another matter animate to go forward.
We will give it my third body afterwards.
Here I have created this.
This is done.
Now another.
And the last thing is the button, reload, reload, button and equal to new button many more times
to reload, of course, and clone semicolon.
And then we will give the listener to that reload button not set on action name does this one give some
space insert and make another method by being called reload and here our part is done.
So what do we have done here?
Firstly, we have the user and drag the link change and updated the text field with the new link.
So here it's done.
And another thing is we have created the updated the progress bar and this progress bar while the back
page is loading.
And another thing which we need, okay, so we have okay, we have to do one more thing as well.
One type of URL in the text field, it has to stretch as well.
So we have not done this thing, so we have to do that thing.