Hello, people.
I hope that you all have been through the introduction part of our town application made in Java.
So if you have went through the introduction part, you may get an insight of what is going to happen
in this loaded down application.
So now let us understand the working of this application.
I have already told you that we will make this application under Java, WP and string libraries and
packages.
So let's see how they work.
Suppose in this application there is a frame.
So where this frame came from, it came from the library of Java where there is a class named J Frame.
So yes, this is the frame of this application.
I can minimise it.
I should do so.
Yes.
This is the frame of the application.
Now let us see what are the scene consists of?
So in the heading we have name of the application as noted down.
So yes, motel down shows us that this is the title of our notepad application.
Or we can see that the notepad clone which we are building, are going to build in this project.
So yes.
It contains a file button and a button and a help button.
So see the options inside the file button.
We have a new open save print and exit option in there that we have copy paste cut select on.
So if we want to edit the text, we can do it by copying and pasting it anywhere.
Cutting any part of the text and then testing it anywhere else.
Or just simply remove it.
And also it contains a selector feature so that we can select all the text and export it to wherever
we want with a single click.
Also, it has a help option which contains the about of this notepad.
The other window which we have discussed in the introduction part.
So if I click in this about option.
Yes.
So this is the about page.
The back window opens after clicking this button here.
So in the about option, we have the basic idea behind this application, like the name of the application
and what it does note it down is a word processing problem as we have already discussed and allows us
to text change the text of the computer like it has an introduction similarly to the open option also
so we can open any file from our system.
And that's what the introduction part about Pass is about.
But we can change the text in our competition or the existing file in our computer can be changed to
this note down application also.
And of course, we can create any text document from scratch.
Also, this program enables us to create documents, as I already said.
So after clicking this button, this will be closed.
So yes, often.
So the about section I.
I hope your mouse must have got done and I doubt it.
Now let us try and write something like if we create a new right, so suppose.
Hello everyone.
Today we are going to learn Java.
So yes, I have typed some random text.
Hello everyone.
Today we are going to learn Java.
So if we select.
Yes.
So from day one, if we select the copy option as before selecting some so as everyone today and copying
it and then try to paste it here.
So, yes.
It's.
Excuse me, please.
Yes.
So if we try to.
Select some text.
Copy it and then try to paste it here.
So, yes, everyone today is copied from here and then pasted here so that adoption is working perfectly
fine.
Now, if you want to cut something, so we have to select it like we want to cut it down.
So we firstly we have to select this click on the cut.
So yes, it is cut.
Now if we want to paste this, suppose in the next line.
So yes, we have cut the part and now we want to paste it.
So yes, we have pasted it successfully in the next line.
Now the other option is select one.
So selecting one.
With the help of my mouse.
But now we will select all with the help of this shortcut.
So yes, you can see that after clicking the select all button that all all of the text in the notepad
is selected.
Now suppose we want to cut.
So, yes, everything is cut.
Selector and cut.
So yes, they added water and its features are completely explained.
Now let us move to the file option.
So yes, if you want to open any file from our system, we will click this open.
And yes, all your system files are open.
Now close it.
Yes.
So if you want to save any file, suppose you have to write.
Hello, everyone.
Okay, so if I want to save it, I will click on the save button and opens.
Yes.
So perfect.
I can save it at any random name at any place.
So in my documents folder or wherever you want it to be saved.
This is a beautiful linking of your system and this knotted down application that we are going to learn.
So if I click on say yes.
So it is it.
So if you have a printer attached, you can also print this document and it will be printed in a page
or whatever you want it to.
So yes, print option works also fine.
Now that we have learned all the functions of this application, like creating a new opening up, saving
printing now and then.
We are going to exit this application.
So, yes.
If we click on the exit, we exit the program successfully.
Now, trying to run this again.
So yes, after exiting the program, we have returned to the program and trying to explore some more
features of this application.
So you can see that after every option, we have a shortcut attached.
Yes.
So we have a shortcut for creating a new file and open up the folders from our system.
Save them, bring them and exit.
So let us try to use a shortcut like suppose if.
Right, some random text and from your keyboard click control c and the text will be copied.
So yes, keyboard shortcuts also works fine here.
So if you copy this and now change the line and try to paste it.
So yes, from Control V, I am able to paste this text again and again.
So it's up to you how you want to write text with the help of keyboard shortcuts or directly from the
application may have link to the number.
Okay, so this is the working of this note down application and I hope you must be wondering how can
we make this application?
So we should start learning the code for this program and explore more about it.
One thing I also want to add that we can also open.
Soon print an escape by pressing a skips key on the keyboard.
They shortcuts also have a functions attached with them.
Let's suppose if I want to save it I will click on control s and yes.
So it opens up your system as well.
You want to save that?
Similarly, if I click control P Yes.
So if I click control p.
The print option pops up since all the shortcuts have a functions attached with them.
So in the next part we are going to make a new Java project, a project in our favorite compiler we
use to decode and try to write this code for program it down.
Thank you.
See you in the next part.