Hello everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction of the application part pretty well and must
be eager to learn that how actually this application is going to work.
So here we are with the working of this application.
We like how actually this application functions, how these buttons are going to work, how the height
is going to be calculated.
So we will be adding notes to the tree so that you can like visualize that how the height is increasing
or decreasing.
And of course the main part is to in order for reorder and post order calculation.
So we will be like visualizing everything.
We will be visually looking to these changes, how these branches and nodes are working.
So this is the opening window of the application.
So we were like talking about showing an AWP framework.
So we are going to extensively use the player like panel frame buttons, menubar item and everything
from the string library.
So basically the structure of this application is made with the help of the frame component of the swing
library.
Also inside the frame we are having panels.
So here you can see that title panel with our title of the application as binary search tree visualization
and also an escape and minimizing button.
So this like window closing function, we will write code for it.
Also not on hitting on this class button, we exit this window of the application inside the application.
After the title there is a frame which is containing a panel for height, a panel for this like a text
field and two buttons and the middle of the frame.
Or we can say that the middle part of this panel is containing the main tree.
Bottom of the frame is containing all the tree traversal calculation in order to preorder and post order.
So initially this tree is having how many nodes?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
So in this we are having three nodes like a tree, not a tree.
Parts are root, a left subtree and a right subtree with a total of eight nodes, one of which is the
parent our root, whatever we call it, and other segments are each child.
So there are three nodes in the left, child part or left subtree and four nodes in the right part or
the right subtree.
So like let's try deleting one of the nodes first.
So we are like initializing this application with this delete button.
So let's see how actually it is going to work.
So we want to delete this.
740 you will see that the height will update and the node will be disappeared from here.
Okay, so perfect.
One more thing.
We you must have observed that this in order pre and post order is also updated all three of them.
So the height has changed to three from four.
Initially the height was four, but once we deleted the last or we can say that the most bottom level
of this tree, then the height is changed to three.
Okay, so you must be wondering that what this like bottom level of this tree are called.
So the top part is called the root and the well botanist nodes of the tree are called as the leaves
of the tree.
So all leaves of the tree are the most bottom presented node in that tree.
Now we have tried the deleting function, the height is updated, the in order reorder and post order
is also updated here.
Okay, so let us try adding our node and let us check that how things are going to work after that.
So think about the number which will change all over the structure of this tree.
So if we try to enter a number lesser than 250, then this will edit this site.
So let us try to add 225 to this tree and see how things are going to change.
Okay, so perfect.
So this five.
250 is the parent of these 200 and these 200 is the parent of two.
25 to 25 is greater than.
200.
So it is added in the left subtree part.
Now the height is also updated from 3 to 4 as the height has increased.
The in order is updated head 225 is added and also preorder in the middle and a post order in the first
part.
So this was all about this adding function, how this adding function is working.
You must have encountered this on.
Okay, so now let's try to add the number which is greater than 500 and see that how it is added and
ready to added.
So we will try to add a number 600.
Suppose so.
600 should be added.
So 600 is added in the right subtree part of 500, and it is lesser than both 750 and 700.
So it is added in the left subtree part and became the left child of 700 or 600 is having 700 as its
parent.
Now let us try to add something greater than all of them.
Okay.
So this 2000 that added at the most rightist part of this tree as it is greater than all of the existing
nodes now.
Okay.
So let us try to add 1050 and see how the height increases.
Riverland.
Yes.
So this 1050 is greater than 1000.
And of course all of the existing present note.
So it will be added to the most rightist part, but it is like lesser than this 2000.
So it became the left child of 2000.
Also, the height of the bay stays updated to five as we are having one, two, three, four branches
and five nodes.
So the height is basically the maximum number of nodes in any possible way.
We can traverse any way to check that which is the largest possible path like oh yes, which is the
largest possible path for going to the bottom node of the tree.
Also, this is not every order and post order is updating according to like the addition.
We are meaning to the tree now we have like checked all the functionalities of this application.
So let us try to look that what coding path we have to include to perform all of them with the help
of Java.
Like what are the functions classes method we will be invoking in order to apply all of this in the
application.
So basically I have written all the like initial steps we are going to look up to by making this application
like we have to firstly initialize our frame inside which all of the components are going to be consistent.
So like after the creation of the application in the ID, we have to.
Put up things inside the frame.
So suppose we have created the application in the I.D. as Create Java project.
Then we have to initialize the frame and inside the frame only we are going to add these panels for
the title The Tree, the Height and everything.
So yes, initialization of the frame is going to be the first concern.
Now we have to like initialize variables for storing everything or whether it could be the height of
the tree, the nodes.
So we have to initialize all of them in order to access them in the rest of the code.
Or also we have to set a layout so the layout of the application is going to be pre-decided that where
the tree is going to be located, also where it is located in the middle of the frame here we have height
in the left part and the buttons in the right part and the travel segment in the bottom part and of
course, the tree.
So these layouts have to be set initially after the declaration of the variables, all kinds of variables,
whether it could be the node, the height, the elements of the tree and everything, that in order
to run a pre order functions are also going to be created.
So they will also contain some object.
So we have to declare them initially in order to access them later.
And yes, everything should be declared in the beginning as the global variables, the frame should
be initialize of course, and the layout should be set in order to decide that where which path is going
to be located.
Now the next function will be to add elements inside the BSD.
So we will be writing an algorithm for addition of elements inside the binary searching.
So there is a very beautiful method of adding the elements inside this one research tree.
We have discussed in the introduction part that, like while adding the elements inside the BSD, we
have to keep in mind several things like the left subtree should be lesser than the parent, the right
subtree should be greater than the parent.
And also the like.
Subtree, which we are talking about, should be a binary search tree itself, as the rules should not
be violated in the subtree as well.
We have to keep in mind that the right part is greater than the root, and the left part is like smaller
than the root overall to this tree.
So yes, this is like a algorithm which we are going to include for adding elements in the BSD or similarly
for deleting the nodes from the BSD.
So once we are deleting the node, then we have to like readjust this tree.
So suppose that I will show you that how actually this deleting is going to work.
So suppose we try to delete this 750 then all of this left, right, subtree and left subtree of this
750 is going to rearrange themselves in order to become a binary search tree itself again.
And with respect to this root, they have to like be greater than all of the elements are greater then.
So let us try to delete 7/51 and see what happens.
So yes, the 750 is disappeared now the like right subtree is a head became 1000.
1000 is greater than 500 of course.
And again, 706 hundred are greater than one are like less than 1000.
And these are 201 050 is greater than 1000.
So this is again following the principles of a binary search tree.
There is no violation in the rules and all of these elements are greater than this main root.
We can say that.
So it is following the roots of mine resisted even after the deletion.
So yes, you must have encountered that how beautifully things are rearranging themselves.
So there should be plenty of code in order to handle all these functionalities and we will be looking
up to it in detail.
Till then we like start the programming section, so see what's left.
Okay, so we have completed this and now this is like for taking the maximum element from the left side.
So like.
In order to write the logics for this, in order, pre-order and post order, we have to like rearrange
this tree first.
So the maximum element from the left side is going to be the.
I test part of the left subtree and in order to calculate the in order and pre-order and post order,
we have to write simple objects that in order is working in the manner of.
Like a root in the left.
It is containing the left part.
So basically it is left root right.
And how this created it, it is working like a root left and then right.
So first all then all of the members of the left, subtree and then the right subtree, of course.
And also this poster that is taking the root as it ends.
So left subtree, right subtree.
And then the root.
So this is how this logic of another parent and post order is working.
We will be writing a separate code for this functioning also.
Okay.
So also for the calculation of the height, we are going to traverse the tree and trace that which is
the longest possible path in order to the leaf node.
Like here we are having leaf sets 225 601 050 So basically what is a leaf?
So if is a node which is having no child.
So yes, all three of them are having no child.
Also there is 350, which is having no child.
So basically we are having 1 to 3 and four leaf to this tree.
Now, in order to calculate the height, we will be traversing from the root to all the lymph nodes
and like store the variable which is going to count the nodes in order to traverse this route from the
leaf and which is going to be the largest, should be returned as the height of this beast.
So, yes, all this programming logic we are going to cover in the next part.
So calculate height of Vesta using recursive method.
So we are going to follow a recursive method for this calculation.
Like our same part of code will be written and this root will travel to the leaf nodes with the same
recursive code again doing like coming back to it and then again going to any other leaf.
So this is all going to be performed recursive.
And then the last part is going to be our functionalities for rearranging the node after the deletion
and addition.
As we have seen that once we delete or add a node, then all of them rearrange them.
Also in this tree and industry order, post order and in order.
So after all of this we are going to like run this application and check that how everything is going
to be put up together.
So we will start the coding section in the next part.
So see you in the next one.