Hello everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction part pretty well and have again like much
idea about what actually this project is about, what are the functionalities we are going to attach
in this project and what are the concepts we are going to learn after the successful completion of this
project?
So after getting through the rough idea about this project, we are here to check the working of this
project, how actually this project works, what are the options?
How choosing options, navigating between accounts and everything works.
So in this part we are here.
After running the program, we are going to write the program on our own.
But I am here to explain this with my already written program and to like check everything is working
perfectly or not.
So on running this project, this welcome to the project message will be displayed on your screens and
again asking for that type of account like we, whether we are existing users, then we will have to
log in and if we are like new user, then we have to create a new account to this project.
So suppose we are a new user and we want to create a new account, so we will be hitting two options
from our keyboard and on hitting enter we will be asked for enter your customer number.
So this is upon us.
We can choose any number.
So suppose I am choosing like four times nine as my customer number and and terrapin to be registered.
I told you about that.
These credentials are very like explore visible.
Yes, they are possible.
So we have to keep these credentials very secure and do not disclose this information to anybody asking
for it as this is about the security of our money and this has to be kept in mind that we do not like
share these credentials to any random person which we are not knowing well.
So yes, after hitting enter yes your new account has been created, successfully registered.
So this message will appear on your window and then you will be redirected to the login window.
So if we have a pressed one in the choice option, so automatically this will be a padding.
But we have chosen the create account option.
So this is the additional part which will be asked by the user that you have to register first, then
only you can enter to this item like system.
So we are like we are having our customer number and pin number already so we can like see them and
type.
But I have told you that you have to remember this in future if you want to log in again.
So enter your customer number and enter your PIN number has been entered successfully.
Now after this, we are logged into our ATM system.
Now we have to select the type of account you like we want to access.
So type one is the checking account and type two is the savings account.
So suppose we want to enter in our savings account and hitting to and after this this savings account
interface will open.
So suppose you want to view the balance.
So initially our balance is zero.
We have nothing in our savings account balance, so we want to deposit some money.
So current savings account balance will be displayed at every step.
We have already discussed it.
So amount you want to deposit.
So suppose I want to deposit $20,000 to my savings account.
So current savings account balance will reflect our value of $20,000.
Now, in the next step, if you will be like viewing balance, then the balance will be updated.
Now the next step we want to perform is suppose we want to withdraw some money.
So on hitting do it will be asking for amount.
We want to withdraw.
So suppose I want to withdraw to $2,000.
Yes.
So once I withdraw $2,000, then the current savings account balance will be updated to $18,000, which
is like working pretty fine.
We have like withdrawn 2000 automatically.
20,000 -2000 is $18,000.
Now, the most interesting feature is like transferring funds within the account.
So let us check that function also.
So select an account you want to transfer the funds to.
So you want to transfer funds to our checking account as we have like nothing in our checking account.
So amount you want to deposit.
Suppose we have $18,000 and we want to deposit it to our checking account balance from our savings account.
So the current savings account balance will be 10,000.
Now, after this, we want to exit this frame and we want to enter in that checking account window.
Now, in the checking account interface, suppose we want to view the balance.
So our checking account balance is updated to 8000 as we have transferred funds from the savings account
to the checking account balance.
Now here also we can transfer the funds to the checking account savings account balance from this checking
account balance.
So suppose we are transferring 2000.
Okay.
So you want to transfer funds to a savings account and 2000 or so checking account balance updated.
Now let us check whether the savings account balance is updated or not.
So what we had, we had I think the savings account balance was at the last step, 12,000.
Yes, I can see that we have 1000.
So on hitting one.
Yes, perfect savings account balance is to end $12,000, which is like working perfectly fine.
We are like done with all the functionalities checked.
We have checked that.
Yes, the logging and registering thing.
Now, after that, we logged in to our ATM system, after which we have entered the savings account
interface.
Now did some functionalities inside the savings account interface, like depositing funds, withdrawing
funds, viewing balance, and then at last transferring funds to our checking accounts.
So after which we have like navigated to our checking account.
And again, we checked the balance, we transferred the funds again from the checking account interface
to the savings account.
So everything till now is working perfectly fine.
So this is an interesting project in Java where we are like switching between options.
We have this code which reflects object oriented programming.
We are having objects, classes, and inside the classes everything is like taking place.
All these steps are maintained by separate classes.
So like let us firstly prepare a rough prototype of what actually we are going to do inside this programming
section, which we will be looking in the next part.
So firstly, we have to create a new project in the ID, and after the successful creation of the new
project, we will be creating a main class which will be responsible for like our testing and running
of the IT management system or testing and running.
Testing and running is only performed by this main class.
No other classes will be involved in testing and running of the like system, only this main class.
So initially we will create a main class.
Then after that, what are the other classes we will require in order to complete this system project?
So the second class will be a account class creating the account class, and this class will be like
managing everything about the type of account
customer verification thing, like whether the credentials entered by the customer is like correct or
not.
So we have to like have a two factor authentication thing to check that whether the PIN and the customer
number entered by the customer is correct or not.
So we will be like managing our functionality for that verification in our account class in the project.
Now the third thing we will be going to manage inside this account class will be like operations regarding
the balance calculations.
So operations regarding balance calculation will be also managed by this account, class only.
So yes, this is the third thing we are going to manage inside this.
Now suppose that if a user enters any wrong choice from like their keyboards or wrong option is selected.
So also there is an exception checking like exception handling method for invalid choices which we are
going to manage with the help of try and catch blocks.
So yes, this exception handling will be performed with this account class for invalid choices also.
So this is all about this account class we are going to create.
Now, the fourth thing yes, the third class we will be creating.
And the fourth thing which we are keeping in mind in the prototype section, is to create creating an
option class.
So option menu class we can see and this option menu class will be responsible for displaying the options
list like displaying the.
List of choices.
Yes, this is the right word list of choices from which the user has to select that what he actually
wants to do.
Then you want to log in or create an account.
Then after that, whether he wants to enter to the checking account interface or the savings account
interface and everything.
So yes, this is option menu class and displaying list of choices is the role of this option menu class.
And the rules are to handle the exceptions, to handle the exceptions regarding the like option selection.
But suppose that the option attached to a specific choice is not entered correctly then to handle the
exceptions regarding the.
Yes.
So handle the exceptions here.
Exceptions regarding the switch cases.
So what actually switch cases are?
We will be like discussing it in detail in the programming section.
So yes, exceptions regarding the switch cases will be handled inside this option menu class.
And at last, this option menu class will be mapping things like we have a choice and a special option
attached to that choice.
So that is a unique choice with every key press.
So with the help of mapping, we are going to perform this.
Yes, here me correctly, I am talking about mapping.
We are going to use hash maps, data structures in order to link choices to specific options so that
on pressing that specific key, that specific option is to be performed.
So this option menu class will be going to like responsible about mapping values or with every key press.
Yes.
So we are going to map everything.
Every key should be mapped to a specific option and everything is going to be like linked in a manner
so that nothing overlaps.
Like suppose you press key file for the extracting and that key on pressing that key you enter to transfer
funds interface.
So this is not going to work.
We have to map everything like correctly in order to make things properly functional without any overlapping.
So to avoid any kind of exceptions overlapping, we are going to use different types of data structures
which we will be looking in the programming section in the next part.
So I hope you have understood all the like blueprint part of this project.
Now from the next part we will be start creating a new project and then initializing all the classes
and functionalities related to them.
So see you in the next part with the coding section.