Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have been through the introduction part of the application in Java that we are
going to make today.
And after that introduction you must have gained a draft idea about what actually we are going to make
in this project and what are the concepts we are going to learn while making this project and what are
the specifications of this project overall that we will be looking up to while making this project?
What should be kept in mind before starting to make this project?
So in this part we will be looking up to what is the working of this application, how actually this
application works, what are the functionalities attached in this app?
And also like what will be the final output of running everything and we will see that.
So this is the window which is going to open when you will run the application in your compilers or
from the icons which we will make on the completion of the project.
So yes, we can see that there is a frame basically inside the frame that is like Title MENUBAR title
is the component of the frame framework which we are using.
I have told about it it was Swing and AWP.
We will be using these two frameworks while making this application.
So this is the title containing a Java coffee mug icon and order as the title of this window.
Okay, so inside this application there are some options and first options as for size, that is a dropdown
down test asking for small or medium large.
So on selecting any one of them, it will be displayed here large and then we are being asked for select
which type of beverage you want to order.
So we will be choosing one of these to check how actually it works.
So suppose I am going to select coffee.
So we are ordering large coffee.
And how many glasses?
So suppose I want to order six glasses of coffee and you can see that initially the order button is
like a light.
It is not clearly visible, visible.
It is like a paring light light border.
That is no highlight to this button.
Once we will click add, then automatically this order button will be in like come in a different color
similarly like this red button.
So currently this order button is non-functional.
Once we will add something to the cart, then only this order button will become functional and change
its color automatically instead of being this grey like looking.
So I am clicking on this add button.
So this dialog box up there asking me for add ons.
So suppose if I want to add milk to my coffee, are there are people who prefer coffee without milk
like diet conscious people so they will be clicking?
No.
Then the order will be made in that terms only.
But suppose I want to add to it to check how it works.
So would you like milk?
Yes, I would like to add milk.
So six large glasses of coffee with milk added.
So we have successfully added six glasses of coffee with milk.
Now you can see that this order button highlighted up and now we can click on order so that yes.
So again, a message or dialog box appeared and six large glasses of coffee with milk will cost me 58.5
like currency units, whatever it could be.
And once I will click, okay, so this dialog box, then again a dialog box will appear showing me that
how much I should pay for this application.
Like what is the total amount to be paid by me once I will check out the card.
So this is the like overall process of ordering something.
So I am clicking.
Okay, so everything is now like previous.
The like.
The initial state application jumps back to the running state initial window opened and now we will
try adding more than one thing to the like cart and then we will try checking out to see what actually
happens.
So suppose the size remains medium and I am ordering a juice of five glasses of juice and then I am
clicking on this add button.
So this is a new thing which we haven't talked about.
So I wanted it to discuss in the working part for a better understanding of this thing.
So one more dialog box is attached to this application asking for flavors of juice.
Like what?
What things?
Juice we want to order.
So suppose I want pineapple juice.
So we have selected this fruit in the dialog box as well.
So this dialog box is containing our dropdown menu.
It is a dialog box itself, it contains a dropdown menu and again the cancel button to confirm.
So I am clicking.
Okay.
And then 5 million glasses of pineapple juice added.
Perfect.
So suppose now again I want to order or the size should be support small and suppose again I want to
order five glasses of B so I'm clicking and it is asking for would you like sugar?
So it depends on the like user whether he or she wants to add sugar to the tea or not.
So suppose I want to add sugar on clicking?
Yes.
Five small glasses of tea with sugar added.
So these two things are added to the cart.
Now I wish to like check out.
I did not want to order anything else so I'm clicking order.
So to see this dialog box pair displaying that what actually I have added to my cart and what is the
cost attached to these specific items.
So 5 million glasses of pineapple juice costs 52.5 and five small glasses of tea with sugar costs 18.75.
So it is perfect.
We have ordered two things and the message is showing the same.
So everything is working fine now.
On clicking.
Okay, so the total amount to be paid by me is 71.25 units of currency and this is like adding the amount.
So we have 51.25 and like I am not remember remembering the data but they are adding the cost of the
tea and the juice.
So this is also a special functionalities attached in this application are for totaling the items cost
and then displaying this in a separate dialog box.
So on clicking.
Okay.
Yes.
So perfect.
We are back to the previous window which was opened when we run the application and we have ordered
two things.
So everything was working perfectly fine now.
So you have gained all the idea about the working of this application and I hope that you must be like
excited in order to learn how to write the program of this application on your own, learning every
concept behind the program, and then complete this application to learn more and more concepts in Java.
So here we will be like writing the prototype of the application, which we are going to make today.
So what actually are the requirements that will be kept in mind before creating the application?
So firstly, we have to create a new Java project in the ID, a new project in ideas of our choices.
Like we will be using Visual Studio code for creating this project.
So firstly we will be creating a new project.
Secondly, we will be like creating classes inside the project.
So creating.
Main class first.
So the main class will be responsible for testing and running of the application, responsible for testing
and running of the application.
So whenever we will be like making things like putting things together and then we will be checking
that how things are working or not.
In each step we will be running the main class only, not any other class so responsible for testing
and running of the app.
Okay, so after the creation of the main class now we will be creating separate classes for each of
the like you have.
You must have seen that every order was asking for a different add on.
So in order to make things like different from each what we can say that menu items so we have to get
the different menu items with different add ons.
So we should be creating different classes for each item.
So, okay, so as a whole we will be creating a beverage class for like consisting all the items in
the menu and after which we will be creating separate classes for each of the items in the menu.
Suppose we had coffee, juice and what else we had.
I think it was three and our.
Yes.
So we have ordered so we have to order things from these four options only.
So we will be creating four different classes for the menu items in order to attach like the add ons
which they were asking for separately.
Like there was nothing combined.
They were asking for different items.
Suppose coffee was asking for is it was milk or juice was asking for flavours like we chose pineapple.
I think so.
Flavour.
So we will be attaching everything separately in these classes.
Only tables asking for sugar and water was asking for ice, of course.
So we will be like attaching everything in these classes separately and after which we will be having
a total of five classes.
So in the fifth step we will be having total of five classes.
This is amazing.
Total of five classes to be made in order to complete this project.
To be made.
So to be made.
So we have like a rough idea about what we are going to make while like creating this project in our
compiler side or whatever we see and after the creation of these five classes.
Except for the main class like we have for things, for the menu items and our beverage class which
will be consisting all the items in the menu in a combined manner.
And okay, so if we are main class also, so we will be creating six classes as a whole and this main
class will be consisting on the form.
Yes.
So basically it is a form and we are filling this form in order to complete our orders.
So here now we're like gathering all the idea about this application.
In the next part we will be looking up to creating of a new project in our compilers and then starting
coding part of this project.
So see you in the next part with the creation of a new project in the compiler.
Thank you.