So in previous videos or explanations, I told you how we are proceeding with this.
So I imported this in my part, and now what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention some code here.
So let me go to the project structure.
You can change the views of your packages.
Also here, you can check or you can see project structure also.
So in CRC main in Java, you can see this is my package basically.
So I don't want to go in further apart.
So what I can do, I can just switch to the package view and inside the package I can see the packages
also.
So this is all the things and these are application properties, which is basically the application
things here.
So as you can see, this is the application properties files you can check here.
So let me close this.
And what I'm going to do now is I'm going to invoke some things here.
So let us check.
What I'm going to mention here is basically.
So before going in for the part, I need to mention one thing here, or as I told you, I'm going to
use your one CSV file, which is basically from raw data file.
And I'm using here when you get a raw data file, it is deploying in every day.
It is updating it in every day.
So I'm going to fetch data from that file.
You can use any other thing, but my recommendation is check for the headers, check for each CSV file
or not.
So these are some important things.
So in this part, what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention one thing here.
So let me right click this.
So okay.
So let me right click this click new here.
I'm creating Java class here.
Well, you can use my directory structure.
You can go by file name.
You can go to class.
Let me go with click new.
Java class.
This not.
Okay.
So what I can do.
I can go to the projects of you.
In this application.
Click New.
Don't.
Now what I'm going to engineers is basically coronavirus data service.
So what it will do, it will create a service package with some this which is basically our class and
it is going to fetch the data for us.
So clearly tender.
So what happened?
Basically, it's created a service.
So if I go to packaging, you can see services is created here.
So this is my another package.
And let me.
Go with that side.
Let me zoom this part later.
So this is my package.
Go with this.
And this is basically our service.
So I imported this file, so.
I need to mention that you are a data first.
So what I'm going to do is I'm giving up your private.
It's that big.
Or your data.
Basically, I say, which is basically string only string.
And the name I'm going to specify is virus data URL so you can use anything.
But I already coded some part here.
Why is it a URL and let me go with this.
So let me mention the data file here or we can see you are here.
You can use any other thing here.
But as I told you, you you need to maintain the or basically it's a CSV file check for each CSV file
or not.
If it's not a CSP, you have to check the ceasefire.
I am using your data raw data failure.
I told you, I mentioned your little data file.
What is data you really remote.
So now what I'm going to do is let me create one thing here or let me mention something here.
So this is basically the statistics, but I need to append this list in one location status because
it's location wise.
I need to create one list here.
So let me mention this list.
So I'm going to explain you.
What is this thing?
Let me enter this basically.
And what I'm going to do is.
Let me start this.
Okay, so location stats, I'm going to explain you.
What is the useful thing here?
I'm going to mention here.
So this is the basic thing I mentioned.
Now let me create one thing here, which is basically list, public list.
Location.
Start with all stats, so it will get the all statistics from that.
So it is the location style.
So I will explain you later.
What I'm going to do is here, so I'm just invoking the URL, but what I'm going to do is I need to
create one method to face that things.
So in this class only after closing this, let me mention one method to face the data.
So let me create public.
Boyd.
Which could be data.
Or we can see which virus data.
This is my method.
So.
Okay.
As I told you, we need to mention this again.
I need to mention the this thing.
I'm going to create location stats.
Don't worry about it.
I will create it later in later part.
Let me create one HTP client here.
HTTP.
Client.
So remember, this is a Java thing and what I'm going to mention is here.
So dot net, java dot net file is HTTP client file.
And let me create one client here, which is basically name as the single class first.
Client is equal to.
New.
And she declined.
So this is all about how I am going to do this.
Okay.
I forgot to mention our client is not this basically.
I'm explaining this again.
The thing is to create a strategic plan.
So basically http.
Client dot new.
It should be client.
That's it.
I need to mention the tip line to receive the client request.
So let me create one builder thing.
What is the builder thing is basically a HTTP request.
Steep request.
Or let me mention this as a request only so variable.
You can use anything here.
CDB request is equal to request with some builder class, which is basically http.
Request, not new builder.
Or we can say of a new builder.
The new builder.
Not so by mentioning the DOT, as I told you, our data is you are not.
You are.
I think I need to mention.
Here you are.
I also.
You are so you are.
I is basically nothing but integrated.
You can say you are.
I create and I'm going to mention this virus data.
Is that a URL?
Unless I mention I need to mention one thing here is building.
I need to build this.
So build this.
So I mentioned this, so we already created this.
So I need to mention one thing here is this is basically htp url.
Our request is but I need to mention it.
So you are.
You are.
I is embedded.
So I need to create one embedded thing here.
And I mentioned this.
So forget about these things.
I'm going to create the ArrayList for that purpose to store the location.
I already created this.
I'm going to run this project after all the things I invoke.
Let me just do one thing.
Whenever there is a.
This thing.
Let me.
Do this part.
What I'm going to do is.
System.
Dot dot thought Ritalin.
Nyquist.
So this can be printed.
Sorry, we cannot print a request here.
If you want to do, you can print the request also.
But before that, we need to create a string framework here because it's not a string.
First, we need to make a string here.
So what I'm going to do is step response here now.
So response.
Then inside this response, I'm going to mention when it's a string framework string.
Use this string only not a small string because we are going to handle the string handling methods.
Also HTTP response only and engineer response is equal to.
What I'm going to do is client.
This is client send.
Now I want to mention the HTTP response.
So first is basically request.
So this is basically we can say we are working with client request and this model in the spring framework
only SGP.
Or for this purpose.
What is the thing is HTTP response only.
GDP response.
Don't body handlers.
Then again, the of.
Bring.
Okay.
So.
What I need to mention is here is basically.
Response.
Body handlers of spring.
Spring, not spring saw the strains.
Let me do this again.
So.
So it is telling me to.
So our example is not throws exception.
That's a.
Year.
Are you exception?
And interrupted exception I need to mention here.
Because we are going to face that exception also.
Oh, so this is it.
We are going to do this.
So let me do one thing.
Let me invoke.
This.
Directly.
So what the missing thing is, I'm specifying this so this can be generated.
Or sometimes I mention this request with this and what I can do, I can print your this.
Okay.
So in loco with this application what I can do.
I can run this application, so let us check it's running or not.
If there is an error, we are going to develop this and we are going to check that part.
So currently it's taking, it's running and each and everything it's doing is running and directories
also it is taking the part of that.
So it will take time to run each and everything.
Once this is done.
You can say this is the.
Thing which is renewed in future.
But our spring boot is doing very well.
None I can see.
Change this.
This started with application.
GBM is running now.
So this is over.
Basically the application is running, it is creating stability engine.
Everything is running and spring is working very well.
Springwood.
So this is basically warning.
You can check.
And as I told you, I'm just printing this part only.
So it will print the info part.
We stop this.
So our response team is working very well.
So I will remove this in later part.
Let me create one thing or let me add one dependency injection here.
So our dependency injection is nothing but when.
What we can see.
Comms failure.
So let me copy it from web.
Uh, let me go to the.
Okay.
Do not open nearly to check on me only.
So let me go to the project here.
Let me go to the XML.
So I need to mention one spring dependency.
So I will add it here, which is basically a CSP and which is basically the for the common thing here.
So you can check here.
Injection.
So let me load this part.
So it is resolving our dependencies.
And if the dependency found, it will download that.
So this is the basic thing of what we can say, checking each and everything.
So this is the dependency injection here.
So as you can see, our dependency now injected variable, which is basically a dot coms.
So what is the basic thing I'm using here is while printing the data, I don't want to mention it as
a comma separated.
I need to mention it says handling the request.
And so I invoke that part.
So later I will explain how this is going to work.
So for other things, I'm going to check this part also.
Let me add two or three things more here, because due to time constraint, I don't want to specify
much more time in that you can use directly these things.
Also let me mention that part first and it's very useful, but it is basically KSP part nothing more,
which is basically string reader.
I'm going to use it later because.
And.
You can import Java or your dot star.
Star then is also.
Start.
So useful thing is in Java is you can import all the libraries.
Let me make a change here is importing.
So you can check.
I'm importing the libraries.
These are the some system default libraries here.
And let me add one more thing is basically passing the thing with string reader, which is basically
terrible.
Iterable is nothing but checking this again and again.
So.
Again what is the thing is basically pretend to.
So all.
I'm going to pretend again.
So it will create glass in each and everything.
Let me do that, Slater.
So it will import this and this is we already done it from dot XML and I'm mentioning a default in here
or you can check the documentation of comps on the Internet.
But commerce is nothing but it will check all the headers files.
So as in this GitHub file or we can say raw data file, GitHub data file, there are already errors.
In further part, I'm going to mention a HTML page also and we are going to depend that part and we
need to store the some locations also in our system.
So I will tell you how we are going to do that.