So I hope you all have watched the introduction section of this project and the overview about this
project, what we are actually going to do in this programming section of the school funds system.
Now let's begin by creating a Java project in Visual Studio code.
I hope you all have installed the JDK latest version and Visual Studio code ID in your systems.
We already does.
Discuss the installation and download part in the earlier videos.
So yes, let's start with creating a Java project in Visual Studio code.
Look at this Create Java Project button.
You have to create a Java project by clicking on this button.
Select No Build Tools as we are creating our basic ops project.
So initially we have to select this no build told options.
Yes.
So this project requires a path where it will be saved.
So I am going to create a new folder in my desktop and call it as school.
Funds.
System.
And so I left the project location.
After selecting the project location, we have to input a Java project name for this project.
So we will input a Java project name in the text box.
We will limit the school funds system.
And press enter.
So here is the School Fund System Project in Java with the inbuilt folders like settings, not JSON,
which the Visual Studio calls provides by default a lib file which is empty and unnecessary folder,
which is the main folder of this project.
All the required files will be built head only.
Yes.
So it contains app dot java already.
And this is the main file of this project which we are going to run to get our output of the school
funds management system.
Here we have a public class called App, and inside the class there is a function public static void
with arguments as string.
And when it throws up exception, the app throws one exception that it will print out this helloworld.
And for printing anything in Java we have to write System.out.println and we will see it later in this
project as well.
So if we run this part of code, we will get the output.
Yes.
So here you can see that Helloworld is printed in that terminal.
So the code is working perfectly fine.
Let's start by making our files required in this project.
So the first file we are going to create is in the A-Z folder and we will name it as.
I mean, not Java.
So here you can see that I am creating a file called Green dot Java.
So you can see that our main file is already created.
Here we have a main class.
You can see we have already a main class.
After creating the main file in SC folder, java is all about class as an object.
So yes, you can see that we have already a class.
Now we will import the dependencies and the library required in this package.
Basically we are going to attach all the packages required in this project.
So I am going to import.
Java analyst.
I.
I will tell you about what java analyst is.
Let me first import this.
So yes, we have imported java util Aaron is currently it is gray as we haven't used in the code.
But later when we will use this, it will become colorful.
Now let me tell you about what Java ArrayList is.
Java util is a package for Java for writing Java codes and ArrayList is a property of Java which gives
us a resizable array and this ArrayList is found in the Java util package.
As you can see that I am writing it like java dot dot arrows.
So inside the Java util package we will get the ArrayList list function.
So yes, ArrayList is resizable array, which we will use later in this project for adding features
student to the array and it will be resizable.
It will help us to increase the number of features that students in later without having any conflicts.
The next package we are going to import is our list.
So let me import it as import java or util package itself, not list.
Yes.
So we have successfully imported list and arranged for our project in Java.
List is the facility to maintain order collection.
It contains index based method to insert, update, delete and search the elements.
So we will use list and list properties of Java in this project.
Now let's begin with the.
Plus and we will create a function public static.
Void mean it will be our.
Main function containing arguments as string.
Square braces and.
OGs.
So yes, the parameter is passed as string arguments.
Inside the main function, we will initialize the.
So inside the main function we will be declaring new methods later.
But let us first create a student class, teacher class and a school class.
This means that Java will be responsible for running the program successfully.
So let me create a new file in the SLC folder as well and name it as student dot java.
So here it is.
We have a class called student and.
This class will contain all the information about the student ID, its roll number or whatever information
like the fees paid.
What is the fees paid?
What is the fees left to be paid by the student?
And similar kind of things?
So let us begin this with starting this student part of this program.
So let's start.
Private, which is the axis specified in Java.
There are three axis specifies in Java public, private and protected, and they have their own rules
for the variables.
Like if we declare a variable as private, this variable will be not would not be accessible with any
other class.
But if it is private public, it will be accessible by the other classes of the program.
And the protected is similar as private.
It is protected from the other classes that they cannot access that variable in the program without
permission.
So let's start with giving an integer ID object inside this class student.
Similarly, private string name.
And similarly for the other three variables which we are going to use grade C, spade and C total.
So here we are.
We have declared five methods inside this class.
And let me commend the purpose of this file.
So I am using control plus slash to command like this file is for keeping the track of student name
fees, grade and C sprint keeping the track of.
Yeah.
So here we go.
I recommended the significance of this file at the top of this file.
Now, to create a new student by initializing it, we have to create a class again.
This class is not a simple class.
This is a constructor.
So constructor is a class basically with same name as the.
Above last.
But it contains parameters inside it for the functioning of the program.
So inside it I am initializing the arguments as in the ID name and grade grade of the students, and
I am doing all of them inside the student constructor.
So yes, inside this constructor, we are going to call all the functions which we declared above in
the classes.
So, yes, inside this constructor we are going to initialize operators for the field declares declared
above this dot ID is for ID this dot grid is for grid and this dot name is for the name field which
we declared above.
So yes, we are writing.
This operator for each field mentioned above inside the constructor.
And yes, here we are.
So let me give you a quick idea about what constructors are so commenting.
So when we will require to add a new student to the school, this constructor will be called and with
the use of new keyword in Java, the constructor is called automatically in every place, wherever we
want to call it.
So let me write this to create a new student.
This constructor is called by initializing this constructor.
The constructor with the name student.
Yes.
So here we are.
So this constructor has the job of creating new students by initializing them.
With her idea, unnamed and agreed, which is a compulsory fee for every new student to be admitted
in the school.