This following image will help understand the coordinated values a bit more.
The courtside seats, the coordinates on the Tetris piece, for example, numbers minus one and one
here and minus one and zero and zero zero and zero and the minus one represent are rotated as shape.
So the following diagram illustrates this shape.
Here you can see the shape as well.
The minus comma, minus one, comma one, the x and the star y minus one and the one the minus one.
And this two zero and the zero zero and the zero, comma minus one here.
This will be our rotated shape.
So we will apply this logic in our program.
What we will do next, we will write.
Private.
Lloyd said X And then to this we will write and index.
Coma in NY and after this we will write cards and we will take the index as well with the zero and another
one equal to x and close via curly bracket.
And before that we will write a semicolon.
And after this.
We will do one more thing with the viral.
So you will write private void, set y and write in x comma in the y
bracket.
Open cards next and another one will be the one and equal to y colon and curly bracket close.
So after this we will write also public X and index
clues.
In this matter, we will write return cards
next to one and clues and curly bracket.
And similar to this write into why we provide a parameter index here.
And after this, in this matter, we simply write return cards index with the one.
Simply close the curly bracket.
And another one we have to do for the terminal, that ship.
So we will write.
Trump.
No on me.
Another matter.
Get shape.
And simply into this matter, we will right return our piece ship.
And simply close it.
No, we have to do one more thing.
We have to set the random sheep.
So before this, we will go.
Okay.
We will write another method for the random sheep.
So here we will call the public void and name it as a sad, random sheep.
So we're set to random sheep.
And to this method, we will create a variable or.
I mean, you know.
Create this object.
And after simply this we will write index equal to matter dot and take the absolute of the or dot into.
So next in and after this, we have to take the absolute so module seven plus one because we have the
seven shapes, right?
So we take the same so import random and simply imported this.
And after this we will.
Call the terminal.
Clear the area of the terminal values, take the terminal values
and right set ship into this.
We will provide the values with the x and semicolon.
Now what we have to do, we will firstly create this type public int minimum x and in this matter we
will create another variable with the area initialization equal to code and set it to zero.
000 and semicolon.
And then we will create a word for loop.
In this loop we have to write an equal to ICAM, equal to zero, i.e. less than to four, and then post
increment of i.e. in the letters for loop.
We will write an equal to math dot.
We will take the minimum function and here we will give the parameter m comma another error name code
with the next i.e. and this one will be the zero.
So here this thing is done.
And we have to return this value.
So this is set similar to this.
We will create a minimum write.
So after this you will write uplift and minimum VI and you will write in equal to cards.
Start with the zero and the run and ride for loop int equal to zero i less than to four and post incremental
i.
And after this we need our math function for the variable am and am equal to motherboard minimum.
And here we will take the M.
Now here we will call cards I and this one will be the one and done.
And again we have to return the value of RAM.
So return and done so this system.
Now we have to code our new method which will be rotate a piece to the left so we will create a new
method called this public shape.
She did not surrender this matter.
Firstly, this code rotates a piece to the left so the square does not have to be rotated.
That's why we simply return the reference to the current object.
So looking to the previous previous coordinate image, we are to code this as well.
You know you will, right?
If I take trapeze shape equal to the terminal dot square shape.
So into this we will write written simply this.
After this, we have to create a variable resolved equal to new shape object and often the civil rights
result art piece shape equal to this shape and we will create our for loop and right or in equal to
zero.
I.
Let's turn to four and here we will not do the post increment.
Here we will take the pre increment of the I and under this for loop we will write.
Resolved it resolved.
Don't settle.
We need a set x.
So you're right.
The same as it is.
And here we will write y.
Under this we will provide the parameter y y to the I.
Similar to this we will write result outside to y same as the I in, but here it will be the minus x
and that will be the I here c and simply return the result here and here over my person.
The score rotates a piece to the left.
The square does not have to be rotated twice.
We simply return the reference to the current object here.
Return this so what we have to do next.
We have to complete this thing and take the rotate right as well.
So we will create another matter and simply write public shape and rotate right.
Similar to the rotate left under this same if these shape.
Not only do that, draw no square shape.
Simply return the reference to the object.
Return this.
And
here.
Same as it is to rotate left as variable result equal to new shape and result piece shape.
Peace sheep equal to the beef sheep.
And our brothers.
We need that for same to the previous one.
So we will write.
Four.
I couldn't do zero and I.
Similar to that.
Less than four.
And need the increment of I.
And under this for low we will right result or set.
You need the x one provide the index I to the minus vi here and try it and this I now need result set.
Why do my here index with the I and here we will see X with the I and simply we are done with our rotate
left and right matter as well.