So we need a class of album, so we're creating a playlist player application, so we have to need a
song and then we will.
We need to have an album.
So there will be a Java class and this will be called as album Java.
So here is our album class.
And what we have is the properties of album is the name of album and artist, which artist have created
this album and ArrayList of songs.
So ArrayList is basically an array, but with more functionality and more, you know, as dynamic area,
we can see ArrayList as a dynamic area, we can add elements, remove elements.
So here the first thing is our name, so private string name, and then we have string the name of the
artist.
So private string and artist and let's have user defined parameter constructor.
So we have to initialize our ArrayList here.
So new ArrayList of song.
So here is our album and let's create an empty constructor also.
But I'm not going to use it, but it is always a good practice to have an empty constructor.
So here we are done with the properties of album and the next thing that we have is that we have need
some functionality to add songs inside the album, right?
So let's define that method so public and what we it will be our return type public, right?
So we need some functionality.
And so yeah, public and the return type is going to be the boolean because.
We have two written songs successfully added and also public boolean.
We call it Add Song, Add song and we have to pass in the name of song and the duration as well.
So string title and double duration if we are going to add song to an album.
We have to check that if that song already exists.
In our list or not.
So it is good to create a separate matter which checks for the song if exist or not.
So here in this matter.
If let's call the method do we find song so fine and we'll pass the name of the song's equal to null.
That means the song that we are going to add in the list is NULL.
That means that it doesn't already exist in our list of songs so that only we have to edit it if find
song title is equal to null.
So in that case we will add this new song.
So as songs dot.
All right.
And here we have to pass that song.
So let's create a new song because we don't have the song.
So we have to create a new song.
So let's pass in the title and the duration that we are getting from.
Here.
And after that, we will bring.
This better means some successfully added.
So we have added this to our list and will return true as well.
And in the end part, we have to return false and print something we say with say song with name and
then the title.
So in the last part, the song already exists in the list that we are going to add.
So let's create this find song.
MATALIN Here we have this bumbling underwritten type is going to be the.
So great to.
What will we do?
The return type is going to be the song because we are checking for the song.
So I will be the song and let's call it the fine song.
Of course, fine song.
And here it takes string as title, string, title of the song.
And then we have to check.
Now we have to iterate through the loop, right?
We have to iterate through the loop to check if the song exists or not.
So for that, we are going to use enhanced for loop.
So far we have to check for song and the variable we are going to use for the traversal is called Check
the song or so we.
Pipe the songs here inside the list.
And the list is the core songs and if it already exists.
So if chad song not get title if you remember we have.
This getter, right?
Get title and sign the song class.
So if we checked some dot title equals, if this is equal to whatever passed inside this smarter title.
So that means we have a song with this name in the song list.
So in that case we will return whatever the song is.
So we will return the song and else part will not as will simply return because the return type is not
boolean.
So if song already exist in our list, it will return that song or else it will be returned.
NULL.
So here we find song title is NULL.
That means no such song exist in our list of songs.
Then we will simply add that here we are done with add song method and.
And yet find some other.
And the next thing that we can do, we have we can need a functionality to add song to the playlist
and this song must exist in our ArrayList already.
So then only we can edit our playlist, right?
So by the public boolean.
And let's call this as add song to playlist.
So we can only add those songs to the playlist that already exist in our album.
And that makes sense because we cannot add the songs to the playlist, which doesn't even exist in our
album, right?
So the first thing is we need to check for the.
Track number.
So we will pass the track number here.
And the second thing is going to be a link list.
Link list as that means what playlist we are going to add the song.
So link the list is basically a data structure which will, you know, have a reference of the next
element and the previous element so that what makes sense while creating this playlist player app.
We need to keep that.
What's the next song is?
And one of the previous songs we are going to use a linked list and this link list is going to be of
type of song and let's call it playlist.
This is going to be a playlist.
And here the first thing that we need to track and we have to convert this track number to an index.
So index have a zero indexing.
The next our zero indexing system and but track number have one indexing system that it will start its
numbering from 1 to 3 and so on.
But index is start is numbering from zero.
So zero one, two, three.
So and index is equal to track number minus one.
So here we have this index and we have to track that if a fast track number and everything is valid
or not.
So if index is greater than zero and no at the same time indexes less than.
Equal to the list on the size of the song.
So this song's got size.
So index lies between zero and the size of the song.
Then only we can add.
That thing to our playlist.
So in that case, playlist, which is a link list, not ad.
And here we have to add whatever the song is in the list.
So this dot songs now we have an access to a list and we will get the next.
Which will have a return type of song.
And here we have to pass in the index itself.
Here and it says so we'll pass the index so it will red zone and which is already present in our ArrayList
to our created display list.
Right.
So if we are done with this, will simply return true.
Return true.
And else we have to see that this album does not have a song with this track number.
So after this outside if statement.
We will print system, not our doctrine telling the Sultan does not have song with the track number
and whatever track number it is, we will simply return false after this rate.
So return false.
Oh, here we have Muppets which are fine song this one and fine song, then the add song and then add
to the playlist which have a track number and a linked list as playlist want.
The next thing that we need is also have to create another method.
Add to playlist that takes a title of the song as an input.
And again, Links Link List, which is the playlist itself public and put it on type as a boolean as
well.
Then add to playlist that same name to playlist.
And here the inputs are the basically we have to see methods but different parameters inside it.
So user can either add songs with the track number and playlist and either we can title and the playlist.
So we have a string title of the song and the next thing that we have is a linked list of a song as
well.
So song and let's again call it playlist.
And here what we need to track is that of the song already exist in our album.
That song already exist in in our album or not so we have to it so far let's use the enhanced for loop
and let's call it a song song and track song inside the list.
So this start songs and here if.
This song already exists in our list.
In that case, only we can add to our playlist, right?
So if the song don't get title and this thing is equal to the end title, which is title, if this exist
in our album, then only we can add it to our playlist.
So playlist start and tag this song and we are going to add that song with just that song and run through
because our operation is successful and outside this for.
Outside this fall, you will have to prove that there is no strong title and it is there no such song.
So an album will return false.
So here, this is all about the album we have created and a constructor.
And here this is all about the album and the constructor.
And then we have find the song which will return the song that we have entered as a title under the
knowledge there is no such song.
And then we have this method called Add song, which will first check that the song already exists in
our title novelist.
And if it doesn't exist that we will simply not add that song.
We cannot add that song because it already exists, and else if it doesn't exist, then simply add that
song to our album.
And then we have this add to playlist method to add the song, which is already present in the album
to the playlist, because then only we can create a playlist if that song already exist in the album.
And here we have two similar method, right?
We have two similar matter, same name here, one which has a parameter of track number and then the
playlist and where we have to add, which is a linked list.
And the second method is which the string is parameter and the list a linked list where we have to add
it.
And this thing is again called playlist.
Now if the song already exist in the album, then add it to the playlist.
I'll simply print.
No, here, no print.
No.
And here in this matter, we have to check for the track number that and the track number is valid or
not.
So now we are done with the album class.
So what next we can do?
We will create our another class and will name other object.