So now we are going to develop our first quarter on the steps of development is understanding what is
the things here.
So this project is, we can say deployed in two parts.
First, we are going to create one console or console thing here, which is basically console application
for Java to understand different algorithms and how the encryption work.
After later on, we will discuss the solid part which Java application we can see, which is providing
encryption and decryption interfaces.
So once this idea homepage, if you are loading to the previous projects, you have to customize that
part in the preferences.
I set it to welcome page always.
So new project here.
Will you mean the new project window for you?
There may be no lack.
There is some lag deploying this for me.
Or just taking time to plan new projects.
Okay.
So for me, new project is started.
It will do one thing I choose.
Previously, Marvin.
So we don't want Marvin.
We required your Java project.
So let it be loading.
It is detecting Zika for me.
So choose Java project.
Your GDP -16 .0. 116.
Virgin hit next.
Don't do this it next.
These are some settings but you mention here.
Encryption key command line interface
encryption seal damage this.
And finish.
So it will take time to create a new project for me.
So if you want to check different things related to cryptography, you may check on Internet.
There is a lot of information available for different algorithms, but most common algorithms I already
told you and I already shared the previous information about cryptography, how it's important for different
purposes.
So wait for some time to choose its best settings.
It will create the source folder, everything for me and wait for some time to ID work on this.
So he's working for me now.
First, I'm not going to look good directly.
I'm going to create here two things.
First is mine is for how the key is generated.
So let us see how actually key generation part works.
How is actually he thinks working here and what is the basic things I'm going to explain here?
So let us take to that part and let us first create that part.
So let me mention one thing here, which is I'm going to create one class here.
It's.
Okay.
So wait for some time to response the ID.
It will automatically detect your parts and everything.
So in the HRC folder.
Go to the H.R. sitting here.
What did the HRC click new and choose your new class?
So for me, I'm sitting to the symmetric as my class name.
There should be one public class.
So you mention symmetric.
Hit Enter.
It will create one class for you.
For me, it's symmetrically symmetrical.
So it will take time to create your own class and routines.
So once you go to this, you can check your symmetric classes created.
And now let me minimize this because this is no longer required.
Okay.
So this is my asymmetric class, which is going to have some class which is going to create a key for
me.
So for me, I'm for this video only or this tutorial.
What I'm going to create, I'm going plus to create.
You mentioned.
So to kill it
then if we mention one string, I'm using your algorithm.
So A is let me mention.
But before that, it should be fine.
So let me mention public static finally.
So why I'm mentioning.
Only if not for the public.
So why am mentioning this?
It's final.
No one can change this.
So I want to stick it to that pot.
Then I'm going to create one function.
To create one secret.
I am going to create one function to store the secret key.
Understand why I used your aye aye aye is as final note being your cubicle function to create symmetric
security.
Why I mentioned is final because a is my algorithm.
Let me mention algorithm for.
Encryption.
For encryption.
Uh, this is my final algorithm, which is an advanced encryption algorithm I'm going to use.
Then let me mention one function.
Public static.
Cigarette.
In.
Complete static secret key.
Secret key.
Or there is one default thingies.
Three eight.
It.
Is a.
With so many around us so old and so why I used your old tender crypto java crypto secret key is going
to use here or now it should.
Pros.
Perception and dimension, because if there is exception, it should throw some exception.
Then I'm going to create new instances of insecure, random class.
Create new instances musically, object instances for new classes, which is basically secure random
classes.
And you can mention glass also.
Then maybe no later, you will understand why you're developing this so secure.
Random.
I'm going to mention secure.
Random as secure.
Random.
Secured random.
Is equal to new.
Security.
So this is my object for secure random team, which is going to create random class for me passing the
string to key generator.
Now what?
I required passing string to create generator.
Passing string.
I need to pass the string.
Key generator.
So passing string key generator is very easy.
There is one default function here.
Key generator, key generator ignition.
Again, key generator is equal to new key generator.
And I need to mention the algorithm also.
So what is my algorithm here?
He used only.
But you know, I need to mention here instances why I need instances.
So for the purple key generator, which algorithm I'm going to use, I need to mention that get instances.
So.
Violet is for me.
Okay, let me.
This again.
New generator.
Get.
U.S..
So there might be.
Look, I need to.
Don't want to space.
There is no role of new because I'm not creating any instances.
I'm mentioning directly instances here.
So.
No, no.
That you need to specify a new thing here.
Then I need to mention the initialize the key generator.
Initialize E gen.
Kitchenaid's Kitchen.
I'm mentioning here with 256 to 56, which I'm going to initialize.
So that's a database which is going to convert to 56, which means it's going to randomize the 256 bits
directly.
Then what I'm going to do is keep generation initiative.
So it's very easy to generate a dot in it to 56 to 56.
This is my key size.
Now.
Not with this only I need to mention which algorithm secure random need to mention secure random.
So now what will be happen?
256 with randomize time is going to check not any patenting.
Then I need to mention secret key.
Security.
With which instance?
Secret key as my key.
Key part for which purposes.
Let me mention a small key device.
Which which radar key generator with key e generator with generation of key which is basically generate
key.
So it will generate key for me.
Now it should return foreign.
So no, you shouldn't understand.
So this is the method for creating the key generation part and everything.
So in the next part, I'm going to create and I'm going to summarize this because this is not completed,
but it's just instances of this algorithm, which is I'm going to create class to create three with
symmetric.
So it will randomize things and I will tell you how it's going to work.