So previously we have seen we have a few new variables for the enemies.
And here I have the IndyMac's enemy health.
Now, what happened next thing?
Now, every time we go on an attack or going to combat with an enemy, it's going to randomly generate
the amount of health they have.
This is going to be the maximum amount of health they can possibly have.
So the number is going to be from zero to this number here.
And I'm going to go ahead and set this to be let it.
I think let's set it to 70.
But again, you can play around with it.
You can set these to pretty much any numbers you want so you can see how it works and when you change
them.
The next thing we need is the attack damage for the enemy.
We need to know the maximum attack damage or the maximum amount of damage an enemy could do to our character
when we are going.
So let's go ahead and call this enemy attack damage.
So here the next variable I have in.
Enemy attack damage.
And I will set it to the, let's say, 30.
And for example, we don't want our character dying too quickly.
So now that we have set up the enemies, we can go ahead and see player variables.
So we are going to stop some player variables here.
So the next thing I will go ahead and start with the command here and leave that to player variable
here.
And so here, first of all, we will have the health of our character.
So here I will write in health and I will set it to 100.
So you can use whatever values you like.
And we can set our players attack damage.
How much damage we can do to enemies.
So we can go ahead and to our guide to more damage to the enemies they can do to us.
Then we will go ahead.
And so here I will write.
The next one is the attack damage here.
And I will set it to.
25 years and the next two more variables we want and we want to keep fighting as long as possible.
So for that, we want our person to be able to heal up.
We are going to make something which we need is the health potion, the health potion, the mechanic.
We are going to make it so.
Our enemies are going to make it our character and can then have a health potion.
If he or she learn health and he or she, the player, can go and can get some more health aesthetics
and for that.
So we are going to go ahead and right here in num name it as the health potions here.
And this is going to be the number of health potions that are that our character starts out with.
So this is the health our player starts with.
So this is attack damage of our player.
And so the next thing is the amount of the health potion.
So here I will set it to.
Let's save for and next thing which we need the amount of health potion that our player will start with.
You can go ahead and add comments to the side of each of these.
So here I will write.
The next one is we need.
Health ocean he amount 30 to 30 year.
Ann helped push and set it to drop chance here and just put it with the 50.
And here it will be.
The other player will start.
And you can go ahead and I will add the comment here of tip percentage so it can easily remember which
ones they are.
So we need two more variables for these, the health question here.
So these are the other variables that actually give some static so to them, so we can say integer health,
ocean amount.
So this will be the amount of health the portion heals.
So for go, I have created and set it to the 30 and we can have one final integer health portion drop
chance.
And here I set it to the 50 and we are going to make a and so every time you kill an enemy, there is
a certain percentage chance for them to drop a health potion.
And I'm going to go ahead.
And here I had set it to the 50% and I will just add a command and see here the percentage because it
may not be obvious.
So the half, 50% means the chance to drop a health potion.
Or 50% not.
But again, play around with these numbers.
You can make them whatever you like.
This is going to work either way.
So now what we know, what we need is we need a boolean variable.
We are going to call this running.
The next variable, which we need is a boolean variable.
And this set it with the running name here and just write that to the true here.
And because not this running variable is going to be a part of a while loop, so it's going to be the
condition for a while loop.
So the game is going to keep iterating over and over until we tell it to stop or tell until some conditions
are met so that the game has to stop.
So we are going to go ahead and add our system, dot out.
And I will write.
System.
Not our friend Alan here.
And under this I will write.
Okay.
So here.
Here we are going to give a welcome message for the game.
So this means our game is start so we can see what we can say.
Welcome to the adventure game or the menu because the name of our game is Dungeon and this will be the
start of our game.
So here we are going to go ahead and say so.
Here firstly, we are going to say.
Guest.
Welcome.
Through the Dungan.
And so here it will show the start of our game.
And the next thing which we need is the game label here.
And it will show that while running and now we need a wide loop where the whole game happens.
Before we go into the loop, we are going to add one thing here.
I had added this is the label.
We need this because I'm going to go her and here I have right to team and then the colon.
So what I have done we have.