In previous thing I already told you, we created one email application and we are processing closely
with that part.
So what we have done yet is we created one index or GSP.
If you want to check whether how it's looking or anything, what you can do, you can just go here.
You can check here the options and.
You can check for that purpose.
We're web servers or.
Is config if their servers are not configured, you have to check for the web server configuration for
that purpose.
So currently no service is running for me.
So if you want to check, you can go to the settings and you have.
I'll check for the server, but this is for JSP page.
So go.
So was.
So you can check for that here also so you can check for all these.
So this is our JSP.
But.
So this file which is formatted to send.
One email application with some table size and I'm adding some here.
So remember this op ego is just from this plant.
So this is my class where all the solids are going to work.
So this is my class I already prefer or I already told you about this.
So in this class, what I'm going to do, I'm going to create one method to handle request and response
everything.
So what I'm going to do is notice once this is constructor is closed, I'm going to create one method
to handle request.
And they request.
And just spots.
So what is the handling request or response inside any class of HTTP servlet?
I need to get to methods.
If you do post and you get which are very popular.
But in such case there is no required like do post method.
Because I'm not forwarding anything or I'm not doing any complex application I'm proceeding with only
do it.
So what I can do protect it.
You can use us public also, but remember I am giving particular way to get this is the method basically
to get inside this to get what I'm going to do is it's ETB.
You insist, so I can choose for my response and everything.
So response and depend.
Yeah.
Then what I want to mention is here.
So let me do one thing here is GDP.
So it's not a response or GDP, solid response.
I forgot to add, Stevie.
It's a solid response.
So so response.
This was an introductory solid request also.
So you can take four years to be solid.
It was.
What?
Only I can lose this horse because it's no longer required.
Giovanni Lapin.
And we are done.
Yes.
But.
Oh.
Now I need to handle it.
Request dispatcher And also so let me do one thing.
Let me minimize this so I can display this all.
So if you know there is one request.
DISPATCHER So you can refer any name here.
As I told you, I'm going with already.
Which is really common in the case dispatcher.
So it's a request.
Don't.
Get request.
DISPATCHER So it's basically going to fetch the string part.
So which string part is going to lose index?
So in this dot GSP.
Oh, now we are done with this.
So what is going to do it is going to fetch all the data as a string format from next door GST.
So this is basically you can say the location of my index dot is PM providing.
So remember always handle any exceptions through work exceptions, you might find your first servlet
exception.
So that exception Java solid exception.
Plus if I'm not providing input and output I.
Oh, exception.
So that's it, I'm going to tell you.
So now why am I here?
Sometimes in you may not get any exception here or you may not get any error.
But by the user, if I'm not providing any input output, then this will not proceed.
So for that purpose, I'm putting this exception.
I'm handling the exception to print that part.
Then our forward.
Response.
Request response in
response.
I'm going to handle this request in response.
So this is just a method to do anything.
So.
Right.
Okay.
First I will get request and then I will get response.
So I made an error.
We just don't know this is done because remember in the foreword, first is request, then response.
There is no first response from the server.
First is request always.
So you put here first.
Is always.
Nyquist any solid part.
So the solid but remember this is just getting part out we can see fitting data.
If I want to put any message, I also need to do post method.
Remember while posting a message.
I need one.
What's the matter here?
So.
I will put your get method.
So let me put one matter to bring.
So message to.
Page.
So this is.
Post mortem.
Similar thing, protected void.
The Post.
If you know HGTV, Solarte is also.
Request.
So let me do one thing here.
Let me copy this part, because it's as it is.
No need to change anything.
The two post and the gate method remain the same and it throws this again.
I have exception and everything.
So why it's showing I exception.
I will tell you while developing any application you may find that part.
So what is going to ask her?
It will ask or what is going to fetch?
It is going to fetch.
It is going to fetch some data.
So which data stream email first.
So if you know request dot get get parameter if you know the thing this get parameter as a string it's
going to fetch.
Stringer's image is going to fetch.
So let me copy these things again and let me tell you what I'm going to do.
So this for this, then this is just to send an email which receiver's email then subject for this purpose
I'm going to put here, subject.
Subject is basically anything but your title of your email and body, so you can put anything here.
I'm putting as the message here message and this change also message.
So which are these strings, emails, objects?
And if you don't know, let me show you while putting this I gives the name here.
This is email, fish, email, subject and message.
So I created a connection here and I am now fetching this data as my everything.
So let me do one thing.
I can create an operation in Heroes.
So let me tell you why I'm putting operation.
Because by entering and accepting that in email application, once you put that part, request out,
get parameter.
And it's operation.
So I'm mentioning operation here.
Oh, let me show you.
Operation this operation.
So I need to create this op and everything.
So now.
So these are done.
But email.
We go, which is basically same thing here, but equals which is basically going to equal signal case.
It is going to ignore the cases or be.
She basically this OPI in the case is higher ground with that much on that part.
Now I'm going to set some messages in here, then I'm putting some things here.
So let me just copy these things and I will tell you what is the significance of this and what I'm going
to do here.
Get me a copy of this piece just so you.
I haven't created this part.
So what is going to do it, will?
I'm going to create an email message class here, which is going to handle set two sets, object, set,
message, set, message type part, which is basically HTML page is HTML message.
I'm going to mention here.
So all the things is consist in this email message part with email utility and it's going to send that
message.
So it's related to all these part, but I haven't mentioned this part.
So let me do one thing.
Let me handle this first, which is basically request.
Set.
Attribute.
Request.
Dot.
Set attribute.
First, the string.
String is message.
And what I'm going to mention is your mail.
Has been sent.
Successfully.
So once this is sent, what it will be do it will print this in that HTML part or we can say JSP part.
So I'm going to do this part later, but I just copied this and I already created this part.
I will tell you, what is the significance of this letter?
It is the main function to send any email here.
So this is done in e loop.
Now let me handle request dispatcher because dispatcher or d only is equal to request dot get request.
DISPATCHER get request.
DISPATCHER which is basically string indexed dot JSP is just that location which is single location
I would prefer and r d not.
Forward.
Request slash.
Response.
So now we are done with this male client.
So male client handling is very simple.
It will handle some it will ask for and fetch the data handling that JSP part.
It will do.
It will handle that part.
This email message is going to work with male client.
So considering if I told you earlier how my SMTP is going to work, I will tell you later.
But what this class is just doing it just like act as a fetching the data from that justified because
we are putting in JSP but we as a user we know that that we are putting in that mail client but we don't
know how the backend works actually.
So that's the backend part.
First, this mail client going to fetch data in further tutorials, I'm going to tell you how I am going
to create.
I am explaining the SMTP port also how it's going to work each and everything.
Plus I'm using here at Gmail as my SMTP.
I'm again telling you, if you are familiar with other SMTP services, there are a lot of SMTP services
available on the internet.
You can check through free SMTP services also works, so you can use that part also.
But I'm going with Jim.
Hope you understand this.
Thank you.