So in this video, we will be talking about the next two Java files of this project.
Those will be the Splash Star Java and Log in Java.
So Splash Java will be the first file which we will run when we will run our project.
After that we will move on to our login page, then to our main page.
So a splash stored Java file is basically just a Java file which we have created for the better representation
so far, which what we did is we have imported here Java dot dot strict class which will help us to
create a better graphical user interface as it is abstract window toolkit in build package provided
by the Java.
Similarly, we have imported the Java Export Spring package also to use its inbuilt classes and methods
for better graphical user interface.
After that, we have defined the class a splash.
Then we have defined its main method.
Inside the main method, what we are doing is as a frame we have created as frame type of object F one
and new as frame or actually the frame class we have defined here, this is the class.
So we have created the object for this class as frame type of object f one and passed the argument test
payroll system free license version 2.2.
That's for the reference only you can write anything here f one dot set visible is equals to true two.
So the first for this visibility will be true for that frame.
And we have defined the variable I and another integer variable x is equal to one.
Now we have iterated over these two variables I and x and set the F one dot set location with this calculation.
Now what this calculation does is this will open the menu or a window of the frame with a.
Some speed and incrementing at a particular speed and F1 not set size.
So size will be I plus x comma I.
So this will iteratively increase the size of that window till the perfect size for that purpose we
have used it and try is it close to thread thread dot sleep ten.
So what it does it will create the.
Closing of the window and the opening of the window for that every 0.1 second.
So actually 1000 will be for the one second.
So one zero will be 0.0 1 seconds.
So it will close and open the window every 0.01 second.
And in the catch block we will be handling any exception if occurs.
Now let's have a look at the class frame.
So class has a frame which is extending the frame and implements renewable interface.
Inside which we have defined a thread type of instance.
Stephen And then we have defined its parameterized constructor as a frame which is taking our argument
of a string as that's why when we have created the instance of that string class, we have passed that
argument.
Payroll System Free License Version 2.0.
After that inside the super, we have passed that a string which we will be passing to it.
It's constructed during coddling.
And so that construct, that value will be at the heading of that window.
After that set, layout is a new flow flow type of layout.
Then inside the image icon variable, see, when we have imported the image from our source of the image
by passing the location of that image.
After that, inside the image instance, even we have a scale that is scaled the size of that image,
which was previously in C one with the help of get image.
And we get a scaled instance.
After that, we have a store that is scaled.
Image object in our new image icon, which is a two then in the label RM one we have restored that image
icon two.
After that we have added the label, added the that label to our frame and initialize the table is close
to new thread and past the current instance of class into that thread.
Now to even start.
What it does is it will start the thread.
After that, there is a public wide run method we have defined, which is a method of the enable interface.
So inside the tribe log, what we are doing is thread dot sleep 7000.
So the thread will sleep every seventh second and this dark side as well as equals to false after that
login f one is equal to new login.
So after that completion of the run, we will be moving the window and closing the window to the.
Login page.
So this will after in the catch block, we will be handling exception if any occurs.
So that's all from the splash class.
Let's have a look on our the next class, which is login class, which will appear after the running
of this class.
So let's have a look at login class.
Here is the login class.
So inside the logging class we have imported the packages like Java or JWT District for the graphical
user interface, a DOT event or district for the event handling over the buttons Java string for better
graphical user interface and Java SQL for connecting with our database.
After that we have defined our class login, which is extending frame and implementing action listener
interface.
After that, the label is L1 L2.
So we have defined the two labels and after that there is a one text field, one password field and
two buttons.
So the two labels will be storing the that username value password value.
After that one text field will be storing the enter value from the user and the password field will
be storing the enter password from the user.
Then there will be two buttons.
One button will be for the login purpose or b two button, which will be for the closing purpose for
cancelling purpose.
Now we have defined the non parameterized constructor and its heading as login page.
After that, setting the layout as border layout.
Now we have defined the J2 is close to new J password field size will be ten and we have defined the
text field even as equals to new text field size is ten.
Now inside the label we have defined J label and new image icon class for the quad get system resource
from this pig.
So this so this label will be storing the pic, which we will be adding in this label.
And after that we have defined the B1, which will be new button named as submit and we are adding that,
adding an image also on that button that is a login image.
So that button will be also having an image.
And similarly for the button B to cancel, it will also have an image whose path have been passed as
argument inside class load or get system resource.
After that we have added action listener over these two buttons p one point add action service and B
to dot add action listener.
Then we have defined our four panels.
We won't be 23, 34.
After that, we have defined these four panels b1, b2, p three, p four.
Then we have added.
Hell with the border out west.
So L.A. is restoring the image icon.
That's the label which we have added to our frame.
After that there is ap2 dot add new j label username.
So inside the panel p two we are adding the new J label labeled as username and adding the text field
on that panel also.
Similarly in the p top panel, we are adding a new J label as password and adding the D two tech password
field in that particular panel.
After that, we have added that panel with the Border Layout Center in our flow layout frame.
After that, there is a penalty for which will be.
Inside which we have added our button, B one and V two also then we have added that p four panel in
our frame with border layout dot south.
Now we have set the size of the frame as 400 comma to 50 and its location as.
600, comma 400 set the visibility of the frame as true.
After that, what we are doing, we have defined the action performance method with the action event
object and inside the tribe log.
We have initialized the connection with our database first with the help of our com class and after
that we have defined a string you is equals to one point get text.
So what this line will does, it will take the text or the entire value from the user and store it into
a string view.
Similarly for the string via restored the password field as well.
So two point get text will restore the password field the entire password from the user in our string
v and after that is in a string.
Q We have written the query select aspect from login where username is equals to you and password is
close to you.
So what this string does, it is creating a query which is select a string from login and inside the
login table it will check for the username and password.
So if there is any record for which the username and password will match, so then it will be executing.
Oh.
And taking as the control of the program to the new window.
That will be window of the new project class.
After that, with the help of results.
At instance, we have executed that query by passing it to the asked execute query method as an argument.
Then if asked next.
So if asked next quarter.
Does it will fetch the record for.
For the particular username and password if it match.
If it does not mind, that does not match.
Then it will return null.
So if it it will, it will return null.
So the if block will not be executed.
So if it matched, then we will.
What we are doing is we will be calling a new project instance and set the visibility as to.
After that we are setting the visibility of the current window as false.
So in the block, if the password and username not match, then we will be showing the dialog box that
invalid login.
Then we will set the visibility of the current window as false.
Inside the cast.
BLOCK We have handled any exception if occurring and inside the public static void main.
What we are doing is we have just created the instance of the our login class.
So these are the two classes which we have discussed in this project.
The first one was Splash or Java, which we did the very first class.
We will be running just for the better interface.
And looking after that we have defined the login class, which will be help to validate the data of
the user with the help of username and password, which will be validating the data from our database
table login.
So that's all from these two.