Hello, everyone.
So I hope you all have went through the introduction part of the noted down Java application that we
are going to read today.
So after getting through the introduction part, I hope that you have gained an insight of what we are
actually going to make in this project.
A text editor or something that we call it.
So to begin this project, we have to create a Java file.
Sorry, a Java project.
And then.
Start the project coding.
So let's get started.
We have opened the welcome page of Visual Studio code and then trying to write our code.
So.
On clicking this explorer icon.
We get the option of create a Java present.
So clicking on this icon, we will get an option of create our project.
We will click on this.
Then we will select No Beatles.
Remember, we have no need of Springboard Quacks or Micro Profile in this programme project.
So we will select no build tools.
You also have to select this in your system.
So yes.
Now we have to select a path for our project.
Suppose I want to create my notes down in my desktop folder.
So I will go in the desktop and select the project location as desktop.
Now clicking.
We get a text field asking or asking for an input, a Java project name.
So think about the name that you want your project to be named as and input in this text field.
So I want to name my project as noted down.
A folder, not a noun will be created if I hit enter here.
So name your projects carefully and then press enter.
So after hitting enter.
So we navigate to this folder not down here with some in-built folders inside it.
So you can see that this noted down folder contains this dot this dot virus called lib, which is for
libraries and and a CRC folder.
So the Farsi folder is the main part of.
Any Java project.
So if we open this, expand this ASIC folder, we get already an app that Java file is created.
So these are the invalid folders which are created after hitting the Create Java project option and
opening this approach Java file.
We get this thing on our screens.
So this approach, Java is basically a class of Java.
This class is named as app inside this class we have.
A main method.
Which contains which is access specified as public.
So any class can access this throughout this project.
And inside this we have a string argument passed.
So what?
This function will return our string, of course.
So when this function is called, when an exception is thrown, this part of the project is outputted.
Helloworld.
So what is the exception?
You may be wondering.
An exception is that type of error which arises under runtime in any program.
So suppose we are running this program and there is some error.
So this exception will throw this.
This part in the console that whatever we want to write that suppose we want to write it asks whether
we can write it anything.
By default it is written as helloworld.
So yes, if the program is any exception, this is called as an error.
So if I run this part or whenever this part is called.
Yes.
So it displays error.
So exception handling is one of the powerful mechanism to handle the runtime error so that the normal
flow of application can be maintained.
It is very difficult to find the box on your own.
With the help of the compiler, we can know that on which and on which part of the code, we are getting
the error and it becomes easy for us to debug this and run the code again to get our successful output
or to program what we want to run it as.
So after this.
We are going to create a node node loan application, so we will create a new file.
In that sassy folder itself and name it as not.
But not Java.
So this is the name of the file.
I am going to create Notepad on Java and this file will going to display the main window of the application
that we discussed in the working part of the code.
So after hitting enter a notepad class is already created.
So we want a class named as notepad.
Now we want a frame inside which the notepad application is going to be consistent.
Store.
We have to import the libraries for creating the functions.
Yes.
Let us import the Java String Library, which is going to give us components like free panel and so
on.
We have many other packages inside the string API.
So yes, importing.
Java X string.
Yes.
So this asterisk here denotes that we are going to import all the classes and components of this string
package and currently it is gray as we haven't used anything from it.
Once we will use it, it will automatically change its color.
Now inside the notepad class, we are going to extend that clear to J frame.
Yes.
So this frame is a component inside the Java String Library, so you can see it in the suggestions.
So yes, we have imported.
Swing Library and use a different component from it now.
Inside this notepad class we are going to create a constructor.
Or we can say that we are going to invoke a method called Notepad inside this.
Now.
Suppose that we want to give our title to the app, so calling it to set title.
And think about a title like yes.
For me, the title goes as noted down.
We have started the title for our programs.
Program.
Sorry.
And yes, I missed a race after this.
After creating any constructor, we have to enclose everything inside races.
After setting the title, we are going to set bounds like there is a height and width for the frame,
so we have to decide it how much wide and how much longer we want it to be.
So I am setting bounds.
Yes.
A rectangular one?
I think so, yes.
I suppose you can create any size you want.
Now for him to be.
600.
Yes.
So.
I have created bonds.
Now I am going to.
Set the default close operation like on exiting the program's close.
The window is going to close automatically.
So setting default close operation.
I have to write set default close operations and.
But they should be closed on invoking this method.
Exit on clothes?
Yes.
So the suggestions are life.
So that said, default close operation is going to close the frame when we exit the program.
Now let us try to run this and see what output it is going to give.
But before running the program.
Firstly, we have to create a function which will be responsible for running this notepad class.
So creating a public class.
Collector's men, and the arguments inside will be a string.
Yes.
No.
Setting this.
New notepad plus.
Setting the visibility of these classes through.
We have to call set visible.
Yes.
Set visible.
And it takes automatically a boolean argument.
So we want to see the application.
So we are setting this visibility to.
True.
Now let's try and run this class and see what output we are going to receive.
So perfect.
We have created a frame.
Yes.
So these are the dimensions for this frame.
The name in the title.
And when we click on the close, it will automatically close and exit the notepad.
So perfect.
We have created the wide frame of this program, a mainframe which we inside which we are going to.
And all the components to be performed for editing, writing and saving our text documents.
Now, in the next part, we will learn how to earn nav bar items such as file, edit, health and what
these buttons will consist of.
So see you in the next five.