In previous videos or in previous project steps.
What we did is we created a one class email class.
We created one scanner class which is public.
Always remember the scanner is global.
I will write here also.
Global.
This is global.
You can use this all in this project.
Then these are private.
These are strings.
Also are global.
You can use this inside this email class and we are going to use it inside this class also.
So all these are about creating class.
We already created this class.
Now we created one constructor to receive first name and last name.
Now, what is the significance of constructor is if I am putting here only these parameters I'm putting
here, it is not like abstract or something you can you are using that class and you are not securing
it.
Anyone can change that part like your private if name for first name or last name, they can change
So significance of this is creating constructor is to receive first name and last name and protect that
from original one, which is private string and first name and last name.
So let's move further.
Now, in this constructor, what I'm going to do.
I'm going to assigning this f name to this F name.
To do this.
What?
We are going to use this keyword.
This dot f name.
Is equal to F name.
Similarly for this also like this last name, Elin, basically.
A name is equal to a name.
So what happened is.
You can see this and these are equal now.
So it is not just forwarding the value.
It's copying that value from here to here when we are going to run this program.
No.
I'm going to print output system.
Not out.
Not print a line.
Inside this, I'm going to bring like new.
Employee.
Let's.
This board is named.
Unless I'm going to do some small gap year in between and then this dot.
And.
So we are done with constructor.
Now inside this, we are going to develop more in this one sector.
So I am leaving some space here.
Now we are going to create some methods.
So from the PowerPoint and that template, we already know we want to create some email, generate mail,
generate password.
For that we need to create some methods.
So let's start with creating some methods here.
So let's begin with.
Some department asking the department and then password or.
Let's start with generating email.
Generic.
Me.
Okay.
Male method.
Now, remember, this should be private.
So I'm creating private.
It's not really that.
You have to always create it private.
You can create it public.
But to achieve the abstraction, I'm going to use private.
It's going to return string.
So string generate.
Email.
These are the same types of creating methods.
Now what?
It will return.
It will return email.
This format is this dot f name.
So if you are putting first name in capital and email is always in small letter to convert this to all
small letters, there is system default method or we can say user library to lowercase.
You can see two lowercase.
You can put two lowercase here.
So what it will do if you are putting all the capitals, even if you are putting all the capitals,
it will create to the small case.
Similarly, this dot we know.
Okay, okay.
Before that we need to put Dot here plus again this dot.
In Name Dot.
Bullock is.
Now we want to put your address in bold.
So it.
Oh.
Then this dot.
Department deputy.
Not again to lower case.
This syntax, as I told you about all the syntax here.
Let's now simply dot company.
Dot com simple remaining.
So what it will do, it will take first name, last name from user, and it will put with the department.
It's just letting them in.
Now we will move further.
So what we did is we created first method for we we are going to move in the second method asking for
department, asking or department.
Again.
Private, private string.
State Department.
Since we began putting in.
No.
I need to put some user interaction.
I'm not going to send directly you for that administrator.
It will ask which department do you want to put?
So I will put here first system.
Not all dot println.
Depart.
Department foods.
Then what it will be?
It will print department quotes, basically.
Likewise.
This one.
For sales.
Remember, selection will be put in the next line.
Next line for new line or for new line.
I'm putting slash in.
Development.
Oh, a third department I'm going to put is for accounting.
Accounting department.
And last time building zero for.
None.
Nothing.
I'm not going to mention here anything I'm putting here?
None.
So.
Now.
What I want to create some loop or what we can say to choosing part here that one, two, three.
So you can go with too many cases like switch case and something, but I'm going to use your switch
case you can use if else.
But using switch case is more efficient here.
So I will create one flag here.
Let me tell you why I'm going to use your flag.
Because I want to execute it again and again, like.
If.
I'm not going to execute it again and again.
It will generate only in first time.
Or we can say if you are entering first employee, it will ask I want to put form multiple in place,
so I want to create some loop.
I'm going to use your do y loop or y, I'm going to use do y.
Loop is very important here.
I want to execute at least one time and the do y loop will execute at least one time for other loops
like for loop for a loop for each loop or enhanced for loop.
In Java there is no like condition, there is not any condition.
It will move for one to but do y loop will run at least one time.
So I will put do here first do if you know the syntax do then I will prepare a system.
I'm going to ask like System.out.println.
Just.
And Department could.
So this is very simple back department code.
After that, I will create one.
The choice would be good choice.
No.
What I'm going to do this next end so you will understand.
What is this?
S.
S is this scanner part?
Scanner.
Scanner part.
So I'm going to use this to take user input.
Now switch.
Switch.
As.
Also the switch choice.
I would then kiss one.
If you don't kiss one.
Then since.
It's if it's putting the ideal condition, you have to break it.
But there is not any significance for this.
You have to put a brake statement here.
But I'm going to just returning this so it will return only in one time.
It will not.
Or again and again start looping inside the switch case.
So just returning the need, any break line here is three.
Return.
We do need a return.
Ofcom.
And if case zero return on.
No.
Guess.
Well, it is not the.
Okay.
This.
Border was, I guess, zero.
It would've been.
None.
That's it.
So we are done with this, but we are missing something.
Like we didn't want to exit that loop and we want to create some default conditions.
So we are done with our logic, but we are not done with our perfect code.
Let me complete that one part.
Also default.
I will print your system.
Dot, dot, println.
Invalid.
Joyce.
These.
Through.
Again.
Now we are done with this no switch case.
Now I will end up with the well.
So this is do part of it.
So I will put a file.
It's like.
So what did you do as flag is always false.
Not always true.
It will return null.
That's it.
So what it will do.
It will execute at least one time.
Written.
Not.
So.
Now we are done with this part.
As you can see what we did here.
Let me summarize this.
So what we did is we created one constructor, public email string, first string, last name with parameters
we.
Invoking it with this name, dot f name.
So what we are doing, we are going to assign this F name to this f name, this last name, to this
last name, and I'm going to print this here.
So now constructor part is not done.
We are going to create and invoke some other methods also there, but its initial condition for the
constructor.
Now I started with our methods.
I created first private string generated method.
So what it will be do it will do generating the mail according to our syntax.
So return this dot name dot to lowercase into dot, this dot or these are the lines.
So what is the significance?
These are f name.
It will look this f name here dot two lowercase.
It will convert all the strings into lowercase.
So no need to worry about uppercase and lowercase.
Then dot.
Then again this for last name and this for department.
These for the company dot dot com.
So it will generate that mail according to that.
After that I want to set department, but setting the department is all about the process from user
or we can say administrator.
So I will put here one, two, three and zero for the options sales development accounting respectively.
Then I will create one boolean flag to execute that loop.
I'm going to use your Dubai loop because it will at least run one time.
Again, the department code or choice I'm giving.
I'm using switch and switch.
Case method here.
Switch.
Case conditions you can use if l conditions also.
But it will take too much time to execute that to reduce time complexity.
I use switch choice case one case for case two for development and according to that default condition,
execute exiting that way, loop with the flag and returning.
So I created two methods generator mill and said department.
So now we are done with this.
So I will explain what is the significance of this in part also.
So this will assign the you understood that part.
So let's try it.
What is this part?
So let me show you.
What is this?
Significances.
So this is the this is the reference variable that returns the current object.
It gives states and behavior of the object.
It simply leaves global variable and class variable.
All the same.
You want to invoke it same, it will assign it and we just did it.
The global variable is different and class is also same for that purpose.
We just use this one.
If this is not used here, it will return null value.
If local variable and instance variable are different, there is no need to use if.
What difference are different?
Like global is different.
Class variable is different, but you want to assign it to is equal to is equal to.
You can do it, but name should be different.
So avoiding using different names.
I used your this keyword and this is very efficient.
Also, this can be used to invoke current class constructor.
What I did in this part to invoke the current class constructor.
So we will move further with another method.
Also here.
So let us see what other methods we are going to see.