Hello, everyone.
So in this series of Megan Java projects, we are going to make a new project again and going to add
this snake of really a game to your hit list of making Java projects.
We have already covered many projects.
Now we are going to make this project also.
So let's begin making the project in our favorite tidy Visual Studio code by creating a new Java project.
So.
Clicking on the file icon and clicking on Create Java project insert in the file icon.
So after clicking on this button, a popup asks for option that what are the tools we are going to use
while making this project?
So we have no use of this library.
So we will click on this mobile tool option and select this after which it asks for a path that where
we want to store our project.
So suppose I want to store the project inside my desktop.
So selecting the project location and then.
It asks for a name of the project.
So my choice of name says that I should name it as snake failure.
Feed the snake as we are going to feed the snake in this game.
So after inputting the name for this project, we have to hit enter so that we will enter in the frame
where we have a new Java project.
So after hitting enter.
So I have already a project named like this, so I will try something other like the snake.
Ofelia.
Yes.
So the folder will be named as the snake of failure?
So we are inside a new Java project with some inmate folders inside it.
We have the starting window where we have a dot vs code and dot based extension folder and we have a
lib and SRT folder.
So the SRT folder is going to be the core of this project inside a RC folder.
Only we are going to build the files required in this project.
The classes will be consistent inside this SRT folder.
Only the SRT folder already has a Java file which contains the app class which runs whenever there is
an exception in the application.
This file is for the handling the exception if the project is not able to run or there is any runtime
error in the project.
So we have already listed the factors of error handling, exception handling in the previous videos.
Also in the previous videos we have covered how to install this application and how to run the execution
of the compiler, the JDK and everything.
You can check those video if you already have no Visual Studio code and JDK in your system, and then
come here to make this new Java project, which we have created right now.
Okay, so we have successfully created the frame inside which the project is going to be made in this
compiler.
Now we have to import the requirements of this project.
Like I have already told you that we require images of Apple, which is going to be the object.
And for the snake we have to import images of dots.
We had an green dot or I can show you.
Yes.
So we have a green dot, red dot and this apple.
So we have to import these three images first to begin making this project.
So before going to start the programming path, let me import the icon.
So here we have an apple dot PNG folder, file a dot dot PNG file and a head dot being defined.
So this is inside this icons folder and I am going to drag this inside my SRT folder.
So here we have icon folder which contains a green dot.
I can zoom in.
Yes.
So it is an apple?
We have the green dot, which is going to be the body and the tail of the snake and the head of the
snake as a red dot.
So we have successfully imported the image requirements for this project.
Now we have to start making the project by creating classes.
So in order to create the frames, we have to create a class called Snaked Java as a new file inside
the folder.
And this is going to give us the snake class.
Yes.
So here it is.
Similarly for the board, this is the board which will set the frame.
So to make the board, we have to create the board Java file.
Inside the SA folder as well.
There is no other path where we are going to create the folders.
So yes, only necessary folder.
We have our icon, we have our app dot java file.
We have bought Java and Snake Java.
All the classes are inside this SABC folder only.
Now switching to the prototype which we already made for the project, we will check the points which
we have covered.
Like we have created the new Java project.
We have added the images to the project and now we have to start creating the frame.
So to start creating the frame, so the snake class is going to be the main file which will be responsible
for running this snake game.
We have created a board Java class also, so we have two classes.
Of course we can make it in a single class also, but the code will become complex and it would be difficult
for you to handle that.
What function is doing what?
So to make that things distributed, I created two different classes.
So to begin with the coding part, let's create a constructor called Snake and Inside which we are going
to add the functionalities, what the game is containing.
Now, just after creating the snake object, I am going to call this object inside a public static mean
function.
Public static void main.
And the argument goes as string art.
So yes, the object is created, the function is created, the object is going to be called inside this.
So we have created it.
And now.
Adding braces and inside which the frame or third part of the prototype was to create the frame.
So using the new keyboard, I am going to call the snake object, which we have just created in the
line number three.
Yes.
So the visibility is by default.
NULL or false.
So we have to set it to true to see the frame on our screens.
So we have set the visibility of the frame as true.
So it is showing an error.
So let us check what the error is showing.
While so we have set the axis specified as public, we have to change it to private.
So there it is.
Coming through.
Still there.
We have to remain the class access specified as public.
Let us check for the other way.
Like, Oh, this is set visible, not set visibility.
Some typos are such a headache.
So we have set the set visible to true.
Now let us import that we are setting the frame to true.
So firstly, we have to import the frame.
So that frame is inside the Java String Library.
So it is imported as Java X dot swing dot.
It is like all of the components are need to be imported.
So we are giving it asterisk.
So perfect.
Now that class has to cover the inside the frame.
So we will extend this class as a frame.
As the frame is the component of the Java String Library inside which we are going to create the application.
So we have extended this to the frame, imported the Java String Library and.
And perfect.
So we have created a frame we have set its visibility to.
True.
Now switch to the board dot java class.
So in the board class, similarly, we have to import the string package as it is needed everywhere.
So importing the string and after that one more package is need to be imported, which is AWP.
As string is built on the top of the WP Java dot, it is also needed with same importance for this project.
So Java, JWT and similarly the string as we have to use most of the packages components of this package.
So yes, we have created the class.
We will extend it to Japan.
Now, you may be wondering that we extended the.
Snake, but as a frame and we are extending this as a panel.
So there is a panel inside which the frame is to be consistent.
We can't put the frame, head and hair at the both places, which is not practically possible.
The program will give an error.
So we have created a panel inside which we are giving the frame.
So the board is a panel extension.
Now we will create a board object or constructor, whatever you wish to say it, and in the similarly
setting, the dimensions of the frame.
So set preferred side, we have to set a size from before the frame like if it is new.
X it's like the size should be ten as new dimension.
And removing this unwanted lines from the new dimension.
And suppose we want to give the height and width of the frame at 303 hundred.
So we have given the size us 303 hundred for both height and width.
This is unwanted.
So we have set the frame size.
303 hundred.
Now switching to the snake class and calling the board there.
So for calling the board there, we have to add a board object inside the snake object.
So the board object as new or not?
Not simply new.
The new board and the brackets and closing.
So let us try to run this and see what happens.
So the snake class is the main class.
We are going to run the Java program.
So yes, the frame is perfectly created.
You can see there on your screen the frame is created.
Now we have to open this in the full size window, like in the middle of the.
Page.
So adding.
One more line in the code which will responsible for doing so.
So we have called back and now we will try to run this and retain.
So perfect.
We have a full frame which we have created of size 303 hundred on running the Java for the snake class,
after which we have successfully created this.
Now we have to add the snake and the apple object image inside this frame, which we will be covering
in the next part.