In previous tutorials, I told you how we are going to create this project, which is basically every
project.
So this is our title page and I will create here.
Welcome to the.
So this is our name.
What I can do is like this.
Okay, so these are the basic names and.
I'm going to create two things here or library and login.
And another thing is admin login.
So first, create admin login.
Admin login is very simple.
As I told you, this is importing lavatories I will put here.
Including.
Libraries for the library, do post commentaries for the postings and I'm going to add some things like
admin log in form.
So we are remaining with now I will create one lab home which is basically going to the navigation page
again.
So let me create one Web page, which is navigation on this very simple page.
I'm going to create.
Let me delete this first and I will add that now home page.
So this is my navigation homepage.
So once this is clicked in this and it will go to this part now, I mean, it's basically the first
page of this form for going to index page again and Liberian and Liberian page and logo.
So I have to create logo admin part also here.
So let us see how we can create logout admin.
So it should be in servlet.
So let me mention that part also.
So let's.
Not.
As you can.
As you.
If you know this.
And also copy edition.
We'll put this again here.
So now let me create log out admin part.
Also let me control see this.
This should be the new logo in Finnish.
Finnish?
So this is my lobotomy.
I will do one thing.
I will optimize these inputs using star.
Then again, using.
Studying and.
Eugene, start here again.
So no need to do this.
No need to.
Require this part also.
New York process, request and everything is required here.
So there's nothing but.
Okay.
So this is my class and I'm importing languages now.
I'm importing one another library.
It is basically.
Java X dot servlet.
Dot annotations, basically because annotation is basically is overriding.
Annotation dot dot dot oc.
So now I'm done with everything.
So.
Let me add one thing here.
I did it with solid.
And so in this bracket.
What I'm going to mention is here.
So let's not.
Name is local.
So I'm done with this.
Now let me create one protected one.
What I'm going to do is.
I'm just going to.
Use defaulting in.
I don't want to waste time in this.
I will explain this, but it is very easy for.
If you know this part.
So it will do get a request and response.
It throws servlet exceptional exception.
That's it.
So let me do something.
Okay.
Now I'm going to mention request.
Not.
Get session.
This session, not invalidate.
So what it will be do.
It will be invalidated that session directly.
As you can see.
Where it will be.
Go the response.
Send direct redirect.
Basically.
Send redirect.
Where should we go?
Index dot html.
So that's it for the logo part.
Let me add your comments.
Including libraries.
Logout.
Return for.
I mean.
So now we are done with logout method of admin.
So now we required some more things, like we created an admin and you can see add library and view
library and log out.
So we need to create some form methods also here.
So this should be inside the servlet part only.
So let me create your also let me write this now why this is important.
I'm mentioning the location of this.
So.
Once I'm done with this, I will explain you.
What is the significance of this?
Okay.
So for this purpose, if you see here admin login, you can see there are different request, not footer
or HTML for the footer part.
So this is nothing, but it's ending of everything.
Then.
Now home is basically the navigation home, which is similar to the index page.
So when you need to require this also navigation admin for admin part and it is again HTML part only.
As you can see, collapsing and everything, but it's showing index rotation for this and all the library
and part.
Now we are done with admin login.
So I'm mentioning admin login as default thing here.
If you want to add some more admins here, you can add using LC part.
Also if you want to use, you can use switch case also methods here, but I'm considering only one part
here.
The index estimates for the index.
So let me open this admin.
This is admin.
Log in and.
Just now we created a logo remain part.
So.
I'm done with this.
Now let us see inside the that part.
We need an admin admin library and login forms.
Let me copy this part because I'm going to create a new servlet.
Or you cannot see the dialog box because it's another window recording.
But the thing is very similar.
You need to choose servlet.
You need to mention the class name, which is basically we copied name that part.
Then add information to deployment descriptor, which is basically XML.
You have to check that mark and click the finish.
Once this is done, I'm going to clear out this because.
We already gone through this.
So let me use this part.
So let me import one package is basically package solid because we are accepting that solid part.
Then.
Let me use this part again.
So I forgot to add so that also there.
God.
Okay.
Now, let me explain.
What is this?
So if I create a blog ad librarian form which library and form this basically tab, it should go to
the this part I level librarian form dot html.
Okay.
I understand.
So it is very simple.
It is just for part.
So let me create one HTML page for this admin login form.
If not, it will go to the navigation admin panel and putting that part again.
So new HTML page.
I will use this as an finish.
I'm creating new HTML page for this purpose.
So let me use some default template here, which is basically admin log in form.
And that's it.
So what is it, librarian?
It should be contained.
Name, email, address, password and mobile number.
So that's it?
We required here.
Let me save this and let me save this.
If you are not saving, you can see there is a black part here.
So this is admin login form.
I will again, I will optimize the inputs.
Because.
Optimizing imports is very important here.
If you want to describe all things, then it's no longer required.
But.
I'm optimizing the inputs and.
Importing heavily.
So now we are done with admin log in form.
So this is done.
But as you can see, this is admin login form and etc..
I as you can see there is one method is add level librarian.
So we need to create some add librarian method also to invoke that and put in the database because we
are going to use your database connection also.
So in further part, I'm going to tell you how we can going to do.
Always give full name for that purpose.
As you can see.
You can copy this from your also because it's in a solid package.
So copy this part and you can put here again.
Let me say this.
So now we are done.
Let me run this project first.
I will click clean and build.
So in the output window, it will take time to clean and build everything.
As you can see in the libraries, we added some files.
So let me add another jar folder also because we haven't had Java X Jar.
Let me add the Java X Jar also.
So now it's added.
And let me run this hourglass fish server.
So it will take time and it will be deployed on your web itself, on your web browser, through the
glass fishbowl.
Sometimes it gives the error that buildings fail.
Then there should be error in Java or something that you have to rectify that error first and then you
have to deploy that part.
So this is just we are doing with printing and we are facing the data.
But now what we are going to do, we are going to put that data inside the database.
But before that we need to create one user in the database, a different user.
If you want to use default user, you can use.
But I'm going to create another user for this.
As you can see, build is failed now while build is failed, as you can see here, module has not been
deployed.
Let us see what is different and why it is doing this.
So as you can see in admin librarian form, we created everything.
But there is something missing always.
Let me check now.
Admin each it is created.
Admin login form is created.
All things are created, then what is the missing part here is basically we haven't deployed every part
like you can see logout admin and we will leave it in solid.
So this is not done yet.
So we need to create this method also.
So in the next part I'm going to tell how we are going to create this part view library and everything.
So first, create one user, different user.
For this part I'm going with default user, but if you want you can create another user for database
and you have to execute some queries there because you need to execute that part and going to store
that part inside the database.
So in further videos, we are going to create each and every part here and I'm going to show how we
can execute this because we haven't mentioned some part here.
Lake View.
Lebanon is not declared so.
In the next part I'm going to create a view library and method logout method we already created.
So we will have a written method will be created there and we are going with that part.