Our log in Java file.
So it is defined inside the package airline.
As you can see, this is the package and inside which here is the log in or Java file.
So we have defined this file inside the package airline and we have imported the necessary packages
like JWT, which is an abstract mental toolkit which is being used to develop graphical user interface
test, top based applications.
Then there is a Java swing package, which is a modified version of Abstract Window Toolkit, which
is also used to develop attractive graphical user interface of applications.
Then there is an abstract window toolkit event.
Class.
Package.
Which is used to handle events in the login page.
And then there is a Java SQL package which will help us to create and interact with our database, which
we have created in our last video.
Now we have defined the class login, which is extending the frame and implementing the action listener
interface.
Then there are two labels, 11 and two.
There is a one text field element and one possible field data.
Then there are two buttons B1 and B2.
Now.
Here is the login.
Constructor, which is a non parameterized constructor.
Inside the constructor it is headed as log in.
The layout of the window is set to be null as default.
And then we have initialized the false label L1.
Labeled as username.
After that, we have set the bound for the label.
Of which first argument with the X and Y positions is starting position of the bound.
And second and third values will be width and height of that label.
Then we have added the label to our frame or window.
After that, there is another label named as password.
For which we have set mound for that label in which similarly.
X and Y values are 40 and 70 and width and height is 130.
We have added a to in our.
After that, we have initialized the text field, which is one.
Setting the tone for the text field.
X is 150, Y is 20, its width will be 150 and height is 30.
Adding the text field to our DJ frame with the help of a method.
Then there's the password field.
Initialized as a variable to.
Then we have set the bound for the day to.
X is 150.
Y is 70.
Its weight will be 150 and Hyde will be 30.
Adding the data to our frame and window.
After that we have added the image in our login page.
So we have defined the image icon ie one which will loading the image from the source.
By using class loader, get system resource and passing the location of the image.
The image icons are stored here in this icon folder.
As you can see.
Here is the second jpg, which we have used here.
So in the next line.
We have created.
Object of type image item, which is which is used to scale the height and instance from the image icon
object i1.
After that we have created another image icon object ie three to create an image with the.
Help of object.
I do.
And I too is holding the image with the correct.
Size.
After that we have initialized a label L three and added the image icon three to that label.
So this label will use to show.
The image.
Now, after that, we have said the bond for the label X is 350.
Y is ten.
It's worth will be 150 and height will be 150 as well.
Then we have added the label to our window and frame.
After that, we have initialized the button new button login.
Its name is login button setting the bound for the button where x is 40, y is 140 and width is 120
and height is 30.
Then we have set the font of the button.
One family is safe and one type is bold and the font size is 15.
I did the action list not for the button because button will be used to handle any event.
After that, we have set the background color of the button.
As black and for brown.
Color of the button as white.
Then adding that button to our frame.
After that, we have a button to.
Named as cancel and we have defined the bounds for the button where x is 180, y is 140 and its height,
width and height are one, 20 and 30 respectively.
Similarly, like log in button, we have set the font of the cancel button here.
Font family of serif and.
One type is bold and font size is 15.
Setting the background color of the button as black.
And for one third of the button as white.
Adding the button to our frame.
Then we have added action listener.
To our button be two because button will handle any event.
Next we have initial initialize the color of the whole window background color of the whole window as
white.
After that, we have set the visibility of the current window as true so that whenever we call the login
class, the window will appear.
Setting the size of the window that is 602 300.
That will be the size of the windows.
600 will be the.
We wait and 300 will be the height.
Setting the location of the window from which point the window will appear in the screen.
So X coordinates 600 and y coordinates 350.
That will be the location from which the window will appear in our screen.
Next function, we have defined here the action performed method, which is a method of action listener
interface, which is taking the argument action event, a inside which we have defined.
If a statement which is inside which we have given a condition that if the source of the event action
event is from the B1.
So this means if the B1 button has been pressed.
So let's check.
For what?
Think we have created the Beaman button.
So be one button is labelled as log in.
So this will be used to log in.
So if the log in button has been pressed, then we first create the connection with our database and.
After that, we will be fetching the username from the demon text field.
And.
Then and storing it into a string.
You and then we are fetching the password from the t two password field and storing it in a string.
We after that we have created a string.
Q Which is holding the SQL query.
That is select extract from login where username is equals to you and password is equals to read.
So this query after that we have using the results set object are as we have executed the query queue
by using the connection object C one and a statement object as and pass to the queue string to the execute
query so that the query will be executed.
And next statement we have defined another if a statement with the argument asked next.
So this will start next.
We'll iterate over the rules of the login table where the username and password match.
So suppose if the username and password does not match, the control of the program will not enter this
statement until the username and password matches from our database values.
So if it matches, then the then.
We will call the new mainframe class.
That here is a mainframe class.
Here it is.
We will calling this mainframe class to take us through to our next window and setting this visibility.
As to after that, we set the visibility of the current window as follows.
So the login window will be closed and the main frame window will be displayed.
We will be knowing about the mainframe below mainframe Java class in our next video.
Now in the statement, if the user name and password does not match us with our database, in this case
we will display our dialog box showing invalid login and set the visibility of the login window as false.
If any kind of exception occur, that will be handled by this catch.
BLOCK And now if the.
The source of the event is from to.
Me button is labelled as cancel, so that will be used to cancel the login page.
So then we will just simply call system dot exit zero.
This will move the control of the programme out of the programme and close the programme.
Now inside the main method is static void main.
We have defined or created just the login object.
So whenever it is called the login object will be created and constructor will be called so that everything
we have just defined inside the constructor should be implemented in our window.
So this is all about the login class, the first class of this project that is a line management system.
Let's have a look on the run how the window will appear.
So if we run this login page.
So let's run this file.
So that's how the window will appear.
This is the window.
Here you can enter the username and username or password.
That is the password.
If you click on cancel, it will move us back out from the program.
If you click on Login, if the details matches with the database, then it will take us to the mainframe
page.
Let's close this window.