We are developing an employee platform of web platform using spring framework and we already set up
our project with spring and we develop some code also.
Now let us see what is a hybrid framework, basically.
Hibernate is basically used for the database concepts which are basically object relational mapping,
but you can say it's not more related to the Java interface is more related to Java to database connectivity.
So hibernate frame.
So if you already know we have already gives Java database connections and servlet, we can perform
database like that back in part with Java.
But why?
Instead of using servlet, we can use hibernate first thing.
You can use injection dependency in hibernate plus.
It simplifies the development of Java application if if you closely look in a servlet code that you
can check that we are putting the dependencies directly, that that Java database and all the things
directly.
We are not performing as application properties, we are performing that database connection as a class
properties.
So there is a tight coupling between this if there is an error in something.
So our application will not deploy.
If we have some database errors so we don't want to on.
And also we are embedding the skill statements directly like Select Star and all the things, then inserting
things.
So that's a very difficult thing and it's not appropriate while developing all the what we can say database.
So it is an open source lightweight or an object relational mapping tool.
Plus it's hibernate implements the jpg, which is Java Persistence API for the data for the systems.
So what is the data persistence if you will default entries in database rows, relational database are
null.
So it will not accept that null database.
Basically it will accept only the valid databases hibernate.
Then you are empty.
So what is the r m doing?
It's a jbc api.
As it's interact with gcc api.
But it's for data creation, manipulation and data access.
So it is basically programming technique which maps objects to data stored in database.
And here you can closely look at this Java application and this is object.
You can select like we can create an object in Java application which passes through Aurum and which
goes to database.
If you closely look the servlet database and you see there is one separate API and its path is the skill
set throughout the skill set.
So we are eliminating that concepts, embedding the skill statements in Java.
We are excluding that part.
We are directly putting that and I will tell you what is the job here.
So JP is basically Java persistence API, Java, you can say here is Java object or database column.
So basically the JPA is you can say the persistence for the classes and interfaces.
So let us see in the ID part, we are going to perform different things.
So wait a minute.
Pick me up on sale properties first.
Can begin.
You can change the things inside.
So I'm changing the lighting.
Okay.
So for the proper visualization.
So currently we haven't employed any JPEG.
Currently you can see these are the list and I already created one interface for that purpose.
So this is just the interface I created.
Interface is basically just 100% abstraction which provides and dabbles in abstraction because I don't
want to anyone to change this part.
So I will tell you what is that gate employed by ID and what is the things here?
Basically so void save employee is going to save the employee ID and defaulting here then.
One thing I need to create one employee list.
So I mentioned your employee, but I won't mention what is the employee.
So if you want to check your persistence, you can install the plugin structures and you can get all
the hibernate concepts here.
Currently I'm not implementing any deep connection, so let us create one thing your model.
So as you can see, go to this model thing.
Basically.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to create one package here or.
Let us assume when package your new and I'm mentioning as package model.
It's.
Mentioning Neiman's model.
So as we can see this inside this, I'm going to create one class and.
Well, let me mention the class name and employee, because I'm going to do that employee.
And this I'm going to create one employee class.
I.
We don't require this to focus on this only.
Now let me create one hour import package, which is basically.
Java expert assistance, which is basically GPA.
What is distance?
Don't start because I'm going to implement everything here.
Then.
Currently these things are.
I think that will work.
But let me mention your database.
So it's very useful and easy, as I told you already.
No need to mention anything.
Just me.
You need to mention.
If an independent entity.
In the entity.
You should mention a name.
So even.
Intractable.
You've the name.
So in that database I'm going to mention name as MP employee.
As I told you already now.
Or you can see these things are done.
So what I'm going to do, this model will face the data from the database and we'll do the database
connection, basically.
So it's very easy entity.
Entity means in the database entity.
I need to mention table as MP.
I'm going to create that table inside the database.
So as I mentioned this persistence and table everything you can check your this logo will come so that
so mention it's a JPEG Java persistence which provides the database connection.
Now let me mention one thing I'd.
Heidi.
So it is nothing but to create the generate value and bring everything.
So.
These are the some default generated value you need to in your strategy.
Strategy.
As you can see, it's x x using for the strategy.
So it's a matter of basically strategy and we need to mention generator type ID.
Then Russian type identity.
So it will create one unique parameter identity.
And inside this unique dimension.
Private.
Long.
I.
So what is this thing?
So, as you can see, I created this ID access to that ID thing.
So I am going to create one ID thing inside table.
So it will face that data throughout that ID.
So no need to require to mention your.
What you can say is called statement select start from where everything so it will automatically detect
this is identity and identity party's ID.
So now let me mention the columns here.
Problem.
Column is first column I'm going to mention his name is equal to.
Horse name.
So remember all these names should be.
And again, private spring and spring.
First name.
That makes this possible.
So this will be the entity inside the database.
Now let me copy this part.
So why I'm hoping I will tell you or I'm going to mention it again.
Last name and email only.
I'm considering your last name.
Again, the.
Last name.
And again, I'm mentioning the third column here.
Mimi So remember, these entities should be same in the database.
Also you can mention the screen.
So.
Chicken.
Violence.
Of the database.
Fill this in my database.
And now what I need to mention, I need to create one gaiter and set the property.
So for this purpose, instead of putting again and again what you can do, read, press, insert to
insert the things here.
So for you, I think the it will create a one generate option.
So I don't know what is the different shortcuts for another system, but for Windows you should press
button, insert you can check through the keystrokes, also get trend setter, go to get trend setter
methods.
Then you need to create for everything getter and certain methods.
So choose everything and it okay.
Once you hit okay, you can see it will create all the glitter and certain methods.
So.
These things created.
These are my columns.
So let me.
The one thing.
This is public ID.
And after this I'm mentioning the columns and after this I'm creating a range of methods.
So let me mention get an.
Better methods.
So this is for gate and set methods.
So this should be public.
No need to change anything here.
These things should be public.
So this will face the data from the database.
So now we are currently saying these things are not deployed in anything.
So I will create and I will tell you what we are going to work here and everything in the later part.
But in the JPA, as you can see, you can check your upper classes.
These packages, this table is this no need to check for streamlined court log but in employee database
or you can say employee class we need MP as my table.
So let me close this because the CGP pallet and that's it.
You need to work around the GPA.
Also.
Now it's currently showing the food related problems because our code is not properly developed, as
you can see, because we haven't mentioned the gate employees and we make cuts here.
So in the later part, we are going to check what is the gate implementers, how we are going to perform
this, how we are going to it with MySchool.
So if you are developing on deploying on line server or on line server, you need an online database
for that.
So my recommendation is go with PostgreSQL, MySQL or MongoDB.
MongoDB is not a relational database.
So the again, these things are going to change in that database, but preferably go with my skill,
my skill.
So it will really help me help you understand.
Thank you.