So here is our login class, which is defined inside the package.
Travel.
Importing the necessary packages like Java Auditability, java dot string, java dot event, java scale.
And then we have defined the public class log in which is extending frame and implementing Excel listener.
After that, there is a private instance of a text field, a password field, and the three buttons.
Then we have defined the public login non press constructor, setting the background color of the frame
bounds of the frame.
Then we have defined the instance of panel setting background color of the panel layout.
Adding that panel to the frame and setting the layout of the panel.
After that, there is another label as user name setting the bound for the username whose location is
124 comma 18 and sizes 95, cross 24 and adding that label to the panel.
After that, there is another label labeled as password host setting the bound for that whose location
is 124 2124 and size 95 cross 24 and adding to that, our panel.
Then there are respective text field that is text field for the username setting bound for it adding
to our panel.
Then there is a password field setting bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there is another label which is the empty label setting bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there's another label that is also an empty label sitting bound for it, adding it to that, our
panel.
Then we have created an image that is a log in image and added that log in image into a label and set
it bound for the label and adding that label to our frame.
After that, there is a button B1, which is a log in button adding action to that button, setting
the foreground, background color and bound of the button, and adding that button to our panel.
After that, there is a sign up button adding action listener to that button, foreground and background
color of the button setting bound for the button, adding that button to our panel.
After that, there is a button three, which is a forgot password button adding access to it, foreground,
background, color, setting the bound of the red button and adding that button to our panel.
After that, there is another label for a label five, which is trouble in log in, setting font for
it, foreground for it, and bound for it, adding that to our panel.
After that, there is another panel setting background color for it and bound for it.
And adding to that, our panel.
After that, we have defined the action performed method with the action event object.
So if the action event sources from B1 button, so we will set the boolean variable status to false
and try inside that we will create the object of connection class, which we have just discussed in
our previous video, and then we will.
Creating the string SQL inside which we will, is storing the query select aspect from account where
username is equal to this and password is close to this.
So prepare the statement.
We will create the prepared statement by passing that is equal to the prepared statement method by using
the connection object and the connection.
The and then we will set.
Using that purpose statement, we will set a strings in our database.
Text filled out by getting text filled from get text field and password from password field.
And after that we will execute that query as a result that will execute that statement, prepared statement
and if asked next then is set with well false and the new home class will be called.
And if the password does not match, then it will be shown invalid login or password in the cast block.
We will be catching the exception if any occurs.
If the source of the event is from Beta Button, we will set the visibility of the current Windows file
and call the sign up class and if the source of event is from beta, then we will set the visibility
of the current window as well and call the forward password class.
So let's move to our sign up class.
So sunglasses defined inside the package travel.
We have imported the necessary packages.
Java JWT.
Java String Java Java Debilitated Event, Java Linked Bar.
After that, we have defined the class which is extending frame and implementing action listener.
There is a private panel and.
Four text fields, two buttons and two combo box.
Inside the main function, we have created the object and set the visibility of the frame as true.
Then we have defined the non parameter as constructor.
After that we have set the bound for that frame and created the instance of.
Panel.
Master of that panel, adding that to the frame background of the panel.
Layout of the panel.
After that, we have.
Created a username setting foreground colour for it, font type and family and size for it bound for
it and adding that to our panel.
Under the label as name setting, foreground colour, font bound and adding to a panel.
Then there is another label password setting, foreground font bound and adding it to a panel.
Then there is another answer, which will be the answer of the security question.
Four wrong colour font bound and adding it to all the panel.
Then there is a combo box that will define the combo box with the security question, like your nickname,
your lucky number, your child superhero.
Your childhood name.
Combo box.
Said Bowen, sitting down for it, adding that box to the panel.
Then there is a security question label setting for one colour for it and.
Fought for it, bound for it, and adding that to our.
Panel.
After that, adding the image in the sign up and.
Adding that image to the label, then setting the bond for the label, adding that label to the frame.
Then there is a text field, respective text fields setting bound for it, adding to the panel, another
text field setting bound for it adding to that panel.
Then there are all the full text field have been set with their respective to their bounds and location
and size.
Then there is the button one which is create adding Excel font bound background color, foreground color,
adding that to our panel.
After that, there is a button B two which is labelled as backs action listener font lb foreground color,
background color and adding to that, our panel.
Then there is another gel, another panel for one color for it set the bottom.
This will be used to set the model with named as create account and set the bound for that panel.
And background color of that panel and adding that panel to our frame.
Now we have described the action performed event action performed method, which is taking an argument
as action event and instead we have created the connection.
If the source of the event is from button, then we will create a statement and stored it in the string
as well, which will say that insert into account with username, name, password, question, answer
and values.
Then we have created the prepared statement and inside the statement we have set a string for all the
fields by fetching respective details from the text field and the combo box and set the I is equals
to execute.
If the execute query will execute successfully, then I will have a non-zero value.
So if I will have a non-zero value, then it will show the dialogs, work that account, create a successfully.
Otherwise we will set the text fields as null again and if the source is for button B2, then we will
set the visibility of the current window as false and call the new login window again.
Cache block will handle an exception if occurs.
Now let's move to the forgot password class.
This will be used if you forgot password.
So let's have a look in forward password.
This is defined inside the package travel unnecessary package have been imported Java Swing, Swing,
Border, JavaScript and Java JWT event.
After that we have defined the four plus four class, which is extending JVM and implementing accents.
After that, there is a J panel five text field, three buttons inside the main function where we have
called the power password class and the visibility of the frame.
As to then we have defined the parameter as non parameterized constructor, setting the bound for that.
Frame, defining a panel, setting the border for it.
Adding to the frame background colour for it and layout as well.
Then there is a label, one setting font for it, bound for it.
Adding to that, our panel.
Then there is a label to name setting font for it, bound for it.
Then there is a label your security question setting font for it bound for it.
Adding to that our panel.
Then there is a label for answer setting bound for it, font for it, bound for it and I to adding that
to our panel.
Similarly, we have the password label.
Then the respective text field, one setting font foreground bound.
Adding to that our panel for the text field PT one similarly for the PT 233, 84 and 85.
Then we have created the image icon.
Added that image icon to the label l6 setting bound for the label added that label to the frame.
After that, there is a button search setting x listener font bound background color, foreground color
and adding to that, our panel.
Similarly for the button B2 that is retrieved similarly for the button b three, that is for back then
there is another panel sitting bound for it and for background color is pink.
And adding to that, our panel.
Then we have defined the action performed.
Method which is taking action event object.
After that we inside the trip log.
We have created the instance of connection class.
If the source of the event is from V1, then we will create a query that is select as to from account
where username is equal to customer.
That is a prepared statement created nested that is equal to Condorcet or C a prepared statement pass
the Haskell into the prepared statement.
After that, we have to set the.
Uh, text which have been fetched from the.
Text field, Stephen, and we will execute that query.
And after iterating that results set, we will also send the name and question of the.
For that particular username in the account table.
After that, if the source of the button is from B2, we will select equip prepare a query select extract
from account where answer so.
For that, we will execute the and set the required text from the text for and execute that query and
again set the password for that particular username.
If the button is B3 and source of the event is from Beta three, then the visibility of the current
will will be false and new login object has been created and visibility will be set to true.
So this is all about the login.
Sign up and forgot password class.
Let me show you.
So I will be running the login file.
So this is the login file.
First we need to sign up so I will go and sign up.
This is the signup page so we we can sign up by writing details here.
I'll be not signing up right now.
I will click on back and I will be.
If I click on Forward Password, it will take us to the forgot password as well.
I will be kicking on back as well here.
And so those are the outputs of the three classes.