So here is our hotel management system dot java file which will the first file which you run.
In this project.
So it is defined inside the package hotel and we have imported abstract window toolkit package, swing
package and event package that is defined inside the Abstract Window Toolkit.
Now Abstract Window Toolkit and Swing will be used to generate and develop graphical user interface
standalone applications.
Now we have defined the class which is extending j frame j frame will be used to frame the designing
of our window.
And this hotel management class had implementing action listener.
Excel Listener is an interface whose method will be redefined in this class so that the event handling
can be performed.
Now there is two instance variable versus jailable that is L one second is J button, that is B1.
Now we have defined a non parameterized constructor of this class that is hotel management system and
setting the size of the j frame.
This is will be the size of the j frame layout of the j frame setting as null and the location of the
j frame from which it will start displaying that we have set using the set location and initializing
the new J label that will be 11 with null values and the button with new J button that will be labelled
as next and setting the background color of button and the foreground color of button as white and black
respectively.
Image icon that will create an image icon class loader.
Get system resource using the system resource.
It will create the image icon.
Now image will get the image from the image icon and the scales its default and size as well.
Now then again, image icon will create image icon by using the image object that is three.
And now the label has been created by using the image icon.
So the limit label will show that image now created a new label that is labeled as hotel management
system, setting the bound for it.
The first value is the X value.
Second is Y value from the start, and the third and fourth values are height and width of the.
Label.
Then we have set the font, family type and size of it, the label and the foreground color of the label
and adding that label to the L1.
Then we have set the bond for our button and label both adding the lib button to the label and adding
the label to the frame, adding action listener to our button, setting the visibility of the window
as true.
So while true, we will set the visibility of ID as false so it will an infinite loop.
Set the visibility of lead as false leads hotel management system.
So this will be setting as false and try to thread dot sleep 500 so thousand is equal to one second.
So that means 500 will it will blink for every half, second, half, second it will set as false and
every after half second it will set as true.
So it will it will display and disappear one by one.
Now this will catch oxygen will handle the catch.
Then after that we have set it as true again.
We have settings thread 500 so it will again blink for the half second and catch will handle the exception
inside action performed as there is only one button that is next button.
So it will take us to the clicking of the next button will take us to the login page.
Setting the visibility of this window will be false and setting the visibility of the login page as
true.
Inside the main function we have created the management object and setting the visibility of the object
as true.
So let's move to our login page, which will be displayed when we click on next button of this page.
So login page is defined inside the package hotel imported the AWG Abstract Window Toolkit Package Swing
Package Abstract Measure Toolkit Event Package and SQL Package for Database Connection.
Define the class which is extending the frame and implementing acceleration.
There are two labels element and two one text field t one and password field TX two two buttons p one
and B to define the non parameterized constructor of the login class super logging which will be headed
as login setting the layout of the frame which will be null.
First frame is labeled as username.
First label will be user named as username, setting the bound for the label.
Adding that label to the frame second label is named as password, setting the bound for the password
and adding that label to the frame.
Similarly we have initialize the text field setting the bound for the text field and adding a text field
to the frame.
Similarly, for the password field, setting the bound for the password field and adding it to the frame.
Similarly, we have defined here the image.
Again, that is a second or jpg from getting the system resource.
The image will be.
It scaled by using the image object that is A2 which will get image and a scale is instance, size and
scaling.
Image three will create the image.
Icon will create the image icon by using the image object that is A2 and.
Creating another label, L3, which will show that image.
Setting the bond for the label and adding that label to our frame.
Then we have created the button log in labelled as log in, setting the bound for the button, setting
the font for the button, adding action listener to the button, setting background colour as black
and white for the foreground cloud of the button as white.
Adding that button to our frame.
Then we have B2.
That is another button named as cancel, which will be used to cancel the login.
Setting the bounds for the button.
Adding the font type family and its size foreground color as.
So the background color as black and foreground color as white and adding that bit of button to our
frame.
Now be to add extra listener this will adding the action listener to our button now get content and
setting the background color of our complete frame window as white, setting the visibility of the window
as true, setting the size of the frame and the location of the frame inside the action performed as
there are two buttons b1 b2.
So if the source of the event from is B2 B1, then we will stabilize the connection with our connection
class and database and take the text as a string you from the username field and from the password field.
It store the string in B creating a string variable Q which will hold the query.
That is a select aspect from login where username is equals to you and password is goes to re executing
the query by using a result set object rs seven point se dot execute query q passing the string which
is holding the query and if asked next to asked next will iterate will bring the record for them from
the next row of the login table and a new dashboard dot set as well.
So if the RS start next is executed successfully, then we will move on to the next page setting by
the visibility of the dashboard page as true and setting the visibility of the current page as false.
And if it does not match us with our database record so it will show the dialog box as added log in
and setting the visibility of the current window as false catch bug will be used to handle the exceptions.
And as if if the source of the event is from the be too button, that is a back button or cancel button.
So this will simply systematize it.
It will close for the complete program as the log in module will be canceled.
And inside the main function we have just created the log in object.
Let's move on to the dashboard class which will be displayed after the successful login.
So here is the dashboard class defined inside the package hotel.
And first we have imported the Java Abstract Window Toolkit Package and Java Swing dot package and Java
.8. event package.
Define the class, which is extending the frame.
And a public static void went inside the void.
When we have created the object of the current class and setting the visibility of it's as true.
Now we have defined the constructor headed as total management system.
Setting the foreground color as can and setting the layout as null.
Again, adding an image is scaling its size and.
For instance, adding that image to the image icon, adding that image icon to the label and setting
the bound for the label and adding the label to our frame.
Creating another label as airline management system that is headed as the Taj Group welcomes you.
That's for reference.
Airline management system setting the foreground color of it, that label font of that label bound off
that label and adding that label to our frame.
Now there is a menu bar instantiating the instance of a menu bar as menu bar setting the menu bar passing
by, bypassing the object of the menu bar that is menu bar and creating the menu object instance by
airline system that is added at hotel management.
So for our first item will be hotel management of that menu, setting the color for that foreground
of that menu and adding that menu to the menu bar.
Another menu item will be reception.
So menu item, first menu item will be reception and adding airline add flight details.
So that will be added to our menu.
Now second will be admin setting the colour for the admin and adding that admin menu item into our menu.
Well now another menu item will be added employ and adding the add employer to the admin section.
So admin will be able to add those employee.
So add employee will be inside the admin section.
Now flight details shallow one.
So five little settlements means adding employees will add employers click so that this portion of code
will be for whenever add employee event will happen.
So inside which we have defined action performed which is taking action event try.
If the add employee will be called, then we will call the add employee class and setting the visibility
of it.
True.
If any exception occurred, then we will handle those that exception.
Similarly, we have added add room inside the admin section at room inside the admin section.
Similarly here we have also.
Define the action event.
If the ad run will be event happen, then we will call the ad room and settings will be visibility as
true.
Then we have a flight details action.
If flight details is clicked, then action event.
We will open the reception menu.
So if the reception menu will be clear, then we will set the visibility as true of the new ships and
object.
Now flight item.
Then another item is the add driver that will be inside the admin.
So similarly we have called the add driver class inside this action perform method whenever it will
be clicked or event that happen setting the size of it as.
It's off the window and setting the visibility as true and setting the background color of that window
as white.
Now, let's see how these three classes are interrelated.
So let me start with the hotel management system class, which is the basic class.
Let's run this file.
So it is running.
So this is how it will look like.
This is how it will look like.
Here is that red dot sleep which is blinking at every half second.
So let's click on Next Button, which will take us to the login page.
Next button, here is the login page.
As you can see, here is the login page username or we have already entered.
That was in the previous video admin and its password is one, two, three, four, five.
Let's hit login.
So login will take us to the this page that is heading as hotel management system and there are still
menu item, hotel management and admin.
I told you that inside admin add employee add rooms and add drivers inside hotel reception.
Now in our next video, we will.
Take a look on the admin portion that is an employee at and driver classes how these are these will
work.
So this in this video we have learned about these three classes.