We already started our project, which is based on Java BLOCK System, which I refer to name as Connect
to Globe because I'm connecting the people to the software.
Or we can see server deployment through JSP and Java servlet.
So if you have seen we already created this, not this page we created indexed JSP page and I already
coded some part.
I will tell you what is the significance of this part?
So this is the index page, which is basically first loading page or landing with web page.
You can see now, what is these things?
I will tell you later, but this is very important.
I'm preferring my page language java, not HTML.
So I'm embedding embedding the Java code in HTML you can say throughout the JSP.
So this is the beautiful thing of JSP and ignore this.
These are all the JavaScript where I preferred some CSS files.
So if you have seen these things, let me show you.
These are the JSP, which I'm going to create.
But if I'm going to downward a little bit and I will tell you, I'm using JSP here.
So all these things are basically just be JSP language or we can save this language.
Okay, now you are seeing this not logging message.
Everything all dot println.
It's basically not HTML.
It's.
So I am embedding inside these.
These are the things very important showing in the green.
So the Green Party is Java.
So I'm using JSP now.
I am using JSP instead of using HTML.
You say.
HTML is very useful.
You can use this in HTML only.
But the thing is, while printing this message you can see this.
I just want to create, not log in message or something like that in this.
What I have to do, I have to create one HTML, then I have to create one servlet.
For that servlet I need backend each and everything.
Now I can create one JSP file and inside that only I can use Java file and it will load directly.
So that's a beautiful thing because I don't want to create index HTML and that index servlet also.
So I embedded this.
I will tell you what is the JSP thing here?
Then I created an admin page admin JSP, which is pretty similar, which is loading pretty similar.
But one thing is here is.
Just ignore this.
I just added This is nothing but just sentence.
If you know the java or HTML basics, I'm just writing this part because I don't want to add some imaginary
part.
Am writing just this part.
And these are some images I'm downloaded from the internet and.
Here.
You can put some things then all the things you can put here.
So important thing.
Here is this form.
Well, then what is the form?
Basically, add a log in admin, log in process.
Just create action.
It will ask for username and password name as username and password to log in.
Everything here is very important and I'm including footer html to add that footer and which is the
food html.
This is the html.
Basically nothing.
But it's having some links images then something here like that.
So this is we all already created.
I just added admin jsp with this.
If you want to create another thing here like just only form, you can add this to give minimalistic.
Look, I'm just adding all the text here and I'm just copied that part only so you can add that part.
So let us see what the JSP is.
So our.
So let let me go to the soil first.
If I told you that.
Solid.
What is a solid?
It's a pure Java code.
You can add a HTML inside that, but it's request server and response time each embedded with this.
But what if I can use only HTML?
I can put that java file on the network instead of being on the server instead of giving load on the
server because server is also searching that file for that particular purpose.
Instead of that, I can put Java file in the network layer, which is basically network is also having
some storage capacity we can say, or we can transfer capacity.
So I can embedded that part in HTML only.
So this is the forward method, include method each and every thing, then servlet, important parts.
I'm going to tell you if you know the servlet, there are three important parts.
Here is HTML, CSS JS for frontend java servlet program for backend or logic we can say and web XML
to control flow of web app each animating one instead of this.
JSP is a Java servlet pages basically Java language inside extreme page, so you don't need to worry
about web dot xml.
My file is added or not.
No need to worry about that.
It will take care itself with that syntax.
Or we can say scripting syntax for that purpose.
Tooling between java and HTML.
But you can cannot use JSP directly for the database connection.
Remember that you need to create java separate java file for for that like listener files or everything.
So that's another thing.
But I don't just for fetching part, just for displaying part, I can use JSP.
So JSP technology is used to create web application, just like servlet technology.
It can be thought of extension of solid because it provides more functionality than servlet like expression
language.
Still Java scripting language is everything raw transcript language also provides so JSP page contains
a statement text plus JSP text.
As I shown you before that part, then JSP pages are easier to maintain because of servers.
Because we can separate designing development if you know, like let me show you.
This admin got GST.
There is more padding here because it's shifted to this part.
Notice let me use this part on you.
So it's very big file, as you can see.
So as you can see in this part, you can see this.
All the things are basically design.
And these all the things are basic part of our development.
So GSP is easier to maintain, or we can say easier to specify the gap between designing and development.
If I am using HTML and servlet, what is the difference?
I have to create one another file which is going to slow down the server and which is going to load
so it takes more time and everything.
Maintenance is very difficult.
In that case, it provides additional features with some expression languages, custom tags.
You can create some custom tags in cases or JavaScript.
You can use that directly in JSP.
So that's a very huge thing.
A lot of things you can do.
But what is the advantage is basically I'm going to tell you it's an extension to servlet.
If you notice that we have some limitations like for the gate forward method each and everything, you
have to remember everything, syntax each and everything.
But here there is not that such case.
You can provide as many as four word cases, everything.
And it's an extension of servlet because why I'm doing extension, you can use some implicit objects,
predefined tags, custom tags, you can create expression, language, you can create, you can create
another methods in JSP also just like Java.
But you have to remember, you have to give the syntax.
What is the JSP image?
It's entirely just that triangular arrows with percent and you have to end that JSP.
Do you recall that HTML having some JSP tags then easy to maintain as I told you is very easy to maintain.
We mix our business logic with presentation logic in servlet like logic is basically development and
presentation is basically design.
We have to mix both like for the center part each and everything you have to put out and everything.
Oh.
Then fast development.
No need to recompile and redeploy.
I will tell you what is the team here?
Why solid?
If you create a new servlet, you have to redeploy it again.
You have to run it again.
But in JSP consider you develop the one code in JSP or you can say you develop one AB, which is related
to your car booking.
Car booking app.
You create it in JSP fully.
And after developing in that part and deploying on the server, I'm not telling on this local server,
I'm telling one online server after two or three weeks, you understood as a developer you have some
mistakes in that you need to add one more GSP.
You can add that JSP in that server part or we can set deployment, but just add it.
You don't need to redeploy.
No need to change your dot.com part or your L part.
It just added and it just automatically redeployed.
So no need to recompile once.
It is very.
What we can say.
There is no errors in that DSP.
You can redeploy it again and again as many as we want because it's automatically redeployed in JVM
or Java server.
Similarly, if JSP pages is modified, we don't need to compile redeploy, so let course need to update
it.
Recompiled.
Sometimes what happens while fetching the database if we have no entries there, that thing is also
showing the null.
So it's if we have change, look and feel the application and everything, we have to redeploy it again
and again.
So that means we need to stop the server, we need to redeploy it, then again bring back server like
so instead of this, what we can do, we can just add the JSP inside that and we can perform such actions.
So let us see in the ID what I've created already.
So this is admin and if you have seen I put a log in JSP, so let me log in process.
JSP So this is very simple file.
What I'm putting the admin netbeans is my password.
You can choose any different because I am specifying this only I don't want to specify or.
Molting year, and this is importing this part and all the things it's displaying.
So this is all about how I'm creating this.
But let me tell you what is the basic theme here is if you have seen this part already, I'm specifying
the A status DSP.
So I will tell you later what is the significance of this status?
Everything.
But always remember one thing while developing this.
You don't need to recompile it again.
As these are the JSP files you don't need to recompile.
So what you are going to do is just here, just add that file in your project in JSP.
As I told you earlier, how we can add these files in your JSP.
Similarly, you need to add that file in GSP.
Just recompile it and you are good to go to develop your files and each and everything here.
So this is all about how we are going with this.
So in further videos, what I'm going to tell you, I'm going to create some files here and I'm going
to build it throughout my project with some default things I'm mentioning here.
Some files you need to create here.
But.
Always remember, create all files.
Don't miss any footer, file or anything.
So this is the status and I'm using a skill.
I will tell you what is the significance of this?
Why I am putting the SQL file and each and every thing log out.
JSP I'm going to create.
I'm putting everything here.
So I will tell you what is the significance of this each and everything in later part.
So this is it we can create.
So let us create one more GSP, which I already created.
It's just see what you can say showing the file.
It's not very useful file because there is no logic inside this.
But let me show you what is the file name?
So specify the file name is Apia.
You can finish.
So it will take time to create JSP file.
Once it is loaded.
You can see this file is no use of this.
If you want those fish, I'm cooking this as it is because I want this fish that I'm going to need at
this point.
So let me tell you what I'm going to do this year.
So my thing is very simple here.
Usage is very simple.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to create one.
I'm going to use one HTTP protocol here, which is basically nothing but some.
More what we can say package here.
Some templates which I'm going to use.
So it's nothing but just creating the objects, everything I'm going to create and some I'm going to
edit some locations.
So if you want to add more locations, you can add.
But I just added only two.
Three locations
you're only.
These are the locations I added and which I found on internet easily.
These are some random locations I added, and I just want to put this.
So if you want to add, you can add it here more using or creating by objects.
So these are the property and these are all the JavaScript things.
So that's it about JSP, which I created.
You can directly copy this part or if you want, you can develop this part.
Part is very easy here, but I'm adding some functions here, as you can see here.
So this is how you can develop this part.
Function, functions, family, all these things are related to script JavaScript.
So if you want to add in Java, you have to mention that it's in text, but I just added in JavaScript
part for the frontend.
So this is how we can create the this part.
I hope you understand.
In the further part, I'm going to explain the main logic of SQL part here with the database connection.
And this is it about this topic.