So before loading our images into the image area, we have to create a constructor of our class, a
parameterized constructor in which we will take a board initial.
So what we will write.
We will write a public board.
Give the parameters with the G label status for.
A new bracket open.
The START status.
We need the status.
Okay.
The stance is what is equal to the status bar.
We need to create a method by the initial board here.
Okay.
So in this matter, this created.
Create.
Feel.
Private label.
History does what it should be.
Final, also private, final and done.
Becky Sue So this thing is done.
Now what we have to do.
We have to do our code of loading images into the image area here.
So here I will write.
Let's see.
Send the preferred size first.
King said.
True full size.
Here.
I will write a new dimension and get the parameter at the board width.
First comma.
Board height.
And then.
Set for science.
No.
We have just a minute.
Just hear what we have to do.
We will take our image and rehearse.
So we will write.
I am g equal to new image.
And this we will give no.
Here and now, images of images we have total that is 13.
So this will be the size of our area.
And here we will take a four loop and fry it in three equal to zero.
And I is less than with the normal number of images and make the increment curly bracket open here we
will write variable part equal to and here we will give the part.
So it is under CRC resources slash done and I and plus and not be in g data image.
The next one is equal to new image.
Here I will write image.
I could take the part node get image and this is done.
So here we load our images in the image area.
The images are named as 2012, three, four, five and so on with the dot, p and G.
So the next thing we have to do is to initialize the minesweeper game with our new method called this
new game.
So here I will take that matter and write new game and create this method.
Not.