Hello everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction part and the working of the application part
pretty well, and now you all must be wondering how to start the coding section of the application and
must be excited about start the programming part.
So let us begin this by opening the welcome page of our IDE Visual Studio Code in which we will be creating
this application.
And once opening the welcome page, you will be seeing like an interface like this on your screens where
you will be provided some options like file, edit and so on.
So on the welcome page to start to create the application, we have to click on this file Explorer icon
and once you will click this Explorer icon, some options will appear on your screen.
Let me like maximize this in order to make it more clear.
So we are having options like open folder, clone repository and create Java projects.
So we are going to create a new Java project from scratch.
So we will select this Create Java project button from this Explorer option in the welcome page.
Once we will click Create Java Project Option, then we will be provided with some options.
And these are basically the toolkits which are used as a support to make any application in Java, and
there are toolkits like Maven, Springboard Quads, Micro Profile and so on.
So in this we are not going to use any Java support, any tool kit except like we are going to make
this application from scratch.
So we do not want to embed any of these supports in our applications.
So leaving this and clicking no build tools and we are going to work with source code directly without
any build tools.
So we are not going to use any build tools in this application.
So clicking on normal tools and our interface will open file chooser of your desktop will open basically.
And inside this we have to select the location of the folder of the project we are going to make.
So I am choosing Backstop as my project location.
You can choose any location of your choice, but keep in mind that you have to remember where you have.
Choose that location.
So and later, if you wish to like open the application, it would be better if you like, remember
the location to make things more times.
So I am choosing desktop as my project location and I input text field pairs asking for input java project.
So we have to input a project name of our choice, which is going to be the title of the folder which
will be created inside which the main folders and files of the application will be consistent.
So you can choose any name for the project.
I am going to name it as food ordering system, so my choice of name suggest that I should name this
application as this one table.
I want to give you all that we should name our application, our projects according to the functioning
of that, so that it makes us clear in future that what actually this project was made for.
Like suppose if I name this application as a whatever, ABC, X-Y-Z or any other like fancy name, but
that would not help me in any way in future.
Suppose in future I have to search that whether I have made a food ordering system application in my
past and I would like I am not remembering that I have created this.
So this will be like very complex in searching like ABC X, Y, Z or anything, any fancy name.
So things becomes complex on naming applications in a fancy way or any like anonymous things.
So we should name our.
In such a way that it becomes easier for us to find the like, what is the significance of this application?
So name your projects wisely.
Choose our appropriate name for your applications in order to make things more like this was basically
a tip I wanted to give you all of, but otherwise it's upon you.
If you remember things then you can name it anyways.
So yes, I have selected a name for my project food ordering system.
And now I will hit enter to.
Land into our projects folder.
So yes, we have entered our projects folder and there are some inbuilt folders in this project.
So we have selected the Create Project option from the Explorer tab and inside this Java project called
US Food Ordering System.
We have our dot list and dot v is called folders and these two folders are with the mercy of our compiler.
This has nothing to do with our project.
We are not going to use these two folders in our project anyways.
So better ignored these two.
We are going to use this sa z folder as a whole body of our project.
So suppose that is a body.
So inside the body we have body parts.
So this is our C folder is the body which is going to contain the parts of our project.
And these parts I say, I mean that files and folders which will be consisted inside this folder and
will be totally responsible for testing and running of the application.
Okay.
So now switching to the prototype, which we made in order to like understand the functionalities and
working of this application, the first thing was to create a new project in the ID, which we have
done already.
Now, in the next part, we will be creating a main class of this project inside the SA C folder.
As I said, this is the main body of our application.
So creating the main class, calling it labelled Java.
So we have to create files and while creating files, we have to keep in mind that these file names
should end with not Java.
So in order to make it a Java program file, so we have to add dot java as a necessity while making
files inside the folder or any Java project inside any other folder.
So the main class is called as labelled on Java.
On hitting enter, we will be landing in the labeled Java like file and we will be.
Yes.
So there is already class made called app dot java and this approach java will run once there will be
any exception in our app.
So this app.
But Java will run in case of any runtimes error arising in our application.
So basically it has no functional use in our application.
It is just an inbuilt file inside the SA C folder and contains no functionality of our application.
So yes, we have created labelled Java file.
Now inside this we've been declaring a class which will be called as label.
So we have created labelled Java.
So obviously the class name is going to be labelled, this is the public class and inside it we will
be like declaring some of the variables or we can call it as objects as there is a class.
So inside class we have objects and inside this class we are like declaring the objects as public static.
Final long.
So these are the objects which are going to be used in our application.
Okay.
So these are the objects required in this project in order to make the form complete for ordering the
food items.
And these are objects are from the single library.
So we have to import in order to make things working.
So we are importing everything one by one importing.
Gerardo I have already discussed this that we are going to like use this string and NWT frameworks extensively.
So we are doing that now.
So we have imported all the objects here from Java swing and Java String is the main toolkit which is
responsible for making the frame of the application.
So inside this class we are going to initialize a constructor called as label also as well.
So this public label constructor is going to contain the layout of the like how the interface will look.
So setting layout to null as this is going to be in default state.
So we have set the layout now we are going to set the size of the frame and the size is going to be
suppose.
The set size is going to be 600 by 400 or the height and width of the application.
And we have to import something in order to make think like we have not created the method.
So we will create the method later in this class as well.
Firstly, let us set everything in order to make the frame idea like what the frame is going to look
at.
So location.
Relative to.
None.
This is also going to be null and after this.
We are going to.
Set some more things.
Okay, so before setting the size and layout of the frame, firstly we should discuss what are the objects
we are going to use while making this frame or application.
We can it anyways.
So we are initializing a long data type for version uid.
So we have a serial number for every menu item.
Similarly, we have like four labels.
We can see it here.
So we have labels for size, for how many glasses we want to order.
And similarly for the report and beverage we have ordered, the dialog box will also contains labels.
So if you like, memorize it, you will get to know.
So this J label is for all the labels inside the application.
Similarly, this J combo box with a data type of string is responsible for the size like the J combo
box is.
Basically that what we call it?
It is the like options which are appearing here as the only medium large you can see here.
Small, medium, large.
And these are possible with the help of J comma box.
The sizes there are three sizes in whole.
Also, we have radio buttons for all the items in the menu.
We have already discussed in the introduction part that these radio buttons one, two, three, four
are according to our choices that how many radio buttons we are going to use.
So initially we are like declaring four radio buttons for juice, water and coffee.
Similarly, for buttons we have buttons, add and order.
So a button group is to be declared before and then after.
We are initializing the buttons with the help of bit, then add and order.
Also for the last we are declaring a text field, but how many glasses of the specific item from the
menu we want to order and amount of.
So this is the integer which is going to contain the amount of this for.
Text.
So this is going to take integer outputs, inputs.
So we are going to save it as amount of with the help of this.
So we have declared all the objects associated with this application.
Now in the next part we will be looking back with adding some more styling and force with separate beverages
as coffee, tea, water, juice and the add ons attached to it will be declared inside those classes
only.
So everything will be attached inside the classes and we have to add functionalities of each menu item
within their classes only.
So see you in the next part with all the other classes.