Hello everyone.
So I hope that you all have been through the introduction of the application part and working on the
project part pretty well and have understood that how this application is actually working, the time
management interface which we are going to make in Java.
So coming to the coding execution part, we have covered everything like how each of the functionality
is working, whether the home page are these buttons, these are scheduled page which is scheduling
our task.
Accordingly, there is a timer attached to it.
And again, on hitting this continuous button we enter in this frame, there is a timeline that is a
done button.
Also there is a timer running for how much time which is left for our tasks and also the help page and
definitely the end page, which is going to tell us that how much time we saved or wasted.
So in the coding part we are going to like code everything.
This application is going to look exactly like this and we are going to start this coding from scratch
for this time management application and you will see that how we are using the concepts of Java in
order to make this time management application.
So this is the welcome page of our individual studio code here.
We can see that there is an Explorer button on hitting this Explorer button, our option or paths for
creating a Java project.
So after hitting this explore button, we have to select this create Java project option from the like
menu bar.
We can see that and again our options for to leopard.
So this build tool is asking for what is the type of tool we want to attach to our application.
So in this application we are going to work directly with the source code.
We are not using any external tools for our application.
Otherwise there are several vehicles in Java you can explore about them later and make some other projects.
There are Maven, Springboard Works and Micro Profile, so if you wish to learn about them, you can
explore more.
But in this application we are going to hit this noble tool option and work directly with the source
code without any tools.
So on hitting the normal tool option, our file chooser of our desktop opens up and asks us for a project
location where we want to locate our project folder tool.
So in this file chooser, I am going to click desktop as the location for my project.
You can choose any location you want to store your project to, but I will advise you to choose a wise
location for your project so that later, when you need it, you can find it on that location.
So I save all my projects in the desktop, so I am saving it in desktop.
Now let us name are like our input filters upper asking for a Java project name.
So I would encourage you all to name your projects wisely as the name is worth defining what this application
is containing.
So in the later future, if you need that application, then you can find it with the help of its name.
So do not name any like anonymous type of or any fancy name to your application name.
Your application according to what is it is actually doing?
What is the outcome of that application?
So this application is for time management and I am going to name this application and that manner only.
So time management interface or we can call it as time management tool also.
So what time management tool is the name for my project folder on hitting enter, I will land up inside
the project folder, the time management tool and inside this time management tool there are already
some inbuilt folders.
So this dot dot v is called folders are created as we have selected the create project option from this
ID Visual Studio code and they are of no use inside our project.
These are just created by the compiler or this.
This compiler has some libraries for Java project, but our current we have no use of these two folders.
So we can simply ignore these two and we can move forward.
So there are two other folders that live in the cited folder.
So this is our C folder is going to be the main folder of our project.
All the important files and folders we are going to make inside this application is going to be consistent
inside this SRT folder only basically this folder is going to be the body of our application.
And inside this.
Body.
All the body parts will be consistent.
So keep in mind that any of the file folder you meet in your like project that should be enclosed inside
the society folder only and not anywhere else.
So.
Okay.
So that is the Java class which is like in built file made inside the society folder.
You can see I have not made this file.
This is already an inbuilt file.
We have created a Java project.
So this after Java is created or like already.
So inside this app there is a plus or there is a main function which is like handling the exceptions.
So if any kind of exception is going to arise in this application, then this part of the code is going
to be executed.
This system that are the println is used for printing any string or if there are any kind of bugs arising
in the application.
So yes, if the application throws any exception, then this is going to be printed now or coming to
the like main part we have decided in the prototype, like we have set a path in that manner that firstly
we have to create a new project in the ID and in the second step we decided to make the main class.
So the main class was going to be named as the timeline or Java.
So we will be creating that main class inside this folder only.
So let us start the coding execution part of our project.
We are going to create our main class inside the society folder on hitting the right click of a mouse.
We have to select this new file option inside the SA C folder and we are going to create our new file
timeline dot Java.
So yes, this is going to be the name for the main class timeline.
So I am going to name this as timeline dot Java and we should must include the Java extension at the
end of every file we are making inside this Java project so that all the Java functions and classes
become executable inside our file.
Now on hitting enter this timeline class is already created, so this is definitely going to be our
main class which will like be responsible for running and testing of our application.
Now I'm going to extend this main class as a frame and inside this J frame.
Okay.
So this frame is going to be an import from the Java string package or the Java string is a framework
and inside this frame is a component.
This frame provides this frame.
Okay, so this is the main frame.
This frame is providing us the frame inside which all the components, the panels and whatever they
are, the buttons, the scheduling tab.
So all of them are enclosed inside this frame only.
So we have extended the main class as the frame.
Now let us create a main function first.
So the function is going to be run in order to make the application running.
So public, static, void, main and a string argument we are going to pass inside it.
I mean a square bracket and arguments as are.
So this is how a main function is created.
We have already seen it inside the upload java class.
So the public static void main this main function is going to open a new timeline.
So this timeline is the class we have just created.
And this function is going to run this class, make this class executable.
Now in the next step, we are going to make our constructor timeline.
And this constructor is going to contain all the objects and methods of this timeline in class.
So, yes, I am using this super method.
So this is the way to initialize a constructor with a bracket.
This basically costs that class inside this public constructor.
So this is a constructor and we are accessing the class.
So what is a constructor?
So constructor is our function, we can call it, and it has the same name as the class.
So the names are identical inside the super method.
We are going to set the title for our application and the title is going to be task cleaner.
So what is the super method?
So this super method invokes just above parent class.
So just immediate parent to it is invoked with the help of this super method.
So yes, the super method is going to invoke this function, the timeline constructor, the method we
can call it, and it will open up with a title task line.
Now we have to set aside for the frame.
So calling, set size and this is going to contain the length and width for the application whenever
it opens.
So 700 by 700, I am setting the yes.
The frame as this now.
So we have to set the default close operation.
Also here you can see that we are having a default close operation.
So yes, we have to set that also inside the frame only.
So default close operation and by default we have to set it to exit on close.
So whenever we exit it should escape through the window which is opening, it should basically escape
out of the application window now as set content pane.
So that is a content inside the panel or the frame we can call it.
And this content is so new based.
So this new base is going to consist all of the frames.
So basically it is a multi-vendor interface.
There are multiple phases of this application here.
You can count.
This is the home page, this is the schedule page, this is the timeline page.
This is the help page which is opening.
Basically, we can call it about the split.
And then so 4 to 5 frames are consistent inside this application and this set content pane is going
to call invoke this new base method, and this base method is going to contain all of them at a single
place.
We will be just creating this immediately after this timeline or constructor.
Okay, so setting resizable to true we can maximize the frame or minimize the frame head.
We are having a maximize and minimize buttons.
Also here you can see that this is the resizable thing for the frame or the window, whatever you call
it, and set visible is set to false by default.
So to make the frame visible, we have to set through it, to set it to true again and again while making
any application.
So keep this in mind to make any of the application visible enough frame set visible.
True is the important factor to be kept in mind.
Okay, so now let us create the base.
So outside this we are going to create the base method.
So this is.
This is inside the main class, the constructor.
Now.
I'm coming to the base.
So, yes, this is the base class we have created, which is extending itself as a DJ panels.
So we are having a panel for the homepage, a panel for the schedule page or panel for this timeline,
this whole about page, we can call it and the end.
So inside the place base class after extending it as a G panel, we are using this home.
So home is our object inside this class based help schedule plus the timeline we can see this is so
this is the timeline.
This is the schedule, this is the home.
And this card layout is for the image which is appearing in a form of a card or the background image
we can call it, and the end page.
So yes, these are all the panels which are going to be enclosed inside the base class.
Okay.
So this inside this base class, invoking this base constructor and this base constructor is what we
can call it, initializing the objects for all of them, whether it is for the card layout.
So this is the method card is equal to new card layout.
So this is going to create a new object for the card layout.
And similarly for the home help schedule timeline.
And, and with the help of this keyword, we are going to access which we have already declared it here.
So to access anything which is any object which is declared inside any class, we have to use this keyword
in order to access them.
Now setting the layout, of course.
So we have to set a layout for the class.
Yes, the cards.
And this is the card.
And again, adding all of the panels to the frame.
So adding all of the panels to the frame is done with the help of this add keyword.
So we have added all of them home help, schedule time and then all five of the panels inside the frame.
With the help of this art and this public word show, it is going to show this card.
So, yes, all of them are appearing in the form of a card where there is this and it's this.
So all of them are appearing in the form of a card.
So this show it function is going to make them visible in the form of cards.
So this was all about the mean class.
Now, in the next part, we will be creating all the other required classes.
So I'll see you in the next part with the rest of the classes.