Hello everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction of the application part and working on the
project part pretty well and must be wondering how to start coding a section of this application.
So now in this part we are going to start the programming execution of the application, which we name
build a canvas tool using Java.
So here we are going to make a paint interface which is going to be a similar application to RMS paint,
which we are using since childhood.
So yes, in this ID welcome window, we are going to start like setting up our project by making the
classes like functions calling and all objects, definitely as we are going to follow the principles
of object oriented programming while making this project.
So we will keep this in mind that everything revolves around objects and classes.
So on your screens you can see the welcome page of Visual Studio Code compiler, like it is the ID inside
which we are going to start coding our project.
So yes, on the welcome page we have to click on this Explorer button.
Basically it is an icon on the sidebar of the welcome page.
So on clicking this, we will open up our interface which will contain three buttons overall.
So we have to select Create Java project from these three so that we can start creating our Java project
inside this ID.
So yes, on clicking Create Java project, we came across various options like they are basically the
supporting tools or we can call it them as build tools.
So there are several tools in Java such as Maven, Springboard Quarks and Micro Profile.
So these build tools basically come up with templates or like already written templates.
We just have to use the call the templates and write the code in like write that text inside the templates
and everything will be like already made a kind of code structure.
But in our this project we are going to work directly with the source code.
So we will be choosing this no tool option as we are going to like start without any tools.
So on clicking that notepad tool option, we will come across our file chooser of our system.
So it will be asking for our location where we want to save our our project.
So choose a location like correctly, like in a letter switcher.
If you wish to find your project in your system, then you have to like navigate to that location to
find the project folder.
So I am choosing desktop as the location of my project folder.
Hitting on the select, the project location or text field will appear in the ID is input field, so
it will ask for a Java project name.
So in this text field we have to enter a name for our project.
So let us type any name like we are going to build up.
Bean canvass
tool.
So I have named this folder as paint canvas tool.
We are going to make a canvas basically for the drawing.
Like for painting.
It comes up with shapes, colors as dimensions and everything.
And later we can save that in the form of an image.
So I choose a white name for your project.
Like this name should reflect that what actually this project is doing.
Do not name your project in an anonymous manner.
Choosing a fancy name could harm that.
Like it should reflect the actual meaning of the project.
So, like, be wise while choosing names of your projects.
So I have named Paint Canvas Tool.
You can name your projects in any manner.
Just keep in mind that it should reflect the purpose of that specific project.
So on hitting enter, we will land up inside our project folder.
Okay, so this is the welcome page of our project folder.
It contains few inbuilt folders so we can see that there are four inbuilt folders and added mid-autumn
day file.
So these two folders, dot dist and dot vasco are due to the mercy of this compiler.
Like we are creating a Java project inside Visual Studio code.
So these two folders come up across with this Create Java project function of this compiler.
So these two folders have basically no use in our project, so we are going to simply ignore these two
folders.
Yes, they are of no use as far as I can see that.
So this folder as RC is going to be the main folder which is going to consist all the important files
and folders of our project.
So yes, this is RC folder is the main folder.
So keep in mind that while creating any file folder, you create it inside this RC folder or in order
to make it like functional.
So firstly and this RC folder, you have to right click from your mouse and this dialog box will appear
asking for several options.
So I am going to select this new file option.
And the first class we are going to create is the main class.
So here our main classes, the drawing editor dot java.
So here the drawing editor dot java.
So yes, on hitting enter we are inside our main class drawing editor, dark java and.
So we have created a class called Drawing Editor, which is a public class.
Now, this class is going to be used inside other classes.
Okay.
So let us first look at our project window.
That how actually it is looking.
So what are the constants?
So basically we discussed this in the working of the project path that we are going to create separate
classes for this rectangle, oval and the line and a class for this drawing area which is going to be
saved later in the form of the pages so that we can access that dimension in the like later times now.
Okay.
So in the next class we are going to create is going to be the rectangle class which is going to handle
the functionalities of this button, which is the rectangle button.
So, okay, so let us create the rectangle dot Java class inside the Assessee folder as well.
So hitting on this new file option and typing the class names rectangle dot java and hitting enter a
rectangle class is created inside this file.
So okay.
So this rectangle class, we have to import few packages first.
So import java jwt.
Dark color.
Okay.
So it is a w t dot color which is going to import the color component of the AWP or.
So framework.
So basically this AWP stands for Abstract Builder Toolkit and this color is going to provide the color
feature inside this.
Like suppose we are coloring something so that color feature is going to arrive from this AWP framework.
So inside the Rectangle class, we are going to create some methods and then like call some arguments
also.
So yes, inside this class we are going to create a constructor rectangle.
So this rectangle object is going to cause some arguments such as in text, into y, into W and into
each.
Okay.
So these four are the arguments of this rectangle object.
Also other like arguments are going to be the colour C and non integer F.
Okay.
So here we are now inside this constructor, we are going to call a super method, which is going to.
Argument x.
Y.
W h c.
Okay.
So inside this we are going to use if f is equal to one, then R is filled, should be true.
So we will discuss this in our moment.
Let me first complete this coding part.
So as filled is equal to true.
Okay, so yes, this is the rectangle class and this is how it should be.
What is this, x, y, w c?
We will be coming to this.
Okay.
So this is the rectangle class.
Inside this we are having a constructor called Rectangle and the arguments are in text, in divide,
into W, in text and colour and F.
So let us come to the like practicality of this argument.
So what actually this edge is.
So here you can see a black coloured rectangle.
So that index is going to be defined the distance of this like x rectangle from the x axis.
So suppose this is the x axis horizontally and this is the y axis, so that x and y are going to decide
the like layout of this rectangle from the axis.
Now what is are the blue and edge.
So the blue is going to be the width of this figure, like this horizontal.
It is going to be decided with the help of this, the blue.
And that is going to be the vertical width of this rectangle, or we can call it as height.
So we have named this as edge.
Now the color.
So, okay, so if we have selected this as full or empty, so helpfulness F So if F is true, like if
is filled is true, if the figure is full, then this F is going to be called, this f is going to be
executed.
And otherwise nothing is going to be executed.
Simply a rectangle will be drawn.
So if the color is full, so we have to fill colors inside the borders of the rectangle, the return
height.
Should be the range of the color to be filled.
And that's why it is inside this super method.
So this super method is going to set the dimensions of the rectangle, whether it be the distances or
its like height and width, or whether it should be filled with a colour or not.
Now we are done with the rectangle class.
In the next thing we are going to be concerned about is going to be the circle class.
So here we are having three figures, rectangle or the circle and the line.
So the rectangle and the circle class are going to be simple and almost similar.
They are going to be like the circle, flags are going to be similar in the way this rectangle glasses
just the difference will be in the name of the class.
So just in the place of rectangle here we are going to write Circle and all the other arguments are
going to be same.
And even if this if statement is going to be the same, so let us create a circle class inside the society
for the Circle dot Java is going to be the name for the file.
And yes, here it is.
So let us copy the same code.
And just based it inside the.
Circle dot java.
Just replace the name of this rectangle.
That's good.
So I am going to use refactor.
Okay.
So perfect.
We have renamed the Rectangle Classic Circle and all of them are going to be the same.
So this was all about the Rectangle class and the circle class.
So in the prototype section, we have discussed that we have to firstly create a project in the ID and
we have did so then we have created the main class or we will be writing the code inside the main class
in a moment.
But initially we were concerned about creating the classes for three of the shapes.
So we are done with the rectangle class and the class.
Now for the third class we are going to create is the line class.
So this line class was bit different.
If you have seen in the working part the control panel was working differently in the manner of this
line class.
So the line class is going to be a bit different from this rectangle and the circle.
So yes, we will see that how that line part was like working and what is going to be the code for that
specific difference arising between the rectangle circle and the line class.
So yes, we will be saying it in the next part.