Hello, everyone.
So I hope that you all have went through the introduction part and the working of the application part
pretty well and have again much idea about what actually this project is about and what are the functionalities
which we are going to attach while making this project, what are the classes and what's inside the
classes or the like methods we are going to add in order to make this project properly functional.
So this is like the internal initialization of the programming section.
We are going to make a new project in our favorite indie Visual Studio code, and then after we are
going to like add classes and functions in order to make this system functional.
So this is the welcome page of our ID Visual Studio code.
And inside this welcome page we are going to create a new project on clicking this Explorer tab.
Our option will appear and we have to select Create Java project from that sidebar option.
And in inside this we have to like choose the type of build tools we are going to attach in our project.
So this is our basic project.
You, we are going to use code Java in the programming section of this project.
So we will not be attaching any external build tools.
Otherwise we have several tools in Java such as Maven, Spring Boot, Cox Micro Profile, and these
are a lot like very important tools in making most of the projects.
So yes, in this project we are going to work with the source code directly without any build tools.
So we will be selecting no build tools.
Now after that, a file chooser of your system will open and ask you for that.
What is the location of the project you want to keep of the folder which will be created, which will
be containing all the files regarding this project?
So choose our like correct location for your project in order to like if you want to find that project
in future, then you can find it without any mess easily.
So I am choosing desktop as my project location and on hitting the Select Project Location button.
We will enter this input field which will be asking for the Java project name.
So choose our like a good project name, which is going to be the name of the folder containing the
project.
So like Choose Your Name Wisely, which defines your project that what actually this project is doing
so that if in future you like going through all of your projects just by listening to the name, like
reading the name of the project, you can like remember everything that what is happening inside the
project.
So do not choose any fancy or anonymous thing as a name of your project.
Just simply name your project with what actually the like files are doing inside the project.
So I am going to name this project in management system.
So a data management system is going to be the name of my project.
You can choose any name for your project according to your choice, but to make sure that it defines
the meaning of the project pretty well.
And there should be no anonymous kind of names for the folder.
So a data management system is my choice of name for this project.
On hitting Enter we will enter the window of the project which we are going to make.
This is the folder management system.
There are some subfolders inside this which are like already present in this kind of folders on creating
this Java project.
So we have created this project project on hitting this Explorer option from the sidebar and then creating
a Java project.
Now selecting a location and naming the project.
We enter this project like interface in our compiler.
So this dot day standard has codes of.
Borders of this project are due to the mercy of this compiler.
We are having no use of these two folders in our projects.
These are just like in folders of the compilers which have no use, zero use for us right now.
So yes, they start based on the dot vs code folders can be ignored right now.
Now after this, the SLC folder, which is going to be the main folder of our project, this SLC folder
is going to like contain all the main files or the folders which are going to be involved or containing
the classes and functionalities of our data management system.
So basically we can understand this as this folder is the body of this project.
And inside this body we are going to have different body parts which are going to like handle this complete
system.
So inside this RC folder there is already present file and this file is containing a class called F.
So the name of the file is after Java and it is containing a class app.
Inside this class we are having a function, a main function which are containing string as argument
and this will run whenever this application will throw a runtime error.
So we are like handling the exceptions with the help of this app class and whenever there will be exception
this will print.
Hello.
So we can like signify that yes, there is some runtime error.
So we have to like debug things and try running the project again in order to avoid any kind of exception.
So yes, this is going to be like the structure of the project once you create a new Java project in
the beginning in your compiler.
So now what actually we have to do, firstly, we have to like we have discussed in the prototype section
that we have to create a main class which is going to be responsible for testing and running of the
program.
So the main class is going to be the class, of course.
So I am going to name this class as a theme dot java.
So the file is created and we are inside the file.
We have a public class item created already and this class is going to like, as we said, responsible
for testing and running of the application.
So yes, now inside this class we will be creating a main function, of course, whereas we have to
create a main function to like test and run the program.
So public static, void main and again string arguments are going to be parsed inside this function,
a square bracket and acts of course.
So the arguments are strings and this will throw exception.
Are you exception?
And this iOS exception will be thrown whenever there will be like any kind of exception all while running
of this project.
So inside this we are going to create Option Menu.
So we have discussed already in the prototype section that we are going to integrate every options inside
the options menu class.
And that option menu class will be responsible for handling everything about the care like inputs and
the like functions attached to every choices.
So option menu.
And this new method is created inside the main class now calling the introduction.
And the introduction will be called as a method or the constructor.
We can say that or we will be creating this inside the other classes.
So option menu.
Yes, dot main menu will be like reflected as soon as we execute the program.
So we will be creating this option menu later in this project.
Just in the main class, we are making things clear that what is going to happen whenever we run the
project.
So is the introduction class or the function we have created is going to be like containing our sets
out.
So since out is the shortcut for system dot dot print, which is going to like print anything to your
terminal or the output window, we can see that.
So let us like capitalize everything welcome all for a better like view.
So welcome to the Eden Project.
And yes, so welcome to the Eden Project.
Exclamation mark goes well with it and here we are.
So we are done with the main class.
So as far as I can see that of yes, you can see that we have called this exception our type of exception
handler.
So automatically this Java exception package is imported to our class and what actually this import
does.
So in case there is any kind of input output exception as we are like inputting values from our keyboard
and according to that the compiler is outputting the like regarding function to that specific choice.
So everything is going to be handled with the help of input output function.
So any kind of exception will be handled with the help of your exception package of the Java Library.
So yes, this is going to be our main class.
This will be like running at the time of testing and running of the project.
So let us first create some like real working things to the project.
So the second concern was to create an account class.
So account dot Java is going to be the name of the second class we are creating inside this account
that Java.
We are having our account class and everything about the like we have mentioned it that this account
class is going to handle the types of account, the customer verification process and the operations
regarding the balance calculation will be mentioned inside the account class.
Only the exception handling for the invalid choices will be also handled inside this account class.
So yes, everything will be handled.
So our first step should be like declaring some global variables inside this account class.
So we will move forward with the help of this private access pacifier integer for customer number and
for a pin number.
So initially we were being asked for a customer number and a PIN number and both of them are going to
be integers.
So I will be copying this.
And again for a PIN number, just changing this customer to pin and things are going to be working the
same way.
The third and the fourth integer like double global variables will be checking balance and savings balance.
So private.
Double.
And checking balance.
So checking balance and saving balance in the similar way.
This should be in small and initially the checking balance value will be set to zero as initially we
have no balance in our account.
Once the user deposits the money, then only the balance will be updated, whether it be the savings
balance or the checking balance.
So here we are done with the declaration of all the global variables.
Now the next concern is to introduce the scanner, which is going to like scan the choices inputted
by the user.
And then our next concern will be to get and set all the values which we have declared here, like the
variables, customer number, pin number, as we have declared everything as private in the beginning.
So in order to access these variables on objects, we can see by any other classes we have to use,
get and set method in Java so that it can be accessed by any class without any exception.
So yes, we will be seeing that in the next part.