So our project is basically we are going to create a chat application.
So we already created three classes server client chat message server for the server establishment client
is for the user side and chat messages for the handling the all the chat messages.
So I created three classes so we can see three Java files here.
So for first, I'm creating this
which is basically server file.
So as I told you in previous sessions, I did this and I created a constructor I am creating or start
each and everything.
Always remember the start and some run are both are related to the.
Basically related to the what we can say trading concepts.
So after this, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a function to stop a server.
So I'm going to create a function to stop server.
Again, it's protected.
Protected.
Stop.
Then you know, there is one function keep going is equal to also, I'm telling you.
Including because all segments should be and then new socket.
So this I'm going to mention local host.
Which all.
And.
What I'm going to do is.
Etch.
Exception.
E.
System.
Dot dot intel n e.
So we handled this exception and I created to stop this.
Then I need to create.
So remember why I created the projector?
Because I'm going to use inside this.
Only I'm not invoking inside the client, but so I can use this edge protected also.
So.
The specified is protected.
This lay.
Even console.
I can say or we can say message console private.
Or.
Display.
Do.
I'm bringing message here.
But I need time.
So basically string time is equal to def dot format.
And so this what I'm going to do is I'm going to specify this new.
Date.
As it is.
Let's.
This list.
Even, you know, this space also.
What is?
So we have created this zone.
And what I'm going to do is nothing but system dot.
Not telling.
Fine.
What I'm going to do.
I'm going to bring.
So now I am going to create a synchronized thing.
Are you going to say?
Who brought up cost.
Message.
To all.
Our clients are basically private synchronized.
What?
Why?
It should be synchronized, I will tell you.
Bullion.
Broadcast.
Because I'm going to handle it in a thread so it should be synchronized always.
So I created synchronized string.
Really created images.
So I'm creating your message.
Now timestamp is very important at Timestamp.
String.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this because I'm going to use this again.
Sort of broadcasting the message.
That's it.
And.
What I'm going to do is.
I'm going to check messages, private or not to check, because I'm going to create a constraint which
can be like you can send message private.
That is see to see c klein to Klein, basically.
So what I'm going to do is for such purpose.
I'm going to split the message.
I will tell you what is the significance of this and I will split this message as this.
Now, what I'm going to do is.
If character is this what is the basic thing is basically is it if you put something name like.
And John.
Or you can say at their expense, John.
But added John, then space message.
Private message.
So I'm going to do this so it will help me.
Like that and limit is three while I'm reaching the limit is threes, as you can see.
One, two, three, four.
So like was that it should not be exceed.
So I'm using this and.
Now let me use some.
Okay.
So I will use your.
I will tell you.
What is this?
All things.
So if private mention st mention username only using this so it will go to that particular part and
we loop in in order to find the mentioned name.
Basically, I'm checking in the reverse loop to check the username throughout the client head and I
will tell you what is the gate username and each and everything here because I haven't created any client
yet.
So I will create that and I will tell you what is this basically.
So this is all about this.
But what if a message is not found?
Is.
Let me do one thing here.
If the message is not phoned, what I'm going to do is I'm going to display something.
I already created this part, I will tell you.
So.
Okay.
Wait a minute.
So this is all about how we can do this.
So if this is true, I'm going to mention this.
What if.
If I'm printing else something else, basically.
It should be given some.
KING So what I'm going to do is if message is broadcast message, it should be printing something now.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to use this part.
This is basically part if if message is not private, it should be broadcast.
So it will be directly put out to the client and it will go to the right.
And I will tell you what is inside the client read only.
So I will tell you what is the significance of this.
So this is all about how we can create this.
Now I'm going to create one log out method also here.
To create one log out thing.
So let me go with the log out also.
Well, this is the end of private and everything.
Okay.
Now.
So let me explain all these things.
So we already created this method.
If you know that's what is starting.
This is what the starting of the server.
So we're starting.
Then this is the constructor, basically, as I told you.
Then these are all about of starting.
Why?
It's because I'm using some default libraries here and while keep going now I'm doing this and printing
stops and each and everything.
And then I created a protected void to stop the server.
Because while I'm doing this, keep going is false.
It will stop the server.
Now this is display console message and to broadcast message.
All I'm going with this is the format and F and everything.
If the message is private, I'm splitting this.
What it will do.
It will check something and each and every year first.
Then what it will do is it should be zero plus.
Two means basically that length and it will time plus message.
It will print boolean found is equal to false.
Because I'm stopping that part and I'm reversing or I can looping the part in a reverse to check that
client through the client ID and using it username and I'm sending to that particular username only
found if found.
Deliver the message and basically break the loop.
If found is not equal to to be basically major is not user found.
It should be written false and false is basically nothing.
But if message is a broadcast message, not with any edit or any symbol, it is going to print this.
And what it will do.
We will look in a reverse order to remove the client also because it is disconnected.
If it's disconnected, it should be removed from the client thread.
So I'm removing to the client and client thread is nothing but ArrayList, which is handled through
the throughout the client threads on each and everything.
Then I created one logout method.
Your string disconnected and each and everything.
And similarly I can use this remove part.
As you can see this remove.
It is basically system default thing here and we can save our which is basically ArrayList.
We can put remove here and has broadcast the message.
This notify is equal to that is basically disconnect this.
Room or we can sit chat room.
This is all about how we can do this.
After this.
What is remaining thing is.
Or I need to create a server and to run a chat application for the server side.
I need to mention some things.
So what I'm going to do is I'm creating your PCM, basically public static void main.
Then what I'm going to do is here.
I need to mention some.
Things.
What the things I'm going to mention is what number?
Then switch gears for argument length and each and everything.
So I will mention here or number.
Is equal to 5000.
I'm mentioning 5000.
You can check your boat number, then switch case and each and every thing I'm going to mention.
Your.
So let me use this first.
So what is doing this?
It is going to pass that inside this if exception found invalid number java server port number is not
found here.
Basically it will print.
This zero.
It's basically since you said java server because it is not using and server object to start the server,
it will start that object easily.
Server is basically this.
So we have we are done with this part, but we are remaining something here which is basically.
Okay, let me check which is this part again.
Somebody said, it's over.
And this is part this part is not it at all.
And this is inside.
And it should be in privacy.
So we created this part.
And now what is remaining things we need to create one client right then, which is basically we need
to create a one class for that purpose.
And we already did this.
But now the client trade and all the things are remaining here, which is basically very important and
we are going to create this and now we can stop this basically, which is basically public class and
each and everything.
As you can see, our client is missing.
Now, I'm going to create one client trade also here.
If I'm removing this.
As you can see, nothing is.
Displaying error.
So this is all about and we know remaining with some errors, which is basically not declared already.
Now I'm going to declare that part.
So this is how you can delete this part or you can do this part basically.
This is basically server side.
I'm creating one ArrayList int for unique ID date format or number and keep going format.
I'm using your localhost, so no need to mention each and everything.
As you can see, I'm using localhost only.
You can change the port number through this.
So what I did this is I created Zoom to start the server basically because all the things are mentioned
here only.
So once it is started, all things are embedded in this only.
So what I'm going to do now is I will do I will create one client class which some methods like get
user name right message, then all the things like stop and each and everything username also I need
to mention.
So I will go with that part.
And in the later part I will tell you it's very big code as I as you can see, I already done our own
design, but it will help me to run all the processes on the server side and the client program will
be very easy in this part.
So in the next part we are going to see some client things also and chat message things also including
I'm going to create trade also here and before that I will explain the trading part also.