So in the previous part we have created the item class, which is going to be responsible for testing
and running of the application.
And then we have created this account class which is going to manage everything about the calculation
thing and the input output management.
So we have created some global variables such as customer number, pin number, checking balance and
saving balance and like initially setting a value of zero to go to the balances.
Now this scanner input method is going to scan the input by the user, according to which the choice
which is input and the function will be performed.
So we have created this account named constructor.
So this account object is containing some arguments such as customer number, pin number, checking
balance and saving balance.
So all these four are going to be the argument of this account constructor and we have accessed all
four of them with the help of this keyword.
This keyword is going to access all the objects which is declared inside the class to this account object.
So now we have covered like creating the class, creating the constructor, passing the arguments,
and then like accessing the objects with the help of this schema.
Now after that, we are going to use set and get the methods for accessing like get the method is used
for accessing all four of them in other classes and set method is used to update the values accordingly.
So the first thing we are going to like get is going to be the customer number of course.
So public int can get customer number.
And this customer number is already declared variable.
So get customer number.
Is used to like access that private specified variable, global variable.
And this is going to simply return the customer number which the like suggestions are showing.
So we have a get the customer number.
Now after that, we will be like getting all four of the global variables we have declared.
So I will be copying this and pasting for four more times in order to like access all four of the global
variables which are specified as private.
On formatting.
Yes.
So after the customer number, we are here for the PIN number and this is going to return the PIN number,
of course.
After which we are having double.
Double date start time for the check ins balance and savings balance.
So yes, for the checking balance we are going to use checking.
Balance.
And this is going to like help us to access the checking balance.
And similarly, the function will be returning the checking balance.
So I am pasting into the see was small.
Yes.
So similarly, we are going to like use this double method.
For the savings balance, just replacing this, checking with saving and also health.
So we are done with getting all four of the global variables we have declared.
Whenever it is needed by any other class of this project.
Now, our second concern is to, like said all four of them, we have use get for all four of them.
Now the next one is to set and that set method is going to help us to update the values of these for
whenever we need it.
So like in the next step.
Public.
In.
Gus said customer number.
And this is going to update the.
And we have to pass a like argument inside this as customer number as this set method we are using to
update the value of the customer number.
And this keyword will be again used to access the customer number first and then setting this to customer
number again.
And on the next step this will return the custom simply like the gate method was doing.
So with the help of suggestions, everything is so convenient saving it.
And yes, we have great method for customer number and set method for it also.
Now we are going to use this similar thing for the PIN number.
So yes, just changing the customer to pin here and everywhere.
Just simply replacing customer pin.
Also the brain is in danger, so nothing is going to throw exception in any manner.
So bin again.
And setting it to.
Also this is going to return the PIN number.
So replacing.
So here we are done with getting and setting off all the like private global variables.
Now our next concern is tools like yes for calculating the checking with zero.
So here we have two types of accounts checking and savings.
Now suppose if the user inputs one and he or she wishes to withdraw funds from the checking account.
So we have to set our like mathematical calculating function, which is going to like calculate the
amount which will be left in the checking balance after that specific withdrawal.
So public.
Double, which is the data type for the balance.
Get checking balance.
And like we are going to calculate so public double calculate the checking balance.
Just replacing this.
Get it, calculate.
And here we are.
This is going to contain our amount as argument.
And this is going to be a double data type.
Again, inside this calculating function, we are going to like update this checking balance.
So checking balance minus that amount, the user inputs for which to draw from the checking account,
of course.
So after this, let us enclose this inside a bracket for a better code representation.
And this is going to return the checking balance after the successful withdrawal.
So, yes, this is the method for calculating the share, like checking the.
Checking withdrawal.
Not the balance which to draw.
This method is for the bit to draw.
So yes.
And here we have balance.
So after the withdraw, the balance is going to be updated.
So this is the method for calculating the checking with the draw method.
Now, in the similar way, we are going to calculate the saving withdraw.
So I will be copying this same function and pasting it here for calculating the saving withdraw.
So just replacing the checking with her saving and Korea.
So, yes, this is for saving.
The argument will be amount no change there.
Just the checking part will be changed with the saving part and everything will be just remain same.
So yes, this is the function for calculating the saving withdrawal balance.
Now we are done with the withdrawal balance calculation.
Our next concern is to calculate the deposit balance for both the checking account and the savings account.
So, yes, we will be doing that.
So here we are done with savings deposit and like checking deposit where we have already covered the
saving withdraw and the checking withdrawal function.
Now similar way we have checked the deposit.
So for the withdrawal we have to subtract the checking balance from the amount which is to be withdrawn.
And for the deposit, we have to add whether it be the checking balance or the savings balance with
the amount which is going to be deposited as deposit is to the bank and withdrawals away from the bank.
So yes, that calculation is performed in that manner.
Now for calculating the transfer, whether it be from checking and savings.
So for that, we have to like check two things.
We have to subtract checking balance from the amount.
If the transfer is from checking account and if the transfer is from the savings account, we have to
subtract that amount from the savings balance.
And the second part of this thing is the savings balance will be updated with the amount which is transferred
from the savings balance to the saver, like checking balance to the savings balance and vice versa
for this savings transfer.
So yes, that subtractions and additions are going to be performed in a similar way for both the types
of transfers.
Now our next concern is to like we have performed everything about the calculation of like withdrawal,
deposits and transfers.
Now the next thing we are going to cover is to create a function for getting the withdrawal input from
the checking and savings accounts.
So yes.
Okay.
This get method is used to get the withdrawal input from the user and we are like checking our exception
kind of thing for the input which the user like made for withdrawing some money from the checking account.
And we are going to do similar for the savings account withdrawal as well.
So suppose the user input some money like he or she wants to withdraw ₹2,000 or dollars from the checking
account.
So the system is going to try.
Yes, the current checking account balance will be printed in every step.
We have already like discussed this in the introduction part and the money will be yes displayed in
the form of money format and checking balance variable is called her system is going to return amount
you want to withdraw and this is going to like the kind of scanner it is going to scan the input from
the user.
So yes, it will be asking for the amount to be withdrawn and it is going to check that whether that
input amount is a valid or not.
So first thing, it is checking that the amount is greater than the balance.
So suppose you have 10,000 in your account and you are willing to like withdraw 20,000, then this is
not going to happen.
The balance is greater than the like.
The withdrawn balance is greater than the account balance.
So this is going to be checked inside this try and catch exception handling methods.
You also the balance cannot be negative.
So yes, that's what I like.
Yes.
That said about so the balance will become negative if the withdrawn amount is 20,000 and the already
present balances 10,000.
So it is going to like output.
That balance cannot be negative.
Enter a valid input to be withdrawn.
Similarly for the savings account, we have the same trying catch exception method for the savings account
in the similar way of the withdraw input account.
So checking some savings accounts works in a similar manner.
So this is for checking deposit.
So yes, similar the way we we were withdrawing the money.
We are going to deposit money to the checking account and this is going to ask like current checking
account balance.
Oh yes, it will display the current balance and after which it will ask that what is the money you
want to deposit to your checking account?