So in this video, we will be talking about the next three classes of this project that is homegrown
Java, Add, customer or Java, and we have customer Java.
So let's start with the home file.
It is defined inside the package cab booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages and after that we have defined our home class, which is extending
the frame.
There is a string type of variable username inside the public domain is a method we have called a new
home with the null value and set the visibility as true.
After that we have defined the public home with the parameter string username heading as cab booking
system and the set setting the current instance of username to the past a string username.
After that there is a foreground color setting as callachan and set the layout as null.
Then what we are doing is we are setting an image with the help of image.
I can image objects passing that image to a new label and setting the bound and location size for that
label and adding that label to our frame.
After that there is a labor transport gap and there is a labor setting for around colour for it, which
is white and fond family type and size for it, setting bounds for that to set its location and size
and adding that to our new label.
After that, we are creating a menu bar and setting that menu bar to the frame.
After that, we are adding a menu element named as customer, setting its foreground colour as blue
and adding that to our menu bar.
Now we are defining the.
Menu items for that menu element.
First is add customer.
Second is update customer detail.
Third is customer detail.
Fourth.
Delete customer details.
So these are the menu items inside the menu element customer.
So we have added these menu items to that customer menu element respectively.
And when am I one?
Am I too?
Am I three?
And am I for respect for that customer, updated customer view customer and delete customer details.
Then we have defined action over this.
Menu items so far am I one?
We have defined the action performance method inside which we will be calling new customer with the
current user name and set the visibility as true.
So we will be adding a calling the add customer class with the current username if the action is not
performed, is on menu item one.
Similarly, if the menu item too, then we will be calling new update customer with the current username.
Similarly, if the menu item is three, then we will be calling.
View customer class with ten the visibility as to if the menu item is selected from the phone and action
performed on it, then we will be calling new delete customer and set the visibility as to after that.
What we are doing is we will be creating another menu element as book and recap.
It said the foreground colour is as red and background colour as sorry, adding that to our menu bar.
After that we are adding menu item inside it.
That is a book cap and another menu item as will book the cap.
Then we have defined adding action performed over the menu.
Item seven.
If the book tab will be chosen, then we will be calling new cap with the current username and the visibility
as through.
After that we will be defining menu item five X and performance method and inside which if the View
book gap is chosen, then we will be calling new book The Gap class with the current username and send
the results to.
After that, we have defined another menu element as book intensity gaps and the foreground color as
blue and adding that to our menu bar.
Similarly, it is also having three menu items will caps book gap and will book gap.
So if the view gap menu item action performance is on the Gap menu item, then we'll be calling our
View Gap class and set the visibility as true.
And if the menu item nine will be executed event on menu item nine, then we will be here.
Define the action, perform the event and we will be calling Candlestick Cab with the current user name
and sell the visibility as true.
And if the will book the cap class is a menu item has been selected, then what we are doing is defining
the action perform method and calling the intensity booked cap class and with the current user name
and setting is visible.
It's true.
Similarly, there is another menu element as transport setting its foreground calories red and adding
that to our menu bar and containing two menu items book package or billboard package.
So if the book package menu item event is performed on the book package menu item, then we will be
calling our new tracking class with the current user name and set the visibility as to if the event
is performed on the booked package.
Then we will be calling our tracking details class with the current user name and set the visibility
as true.
Similarly, what we are doing is there is another menu item named as Bill and we have set the foreground
color as blue and adding that menu item to our menu bar.
After that, it will be containing a menu item check bill.
So if the event is performed on that check bill menu item.
So we will be calling our new check bill class with the current user name and set the visibility as
true.
There is another menu item as the payment, so we will be setting the foreground color as red and adding
that menu item to our menu bar.
And then we will be defining its menu item.
Pay the payment inside that payment menu element and we are adding that menu item to that menu element
payment.
We are defining the action, perform method and call our payment class if the pay the payment menu item
is being selected or even performed on that.
At last there is another menu named as utility set the foreground color as blue, adding that to our
menu.
But it does contain three.
Yes, it will contain two menu items, notepad and calculator.
Adding that to that menu element.
After that, if the notepad will be selected, then we will be calling or executing runtime red dot,
get runtime and executing the notepad file.
If the calculator is being selected, then we will be executing our calculator, which is a standard
calculator.
Then there is another menu item M7 labeled as about set the foreground colour as red and menu, adding
that to our menu.
But it will be containing a menu item about and if that about event is performed on that about menu
item, then we'll be calling our new about class and send the results to.
After that, we have set the exchange strategy from that, maximized both.
And after that we have set the visibility as to and get the content bands at the background color as
white for the window.
So this is all about the home dot Java class.
Let's go and move to the add customer class.
So here is that customer class.
This class is defined inside the cab booking system.
We have imported the necessary package whose classes and methods will be we will be using in this file.
So the class add customer is extending the frame.
We have defined the connection variable as null and prepare the statement as null.
There is a one private panel type of panel variable and the text field a text field.
There are one combo box and two radio buttons and the one choice.
Inside the main function we have called the Invoke Invoke Letter or enable and define the public run
method inside which we have created the current instance of that customer class and set the visibility
as true now inside the public, add customer which is throwing a scale exception we have defined, we
have printed the user name.
After that we have set the bound for the frame.
We have set the content panel and adding that to our frame.
After that, set the layout as null.
Then we have added an image to that our ADD customer class and added that image to a label settings
size of the label and location of the label and added that label to our frame.
After that there is another label as new customer forum for which we have defined the font, family
type and size, setting its location and size and adding that to our content pane.
Similarly, there is a label for the user name, setting its location and size and adding that to content
pane.
With respect to text field, there is a text field seven setting its bound size and location and adding
that to our content pane and its maximum size as ten.
After that, there is a label ID for the ID setting its bond size and adding that to our content pane.
Similarly, there is a combo box which is storing a string array named as passport, Aadhaar card,
voter ID and driving license and setting its bounds.
Which will set its location and size.
After that, what we are doing adding that combo works to our content pane.
Similarly, there is a label for the number setting its size and location and adding that to our content
pane.
Then there is a text field, even setting its size location and adding that to our content pane and
setting its maximum size to ten.
Then there is the label label for the name, setting its size and location, adding that label to our
content pane.
Similarly, there is a text field for that respect to name label, setting its size and location and
adding that to our content pane and its maximum size is ten.
Then we will be setting a label for the gender and its setting its location size and adding that to
our content.
Similarly, there is a R1 radio button that is labelled as male, setting its font, family type and
size.
After that, we have defined the background colour as white and for setting its location and sizing
added that to our frame.
Similarly, there is a radio button for the female as well, setting its font type size and family.
After that, we have defined its background colour as white and settings, location and size and added
that to our frame.
There is a label for the country as well.
So setting its bond size location and after that add that to our content pane.
Similarly, there is ad3 text field setting its bound location, size and size of that text field and
adding that to our content pane.
After that, what we are doing there is another label for the permanent address, setting its bound
location and size and adding that to our content pane.
Then there is another text field setting its bound size location and adding that to our content pane.
Then there is a label for the phone number setting.
It's bound.
And adding that to our content pane.
Similarly for the 30 text field and there is a label for the email after that there is a text field
to enter that particular email.
We are setting its bound and adding that to our content pane.
After that, what we are doing inside the blog, we are creating the connection and executing a query
with the help of the results.
Set instance select extract from account where username batch and over the over those accounts in our
account table.
We are storing the username and 37 text field and name and 32 text field.
After that there is a button defined as ADD and for that we have defined the action performed.
We will be creating a connection with our with the help of our icon class and a string radius equals
to null.
So if either one is selected, then we will set the video to mail.
If ARP is selected, then we'll send the US female.
Inside the block.
We have restored the required information from the text field combo box and the radio buttons to our
respective string.
And we will be stewarding those values with the help of the query insert into customer buy, which will
help us to install the values in our customer table.
And so that show that dialog box that customer added successfully.
If the any exception, I got an email so that please enter a valid number.
Then we have set the location for the buttons and background and for controller added that to content
pain.
Similarly, there is a back button which we inside which we will be just closing the current instance
of our class and we have set the bound for the exit button background and for controller and adding
that to our content pane and its current foreground colour as of the complete window as white.
So this is all about that customer class.
Let's move on to the view customer class, which is defined inside the cab booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages here and after that the customer class is extending the frame
and we have defined the variables of table label and everything is there after that.
Inside the Void Main, we have just created an instance of the current table set.
The visibility has to.
Then we have set the default close, operation exit on close.
After that, we are defining the panel empty border, adding that to our panel layout as null.
Then we have added the image with the help of label and setting its bounds and adding that label to
our frame.
Then there is another image.
We have added that to our label and that is found bound and added to our frame.
After that, what we are doing is we have defining a table, setting its bound and adding that to content.
And similarly inside the trip log we are creating a connection and there is a query select extract from
customer.
We are executing that query and setting it to our model.
With the help of the result set to table model, that class will set the model for this window and then
there is a button as back button.
So inside which we will be creating just the set, the visibility as false.
After that, we have set the bound for the button background and foreground color of the button, adding
that to our content pane.
Similarly, there is a label for the A user name.
We have set its bounds and adding that to our content pane.
Then there is a label for the ID type, set its bounds and adding that to our content pane.
Then there is another label as a number that is bound sending that to our content pane.
Similarly, where we have done the things for the name label, a gender label or country label address
label or phone label and the email label.
So with the help of these labels, we will be showing the details of all the customers which are present
inside our database.
At last, we have set the background color as white.
So this is all about the three classes which we have discussed in this video.
We will be discussing about the next classes in our next videos.