If the user selected the other part, and if he wants or she wants to convert it to the US currency
or let's say to the Nigerian or to Brazil or the Caribbean, so, etc., etc..
So we have 2.9 countries one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So we have to write a single logic for all each of these.
So it will be longer and simply if the here we have take the Nigerian part also it should also change
it to another these nine countries and here Canada to these nine.
So it should be a long thing.
So what we can do, we can do one thing here.
We will take the first currency and simply convert it to the points here and then let to get to the
pound to the second currency here.
Right.
The first currency converted to pound and go to pound to the second currency.
So what we will do, we will go to the our project here.
We will.
Here.
We have to first convert currency, right?
So
convert currency to double name.
It has to amount to change.
And we have to get the text right to right get text.
Sorry.
First two.
First currency tax regime has.
Text first, girls.
You could not get text where we can get our text to buy these smarter calling and convert to the.
We have to pass this or write, download or stable here and pass this thing as the parameter.
So we have done this part.
It's no deal.
What do we have to do when you when we have to take this amount in this area, will we have to change
it to the pound also?
So we will take a variable name, double amount in pounds, and initially we have to put it to 0.0.
So it's done.
Now we have amount to change and it go to the pounds and now what we have to do, we need another variable.
We have to first take another.
We have to take another error also to back here.
The party simply right.
No, simply to
name it as the US dollar and put the values here.
Nigerian
Nido.
These are the values.
Simply you can change it to the current one also.
Brazilian real.
Need to double Ghanaian
shilling initialize to one 32.53.
No one should be named to the new.
Mission repair rate inserted to the one nine.
Big trouble.
Indian rupee.
And it to the.
And the.
Cindy Biscoe, you just won.
Let's say to 92.23 another.
The last one will be over Pakistan rupee to double.
Pakistan
will be subjected to
122.
So we have to clear here on thing.
We have to clear these because we have to take these values as a multiplication.
So we will go to the design here and you go to convert here.
So now what we have to do, firstly, we have to write the amount in pounds and then we have to convert
it to the pounds.
So what we will do switch.
And.
Okay.
What's the first one is the first country we need.
Most country don't get selected item.
No
get selected item and convert it to the two string.
Okay, so here, this thing is done.
Now we have to write the cases.
So the first case will be of us.
And simply write us.
The right amount in pounds is equal to amount, amount, whatever the amount the user give.
So here amount to change.
So we have to divide because we already have.
These one don't happen to smudge dollars.
So what do we have to do?
Right.
So go to here and simply write Divide and you will send us this one.
We have initialize it.
And it's now another case when we
we already have these this one value here.
So simply it gives the calculation with dividing the value so we can get our amount already in the down
here.
So another thing which we can do, we have to take firstly, we have to take another such case.
And here we even get a second look.
This one gets selected right down to two string here.
We have to check.
Check the case
if it is in India.
The user selected India.
No what we have to do if they're already user connected to that phone.
So we have to convert it to the Indian rupee.
So take another variable.
The amount changed here changed and equal to 0.0 initially.
And now what we will do here, we will try it among the changed and now we have to take this amount
in pounds value here.
So we will right amount in pounds simply multiplied by the Indian rupees.
Okay.
So we have to convert it to the Indian rupee so we will take
this one, this Indian rupee simply multiplied by this.
This is
these variables only contain of £1 value.
Okay, so.
So now we are to do these similar things.
Just a second.
Firstly, we have to convert it to string.
Also, so do string value and write
string.
Not for married.
We have to.
We are doing this thing because if we get the amount in value and the amount and bounce, it will go
with the point after point values will be printed.
So we have to decrease it and fix it.
So what we will write here, percentage or in two?
And coma among you changed.
Soon it will dawn here.
And now we have to set this value in the.
Okay.
We need that.
Text
16.30
set text.
We need set text and give the value to the value.
So it's done simply.
We will run our programme here and we will check the programme.
So if we choose a USA simply to and convert it to India here now we will convert this and record the
113.30.
So it's working, right?
So simply click exit and now we have to do this similar thing for every nine countries.
Right?
So we will do that thing here.
Mostly we have to write another case and simply write Nigeria.
Right Mountain sequel to.
Amount to change provided by the Nigerian one.
Nigerian naira have not tried to take part.
Okay.
This one lone break.
Another case will be.
Next case is over Brazil.
So huge the same thing amount in bonds equal to
amount to change and simply divide it to the Brazilian real and it's done.
Simply break.
This network is going to be Canada.
Mountain farms.
To change.
So do.
Do Canadian, I think.
Maybe we have not set a variable here.
I think.
Well.
Okay.
We're five.
So the next thing will be the Canadian dollar
and simply get the value, whichever the current value.
Me mean the double.
Go to your
now Canadian dollar and simply copy this.
Do it for another one.
Now, another one we have is a Kenyan.
One inch long and the next one is the donation.
The next one will be our India part and simply.