Hello, everyone.
So in the previous part, we have looked up to all the objects which were declared in the class label
and as an extension to this class, we have extended this as different as we have to set a frame, layout,
size, location and everything will be attached to the frame and the frame is going to be like added
with the help of this Java showing frame import which we have already imported.
So this class has extended to the frame and which is going to implement action listener.
So action listeners are going to be attached with all the buttons and labels that are embedded in this
application.
We can see that we have buttons, we have radio buttons, we have a check box and everything.
So these are all are going to be made functional with the help of action list, not implementation.
Okay.
So we have already made extension as the frame and implemented the action listener.
So to implement this action, we have to call this override for like this is a function public word
action for font is the name of function which we have to declare like as a necessity in order to implement
this action is not our main class.
So this override is basically overriding one function over other.
So this is our main function.
And to attach actions to it, we have to write our program inside this action performed function.
And the argument is going to be E which is event performed with each action.
So that is the event and every event is attached with a function or action.
We can say it anyways.
So yes, we have made everything like clear till now.
We have set the size of the frame, we have set location, we have said the title.
Okay, so we can set title according to our choices.
Like here we have order as our project title.
We can set it anyways.
So suppose I want to set it as food ordering.
System.
To make things like more appropriate.
So I changed that title for our application.
Now to initialize this application, we have to make a dedicated function inside this label class as
well.
So let me first initialize this image to make the error vanish.
So it is going to be a public void function of course, and inside this init function.
So you can see that the error has vanished.
Now inside this init function I am going to initialize like we have what we have on the top.
So we have select size or like label on the top.
So firstly we have to initialize it label size and it is going to be a new jailable.
Jailable label is also a component of the Java String Library.
So the new label is going to be the new object and the like.
Text inside it is going to be select size, select size of what we want to order.
And there are three options.
We have discussed it already.
So a label that labels the combo box.
So we have a label to our combo box.
Now we have to set a size for this again.
So we have to like similar where we have to label size dot set size as we have done here for our main
label.
So dot set size and dot set select location is going to be attached here in a similar way.
So we have successfully set data size for the select size combo box.
And a location like that is it has to be located on the window, which is going to be the application
main window.
And similarly we have added this label size to our frame.
So in order to add everything to our frame, we have to do this.
Every method is going to be added to the frame with the help of this add keyword.
So we have created this size thing and now the next step should be like adding inputs to the combo box.
So string inputs are going to be added for sizes.
So the sizes are we are three sizes option, I think.
So they are small.
Medium.
At large as far as I can see that.
So we have to like name all the sizes option inside this string sizes thing.
And now after adding names to the sizes in the next step, we have to in the similar way, set size
and set location and then add this thing to the frame also.
So these drinks are going to be consistent inside the combo box like you can see it.
This is a combo box component.
And inside this we are having springs, small, medium and large as the sizes of the menu items.
Now size dot select index is set to zero like the argument inside the select index is set to zero.
This means that by default the size is going to be small, so that should be a default size to the items
that should be open.
Like this is the opening window of the application and by default it is showing small in select size
combo box.
So this is responsible for that thing only.
So size do not select index.
So index is zero.
We have 3012 indexes for small, medium and large.
Basically this is a string area we call it is a collection of like events, inputs, strings, integers,
doubles, longs and everything.
So we have string array and it is going to contain zero one and two indexes small has index zero.
So this is set to default as small.
Now this is the size of the combo box location of the combo box.
And at last we have added the size to the frame.
So I have already discussed it that this is responsible for adding everything to the frame of the application.
Now we have successfully added this select size label in our frame.
As a next step, we have to add this select which type of beverage you want to order and after which
are like radial button options label is to be added to our frame.
So our next concern should be adding a label, which is going to be a label, of course, and this label
is going to contain a string which is asking for select that type of like drink you want to order,
so type of drink you want to order.
And this is going to be a label added to our frame and a colon.
So this is the label and or similar way we have to set the size for this label and location also.
So we have added a title to the label.
A size is set for the label and a location is set for the label that where it should be located on the
window.
So head this is located.
This is 100 from top and from the left it is 75.
This is the size layout.
Also, we have added this to the frame with the help of add keyword.
Now our next concern should be creating radial buttons and we are going to import our group object which
we have like declared already globally.
So we have.
Successfully called our BETAINE Group here.
We have declared this group as a private global variable.
Now our next step should be adding items to the radio buttons.
So like, suppose we are adding radio drink juice and calling it as our juice and we are going to add
a new.
Radio button.
So that frame and the string should be added as argument, which is going to display the items beside
the menu button, like the button and the name of the item should be displayed side by side.
So we have successfully created our first radio button.
Now set the size for it as well.
So our deduce at size dot set size is going to set the size.
And suppose we are setting it as 75.
Trauma 50.
So this is going to be the size of the radio button in the similar way.
We have to set a location and add this radio button to the frame.
Now, in this similar way, we have to add three more items to the menu.
So I am copying the same thing three more times in order to delete things one by one.
So the second item is suppose what the third one is.
So P and the fourth one is coffee.
So yes, just rename this everywhere.
And now after renaming every, like, the radio button and setting a unique location, a dedicated location
for every radio button, the size of the radio button is going to be same, but the location should
change.
Like from top, it is going to be one 110, but from left it is going to shift some like how many pixels
we are shifting it.
Suppose you have 100, then 175, then 250, then 325.
So initially we have this distance has 100, then 175, then 200 and then 325.
So this is the location of these buttons from the frame's left to border.
Okay, so now for as far as I can see, that we have created the frame items still here.
Now, our next concern should be to add these radio buttons to the frame.
So our next concern is that only to let us try to add, okay, so we have added all the buttons to the
frame with the help of these ten group objects and we have declared this meeting group head.
Okay, so we have declared this.
Hair also.
Yes.
So this button group is the name of the component which we are using from the library package.
Swing and in group is the name of the object.
So we are adding everything to the frame with the help of these B10 group keyword.
Also, our next label asks for how many glasses of the specific item we want to order.
So in this similar way, we have created a G label.
Here we are creating a label for glasses also and asking how many glasses you want to order inside the
label bracket in a form of a string, setting a size for the label and location for the label from the
frame like top and left border and adding this LP l glass to the frame.
Also a text box is added which is going to take input as how many glasses we want to order.
Like this box is responsible for that and we have also set the size and location for that box also.
So till now we have covered everything for select size and the type of item we want to order from the
menu as radio buttons and number of glasses.
We want to order as we have covered this thing.
Now in the next part we will be covering the button parts like how to add buttons and how to make them
functional.
And there comes the importance of this action event.
Like we have to attach some actions to those buttons and then complete like ordering process, which
is the main concern while making this application.
So see you in the next part.