Hello, everyone.
So we have already created our project in the ID.
We have created our main class, which will be responsible for testing and running of the application.
Now our next class, which we will be creating, is the Contact Java class inside the CRC folder.
So that I already said that we are going to create all the important files inside the CRC folder only.
So, yes.
Yes.
So after hitting enter this public class contact is being created inside this AC folder and this file
is going to contain all the consistence of the form or whether it be the first name, lastname, email,
phone number, address, the address and at last the notes.
So we are going to like declare all of these fields inside this contact class.
Later we will be creating a contact constructor which will be like calling, like accessing all of them
inside the constructor.
Then later on we will be using set and get methods in order to like access and update all of them,
whether it be the first name, last name, web address inside any other class as we have to access all
of them in other classes also.
So in order to do that, we have to set and get them all like in the first part so that only we can
access them.
We have already discussed the setters and getters in Java.
Set methods are used to set like update the values.
So suppose we want to update any of the fields inside the log in form, contact form then set.
The method will be called again and again, which will be setting like the updated values to all the
text fields and gate methods is used to access that specific set data to other classes.
So there are more than one classes.
So in order to access all of them, we will be using certain methods.
So this contact class is all about creating the like labels of the font here this and set and get methods
for all eight of them.
So let us start creating this.
So inside this contact class, we are going to declare some global variables for the labels of the form.
So the first one is first name.
And similarly we are going to set eight fields for all eight of the labels.
So this is okay, so write it in camel case.
Or a better appearance.
And then I am going to copy this.
For seven more times.
We actually we have eight fields, so total of eight global variables should be declared.
Okay.
So we are here with five, three more to go.
So all of them are going to be in string data time, whether it be the name, phone number, address
or not.
Just simply update the names for the.
Like labels.
So email.
The fourth one is.
Okay.
So the fourth one was, I think phone number.
So phone number.
The fifth one was for the email or not email the address.
So address is going to be consisted inside this and for the fourth one web address.
Yes.
So we are done with the.
Address it is.
We are done with the six parts now.
Two more.
I think we have total of.
Discount.
First name, last name, email, phone number, web address, address and notes.
firstName, lastname email phone number address.
Okay, so only one is left, which is notes.
So let us update this also.
Okay.
So we have created all the required global variables inside this contact class.
Now our next concern is to create the contact constructor.
Okay.
So inside this contact object few of the.
Okay, so all of the eight declared.
Global arrivals are going to record.
Inside this.
So let us simply paste and remove all the public.
We are going to use all eight of them as arguments inside this contact constructor.
And.
Okay.
So let us come after fixing this.
Okay, so here we are.
We have created this contact constructor inside this.
We have passed all of the labels of the form as arguments.
First name, last name, email, phone number, address, web address and notes.
And we have used this keyword to access these all of the variables from the contact class.
So in order to access the variables or we can call it as objects of the class inside our constructor,
we have to use this keyword.
So this dot first name is the way to write and we have done it for all.
Okay, so three, seven of them.
So, yes, after this, our next concern is to like a set and get method for all seven of them.
So we are going to use public string.
Forget first name.
This is for getting the first name inside the.
Like any other class where it is being asked for.
The class will call this get first name and it will be accessed.
The.
And this is going to return the.
Simply return the first name.
Other string.
So.
First name.
Yes.
So we are done with using the gate method for the first name.
Now the next part is to set this first name.
So in the next line, public set, first name.
And this will be helping us to update the first name whenever it is required.
So the data type so argument is going to be the first name.
And inside this set method we have created.
And this is going to.
Update the first name with the help of this keyword.
So whenever we require the first name, we will be using this keyword to access this from the contact
class.
Okay.
So set first name.
And okay, so this is a void function and this is not going to like return anything, a void function.
So I hope you have all been aware about that.
Void functions do not return anything.
So yes, they simply like will be not returning, but just updating the first name and this get first
name is not a void function.
It is going to return the first name.
So yes, this dot first name.
With a set of first name.
After the update.
So yes, we have used the get and set method for the first name.
Now we will be using the get and set method for all of the labels.
We have declared her the last name, the phone number, email address and everything.
So here we are.
We have used the get and set method for all of the labels we have been declared, whether it be the
last name similar where we have like set last name and this is going to update the last name which is
being passed as document later.
Similarly, for the email and for the phone number for address and web address and notes.
So all of them are in the string format.
So it becomes easy for us to like copy and paste the same snippet just to changing the argument and
the name for the function.
So yes, all seven of them are done.
Now, at the end we have to like return.
What?
Yes.
So this is going to be returned here in the form of like first name plus last name inside the contact
repository frame.
So, yes, this panel is simply containing the first name, plus our space between them and the last
name.
So we have to, like, concatenate this in the form and then return this in that manner only.
So we are going to use two string function, which helps to concatenate strings and return the output
in the form of strings only.
So after that, using the tool string, we have to like use the override the keyword inside this override
keyword.
We are going to create a public string to string.
My third, which is going to return the name as a concatenated text.
So yes, inside this what we are going to actually return to inside this string function, we are going
to return first name.
Plus space between them and plus the last name.
Okay, so here we are.
We have completed this contact dot java class.
This will help us to set all the labels inside the contact information form and to get them whenever
needed by any other class.
Also the contact repository like.
Basically it is representing the view of both the form, both the divisions of the frame in the beginning.
So in the beginning we have this and what this will be consisting of all seven of the labels and firstname,
plus last name in a concatenated form in the repository sign.
So yes, we have covered this contact class.
So as far I can see that we have created the mean class and the contact class.
Now our next concern will be to like create these buttons, how these buttons are going to be like acted.
We have to attach action listeners to these buttons and then create a separate function for adding,
updating and removing inside the frame class, which is going to be the most important class of this
project.
So let us create a new class inside the society folder, naming it as a repository dot java.
And yes, inside this class we are firstly going to import the Java list import.
Java dot util dot list is the way to import the list.
List.
Okay, so here it is.
Java to list is being implemented.
Now what this repository is actually doing.
So this repository helps us to like get the functionalities according to which it is being called for.
Basically, this is going to be the structure of this repository and what this repository actually does.
So it defines a new, elegant type of method for storing, updating and extracting the data stored from
the application.
So whatever data is being stored in the application is going to be like.
Yes, here we are going to store up data and extract all of the data we are creating, whether it be
the information about the contacts.
So once we will clicking any of the three buttons, then the actions attached with these buttons will
assist us with the updated information.
If we remove any of the content, then it the repository will assist us with removing that specific
row from this repository block and a similar way for the update and admittance.
So yes, this the repository is going to assist us with our storing, updating and extracting that data
stored.
So yes, till now we have created three classes, the contact class, the main class and the repository,
which will be helping us to access the add and update and remove functionalities.
Now our next concern is to create the next class for handling this or object repository.
So here we have a code, all the functionalities, whether it be update or removal, and now the next
class we will be creating is going to be the object repository class which will be containing information
about how to add up data and remove data in the frame.
So yes, we will see that in the next part.