In previous sessions and tutorials, I told you how we can set up our project and we created an index
HTML for the loading page.
So it contains two links for admin log in, which is basically for teachers and students.
Log in for those students.
So let us see how we can show the student log in page.
So this is our student log in page.
Remember, this is JSP.
So we can include some Java.
Classes on weekends in Texas, also year.
So we can do that.
So this is all about the case and I'm using bootstrap just for all these things.
And this is tiny because I don't want to create another file for CSIS so I could be embedded here only.
So this is all about.
But remember, what is this?
If our gate parameter is null, like if we are not putting something on username or password, it should
enter enter username and password first.
That's all the message things here and because dot get parameter is getting parameter from that part.
Similarly again, this is for if our validation is successful, it will show the message in the green
part.
So this is very important part for my actions, which is using validated student as action.
So what is this first USB dot controller?
As I told you, we are going to create when.
So package insert package which contains another package controller which contains validates through
the controller, is basically controlling all the parts.
So I'm dividing my for my convenience, although Java codes, Java servlet codes.
So the user ID field which takes username and password, which takes password, if I click exit, it
will go to the first page and if I click submit, it should go to the that part and validate that part.
So similarly for the admin page, as I told you here, I'm going to use method validated.
So let us see how we can create validate student part.
So valid for the validate student you just need to create one.
So package inside us and controller and you can create new hours on it.
So I'm importing all libraries here, then I'm importing.
All packages.
So here I'm going to use database package, which is what is database package?
So it will contain all the database searching part and model contents, all the log in and log logic
and everything.
So what is it?
Student It's actually overwriting.
I'm using overwriting method here.
So validate.
Student Will use this validated student as a super method and then using the due course method, I'm
going to search that you name and first name.
And for this I'm going to create students which is basically checking that part.
I'm using Boolean path here.
So this is just for the what we can see controlling part of that JSP.
If our organization is correct, it should go to the student instruction.
JSP.
Further, I'm going to create one student instruction in JSP file because if you know, like you on
some online portal and you just click that on the login, it should go to the instruction page or something
like that.
It should be needed if not go to that part plus message with message like invalid user.
As I told you, this message should be printed.
So these are all about the validates.
Let me say this.
So.
I'm overwriting method.
Remember that you can override this method with the serial version id and these all things are the same
and default.
As I told you, no need to change these things, but you can change your own things here and your own
logic.
I'm using this logic.
So these are all about value.
Shouldn't same as validate admin.
I am mentioning all the libraries because you can use star, but I want to specify each and every library
here.
So I use this.
Then which extends to a should be solid similar method it takes you name or from admin login jsp.
You name and pass this name and pass it will take it will check for that admin.
It should go to the admin panel if username is correct.
And if not, it should go to that same page admin login.
So remember in so lit you have to use forward method.
Here you have to use response dots in direct.
If not, you are going to use the same direct to that particular part.
So no need to include that forward and include method only to use that part.
You can use only one method.
Send direct part here.
So again, this is the STB session is handled as in JSP or Java, I can tell you.
So in due post you have to use gdb session.
No need to use http servlet and all these things.
I'm I'm using http solid to fetch data, but for the forwarding part you need to use this.
Which attribute also.
Your attribute should be same because I'm going to print attribute like welcome student or welcome that
admin part.
So this is all about this.
So let us see how we can create one database featuring part and everything.
So before database teaching part, I need to mention the connection.
Or we can say we need to create connection.
I am using here another dedicated Java file for the connection.
But why?
Why I'm using this.
So in each and every connection, like for I mean, then students, then questions, then instructions.
All of these are stored in their database.
So for all these purposes, for storing the questions and everything again and again, I'm going to
create a connection.
So if I use methods and I implement some object oriented logic here, I can easily create this method.
So let us see.
First, create is DB or file here.
Why I'm specifying this package because.
I am going to use as a sub packaging material, so it is not DB for storing the databases file.
So this is another my provider.
I am switching that provider, this provider.
So this is good.
You can always use this actually.
No need to specify everything.
Just put this.
It will ask for everything.
And I am including the libraries.
This very simple thing then provided as a class study connection, basically, because you know, for
that purpose you need to create connection, get Oracle connection, basically.
Then connection.
It should be it.
You are.
I can told you it should be allowed.
You can directly put connection here.
Also know or do that all things you can put connection and is equal to this.
But I'm creating this part again.
Right?
Always handle the school connections and with inside the try only or you can use throws also here but
I'm using edge as a exception part exception catching part.
This is for Oracle database then this is system, my user name or that Oracle database password for
passing.
Then this is all for get connection user read pass.
If this is correct, it will show that connection is successful inside this.
If not, it will provide some error or exception inside this out.
But what we can say our command prompt.
So I'm creating one dedicated I have created already this part for connection so this is our provider
is over it or dedicated connection java file for builder connection.
So let us see how we can create admins.
Java file.
So inside the admin java.
What I'm doing is.
I am featuring all from that database.
Or we can say we are providing it into the database and I am returning it.
So this is very simple part which I already created.
It's very, very easy.
Which is basically pre count.
So this is very basic thing and username and password and I'm putting the git username, string username,
gate password, set password as our primary sensor.
So I'm just using that variable and I'm assigning to another variable.
So this is very easy.
Students.
Dot Java is also SIM, which is using this database, but it's very easy.
I'm just doing same stuff as admin.
I'm putting in this and I'm returning that part and I'm storing in dedicated same string name and all
these things.
So this will be easy.
Same for the question part.
I'm what for the question great question is for the great question.
State question is to set the question like the question for user side, but or we can say student side,
but that question is for the admin side or teacher's side.
Get a means for optional then say it for that purpose.
Get B for.
No student said before another student, get c, c, c, get D.
I'm currently sitting the four options only get answer answered answer.
That's it.
So the answer is for sitting that answer or get answer for admin part.
Then instructions draw Java.
So.
This again, same state instruction guides instruction.
So the book contains all the files which just creating the connection part.
So this is all about this.
Now, let us see how we can create one thing here, which is basically admin, the one student deal.
So I told you about that.
How we can create admin java file and remember why I'm using this admin here.
So if you see the admin is where it is used.
I'm using this new admins and I'm set username and I'm setting the password.
So when I say so, I will put your.
Creating.
Object.
So this is setting the password.
So why am using this?
Like I'm switching from one, I'm setting it to the another variable and I'm using this.
So it is very common method in Java.
If I'm using the same variable, it will change its value again.
Then again, like if I put admin username and password is Edwin and I want to change that part, but
I want to store that admin admin, I want to add it or append it in the admins so it will help.
If I'm not using this part like I'm switching from one variable from I'm fetching data from user side
and I'm storing it to the same variable and I'm using same variable again and again.
Then there can be an anomaly or we can say there can be some security issue.
Also, like you can easily find the answer of our questions or anything.
So putting into the another file, it will create some dedicated file for that purpose.
So I'm setting this username and password method.
And I'm using that validated.
So I'm using this part.
Or and it will send to the admin panel.
We will create an admin panel for that purpose and further reduce use.
I'm going to tell you how we can develop a JSP files only because we are mostly done with our Java files
required I think, or 2 to 3 only remaining for that purposes.
And in the controller we required to create some log out, log in all out for admin, log for student,
then question insert method student insert method also and some instruction insert methods also.
So that's it.
But mostly we are done with our Java file, so we are now only focused with our JSP files only.
So this is all about how we can create.
So let us see how we can create student the method.
I'm going to use method to validate which is basically boolean which tells us status as false or so
what it will be do.
It will checking for the connection.
Then db provider as I told you and student Pat.
So it will help me to check everything and I am passing in line object you can say for that or inline
thing.
So do you basically construct or not?
So I'm going to use this again, as I told you, as the get user name from student method and get password
from that student method as a let us see how we can.
I told you here this is get username and get password method.
So I'm using this.
So from provider dot get Oracle connection, which is basically our provider dot java file only.
So this will use this again.
Recognition.
Then no need to require to create another thing like as I am using this DB dot provider which is basically
specific file, I'm using your I'm not mentioning only DB here so I can use this provider to get connection
here which is basically fully defined name.
Or we can say I'm using this string to fetch that part.
I will again print here like a school.
So this is clearly for the user ID and password.
So in for other things, I'm going to create tables in the database.
I will tell you which queries you have to use and this is all for the setting.
The name Evo is due to set name, which is basically we are setting name here and our string string
is equal in the name basically.
So it will return true.
If not ls false, it will catch the statement.
Similarly for the insert student, I'm creating another thing because I don't want to create one another
file to insert students and everything.
So I just created then get all records from the ArrayList because from the student table I want to check
for all student lists.
I can use a list here.
Similar thing you can use and remember always first time clear that and again printing that because
there may be some two names also inside that part.
So I'm using this.
And delete records.
I'm adding the delete record method also and get student name method also you are then do update new
record because I want to update new record also.
So this is all the methods you can minimize methods you're also.
So this will be the part you can check for this.
It's very easy, but it takes too much time because I created in only one single method, which is basically
student video.
So this is all about student in further batch I'm going to create you can create how you can create
the admin part, then inserting part and everything.