So here is our reception java file.
So.
Let's start explaining it.
So package hotel, it is defined inside the package hotel inside which all the classes and Java files
have been defined.
We imported the Java String package as SQL Package eight Event Package and Abstract Window Toolkit Package
to provide a graphical user interface for this window, we have defined the class reception, which
is extending the frame initialized panel named as content pane, which is a private instance variable
of this class.
Inside the main method, we have initialized the object of the current class as new reception.
Then we have defined a non parameterized constructor named as the same the class name reception setting
the bound for the frame.
Initializing the new panel setting, setting the content pane, setting the panel into the frame and
setting the layout of the panel as null.
Then we will creating an image icon, then adding the image icon to the object of image.
Adding the image again into that another image icon object and adding that image icon into the.
Jailable.
Setting the tone for the label and adding that label to the frame.
Now here is the button object variable named as button.
New Customer Forum Label as new customer form.
Adding the action listener to the button.
Whenever action performed in this button, we will try to open the new customer class as this button
will be used to enter the details for the new customer.
So new customer class will be called in this setting, the visibility of the customer will be true and
current window as false catch block for handling the exception.
Then we have set the bond for the button.
Its background color as black, foreground color as white, and adding that button to the panel.
Now another button labelled as room, adding the action listener to the room.
Whenever any action performed on the button.
If the room button will be clicked, then we will call the Room Java class of our project so that the
room information can be visible, setting the visibility of the room class as true and current window
as false.
Catch block will handle the exception if any occurs.
Setting the button for the button and the room button.
And.
Background color of the button foreground color of the button.
Adding the button to the content pane, there is another button labeled as all employ and for similarly
adding the action performed event where if to imply all employer info button is clicked, then the employer
class will be called and visibility of the employer class will be true and visibility of the current
class will be false.
Catch block will underline the exception if occurs, setting the bound for that all employer info button.
Background color of the button and foreground color of the button.
Adding the button to our panel.
Third button has the customer info.
Similarly, we have added.
The customer info class.
It's called the customer info.
Setting the visibility as true and setting the visibility of a current window as false.
Catch BLOCK will handle the exception setting the bound for that button.
Background color and foreground color of the button and adding that button to our panel.
Next button is managed in Photoshop.
Have a look on a number of manager and list of manager details of manager adding the action event onto
that manager.
And similarly we have setting the bound for it for run color and background color, adding that button
to the work content panel.
Then we are button for as checkout, similarly adding the action event bound of it, foreground color,
background color and adding that button to a panel.
Similarly for the update check, we will call the update class, set the bound for the button, adding
the background color and foreground color and adding the button to our content pane that is a panel
next button will be updated.
Room status will be whenever event performed on that button.
Then we will call update room class.
And set the bond for the button, set the background color and foreground color, adding that button
to a panel.
Similarly, for the pickup services, we will handle the event by calling the pickup class.
Set the bound.
For the pickup.
Button background color and for of outfits and adding that button to our panel.
Then we have search rooms and for the search room, they will do the same thing and adding the button.
Background color and foreground color, adding that content pane add button search room.
Then we have a number number seven, that is logout.
This will take us back to the login page as we have called login class here.
Whenever any event is performed in this button, setting the button for that button, adding the background
color and foreground color and content, adding that button to the label, setting the background color
of the complete window as white, and setting its visibility as true.
So this is our reception.
Plus, let's move to the ad driver's class.
Here it is, a driver's class.
It is defined also inside the package hotel importing the necessary packages.
Abstract Mental Toolkit Swing Swing Border Upside Toolkit Event as well, class and class.
Then we have defined the class which is extending frame and implementing action.
Listener panel is private instance variable content pane text fields 20 23334 Combo box combo box and
combo box one button be one and be two and choice of C one.
Inside the main function, we have declared a new object of the driver class and setting visibility
as to inside it.
We have defined the non parameter as constructor setting the bound for the constructor.
Sorry, setting the bound for the frame and the window new panel and sliding the new panel.
Setting that panel into the.
Content paint and setting its layout as well, adding an image to our frame and panel, setting the
bound for it and adding that to our frame.
Another label as ad driver setting the font for it, bound for it, and then adding it to our panel
and.
Another panel has labelled as name setting the colour for it for round colour and font type family and
size of the font setting the bound for it and content adding the label to the panel.
Next is the text field setting the bond for the text field and adding it to our panel set.
Next is labelled as age foreground colour for it, background font, setting the font for it and bounding
its position and adding it to our panel.
Next is the another test text field setting bound for it, adding it to our panel next to the vendor
setting foreground color.
Setting its font and its bound and adding it to a panel next to the combo box.
It will select ratio buttons like male or female.
So for the gender you either can select male or female setting bound for it, adding that combo box
to a comma panel, another which is a car company for one color, for eight font family, for it type
and size, setting the bound for it and then adding that to a panel next this text field.
Bound for it, adding that next to our panel.
Next is car brand for its fallen color, its font, family size and type.
It's bound and adding that to our panel next is text filled for the car brand setting the bound for
it adding it to our panel next is label.
Which is available, setting foreground for it, font type for it, and adding that bound adding it
to the content pane panel.
Next to the combo box one either yes or no setting down for it and availability.
Either you can select yes or no and adding that combo box one to our label.
Next location driver location will be written in this.
And similarly we have added foreground font bound and adding that to a panel.
And there is the text field for.
Location field.
Now we have added a button to add this will button handle the event for add action setting the button
for it, background color, foreground color and adding that button to our frame.
There is also more and more button that is a back button adding a listener to it, bound for it for
background color and foreground color.
Then we have added that button to our panel.
Adding panel background color as white.
Defining the action performed.
Method.
If the event sources from women, then we will stabilize the connection.
Take text text field as name and age.
Gender.
Company.
Brand availability and location from the respective fields which we have discussed about in the seminal
same class.
Create a query as SDR.
Insert into driver values.
Name a gender company brand and available and its location.
Execute the query using the.
Connection.
Not a statement or execute update.
Passing that string.
And.
Should I lockbox that driver I did successfully and set the visibility of the current window as false
if an exception will be handled by the catch block.
If the button if the event sources from button two, then this window will be closed.
And another exception if an accession occurs.
Let's move to the add employ Java class, which is defined inside the Package Hotel.
We have imported the necessary package.
Extended the frame and there are text fields one, two, three, four, five, six text fields and one
comma box.
Inside the non parameterized constructor we have added foreground color as blue background color as
white title as an employee details and default operation as hide on close.
Set size setting the size for the window layout as null.
There is a label passport number that is a name setting font for it, bound for it.
And adding that to our panel and another text field for the name setting, it's bound and adding that
to our panel.
Then there is a save button that is setting bound for it background and for one color for it adding
to the panel.
Similarly, we have a large label of edge text field of the respective age gender for the.
Imply and adding a radio button either can be male or female.
Hear the radio buttons of male or female and address.
Of them blow and a string.
Cause this is the combo box.
A string.
Cause either the employee can be a front desk clerk.
Porters, housekeeping, kitchen staff, room service waiter, waitress, manager, accountant or chef.
So this is for that label nationality that is equal to annual salary.
So this is for the salary, the text field perspective for the salary.
Phone number.
This is label for the phone number and its respective text field.
Then there is a hard it's respect to text field.
Then there is an email and it's respect to text field to add the email, write by email, setting the
visibility of the current window as true.
And then there's a.
Employee details.
Citing employee details and the image icon for the current label, adding that image to the frame.
Then next we have added action listener and action performed method in which we have fetched the respective
fields of the employ from text fields.
And if the new radio button is selected as male, then gender is male.
If a female is selected, then gender will be set as female.
Then we have checked for selected item from choice one and establish the connection with the database
inserting those values.
Into the table employee sharing the dialog box dialog box has employee added, catching the exception
and setting the size of the window visibility as true and location and inside main function we have
created the new employer.
Let's see how the reception page will going to look.
Run this file.
Let's.
So when we run this file, this kind of form will appear.
So inside this is the reception.
Now let's look at ad drivers.
So when we run add drivers, so it will look like this where we have it.
Name, age and record company carbon availability location.
So that's how a driver class will look at employer class will look like.
This.
So this is the added class where you can select.
This is the job.
Which type of job will he or she will do?
So this is the.
It is.