So here we have a stretch of the wall text reel and this all in the previous video.
We have seen it and done this thing.
So now what we will do, which we have created here, we have to build the UI part also.
So what we will do, we will create the image class.
So here what will do?
Image button, create a class by the name image button.
And here I have created this class.
Now we have to do first thing.
Firstly, image button.
Inherit the class.
No, inherit the interface by button, which we have used in the earlier class.
So it will import this.
And now what we will do.
We have to create the private string.
Niemeyer.
Does the style normal?
Okay.
So here I will do one thing and right style.
Normal and set.
It's the value here.
The fix a new style background.
We will write the background color here and set this thing to transparent.
It's done and afterwards we need the padding part also so right the padding attribute and set its value
to comma two, comma to, comma to and extra.
And after that, we need another thing.
So it has to be the uppercase string we need.
Same thing, but we will need what we are doing.
Firstly.
Okay.
Just write me.
Let me write.
We will give it to the press.
So what we are doing the buttons which we have created, the bag, the forward and the reload button
here.
I have given this the style normal run.
It's showing something the button it's created in the rectangular form and then it's showing the normal
form.
We have seen it in the right form or something, but when we press that button, it will react with
the UI part.
So here which we are, what we are doing, then it's a normal, we have set its colour to the transparent
and it is operating now here we will do another thing.
Then we will press when the user presses that button here, something which will give it the effect.
So here we will write the effects by background colour.
This thing inside it's the value to the transparent of force transparent.
And afterwards we need another thing that is the padding part.
So padding and sets this value 3113 so it's done this done.
This is also done.
So now another thing which we will create our image button costs by image button method.
So here what we'll do, we will take it as the each button method and give it the parameter as the image
and orange.
No.
Amy Grant here.
Another thing which we need the high end of.
So we will set it to a double edge and double W.
No, we will give it some body, of course.
So here I will do the image.
You set the new image equal the new image view and give the parameter to the original image.
Okay.
So.
We have to import this also.
So we importing this import image to the beauty.
Okay.
Something I will do one thing.
That image.
This one even imported from the Java text or seen image.
Not that part.
And here it's done.
So put the semicolon and afterwards we will give it the height and the width.
So we may not set foot height to the achievable image dot set foot width to the W variable which we
have initialized.
And then use the set preservation.
We need the preservation tool.
So the preserve ratio set it to the true and afterwards we need the graphic, but also the set graphic.
Okay.
Give it some better meter to image and lantern.
And afterwards we will.
Set the style and give it the parameter style.
Normally.
So this thing.
The style normal.
Okay.
We have.
Make it to the case.
I have done it in the lower case and it's done so here.
We have to give the action here and also so we will call certain mouse pressed, the user will interact
with the mouse pressed, even not clicked.
So we need the mouse pressed event here, this event handler and set to the event Arrow, said Stein.
What does this do?
This one and that spring which.
But we need the press.
Well, not the normal.
This one, I will write the blessed value and simply copy this again and the user remove the pressed,
remove its finger.
It will set it to the normal value here, to normal thing here.
We have done this thing and you're ready.
Your interaction is done.
But another thing which we need is to see us as part two.
So what we need, what we have to do, we will create another C file in this folder, this RC mean this
the resources will go into that and create a new file name as the style c is silent.
S In this thing what we will do.
We have the bar and the scrollbar.
We have to give it the style also.
So here I am using this thing and what we will do.
We have to simply write our thesis part so we will write C assist or not bar and give it the thing to
the effects background thing by chrome insets and set it to the one, 1 to 1 here.
And another thing which we need is the padding part.
So here the padding and done and set it to the point to zero.
It will be enough.
And afterwards we have to give the style to our body thing also.
So here I'm using the body part and I use it to the X and the Y with the height and width part.
So overflow the blue and sorry the x one so related to the hidden thing.
And afterwards you need the writing also.
So set it to hidden also.
Here.
It is done.
Okay.
No space.
Sorry.
So everybody is done.
And the thing which we need, the scrollbar, which we will see it as the right colour.
So we have to give it colour also.
So we will write the scroll bar and get the parenthesis and set its word first.
We will take it as a 16 x and it will be show the string on another thing which we need to get.
Get on.
We will set the colour of the school scroll by track.
So here we set it to the background colour.
Background color to white this one.
So we have done our part parting.
Now what we will next thing we will do, we have to complete our browser class.
So it will be our last step.
And here we will do our last step.
Is the browser class created.