So here is our home Java file, which will appear after successful login in our login page.
So this home dot java is defined inside the package travel and we have imported the necessary packages.
After that there is a defined the class which is extending frame instead of is there instance a string
username?
After that in the main function, main function or method of this class, we have called the new home
with null values as a parameter and setting the visibility as true.
Then there is a public home, a string username.
Then we had a detestable end to his management and said the username as the correct instance for color
layout.
After that we have.
Created an image added into the label and set that into our frame.
After that, we have created the label for the Travel and Tourism Management Forum.
A lot of it font off it bound for it, adding that to our added that also to our label.
And then we have created a menu bar instance set that menu bar.
After that we have added menu element customer foreground color as blue added that to our menubar.
After that, we have set the menu items inside the.
Customer menu items will be first at customer update.
Customer details, have customer details and delete customer details.
After that we have added action listener on all of these menu events.
So for me one that will be add customer.
So inside that customer action performance event, we have called the ADD Customer class bypassing the
username and set the visibility as to.
After that, if our.
Update customer.
We have defined the action performance method and call the update customer class.
Set the visibility as to.
Similarly for the customer, we have called the view customers class inside the action performed event
and inside the action listener of the delete customer menu event.
We have called the delete customer class and then we have defined another menu that is a package menu
for calories.
Read added that to our menu well then defined its three items check package, book package and view
package.
For the check package we have called the check package inside the Excel listener for the book package,
we have called the book package Inside the Action Listener and for the view package, we have called
the package class inside the list.
And then there is another menu, the element as hotel for color calories blue and added that to our
menu bar.
It contains three element items as well both hotels we hotels and we booked hotels for the book hotels
we have called the book hotel class and inside the Excelsior and for the hotel we have called the check
hotels class inside the accent list.
After that, we have called.
We booked hotel class inside the hotel menu item access, and then we have added another menu as payment
and set the menu items.
Pay the payment.
Add that to the menu item.
And for that particular menu item defined the action upon which will call the new payment class.
And then we have another menu as the utility setting the foreground, color as red, adding that to
a menu bar.
Then it will have two items notepad and calculator and defining action performed on notepad and calculator.
So notepad will open.
The notepad calculator will open the calculator.
After that there is another menu seven which is for the about.
So.
This will just call the about page and setting the extended frame.
This will extend the frames and visibility through and background color as white.
Now we will be having a look on add customer java file so package it is defined inside the package travel
and java .8. bottom layout.
It will setup for the bottom layout.
We have imported the necessary packages.
After that we have defined that customer class, extending the frame connection as null prepared statement
as null private panel.
Text fills combo box and radio buttons.
Then inside the main function, we have called our class and set the visibility of the frame as to after
that inside the parameter constructor of that customer we have.
Set the bond.
And then we set up initialize the panel and its properties.
After that, we have added an image with the help of the label, and then there is the label new customer
setting font for it, bound for it, and adding that to our panel under the label as user name, it
says back to text field ID for ID.
There is a combo box which is containing the string passport, Aadhaar card, voter ID and rival access.
Similarly, for the another label that is number respective text field for the number, then there is
a name respective text field for the name.
After that, there is a gender labeled as gender.
For which we have radio buttons.
First is male and second is female.
Then there is the label country for which we have a text field respect to t three.
Then there is a.
Labor reserve room number.
Named as permanent address.
That's the label name reserved room ll be reserved room number that will not affect the label as permanent
address setting bound for it added to text field for that particular label.
Then there is another label for the phone number.
Adding text feel to it.
Then there's the label email, setting it and adding text filter for the email.
And then there is inside the try block.
We have initialize the connection executed the query select x2 from customer where username is equals
to username while are start next we will set the text as username and name and after that there is a
button new button which will add.
So when we click on add then it will call initialize the connection with the database set radio as null
if asked is selected if the selected is male or then we will set the radio as male.
If our to selected then we we'll set the radio as female.
After that, inside the try block, we have fetched all the required information from the respective
text filter and combo box and we have created the query insert into customer values which will help
us to insert values of the customer which we have just inserted by in our text file and combo box.
We will then execute update that query and show that the customer added successfully.
After that we.
Then we have.
But I knew that setting bond for it.
Background color for it.
Heading that button to our panel.
Then there is a button exit for which we have performed, action performed.
Setting the visibility of the current window as false and setting bound background for foreground color
for that button, then adding that button to a frame, setting the background color of the frame as
white.
Now let's have a look on update customer class.
So this is the update customer class, which is defined inside the package travel, importing the necessary
packages, update customer class connection, statement, prepared nerd and a private panel content
pane.
And there is a ten text fields inside the main function we have called our current class object customer
and set the visibility of the frame as true.
Then we have initialized a parameterized constructor for which we have defined image by the help of
label.
After setting the bound of the label, we have edited that to frame.
Then there is a label name update, customer setting font for it, bound for it, and adding that to
our panel.
Then there is the label username for which we have a respective text field.
Similarly for there is a ID label for with respect to which we have a text field, then there is a label
number for with respect to which we have text field and there is a label name for respect.
We will have a text field in respect of that table and then there is a label gender.
With respect to we have a text field and then there is a country and text field for it.
There is a permanent address text field for it.
Then there is a phone number, text field for it, and there is an email text field for it.
Then inside the block we have initialized the connection and executed the as to from customer where
it is invisible to username and we will set the information in our text fields.
All the nine text fields.
Then we will for the radio button.
So the button that is update button, we will define here the action performed for which we have initialized
the connection inside the block.
We have a store, the information from the text field on our strings respective in strings and created
the SQL statement.
So which will that is update customer set ID type that will the statement which will be executed by
using the connection class instance and the statement instance.
Then there is a.
The dialog box which will appear customer details updated successfully and after that we have.
Set the new button down, adding background color, foreground color and added that button to our panel.
After that, there is a bag button for which we have defined the action, perform the event, setting
the visibility as false.
Then there is an exit button setting foreground background color for that button that is black foreground
color for that button that is white and.
Added that Britain to Spain.
Then there is a get content paints at background color as white.
So these are the three classes.
Let me show you the output of these three classes.
So first is home class, which will appear after the successful login.
So I will be showing you by running this file.
So I will run this home file.
This is how the home file will look like.
As we have defined these menu elements inside customer we have four menu items ahead.
Customer Update Customer View Customer Delete Customer And inside package we have check package book
package will package hotels, hotels, waters and the bug totals inside payment pay the payment utility
notepad and calculator and add about will show as to about this.
App.
Now let's close this.
Let's have a look at the ad customer result of this ad customer class.
So I'll be running this.
Sorry.
This will be the output of the ad customer.
That is a new consumer forum.
You can right username select it from here and then a number of the ID and name select either male or
female.
I will be clicking on back.
We will be adding these details in our live video.
Then.
Let me.
Here.
Then let me show you the output of update customer class.
When this file.
Complete customer output will look like this.
This is how the.
The result of a great customer class will look like.
Where we can enter all the details of the user and update those details.