So here is our ad student class, which is defined inside the package university.
We have imported the necessary package.
Abstract Window Toolkit Package, Abstract Window Toolkit, DOT Event Utility, Random and Swing Package.
After that, we have defined our class, which is implementing action listener.
We have defined the instance of frame.
These are the labels and text fields, buttons and combo box instances which we'll be using inside random.
We have defined the random values to generate the student roll number by using math or math class and
inside the.
Public and student that is a non parameterized constructor created the frame background color layout.
Then we have defined the label inside which we have defined the image.
Add that image to the label said bound for it and its layout.
Another label it bound for it found its its font for one color, adding it to our label adding it to
the frame.
Another label has name bound for it, font for it, adding it to the label.
And that text field even respect to that name and adding it to the label.
Under the label as Father's name bound for it font and adding it to the label similarly for the respective
text field.
Then there is a label age setting bound font and adding it to the label respective text field then.
There is date of birth bound font, adding it to the label respect to text field for the date, date
of birth setting bound ending to the label.
Then there is an address bound for it, font for it.
I think the label is better text field for the address, bound for it, adding to the table respective
label as phone setting, bound for it, setting font for it and adding to the label.
Then respective text field for the phone number setting bound for it, adding to the label respective.
Then we have a label email ID.
And setting bond for it font and adding it to the label.
Then we have a respective text field for the email bound for it, adding it to the label.
Then we have a new label as class 10th setting bound for it, font off it and adding it to the label
after that.
We have respect to test field for the class ten math.
Then we have the bulk of Class 12 marks.
Respective test field for the class 12th marks are the high number labels we would estimate for that
number label.
Then roll number label, which will estore respect to text field for the roll number.
And this will add the roll number, which is starting from 1533 and add the remaining first, which
we have calculated prior.
Then we have label course combo box for the course label branch combo box for the branch, then the
button submit and button cancel adding the extension to both of the buttons.
After that, we had set the visibility of the frame through its size and location.
After that, we had action performed fetched all the required details of the student from our combo
box and text fields.
After that, if the source of the button is from we setting the connection, creating the query to insert
into the student table, executing queries, selecting, showing the dialog box that is inserted successfully,
catching any exception.
If any exception occurs, then if the one button is pressed that is for cancel, then we will set the
visibility of the current window as false inside main function, creating the instance and setting the
visibility of the frame as true.
Let's move to our next next class that is told in details class.
So inside a student detail class, it is defined inside the package.
University imported the necessary package that is a WTA event, swing and SQL.
Then inside then we are behind the class is student details extending frame and implementing action
now and three labels.
One table and three buttons, text field and a string.
Which will hold for the columns of the student details.
Any string of this area of a string, two dimensional area of string, 20 plus 13 inches close to zero.
Then we have certain details.
Had a restaurant setting size for its.
Location and layout.
Then there is a label.
In the role.
Number two, delete a student bound for it font and adding it to the frame.
Respective text field for the roll number.
Button delete background foreground bound for it.
Then there is the label new statement.
There is label a student.
There is a button at the student.
And there is a label update.
There is a button for update.
A student adding.
Excel listener to all the three buttons.
Now inside try block.
Initializing the connection, creating the query is storing it into a string is is one.
Executing the vary by using execute query method of using the statement instance and storing it in the
results set.
It will iterate over the records of the student table in the database and storing the records into the
two dimensional array by incrementing the columns at every line and at last incrementing the row and
initializing the column again to zero.
Then creating the table by passing the two dimensional array and the column area of a string catching
any exception if occurs.
Initializing a scroll panel.
Setting bond for it and adding that solar panel to the frame.
Background color is white and adding action to the B1.
Now action performed we first inside the connection.
If souls from B1 V fetch the required text field and create the query.
Delete student from student where roll number is equals to this execute.
To update that query, we will execute update method to update record in the student, delete the record,
set the availability of the current window false and the student details window as.
True.
Then there is a cash exception which will handle any exception because if the source is from B to we
will open the screen class from the B three, we will open the update in class.
Then inside the main function we have created the instance of the current class.
Now let's move to the teacher details which will look more similar, like the student details as well.
Define inside the package university we have imported the necessary packages a w t a w t event swing
and a scale.
After that we have defined the class teacher details extending frame and implementing Excel three label
one table three buttons text field a string exclusively used as column to create table and a two dimensional
array of a string 20 into 13 angles for row and column respectively.
That is integrated variable initialize to zero zero then inside teacher details heading into teacher
details setting size for the frame location of the window.
Layout as well, creating a label enter roll number to delete feature.
It's not roll number.
It should be employ ID.
So that will be the interim idea of the teacher, then setting bound for it.
Font adding new text field for the to write the employer ID.
Button delete add new teacher label button.
Add update teacher details.
But an update adding a listener to the three buttons inside the dialog in the connection selecting the
vary from the teacher executing that query is storing the required details inside our 2D array of strings.
Creating the table by passing the to the area and the column area.
Adding a scroll panel to the table.
Setting the background color as white.
Hiring action is not off the table.
Inside the action performed.
Initializing the connection.
If the saw is from B1, then we will fetch the required details in the string and a string.
Q.
We will execute the query delete from teacher where it is goes to the fetch details from the text field.
Execute obtain that query so the visibility of the current as false and the teacher details as true
catch operation will handle the errors if any occurs.
Sources from B2 we will call the teacher class.
Sources from B3.
We will call the update teacher class.
Inside the main method we have created the current class instance and setting the visibility of the
frames through.
Now we have discussed about all these classes.
Let's have a look on the run of these classes.
So let me run from the login class.
First.
This will be the result of law in class.
I'll be validating the details.
Click on login.
This is the result of project class inside master new faculty.
This is the result of ADD Teacher Class.
After that.
And you would imagine this is the result of adding a student class.
Now inside the detailed menu element, we have student details.
This is the result of student detail class.
So as there is no any detail not we have added any student.
So this is showing the back end table, which is upside down, is scrollable as well.
So we will be adding details in our library, which will be the last video of this project.
And similarly, we can check the details, teacher details as well.
So this will be the result of teacher details.
So.
We have seen the implementation and line by line explanation of this code of these three classes.