So in previous things I told you about.
I created this session with some user name, then submit part, log out part.
I'm going to play it here.
So I just added some more geosphere and I will tell you what in this post.
So this is pure JSP.
As you can see, there is not here.
So the create topic to create and topic todo is can then get attribute.
Please log in first if I log in or I'm just logged in.
Inside this parameter is topic and email.
I have to set the email and which is I'm going to perform this which is basically select store and I'm
going to create this topic.
So let me tell you what I'm going to do here is.
So this is all about this class and part, and this is the GDP sitting here.
So let me mention my password.
If you know your password you can use because default I'm just adding this system and Oracle system
is username and this is my password for the Oracle database to give the entry to the Oracle database.
Still, I haven't created this part, so I need to mention this topic each and everything using the
my listener part.
But I will tell you how I'm going to do that part in later.
So this is the same thing.
Then let me show you the delete things.
Delete thing is also similar.
I'm doing it again, okay, because I change it to the my team.
So this is all about to delete that part then for the discussion part.
Also, these are the all things here following the discussion.
So I'm just adding some random text here to the discussion each and everything.
We're.
So this is all about how I'm going to develop this.
Okay.
So.
Let me show you the phone.
Fine.
So basically fine name is to find the username.
And this is the oracle.
You need to understand this.
What is these things?
So this is the URL.
Or we can say driver here and this is the my prepared statement select start from this I'm going to
create and all the things I'm mentioned here.
Then the find name is also similar.
I need to mention my password here.
I haven't created any table inside that, but I'm using Java file only to create this and I will tell
you how I'm going to do this.
So fine.
Name one is for finding the name.
So all the teams are having some useful things here.
As you can see, this is very similar to this, but there are more usefulness for this that I will tell
you in later part
each find them as having their own functions.
But I will tell you what is the significance of this in later.
But remember that for finding each name you don't need to create each things.
But while developing this, I understood that for checking from different different aspects, like from
country or fine from state.
I need to create this instances like from finding the inserting.
I need to create this through the email.
So I need to create one another finding here because I don't want to mention similar things.
So let me save this first.
Close this post because these things are over.
As you can see, these are all the teams here.
And when I just added this, so I need to add one library here.
So this note.
Let me move to the Ed Jar folder here.
Once they see click, it will load to this file.
So let me go to my jar file here.
So it is that is worse.
In Oracle database.
I am having this fight, so.
This is a.
So I will be open.
Look at this wide open GDP.
It will take time to load.
As you can see, this is loading now gbk 14th version so you can use this part.
So as you can see, this is loaded now.
So it will.
Wait for these things.
Dispensing these known addicts.
Let me say this again.
So instead of putting this again and again, you can create one another.
Java fail to mention this part, but I'm putting it again and again.
Well, then this is the one for if you forget some text to get in for each and everything I'm adding
here, or if you want to add some more part in your file, you can add this.
So I added this part just for backup purposes.
You can see this all the things some including part and header GSP is nothing, but I'm adding one header
in one file to three files.
So for this purpose log out JSP each and everything.
I'm adding this part.
So that's it about who I'm going to add it.
Let's create one more thing here.
So what is the listener thing is just basically to create one.
Or we can say create all things here, like just creating, not creating only the servlet.
I need to create everything here.
So let me do this.
So.
No, I don't want to hear this.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to add one Java class in default package on new, which is basically
solid.
I'm mentioning the solid name as this might.
So you can add the package here.
Okay.
So, listen, we highly recommend do not add this, so let me cancel this.
Let me create one package here instead of creating in default package, let me create one Java package
here.
Our packages basically connector.
Great finish.
So.
In this.
Let me add a one.
So let me match my solid.
Click next and add this information to a dot examiner.
So it will take time to load everything.
And once this is done, you can check your connector app is done.
As you can see.
Okay.
So this is done.
What I'm going to do is and closing this part and maintaining this and I'm deleting this part, I will
tell you that I am doing this because I don't want to put everything here.
Now let me import some files.
Import Java x dot.
Lord Stern.
Then in Java dot school.
Don't start.
So I'm going to add these files.
Now, let me create one public class.
Public.
Class.
My.
Listener or listening what my listener implements.
Oh, no.
I need one thing here while I need to create implementation using solid.
I don't want to put that everything.
Like try catch and everything.
I'm going to use that.
No, no.
But I don't want to put that HTTP request responsibility.
What I can do, I can add directly your servlet.
Context.
Listener So which is nothing but.
So.
It will take care of this, my listener.
So it's not abstract.
So currently it's not abstract.
So what I can do is I can implement that all abstract methods later.
So I will tell you how I'm going to do this and everything here.
But let me add one more thing.
Because it's there is no method.
So I need to create one method.
Public void.
This.
Mr..
And all the things I added.
So it's showing me that.
It is not abstract.
Do not overwrite with context, it so little context event or anything.
So I need to create this class or the.
So you can create abstract classes like this.
You can mention this.
So is one thing here I just want to mention and let me create one connection.
Then I need to mention string.
User is equal to system, which is for the oracle database.
Then I need to mention string pass is equal to.
Bossman booty.
My data is.
I'm going to do this.
Okay.
So this is it.
I'm going to create.
But let me create one class for name each and everything because I want you mentioned right here.
Let me add one.
Also.
Exception in.
Justin.
Dot.
Ellen.
Section.
So that's it.
I'm not going to mention everything like class for naming everything which I already created.
Then on I'm going to create a one connection here on is equal to driver manager everything dimension.
So I don't want to waste time in this.
So what you can do is I already created here somewhere in the Justine.
I can use this directly.
Okay.
So instead of using this, what I can mention is here, because this is direct passing and I want to
create one abstract thing here.
So what I can do is this.
Okay.
You wouldn't pass because these are the two things I can use directly here.
So this is all about how I can perform this.
So let me add some prepared statements and create everything here.
So do all the things I'm going to create.
I forgot to add one thing.
Okay.
So these are the things which I'm going to adhere to clear statement, execute update, I'm going to
create table.
So you can create one sequence here each and everything I'm going to create here with replace some triggers.
I'm going to create all that in here.
So this is all about how I'm creating here.
If you want to add one more thing, you can add another thing here.
Let me ask this.
So let me add one more thing here.
It is basically to update everything here.
Okay.
So let me add one more method.
The project is deployed and deployed.
So that's it.
Who I can add.
This is my listener part.
So that's about how I edit and apply the triggers.
So this is it about this process.
And my listener is just for creating or replacing the trigger creating table, which is basically,
as you can see, this forum registration.
And if you have seen this, you can see this forum or you can see everything here is I'm going to create
throughout this project.
So my listener.
So what are you going to do?
You can execute this first and you are going to mention this or what you can do.
You can directly run these files or you can directly run this on your site and you can develop this
so in for everything.
I'm going to create one JSP to run this file directly.
My listener Java.
So hope you understand this part.
In later part I'm going to mention everything and how I displayed everything.
These parts.
And next part, I'm going to tell you what is the next thing I'm going to use?