Now the next part, we have to display the images here first on the rock paper, on the scissor here.
This will be on the user dependent.
So what we will do, we will create our function here for displaying images in the G labels.
So here we will write.
Create a commission to display images in label.
So what we will write we will write public void Newton Display image.
And here we will give parameters of image path.
And another one for the Chili Bowl, my new label, which we need in case you cannot find some more.
Get Capital G.
I am bored.
And so what we will do.
We already have the images of rock, paper, scissors.
So what?
Here I have my three images.
When the new paper, we wrote the answers, we simply just renamed these first.
Only the paper one.
Refactor rename the Rock one and this one will be renamed to two.
Repack here.
We will go to the image part.
So here we will write image to spot and we will take it in a string.
Mm.
Raw and simply write images.
Slash.
Here.
I drop.
Start being Bianchi.
We have.
I'm done.
Similar to that.
We have to.
People here we will write images and people not being here seem that post-rock rock references.
In this part we will write.
Images, Souza.
Not being
here.
We have said image.
Image.
But so the next work is to do.
To display images.
In the borders.
And after this, we will write.
Display image.
And we have our legal name right.
The new Chile will drop.
Clearly when people
display image.
We need the scissors.
And here you will write
scissors.
On this matter, we will create a logic for displaying the images here.
We will write image icon.
Image icon equal to new image icon.
New image icon under the civil right class
identities art resource
here we will give the parameter to image but.
And then we have to import this image and plus.
Okay.
So here we have get the image.
So we will write the image here.
No.
We have to resize the images so you can try to resize the images.
So here we will take image.
I am g is equal to the mean I am g.
I go not get image.
And under this we will write.
No.
After this, we will write down what we need.
A martyr.
Get killed.
No.
We need a model named as get scale instance.
Here we will give the word height and root again.
So what do we have to do?
We have the image.
Okay.
So we have the image front on the label here.
So here we will write this label, not get it.
Same with the label or get tight.
Will not get tight again.
Here.
We will write.
This is image.
In
image to skin.
Smooth.
We have to put this.
Reporter Don't know what we have to do.
We have to set image in the G label.
So after this, resizing the images.
We reset the image in the GDP.
So here we will write label dot.
Sit tight under the tree will give barometer of image icon.
Not.
We need a major food.
So here we will give the parameter to image here.
So simply run our file and see the output first.
Okay.
So we have the interception.
So here we have said that we what?