Now so that we have like initialized all the global variables, all the objects which are going to be
required in this project.
Now, in the next step, we are going to be concerned about launching the application, and we have
already mentioned it here also.
So we have created the mean class named it not stresses is not Java and now we are worried about functionalities
for launching the application.
So firstly we have to create a function of course so that we can move forward in order to add anything
inside it.
So it is going to be a main function taking string argument and.
After which arcs.
So we have created our function and inside this function we are going to like add cases for running
after application, opening the like application in a separate window and then other processes involved
here.
So this is the required functionality for launching of the application and this consists of a try and
catch error like exceptional hand handling method and this is going to handle all the exception if suppose
there are any complexities in a runtime of the application, so this try and catch exception handling
methods are per listing that if like try to open this window in a new window and windows dots like we
are setting visible to true.
We have already covered this that by default visibility is set to false.
So in order to make the frame visible in a new window, we have to set visibility to true.
So suppose like we are trying to open this window and if some exception arises then we will like catch
that exception and we will print step three like print stack press.
And this is going to handle the exception like any of the runtime errors appearing by launching of the
application.
Yes.
And this event you invoke later is handling the re-enable window.
We have already seen that the window was responsive and the difference difference in the window is going
to handle with the help of this statement.
And this will make the window run even after this, a covering of running the like, launching the application
part.
Our next concern is to create the application like how to handle functions or for the read layout,
the buttons and everything inside the frame.
So for creating the application, firstly we are going to initialize public and this function which
is going to initialize the application.
Like initially the window was opening.
I already showed you that an empty of nine blocks is going to open when we like run the application.
So this is going to be responsible for that initialization and we are done with this.
Now in the next part, we are going to set conditions for winning of the game, like who is going to
win the game?
This bridge should be placed here and after this we will set the initialize function later.
You do not need to worry about that.
This is just explained here as after the like launching of the application, obviously the initialization
should take place.
So after this, if we are creating a two player game, so we have to set conditions for winning or losing
of a specific player.
Like suppose if one player will win, other will lose, or if the game draws, then we have to set a
condition for that also.
So we have created this private void winning game function and inside this we have to write queries
for make a specific player then.
So suppose firstly we want to like cover that like suppose firstly for player X, so for player X,
what are the winning conditions we are going to look up to in this part?
So we have to set like if condition that is going to be responsible for checking, like whether x x
satisfies all the like winning conditions or not.
So if B one and B two is equal to one and B3 is equal to one, then X will win.
So let me explain this.
Like what actually this F is doing.
So this is the launching frame.
Like we set a function for launching of the application and that is responsible for launching of this
frame.
Now suppose that we set the if condition that B1 and B2 and B3 is equal to one.
So what that actually means.
So suppose that we have nine blocks.
This is the one way to be three, three, four, five, six, seven, eight and nine.
There are nine blocks, empty blocks in the beginning in the grid layout structure.
And we are checking that what if player X wins?
So if like the X comes here, here or here, firstly, we are going to check for the horizontal like
like configuration of x and this consecutive three occurrence of X will be responsible for making x
win.
So in the F condition, we are writing that only that if three in a row becomes equal, then X is going
to win.
So I hope you understood what this statement is signifying.
So I already shown you that what happens when a specific player wins like three cups in a row, whether
it be horizontal, vertical or diagonal?
This dialog box appears showing that player dash wins and we are going to set up function for that only
inside the active condition.
So yes, here it is.
This J option pane dot show message dialog is responsible for that dialog box, that pop up box, which
is appearing whenever a specific player wins.
And this consists of a frame, a message which is in a string format displaying that player excellence
and not central.
So the title of that frame here you can see and after which we have the option pain information method.
We have called these two option pane heading and information message which is displayed and we are increasing
the score of X by one.
This is responsible.
Like initially we have set this to zero and we are implementing this by one.
If X wins and then set text string value of like we are setting the x count in this code box that we
have incremented the score and now we are fixing it to this block only.
And similarly we are going to do this for all the three rows.
But suppose if there is a if that should be as so what if one, two and three comes in a row and there
should be a else condition also?
So basically it is not about the S condition, but we call it as if condition.
Let's suppose this happens then this is going to be displayed as if this happens, then what is going
to happen?
So we have to like analyze things that what are the possibilities of making a player win?
Suppose that we are considering X, so what are the conditions for making x win?
So this is one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine blocks and let us analyze that.
What are the actual condition which will make x when?
So if one, two, three comes in zero and four, five, six and seven, eight, nine, similarly, one,
four and seven comes in a row equals to one with an operator.
And this is like two, five and eight and this is three, six and nine.
So we have to set conditions for these three combinations like total.
We have three, three, three and totally we talked about six condition.
So we are going to copy the same thing and paste it inside.
ll6 block as we call it.
So copying this part and then again copying it inside this same public like private void, meaning game
function and pasting it a total of five more times.
So I am pasting it five more times.
We are done with three, four and this is five.
Now we will update the variable inside everything.
So we are done with one, two, three.
Now we will change it to one.
We are changing it to like let's check one, two, three, now, one, four and seven.
So we will update it here with one, four and seven.
So this is going to be four and this is going to be seven.
In this similar way for all the other ones.
So we are done with one, four, seven.
Now what are the possibilities?
This this is covered now two, four and six should be taken into consideration.
So suppose this becomes equal.
So this is going to be before and this is going to be six.
And inside this, if we have to write it, this is of course we will update it with ls everywhere.
And after that, we will be updating this everything.
Let us quickly analyze the inside structure of bias analysis statements so the inside options are going
to be same.
The inside component of this statement won't change for all the nine combinations we are going to write.
As for a specific player to win, we have nine possible combinations, like nine or eight.
Let me count one, two, three, four, five, six, seven and eight.
So yes, there are total eight possible combinations for a specific player to win, whether it be X
or it is zero.
So we will be writing like nine and and six conditions and inside the structure of the code will remain
the same for X in the OR in all the eight cases.
Just this if thing will change in every code.
So yes, let us try to like change it with every statement.
So yes, we have successfully like updated everything the if conditions and the condition with the possibilities
of player x meaning we are written total one, two, three, four and five, six, seven and total.
Yes, total.
So yes, totally.
IT conditions are there for making player X again.
Now in the similar way we will be writing code for player or winning inside this or private void winning
game function as well.
So let us take a look at this in the next part of this series.