Hello everyone.
So in the previous video we have created a student constructor and passed the argument for ID name and
grades.
Yes.
So.
We have passed the three variables and these are fees.
These are for fees paid and total fees of the school.
So, yes, if a student is admitted in the school, the fees paid by him or her is zero in the beginning
and the total fees is suppose one less 10,000.
So yes.
So this is not compulsory to add this keyword to fees paid and fees total as they are not passed as
an argument in this constructor.
So but for the uniformity in the code, I am attaching this keyword to fees paid and fees total variables.
So now we have to set the grade.
And you must be wondering that what is a set?
So we have set and get method in java for updating a variable.
Suppose if a variable is changing continuously then firstly we have to set it to a value and then the
compiler will receive it after the execution with the help of get keyword.
So yes, setter and getter in Java are very crucial.
But updating variables.
So you must be wondering why we haven't got set and get for a set for ID and name so you know, name
and idea of a person or student whenever he is admitted to a school, never change it.
It remains constant for the rest of his life.
Like if a student is admitted to the school, what name is registered in the school directory?
It will remain the same.
So we do not have to worry about setting the name and the ID.
But what about the grade?
And it remains the same for the rest of the life.
Think about it.
So the grades never remain the same.
It changes after every half yearly exam or the final exam.
Suppose if a student scored 100 like 90 out of 100 in an exam, it doesn't remain the same.
It is a very, very rare thing that the dates remain the same.
Great changes.
And so we need to set the grade after every for every student, every student has different dreams.
So for setting the grade for every student, we have to use this dot for every student and.
For ID we have called this function public in get ID.
ID does not need to be set, it just needs to be get.
And this function returns the idea of a student.
Let me commend this out for your convenience.
Returns the ID ofa student.
And this part
set the updates.
The set method is used to update, so I'm using update grades of the student s.
Similarly for the name we created this function public string get name and this returns the name of
a specific student returns the name of the student.
So yes, we have.
Get your name and I.D. Now we have to get the grade of the student public and get grade.
We are using camel case for a better understanding of the code.
So you get a great.
This returns the grid.
So here we are.
We have a set target for all the variables declared in the above student class.
Now we will jump to the teacher class and make a teacher Java file.
In our SRT folder as well.
So naming this class as teacher or Java.
We have a class named teacher.
Now what a teacher can attain as a variable.
Think about it and then write with your own experience.
So yes, our teacher can have an ID, a name and a salary.
So initializing the variables as private access specified.
We have already discussed it about previous student section.
Private string funding.
Names are strings.
We know that private end salary.
So yes, if a teacher is here for teaching in the school, he or she must be expecting a salary.
Now in a similar manner.
In the student class, we will create a constructor named Teacher for the Teacher Class as well.
A constructor is an object we know with the same name as the class and contains arguments.
Basically it is a copy of the class we have made and where we can pass arguments of ID name and salary.
So yes, calling all of the fields which we declared in the above class ID name
and salary, of course.
And salary is equal to salary.
Obviously, this is wrong spelling.
Yes.
So here we are.
We have created this new teacher object.
Let me comment this out for your convenience.
Creates this part.
Creates a new teacher object.
New teacher object?
Yes.
So here we have it.
For every teacher named for every teacher and a salary for every teacher.
Whenever we call it for a specific teacher, it will consist of ID name and salary.
So in the student section we have a freeze and a freeze total part.
So the freeze total part was supposed like one like 10,000 and the fees paid was zero in the beginning.
So similarly for teachers in the beginning, the salary earn should be declared.
So private end salary earn
is declared in the class.
And in the constructor, this not salary earned.
Is Z2 in the beginning.
Yes.
So.
After this.
After successful creation of object and class, we will use the get and set method as we previously
used in the student on Java file.
So let me give you a quick reminder about set and get.
So we have used as private as our access specified for this teacher class.
So for accessing this variable in the class, as we know, that private, private initialize variable
could not be accessed by any other class in this function.
So for and even for using it for the same function we use set and get methods so set and get provide
access and update of the value for a private variable.
If we need to access, we call this get and if we want to update the value of a private access specified
variable, we use set method.
So yes.
Similarly, as for the student Java file we will set.
The.
Salary?
Yes, salary.
So you must be wondering for the student.
We haven't set the ID and the name.
So similarly for the teachers, we will not set the IDs and the name as.
When a teacher joins the school, the ID ID is provided and which is safe to that dataset and remains
the same for the rest of the life and the name as well.
But the salary may increase in future if the school is impressed by a teacher's performance.
So yes, we will call, get and set for salary and later on we will initialize our function for ID and
which will return ID and name for that teacher.
So this public function contains the integer ID and this get ID function returns the idea of the teacher.
So let me commit this out for your convenience.
Returns the ID of our teacher.
So.
Yes.
The ID is returned here.
Similarly, we have to return the name.
So copying the above code and.
The name is a string, of course.
So writing it as name get a name.
A string.
And this is going to return the name of the teacher.
Yes.
It turns out the.
Name of the teacher.
Yes.
Now for the salary.
First we have to set the salary and then update it in case if it is needed.
So, yes, this is for the salary.
This returns the salary.
Typos.
Returns the salary of our teacher?
Yes.
So salary the teacher has her is declared as in now for setting the salary we have used public void
set salary in salary.
So yes, this is the snippet for setting something in Java.
Public void set salary.
And inside we have to declare the parameter what is need to be set.
So this part what it does.
Let me comment this out updates the salary of our teacher setting a salary, conveys updating it whenever
it changes, or which teacher it is being asked for.
Public void set salary in salary.
This salary is salary.
So yes, we have successfully set and get all the variables which were declared here.
So the first part of this teacher class is completed.
Congratulations.