So now, after the successful creation of the flame, we are going to add some customization to the
frame where the game is being run.
So you must have seen that.
On running this Snake Dart Java class.
The frame opens to the top left section.
Let me run this and show it to you.
Yes.
So the frame opens at the top left corner and there is option to maximize it and minimize it.
So if we want the game in a limited frame, like a fixed height and six width for the snake to be collided
and or complete the game.
So we have to fix this to a fixed border.
And also it should be open in the middle of the page, not in the top left corner.
The top left corner is the origin like here it is zero zero location zero zero.
So we have to move this to the middle, not open header.
It should be opened in the middle of the page by default on running.
So let us try writing some code for doing so.
So we have to set location.
Relative to null.
So that location relative to component and passing the argument as null.
Also for.
For the size to be not altered.
A fixed frame should be fixed in the beginning.
So I have to set resizable as false so the frame can't be minimized or maximize later wards.
Now let us try to run this.
On running this.
The frame opens in the middle.
Perfect.
So now we have set the site to resize the well as false passed as a false parameter.
The frame is now not able to be maximized or minimized.
It is showing a gray like invisible part is shown for the maximize button.
We can close this and open this and escape from this.
Now, our aim should be to set a title for this scheme.
Like after this Java coffee mug option, we have to show our title.
So for setting the title, as we have already used this feature, set the title as inside this.
We have to pass the title for the game.
Like suppose I am passing it to Snake Ofelia.
No snake.
Ofelia?
Yes.
Perfect.
So I have said the title for the game.
Now, let me try to run this and see if the title is set perfectly.
Okay.
So we have set a title for the frame inside which the game is going to be played.
Now after setting that title, moving the frame to the middle of the page, setting the resize ability
to false.
We will add a black screen like a dark mode screen for this name.
For a better appearance of the game.
Now we have completed this snake class moving towards the board class in the board java file.
We will set a background color for the frame.
So inside the board object I am going to set call this set background.
Yes.
So I am calling this background method and inside which I am passing the color as color dot black as
I want the background to be black in colour.
So let us try and run this if it is perfectly working or not.
So waiting for the execution.
Yes, it is perfectly set to black.
Our background is black.
Our title is done.
Now switching to the part where we have written a prototype and see what tasks are to be performed after
the creation of the frame.
So yes, we have created a Java project, added images to the project inside the icon folder.
We have created a frame.
Now we have to place images inside the frame and complete the images section, after which we will be
adding keyboard events and action listener to the project.
So let's begin closing this and now trying to add some more code for the image section.
Now in order of adding images inside the frame.
Firstly, we have to create a function called as public void load images.
So firstly we have to load the images to our program trail and then only we can set positions for it
or we can say that we can decide the places where they're going to be.
So calling a major icon.
Suppose for the first one like it was Apple so naming it as iPhone image one this implies and image
icon again.
And inside this we are going to call class loader component.
Plus loader don't get system.
Plus get system resource.
So that's hard one.
And inside this, we have to call the path for the image.
So we have to write this inside the bracket.
I am pasting it.
I mentioned the name.
We have to set the part where we have.
So we have to write the path after a certain folder.
Like if we close, we have to write the path from here.
So inside this RC, we have icons.
So I am writing it as icons then.
Inside icons we have apple dot png so writing it as icons slash apple dot png.
So this is the path for the apple object.
The program has no words.
No.
Similarly for the boat towards the green one and the red one.
So copying this part from hair.
And trying to paste it.
Two more times.
For the green dot and the red dot, which is the head changing it as let me see the path.
It says dot dot.
The green one and head dot png for the red one.
So second one should be suppose the head.
So the head one is the head dot benji and the third one green dot as.
Dot.
I think it was.
Let us try.
Yes.
So there are no errors now.
There is a grey underline in this high volatility.
So firstly, we have to.
Call it in the class board.
So inside the class board, we have to create a private like a global variable for all the three measures.
Without which we are not able to call the images anywhere in the program.
So far globally declaring it, we have to do this three more times.
Image.
But let us let us copy this three more times.
So pasting it two more times for the head and the door.
So for the dirt and for the head.
Yes.
So this is done now.
So after adding the images as the global variables now to make the images appear in the frame, we have
to call it that I do not get image.
So using that image method, we are going to call these three images now for the coordinate part like
let me show we have a coordinate.
This is the Y axis and this is the x axis.
So thinking it as a coordinate.
We have an X coordinate and a y coordinate.
So we have to call two global variables as an array like X and Y.
We have total 300 dots, total 302, 300 is 900.
So we have 300 as our bit.
Let me show this to you in the board section.
Yes.
So we have set the preferred size as 300 by 300.
So all dots will sum up to 9900 like 300 this, 300, this and every line contains 300 dots.
So on multiplying it, we can see that there are $900 in total and we have set a random position for
the snake.
So another dot dot is ten.
So basically the size of the dot is ten units in the beginning and random position for that, we can
see that that changes its position after every run.
Let's try to run this and see what I am talking about.
So when we try to run this snake dot java file.
We can see that the game begins.
And the snake.
So this is the new program.
Let me show this to you in our already.
So when we start the game, the apple has a random position anywhere in the frame and the snakes starts
from this position.
See the cursor.
The snake starts from this position every time and Apple changes its position.
So we have a fixed position for the object and a random position for the apple.
So the dot is fixed and the apple has a random position.
After this, we have set all the positions.
Now we have to add images after images.
In the beginning we have three dots, so we have to add one dot after other.
And for this we are going to use a for loop inside the new public init class.
So public static.
Public's void in it and inside it.
I am going to create a far loop so that images can be added one after the other.
It's like void and inside it.
We are going to add a for loop.
So we have created a for loop for the image addition in the snake's body.
So initially we have three dots.
Let me declare it somewhere here as private and as the dot size is integer.
So we have to initialize it as private dots.
So after this, the red underline is vanished.
So after which the for loop part is executed as we have a starting position for the first image and
it should be less than naught.
Initially it is three and it will grow in size as the snakes eat the apple and grows in size.
So the initial position is set as the x axis is 50 minus z and y axis.
So the distance from the x and y axis for the snake is set.
This is the distance from the y axis and the center distance from the x axis.
So the body of the snake has this distance from both the axis in the beginning.
And after creating these two functions, we have to call it inside the board object as load images and
in endgame.
So we have successfully created two parts of the program as load images and in.
Now in the next part we are going to create the position for the apple and the rest part from the prototype
we have created.
So see on the next part.