If you already seen the previous tutorials, you should understand that that's very primary thing I
did.
Just checking my.
Oh, so like target.
Target is nothing much any or address.
I'm not considering any special advisor, but the source is basically our victim.
Or we can check that that part.
Or we can say a part is like one network or not that part we are checking.
So it's not actually very useful thing at all, I'm telling you.
But we can create a more advanced thing using for loop or you can check your report numbers also if
like go check or there is in ViCAP Wireshark are also available for both checking things.
What is the training?
We are checking the open ports and close also.
Which is close.
Basically connected ports.
If we find there is one open port as we told you, that disconnected part.
So we know that that port is not connected at all.
So such things like that for the source IP, that port is open now what we can do using that or we can
connect to that source.
So for further information gathering anything cybersecurity thing that's very important, checking the
ports and everything according to the networking and everything.
So that part we consider as it collecting port everything, but we are not bothered about that.
So that's very preliminary part we created.
That's not exactly package sniffer.
Work for me should use that package like http or that should use some pcap files directly read that
files.
So for that purpose we need some prior java knowledge.
So now what I'm considering I'm doing one java ui thing here.
Not very.
Difficult.
Very simple.
Which is going to work on a 32 bit system.
It's not going to work for a 64 bit system, I'm telling you, because of some libraries.
But again, it's system independent.
But if you are using Linux system or Windows 32, which system, it will very useful.
Plus, you can change the libraries and you can perform it later.
But let us see how we can perform this.
So in the later part, I'm going to use one my main project here.
I'm going to create one project also, which is very helpful while developing this application.
So we will check that part later and I will tell you why I'm using my one here for dependencies and
editing everything.
So instead of using anger, Gretel.
Gretel, we are not at all using here because we are not performing any application was not a mobile
application we are developing.
So here we are considering only two scenarios and development or my own development, but for the dependencies,
I'm going to use my will in the next project.
So in the first part only I told you this total tutorial is based on three projects.
So first project is we created the port checking and everything.
That's not a project.
That's a simple code I created.
Now we are on the second part how we can create UI and everything.
So let me go with Java classes and methods.
So I am telling you such basic thing here because by developing using Maven, I'm not going to discuss
this part.
Second thing for the Mavin classes and methods are very important, so let us see how we can do this.
So Java class and meters.
So everything is in Java.
It is associated with classes.
Without Java you cannot create a single code offline.
Also not even the Hello World program.
So for that purpose class and methods.
So Java is secure language because we can create classes and methods directly.
Object oriented.
It's partial object oriented, not total object oriented classes, but language.
But we can directly create classes and methods.
So what is class?
In real life?
You can consider Cartesian object and God has some attributes.
So what is the car like?
Car is a class.
Honda is their object.
I'm considering Honda when car brand for an object car has many attributes such as color anyway, but
it has also meters.
Also like for meters there are different things brake, then drive then open road open everything mentioned
also excel methods.
So what we can do, we can create one car, plus we can put some attributes, we can create methods
and we can invoke it using Honda.
So that's a very fundamental thing related to the classes, classes like and then object constructor,
why we required object to invoke classes and invoke methods or use that data types like integers or
anything we have to use while performing any coding language.
So for that purpose we needed these classes also holds some user defined attributes, past values or
inputs.
Anything objects are to use classes.
We need required object.
Without object we cannot invoke or use particular class.
Then let's see what is the class?
Syntax is basically the syntax class name and this and you have to mention some more access specified
which is public, private or anything you can do.
Yeah, I hope you understand this.
So understood this.
So it's a very simple thing related to the Java class.
So let me show you how I'm going to perform here.
So I already coded this part.
Okay, so.
So we are going to use here one library name as GP cap, remember GP cap.
Another thing, we are going to use Java X for swimming and everything and Java is one most common thing
here.
So let us see what is the GP cap?
First, it's working for UDP, ICMP and different packets.
So what I created, I created this implement packet receiver which is basically GP cap only.
Then it's asking for it should be public.
Remember, it should be public.
But if you create it here private, then it acts as a private network thing.
So it will check for PCB packets in private network only.
So remember, consider TCP packets TCP, UDP and ICMP ICMP for the incoming message mail mailing part.
So if you want to put it more, I'm considering only three scenarios TCP, UDP, ICMP.
You can put different, different things here.
Let me show you how we can perform here.
So let me put public static.
GDP.
Back it goes.
So wait a minute.
For GDB, you need to create a class or you need to mention that part, so you need to create this class.
So I'm not at all mentioning this, so let me remove this.
So I am not considering HTP because it's very common and you will get full http only because once you
connect it to the net or you are receiving HTTP packets continuously or HTTP is packets continuous.
So I'm not considering here that part.
Then public setting with.
I created one list I released for this.
Then I created one method.
This you package with constructor.
This respect public void and width instance of PCB package.
So the very important part you have to mention this part in this if like I'm visiting TV packet.
Or ad number sne for number.
PCP linked TBC source TCP and add that as a TCP so it will add an object as a row property row in that
at least this ArrayList released.
And then it will add this sniffer with DCP length.
This now let me put all the things here sniffer, which is basically our sniffing thing.
I will tell you, what is this number?
It means which number of packet?
First, second, third, fourth, anything TCP length message, message of that part.
If this is also IP, TCP just like destination IP with TCP again TCP source TCP port like what is a
source port and distant destination port AC is just acknowledgement by TCP header.
There is a protocol in networking, but let me tell you that TCP consider of one header.
So header has some few fields, so it has also acknowledgement field.
So for that purpose to check a TCP exec number, which is basically acknowledgment number data.
Now, the data is very crucial.
I am considering printing data directly.
So while putting on this you can perform like I'm sending packets like username my username a, b,
c, so packets will divide into the three part.
First part is sending to the A, second part is B, second third part sent C so packet one has having
data a, packet two having read a, B and packet three having read a C so that my data in ASCII codes
or another thing also that my date data converted into ASCII code and ASCII code is converted into binary.
So that's the TCP data not I'm going what data holds the actual data of that TCP TCP sequence.
What is the sequence of that offset and header part is that all the heading parts modal after this default
table mode you need to create it is.
Swing the moon, which is going to add here sniffer level with that model and model door gate pro with
sniffer number plus plus which is basically if that package, the sniffer will go further.
Like when a number is given here like one, then it will print to do, it will appear in that or it
will increase increment operator.
I use the.
If I found the UDP packet then again same thing I'm doing here i SNP packet form.
I'm doing that step sensitive steps here.
So that's done here.
Packet receiver part.
So now let me show you the.
These are the Java parts.
Not these parts.
These are the Java part.
That's all the back end.
And with some utilities part I'm using here.
This part comes, which is swing utilities, trade.
So why I required this part, I will tell you.
So that's all the JP cap.
So I created there all the back end end switching part.
But someone needs to run it again and again and again.
For that purpose, I created this trade class.
So these in the trade wars and everything looking to get value set value finished methods, interrupt
methods I'm adding here and all the things we put enable interface I'm invoking.
So now this is the sniffer.
So this is the form method which all you can say here, but it has captured button stop buttons to button
filter option everything with JP capacitor capacitor is basically for the capturing and everything in
the cap folder.
You may found it with this.
So my recommendation is you can design here that you are directly.
Once you choose this in the Higgs you you will find the Higgs X view capturing the for capture.
Now the list of interfaces I will tell you what is the list of interfaces?
So I created this for the Linux purposes, not for proper Windows.
Windows having only one network interface, but while you are looking at a linux kernel you may find
there are VLAN.
Not due to the Internet, not windows are also windows are also having some interfaces, but that's
a system dependent service.
So for that purpose, I created this capture button.
As you can see, this capture button, this stop, stop button, save button for the saving list of
interfaces.
This filter button or filter options you can choose filter here.
I'm going to open that list again and again.
This is packaging for one and this.
So let me go to the source again so you can create design that part directly here, but we need to add
some GPC themes also.
So what is the GP captain submitting here is just basically this cap trade part, index part, I added.
And.
This is the interface window, so I need the window here.
So this is the inside.
I need this part.
But for main purposes, I need this window so I'm not accessing this part.
So now we are done with this.
So let me press here.
Clean.
And we.
If you look at the notion.
What did you do?
How could you do?
So.
Let us check whether this is cleaning or building anything.
So it's clear.
Simple glasses.
And again, this is very basic.
If the.
After this, what I'm going to perform I'm going to create one my venting which is very useful, very
powerful tool.
I'm going to create the.
Then we run.
So it's not only.
Well, you can take.
This is my budget, but it's more than anything.
So this is my culture part and everything.
So let me tell you why this is not running, because it's 32 bit system.
I'm not performing on this.
So you can check here if I click here.
List of interfaces you may found this error.
JP cannot find dependent lefties.
Why?
It's not loading this part, it's an A2 method and you may find that it's a built in class loader is
built in with 64 bit architecture.
Virtual machine architecture.
Java virtual machine.
Not ready to build.
If you are interested in 32 bit and running on the windows, you need to install JDK 1.8 32 weeks,
JVM not 1.8.
So for that purpose you needed this, but for the other purposes, you can consider this as an ideal
UI.
So I hope you understand this.
In the next video or next tutorial, I'm going to deal with some venting and how we are going to use
it.
That part I will take.
So if you are using 32, build any architecture.
This is very helpful code.
You will receive all the packets.
And rather than using Wireshark and you're using virtual machine is very good idea why virtual machine
is not existing system while the networking.
So you may create one more threads on the existing system then virtual machine.
Hope we understand.
Thank you.