Well, next thing we need to program the movement of the spots in this code will be letter calling,
letter via call callback, respond to the cursor movement so our game will support multiple move simultaneously.
Those are three converted the best position on the screen in the.
We get a version of empty tag and look for the direction of movement to support several of its movement
at the same time.
So what we will do?
Firstly, we have to take the constructor of our class.
Under that, we will take the most listener event.
So firstly, so we have not here, we need the private boolean and what we have taken the game over
this one, this variable.
So we have defined this and what we will do here we have true if the game over and false otherwise.
So this is done.
We need our variable by the name great size.
So here I will write private and name it as the grid size here.
So what we will do here?
I will create my constructor of class.
So I will write.
This can not be private.
So here I will write public game of 15 under this parameter constructor.
What will it be in size?
Comma in term, comma in margin.
So here I will write.
So we need margin also.
So private int and margin here.
Don't know what we will do and I will write the match.
Okay.
We need to distort size.
Initialize it to the size here.
After this, we need the dimension is equal to then.
And another thing which we have the margin equal to more.
Okay, so this is done.
Now what we will do, we will initialize the titles.
Here.
Initialize.
No, it's here.
So we need annuitize, literally equal to size, multiplied by size, minus one.
Here, the minus one because we don't count blank tile.
Okay, so here.
Right it minus minus one because.
We don't.
We don't count blank.
Okay.
So you take the diary which we have created now initialize the new int and under this we will write
size multiplied by size.
Okay.
So here mainly we have to program the movement of the spots in the array.
So here we will take we need the mouth, mouth listener because we respond to the cursor movement.
Right.
So what we will do.
Okay.
So we need.
Yeah.
After this we need.
And Mouse.
Listener Under this we will write mouse adapter.
This one.
Okay.
So no notice what we will we will write our logic.
We have to override the mouse breast event.
So here I will write public void and mouse.
Trust.
We are overriding this matter.
So.
Right.
Mouse E went with the E.
So yeah.
This really used to let the users to interact on the grid migrating and we have to implement the interaction
with users to move tiles to solve the game.
Okay so here what we do.
I don't think it is the right
word right here.
We know what we will do.
Firstly, we will see we have to users to interact on the grid by clicking.
So we need the condition first of the game over.
So game under this we will call our new game, which we have created already.
And in that else part, what we will do.
We get the position of the click.
So here I will write in x is equal to e dot.
Get to x.
Get x.
It will be the machine.
Q Done this one and another one to get to Y.
So if y is equal to what you get.
Why take it with the machine here?
Okay.
So now we have to check it is click on the grid or not.
So click on click in the grid.
So here I will try to condition if.
If X is less then with the zero.
OD e x is greater than the grade size oc or imai is less than zero.
Or Eli is greater with the great size.
Okay.
So what do we do then?
Okay, now, another thing.
We have to get the pollution in the grid.
Get position in grid.
So here what we will take.
Position in the grid.
Now what we will do, we will take another variable by the name C, initialize it to the e x and there
I did with that tile size.
Tile size.
Take in r one which will refer to the row one.
It will go with the E divided by tile size.
So here, Don, now we have to get the position of the plant cell also.
So what we will do, we will take the C to set it to the.
Long position and more to the size here.
Now, another variable which we need is the order to set it to the blank position molded to the size.
Okay, so this none.
Now we have to convert another 1D coordination.
So here,
1D coordination.
So what we need, we need int and create a variable to expose.
Position two position which will take equal to r one multiplied with size and added to C column one.
Now we need another variable in the direction cited 2 to 0 here.
Now we search direction for multiple times at once.
So here I will take the research.
Medication for multiple items at once.
This one is done.
So we will take another if condition here.
We will check for the column.
One is equal to the column two and goes with the.
You need the math class and check it with the absolute of the R one minus R to so it will not take the
negative value and check it if it is greater than zero.
So what we have to do.
Zero.
Okay, so we will write the action is equal to r one minus r two.
Greater than zero and take the ternary loop.
Subtract its size, the minus size.
Okay.
Now we need another one.
Take the LCF.
Who would be the answer?
Look here.
We will check with the rule.
One is equal to rule two and not absolute and goes with the C one minus C two is greater than zero.
For the body.
The other direction is equal to C one minus C 2 to 0.
So what will it do?
Set with the one all cologne minus one hair the lot.
So another one which will last is the condition here we will take.
The direction is not equal to zero here.
We move twice in that direction.
So what we will do is take the collar jacket open.
Move piles in that direction first.
So what we will do, we will take a loop to do a loop here.
So under this, you will write.
What do we put in blank?
We need a new blank position.
Blank pose, which is cited to the blank.
Okay.
So this one.
Blank pools.
B, I are here.
Here.
I know what we have to do.
We have to take the tiles.
Right.
The blank pools here, which will initialize it to the tiles of new blank push.
So a new blank creation here.
And third, the blank position.
With your new blank position then not to do this no wine loop.
We will check the condition of blank, whose is not equal to.
Click pause Sudan.
And what we will do?
We will take the tiles array and set the blank position to zero.
Here this we have done.
Now we have to check of games on which we have created our material here.
This one is so sorry.
So what we will do here?
We have done.
Now we check.
The game is solid or not.
So take the game over variable.
Right.
It's a solid.
We need a solid here and now.
What we need our panel is here.
We will create our new master repaint, which will repaint the panel here.
Okay.
So this done.
And after this, we will call our method new.
So finally, we have programmed the moment of the sports daddy, this code, which we call a callback
to respond to cursor movement.
Our game will support multiple times simultaneously.
So those are converted the press position on the screen into a.
We get the position of the empty type and look for the direction of the movement to support several
of its movement at the same time.
So here we are converting that.
And this is all of our movement of the sports in a.