Now on this matter, we have to change the minesweeper game.
So before that we will hear some variables from the cell writer to variable.
Random is equal to new random.
You
know here we have to set the in-game variable with true.
Need some minds left people settled with the number of minds here and next we will be doing mean is
the multiplication of the number of rows with the number of columns.
So it will read all cells.
Here all cells is equal to number of rows is the multiplication with the number of columns here and
done now.
It should be okay.
We have not created.
No, it should not be local variable.
Should be an instance variable.
So what should we do?
We will go here and initialize that variable.
So we will write private and animate as all cells.
On the sandstone.
It should not be local variable.
And now what we have to do, we have to set up the minefield.
Every cell is covered by default.
So here we will take a field.
Is initialize that array with the.
On sense.
And then now we need a former law to set up the minefield.
So here I will write in equal to zero, and I should be less than all since I increment their bracket
open field.
I need to add a field, i.e. index which is equal to cover for cellular.
And so these lines set up the minefield and every sale is covered by default.
So the next thing which we have to take a while cycle in which we randomly position all mines in the
field.
So what should we do?
Here I will take a wide loop first.
While I should be less than two.
And mine's.
Here before that.
We have to take a look and initialize it with the zero here.
Wonder the smile loop.
What do we have to do?
We will right into position.
Is equal to.
All cells.
Multiplication of the random dot next to double.
We have to typecast.
This should be in the parentheses and it should typecast in the entire row.
Done.
And put the semicolon here.
Now we need to go with another condition.
So if.
Here.
I will write.
Position is less than all cells.
Okay.
This one and next thing.
I'm in that condition with her and.
We should check for the field position also.
So field position we have.
No.
We need all three.
Field
position here position.
It should not be equal to the cover mindset.
So here I will write.
Not equal to forward mindset.
Don't.
When the racketeer.
Position here.
Sunset and key.
We've all learned one thing here.
Also, we have to take the status bar here in the status bar.
Don't sit next.
It should be endangered, ought to string and get the mines left value so done here and now.
What we have to do is we have to complete this condition first and we should start with the current
column and give it the value in the collection mode and calls.
And feel and even the cozy shin value position which really cool to the coal mine.
Sell mine.
Hold on.
It should be I increment and.
Holy --.
Okay, so this is done.
Now we in the vital cycle, we randomly position all mines in the field.
Now what we have to do, we shoot cells.
Each of the cells can be surrounded up to eight cells.
This will not apply with the border cells.
So we raise the number for adjacent cells for each of the randomly placed mine.
So in our example, what we will take, we add one to the top of the cell in this thing.
So what we will do here, I will write to.
Okay.
Senate position with end goals to kill the system.
So here.
I will take some.
Some stole.
What should we say?
Some of the conditions first.
So here I will write.
Current call is greater than zero.
So what should it do?
It will go with the equal to position.
Minus one.
And minus one.
Minus.
No more columns here.
And go with the if
is greater and equal to zero then.
Key position.
We need the position here.
So if the sell is greater than or equal to zero.
So what it should do is field.
Okay.
Give the value itself here is not equal to the converted mindset.
Then do one thing.
Field sell.
Set it to the.
Three cent plus one equal to one, and then singles the position minus one.
Here we go.
I already take each of the cells can be rounded up to eight cells.
So what should we do to this?
We will take the cell with the position minus one here and take the if condition for cell is greater
than equal to zero.
Under that, we will take another f loop f condition and set it with.
If cell is not equal to covered.
Mine fell.
So the field fell.
Explosions are equal to one here and now the next.
Another condition for the position with the number of columns side up and then the minus one.
It should be one less.
So here I will write equal to.
Position notes, number of columns, minus one here.
So we will take the flu for cell is less than all cells.
Then we need if filled with cell.
Not equal to gold mines and.
Field with this Senate.
Plus equal to plus equal to one.
So here, this thing is done.
So what we have done.
Okay.
Now we have left some more conditions.
We have to raise the number for decent sales for each of the randomly placed mine.
In our example, we add one to the top level.
So, so cell in the question.
So what should we do?
We need some more aid.
These are only three condition.
We have to take five more conditions.
So here what we will do.
We have the columns minus one.
So next condition, which we need.
As soon as all this.
Okay.
So here after this, we can take.
Then is equal to position minus number of columns.
If we write, sell is lesser than all the sales.
So here we will take if field sell.
It is not equal to cover.
Career mindset.
Okay.
So in this what we will write, we will take the field cell.
And plus equal to one.
Can you position
the next condition here?
Right.
Third is equal to position.
One solution here, which should be either with the number of columns here and leave the condition if
sent, is less than all cells so that if field with the cell column is not equal to the cold mine cell,
then next thing, what we need is to fill and send plus equal to one here and next with the current
column position.
Right.
So here I will take.
With the current.
We already created.
Current column should be less than the number of columns minus one here.
Under that, we will check.
We will set the sun.
No position.
Minus number of columns here.
And at one.
And take another if condition one cell is greater than or equal to zero.
Here what we will write here we will take similar to the previous one if we send not equal to.
Coking coal mines and.
This one in this civil right field cell, plus equal to one here.
And don't know next thing which we need here.
This one here.
I will write cell.
Equal to position.
Plus number of columns here, plus one.
And the similar condition to the previous one, if said, is less than the old sense.
Take it with the if condition of fuel cell.
Not equal to gold mine sell.
Take it with the field, with cell.
Close equal to one here.
Okay.
So.
We have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
We have to take one more last condition here.
For this.
What we have to do.
We will write send equal to position plus one.
And next what we have to write here.
If cell is less than to all sense.
Then similar to the previous one.
If feel the sun color not equal to covered mind sell.
And done.
And here I will write field sell sp+ equal to one here.
Okay.
So.
Done so here.
I have done that part.
Okay, so each of the cells can be found in up to eight cells here.
This will not apply to the other cells.
So we raise the number for adjacent cells or each of the randomly placed mine.
So in our example, we add one to the top of the cell in this next thing, which we have to do.
We have to create a fine three cell method in which we will find the empty cells.