So here I have a game labeled and a colon.
So what I have done with this, I have labeled this file loop game.
So game is now the name of this wallet and now we are going to be using this label here a bit later
letter so that we can allow our program to trade back to the start of this world loop or here.
That's why we need this label right here.
So now that we have done that, there's going to be a lot of systems around that line in this program.
So right here, just because it is a text based game, so it has to be a lot of text printed out on
the screen.
So I'm going to go ahead and firstly, I will write here.
Okay.
I will copy the system out of print.
Here print.
Alan.
Here.
Firstly, I need over while first.
Okay.
So under this while running.
Just honoring the Gottlieb record and put the system not honored.
Friend Alan here and simply copy this.
Here I will write.
Firstly, it will start with the.
Okay.
I need.
New Start one.
So now what we need.
Okay.
So next thing which we need the wall.
Look, the first thing we need to do is to start the combat with an enemy.
So the first thing we are going to do is find an enemy.
Set up the stats for it and then start combat with it.
So let's go ahead and say here, I will see here.
What do first we need?
Okay.
So.
So I will see in anime.
Anime healthier and simply not.
If you remember up here we have set a variable called maximum anime health here.
This is the maximum amount of the A health and anime can have, but it can have a kind of more than
this, but it can have less because we don't want it to be flat.
What is 70 the whole time?
We are going to go ahead and set the value of the anime health each time because again it's going to
be a random and we are going to set this here.
Equal to here.
Going to set it.
And I'm sacred equal to the random object which we have are dot, which is the random object which we
have here.
And the next matter we use now, we will put the full stop here and we have a lot of matter.
So here we are going to use call the next int, next int here and just give it.
So it takes one parameter.
So this parameter is the maximum value.
So here I have the maximum enemy held here.
So this random that this random entire can be.
So the integer that is generated is going to be between zero and the number given.
And the number we are going to get is our variable right here.
With the maximum enemy held for the start of every duration, we are going to set enemy held equal to
a random number.
Why do we not honor maximum enemy health?
So we are going to go ahead and set the string next.
So here I will set a string called Enemy and we need to know which enemy we are fighting again.
And this is going to be randomly generated.
It is going to be a random selection from one of these here.
So we need to access one of these random names.
So we are going to go ahead and see enemies, grab the area and then do the square brackets.
Now, as we have learned, we need to put the index of the array inside the square brackets here.
So I will do.
Mhm.
And yeah.
And then mixing these games is going to be a random integer between zero and the length of this idea.
So the random integer between zero and the length of this area.
So by.
So by doing that it would mean zero and the length of the array we are going to generate a number.
So that is either with zero one, two or three and it's going to randomly pick one of these each time.
So inside the index for the array we are going to see here, we need the enemies and just put a dot
here and start, Len.
Here.
We need the right name first.
Then the next.
Next integer and just put up the enemy.
Start.
And it means dark land.
Okay, so we are accessing the enemies area here.
This.
They are not.
Nada.
We need a square bracket.
Okay.
And it means dirt land, which we have.
Here each time they look inside the next for the area, we are going to say round here the next end
and then the parameter is going to be start length.
So we are accessing the enemy's area here and then the index and we are using this as a random integer
between zero and the maximum length of this area here.
So now that we have the name of the enemy, we can go ahead and just simply write this down note on
dot print in here.
And under this we can I set this up beforehand.
So there is going to be a actually format of the game.
And so it is a text page, obviously.
So here we have to write.
It's okay.
We need some format here, so I will take the three.
Okay.
Hmm.
Just a minute.
What I can do.
What format?
Okay.
I will start with the backslash D.
This is the character for tab in the console.
So we are going to tab forwards one and then we are going to say we are going to do this.
Same here.
First, the hash here.
No, not the hash we need.
We will take it with the.
What I will do.
But with this
we are we have used the symbol here and then a space here, and then we are going to see plus here and
plus we need the enemy string.
Now the next thing.
Will Shu has appeared.
Okay.
And just simply put.
Just simply put the symbol here and the backslash and and then so here, let's explain what the string
is.
So first of all, we do our tab, then we do a symbol here like we do a tab, then we do a symbol like
this and we do the name of the enemy here, which is going to be appeared.
So here I have right has a beard and then another slash with the symbol here and I have the backslash
and make sure it moves on to the next line.
So it's like a line break.
We're moving to the next line.
So if I do a comment here like, okay, not the command, what I will show you, this would look like
an example.
We have tab then.
So just simply run this and.
Okay.
He's not stopping because I have not done it.
Okay, let's control.
Let's see.
Okay.
You can see the output of our it totally showing the rhino variables.
It will going okay, so it is creating over here so we can see our format here.
This is going to be.
Show up in the console right here.
You can see the output over next thing, which we have to do, we need to actually add the world for
that.
So this is an example of what it would like to look like.
So here it would look like this in the console.
So now that we have the enemy appearing, we need to set another loop.
So the next video which we have.