Hello, everyone.
So till now, we have created three classes for all three of the ships which are going to be required
inside our application the rectangle, the circle and the line.
Now, the next part, in this part, we are going to look up to the main class of this application,
which is going to be responsible for testing and running of this application and the name of this class's
drawing and Java.
So inside our main class, we have made few of the imports.
So these libraries are going to be the like main playing, the main role inside our project.
All the components inside this main class are going to be the consistence of these libraries only.
Okay, so first we have AWP, then this a DOT event which is going to handle all the buttons.
So action listener and action event.
So we will be creating events in the form of buttons and attach a function to that specific event,
like attach a function to that specific event and calling it an action listener.
So yes, our separate action is attached to every event or buttons, whatever we call it now, are using
this buffered image from the library inside the Java WP framework.
So this buffer image is going to save the image in the form of JPG format.
Also, we are using file for opening the file chooser.
Option of our system as a is going to be saved in the form of a file.
Also, the random function of Java library as the user can choose any random shape from this control
panel and draw a shape at any random place in this drawing area.
Also we have a change of intention listener as okay, so if you chooses one of the shapes, then in
the next step they can change the event.
So for that we are using change, event and change listener Now inside this drawing editor class, we
have extended this to J Frame As.
All of this window is inside the frame, which is due to the help of this j frame component.
So this gave a content pane where yes, all the contents are to be freed.
So inside the frame we are calling the random variable.
Yes, we have.
Calling this from this package.
So this is going to create a new random object now.
Okay.
So the random entry is created now what all of this is doing.
So this part is for how the buttons are going to perform on.
So how our rectangle should look.
Ah, the program doesn't know it's on on its own.
We have to give our image to how a rectangle is going to look, how a circle is going to look, how
a line is going to look.
So we have saved everything in the form of images.
We have a circle image, a trash delete image, a garbage patch for the delete icon.
This is the line which will be drawn, so the line, length and width are going to be adjusted according
to the specific use the rectangle.
And of course, the save button.
Similarly, this is the take that Benji for undoing the changes.
We have came across this state when we were in the working part of the application.
So.
Okay, so inside this.
We have imported all of the images required.
So in total we have seven images which we have imported using this image icon component of the buffer
image library.
So yes, we are calling all the image and the images will be buffered according to the size set by the
user.
Now the next step is to for the setting, the colour.
So I have told you that the by default color is going to be black and the system color is this is going
to be the which is for the opacity of the color and the shade.
So this is going to be the shade for the color by default for the black color, of course, as the default
color is black.
Now, this is for the lines, color and line size.
Similarly, we are going to use the colors for rectangles and circles also.
So our line is a bit different from the circle and the rectangle, as the line is not containing the
feature empty and full.
The line is simply going to be a straight line without the full range of buttons here.
When we click on the line button, this empty and full button will disappear.
So we have set the line, cut a color in line.
Similarly, we have a radio button for empty, full rectangle and circle.
So there are different radio buttons for the oval and the rectangle.
So we are declared radio buttons separately for all four of them.
Now width and height are also going to be different for the oval and the rectangle.
So this is going to be the width and this is going to be the height.
So we have four integer variables for the return, the height.
Now the drawing area is going to be the center of the frame.
So how this drawing area is located.
So this is the frame.
These are the two panels.
And in the center of the frame, we are having our.
Our drawing area.
So this drawing area is containing a like it is inside a panel and how the panel is located so we can.
So make spaces between them.
Okay.
So this static Z panel is going to be the panel inside which the drawing area is located.
Now we are having a line, a rectangle and.
A circle inside the control panel.
And this control panel is also a panel itself.
So, yes, on the left panel, we are going to contain a rectangle, a circle and a line.
Three of them and also two.
And Don't Rush button.
So, Dan, don't rush witness.
Over her remove and current.
So this was all about the drawing area now coming to the drawing editor function.
So inside this drawing it did a better function.
We have set the size of the frame.
So initially the frame size is 1000 by 800.
So when we will run the program, the window will open in this dimension and then that is a layout.
So we have setup border layout for the frame and also there is a default close operation here.
We have already discussed that on clicking on this close button, we will escape outside the programming
window.
Also, we have a set location relative to NULL, so the window will be opened in the middle of the screen,
not in the left side or the light element.
It is going to be open in the center of the frame whenever we will run it.
And also we have a set that title and setting visibility to true is necessary in order to make the frame
visible.
Whenever we run the program.
By default, the visibility is set to false.
So in order to make it visible, we have to set the frame visible to true every time.
Now the title of the frame here, you can see that.
Drawing editor.
So.
We have used this set title given in order to set the title of the main theme now inside the.
Yes.
Inside the control panel, like inside the center panel, there are three components.
Here we have a top control panel and a left control panel.
So, yes, and this is the main center.
So what actually this is covering.
So the panels are going to contain buttons for rectangle, oval and line.
So basically, all all all of them are buttons, whether it be the same at the three of the shapes and
the trash.
Now to add the buttons to the frame, we are creating this add buttons to the left.
Called function.
This function is containing.
This function is containing objects inside it.
For the rectangle circle line.
Like undo the button and remove all of them.
So basically we have to delete buttons.
This is for undo and this is for Clairol.
So and also a save button.
So we have created all of them using the J button component of the swing library as all of them are
going to be stored in the form of a button now.
Okay.
So the look of the button are set it to a painted set.
Focus to painted is like here we have an orange color of panel, but the buttons have a painted background,
a white paint.
So using this focus, painted is used in order to do so.
Also we have to set the visibility of buttons to true.
And yes, in order to do so we are using new buttons.
So.
In order to add these buttons to the frame, we are using new button and thus visibility is set to.
For us in the beginning.
So whenever the user clicks the button, then the button colour will highlight, which will show that
yes, this button is selected.
Now once the buttons are added to the frame.
So basically we are using the grid layout component of the frame.
So this is going to be set the layout.
Of the panels inside the frame now or adding all of the buttons to the frame are the save the rectangle,
the circle line and remove and clear all.
So this is going to be add the buttons to the left panel and once it is added, then the visibility
will be converted to two now creating functions for the rectangle circle and the line.
So yes, if the button is clicked, then we have to add the rectangle to the frame and automatically
this button will start showing the figure which is clicked.
So once we click a rectangle then it will start showing the rectangle.
So similarly for the oval and for the line, it is going to remove the current element which is showing
at the top and replace that with whichever is selected.
So if the line is selected, then it will remove the current and set it to the line.
Now this rectangle buttons.
So what is going to be the buttons when the rectangle is selected?
So once the rectangle is selected, we will be having a width and height and a colour picker empty and
full, and here it will be showing the rectangle like this.
Now once the oval will be click, then the same options are going to be displayed.
Just the difference will arise that this panel will be showing.
Draw, oval and oval will be drawn when this button will be clicked.
So we are writing separate buttons for all three of them, whether it be the rectangle, oval and the
line.
But in the case of line it is going to be a bit different as we will be just having a single text field
for a side and a set colour and just head text will appear here showing that we have to drag from where
to where we want to draw the line.
So yes, we are using the spinner number model for setting the height and width of the rectangle and
the circle.
This is responsible for that only the bit, the text which is showing her the width and also this rectangular
text frame asking for the height and width.
Now, after this circle and rectangle buttons.
We are coming towards the line.
So the line is here.
So what is going to be the line buttons so far?
The line here we are having to spinner number models for height and width, but for the line we will
be having a single spinner number model.
As you have seen in the working application, like we were having a single text field asking for the
size of a line which was going to be simply the width of the line as the height of the line was going
to be decided by us, not from where to where we are going to drag that line.
So yes, the line button is going to be bit different for for the circle and the rectangle.
Yes.
So it is a bit different from both of them.
Also, this is a cell phone in which the size will be written.
So these are basically the layouts.
Yes.
The spinner will be listening to action like it will change whenever the user will click on the arrows.
So it is containing a downward error, an upward arrow.
So this change listener is listening to the actions mentioned by the user.
Also, the set color is going to be same for all three of them.
We can choose a colour from the colour picker that what colour we want for our line, circle or rectangle.
And a text is appearing in the line part asking for a point like a click on a point from where to where
you want to drag the line.
So this was all about the shapes, all three of them, and the buttons are padding in the top panel
accordingly of all three of them.
So the above panel was changing with respect to the shapes.
All three of them.
So till now we have covered everything about the control panels that how things are going to work.
With respect to all three of the shapes and how this control panel will appear in the case of ship accordingly.
So in the next part, we are going to add actual listener function in order to attach our actions like
events to the buttons that how the functionalities should appear.
Once we click this button, then all should be drawn and what should occur when we select this painful
button.
So in the next part, we will be covering that.