Okay.
So we have done this thing and we will create this t adapter class in under this class so that what
we will do the and the to determine the actual position of the volume shape.
So we will take the methods named as the private int square width parentheses and take it to a curly
bracket.
In this matter we will write the return type across to the end and right correct size.
Don't get rid.
And what this does will be about board width.
This will be border it and create locally.
No, no, no, no.
Just a second.
What we will do.
This.
Will you go with the director?
First, we have to do one more thing.
Take the square height as well, so we will drive the private in.
Square.
We need the height of it.
So we will write the square height, the span, Suzanne, and simply return with the type typecasting
to the end and write get size, not parentheses.
It returns the size of the component.
We have to run in the get height and this will be the board height.
Sorry.
Okay.
So this thing is done.
Who would?
We have what we have done the correction already to my electrical wiring batteries the following datasheet.
So these lines determine the width and height of a single terminal score with the board width and the
board height.
So what we will do?
We determine the shape at the given coordinates.
The shapes are stored in the board.
So what do we have to do?
We will write the private.
They draw money, right?
That draw.
So that ruminant animals chefs shepherd and provide a parameter index comma in why and what we have
to return return board.
Here we will write y, multiply the bold immutable first and then right
after this plus x and this is done.
Okay, now another thing which we have to do must we will write the start method from which our gain
will be the start.
So here we determine the shape and the given coordinates.
The shapes are stored in the board area.
Now we will write void
bracket open.
No, we create a new current shape on the new board.
So what we will do here, we will write the piece I think would be equal to a new shape.
This one.
And after this, we will write board.
Well, the new terminal.
The terminal here we have to.
Right.
We the board.
Firstly, we need to know, firstly, we need to hydrate the bore, hide or whatever.
I don't have to.
So we will write board height in the board width.
So.
Board height and the board width and simply close this.
And so the board is what we have to the board have to be clear and the new volume pieces initialize
so we will write clear board.
Then write clear piece as well.
And this thing is done.
Of course we have to initialize.
We have to write the method this.
We have to write the body of this method as well.
So what we will do?
Firstly, the board is clearer.
The new forming pieces initialized.
So before that we have to must try the body of the method post similar to the start.
So here we will write private void numerals.
The force.
With this we is we have to check is posed equal to the thing we is most sorry is almost done and we
have to check if it's passed and right under this status bar and we will set them.
I think we have to set that text.
So set text and write it to the.
Paused here after this.
We need the spot.
And into this spot.
We will.
Right.
Status bar.
History does not set X and in doing this we will write string or the value of value off.
We need the nom lines removed.
This is done and we will create another method named as the repaint.
So this is done and we have to print.
So we have to set the graphics.
So this part is done.
And we have to.
Connect with the graphic part.