Okay.
So till the last part, we have created our main function, the timeline and the home dot java class.
So these two classes, we have already created the timeline around the home.
This is responsible for testing and running of the application and this is responsible for the home
page which is appearing here.
Now, in this part, we are going to create this schedule inside the scheduled Java file and see how
it works.
So what are the functionalities we need to attach inside?
So initially a text field and a continue button should appear and the bottom should contain a continue
button.
Once we hit any integer head then or that number of steps which should appear in the frame where whether
we hit 510.
So accordingly that number of text fields containing a task dash like whatever one, two, three, four,
five.
According to that, we have to contain that much of the text field to attach tasks to our frame.
So let's first create a file inside the SRT folder.
So new file and we are going to name it as the old dot java.
Okay.
So this is how this scheduled class is created.
Now, again, we are going to extend it to the panel in a similar way.
We were extending all of them.
So this import is made and also we are going to implement action listeners to the button.
So implement action listeners.
Actually, it's not here.
Okay, so this class is made for this schedule.
Now, inside this class, we are going to declare some of the variables private base.
So we have to declare base in all of the classes we are making.
You must have been observing this private for that.
How many tasks we have to complete.
So we should name it of how many?
And calling it as a chimp in short form.
So how many a chimp?
And that's how many tasks we have to complete now.
A private variable for the tasks.
So the tasks list which we are going to create for all the tasks, but whatever the number is.
And Andre button for continues so private.
De Botton.
For Conte Conte contest for the continue button.
Now we have to store the tasks in a form.
It should be resizable.
Definitely.
As initially we do not know that how many tasks we want to add to the timeline so we can use our data
type analyst we already talked about analyst.
Analyst is an expanded form of error.
It gives resizable content like we can.
We do not have to fix any size to the analyst, but we only contain five or six elements.
It is mutable.
Basically, we can mutate the number of size, how many tasks we have to add.
It will bend itself according to that number.
So yes, this manageable list we are going to use for adding our tasks.
So Private ArrayList and this ArrayList will be storing all of the tasks and what will be the name.
So this list is going to contain the info, so we will name it as in info.
ArrayList again.
And this list is going to be in a string format.
It is going to contain the tasks in the string format.
So double closing it and calling it info.
So yes, this is the list containing that task one name, task to name and the time attached to it in
a string format.
And the next part, we are going to create schedule or constructor, we can call it.
So, yes, passing based as all of the previously created classes.
And inside this constructor, again, setting a layout for the schedule page.
So this schedule page is containing a border layout again.
So new border layout.
And this border layout is going to contain no arguments in the beginning of the end, calling the base
as we head.
So whenever we need to access it, the base, we use the crib.
Now the next thing is new tasks.
So B is for creating tasks.
We have already initialized it and to access it we are using this keyboard.
The next part is for the how many tasks we are creating.
So a again new how many we named it as how many?
So new, how many is going to set the tasks like number of tasks we want to add inside our schedules
and definitely the Continue button, which is going to give us the number of text field according to
the number of tasks we have added inside the how many actually so new button for the continue and inside
the g button or string is going to like a pair continue.
You must have seen it in the introduction, but the button is containing a text.
Continue.
You can see it.
Yes.
So this is the button and this is the how many text fields and we have added the of the how many things
like the text field, the continue button and the tasks to the frame.
With the help of this add keyword admitted, we can call it we have added all three of them inside the
frame or we have also made several imports like similarly we have made inside the home dot java file
or basically all of them are same as the home class.
You can see the imports are almost same and again we are going to use the paint component function in
the schedule plus also as this paint component is going to paint that text field according to the user
and tells it like how many tasks the user want to enter inside it.
The paint component will paint this in the form of graph assets.
Yes.
So also there is other continue button here also.
So coming to that.
Okay.
But firstly, let us add the action listener to this continue button.
Like if we are adding a number of text inside whatever it is, integer one, two, three, four, five
and on hitting this continue button, what action is going to be performed?
So we have to create an action for phone function which will attach the action listener to the continue
button according to the how many method it is going to create that many text fields for the specific
tasks the user has entered for.
So action event as the argument and the event is e here and inside this action perform function.
We are going to use this.
If so, if the user enters in.
This is the method to write it as e don't get source.
So inside the get source we are going to count.
We like hit the continue button.
So yes, if they get search support, the user hits the continue button, then an array is going to
be returned in the form of task list.
So this info is going to be contain the list of the task.
Basically the ArrayList, we can call it.
So return an array array for storing the tasks that many number of now there is a time also.
So we are calling the time method as we have to set time for that specific task.
So this time method will help us to do so.
So with every task attached, there is a timeline
time So.
BASH Now showing that time.
So showing the time to the frame.
And this show it will show the label.
So here we are, like seeing this label last time and you can see that this is the task one name, the
textual and the time.
So we will enter the string as time.
So this is for the time thing.
Now, this was the action perform.
The action is not attached to the continue button.
Now the next action listener we are going to attach is for the like.
We have other continue button also.
Okay.
So first let us create our function for this.
How many and this task as it is appearing, then once we create a class, then this red underline will
be gone.
So creating a class for how many?
Again, extending it to Japan and attaching action.
Less notes to it.
So implement action listener.
Action listener to it.
Now inside this, how many class we are going to declare some of the variables such as task, how many
continue button and number of tasks.
And again, inside the how many constructor which we are going to create, we will pass tasks as the
argument.
We will set a layout.
So we are using a flow layout for the number of tasks entered by the user.
So this is going to be a pair in the form of a flow layout of flow layout resizes itself accordingly.
So if there are two sizes, then this distance is this.
We have entered five tasks, so the distance between these two tasks will be decreased.
So this is what actually flow layout does and the text field will be adding and continue button and
we will be adding inside the how many class as well as this continue button is happening.
Once we are hitting this continue and this list is appending, then only this continue button is updating.
So we will be creating that continue button again inside this Harmony constructor.
So let us see.
So here we have created how many class.
Inside this we have declared some of the global variables such as tasks, how many continue button and
number of tasks.
So this how many constructor as we have already discussed that we contain a layout will contain a text
field.
So this is the text field.
How many text string and are the continue button of course.
So on hitting the continue button, the action is not attached to the continue button will come into
action then adding this harmony and continue to the frame.
Now this integer is getting the number of tasks.
So how many tasks we are entering?
Will this integer grab and then return the array list according to that integer which is entered now
this action list now which is attached to the continue button.
So if the user enters like hits this continue button, then we will provide the user with that number
of text field with that task one, task two, task three and whatever the number is, enter name and
also a timer.
So this is going to return the text field according to the number entered by the user.
And if there are any kind of exception, then this catch block will execute, returning it as something
went wrong.
Try entering a proper integer.
So suppose we enter anything except integers in the text field.
How many text will and then hit this continue button?
Then this exception will arise and throw this string as output.
So yes, this was all about the continue button coming to the tasks.
So this is the main thing inside the schedule plus the number of tasks we are creating.
That is a class for the task, extending it as the panel and these are all the.
Feel that name, that time and everything from the yes.
So here you can see there are several things that are attached.
One name and a text field and a time, then two blocks then.
And so this all of them are covered here.
You can like come to them one by one in detail and relate to them how they are working.
So yes, after declaring all of the variables now inside the task constructor, we have created the
text field for them and we have declared all of them here.
We have decided that how they are going to look inside the frame and beam all of them on once the user
enters a name, then a time, then are like AMPM and these all are functioning in that manner.
Action is not.
It is attached to this AMPM button.
Basically this AMPM is a button and there is action is not attached to them which will navigate between
the AMPM.
This is the action list.
So if the user hits PM, then the time should change itself to PM and in that timeline it is going to
appear in that menu.
Now, after declaring all of them or how these things are appearing on the screen, they are appearing
in the form of ArrayList.
Basically, they are resizable.
How many tasks the user want to enter every time it is changing according to that, and for that only
we are using this revalidate and repaint function.
So yes, this repaint and revalidate changes this layout accordingly.
Whenever the user changes the number of tasks then hit the continue button.
So yes, this is a great layout type of yes, the appearance is a great layout type of function or method.
We can call it the grid layout.
We can decide if the user enters three, then the three is to one should appear and according to the
user enters whatever it should appear.
We have used a for loop for the grid layout setting, so whatever.
Then a user enters the for loop will run and return as the number of text field, whatever is the input
entered by the user.
And this list is taking care of the time entered by the user that if it is am then we should shift to
it that night time and if it is PM, then we have to shift it to the evening or on the afternoon time.
So yes, this list is handling everything about that time part which is present here.
Now in the next part we will be creating this this help page first and this end page first and then
we will be creating this main thing, the timeline.
So I'll see you in the next part.