So in this video, we will be talking about the next classes.
Those our classes will be new employ and list employ.
So these two classes we will be talking about in this video.
So name class will be used to add an employee to in this project.
So let's just start its explanation.
So import Java SQL will help us to connect with our database.
That's why we have imported that package and import java export string will be helping us to create
a better graphical user interface and Java JWT will help us in the Abstract Window Toolkit package,
which will be used to create graphical user interface application or Windows and after that.
We have imported Java event which will help us to handle events over the buttons.
After that, what we are doing is there is a public class new employ which is extending the frame and
implementing the interface accent listener.
After that data, we have initialized the seven labels and seven text fields.
Then we have two buttons and one choice.
Now we have defined our non parameterized constructor of a new employer class heading as new employee.
Then we have set the size of the frame as 600 comma 650 and the location has 600, comma 200 and its
background color as white.
Then we have defined a panel P setting its background colour as white and its layout with the help of
grid layout, which is eight comma two and ten comma 40.
Then we have defined the label, new label as a name and a text field with size as 15, adding both
the label and the text field to our panel.
After that, what we are doing is we are creating a choice seven as equals to new choice.
Then we are we are adding choices to that instance of choice.
Seven Add male and female, so that choices will be four selecting the gender of that particular employee,
which we will be adding in our database.
So after that there is a label l two gender and we have added that L two label to our panel and that
choice instance to our panel.
After that, we have defined another label as address and its respective text field of maximum size
15.
And we have added the address label and its respective text field both to our panel.
After that, we have defined a label for which is for the state, and to enter that state we have defined
a text field of size, maximum size 15, and we have added that label for and text field for to our
panel.
After that, we have defined the label city and also its respective text field, which is of maximum
size 15.
We have added the label of state and its text field to our panel.
After that, what we are doing is we have defined the label L six labeled as email and then we have
defined the text field of maximum size 15.
Then we have added the label L six and text 56 in our panel.
After that there is a label L seven which is labeled as phone, which is be used to enter the phone
number with respect to text 57, which is a text field of maximum size 15 then p one dot add.
It will add the label seven to our panel one and the text field segment to our panel one.
After that, what we are doing is we have defined one new button submit and another button as cancel.
So the submit button will be used to submit the data of the employer to our database and the cancel
button will be used.
If we want to cancel from that window or program or application, then we have added both the buttons
B1 and B to to our frame or panel.
After that, we have set the layout as new border layout and added another label with the image icon
by passing its path of the image to our class load or get system resource at the location of West.
Now we have added B1 at the center panel with the help of border layout.
So we have passed center.
So we are adding that panel.
Also after that we have defined actions not over the button one its background color and foreground
color as black and white.
Similarly for the button two, we are adding actually its background color as black and foreground color
as white.
Now we have defined the method action performed with method which is taking argument as.
Action event.
Now inside it's an inside which in a string and we have stored the text from the text field.
Even inside a string, we have a store of the item selected from the choice.
Even inside a string a we have a stored the text field content of the text field three inside the string
as we have stored the content of the text field for inside Siva is told the content of the text field.
T five Inside the string.
E We have stored the content of the text field three six Similarly for the PE, we have stored the content
of the TW seven as well.
After that we have defined a string.
Q are y which will be storing the query to insert the data into our table employ.
So that's in into employer values.
That these are the values which we will be storing in our.
Employ a table now inside the tribe log.
What we are doing is we are first creating our database connection with the help of our con class,
which we have discussed in our second video of this project.
Now 7.8 Start Execute Update Query.
Which will be executing that query so that the data must be updated to our employer table.
And after that there is a dialog box appear after successful updation of the data and it will show that
employer created.
Then we will set the visibility of the.
Current window as false and after that we will cancel the exception if any occurs inside the public
static void main.
What we are doing is we are creating the new employ instance and set the visibility as true.
Let's have a look at another class that is a list employee which will be used to show all the employees
which we will have added to our database.
Here is the list in my class.
So we have imported the package java SQL to connect with our database.
Java starts with strict Java JWT and Java JWT and after that, what we are doing is we have defined
a public class list employer which is extending frame and implementing accent listener.
Inside which we have defined a table and stance on a button instance B1 And we have defined a area of
a string which is a string and bid name, gender address, state, city, email ID and phone number.
After that, we have defined the two dimensional string array, which is new, a string of size 20 plus
eight.
Then we have defined the two variables as equals to zero, and this goes to zero of integer type.
After that, we have defined our class.
Constructor which is a non parameter constructor list employ heading as will employ and set the size
as 1000 comma four and red and its location as 450.
200.
Inside the tribe log.
We have created a spring queue which will be storing select aspect from employ and then we have defined
our connection C1 as equals to new coin, which will be creating the instance of our COIN class, which
will help us to create with the database.
After that we have executed the results set out as as close to seven as execute query which we will
be executing the query.
Q and insight.
Q What we have stored is select extract from employer.
Now, while I restart next.
So I restart next.
What it does, it will iterate over the records every row of that particular table.
And we are storing the record of every row and every column into our two dimensional array, which we
have created so far.
Day zero zero.
The idea of the first employee will be stored inside the d01.
The name of the first employer will be stored similarly from for the zero two the gender will be stored.
Then address the state, city email and phone.
So as soon as the first data is, data of the first row will be stored in the two dimensional array.
What we are doing is we are incrementing the value of I, so I will move to the next row of that two
dimensional array and J will be moved back to the zero so that we will be storing now the second data
of the second row into our second row index in this two dimensional area.
Now Jeevan is close to new table inside which we are past the two dimensional array and list and a string
area of that.
The number of columns or the name of the columns.
Then inside the cache block we will be handling any exceptions.
If occurs, then we have defined a button new button print and added that button at the south location.
After that, we have defined the scroll panel as one new scroll panel, G1, and passed the argument
of Java in that scroll panel.
So what G1 is a given is a table, basically.
So to apply a scroll panel over that particular table.
We have created that scroll panel and past the table and stance into it.
After that, we have added that scroll panel to our frame and we have defined the action as over that
button also.
Now after that arc, we have defined the action performance method which is taking action event A and
inside the drive log try block.
What we are doing is g1 print.
So what is the use of this German print?
This will open the printing page for that particular record and inside the cache block we will be handling
any exceptions if occurs and public static void main.
Inside this we will be calling them creating the instance of new list employ and set the visibility
as true.
So this is all about the two classes which we have discussed in this video.
The first class is a new employer, which will help us to add the employees to our database.
And second is the list employee, which will help us to retrieve the all the record of the employees
and have a look on that record in our application, which we are creating.
So that's all in this video.