So in previous part what we have done, we create already created an index or JSP which is for the front
end part.
Like this you have a mini client and we are importing some file years.
So we are importing this page.
And what is page import is basically I am just accessing this mail hotmail client.
Why I'm putting mail because the package is mail here.
As you can see, this complex, which is my own property, I will tell you later, what is this?
Basically, if you know this, this is just basically the injection dependency thing, dependency injection
I use here.
So I use this as dependency part.
So while I'm putting this, you can see I'm accessing this mail dot client here and I already wrote
the program for this.
So mail dot client is nothing but it's accessing its data or JSP through this and.
This is going to indexing, so it will take them while indexing.
So what I have done, let me tell you, as in previous with some short recap.
So what I have done here is it's very easy.
I have done here.
So.
These are the teams in decline and creating your OP string, which is basically then super keyword I
used as a constructor here to mention this is the constructor of this so you can minimize this as it
is perform that actions.
Sometimes indexing will take a little bit of more time.
But what you going to do?
You can just reload this from your dependencies and it will take part of that indexing.
Slater.
So.
The building.
So it's going to sink this application, as you can see, with the cloud.
So we created this message and everything and it's going to dispatch and I'm using your two methods.
One is to post and one is to get.
So this is it about how we perform in male clients.
So this is just for accessing the data and everything.
Then what is the more things?
I'm going to use your email, not this.
Let me do one thing here.
If we were to do 100 and.
What I'm going to do is you can just reload this because sometimes it takes more time indexing so you
can hide the process.
So it will take time, but I know I can proceed with my further, more indexing part time.
I don't want to stop for this.
So in this part, what I'm going to do, I'm going to create one more thing is email utility.
So let me copy this.
Okay.
I covered this part.
Now, let me go to the mail plan part.
What I'm going to do now is this clicking new Java class pasting this email utility thing under.
So that's it.
It's created for me, this part.
So it will take time to indexing and doing everything here.
Sometimes it takes more time than this.
We are not worried about that part.
We will check it later.
Let us start with coding part.
So I already created this, but we are remaining with some final strings, which is basically SSL socket
factory.
We are going to factories just basically for factory resetting and doing everything part.
So let me go to the demo part and.
We go to the mansion.
But I read.
So let me mention one thing here is
this.
So I will tell you what is the significance of this?
So Cecil is just handling this.
So I'm mentioning this, but I will tell you later how it's going to work.
It's not actually, I'm putting as a comment here and why I'm commenting this part is I will tell you
later, this is just a sizzle factory.
I mention it, so that's not required at all.
But sometimes it's use more preferences for that.
Let me get one.
Private.
Stepping.
So I needed properties proper.
These props, you can now you can add anything.
So.
Sometimes it takes time, like you can check your background task or taking more time due to network
issues and more things it takes.
But we can do with this new.
Properties.
So these are the drama properties.
Then what I'm going to perform here is I'm going to create one static part.
So if you know, instead of putting main dot or we can see upstream upstream is common thing here I
will say public static environment.
If I put a stream.
Instead of doing this method, what I can do, I can just mention a static block so it will execute
for me.
Static.
I can create a static block in Java.
Similarly, I created this.
So now what I'm going to do, I'm going to mention some properties of my SMP protocols properties dot
good first is mentioning the host which is basically mail dot SMP dot host.
So what is the host for me?
You can put here a SMTP, which is Gmail code.
Simply be Gmail dot dot com.
So this is my SMP port for gmail.
Then what is the port probs?
Not good.
Not simply because next thing is, I want to mention the port for my SMTP.
Remember, it's always so mentioned indirectly.
No need to mention a string and I need to mention the authentication part.
So why we need authentication?
We need authentication.
Always true.
We don't want to stop it.
Simply people.
So let me put like on it is always true.
Are you true?
So I'm performing this true part here.
Then we are remaining with Start de Lis or we can say Start, please start this.
So what are these things?
So let me mention here, these are the proper PS of SMTP server.
So I'm mentioning all the properties of a SMTP server like mail dot smtp dot host is my gmail.com or
despite seven authentication is true.
So why we need authentication or likewise you have a gmail account and no password we are going to mention
here.
So I want to mention that authentication is always true in this case while sending a mail, it's authentication
is always true.
So it will run loop inside this and it will give me the true authentication always.
But what I needed before is I need to mention here one thing may not seem to be a simple TV dot start
time to allow service.
Or we can say the.
Anybody else is a very common thing in what you can say.
Any running program, if you have taking Jake through this.
It's basically transport layer security and we have to enable it always this are well using Gmail here.
So now we are done with this.
So let me check.
Indexing is now updating and indexing.
So sometimes it may take time.
It's according to your network connection and moment.
So ignore this.
Let it be done throughout this project and it will take two or 3 minutes.
Sometimes it takes more time also.
So keep it as it is and go forward with your path.
So what we have done is let me tell you again, I'm mentioning the host says this port has this authentication
through and TLS, which is basically transport layer security.
I want to enable and mention as is true part.
So that's it I done here.
So now what I want to mention is I want to mention here when send mail message or snail mail thing.
So for that purpose.
We mean same meal.
So I would public static.
Roy, if you know why I'm mentioning word, it's not returning anything.
So what is the reasoning if you know the basics or if your method is returning something, relocating
or dislocating some memory, it should be here.
It's not doing anything.
Send mail is my method.
I want to mention one parameter is email message, which is my email.
Message.
So there's another parameter I mentioned.
So these are my parameters not.
Anything yet I mentioned.
So I want to know you strike etch or instead of using etch and what I can do.
I need to.
You mention string syndrome.
So.
What we are going to do is.
Here is your email.
I mentioning this because I don't want to do this.
I will tell you that about your email and it gmail dot com if you want this.
Second parameter is password because for the authentication purpose I'm authenticating this and always
to but on which parameters I'm going to take your email address, which is basically username and the
password for the Gmail.
Any SMTP server has specific given specific username and password for you.
So similarly, I'm mentioning this similar email.
Plus.
So I will your.
You mean?
So this is not my email password and it's not my email also.
I will tell you later what I'm going to put here.
So I'm mentioning it here.
Education better mix.
Okay.
So these are the authentication parameters, which is basically send an email, which is basically username
and password is for the password basis.
So I will tell you what I'm going to do here.
Now, let us consider is this a very true thing I'm going to do here like it's a secure thing?
No, not at all.
Because I'm using.
It's public void.
Anyone can check this as a security purpose.
So I will tell you later what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to use string handling and everything I'm going to do here.
But I will tell you later.
For simplicity, I'm keeping like this.
And further part I will change it to more complex thing.
But.
Let me make a connection with server first.
So I need to create a one session
session.
So once this indexing is done, the libraries will automatically edit here and everything will be done.
Session.
Not yet.
All instances.
This default insistence, which is basically very common thing I'm going to do here, is.
On.
Props.
I want to mention here Probst properties and.
Wait a minute.
Let me put your props because it's got props, which is basically properties, then new Coke, new Java
X Lord mail, which is our library.
Mail dot.
Authenticate.
Or Authenticator.
So this is my instances where what is going to do?
It's accessing these properties.
As you can see, these properties will be accessed because this is the static.
These are the properties of a TV server.
It will put this thing, which is basically my.
Or Metal object or becomes a classics object.
And it will ask me through this new Java mix mail authenticated.
Now this is the session, so I need to mention two or three things here, which is password protected
thing and everything I'm going to mention.
So in the further part, I will tell you how we can create a connection with the server, plus how we
are going to handle this thing because now it's currently very unsecure method.
And let me tell you why this is unsecure, because this is public and I'm directly putting my password
and email.
So if anyone having some injecting in our program or server injection, they can found out this directly.
So instead of this, what you can do is I will tell you later, there are many a lot of options you
can do.
But for this condition, I'm going to use some more other simple options.
If you are testing purpose, you can do this.
And two or three things I'm want to mention here, but I will tell you in letter regarding to the SMTP
port and everything.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.