So previously we have seen all the things here and how we created everything I told you.
Now we are moving to the Ajax part.
Ajax is asynchronous JavaScript.
You can see the deployment part here.
So it's asynchronous JavaScript and extremely it's not a programming language, it's a programming technique
model.
Developing any JavaScript or JS projects is a set of web development technologies or techniques using
web technologies.
Use client said created asynchronous applications.
So why I'm using here asynchronous method.
If I am not using synchronous method, let us consider to clients putting the request or blog or the
component anything on my page.
Simultaneously.
They both can get error.
So I need to maintain two processes difference as a asynchronous part.
So I need here asynchronous part here.
I don't want to create synchronized methods here.
So I created one synchronous.
I want to create asynchronous part.
So I'm using your assets so web application can run, can send and retrieve data from server asynchronously
without interfering or display the behavior of existing page.
Because I don't want to change the behavior of that case, so just add that asynchronously.
So this is the more you can say file or you can say flowchart of objects working from the browsers and
events occurs within a single HTTP file XML file same is typically request to the internet server will
take care of this and it will create the response to the internet browser will be done or the process
will be written using JavaScript and update the page content.
So that's it inside this and using Ajax going to use Ajax.
So Ajax is basically asynchronous JavaScript and XML.
It's not the programming language, I'm telling you, it's a programming technique to create asynchronous
methods.
So let us move to the ID.
So I created a few more things here with login process, which is nothing but for the login using email
and each passwords with some file system and everything I'm going to create.
Lynn Longboat for the JSP.
Everything.
I'm going to create log only for the log out I am going to just session invalidate it will go to the
front page only then this is create.
I created open post.
So let me show you where I use Ajax.
So these are all Ajax things I'm using while creating objects, putting in this type and putting and
printing that part.
So that's an Ajax thing.
I'm going to use it.
It's very little thing.
I'm using this while you're creating the open post.
Also, I mentioned this example HTP server to put this Ajax find as you can see, fine name each and
everything I'm using here Ajax.
So that's very little thing.
Let us see what is these things?
And what the thing here specify is basically it's a load document file with some http, you can directly
embedded this and you can create the change content, everything here you can put this.
So that's it about how I'm going to create, but it's a similar HTTP request object.
So if you know the object, what is the object?
It's it can be used to exchange data between the server behind the scenes.
XML is http request object.
So you can use this object to request the data and it means that it sends a possible update parts of
pages without actually reloading the page.
Or we can say hold the page, it will reload that part only.
So that's asynchronous part.
So there are different methods in different things.
Using this you have to change check there.
But best thing is it's access across the domains.
No need to change the domain.
If you have same domain, you can use this or if you change the domain objects, it remains same.
So for the newer things you have to use new HTTP request things, everything about method you need to
create.
Then there is open method also same method also you need to create.
So that's all about thing you can create.
But remember about the four setters or you can say three statuses.
There are basically 200 is 44034 4,000,004 044.
Not for existing so.
If you know this, you are good to go to create a logic here.
So that's it about how I created a just logic.
So let me show you some more thing here.
I created one post to mention this again.
This is again some Ajax logic and I'm adding some things here, so.
Just remember these things that I use to mention this.
I just found some two locations as Ghaziabad and from Madhya Pradesh.
To put this and I found this on the internet, Modi just added random things here.
I don't want to mention focus on that part.
If you want to create for your own location, you can add that.
In an email.
Everything I'm going to mention here.
So that's it.
Who I created.
Let me show you one more thing here.
Register JSP.
So this is it.
I'm going to register the process I need to mention here.
I'm going to create.
But in further more things, I'm going to show you how I can perform these actions.
So we already created when my listener do deploy that web pages, then the status is for showing the
status, like the error or everything I'm putting inside this part only.
So due to time constraint, I already typed everything and I'm going to show you this development or
deployment.
In later part, I will tell you how I can perform these actions.
But before proceeding with this, let me add two or three files here first.
So this is how I can create, but you need to create one test part also upload part also.
So let me go with the login process here.
Okay.
So now what is these things I'm going to mention?
So these are the jobs and you need to mention this for quarterback or vice versa or the Oracle development
you can find on the Internet.
What is the tenure and public member for the public part?
So I'm creating username, I'm accepting and user password the user parsing method and boolean to create
one status.
Then I'm going to create Oracle and I'm going to create and mention the select part.
So once this is done, I can print hi in my command prompt to get that connection is done.
Once this is done, it will attribute said email to email username.
It will ask me for the sign first.
If I'm not directly, it will bring me username and password does not exist.
It will print or throw me from that page.
Which is basically log in page to the index page.
Then, just as I told you, I'm here already.
I already created this part.
So this is it.
How I'm mentioning this.
But.
No.
Remember while developing the my listener.
Or you can say I already created this part.
So it will face that data from that part only.
And it will me it will give me everything here so you can use this, select everything you can use,
replace, execute, update you can do here.
So that's it.
Who?
I created this file.
It's not which I already mentioned, but.
Okay, so there are some things also required here.
Because while developing this before you start each row.
You can see this.
You can see I created from duel or everything.
These are all the please kill thing here I added to create triggers.
Similarly for the log in process, it will appear like that logout is very simple.
Once I click that logout it will decision invalidate message.
Then let us see open post here what is open posting mentioning here why I'm putting this again and again
while posting this.
I need to create one thing here.
So.
High school is very important here.
Because I'm going to add it to my school thing.
So me forgot to change this here, which is basically one, two, three.
So this will add it to my skill page while I am posting this part.
So a part will be similar, but after changing this part, it will move to another part.
So this is an open post theme which will face your post dimension in your if you are adding image,
you can add the image also here so you can do that.
Then I created open t post for opening this post and you can see I added this.
So I also in for what to change here one thing.
It is a distinct.
If you have another thing, you can change that.
Now, let me explain this first.
What are the listings?
So I'm adding this to everything here.
These are the functions I'm adding to the JavaScript.
And so this is very important, what I'm going to create if I am.
Could you please enter some text?
If I marry, it will find the names with the JSP as this is similar to the request window is similar
to its existing.
What is the next thing?
I told you earlier that I don't want to load or reload the file again.
I'm going to load just that window again if name is name is found or something like that.
If not, it will unable to connect the server.
It will print me that error.
So that's it.
I'm going to put this.
So I just want to display that name after finding the name without reloading the full file because it
takes it takes time to reload everything as it is.
Localhost only I can perform this furthermore, but by developing this I can use Ajax similarly for
the post I created header GSP.
Everything I mentioned or registered GSP is again similar for registering this file.
So the thing registration process is again similar.
I already mentioned this part.
Then status GSP is again similar.
He's going to show me the status here.
As you can see, this is good for you.
So always remember you need to.
Well, I'll mention your school.
It would explain everything neatly, because sometimes like this it will throw the error for me.
So let me save this or this is it who I'm going to mention in the next part, which is the last part,
I guess.
So in that part I'm going to mention you everything.
I'm going to specify the files and each and everything in the later part.
So this is it about all the things.
And in the further part, I'm going to put everything.