So here is the ad from Java class.
And that is defined inside the package hotel.
And we have imported the necessary packages.
Java eight Abstract Toolkit Swing Swing Border Abstract Toolkit DOT Event as well.
Package and Util Package.
Then we have defined the class add room using extend, which is extending frame and implementing actions.
Now a private panel type of variable that is content pane for text field 22 to 34 for combo box combo
box combo box one combo box to box three, b1, b2 and one.
Choice type of variable inside the main function we have.
Initialize the object by setting its visibility as true.
There is a non parameter constructor of this class setting the bound for it and adding that content
pane, initializing the panel, setting that j panel to the frame and adding its layout as null.
There is the image icon adding that image anchor icon to our frame and then as another label as add
room.
Setting it bonds, setting the bond for it, adding that to our window adding that to actually it is
a panel content pane is a panel here so adding it to our panel.
Then there is another label as room number setting the foreground color of it, found type family and
size of it, and bound for the font, bound for the room number label and adding that label to our panel.
Then there's a text field adding that, setting the bound for the text field and adding it, adding
it to our panel.
Uh, yes.
And then we have another label which is labeled as availability, setting the foreground of it, font
of it, setting the bound for it, and adding that to our panel.
Then there is a combo works which have to a string type which is available or occupied.
So as it is a add room class, it will be used to adding rooms so room status can be either available
or it can be occupied.
So setting the bound for combo box, adding that combo box to our panel and the label L three, which
is cleaning the status.
So foreground color for it, font type of it and bound setting the bound for the location of it in that
window and adding that to our panel.
Next to the combo box for the cleaning stated either that room can be in clean status or dirty status.
So we are using the combo box.
So combo box setting the bond for the combo box and adding that combo box to our panel.
Next is the price.
What is the price of the room?
For that, we have set the foreground color of that label, font type family and size of that label,
setting the bound for it and adding that to our panel.
Now respective text field of the price setting the bound for the text field and adding the to our contain
panel.
Next label is a bed type, so bed type will be also off either single bed on double bed.
So first setting its foreground color, setting the font type family and its size, setting the bound
for it and adding that content panel.
Adding that label to our panel.
Next is combo box three.
Which is a.
Dating to a loose string single or double wide in respect of BET type, setting the band for it and
adding that to our panel.
Next is a be one button which is added.
So this will execute the event of adding that room to our database, adding the action list and setting
the bound for it, adding background color and foreground color, then adding it to our panel.
Next button.
Another button is back doing the same thing for that button as well.
At last, setting the background colour of the window as white.
Now inside action performed event.
If the source of event is from Demon Button, then we will initialize the connection with the database
by using our icon class and retrieve the information of room available status price and type with the
respective text field and combo box of them.
And then we will.
We have created a query string SDR insert into room values room plus available status, price and type.
Then we have executed those query by using the connection and the statement objects of our class displayed
a.
NASA's dialog box, which states, as Roome successfully added, then setting as visibility as false
catch block will handle the exception if the source from way to then will close this window by setting
as visibility as false.
Let's move to the new customer dot java class.
This is defined inside the package hotel, adding the necessary packages.
Then we have defined the class, which is a stack standing frame.
Initialize the connection object as null, as prepared a statement as null and a content panel g.
Panel six Text Field A Combo Box two radio buttons and a choice for launching the application.
Inside the main function, we have invoked a new enabled void run method and inside the try function
we have initialize the constructor of the current class.
Setting the visibility of the frame as to catch will end any section.
If occurs, then public new customer throws collapse action.
We have defined the non parameterized constructor which will throw the exception if any occurs.
Setting the ground floor for the window.
Initializing the panel setting.
Adding the Japan to our frame and setting its layout as null adding image.
To our DJ friend window.
Then we have a new label as new customer forum for one type of it, adding the bond and it's.
Adding it to our panel.
Then there is an ID label setting the bound for it, adding to our panel.
Then there is a combo box which shows passport, AADHAAR, card, voter I.D. or driver's license.
So ID can be selected as either passport Aadhaar card, voter I.D. or driving license of the.
Customer setting the bound for the combo box and adding that combo box to a panel.
Next is a label that is number.
So number is is respect of the ID.
That number can be of passport number R number voter I.D. number or driving license number setting bound
for it, adding it to.
And in respect of the number, we have its text field as well that is setting the bound for it, adding
that to our panel and set columns for it that should not exceed ten, I think, and then label and address,
name, name of the employer setting bound for it, adding that to our panel that's for the name respect
to text field setting bound, adding it to a panel, setting its columns.
Then there is a gender for gender.
We have a radio buttons.
First is male setting bound for it and background color for it and bound for it.
Adding it to a panel.
Similarly, a female radio button so that gender can be either female or male.
Then we have country, so country will have a respective text field country.
Then that is a country adding that country to our.
Panel.
Then there is an allocated room number for the new customer that we have added to our panel.
After that, there is ac1 of choice new.
So if inside the dialog we have initiated the connection results that select abstract from room while
our start next will iterate over the rows of the that.
Database and even add RSS numbers.
It will add.
Room number in that choice object, which we have created here, that is seven.
And then we have set the bond for this event and adding that to our panel.
Then there is a label checked and.
And there is a label deposit we have setting bond and added both to our panel.
Then there is a text field.
Respective for the above fields, setting bond for it, adding content panel to it, adding it to our
panel, setting the column for it.
Another text field setting bound for it column.
Adding it to our panel and column.
Similarly, there is another 36 text field.
Now there is a button add for which we have added action listener and action performed defined action
performed method.
So on initializing the connection with the database and setting the radio string to null.
So our one dot is selected.
If our one selected then we will set radio as male.
If our to select it, then we will set radio as female in a string as six.
We have retrieved the item from the choice inside the drive log.
We have retrieve item from the respective fields, column box, text fields and radio buttons, and
we have created to insert customer values.
To insert customer values.
There is a Cuban query and to obtain room set availability.
We has qq2 query.
We have updated executed both query by using as one or as connection statement objects.
Then we have showed the dialog box and visibility of the new reception as true and setting the visibility
of the current as false.
After that, there is a button setting the bound for the button, for running the background color,
adding a red button to our panel.
Then there's the exit bag button inside which we have setting the visibility of the reception class
as to and other current last falls, setting the bound for the buttons and adding to them.
At last we have setting the background color of the current window as white.
So let's move to the last class of this video that is a room defined inside the package hotel.
We have imported the necessary packages for this class.
This class is extending frame.
Connection object as a null j panelists content beam AJ Table.
AJ There are one two, three, four, five, six labels in this class and there's a non constructor
setting default frame and it's bound, creating a new panel, setting the bottle for it, setting its
content layout, adding image to the frame, initializing that table and its bounds.
Then there is a button to load data button labelled as load data.
If this method is for.
Performing event on this button.
So whenever load data is pressed or clicked, so it will select extract data from room and execute that
query with the help of results set and table set model, we will set the model of the table by using
this statement.
Next, setting the button for the button and background, foreground color and adding to our panel.
There is a back button as well, so adding its accent listener.
So it will just move us back to the reception window and set the current visibility as false, adding
back buttons, bound background color, foreground color and adding to our panel.
Then there is another label labeled as label availability, setting it bounce and adding to our panel.
Then the clean status and its price.
Then there is a bed type and a room number type of label.
Setting the whole background color of the window as white background color long for launching the application.
Here is the new invoke little new enabled method defined inside the public void main method which will
create the object of the current class and set the visibility of the frame as true.
So this is all about the three classes let.
See how these classes are running.
What will be the output of these classes?
So let's run a bedroom class first.
We will run this file.
It will look like this.
This is actually defined inside the admin menu bar of our dashboard class.
So this is the add room window.
Then if we run our new customer window on this file, it will look like this.
That is a new customer forum.
This is how it looks.
And that room door java file.
Let's run this one also.
So this is how it will look.