So yes, we were discussed discussing about the checking deposit input method, like getting the deposit
input and the try and catch block exception handling methods were being called and these were asking
for amount to be deposit in the checking accounts.
So there are some conditions to be checked before depositing any amount, whether it be the checking
deposit account or the savings deposits.
So yes, it is going to check like the checking balance and amount which we are willing to deposit is
greater than zero and the amount which we are going to deposit is also greater than zero.
So the combined sum of the balance and the amount and the specific amount should be greater than zero
as a whole.
And then it is going to like calculate the checking deposit amount.
So suppose if we have 10,000 already and we want to deposit 2000, then it is going to like calculate
everything.
We have used this calculator method for deposit.
So yes, it is going to calculate everything and then output the current savings account balance which
will be a sum of the deposited money and the current balance.
So yes, this is going to output the overall balance after the deposit and the LS block is going to
return like the balance.
If becomes less than zero then this if will not execute it and this LS block will execute it inside
this overall block.
And this is going to show that balance cannot be negative.
Suppose that you have already 1000 in your account and you want to like deposit some negative number.
Like suppose you want to deposit -2000 to your account, then the overall balances become -1000, which
is not possible at all.
The balance cannot be negative at any cost, so these things are kept in mind before depositing or withdrawing
money from the system.
So yes, this is all about a savings to draw.
Similarly, we have checking deposit.
So in the similar way we were checking everything with the try block and cash block.
We are checking here in the same way, like we are checking the balance.
Whether the sum is like combined sum is greater than zero and the amount we are willing to deposit is
greater than zero or not.
If yes, then it is going to like system drawdown print and then the current checking account balance
we have like operated everything initially.
This is.
Yes.
So after the deposit the balance is going to be like current savings account balance and this is going
to be returned in this manner only.
So yes, this is the output we are receiving.
So yes, so everything is written in the code blocks.
Yes.
Inside these giant catch blocks, we have commands for everything in case.
If there are any exception, then it is going to return invalid choice.
Like suppose you are inputting some alphabetical things in the Romney choice option.
Then it is going to like output invalid choice and if the balance is negative then it is going to stop
this if block execution and this block is going to execute simply.
And we have already covered this invalid choice.
So, yes, the next concern is to get that deposit input.
So a separate function we are going to create public void get.
Checking import.
So checking deposit input.
Yes.
The second one and this checking deposit input is going to be responsible for like checking the kinds
of exceptions arising in the depositing part of the checking account.
Like we have two types of accounts, the checking channel savings accounts.
So we are handling both of them separately or we are handling the withdrawal and deposit part separately
for both of them.
So initially sending the end of false and a while loop is going to be executed like before end of this
process.
What what is going to be performed.
So a tri block of course which is going to check that everything is correct or not.
So this out and this is going to backslash n display the current savings account balance.
So we are checking it for the checking account.
So it is going to display the checking account balance.
So checking account balance and avoid any kind of typos.
I will fix this.
And then all of the typos will be fixed.
And then, yes, so the current balance will be displayed and this is going to be done in the form of
money, formalities and dot format.
What is the argument we are going to pass?
This is going to be that checking balance.
Yes, this.
So we are done with this.
Unlike us, this outing.
Now, the next concern is to ask the user the amount they want to.
Deposit to their checking account.
So now, after asking the user about the amount they want to deposit into their savings accounts.
Okay, so this is the checking account.
We will be replacing this savings account right now and then doing the same for the checking accounts
also.
So get saving deposit input and then it is going to cut end savings account balance.
Like display the balance.
Then ask the user with the amount to be deposited.
And then it will be simply add the current balance to the amount which is going to be deposited and
add that whether it is yes, greater than zero or not.
In the similar way we were checking it for the checking deposit input.
So yes, this is done like this now after this.
Okay.
So this boolean then.
Get a savings account.
Savings deposit?
Yes.
So there is no lack of a brace or maybe extra.
So yes, this is going to display the current savings account balance.
If everything is fine, that is no exception.
Then this if block is going to be executed and if this is not the case, I suppose the balance is less
than zero.
The sum or this, like both of them are executed together.
Any of one becomes false.
Then the complete statement is going to be like an exhibit and the cells block will be executed.
So both of them should be true in order to make this if statement run properly.
So savings amount and amount.
Suppose they become negative, they are less than zero.
Then this else block will be executed and and it prints balance cannot be negated.
So we have to keep in mind these things.
Yes.
Okay.
The next step is to execute a catch block.
Getting that transfer input is also one of the major concerns inside this account.
Plus, we are done with the saving deposit input, checking deposit input and saving withdraw input
and checking withdrawal so all four of them get methods are covered.
Now the fourth one is to get the transfer input.
So public void get transferred input.
Is the next concern.
And inside this document, which is going to be passed initially, is the account type.
Like initially it is asking that type of account.
Like, let us firstly import the argument and then I will show you what actually this does.
So yes, this get transfer import is asking for that type of account.
And we can see that.
Yes.
So select an account you wish to transfer funds to.
So initially it is asking for a string input, which is going to be the types of account, whether it
be the checking account or if we are already in the checking account, then it will be asking for a
savings and exit.
So we have to choose from these two.
So this get transfer input is going to work in that way.
Boolean N in the similar way as the all the get methods we have covered till now.
And while.
North is equal to end.
Then this tribe lock will be executed.
Otherwise, if there is any kind of exception, then we will be having a separate like catch block also.
For catching the type of exception.
So inside the tribe lock we are going to.
The like.
Write the statement, check the account type.
So if the account type equals.
Let checking account then.
The outputs are going to be.
That way we will be looking at right now.
So this out.
So if we are in checking accounts, then a backslash and select an account you wish to transfer funds
to is going to be the.
Like message on your screens.
So yes.
This is the one.
Select an account.
You wish to transfer funds to.
You wish to transfer funds?
So.
Yes, so this is done in that way.
Okay.
So select ten type of account.
Now the next one is going to be the list of choices and the choices are going to be we will be like
copying this.
Okay, so firstly, let us.
Input the type of account string input containing savings.
And exit.
And after that backslash n with her choice.
So copying this two more times.
For the this ultimatum.
The second one is going to be exhibit.
If we are in the.
First there will be a f method, also a like elseif method.
If we are in the like checking account, we want to transfer funds to the checking account.
Then things are going to be different.
So, yes, this is going to be the three sets out for the choices like list of choices we are going
to have now in the next part.
We are going to declare integer choice variable for the type of choice.
User input.
So input dot next int.
Yes.
This is embedded like variable inside Java.
So yes, in choice input, next choice.
And then after this we are going to like initialize a switch case.
Suppose if user inputs like a one for the savings account, if they are in the checking accounts right
now and they want to say switch to transfer money to the savings account, then a switch case will be
executed in order to like ask the user what is the money they want to transfer and everything.
Now.
Yes, the switch gets executed.
The argument is choice.
So we have one too.
And the default case, the first case is asking that if they want to like transfer money to the savings
account and it is going to output the current account balance, then we'll ask for the money they want
to deposit to the savings account.
And then at the next step they will like output the present balance after the successful transfer.
So yes, the same train block we discussed above is the check there.
The balance should not be negative in any case, and invalid choices are also checked.
Our choices should be made very carefully.
Now, similarly, for this checking account type, the things are done in the similar way.
I have already discussed this about this as if we are checking the same thing for the savings account,
the types of account and everything is done in the similar way.
We have checked this for the checking account.
So yes, the string ex except type is going to be the similar for the savings account as well.
If they choose to transfer money to the checking account, then these will be the questions as to the
user what is going to be the type of account and the money they want to deposit.
And at the end the calculated balance will be displayed to the user that what they transferred and what
is actually left with them.
So this is all about the accounts class.
We have covered all the calculations required inside this now saving the next part.