You know, in the previous thing I told you, we created one client trade, which is exchange trade.
I mistake that in first part is we closed that server or class of only.
So the this class client should inside only that server class.
Otherwise it will not run.
So for that purpose I'm going to using inside only that server class.
Now we are created already this constructor.
Now we are remaining with some methods which is basically that get input each and everything, as I
told you earlier.
So first, create a one input or or we can say we can create a one method which is get username for
getting the username.
Inside our.
Client.
So let me create one public void.
Get.
User.
Name.
Which is basically.
Returning.
Username.
So.
Why it should be string.
Let me tell you, it is returning as a string.
So it should be string.
It's not returning void or anything.
Now I need to set the username.
Similar method public.
Now it's it should be void set username.
Again this.
So let me check first.
If I use this set username e anywhere.
No.
So said username is a first time part.
So you need to require.
I told you because.
Or this is very what we can say sometimes this is very huge code.
Sometimes you miss checkers those some part or you know writing or you can say uppercase lowercase.
So always remember you should.
Go with that part.
So this is using the set username to the username.
So this is done.
So this is for the setting, the username and all the things.
So what I'm creating here, I need to create an infinite loop.
Let me write in finite.
New to read and forward message.
So what it's actually going to do, it is storing in the as object that message inside our client we
can say and or we can say edit class released and what it will be do it will print that in a broadcast
we.
So I knew the void meant for public void.
Run run is basically for the running that.
Third, as you can see here, we got this one symbol here.
So what is this thing?
Is it is executing the trade class.
And you can see target run.
It is overriding all of this.
Never change that.
But I'm telling you that before libraries.
Who knew until logout.
So what I'm going to do is William, you know, keep going.
I created already.
Bullion keep going is equal to.
Through.
They'll keep going.
I need to mention the reading part.
So.
Read.
String.
So what I'm going to do, I'm going to read that string.
So what the things we required here is very similar.
I need to create a blog.
I will tell you what is going to do is I will introduce these chat messages and chat messages.
Another class and this class.
And it will go to that input and each and every time.
So as I mentioned this, we need to clear this now.
What is remaining class?
Not found thing here.
So I am mentioning what we can say will specify the carriage block for our exception different class
not found exception different because there is very important part here.
If you are mentioning exception, it will print all the exceptions.
But for our client user interface purpose, I'm using this.
Then.
I'm going to get the message.
I should get that message from that part.
So what I'm going to do is I'm mentioning this part also.
So I will tell you where I'm going to create this great message in the chat message and each and everything.
So what I need to do is I need to get a different action based on the type of that messages, as I told
you, or if that username part is different and each and everything, I can create a switch case here.
So I will explain the switch case first year.
Often this.
I will mention this.
Okay.
Now, what are these things?
After this chat message, I'm going to ask switch get type, which is basically in the chat message.
Chat message is a message which some broadcast it will.
What will you repeat?
The username and the message.
And what is the confirmation to you?
The confirmation is blocked.
No such use exist.
So what is this part, actually?
As I told you.
While I'm asking if I check for that eldritch symbol here I direct John, it will go to that private
research part for search purposes.
What I'm going to do, I'm creating here that broadcast part here.
So you can see I can say that what if I'm printing logout from the user?
It will be disconnected for the who is in metered.
It will print all username since that date part.
So this is all about things.
How we can create.
So I need to create.
If you're out of the loop or disconnected, I need to remove that ID and etcetera.
Things I need to mention here.
Then it will be asked me for all gender.
Okay.
So this is how we can create this part.
So.
Let me do two or three things here first as I created here using method.