So here is the add customer java file, which is also defined inside the package airline.
So we have imported here the necessary packages which we will use inside this class.
So we have.
Importing Java .8. event Q Package eight dot as straight package, which is a stack window toolkit used
to develop graphical user interface applications.
KW 2.1. aspect, which is also used to handle events.
In our next stop based application.
And then we have defined import Java SQL to handle connection off of a program with our micro database
and Java swing to develop graphical user interface in a more modified manner.
Then we have to find the class.
At customer which is extending frame and.
Then we have to find text fields.
Here are the.
Seven Text field variables.
Then we have defined a constructor which is a non parameterized constructor.
Inside which we have set the foreground colour of the.
Window as blue and background color of the window as white.
After that, we have said that title that is add customer detail for the window.
Default close operation has hired on close.
Size for the window that is 778 cross 486 layout as null.
Then we have defined the label.
For instance, as passport number.
Label as passport number as well.
Setting the font for that label.
One family of Tahoma.
Styles plane and size is 17.
Setting the bound for it.
X and y values are 60 and 80.
Height is 27 and width is 150.
Adding the passport number to over a frame or window.
Then we have defined the text field.
Respective to the.
Passport number.
And.
Define it's bound.
X is 200.
Y is 80.
It's worth as 150 and height is 27.
Adding that text field to our frame.
Then we have defined the button j button and stands next.
Labeled as sale.
Then after that we have defined the bound for that button.
X is 200.
Y is for 20.
Its width is 150 and height is 30.
Background color of the button as black and foreground.
Color of the button as white.
Adding that button to our DJ frame.
After that, we have defined another label as being our number and.
Set the phone for that label.
Font family is Tahoma type as plain.
Size 17, setting the bounds for that number as 60 x as 60.
Y as 120.
And.
Height is 27 and width is 150.
Adding the number to that.
Frame and window.
Then we have defined its respective text field.
For the number setting the bound for it where access to Android Y is 120.
Height is 27 and width is one fifth of the text field.
Adding the text field to our frame and window.
We have defined the label here labeled as address.
For which after which we will be adding the text field to enter address for the user, setting the font
for that label, its font family as Tahoma type as plain and size as 17.
Setting the bond for the address where X and Y values are 60 and 170 respectively, and the width and
height of the value, width and height of that label are 150 and 27 respectively, adding that label
to our frame.
Now we have initialize the respective text field to enter address.
Setting the tone for the text field, whose location is 200 cross 17 and its height and width is 150
cross 27, adding that text field to our window.
After that, we have another label labeled as nationality.
Setting the font for is whose font family is Tahoma.
Type is plain and its size is 17.
Setting the bound for the nationality label whose location is 60, close to 20, and whose size is 150
close.
27.
Hiding the nationality label to our DJ frame.
Then we have defined the respective text field for the nationality.
Text field.
Bound here, whose location is 200 cross to 20 and all size is 150 cross 27.
Hiding the text filled to a large frame.
After that, we have defined another label labeled as name.
Setting the font for that label font family tahoma font type plain and font size 17.
Setting the bounds for that label whose location is 60, close to 70, and whose size is 150 cross 27.
Adding the label name to our window.
Initializing the another text field respect to that name label.
Initializing the bound of that text field that is 200 calls to seventies its location and its size is
150 cross 27.
Text field, adding that text field to over a frame.
Defining another label labeled as gender.
Setting the font for the agenda whether it's font family is Tahoma it's.
Type is plane and its size is 17.
Then we have set the bound for that label where X and Y 16 and 320 and which is 150 cross 17 width and
height.
Adding that gender to our.
Frame and window.
Then there is radio buttons for the gender.
First is male whose color background color has white.
Setting the bound for it whose location is to enter across to 20 and inside in width are 27 and 70.
Adding that radio to our frame, another radio button labeled as female background color as wide setting
the.
Bound for the female button that is to a t cross 3.8.
Its location and its width and height are 1727 respectively.
Adding female to over.
Jeffrey.
Then there is a J label phone number.
As phone number its foreign family, the humor font type plain and font.
Size is 17.
Its location is 63, 70, and its size is 150 plus 27, adding that phone number to OG frame.
After that, the respect text will for the phone number whose location is to enrich close to 70 and
its size is one 5027, adding the text field to over a frame.
After that, we are setting the visibility of the current window.
S2.
Then we have another label as ad passenger whose headed as ad customer details foreground color as blue
and its font family is.
The home type is plane and its defining size is 31.
Who is setting the bound for it?
That's location is for 20 cross 24 and its size is for 42 cross 35.
Adding that label to our frame.
Then we have the flight code label setting the font for it with five font families, Tahoma player type
airplane and sizes 17 setting the bound for that label whose location is 60 plus 30 and its size is
150 plus 27.
Adding that flight code label to our frame and the respective text field of the flight code was bound
and location is 200 cross 30 and its size is 150 plus 27, adding that text field to our j frame.
After that we have defined an image icon inside the.
I can folder.
Then added that image icon to our.
Global.
Initializing the bound for the label whose location is 458 and sizes two eight across 410, adding that
label to our frame.
After that we have defined next add listener.
So next must be a button.
Let's see.
Yeah.
Here it is.
A button next.
So we have defined adding a listener to our next button.
Defining the action performed method inside the action performed method.
First inside the string passport number we are fetching from the text field.
Passport number PNR number from the respective text field one.
Address from the respective text field to nationality from the respective text field three.
Name from the respective text field for and the flight code from the respective text field.
Six then send a string.
Gender is equals to null.
A string phone number as equals fetching the phone number from the respective text field.
Five Now defining if new radio button is selected.
If the new data button is selected, then we will select as gender male f is the female is selected,
then we will select gender.
It goes to female.
So that depends on the radio buttons.
After that, inside the drive block we have first initialize the connection see as new connection or
object and define the.
A string.
Hestia inside which we have written the query insert into passenger values p and number address nationality
names and their phone number, passport number and flight code.
After that we have executed the executed the update.
Execute a date query here see dot as dot execute update inside which we have passed the string string
and then we have showed the dialog box as customer added and set the visibility of the current window
as false.
So after the successfully addition of the customer, the window will be set as false.
Catch block will handle any exception focus setting the size of the current frame as 900, cross 600.
Setting the visibility of the frame as true.
Setting the location of the frame as 400 plus 200.
Inside the main method we have just initialized that customer call the add.
This will just call that customer constructor inside which we have defined all the functionalities of
that.
So this is about the customer class of this project.
So.
Let me show you how it will look like when we will run this.
So I will be showing you from the login page.
Let's run the login page.
I will be writing the information.
And then.
Plus there's one, two, three, four, five.
Let's look.
Here.
This is the main fan base.
The previous one was for vlogging class.
This was for the main frame class.
And inside the alarm system, click on add customer details.
Now this base is the output of the ADD customer.
Plus here we can write the details and select male or female.
Phone number and click on Save.
So we'll be closing it.
That's how it will look like when we will run the ad customer class.