Okay.
So we already created this symmetric key generator part, which is generating a symmetric key of.
Ciphertext using a algorithm.
So we don't regret this because Java security, this package will take care of this all welcome.
So we don't want to and as I told you, while developing this code, I told you it will always create
another key difference here.
So you require this XML also, which is Java X bind.
Or you can use Java XML.
You may find this on internet or this is Java.
You have to download another dependency if you are using mine.
You have to use dependency injection directly here.
I am not currently using Maven, so I need to.
Mention this directly, so let us see.
We already created this.
So now I'm going to create full project for this.
So we close this part and this is on the added part.
What I'm going to do is not.
I'm going to create your one app.
So let me give the names app dot Java Java Class App.
So what I'm doing, I created this symmetric case for representation, but for the App Command interface.
I'm going to proceed with this.
Then what I'm going to mention is.
Eat this.
I'll go first.
So again, that's simple.
But in first I used your public static.
Now I'm going to use private here.
Remember that private I need to mention, or I don't want to change this algorithm later so no one is
going to change this as a as the time going to mention after this.
Using BLOCK.
Safe would say for the block.
It's a technique.
CB Technique commonly known as CB is to ensure that block of separate text never going to change static.
Finally green or I'm using the name as is sip siphon siphon.
Now remember is slash which are going on CBS for lack of ciphertext of CBS.
And remember there is one another thing here and p c.
It's for you.
Remember, this four party package is for you.
Mostly Package C is for you.
Pending.
I'm going to use it.
So this is about all about how I'm going to use.
Now I'm going to create one static scanner.
Private static scanner.
Scandal.
And let me mean in your message, but.
So now we've done with this?
No.
I need to mention May 3rd.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I need to create static.
Why?
I required static.
As I told you in previous
tutorial or previous video.
We created that part already.
So similarly, what we required is we required one static key here.
Static key generator or security?
Security static.
So let me create one secret.
We tried to create security.
So, again, it's simple as we already created this.
It should be public.
Public static.
Secret game and great secret JavaScript.
I'm going to use your secret key.
Create yet a is because it is so it should be easy now we done with this so it shows so no secure random
thing that will secure random java for randomizing everything secure random let me small and between
new.
So good.
So that's for.
Randomizing a gene I need to randomize again.
When I were putting new messages like first I put hello for that hello message.
The key should be different.
If I put the next message by for that, my key should be different always.
Then he generated I'm going to use key generator.
That's the key.
We want this key generator.
Degenerative.
Don't get instant.
Just instant, instant.
I need to mention algorithm A.
So it's been.
An exceptionally close search algorithm.
So I need to handle exceptional.
Then similar thing.
I would use a generator.
Generator, I need to initialize it now because I haven't created I need to initialize the generator
in it.
Basically initial 56, similar random connection slash secure random.
I'm going to lose.
So good, right?
Let me.
Now.
I need to create security here.
Security is my security.
Jail and duty is equal to Gideon Rita.
And not this key generator.
Key that key generator.
Key generator dot generators, which is default metal and which is going to be the key.
So let me tell you what is all these things we already created here, so.
Let me mention this again.
Your.
Who?
Avoid the confusion confusion part.
So it's going to return the.
Now I need to create one victor part.
So let me tell you, what is this method?
Do you need a vector?
I need to create a vector which.
Any hints why I need to pass the message bite by bite.
So for this purpose, I'm going to be public static.
Bite me.
Bite.
What I need in not only this bite, I need it create initially.
So I'm going to mention it.
Create an issue.
So this is my name?
No initial.
But you then could create initialization vectors, as I mentioned, as we saw with radiation.
This is my name.
I'm going to use some methods.
So.
Nick Minchin used with encryption.
I need to encrypt something in this data.
So for this purpose, what I'm going to do by.
No, no.
Remember.
I need to create initialization vector.
So initial.
I'm going to mention you.
We will take this.
There's.
You let me use camel case.
So there may be no errors using camel case.
No typos is equal to if you know no by mentioning 60 by 66 and point six, then it will let you do 56.
Then I need to secure random.
Now remember why I need to know?
Because I need to again create a secure, random thing here.
Randomizing every part I need to create every thing.
Random is not only the key gene part, but also.
Achieving the 100% randomizing.
Secure.
Random dot.
Next byte.
And what I need to mention is the victor part, which is basically.
Initially we so.
That I already mentioned.
And what it should be.
It should do return.
Initial return.
But it should be work.
It should be done this part.
Encrypt.
We will do this later.
What we are going to do is I'm going to start.
And let me optimize the inputs because.
It's very useful to optimise inputs on just optimising inputs to avoid.
Modeling delays.
So I created this.
Now I need to create which functions is going to take plaintext with the key with the initialization
and its vector and another vector to convert plaintext to a ciphertext.
So we need to create that part also.
So.
Return to.
A plain text.
And which key convert to ciphertext.
Okay.
So I need to get this also.
So public static.
Static.
Bite again.
Bite.
Oh, let me mention names do a is encryption.
I need to get this encryption.
And inside this inscription, what I'm going to do.
String and string.
Plain text once you.
Secret key.
Information security.
And I need to mention it.
Now.
It is a very long method, so we will create it by.
Small, small building.
But.
So let me tell you one thing here.
Let me put these things as attributes, not as my.
Kings.
And let me tell you why.
It's a tribute because two things are that one.
Initiate.
Or.
With.
I would view them as like this closing this because there are too many things here which are going to
cause me the exception also.
So that's what we required for this.
So these are the plaintiffs security and initial victories.
They're attributes.
And now we are going to create one ciphertext and everything here.
Who let me mention cipher cipher.
Seafood is equal to.
Seven.
But get instance.
You can get insurance.
A.
It is typing on a cipher.
It's so full.
I'll go get them.
So.
It is not.
We currently.
Next name is ASCAP, our algorithm.
Where is that?
Okay, so the CBS cipher block its algorithm is.
I want to say for a good.
No.
What I'm going to do this force, I forbid I required some IV parameters, specs of that part and everything.
So we will do that part later.
So consider I created two vectors with byte, which is initial vector for initializing the randomizing
the part.
And second is to take plaintext and key convert and with the key convert to the ciphertext.
So hope you understand.
In the next part we are going to complete this.