So in this video we will be talking about our next three classes, which are for the cashier purpose,
and these classes will be used by the admin to add any cashier, search for any cashier or delete any
cashier.
So these will be the three classes, the first class we will be having.
Look on this is add cashier class.
So this class is defined inside the package store.
Very important the necessary packages like import font but j button j label menu menu item g panel,
scroll panel j text j text area and password feed.
These all are the packages inside the Java export string.
Then we have defined imported color action lesson and action event.
These are the packages inside a, w, t and JWT event respectively.
Then we have defined our class.
And Cashier, which is extending panel inside which we have a text field type of variable user field
or g button type of variable button add cashier.
Then there is a password field type of variable password field and j label named as error and setting
the string e r as enter username and password.
And there is a two types of string user and pos.
Then we have defined the non parameterized constructor for the.
Plus the set, the layout of the constructor as null.
After that, we have Santa bound for the frame, which is located as hundred and 100 and excise will
be 840 cross 619.
Then we have defined the jailable label ad cashier named as ad cashier and we have set the bound for
it.
Whose location will be 328, comma 45 and size will be 182 cross 21 Then we have set the font for that
label.
Font will be Tahoma font plain and its size will be 17.
Then we have added the label add cashier to our frame.
Similarly, we have added another label named as username font for its font family Tahoma font type
plain and font size 14 setting the bound for it bound is to 46 comma 104 sizes 124 cross 21 adding that
label to our frame after that inside the label password.
The app which is labelled as password said the font for it.
Similar font for this label also and bound for it.
The bound is location 246 comma one 3600 sizes 124 comma 21 adding that label to frame.
Similarly, we have a label sorry text field as user text field setting the bound for it, which is
430 611106 and it sizes 147 comma 20 adding that user field to our frame.
After that there is a button add cashier which is labeled as cashier, so this will handle an event.
So we have defined actions and action performed method inside action performed method.
We have initialize the user string to user field or get text frame so the train method will trim the
string from the any spaces.
Either is starting middle or last the password field.
Similarly we have did with the password feed converted into the to to stream and to to lowercase as
well.
After that, if the username and password is null, we will set the error message that you should enable
either invalid username password or send the username password.
Then if that those are not null, then we will be calling add cashier method of the database class which
we have discussed earlier and.
And then we will set the user fee, set text as null and password fields that text as null.
After that we have ADD cashier setting the bound for that button for 3621, 94 and its location is 147
plus 33, adding that button to the frame.
Similarly, we have a password field where we will be entering our password and after that there is
an error label which will store or show the error whenever any error or occurs.
So this is the ADD case share method and now we will be looking at the search cashier method.
So this class.
Define inside the package store.
We have imported the necessary package like Java eight dot font swing dot button swing dot label g panel,
scroll pane.
Text area, text field.
Action is not an action event.
Now we have defined our class, which is extending the G Flame G panel and there is a text field, ID
field and a button, but an update product and the label has error.
ID comma error is equals to enter product productivity.
Then we have defined the non parameter constructor of this class.
Search cashier center layout of the frame as null.
Then we set the bound for that frame 100 108 sizes.
Eight 4619 Then we will be searching for the label search cashier and that set the bound of 3 to 19
cross three, 1984 and 182 plus 21 ages sites.
Then we have defined the font, family type and size for that, adding that label to the frame.
After that, we have defined the label label user name as username.
Similarly, we have defined the font family type and size for that label set the bound for that label
location has 253 and 56 and size as 124 cross 21.
After that, we have edited and added that label to our frame.
Similarly, we have ID field, which is a text field setting the bound for the text field.
449 comma 158 is its location and its size will be 136 cross 20 Then we have added that field to our
frame.
After that there is a button product update product.
So this will be new button search label as search button and then we will be adding action listener
to that button and we have defined action performed method for that button.
So if the ID field of get text is equal to null, so if the ID field is null, then we will show the
error message that you should enter valid ID after that.
If the text field is not null, then we will show the ID is equal set by IDs, goes to the fields text
entry.
So we'll be setting the ID a string to the provided ID from the text field and call the DB search cashier
method, which will be showing and displaying the details of that cashier for that particular ID.
After that, we have set the button set the button search.
It's bound location will be for 49 to 19 and its size is 136 plus 23.
Added that button to our frame.
After that we have defined the error label with the null value foreground color as red and setting it
boundary 49, comma to 77 and sizes 217, cross 14 and added that label also to our frame.
So this is about the search cashier or Java file.
Now we will be having a look at our delete file, which will help us to delete any details of the cashier.
So this is also defined inside the package store.
And we have defined or imported packages like a dot font saying dot j button label menu, menu item
j panel scroll pane text area text field j password field color action lesson an action event.
These are the packages we have imported.
After that, we have defined our class, which is extending the J panel.
Text filled and there is a G text field named as user field.
G button as button delete catcher.
Then is the password field and another label as L and a string.
There are three string user paths and it goes to enter username and password.
Then we have defined the non parameter constructor for this delete catcher class.
Also setting the layout as null.
Then we have set the bound for the frame like location and Red Cross and read from 108 sizes eight 4619
then we have defined the label delete catcher setting the bound for it whose location is 328 comma 45
and sizes 182 class 21.
After that we have defined the font.
Family phone type and font size.
Then we have a defined edit label label delete catcher tool frame.
Similarly for the user name we have and define the label set the font for that label with the help of
dot set font, its font type font family and font size.
Then we have set the boundary to 46 comma 104 and sizes 124 cross 21 added that label to our frame.
Then we have defined the password field password label as well and setting the font for it font, family
font type and font size.
Then there is a label password for which we have set the bound.
Which location is 246 comma 136 and sizes one 2421 And then there is we have added that label to our
frame.
After that, there is a user field which is a text field setting bound for it, which is location is
440 9106 and its size is 136 cross 20.
Then we have added that user field as well to our frame.
After that there is a button delete here, so that is labeled as the cashier and then we have a defined
action list and define the action.
Perform the method method for this button, delete cashier and which will be taking our argument as
action event of lib named as e inside which we have initialized our user ID string with the user filtered
text and trimming that text.
And then we have initialized our password field as well by converting it to lower case and also training
that password.
Now if the user and password field is equals either of them as equals to null, then we will show the
error message that enter username or password.
If there is none of these fields will be null, then we will be calling our debit or delete cashier
method by passing the username and password to that argument for that particular method that is delete
cashier so debit or delete cashier will call.
The Delete catcher method from our baby class and delete the record for that particular username and
password.
After that, the button delete share.
We have set the bound for that button whose location is 449 comma 194 and sizes 136 cross 23.
After that we have added that button to our frame.
Then we have defined the password field and set the bound for the field.
Whose location is 449 comma 138 and its sizes 136 cross 19 adding that password field to our.
Frame and the error label which will be used if.
We did not enter any values in ID or a username or password field.
So these are the three classes which we have discussed or used for the cashier that are we can either
add cashier or we can search for the cashier and we can also delete the cashier.
So that's all in this.