So while I coded some part, if you closely look, I created different things.
First, I created one employee service as an interface which is passing the list with void some data,
get employees of employees and some fingerprinted.
It's just for page sorting files and everything is going to create sorting the fields and everything.
I created a page employee as my another list.
In this, I created one modality which is purely based on GPA, which is going to create columns and
everything.
Third thing I created in the service is basically this is interface and to implement in the class,
I created one service.
I mentioned one service.
It's very easy thing.
I mentioned some other wire things and I'm putting in the list and I'm going to create that.
I'm creating auto generated part so that just the object oriented thing I created with some accessing
part.
This is very important.
I'm descending in the descending order.
I am creating that field.
I created a one JPG repository to store the cache files and I'm using in this.
So if you close.
Look, I already created a one controller part in the controller.
I'm going to mention one class name as the employee controller to control the employee parts.
So.
It mentioned employee controller.
So this is the main thing which is going to handle the back end and fetching the data.
It's going to create it's going to access the everything part.
So now it's let me mention the controller in the spring framework that is defaulting, which is basically
the controller.
Again, to it is very important to not create a manual connection.
Always we can mention the wild thing then private.
I need to mention service.
So employee service I need to create here.
I'm going to mention employee service.
To employees service.
So it will access that employee service directly.
Now I need to display.
I need what I need to do.
Display a list of employees in that order.
You can see part of your data or part of each HTML file.
I need to display all the things, so for that purpose I need to create one mapping thing so it's easy
get mapping.
Because get mapping.
Let's.
So why it's giving me the error is because create annotation is mapping at the moment.
So I haven't added the mapping dependency.
So you need to access that dependency.
Let me show you.
It's very easy.
And if your dependence is not added, go to here and add my own dependency in this.
It will search for mapping and click here add.
That's it.
You need to perform.
So wait for some time.
It will.
And my independency dependency for you, which is basically the gate mapping.
As you can see, it's resolving my dependency part.
Ignoring this, I'm going to create further mappings.
Which is basically the string.
View homepage, which is basically homepage view.
As the name suggest.
More than.
And so it's me asking me to enter to get that mapping part.
So what we can do is just put together, start to optimize the inputs.
So that's it.
I need to mention here, this is basically my method, which is I'm going to perform this view model
thing.
So a default page is one basically page.
One.
So in this I need to mention the return.
When?
Basically I need to mention that page instead thing.
One, which is basically my one first name as my default thing.
It should be all synchronous.
Or you can say ASCII part and I'm going to mention the model.
Now.
You didn't ask me.
What is this?
So.
It's asking me to create the distance.
But the thing is, I already created in.
Somewhere.
Let me check there.
Okay.
So I need to mention this one.
And the thing is.
I need to implement this also.
So let us check why it's giving the error because.
Okay.
We will check it later.
The main I think is the model.
So.
Let me explore.
Let me do one thing.
It's accessing the everything, but it's not accessing the public public properly.
Right.
So this.
Let me check.
Is there any
we will find find that little part.
So maybe there is one error with.
Mapping part or anything.
So we will check it later.
So we created one mapping for the basic mapping here.
So it's not very complicated data thing, I guess.
So it's just creating a mapping and it's created own mapping part.
So what is it's creating is basically it's creating different things.
So let me do one thing.
Just let me.
Divide this downward and it makes us this.
Let me mention this as this.
And.
I guess this employee controller is basically the.
No, it's not that part.
It's not the fault of this.
In the later part, we need to create one method and defaulting.
So no need to.
What do you about this thing?
So in a similar way, I'm going to create different, different mappings here.
So let me show you what I'm going to do.
So as you can see, I created this part.
Already and least is.
Kim Jong un.
Don't you do not star in the.
Everything okay?
Now, we created this.
So let me tell you what I'm going to do what I'm doing here.
So I'm just mentioning view home page for one, the soccer field first name with the ASCII directory
with model show new employee form to showing the new employee form with this employee with the model,
then save employee.
So these are the gate mapping and post mapping methods I created.
So if you want to check, you can put here or insert also to check whether you can divide dependency,
you can add and you can check everything in the generator generation part.
But let me tell you, this is for the ID purposes, then delete employee again this thing then page
is for the paging part and all the things.
So in the later part I'm going to create one HTML pages and after that I'm going to show you how you
can set up first database and after that, how you can implement that database in your application.
Hope we understand.
Thank you.
This is just a controller part which is accessing the controller.
So if you go to insert also, you can check your auto dependencies with different different dependencies,
task scheduler and everything you can check so you can directly create team live also here instead of
putting again and again so you can found it.
So this is just a great mapping and set mapping methods and creating push mapping also I created so
for the delete employee and everything so by looking this you can check your is very easy you can perform
hope you understand.
Thank you.