So in the previous part we have covered the conditions of player X winning the game and in total there
are eight statements with some queries inside it and showing that these are the conditions for making
the player excellent now or what are the total like combinations of making a player win.
So there are total this 333384x and 840.
So total we have to cover 16 statements in order to check that if a specific player wins the game or
not.
So for checking that if player zero wins.
So these are the LCF statements inside which we have written the similar combinations like one, two,
three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine and
1472581599357
and at last or else if nine.
So there is an additional condition.
We will come to this later for still, let's take a look at this combination that totals 16 combination
we were talking about.
So there are similar rules for player X winning as we are for the player or winning.
So we have similar combinations for both of the players.
So inside conditions are also same just in the matter of fact that for player or winning we are updating
the account to plus one and for player x winning we are updating x count two plus one.
So you can see there are two blocks.
This is for the X count and this is for the account.
And if the player x wins, we are updating the scores head and if excellence then we are updating the
scores above.
So this is the only difference in these two stops like player X winning and player or winning.
And there are no other like a visible difference I can see between these two functions.
So yes, we have covered all the possible conditions for making the player wins and at last, like we
have already showed the message, we have talked about the dialog box thing and everything we have already
discussed.
So we have a 3 to 3 grid and there should be nine possible combinations and we are talking about only
eight combinations, four X winning and eight combinations for player or winning.
So the one condition which is left in both the players chances is this case in which, like I said,
two nine and what is ie nine like that all the blocks are filled and no player wins.
Initially we have set it to zero and one by one.
If the blocks are started filling then I is updated like I.
If this block fails, I will be updated to one.
If this fails, I will be updated to two and total of nine.
So if suppose all the nine blocks failed and none of the possible combination above mentioned here did
not arrive, then what is going to happen?
So if I becomes nine n none of the possible cases above mentioned paradigm.
So the dialog box will appear and see no one wins and this will be going to the heading of the like
I am talking about this now.
We have we have already discussed it in the introduction part.
A similar dialog box will appear this way showing that no one wins with okay.
But then when we click the okay button, the game will be reset.
So yes.
So this is although like 18 conditions by far eight eight common in both and like eight eight all zero
and one X meaning and the two conditions common in both the flip player winning is if I becomes nine.
So this is common.
So there are total nine plus 918 conditions covered by far.
Now this thing is, I think, completed.
So we have checked the functionalities of making a specific plan.
Now in the next part, we are going to set a function for choosing the player like this function's name
is going to be choose player and.
If there is a if statement inside this start game.
So the starting of game equals signal.
Equals ignored kids.
So basically X and O are high uppercase alphabets only.
There are nothing special in the symbols.
So the start game should be small.
So inside this if statement, if the starting case is X, then start and the next player should be zero.
So start game should be set to zero or whatever we say it.
And if there is else, there is will be notes, of course.
So inside there, if the game is started.
So I am going to copy the same stuff for this cells and we'll paste it here and set this or to x.
So this part is covering that.
Suppose the player X is starting the game.
So the next chance will be transferred to zero.
And if this is not happening, then the next chance will be given to X.
Of course the zero is starting the game so the next chance should be given to x only.
So we have covered by far all the winning cases like launching the application and choosing the player.
Now our next concern is going to be like initializing the contents inside the frame.
Like you can see that this is our frame and we have to initialize contents inside the frame.
You can see that there is a grid layout thing which has five in a row, one three in a column, and
there are total 15 blocks, all like a banner title bar and two buttons, three set energy and two scoreboards
for Player X and zero respectively.
So now that we have a dedicated function for initializing the contents inside the frame, we have used
this initialize header also and I told you that we will be looking to it later.
So this is responsible for launching of the application.
Like this application will open and after opening what is going to be consisted inside the frame.
So yes, this is going to be consistent inside the frame.
We have a frame with the mercy of frame component of the swing library.
And this is going to give us a new frame of this dimension.
This is the like length, width, height, and like all the four sides of the frame are responsible
by this line, after which we have our default close operation attached to the frame.
We can exit the frame and that will be responsible for escaping the window in which the app is opening.
We have a great content space and the layout is set to zero, so let us try to check that whether the
frame is correctly opening or not.
So perfect.
We have a picture frame.
We have like this pane I was talking about.
This was the pane.
We have a heading pane and there is a frame of this dimension we have already discussed.
So we have already created our frame.
So congratulations.
Now we will be setting up 15 lightweight layout blocks, two buttons and two scoreboards.
So let's look towards it.
But what are required after this?
So after the creation of Frame, we are going to create the contents of the panel.
So we have a frame.
And inside the frame we have a panel which is going to consist the grid layout.
So to initialize the things with the panel, we are going to.
So these two are the functionalities of panel.
We are going to like create inside the frame and the panel is going to contain a grid layout of a three
by five, and then the width of the body is going to be two by two, after which the panel is going
to contain a border layout line border like you can see that here.
So I'm going to run this part and show you what is actually happening inside the frame.
So it's perfect.
The panel is created and we have a five by three divisions which we are going to cover later.
So by far we have created a panel inside the frame and after which we are going to add more functionalities
inside the frame.
So after setting the like dimensions for the panel, now we are setting a button for for the button
first.
And that button is going to be like an action performing button.
There is an action listener attached with that button and an event is going to be performed on clicking
that button.
So we have a set that text to start game.
So if start game equals ignore X, then button set foreground color to red.
So this first block is responsible for the first chance we are playing.
So suppose the first.
We are trying to play the chance by X, so we will click here and the first chance will be played.
We are going to check this by turning the program also.
So let's go and try running Java for this class and check that whether it is working or not so perfect.
We have set the background for our first panel and we have also set a button like an action listener
button which is responsible for playing the first chance by default to X.
So and we have set the color like text font, font color, we will see it.
Firstly, check it that if it is working or not actually.
So yes, perfect.
We have set this button to a working button which is an event attached to it and the button is listening
to the actions attached with the event of that specific thing.
So we have checked it.
Now we will go back to the program and look at the functionality.
So yes, this was the button thing.
We have set the button colour to read the background colour of the panel to blue and the action attached
with the button is that suppose if we click that button then our x symbol should appear in that block
of the grid layout thing.
So yes, we have done this for the first panel.
Now we will be doing this for other nine.
Like we have total 15 blocks in the grid layout.
So we have to like set everything for every button.
Like we have a separate input covering inside every button so that nine nine, like three three grid
layout is going to consist the Xs and zeros.
The four blocks are going to be responsible for storing the scores of the both the players and the next
two buttons are going to contain, reset and exit buttons.
Yes.