So after the successful creation of the teacher and the student class, we are heading over to the school
section.
So the school is the main body which is managing the funds in a way of giving the salary to the teachers
and receiving the fees from the students.
So the main system here is the school for which we are creating this project for a management of soirées
in the school.
Similar way of the teacher and the student.
We will create a class.
School and inside the class we will create some variables.
So private.
Peter.
We know that a school comprises of teachers and students.
So it is the beginning.
Correct beginning for this class by initializing the students and teachers.
So, yes, the student and teachers now.
School consists of teachers and students.
But what is the actual purpose of this project?
Like we are here to manage the funds.
So how the funds are consisted of in the funds we have a total money on.
Our total fund is earned by the school and the school have to spend it in various ways of giving the
salary to certain teachers and save something as a profit.
So yes, we have to create a variable for that thing also.
So creating a private static class for the total money.
We will learn about static in.
Total money earned.
Yes.
So the total money earned by the school and in the similar way total money spent.
So I will copy this part and paste it here.
Total money spent.
So, yes, we have successfully created the members of this school class as teacher student.
The total money and the total money spent.
Now you must be wondering that in student and teacher class.
We initialized the ID and which was unique for every teacher and student.
Each teacher has a unique name and each student has a unique name similar with the IDs.
But does a school contain a single teacher or a single student?
Is it possible?
Let's think about it on yourself.
The answer is no, that a school can never be built with a single teacher or student.
It will not exist in that way.
So you must be wondering that how to add multiple teachers and student in this class name school.
So I am giving you a second to think about it.
What comes in your mind?
How to gain multiple datas with this teacher variable?
So a method may arise in your mind of declaring this as an error.
Right.
So.
Bring it in this way?
Yes.
So we will declare an error in this way.
But think about it.
So if we take the teacher and students as an error, we know the concept of vary.
It has a limited number of size, like we have to initialize the size of the area in the beginning and
it is immutable.
We cannot change the size of an area.
So suppose if a teacher wants to leave the school or join or a teacher wants to join the school later.
So is it possible to do so with arrays?
The answer is no.
As arrays are immutable, if we create a size initially, we could not alter it later.
So we have to think in a broader way to create a data type which is resizable and adds or deletes datas
of teachers and students very conveniently without any restrictions.
So removing make this.
I am going to tell you about a very beautiful data type code analyst.
Yes, Java has this data type ArrayList, which is resizable and has many features in it, which makes
it useful in many ways.
So I am going to show you this in this demo dot java file.
So yes, here I have already created this demo java file.
Yes.
So in this.
I have created a demo class and inside this public static void main string args.
So here is a main function inside which the ArrayList is called.
So list integer number is equal to new ArrayList.
This is the way to declare an analyst in Java head it.
After writing this link I will show you writing this again.
If I write, list her.
It is showing that it is from the Java Library.
And when I write this list, this import library automatically comes here.
So after this.
I have created a list called numbers, which contains a data type of integer.
So this is a demo function and I am going to run some integers in the array list and show you how it
works.
So let me remove this first and start adding it one by one.
So in the list called numbers, I am going to add an integer and an integer five.
Yes.
So.
And.
And another integer called.
Mistakenly typing numbers.
It is number.
Yes.
So number 1015 and.
This is the method to add numbers to the list.
It was numbers.
Yes.
So you may copy it multiple number of times.
And this is the beauty of aerialist that it is.
It is sizable and it will never say no.
You keep adding number the rest of your life and it will never say Stop.
I am sold.
There is nothing like a limitation in ArrayList.
So after adding numbers to the list, I am going to run this.
So on running this function, I am getting the output as 515, five 1555, 1076.
After adding some more numbers.
I can keep doing this multiple number of times.
Any number I can add, like.
Yes.
And running it again.
So perfect.
Keep adding number to the list and it will keep displaying it in the terminal.
It will keep giving you the output and never say that I am full.
So this feature of Java is very useful for our project as we need this kind of data type only for managing
our teachers and students.
So in our student dot java file and teach your Java file, we are going to use the ArrayList feature
in the school function to call the teachers and students multiple number of times, and we can add teachers
again, again, again and again, and adding students again and again and again.
So let's start declaring this here as an ArrayList.
Now let us write this teacher inside the list.
As we discussed in the demo part.
So yes, a list is created called Teacher.
Similarly for the student.
We're creating an array list for the teachers and the students.
So here you can see that the Java Util list package is imported itself.
And as far as I declare this list, as soon as this list is declared, the package is imported itself.
Now we will move further.
So after creating this school class, we have created a school object or a constructor as we see that.
So the school object contains the parameters as an array list for teacher and student.
So we have used this keyword for adding teachers to this object and students.
The total money and total money spent is not inside this constructor, so there is no need to add this
keyword.
So yes, we have created this object school.
So commentators object school.
It's created.
Now moving further.
So the total money earned is zero in the beginning and the total money spent is zero as well.
Now, as similar as the teacher and the student, we have to set that teachers and students to the school
function school class.
So we are adding teachers to the class and.
Yes.
So setting and getting teachers and students that most.
There is no restrictions with teachers and students that they are they cannot be altered.
So yes we have said and get so this public list teacher returns the teacher.
Let me comment this out.
It turns out the teachers in the school class.
Yes.
Sorry, it was the teacher in the school.
Similarly, this set this is a set method.
And in a of set I have used at teacher for a better understanding of the code.
So this part updates the teachers in the school?
Yes.
So you can see that we have a set and get method for the teacher and similarly for the student head.
This part returns the students in the school class and this part updates the student in the school class.
Now for the total money on the part in the school we have said the.
This.
Yes, we have said this method for total money earned.
So this returns the total money earned by the school.
Total money earned so far, yes.
So total money earned is returned through this function.
And if we need to update, we are using the set method and in besides offset, we have called it update
total money.
So this update.
That total money?
Yes.
So this updates the total money earned by the school.
And in this, we have summed up it as a total money earned.
This is thus some variable.
So total money earned is a sum of total money and plus money.
And in the beginning, yes, we have passed money on and as a parameter.
So total money initially is zero.
So we can write it as.
In a comment I will show you quickly.
Yes.
So this is something in the beginning, it is something as zero is equal to zero plus.
moneyAnd suppose a student submitted our fees like 20,000, so the total money on with total value of
20,000?
Yes.