Hello, everyone.
So in this part, we are going to add functions for adding the songs, finding the songs, and then
adding the songs to the playlist.
So let's begin.
Okay, so we have created us class, the function and the constructor.
Now we are going to create a public song.
Public song?
Find song.
Class three.
A function.
Yes.
And inside which we are going to add string string title.
So that title of the song is going to be the arguments inside the fine song class.
After creating the class.
Now we are going to add or for loop.
Firstly, we have to create.
Of a method for adding some like before the finding of the song in order to find the song is present
or not.
Firstly, we have to add the song to the playlist or the library as we have named it.
So that song is going to be a Boolean type function and the arguments are going to be the title of the
song and the duration the song contains too to matter.
Like the song class contains two methods the title and the duration.
So that is what we are going to call inside this.
So we have created the function for adding the song.
And now we are going to.
Check if the song is present or not.
So inside this if or if statement we are going to call the find the song which we have created her title
of the song as we are going to find the song with the help of its title.
And if the title is present, then this is going to return true.
By default, it is set to null.
So if the song title is present inside the list of the songs, then we are going to add saw songs.
So the list like if the song title is not present till now, then only we are going to add the songs
to the list and this is absolutely fine.
Like what is the need to add a song which is already present?
So yes, we have successfully added the songs with its title and its duration.
Now inside the if statement we are going to lexis out.
This is the shortcut for printing something we have to write as vice, and the suggestions are going
to suggest that we have to select the censored option and this will complete the statement automatically
like system dot dot print.
And so what the if statement is going to print?
Like what if a song is not present in the list?
So we have to add this song to the list, right?
So we are going to write it as.
Title of the song like calling the title variable and then successfully added to the list like this
title is successfully added to the list.
Suppose the title is ABC like name of the song is ABC Plus successfully added to the list, so as a
whole it is going to print.
ABC successfully added to the list and this is going to return true as the data type of this function
is boolean.
This function is returning boolean boolean arguments.
So yes, we are done with this part.
Now we are going to complete the find song section also in the start of the add song.
Like Suppose if the song is already present, then what we have to.
Output, like what this function is going to return.
So if the song is already present, then we have tosses out.
Song with name.
Plus.
Glass is used for adding a variable.
And the variable here is the title of the song which we are wishing to add in the list already exists
in the list.
What list?
The library which we have created.
So if the song is already present, then this else is responsible for returning that the song is already
present in the list.
Do not bother to add the song again.
So the add song part is completed.
Now we are switching to the find song.
Inside the find song function.
We are going to check that the song is present in the list or not.
Like the data type we are using to store the songs is ArrayList, which is a resizable and nothing else.
So this the melody.
So we have to iterate through this list in order to check whether the song is present in the list or
not.
So for iterating, we have to use a loop so that we can move one by one in the songs and check if this
is present.
Like we have to match the string that this title is already present or not, and we are going to do
this with the help of an enhanced form.
So inside the Find Song section, we are going to declare enhanced for loop.
And inside the for loop we are going to check that check.
Check the song.
Check the song like we will create that check song functionality.
Let me first complete that find song section and then we will.
Get tighter.
We have already declared in the song Java class, so get tighter.
And after this get title, if it equals the title we are inputting, then it will throw an exception
like this is already present.
Please do not bother to add this again.
And after this checking.
Song check.
So this is going to be the if inside the four.
First complete the four thing or.
Song check.
Song.
Check the song.
Yes.
The suggestions.
Song check the song is the method is like a colon.
This is the enhanced for loop, which is going to iterate through that list and asking that if the song
is present in the list or not.
Inside the for loop.
We are.
Writing a statement which is going to.
Return that if the song is already present, then it is checking the checking that with the help of
string matching method.
So equals title.
If this is true, then this find song is going.
This find some function is going to return.
Duh.
No.
So yes, we are done with the public song.
Find some function which has an argument as the song title.
So if we wish to find a song inside the list, we have to call a for loop and check that the song is
already present on now so that we have successfully added functionalities to add song and find find
song from the list.
Now the next burden should be to add songs to the playlist.
Like we have a list of songs, list of albums, list of artists.
Now our main concern is to add songs to playlist, which was the main goal of making this project like
we are bothered about making a playlist of our favorite songs.
So let us initialize a function for adding songs to the playlist.
Name this as added to playlist using Camel Case.
And the function for adding songs to playlist is created.
The arguments will be like, suppose the track number.
The track number is going to be like, one, two, three, four.
And it is going to be an integer.
Of course.
Also, the playlist is going to be in that link the list data structure.
So we will come to link list, like what linked list is shortly in some time.
First, let me call the arguments inside the function and I hope we are done.
So we have created the function which is going to return Boolean data like either true or false.
So public boolean add to playlist in track number and we are good to go.
I think the link list song playlist, yes.
So inside this in a similar way, we have done this for finding songs again, for adding the songs to
the playlist.
Firstly, we have to iterate through the list and check that whether the song is already present in
the playlist or not.
So in order to check so we have to like go firstly column or loop and enhanced for loop.
And this is going to check again using the check the song thing like we have used it above in the find
song section and this is going to check whether the song is present in the playlist or not.
So song check the song.
Colon This not songs is used for iterating through the song list.
Now how we are going to create a playlist.
Like we have another list of songs which contains supposed 5 to 6 songs from which we want to add 2
to 3 songs to our playlist.
So we will iterate through the like the list and check that whether the thing is a song is present in
the list or not.
And we are going to make the playlist as a lengthy list.
So you may be wondering why we are creating a playlist as a list.
So I listed the special data structure data type, which is going to contain a pointer to from the previous
element and from the next element.
So basically link list is like or tree type data structure, which has roots where the roots are connected
to the first thing like previous element and the second thing, the next element.
So yes, we are going to create playlist as a link list as the members of the playlist are connected.
The current song is connected to the previous track and the current song is connected to the next track
as well.
So yes, it is going to be done in this way only.
So we have covered.
Mailing list.
Now we are going to check this with a similar way we have added like the similar way we have checked
it in the trying some section.
So I've checked some get title equals equals.
Or not title.
So the argument in the.
Equals is going to be the title.
Soyuz.
Here we are.
So we have checked everything inside the statement and if the song is present.
Like if the song is not present in the playlist.
So we are going to add that to the playlist link list, which is playlist and this is added with this
method like playlist or dad.
Check the song.
Yes.
So it is going to be done like this.
And we have added to the playlist.
This function is going to return a boolean expression, which is going to be true.
Like this is true.
We have successfully added songs to the playlist.