Okay.
So till now, we have created three of the classes required inside this contact repository interface.
The main class.
Which will be responsible for testing and running the contact class.
For all the labels of the firm where the information is being treated into and I repository class.
So we have discussed about this repository that the repository is like a file storing the feature which
stores information and helps us to extract and update the information according to the need.
Now the next class we are going to create is the object repository class.
So basically object repository is a centralized storage of locators in the form of objects.
So we are going to like make objects.
Of course we are making this project based on object oriented programming.
So definitely we will be creating objects.
But had the objects are going to be acted as locators, which will be locating like several things inside
the form.
So suppose if we are like handling these, okay, so this first name is going to be an index for this
input field.
So like this file storing is in the form of key value pair format.
So that is a key and a value associated to that key.
So yes, let us first create the class inside the CRC folder.
So on hitting new file on the Z, it asks for a name, so going to name it as object repository dot
java and on hitting enter.
We yes, we enter this class object repository and the class is created now inside this object repository
class we are going to handle all the key value pair like locating things and like fixing values to the
keys accordingly.
So the first thing we have to do inside this class is creating global variables.
So what are the things that requires acted as a key?
So the first thing we are going to create is a private list, and this list is going to contain the
list of contacts in the repository set.
So the list name is her P and calling it task contacts.
Okay, so private list contacts is created now.
The next thing will be.
Firstly, we have to extend this class in a manner.
So this object repository is going to be retained as.
De Which is a list, of course.
And inside the D there is index.
We are already like disgusted that we are going to handle key value pairs things inside the repository.
So yes extends number and closing this.
And it is going to implement the repository which we have created.
So here it is.
And it is going to be t comma II.
So basically, you can see it is a hash map kind of structure.
A hash map is basically a map which maps a specific key to a specific value.
So here we are mapping things like a key value are mapped in between these repositories and.
We have extended the class, so we will be continuing with declaring the global variables public.
Okay.
So it is private file.
The file, the file with which is containing the list and information about the contacts.
So input and output stream is going to be used inside this.
We have already discussed about this input output stream.
The application is working on input output operations.
We are inputting the information regarding the contacts and output.
The application is outputting that information in that manner only with the user input set.
So basically input output streaming is performed here.
And in the similar way we have to we have a file input stream in a similar way we will be declaring.
Ah.
Output like object input and.
Object output and file input file output.
So just changing this file to output here.
Okay.
So it is.
Like object, not output.
So file input stream object output stream.
Replacing it here also as object.
So file input stream.
Object in output stream in the similar way.
So file just change into out and head there.
File import file output.
Object input object output.
So there are two types of input output streaming handled here.
Similarly, this file will be dated to our object, so we are done with declaring all the global variables
going to be required inside this.
Now our next concern is to create an object repository object which will like a container, try and
catch block to handle any kind of exceptions.
So let us create that also.
Okay.
So there are.
Yes.
Inside this class we are going to create.
So that areas are showing right now, few of the imports are required in order to remove this error.
We will be importing all the required packages.
First, let us create this constructor, which is going to contain string source as argument.
And after this it will through class not found exception.
So pros class not found headed this exception.
So yes inside this object repository or object or constructor, whatever we call it, we are creating
a drive lock.
And this drive lock is going to like address to the files.
So we created a file in the Global Variables section.
So we are accessing that file inside this constructor.
And the final source, of course.
So inside the file now we have to create new files.
So using file dot, create new file keyword and this will create a new file for every unique contact
inside the repository.
Now for the file input stream and object input stream, we are going to create the similar files again.
Okay.
So here we have created the drive block for the file input stream, object input stream.
And the contacts are like our input in the form of a list.
All the fields of the contacts are contained inside this list.
D Now this object input end of the file input is closing after setting the list.
After the input is complete, the input stream will be closed.
So what?
Actually this file input stream is.
So the file input stream takes the input from the user and make it possible to read the contents of
the file as a stream of bytes.
So basically it is used for serialization.
So we are like inputting things in a form of a serialized manner, the first name, the last name and
everything in a serialized manner.
So this file input stream enables us to take this read that content in the form of a stream of bytes
and what actually this object input stream is.
So it is used to convert that input stream to object.
So yes, we were talking about a stream of bytes, but we have to convert that in the form of objects.
As in Java, the classes only understand objects and methods, not the stream of bytes which the file
was giving to the class.
So basically this file input stream and object input stream goes hand in hand.
The file input stream like read the contents in the form of stream of bytes, and then the object input
stream converts that input stream in the form of object.
So this process of conversion in the input stream to object is called the equalization.
So yes, this things are the like inside concepts of Java code.
Like while you study Java code, then you will get to know about this that what actually this input
stream output stream file an object is.
So in this project we just have to gain a little knowledge which I have make you aware about.
So basically this little use of input streaming output stream is done here for the serialization and
the serialization purpose.
Now after this, we have created this giant cache block successfully in case the class is not found,
so that a cache block will throw input output exception in the form of yes error.
There are two types.
Okay.
The first one will throw exception in the list of the contents only and the form will be closed.
Which yes, yeah.
Object input and file input will be closed and the system will print exception.
So yes, this object repository constructor is done.
Now our next concern is to create.
Okay, so we have to get that index in order to like access the justice in a similar way.
We have this in contact Java class forgetting and setting the first name in the similar way we have
to get that index or we are working with key value pairs.
So we have to get and set the values in order to like access, make it accessible to any other classes
of this project.
So in order to do so, we will be using override function for getting the index and for adding the object.
Like here we have add button.
So in order to add the object to the form, we will be using the override function in order to do so.
So after this object repository constructor, we have used this override keyword and this gets used
to get the index for the yes integer value for the list of contacts.
In the repository.
This get all is to get all the information about that selected contact.
After this, if the user wishes to add a new contact, then this boolean type of function will be executed
which will be returning this dot contact dot add object here.
If we add any new contact then that will be added inside this contact repository from now.
Similarly, for updating and removing the contacts.
Now add the last.
When the user like ends up with updating, removing and everything, then we have to save that contact.
All the information regarding to that specific contact should be same.
We have already like seen this in the introduction part.
Let.
Once we hit that button or update button, the information will be saved to that specific selected contact.
So yes, this is going to be done with the help of this file output stream.
So in the similar way the input stream was working, this output stream will work.
It will show itself for the file output stream, will convert that into the set of bytes, make it readable,
and then the object output stream is going to like convert that stream of bytes in the form of object
to make it readable to the class.
We are creating classes everywhere, so then the classes only listen to the objects, nothing else.
They are so loyal to their objects, they do not listen to any other thing.
So this object output stream will help the stream of bytes to be converted in the form of object.
So yes.
And after that the output stream will be closed.
And in case any kind of exception arises, then this cache block will be executed and return false like
the information will not be saved in the specific context.
So yes, in this way the save function works.
So this is all about the object repository class.
We have covered everything about the keyword key value pair indexing thing, the input output stream
thing, whether it be the file one or the object one.
And yes, this is all about this object repository class.
Now, not only class which is left is the frame class.
So basically we have to feed everything inside of frame.
So in the next class we will be creating a frame and which is going to be like basically the main class
for which will be containing everything about this project.
So we will see that in the next part.