Hello, everyone.
So we have successfully created a file button as with options attached with it as new open, save,
print and exit.
So we are done with this file part.
Now we will jump to this edit button.
So creating functions or this edit button as a menu item similar way.
As we done for the files section.
So menu item will be like for edit we can do a cut, a copy, a paste and I think we can select.
So yes, the menu can't.
New menu item will be cut.
Yes.
Writing it as a menu item could.
We can set this.
Method to the edit button.
And we can use this part again.
Space between you and your menu item.
So similarly for copy.
Based and select all text.
So copy.
Based.
Select all.
And replacing it heralds.
Copy, paste and selector.
As we say.
So yes now successfully importing these menu items for Java String Library, now we have to add constructors
to it.
So adding this added dot and.
For the cut one.
So I had cut.
And.
Similarly for copy, paste and all.
Least.
Four times.
And then replace.
Not human cells.
Copy.
Paste.
I'm just a little.
So select all.
Here we are.
So we have created actions for the edit button.
Now we will try to run this.
So yes, running this notepad++ run java and waiting for the program to run.
Checking for the edit button.
So yes, we have successfully added cut, copy, paste and select all options for the notepad.
So when we are inputting text, we can cut it, copy, paste it and select all the text.
Now the file is also as options.
Edit also has option.
Now we are going to add an about a space in the help section.
So for that we have to create a about class.
In Java.
So.
We have successfully created the about class now the Java String Library similarly as the notepad class.
So import java x dot string.
Import.
So that sticker denotes that we are importing all the components from the Java String Library.
Now writing the code four about constructor section.
So creating a constructor called about.
Opening races.
And we have set bounds for the frame size of the notepad window.
So similarly, we have to set bounds for the about section as well.
Let us first set a title for this about section.
So set title.
As.
About noted down application.
So the heading of this about frame is going to be about note it down application.
So it's fine now.
We are going to set a title.
We have set a title now.
We are going to set a bond.
So it's showing some errors or I think I forgot to extend this class.
As Jeffrey, we are going to create a frame then only we can set a title and set bounds.
So yes, extends.
Different now that Assad vanished.
So set bombs.
What do you think the bounce can be?
The rectangle field.
So.
Something smaller than the notepad window.
It could be 101 hundred.
500 or something like 400.
It's fine.
So the bouncer said, Now let us try to run this by creating our main function public static void.
Main, main function is created by string arguments and then try to run this window of about us page.
We have to set the visibility to true first then only we can run this new about.
About the method is invoked the constructor that we created and setting the visibility to.
Through.
Remove this.
And yes, so the about frame is created in a rough way.
Let us try to run this.
So perfect.
We have about window about noted down application with this size.
Now we will try to input something inside this and try to check this after writing the code.
So closing this and trying to.
You might think how you saw said default close operations set
so on closing.
On clicking the close button we exit the about window.
Setting this to frame this poll on close.
J frame.
This falls on close.
So this will dispose.
On close.
So, yes.
We have to set our layout as not.
Now we will similarly add or I can to the about window as the notepad part.
So copying this part from her image.
I can class and.
Setting this like.
So when we run this, we will get a similar window.
There's no notepad on the Java coffee icon, isn't it?
Yes.
So we have the notepad icon in the title bar and on menu mining in the taskbar.
So after adding the icon, we are going to add some text inside the about part.
So for the text part inside the window we have added this G label and inside the G label we have an
HTML tab which contains some text.
As noted down noted down version two already noted.
Down is a word processing.
It is basically a idea about what this app is doing.
So we have used jailable.
So we are using this VR tag as jailable takes only input as a state tax.
It does not suppose backslash.
And so we are using this HTML string from the beginning to the end.
You can see that.
So let us try to.
So I'm running this about window.
We get the output as this the things written inside the jailable system and are displayed here in the
about us window.
No.
In the notepad home page.
We are supposed to edit right and save text.
So that is possible only when we are going to add text field input inside the notepad window.
So let us figure out the function so that we can write text inside the notepad window.