Hello, everyone.
So as far I can see that we have successfully created the flame and inside which we have called to function
load images and initiate volume.
So after these two functions, now we have to create a new function called public void locate.
So we have to locate the apple and we have to set some positions for that so that the coordinates of
the apple are dedicated for this project.
So initializing this function and inside this function, we are going to initialize an integer variable
which is going to be in.
A random mathematical expression and which is called using math, not random.
So we have called the random function and outside which we have to give this asterisk and called random
position.
So we have to set a random position for the apple.
It is not fixed in every start.
Like if we start the game again and then close it and then starting the position of the Apple changes
every time.
So this is created for the X coordinate and similarly we have to create this for the Y coordinate.
So Apple X is R and the dot size.
So the dot size are multiplied by the dot size.
So we have this in our suggestion and we have to create a similar thing for the Y coordinate also.
So Apple has a specific X coordinate and a specific Y coordinate.
So we have successfully created the position of the apple with the help of this locate apple variable.
So we have entire and we have to not to declare this or again, it is already declared.
So, yes, that it is gone.
So let me give a quick idea about what this metadata random is doing.
So commenting it down to explain the random function calls our number between zero and one.
Any random number between zero and one, it could be like 0.1, 0.2, 0.5, 0.6.
So the number is going to be between zero and one.
So suppose the number that is called randomly is 0.6.
So we have to set it like 0.6 to the dot size.
Let us take it to 20.
So the X coordinate is going to be 0.6 into 20 and which will yield it as.
And then that bill passed here in this and again, 12 into 20 is going to be 12 into ten is going to
be 120.
So 120 is inside the frame of the game.
We have 300 in the X side and 300 in the Y y side.
So we have to set this random function in this manner that the snakes, it goes outside the 301, either
in Y or X, the game is over.
So we have successfully created the locator.
Now let us call this locator inside the is in game.
So calling this locate Apple.
The award function is to be called here.
We have called it now after creating the locate apple function.
Now we have to check the apple.
Check that the apple is eaten by the snake or not.
And if the snake ate the apple, we have to increase the size.
And if not, then we have to do nothing.
So similarly, creating a void function for checking the Apple.
Public void.
Jack.
Apple.
Similarly using camel case for the function name.
And yes, so we have created a chapel function inside which we are going to call a conditional operator
if.
If the coordinate of X is zero and which is equal to Apple, Apple's x coordinate then.
I Polacks.
And similarly for the VI one.
So if the Y coordinate is.
Same.
We have to copy this.
The whole part inside the bracket and attaching it with her and operator.
Replacing the X with Y.
So if the X and y coordinate are same as the snakes, x and y coordinate, then we have to increase
the size of the snake.
And if the coordinates become same, we have to increase the dot by one.
This denotes.
Let me comment this out.
Like this denotes.
After this, I am going to add dots is going to be dots plus one dot size is increased by one like initially
the dot size is three and after the snakes eat the apple, the dot sign increases by one, after which
we have to call again a locate apple like if the dot size is increased by one.
We have again drawn the apple.
So the apple appears again after checking the apple is eaten by the snake.
So we have successfully created the apple section like we have created a locate apple and check whether
the apple is eaten by the snake or not.
Now we have to set a timer, like if the snake is started, moved.
So if the snake has started moving.
So if the snake hits the wall, then the game is over.
So there is a fixed time like the snake is not moving for the rest of our lives.
There is a time of like 4 seconds, 5 seconds or something like that.
So we have to set a timer.
Until then, if we do not perform any keyboard action, then the game will be automatically over.
Like the snake will hit the wall and the game will be over.
So the timer is like this.
The timer we have called new timer.
And inside this we have passed operator like 140 milliseconds of time.
You can set any time you wish to and calling this operator and then calling this timer when the game's
done.
We have to declare the timer inside the board class.
And for implementing that timer, we have to implement the action listener to this board class.
And this action listener is under the AWP event.
So we have covered the timer thing.
Now the next thing we are going to cover, which so the board is showing some error.
The type board must implement the inherited abstract method action listener.
So we have to inherit this method, so for which we have to call our override function.
Like if you know the basis of Java, our abstract method cannot be called without the override function.
So after this.
If ingame we have to check Apple so we will create our in-game function first.
Like I'm randomly adding this.
We didn't see this.
So I hope that, yes.
So the border is removed.
We have added an abstract class for this border matter and now we will move forward.
So after covering all the apple and the timer thing, now we will switch to drawing the graphics inside
the frame.
So creating a function called public void draw graphics g.
So importing this as an argument graphics and if condition says in-game like if in-game is true, if
we do not write anything, just a variable inside.
If then that says that if.
Now India is showing errors.
So let me first import this variable, the boolean variable, private boolean endgame.
So endgame here denotes that if the game is on.
So if the game is on is true, then we are going to draw the graphics.
If endgame this denotes that if Endgame is true.
So inside this, if I am going to add some conditions as we if the endgame is true, we have to draw
image and inside the argument section we are going to set it as apple.
So.
And in the x y we are going to write it as Apple X and Apple one.
Apple X.
Apple Y.
And in the observer side, we are going to add this that discovered.
Yes, so that if endgame is true, then this is going to be the case.
And if this is going to be the case, then we have to add a for loop for the dots.
So the graphic will be like the for loop says that if the snake finds the door then increase the size
of the snake legs, move the snake forward and make it to reach the dot for make it to grab the dot
and eat it.
So if that is zero g draw image head, we have to draw a head and attaching with the head.
We have to draw a dot.
So if head then zero L's a dot.
If the z is zero, we have to add the head and as it is going to be simply the dot.
So this is how the graphics are going to be like.
If the snake finds the dot, the size will increase or otherwise the head will remain the same.
We have to do this by using that toolkit function, by getting the default toolkit, and this toolkit
is with the mercy of AWP.
So tanking AWP for giving such amazing toolkit.
So this is going to be the graphics of the game if the game is true, like in game is true if this is
true in or we can say that if one so if one then this is going to be happen.
And if zero like if false, then the game is going to be over.
So we have to create a function for game over also.
Now in order to create the game of our function, we have to recall that what are the conditions that
makes the game to be?
So the game could be over if the snake hits the obstacles.
And the obstacles are that four sides of the wall like of the frame and the snake head sells itself.
So there are these possibilities which which will make the game to be over.
So inside this game of our function, we are going to add that things and then see what happens.
So let me show you that.
What this game, our function is responsible for.
Like which window is it is being responsible for?
So that game over is responsible for this thing like this window will open if that the function which
we are making now will be called.
So that is a game over font written in the middle of the frame and everything is black outside.
So let us try to write inside this.
Like firstly, we have to write a string message which is going to display a frame like a game over
text.
Game over.
So the frame is going to display.
Everything is caps lock.
So yes.
The game over.
Now so that we have created the message which is going to be displayed in the game of our window.
Now let us move forward.