So till now we have covered all the items in the form as the select side, the number of classes, the
selections of menu items in the form of a radio button.
Now our next concern should be adding buttons or add an order in order to make add those items to our
cart or to check from the cart and confirm our orders.
So we will be adding a button and calling this as buttons.
And this is going to be a new button.
And inside this button, the string that is going to be displayed on the button is add.
So call it add item.
Add item is going to be the size like the string displayed on the button.
Now in the similar way, we have to set size and location.
So I am going to copy this from here and paste it here and now.
Just change this glass.
So add.
So adding this button, setting it size and location and then to set like our dedicated size and location
for this button is very important.
So changing the size to 100 and suppose to 30 from the left.
Okay.
So we have added this is a button.
So labels should be replaced with button and this also be done.
So we have added this add button to our frame.
This is the button which we are currently adding.
Now our next concern is adding order button to the frame.
So in that same way, we will be adding the order button also.
So pasting this and just changing the name and size is going to be same, but the difference is going
to be in the like distance from the left border.
So suppose all the above one was 100 from the left, so it should be supposed to be from the left.
And so this is going to be.
So we have seen one thing in the beginning.
We have to firstly replace this add to order in order to make them.
Dedicated for.
Okay, so just pressing enter once we have declared it.
So you do not have to.
Type it again and again.
So we have created this that button.
So one thing I was talking about that by default in the initial window, it was set to the like disabled.
So this order button was disabled in the beginning.
We talk gray background, so we have to set this order button to disable by default.
So this is going to be built in order and we have to set it to like disable so set.
Enable and be a boolean input which it takes.
This set enabled function takes boolean input.
So setting this boolean to force and this will be responsible for disabling the order button by default
in the beginning.
So we will be adding functions in order to make this button enabled in future and we will be adding
code responsible to that also now so that we have added the select size, the radio button selection
option, these input text field which will be asking for the number of classes and at the last page
we have added add button and order button to our frames.
Now one more thing which is being displayed in the form is the number of items which we have added along
with the add ons.
So the code responsible for that is this basically we are calling this as a label report which is giving
us the report of the items which we have ordered.
So basically it is the like log of what is being ordered throughout in that step, that specific step.
So after each order this label will appear like unique label will appear after each unique ordering.
I suppose we have ordered water so that will appear also again, if we order tea then a different report
will appear that we have ordered suppose 3 million glasses of tea.
So this report is responsible for that part of the form and after which we have set the size and location
for that also.
So by far we have completed all the things associated with this label class.
Now we have to add actions inside this.
So in order to add actions, action listener to every button, radio button, combo boxes and everything,
we have to write code inside this action, perform, function.
So in order to attach actions, firstly we have to create classes for the rest of the requisites for
this application.
So in the prototype part, we have discussed that as a whole we will be requiring six classes in this
project.
So the second class, which is concerned with this label class like these two are attached.
So creating a new class, calling it beverage dot java and our class beverage is being created.
So this beverage class is going to be responsible for the size, the prices of the items in the menu
and the amount of the items like how many items we have ordered and what is the total cost of the whole
items summed up as a whole.
And everything attached like size, price and amount is going to respond.
This class is being responsible for those things.
So initializing some global variables which are going to be required for this class creation, the size
and similarly price and amount so private and the size is going to be an integer.
So sorry, the amount is going to be the integer.
So in the amount and then private or double price or price could be our decimal also.
So we are declaring this as double data type.
So size, amount and price.
We have declared now after this creation of a beverage class, we have to create a constructor which
is going to contain the beverage object.
So beverage and the arguments inside this is going to be the size and one more the amount.
So size and the amount.
They are going to be the.
In arguments for this constructor.
Okay.
So we have passed the argument successfully.
Now inside this beverage object.
So part is going to be the title.
So initially there is no title for the beverage frame.
So we are leaving this as empty after this.
This dot size is going to set the size.
So this keyword is responsible for accessing the objects from like private objects from a class.
So we are using this keyword for amount and size.
So we have been successfully accessed the size and the amount after which initially the price total
is zero as initially we have nothing ordered in the card.
So setting it as 0.0, this 0.0 is due to the double data type declaration we have made.
So the price is initially zero.
Now after this, we have to create a functions for get size, set size like we have to use, get and
set methods for the setting, the size and amount also the price.
We have three things so we have to set and get all three of them.
These three are declared as a private data access specified in the class globally.
So in order to access those private objects, we have to use that get and set keywords in Java which
will be responsible for accessing all of them.
So suppose I am using public string as the size is a string, so get size.
Get size.
I am going to call.
And bracket.
So this get method is called which is going to return the size.
So we have successfully created this great method for size.
Now, in a similar way, we in order to update the size, we are using the set method.
So set size is going to be responsible for updating the size of the items which we are ordering through
the application.
So this is like using size as the argument.
And inside this we have to like access the size.
So this dot size should be accessed in order to make any updates to the size.
And after like setting the size, we will get this size with the help of get size method.
So we are done with the size part.
Now, in the similar way, we will do this for price and amount.
So let me copy this part and paste it two more times to set it for price and amount.
Okay.
So firstly, changing this get size to get.
Price.
Yes.
So and the price is double.
So changing it to double hair.
Okay.
So this will return the price and this get metal will return the price.
Also setting the price.
And this is also double.
So double.
Okay.
So we are done with this.
Now after this.
Doing this for.
Okay.
So we have to change this also price.
And this dot price.
And the prize part is also done now for the amount.
So the amount is this data type integer.
So we have to call it as int and then return the amount.
The amount is returned using this get method of java.
Similarly set amount.
Like to update the amount we have to.
Change it to end.
And this event is going to be responsible for updating the amount.
Also we have to change this size head also and set it to price.
So we are done.
They're just changing the amount also.
And similarly here.
Okay.
So we have successfully get and set all three of the object which were declared inside this beverage
class.