So I already created the rectangle and everything.
Now I need to mention the ball collision part here.
So let us create that check map.
Collision with the ball, or you can check anything.
So I am mentioning as ball collision.
In a 30 year.
For that purpose.
I'm mentioning this a four.
Which is basically for each.
You can check it.
For.
And I is equal to zero.
Again and again changing.
So I mentioned like a four year.
I use less than map I'm accessing, which is I'm going to create it later in later.
But map link.
Otherwise I will explain the code.
Also, it will be beneficial for you also.
In that.
Also, I'm going to check your another method.
Geez, Liz.
Then again, map.
At zero position map.
Dot map.
Which is basically what I'm going to use here, my primary dataset for my plant.
And just business as usual.
So A I'm going to use your as you can check here just again and again for so you can check your Internet
for loop.
You can assume that like that.
So if.
What a map.
Dot map.
Is going to exceed then I or Jay.
If we're going to exceed them, I urge.
Score should be.
Plus.
Plus, but.
Our beacon can everything should be changed.
So for that purpose I'm mentioning.
And Brick.
X is equal to J Star.
Matt which is basically nothing but changing the brick width and everything, which is I'm going to
create later plus 80.
So you're going to assume that it will be disappear.
And now with similar.
But here I'm going to mention why.
51, which is again increasing.
And.
Very good.
Is equal to.
Map dot brickwood.
So that's a method to create your own.
So it's giving me a role because it's not defined what?
My function is not generated and.
And for God to change your life.
It's not always.
Did you write?
And with this, I'm going to create.
Similar thing again, a brick.
Eat.
Medicate with medicate.
So I need to mention this now.
I need to create one rectangular thing here.
Which is again one map function you can check.
Rectangle rect is equal to new.
Again, I'm taking part of rectangular with brick.
Dix.
I'm going to use your.
Well, Brick, I am going to use here.
Brick Village.
I'm going to use you.
And with Brick Height, which is basically my four dimension of everything.
Brick height, not height.
So.
That's things I created.
Now, similarly, I need to create a rectangle for ball.
So I created a ball, but I need to mention ball in a rectangle.
So this is not visible actually.
But it acts like a rectangle to check bouncing and everything.
So.
New rectangle always as in Java.
The term pole position.
X ball position y.
And I guess it's starting point.
Is 2020 enough.
And one thing remaining is Rick Stengel.
Not Rectangle.
Be correct.
You are going to grip is equal to it, so it will assign it automatically while deploying anything on
exactly that part.
So now I am going to create right or left bouncing part.
So I'm going to create one.
Your bouncing mechanism of over.
Also let me mention as one thing make of.
Game.
Bouncing mechanism of overboard, basically.
So if my ball.
Gambon is going to direct with ball rectangle intercept intercepts, that middle part, which is brick.
So okay.
So what I will do is first I will create your one brick mechanism, not bouncing brick mechanism of
game.
Which is very important.
So I will create a mechanism.
After that, I will create that bouncing mechanism.
It is hitting that intersects with that big rectangle.
So.
Always I need to mention it in this and be correct.
Small so.
Be correct.
What will happen?
Matt.
Split frequently I'm going to create in that map function brick value.
So it's basically disappeared.
No need to worry about this functioning.
Just basically disappearing that brick.
School will be increasing for you.
As This is my method, we will increase by five and total bricks.
If you're minus minus, which is basically decreased, total mix will be decreased in the code.
Mm hmm.
Okay.
Now I need to mention.
But when ball hit to right or left of the.
Intersected, just like intersecting or intersecting that part.
But I haven't mentioned like.
Wall.
It to right or left of brick.
It should be disappear because it just like touching up that big.
So it can be bounced from that.
But also.
Or it can be fitting that part.
Why?
It's give me no nothing.
Oh.
I went completed this.
Now I need to create the logic for that also.
If.
Wall.
Position.
Like the explanation for injection.
Plus 19.
It's less than or equal to ball rectangular, which is basically ball rectangular x coordinate.
Order.
You can create a condition for or also or ball position X again, which is basically my right part of
brick.
Plus when.
Now remember why I'm not giving again or 1919, because if I'm considering as more part of lift now,
I should mention less part of it of that.
So.
Brick again.
Rectangular brick, correct.
And.
Wait a minute.
What is this?
Or.
We're doing it.
It should not be pole position.
It should be correct.
Let me do one thing here.
I'm going to change this variable because I'm confusing again and again.
So.
And so I'm mentioning this, so it should be very correct.
And should we be correct?
Now it's considerable.
If it's like this x.
And explosion, basically.
That's not complete logic.
Plus.
It should be.
Very great.
Dot.
We it also.
So let me mention.
So that's a user defined method.
If that happens.
Mortgage deduction should be changed because just like putting.
Well, extradition should be changed, so I'm going to change that bold direction in the opposite way.
When top to bottom.
Top or bottom?
Not top to bottom.
Top to bottom of top or bottom of that part brick.
I need to mention Elle's condition here.
Again, while y direction should be changed.
We can assume that it should be negative.
That's basically opposite of that.
So.
So balancing condition of our listing.
So I need to break here, which is basically breaking the EPA, which is I'm not going to continuously
calling this again and again.
So these things are enough, I guess.
Enough.
Oh, no.
I need to mention one thing here.
Which is we are now.
Out of you can take this ball collision.
Now, once ball collision is done.
I need to specify.
This says bold because for further creating an everything.
I am updating.
My ball directions, the game ball direction.
I'm going to update.
So now what I'm going to create is very simple, just bouncing conditions.
If you know this part, it's very helpful.
Otherwise, you can drop this part.
Also, it's not very important, but for seamless gameplay, I'm going to create this.
Otherwise you have to again and again closing and opening the game.
So for such purpose, I'm creating this.
Now it's very similar.
Now, if I'm mentioning one I should mention here.
Why?
Because I already created this.
So he's just basically moving or bouncing condition.
You can check here.
If it's less than zero, it should be opposite.
If again, this should be why and we'll look at it.
This is y.
So this for top and bottom.
Now, let me mention for lower and upper part.
So for why constraint there should not be any conditions for or x which is basically left and right
should be the is condition because below of that it's going to give me the game over part.
So I'm as I mentioned, these things are done and we paint I'm going to call which is basically.
Calling these things again.
So now we are done with our gameplay mechanism.
So now what things are remaining, which is basically map generator functions, which is I'm going to
create it, which is basically very similar to these things, but I'm going to use some color strokes,
graphics, 2D mechanisms which will be helpful to create me a map generator.
So in a later part, I'm going to create one map generator function.
So in that part you will understand what is the map generator thing?
And now I'm going to call that in me.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.