In previous videos, I already created that part and everything related to the network snipping and
everything.
So that's you were in, which is basically for 32 bit.
So let us create one more thing here.
So what I'm going to perform here is let me create one new project I'm using here again in the LG idea.
I've previously used NetBeans to show that part.
Go with my.
Choose your tool.
So I'm using this succinct version of my JDK.
So it is detecting is.
So wait for something it will detect the SDK and then automatically.
Once this is done, we'll need to archive
it really?
For coordinates.
So let me put here.
And work Smith as we project.
Around.
You can finish so it will create a new project for me.
So wait for some time.
It will automatically create a new project.
So while it's creating project, let us see why we should use mapping.
So this for all the Java class and methods I already told you in the Mavin emerging of control.
I don't want to use that dependencies directly.
So what is the dependency?
Dependency?
Just basically connecting between two classes.
I don't want to perform that directly.
There are design patterns that are used to remove the dependencies in the code, which is basically
inversion of control and they make code easier and here is for maintaining each and everything part.
So for that purpose, I preferred your one example class employee address with address and employee,
which is I need to perform there.
Then.
So I did consider that employee address and I'm assigning that address to the new address so you can
check here.
There is a directly dependency, tight coupling dependency.
Likewise, if there is one error in employee class, then there is error occurring in address class
also.
So to remove this, what we required, we required EOC.
So here what I'm doing, I'm that's a tight coupling thing.
Tight coupling means we cannot lose that like tight ones.
We cannot lose that bounce easy.
So I see inversion of control.
I also makes code loosely coupled.
Such as?
There is no need to modify a code or logic over environment.
If we having error in employee as we are using this dot, at least it's not at all directly dependent
to employee is dependent on the this address only.
So it's loosely coupled.
So in spring framework it's mostly used but I'm using here for my when also I'm not using your spring
framework, but that's XML file or annotation I'm going to create here and I'm going to add it directly.
So advantages of dependency injection is basically adding that dependencies in XML is it makes code
smoothly coupled.
It's easy to maintain and makes code easy to test and everything.
So there are different advantages of also that there are predefined templates hibernates JPA everything
in my well that's loosely coupled and this is really easy to test also.
So that's all the things.
So let us move to the IDE part.
So currently you can check it's working.
And it will create me for some files.
So this is my form dot xml and this is my SLC.
Okay.
So to see me do three things.
Java file and resources file and dot xml.
Having some form of xml file.
So.
Let me add some dependencies.
So currently there are no dependencies here.
So we need to perform some dependencies and adding some dependencies also.
So adding dependencies is very easy.
This.
Just I need to add this.
Many movies that I know use of.
So there is one pick up for for Java is one called artifact there.
So it's taking time to indexing as this is very huge and my system is taking load so it will take time
to perform every action.
So wait for some time to compile this and everything.
So it's an indexing.
So.
Complete.
Let it be like this only to complete this part.
So.
Dependency.
I'm just taking down two dependencies and doing everything.
So you're going to check your dependencies, adding their.
So while this is working.
So my suggestion is wait for sometime after developing this part.
So because it's adding the dependency, so it's taking time to perform these actions.
Now go to the Java file while it's doing and create here when Java.
Which is basically our app.
I'm going to go from there.
So right click on this main is RC Main Java.
You can go directly to the view of packages or packages, new packages.
You can directly access this java.
Okay.
So it's taking time to perform.
So it's not analyzing.
Click here.
Right click.
Go to this.
Or if you found Abdul Jabbar directly here.
No need to create this.
But I haven't found this, so I'm putting the app.
Check with the find whether this is working or not.
It is simple thing you can perform.
He is the input because as you know, ESPN is probably a.
It's taking time to load the system.
Oh, don't worry, Alan.
Hello.
Voice.
So that's the thing.
I'm going to print that.
Let me check where whether this is added or not.
So please showing me the error and the error is.
This is already performed for me.
Now let me run this.
So it is running.
While training, it will build this part.
So I'm not going to create your UI thing because I told you UI is going to take more time.
So due to time constraint, I'm going to add some files and I'm going to check that part.
Directly here.
So maybe this is loading.
It's building number and it's building.
So what is the thing it should print?
Hello?
Nothing.
It should print a loan for me.
And as you can see, it's so your programming is now running, so no need to require to use this.
So now we are going to perform or I'm going to work on our application.
So our thing is very important.
What is?
First, we need to list our networking devices.
What is the our networking devices is basically our networking interface, which is going to perform
here.
So first thing I need to mention here is Pcap.
So we can you can check here everything we have done for everything.
So except.
Network interface.
I need to mention that.
So what you can do is just putting the code here.
You can put your start.
Know how we can use this.
You can use this as a device.
Device is equal to null.
My device is currently null because it's not having anything.
So pick up is which comes with very convenient method for listening.
So I will put here 2 to 3 things.
It's basically going to capture everything in networking devices.
So what I'm going to do is it's came with one beautiful method we can say, which is basically an F
selector, which is going to select intelligently over everything.
So you should use strike action so you could catch already because so option.
Section e.
15.
Outdoor Print l.
N.
E.
So what I'm going to do here, I'm going to add that device.
You know, the device is equal to one beautiful thing is a knife selector new and I have selected.
Which selector is going to take select the network in select network terms.
I have the methods it will assign to that part after this part.
This system brought out.
Not.
But in telling print your.
I'm going to print my.
Putting.
Need to work.
Interface.
I'm going to put my interface.
So.
And consistently minus its device.
Plus, what is my device is basically a device.
So if we print this.
And let me run this application.
So let me show you how it will intelligently print, select my device and everything.
So it will go through every networking available on my part.
And it will select that in I select.
It's currently building.
As you can see.
So.
It will take time to perform every action.
Now let us consider why this is putting module is not native method and everything.
So.
You can take this static binder.
Our application is not connected to any static binder.
So for that purpose, specific model cannot be found to the Blue Cap Library.
So for that purpose, we need to implement your w cap also.
So.
For this, you need to develop some embedded dependencies or add some embedded dependencies there.
Let me work on some.
Team here, which is basically gait network device, which I forgot actually.
So before printing this, let me refactor this code.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's very correct.
I'm not saying this is wrong, but we haven't mentioned something, so.
Let me move to this part.
Forgot to mention some parts here.
So.
So this is our network interface.
And let me.
And these this exception.
Then in this public device.
Now, remember, this device is not working.
So for that purpose, we need one thing here.
So now what?
I changed.
I created this gateway device I'm using here.
Now let us check whether it's building or not because specific module is not going to be found here
directly.
So currently this is not if you want to check, you can check this part.
And you can take for the class part and everything.
So we need to add some more dependencies.
So.
We are mentioned with this.
No.
Let me add one more dependency.
So it is taking time to do the right thing.
And let me run this again.
This is currently building.
So it will take time to build and it will give me the current networking devices and everything on my
network.
So it's downloading the dependencies, doing the all resolving the dependencies.
So there may be some time to perform this, but it will work.
If you want to check, you have to use this form or XML as it is using here.
So resolving my bar.
I'm currently.
Including the sinking the part.
As you can see, it's indexing.
So let it be in further part.
I'm going to tell you how we can perform this.