In previous session I told you basics of Java servlet.
Then we created participant login page with HTML.
Then we created a participant signup and participant login.
So participants sign up.
What is the participant signup requirements?
We need to take user input from participant signup page.
Name their username, their password and confirm password field.
So in previous session for the admin page and for the security purpose, what I created, what I used,
I just wrote a Java program using that.
Inside the Java program, I mentioned the list of admins and their password system default passwords.
I'm going to create so admin will require the system default username and system default password.
So I'm not giving any changes for admin.
Admin restrictions are very I'm giving the restrictions to admin to use or stick to that username and
passwords.
But for the participants, log in.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to take username from them, only I'm going to get password and confirm
password from there.
Only I'm not going to give some default participants or something.
In everyday life, you can see the you can see the different websites also that's using this.
And here I'm going to use this part.
So for the participants, log in or signup page.
Sorry, I'm going to create one java.
Let's stop.
So what you can do is just go to source package here, right click new and create Java servlet here.
But always remember in the further process, you have to mention that in the web dot XML part, it will
ask you to you want to edit that part into the web, xml or not, but always remember you have to add
it to the web XML.
As you can see in some part.
Let me open the Web XML file here.
So this is WebEx.
So you can see this is Soviet post.
Soviet validated, then stored up.
I created too many.
So.
So these are mappings, the bullet mappings and everything.
If you are not giving any solid mapping the HTML file and the our Java file or Java Soviet file, it
will not attach to anyone.
So we will use the attaching bolt.
We can say for the HTML and Java.
So always remember take that part inside while creating the solid.
So let us see how we can store.
So as I told you in the folder, you have to ask for this request.
Now we are going to store this into the database.
So we need one more thing.
Import Java dot school.
So these are the default library in Java skill store you are going to use dot star for the all libraries
include all libraries inside this because I don't want to specify each and every library.
So just put don't start after any library.
You will get all libraries here.
So after creating public class stock exchange to HTTP servlet because we are going to create a HTTP
servlet here, I'm going to use again to post return.
Then this is I'm going to create a HTTP servlet request variable name as a request HTTP servlet response
variable as a response which throws our exception and servlet exception.
I told you earlier while creating admin part, admin validation part.
So this is the response set content type text or email.
Why we are using this line.
So in further, I'm going to put some HTML tags inside Java program.
But Java doesn't know that is HTML or text.
If I'm not mentioning this, it will directly forward to the HTML page and estimates shows that part
with tag only inside the body.
So it should be an inch html part.
So I'm specifying this with tag.
So create print statement out dot response out is equal to response or get writer.
These are some default statements you are going to use here.
So what I'm going to fetch is your.
Fetching.
Data from.
The up.
Dot.
I'm pitching.
Strong.
User.
So I'm facing this data.
I told you in earlier part.
So I created this.
So I'm going to face this data from user only.
And from.
HTML part, so always remember your this name.
P name.
P username password.
Remember these names and just do that.
Names only don't change name or anything.
Otherwise you can just copy paste here that part.
So these are created you can directly use these names also here, but I'm going to assign these to another
string.
So to remember a12834 is very quite equal.
Or we can say just for my comfort, comfort zone, I'm going to use this.
So I'm going to assign.
Do.
Another things just.
I'm putting this.
I'm going to Los Angeles to another things.
So, no, this is not a very required part.
You can exceed that part and you can use only these parts only.
But these are very specified name.
I'm going to use a one for username, a two for password field, a three for confirm password.
Why am I going to I'm not storing password field in database.
I'm going to store only password field.
But for the confirmation, I'm going to use this name to if I'm going to store a full name also there.
So if a two means our password is equal to the confirmed password.
As you know, our password and confirm password should be seen.
What I'm going to do is try.
So if I'm not using try, it will throw the escalator inside this.
So for you exception handling, I'm going to use your try.
Asked for a name to invoke Oracle Driver.
As I told you, you have to invoke this Oracle Java file, oracle gbk 14 jar file.
It will load using this part.
Always remember or string connection model with GBC Oracle team.
I'm going to create some default files and I will share that files also so you can use directly.
These are the system default.
You can change to your user.
If you create another user inside a skill, you can specify them and the password here so you can directly
view the this you are l to this part then password and system and everything here.
But I'm assigning to do some strings.
And I'm going to tell this part so I will just like username of database, I'm going to use system default
database here.
Not I'm going to create password or system.
So that's my password and everything.
If you don't want to reveal your password or something, you can create text file and you can take that
from the text file without displaying the information.
But this is very complicated part inside this already.
This is a skill set are very complicated.
So I don't want to focus on that part.
Very complex part.
So now we need to create connection.
So I will put here.
Weird connection.
So always remember while creating connection what you are going to do.
Connection, which is basically a squirrel part.
A squirrel connection is equal to con connection and giving the.
Very well.
Just the new manager.
Also the driver manager.
Oracle Driver Manager.
Dot Gate Connection.
With which connection URL specify user is this and password disease.
So in school statements, you know, these are some SQL statements.
I'm going to tell you as I told you.
I'm going to disconnect this and I'm going to clear screen this first.
What?
In school we are speech.
Why connect?
So what is connect inside IDs?
Connect IDs basically this connection with connection neural as our java doesn't know what is the connection?
So this is the connection you are in with the local machine.
Now we are going to specify a user system.
Similarly, I told you and with the password.
So this is all about the connection skill statements.
So while doing in ID what we are going to use, we are going to use this statement.
No.
What is this quick statement?
So we need to create one statement, otherwise it will not execute any statements or something.
We know our statements are different than Java, so we need to create one statements here.
So use this connection to create statements.
Then I will specify this as a school statement.
Mention this.
Insert string.
Insert into PPI.
Login details.
Values.
Are these.
These.
So this is all about the values.
But, you know, the fiscal statement command or if you don't know how we can insert in plug in details.
Plug in details is basically creating the database.
First, I will tell you how you can create the database.
The national database is very simple.
Just put create.
Cable.
What we are going to use is here.
Log in details.
These are values.
Just copy this part.
You can see control.
See this part?
Copy.
Just right click here.
You can see this plug in details here.
Now the login details in CMD.
Then this right here, follow all the things.
So first I'm going to specify the username.
Worker for the string here mentioned the length of string.
I'm going to put you at 100.
Password, but I will put like this password again.
We are required to basically for the string these and then name we carried to which 500.
I'm going to specify that it exit with semicolon.
Now you can see our table is created similarly.
You can create another table for this.
Belonging duties in your skill commanding.
For values.
What I'm going to enter a1 A1 field for username, A2 field for password.
I told you password this password if for field for the name.
So always remember for candidate that even to a to otherwise it will not execute.
It will throw the exception its exception use this single command then double inverted comma plus plus
sign and insert this follow these rules.
These are some really important things in this results that are as is equal to statement executed to
us then request dispatcher this for executing query like just to create it but you are not pressing
the enter similarly like that you have to result put this result statement then request.
DISPATCHER If this is correct, go to P log in details.
I do that forward.
I told you.
Close this connection, this very important exception.
It is not corrected like our iTunes password and confirm password fields are not equal.
What it will print?
It will print.
Please enter password and confirm password.
Same.
And it will remain on that page only.
So this is all about this.
This is a very important part.
I will put command here also.
Connection.
And storing.
In two.
Database.
So that is about the database.
This is very simple.
I'm going to store only in further videos or tutorials.
I'm going to tell you how you can validate participants with log in information and everything.
But let us deploy these first.
So as I told you, for deployment, Click Run or Click Clean and build here.
So let me open the output part here.
If your output window is not showing, just go to window here and you can see output part here or you
can press control plus for year.
Also, if you are output output part or anything is not showing here.
So as you can see, Glass Server is now currently running.
So it will take time to run everything and it will just show glass which is now running in Chrome or
your default browser.
It will directly load that page.
So as I told you, we created a connection and everything.
You're.
You can see hibernate server is starting Java security manager then these are some signatures are created
inside this so.
These are.
So now our
server is deployed.
On this.
As you can see, our port is now change 2002 last fiscal.
So as I told you, we have seen through the glass, fish and everything.
First I've been logging.
Now I'm going to specify only the participant.
Log in as I click to participants, log in.
You can see participant sign up and participant logging page.
I'm going to use participant sign in page here.
I'm going to James Name username j101 password.
I'm going to specify 1 to 3 if I'm not specifying password one, two, three, four and confirm password
field as four five, six, seven.
It will show, as you can see.
Please enter password and confirm password.
Same.
So now I'm going to enter everything.
You can use CAPTCHA or some statements and different things here.
Also, you can try with that part also.
Then.
One, two, three, four.
So.
As you can see, I moved to the participant login page.
I already created participants, but for the readers I will tell you.
So I would say read information how we can check our information is stored.
So go to the skill command line.
But use these statements.
Select.
Data from.
This this in details.
B log in details our table name.
And as you can see, our James password and its username are stored.
Always remember the sequence should be same as you entering.
In Java file java servlet file.
This one should be for username a two for the password and a for for name if you want to put name first,
then a for.
And similarly you have to specify these.
Also inside the Runescape command line.
This username should be below and the name should be applied.
So sequence is very important.
Don't change the sequence.
So that's how we can store this part into the database in further videos.
I'm going to tell you how we can change that part and everything.
And I'm going to add event and more further parts also.