So we have said the switch cases here in the previous video.
We have seen how we have done this.
We have to take the value and convert it to that.
First, we have to take the first country value and I'm going to do the balance here and take the another
which is not here.
We get the value and convert it to the second country.
So we multiplied it to the second country and in the default the user did not give any value.
It should set it to the 0.0 here should the default 0.0.
Now simply we will run our program and.
Here.
So what we will do here?
See, we take some country.
Suppose around here we take the India, the Nigeria.
And simply I write the quantity and let's say the convert.
So here we get our value.
It should be changed to this current value.
You can change according to your current value, whatever the current pound value right now.
So all this thing are going right now.
What we have to do here, the exit button is not work.
So.
Okay, just a second.
Here the reset button.
Try this on 23.
Onward.
Now we have to set this reset button.
If we click the reset button, it should all clear this text field.
So simply, we have to design this reset button so that we click on it and we will write our code here.
So what we will try the first country not set selects selected near the index and we will go to zero.
Second country set, third set selected index with the zero here.
And simply we will write.
Next first grand three.
Not.
Send text and simply write to note here.
Last one is the text second country not said text and simply write it to the knowledge.
Check this working.
Too soon.
Right.
23 and no, we.
This is working, right?
So.
At all?
No.
What do we have to do?
One thing also.
We click simply convert.
We are getting these right.
So we have to catch this error.
String error.
And simply solve this.
So click exit.
And what we will do.
Go to the.
It's an.
Simply what we will do.
We will check the condition here.
So the first country dot get selected index is equal to zero or second country.
Not.
In selected countries.
Zero.
Or.
The amount the user has not given the amount.
Also search should also catch that error also.
So we will write.
First.
Sorry.
Text first three.
Not get text.
Lord equals.
I'm the.
This one.
So we have to show the error here.
So we will write to option B.
Not true.
Message loud and clear.
We will give no.
And we will kill.
You must.
Let.
Both countries.
So again, here we have two.
Our message here.
We have the do or die policy here.
No information message here.
This is done.
Simply what we have to do.
We don't know what value also.
So I think, okay, so what we have to do now is.
Okay.
So this thing will handle other things.
So it will be goes with our this thing if the user did not put any input or did not choose anything.