So all of you already know that we created three methods here.
Password change password method generating random password method.
Also I created here using that password method using random also then asking for department and printing
the mill.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to set that mailbox capacity.
Now, remember in this first also I told by default is 500.
And but if users want to extend that mailbox capacity, I'm asking for the set mailbox capacity method.
So after this part, I will create some.
Set.
Mailbox capacity.
Method.
Then again, it is public, as I told you.
Why should it really be public?
Because user want to access that part will sit.
Male kept.
That's it.
Then no need to put any argument here because I don't want to put here.
If you want, you can minimize this part.
Also see steam dot, dot, println.
Current capacity will bring current capacity first.
Current capacity.
Is equal to.
Let's this dot.
Male capacity.
And I'm considering this is costing me not in GB, so I know this is very less, but I want to clearly
simplify this in my only.
Then system got out.
Println.
There is no need to ask for what is your first capacity or something?
I just want to create or assign that.
So enter new capacity.
Under new mailbox capacity.
Capacity.
Then.
This not male capacity, that part only.
Is equal to as dot next.
Next integer only.
No need to put anything here next to it.
And it will change like system dot.
Oh, dark.
In Berlin.
Mailbox capacity.
He is successfully changed.
So this is all about Ken setting the mailbox over city.
It is very easy.
Printing first current capacity.
Then enter the new mailbox capacity.
And just from the user just assigned to that new mailbox capacity.
Similarly for that.
Alternate meal, public void.
What is that alternate?
Eamon.
So I will put here first.
Set.
Our Internet.
We to remember comments because it's very helpful while reading the code system dot.
Oh, Lord.
Brent Lynn.
Enter.
New Order.
Net mail or email.
Then this dot alternative bill that we create already created that part is not.
Mixed.
Then system.
This is very simple material.
No need to worry about this.
Alternate.
Male or female.
Is sick.
That's it.
Now these are all about creating or generating something, but I want to create some another method
to display something because we are just generating.
But there is nothing I'm going to display here how I can display the user information or something,
that part.
So to display user information I will create.
Another method.
Information matter.
For that part, it should be public, only public.
Avoid getting info and printing gear to get info.
Simple.
Just printing nothing.
Well that system dot dot printer and just printing statement print statements are only.
This dot.
F.M. now the space between to these.
Similarly that system.
Port au Prince in.
Depart.
Meant.
Plus it will put that department, this DOD.
Liberty.
Department.
This is then for email you can put.
Email.
Then.
This.
But.
All the user information, basically.
Then if you want to put a password, you can put that password.
But here y in ideal condition you should not print any password or you should not display any password,
but for the significant convenience and I want to check it will be running or not I'm going to put here
on you.
So this is for the testing purpose for our application.
This is not password.
Then again, system dot dot println.
Mail box capacity.
This not mailbox mail capacity.
I put the mail capacity.
And I will put in the also like I'm already mentioned I'm putting in this only me.
Then again, system dot dot println.
I don't make.
Internet.
Male.
This.
Not.
Alter email and that's it.
We we're done with these matters, so let's invoke it into that public class.
But before that, remember, we are remaining with some other methods, also store files and this.
But before that I will explain that constructor.
But yeah, so we already created one constructor here and before that creating controller.
What I did is set mailbox capacity, then set change password method, alternate email method and display
user information method that should be done.
Then we want to call that methods.
So calling that method is very simple here, I can say.
So now I will go to this constructive part here.
Now.
I am putting here is calling.
Methods.
So now quality methods is very simple.
This lot.
Department to assign that department.
This DOD department is equal to this DOD set department.
What?
I created the said department.
Now the for the random password.
I will put here for department.
First random password.
This for password is equal to this load generate password which I created.
Now what required here is I'm putting length eight.
What I told you.
I'm not mentioning Len there because I want to put inside this.
So avoiding that part, I just put length here.
So Len will be always it.
It's not very ideal condition to put always Len eight but for the simple condition, I use your eight
or you can put as much you want or you can choose form 6 to 15 or something like that.
Now.
I want to combine this.
Like generating mail.
You know that method this lot.
What is that?
Generate email.
Email.
This is for.
Email generation.
No.
Now we are done with this part.
But.
This is just there is no matter.
You cannot run this like this only because you can see there is no main method we created here we are
remaining with main method.
So this is all about the email part.
In the next part, what I'm going to show you how we can create main method.
We are going to invoke that main method, including that how we can use this all part.
Plus, I'm going to show you how you can create and store that in the specific file dot text file.