A board is cleared and initialized with the following piece.
Right.
But we have to create a timer, and the timer is executed at the period interval which we have created
the variable.
So what we have to do, we will hear, look and.
Right.
I might call the new timer.
Sorry the new timer and do this we will write period.
Interval comma, new games.
We will create this one.
Also, we have game cycle and then none and then timer.
Don't start again.
Okay?
This thing is done here.
What we have.
Create a timer.
The timer is executed at period interval beta interval intervals and creating a new game cycle.
And what we have done here, we have this is the pause method.
This pauses or resumes the game.
When the game is paused, we display the paused message here in the status bar.
And now we will do one more thing.
We will create another matter with the drawing method.
But before that we will do one more thing.
We need the paint component.
So we will write.
We will overwrite.
Sorry, public void.
Being the component.
Mhm.
And component and into this we have to do graphics G and under this some graphics we need this graphics
and under this we will call the super dot print component.
This one set it to the G and we will create that matter which is named as the do drawing and give the
parameter to the G.
So this is done and we will create this matter and we have to write the body of this as well.
So inside the two drawing matter, we draw all the objects on the board.
The painting has two steps here.
What we will do.
We will do one thing.
Firstly, take variable size.
So set the variable size equal to get size and the get size method which we will create a mean class
press.
So here we will the two steps which will be here.
Just see that we will write in more top and right size.
Don't get to I think height and width are board height minus and then multiplied by square table.
It's like square height, which we have created this.
MARTIN okay.
It has to.
We have done the typecasting as well to the end and now what we have to do.
This will be our first step.
So we will create our for loop and write for int i equal to zero semicolon i.e. less than two board.
We need the board.
Right.
Okay.
I think.
Sorry.
Okay.
So I is less than two board height.
Here the board height and.
And we will do okay.
We will do the post increment here, not the pre.
So under this or loop we will create another for loop with the variable g in the j equal to zero and
one j is less than to the board of it here and now post to increment of the g variable.
The system under this for loop we will create.
Firstly, we write that terminal C equal to the Shepard method and here we will write the G variable.
And here what we need would.
Bora Bora it minus a, minus one.
And now, after this, we need some conditions.
So we will write if she.
They're not equal to.
They do not know -- and we have no shape.
Then do one more thing.
Draw near the draw.
We will create a smarter in our class and get the parameter g command g.
We need the square work here.
So what we will call the square root.
And then.
We have to do one thing as well, comma and write board to do the plus.
I multiplied to the square height?
Yeah.
No.
I think we have to multiply with them square height.
And this is drawn by another parameter.
We'll go with the shape.
And this is a I think I have done it wrong.
It should be width, not the height.
Set it to the word.
This has to be so we have to do one more condition and check it to the if
called the Kirby store, that ship.
It is not equal to no ship.
Right.
That terminal, not no ship.
And then we have to do.
The acting and what we have done, we will do in the first step.
We paint all the shapes or the remains of the sheep that have been dropped at the bottom of the board
on the squares.
And remember, in the border we accesses, we access that it using the shape and method here this one.
So we we do another one more thing.
This will be our next second step.
So here what we will do.
We need four in equal to zero.
Then I listed for done I do the post increment and here then here we will write in x equal to.
And I think in the second step we paint the actual falling piece, right?
So what we will do in x equal will call the x variable.
The x is the current piece.
Here we have the current piece and the current tax return.
I thought x and provide it to the OC and similar to that we write in y equal to.
In my current FY plus current peace same thing no current peace and provider not to why I and this is
done.
We pay natural following peace, so we will do so.
We need to draw square.
Esquire.
We're right here.
G Gomer.
Thanks, God.
Scratch beneath the fruit and go with the comma and ride board.
Don't do with the board.
We need a board height.
Right.
So we will ride board height minus y and we will do one more thing, the minus one.
And here this is done.
It should be multiplied with the square height.
This one.
And after this, we need the current peace and not access to the get -- done.
And this thing is done.
So what do we have to do now?
We have to do x is one more thing, the drop down method.
So we will set it to the drop down so we have what we have done.
This will be the first step.
We paint all the ships or remains of the ship that have been dropped at the bottom of the boat port
on the square side.
Remember, in the board.
We exit you using the shape add method and this will be our second step.
We paint the actual falling piece here.
So we need another method and this will be called as the drop down.
So after this, we will create our dropdown method.
We will write private void, name it as drop down and curly bracket.
Done.
Here we will create a new y and set it to the current VI this time.
So if we press the space key, the pieces drop to the bottom.
We simply try to drop the piece one line down until it reaches the bottom or the top of another foreign
Tetris piece when the Tetris piece finishes folding the piece.
I think we will create another matter and name it to not be drowned.
And it is called there.
So what we will do, we have to take the while loop and simply set it to the new y is greater than zero
and not this while loop.
We will provide some conditions and we write if it is not.
We will create this matter after, say, two current peace men comma, current x, comma, new y minus
one.
Here, this one.
And it's done.
And what do we have to do?
We have to write.
Break.
And after this, we have to decrease.
Who knew?
I touch my nose and it's done.
And we have to call that matter.
Okay, so we press the space key, the pieces drop to the bottom.
We simply try to drop the piece one line down until it reaches that bottom or top of the another fallen
Tetris piece.
So when the Tetris piece finishes falling, the piece drop, which we will create here.
So piece dropped.
And this matter will be called and.