So we already created everything here.
So let me explain what I created in the next part.
So I added some form here in this which HTML pages, so much HTML pages as you can see, which is quantity
and everything.
Add book, then add librarian form.
Also I created with mobile number and everything.
Is nothing admin for that.
Esteem and purpose and everything I created.
So this is all about how we already created this.
So let me explain.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to just showing you the deployment in this part.
But let me explain what is admin carousels and everything is done.
So this is log in admin form.
Which is basically.
So let's then librarian.
Librarian log in I'm creating so.
You can say the servlet if you want to.
Do you have to mention this again then this is all email address and password method.
I'm going to do it.
So this is basically navigation admin HTML page, then navigation home page, then return the book form
to form and return book everything.
So you have to check each and every part here.
Otherwise you will get sometimes error here or log in and everything part.
Also let me close this page and I will explain this.
So library method is nothing, but I'm going to add some librarian methods here.
Hope you already created everything inside this and inside the DB.
You mention everything here.
So let me do one thing is here is I'm going to mention.
User.
It makes them mention the password.
And it is.
There's a password and everything here.
So.
Look, I don't want to deploy it again because I will deploy it.
So this is done inside.
We.
Let me explain.
What is this doing?
So this is DB part, which is connection of skill.
Always remember you have to mention G.P.S. drivers also.
Yeah.
So this ad book part here, I'm going to add the book part.
And once this is done, book is saved.
So in the librarian side, we can say this for the librarian part only.
Then after this add book form, why I'm creating ADD book form.
It is just a basic part.
I written in HTML with Java to put the request dispatcher and add book form and everything here.
So there's nothing but just printing the statements html codes here.
Then add librarian.
This part is also very important here.
So it's adding the librarian inside this.
And this very simple thing I'm adding here with some HTML pages or then this is ad librarian form,
as I told you before that you have to check each and everything here like written Google Dot HTML contents,
written book.
But you need to mention where is the written book?
So let's again then you have to mention fully specified name.
Then you have to check this also.
And everything.
So for me is again so late.
So we have to mention this.
This is again so late.
So you have to mention this then also.
So let's mention the fully specified names.
Otherwise it will give the internal errors again and again.
So I already created this part.
But remember, you have to read this.
Let us check navigation homepage.
Also, don't double click that part, otherwise it will start the running part.
So now we are done with this part, some HTML part also.
Then the navigation admin page.
I already mentioned everything here.
Then in admin, log in or library and log in part.
I also mentioned the solid part here.
Then this is no longer just for adults.
That's.
I mean if you one I also mentioned so let's again here.
Then index.html need admin log in form and book.
Also I need to mention so let's dot because it's really important here.
Librarian also.
So let's not.
So.
And and everything.
Okay, now we are done with everything.
Always give the fully specified name and this is the admin login form or librarian form as I told you
inside the java.
Then let me close some things because we already created this part.
This.
This is done, basically.
Let us go to delete book.
I created one delete book thing also your then delete librarian method.
Also I created because we need to mention this part again delete library which is basically deleting
the librarian edit librarian basically editing that librarian part and all the things I have done.
Issue book is very important.
I create an new book form and issue book method also here for the form, methods and everything.
Let us clean and build this first.
So you can directly use these methods or you can create your own methods also here with different names.
So if your window is not showing output, as I told you, go to windows.
And that output here.
And hope you can see here.
Now my build is successful.
Let me run this in glass.
We server.
So it will take time to run on the glass.
Free server will be successful.
So let me open chrome first.
My thing is going to that only.
Oh, then.
I will add that.
Part.
We'll begin to see this this meeting.
And let me go through the admin as I know this is admin one, two, three, logging.
I'm going to add library.
And basically, as I mentioned, it's John.
John.
And the university when possibly.
One, two, three.
Mobile number I mentioned 2989024450.
LeBron added successful if I click view LeBron is not showing anything wrote this so we created everything
here as a library and then everything.
So this is all about how we can create our methods and everything.
Hope you understand this.
Always remember you have to specify some default names and everything here and don't need to mention
each and every time your everything.
Inside law library in the.
Also you can see some methods already created like save and everything.
So always give some meaningful names to these things.
And I already created this part again.
Why it is showing me sometimes error.
Because if you see my library method there are four files name ID also.
So let me add one more thing.
You can say ID and I'm what I'm going to do is I'm going to mention that ID is always some default thing
you can say.
So ID is equal to one.
I'm mentioning ID is always one.
And because I haven't mentioned that part.
Host inside this I'd.
Boy.
So let us put this.
Let me make a question mark here.
Okay.
So because there are five fields inside this one, two, three, four, five.
And in the Liberian method, also one, two, three, four, five fields there.
So sometimes it gives the error.
To me, this is second, this is third.
This is for time.
This is fifth.
Then what is the first part is.
He is not sit.
String.
One form of it is basically it.
So you can put this also or you can check your methods also like I'm using gate name, get your name
on things now so you can use this also or otherwise you can mention directly like.
One year.
You can redeploy these things.
And again, you can check.
So always remember, you have to keep that part specific.
Like if you created two or more things inside this part.
Always you have to mention.
Those similar things.
You have to create some similar things also.
John Deere at University.
JB One, two, three.
And J.
One, two, three.
Mobile number is 9890.
Online.
Submit.
Now you can see why these things are adding because I haven't mentioned the idea.
So you can create, edit and everything, but I don't want to change this IED.
I'm mentioning that when you can create a loop and you can do everything.
So I know this is my email now for the librarian purpose.
If I go to this and I put this part.
And give one, two, three and log in.
Now you can see I'm going to the login page and you can put your everything.
This is all part.
If I go to the ad book, I can add the book.
If I click the view book, I can click the View book.
Let me add, one book is called Number is one name is.
Wings.
It is a big.
Publisher is quality.
I'm mentioning anything or don't check that.
And remember quality and quantity I'm mentioning too.
So book books are successful.
You can sell this book and it should issue book.
If I created book, call number is one student ID is mentioning SX 101 student name is.
James.
Student Mobile number 90234501.
That's it.
You should book book you should successfully.
You should book.
You can see this is issue.
If you want to return, the call number is one s number is 101 written book.
So sometimes it gives the error because it's 101 is not inside this because you can see as 101 is this
and you have to return that book.
All of this.
So this is all about you can create e-library methods and this is all about how you can create each
and every part.
If I create log in, you can see username and password is.
Not correct.
If I go to the home and if I put this, you can see this is very informal part and you can create item
in form.
And each and every method is also I will mention each and every methods.
But you can create such methods and you can create add a librarian part also here as I created your.
If I go to this and I click, you can view this, I can delete this part.
Also, you can see now it's deleted.
Then now I'm going to this logout.
You can do that part also.
So this is all about how you can create the login method.
Always remember use some specific names as I made some mistake while giving the ID so you can do that
part also.
And what you can do.
You can create one loop here and you can do ID default.
Like I just want to use that loop again and again using for loop you can put after one, you can put
the two second, third, fourth like that you can create.
So these are about how we can create a library method.
So we created all the servlet part and everything.
Now we are, we did everything, then we created HTML, we created servlet and we deployed on the class
server.
So this is all about our project.
Thank you.
Hope you understand this project.
You can build your own or things like E library in-hospital methods also.
So this is all about and this is very simple project, I told you.
You can furthermore extend to some card methods.
Also here you can create QR codes.
Also here using some HTML parts.
You can change the UI.
All this also.