Here is the teacher attendance details dot java file which is defined inside the package university
imported necessary package java dot SQL Java dot swing java AWG Java dot dot event.
We have defined the class teacher attendance detail which is extending the frame implementing Excel.
There is a one table instance given one button stands B one and a string area of a string array named
as edge, which is totalling blue ID date time, first up and second off.
Then any string two dimensional area labeled as B which is of 15 class four.
So integer ie is close to zero and is close to zero.
Inside the non parameter constructor headed as well.
Teacher details set the size of the frame as attended.
Comma 300.
Setting the location.
As for four 5150 inside the tri block, we have created a very that is select aspect from attendance
feature.
So this will.
This is the query to.
Fetch all the records from the attendance teacher table.
So we have after that we have initialize the connection with our icon class with the help of icon class
that is seven.
Then by using the result is set statement instance we have executed.
Our query is stored in a string queue and after that we have iterated over the results or record of
the attendance teacher.
By then we have stored into our two dimensionality with the every row in respect to.
In this phase of this two dimensional array, first employed date, first and second of attendance.
After every operation we will updating or incrementing the rows and initializing the column again to
zero.
Then we have created the table with the help of one by passing the two dimensional array in the column
area.
Inside the cache block will handle any exception.
If of course, then there is a be one button print adding the location for that button, the scroll
panel to that table and adding it to our panel.
Frame.
Then there is a B1 ad actually adding the listener to that.
But in print and inside void action performed, which is taking x element as argument instead of try
block.
We have called print, so when we click on print it will call the print method and that will open any
new dialog box for the printing of that page.
Now each exception e if any exception occurs, then it will catch that inside the void main method we
have.
Digit attendance details.
Call it, and setting visibility as true.
Let's move to our next class.
That is a master class.
It is also defined inside the package university.
And then we have imported the necessary packages like AWP, AWP event, Java X dot swing and Java dot
SQL.
After that, we have defined the class Max, which is extending the frame.
Then there is a text area t one and J panel B1.
Then there is a non parameterized constructor of marks.
So this is not in use, I think.
Wait a minute.
Marks.
String str.
Marks as.
So we are calling.
Yes.
So non constructor doesn't have anything then.
We have defined the.
Parameterized constructor by passing a string str, setting the size for the window which is of border
layout, and then again a panel and a text area scroll panel for that, adding the font for that.
Adding the panel and the scroll panel to the window, location of the window and inside the parameter
constructor we have called a method mark by passing the STR.
Now here is the method mark defined.
Let's see what is doing inside the try block.
Initialize the connection now to 1.6 text.
So it is setting the text in the text free text area actually result of examination and subject.
Then there is a result set query in which we have executing the query select extract from subject where
rule number is equal to s.
So this will mention all the subjects from the subject table where row number will be.
A particular rule number.
So for a particular rule number.
Some list of subjects will be mentioned.
So for the RS, one point next.
So for the next record in the table, it will append all the subject list.
After that, there is an execution query which is saying that select extract from marks for roll number
from the Marks table.
It will fetch the marks for the same roll number.
And inside the AIF block we have appended all the marks of the.
Particular roll number student and then in the catch block we will handle any exception if occurs.
And inside the main method we will call the new max class and set the visibility as true.
Now we have the examination details class.
Which is also defined inside the package university and importing the necessary package.
Our eight dot asterisk Java Exports Industry, Java Zinc Border Java SQL Server or JWT Event and Java.
And this is not.
Brought to an end, don't ask, don't tell.
So this class is provided by this library.
This will be help us to model the designing of the table in Orlando.
So this is a public class examination detail and it is extending frame and implementing the action list
now.
And then there is a private panel content paint table, table and text field search.
Another, there are three buttons B1, B2 and B three.
Then we have defined a method book.
Let me have a look at first.
First, let's have a look on this public examination detail.
That is a non parameter as constructor of it.
Set the bound for the window and adding the panel background colour for it, border for it, adding
it to our frame and setting the layout for it.
Then we have created a scroll panel setting the bound for it, adding it to our frame.
Then there is a table adding mouse listener.
So this will also.
Take handling of event of mouse click as well for the mouse click.
We have passed the mouse argument and in the row table get selected row.
So set table model.
So it will model the table on the basis of the mouse click then setting the background color for round
color and font for it and scroll panel set point view of the table.
So a scroll panel will help us to scroll over the table.
Be one point new button result x.
Setting the border with the help of color and line butter for one color font.
Bound and adding it to our frame or panel, setting the label check result font for it for one color
and bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there is a search which is a text field, background color, border, foreground color font bound
for it, adding it to our.
Panel.
Then we have searched outside columns, so it will have ten columns setting the column for that label.
Another level is back on which we have added mouse action is now past the mouse event and set the visibility
of the current window as follows.
So this is the label which will also handle the event of mouse clicks.
Now foreground colour coloured grey font bound adding to that frame.
Now another panel named as panel setting the border for it with the examination details title border.
And adding it to the frame.
Panel looks at background color white.
Now calling book.
Now we have called books.
So let's have a look on the book.
Uh.
There is a method book.
So I think irrespective of the book, this should be called this is examination detail.
So I'll be calling it as.
Still.
And changing the book here to.
It's.
To.
Now initialize the connection select from student.
It will create a prepared statement by using the string as Q will execute that query.
Tabletop set model by using.
Execute of the query, prepare the statement SD and develop a set model will set the model for the table.
Close the set as a result, set instance and the statement instance.
Then close the connection cas the exception if any, occurs.
So after the calling of the stop, then set size, setting the size for the window and set action.
Perform a will if can stabilize the connection from the world connection class.
If the source is from one button, then we will.
Call the new max and search dot get text set visibility to so we will call the parameter constructor
class of the max class and set the current window as false cast exception and inside the static void
main string areas, we will call new examination details and set those built as true.
So these are the three classes which we have talked about in this video.
Let's have a look on this execution of these classes.
I'll be starting from the log in again, so we'll have a better understanding how the program is interrelated.
Hardiman.
And when.
Logging in.
This will be the result of project class.
Teacher attendance details.
These are the teachers.
We have not added any details, so that's why it is not showing anything here.
I'll be.
Displaying it.
Examination details.
Click on examination details.
So this is the label, black label, which will take us back.
And this is the research label when we.
Enter the rule number.
It will.
Show the result of the.
Students.
I will be clicking on the back level.
This will close and enter marks.
So this will help us to enter the marks of the student.
When I will enter the roll number and subject marks, that will be.
Click on submit and the result will be submitted.
Let's click close.
This in next will be having a look on the applet teachers.
Plus.
So let's close it.