In previous things I created the gameplay and we are done with gameplay method.
Now I'm going to create one another thing which is basically map generator.
So I'm going to create another class right click on inside source folder.
Go to New.
You can check your loading menu.
Go to Java class and mention as name map generator.
My generator so it will give me when you public class map generator.
So I'm using it only.
I'm moving you down a little bit.
You can minimize this.
And now in map generator.
First thing, I need to create a 2D map.
So for two D at a similar thing I'm going to create here as we are creating two very.
As map I'm creating as a 2D array.
First team first public int required tiny dimension brick built.
Then public.
In.
Brick, right.
So if you look closely, look this or this is the similar thing.
I'm calling here.
Brick.
So these things will be resolved when I clear the map and everything.
Now I need to create one constructor of yours so you can use your old insert to go with the constructor.
But let me create it as it is.
Map generator, default package.
Or you can check in row for row purpose and int column or column purposes, which is going to put in
that part only, which is.
Smart.
Is equal to new.
India's India's end.
Rule.
Gone.
So it will put in that part.
Or in again, that iReport, which is basically generating some values for map and putting in a map
length.
My blend.
I.
Bliss.
And one more look.
Basically for.
And G is equal to zero.
JS less than maplin again, but not yet maplin map zero which is basically at the starting position
of map.
Lend.
Duplass Plus.
Map.
I meant G.
She should be one.
So I need to mention this.
After this.
I need to mention it.
So.
Brick width and height.
Create width and height.
Liquid.
540 divide by column.
Actually directly depends on this and when 50 divided by.
So it will take directly.
So I need not to mention everything again and again.
Now.
Public void.
Which is basically the shooting this part directly.
So it will divide in a similar or as its end so it will round figure edit the width or you can number
of color bricks in that map.
Let me mention one drop.
Graphics.
2D.
Graphics, 2d.
G.
Yes.
So once I call this, you can check here a W is called.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to create one or loop not want loop for loop.
With the end I.
Zero.
Then I maplin is maplin only.
At length.
I plus plus till that maplin.
So.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this part because.
And very.
So.
Okay, so these things are done.
Now, let me mention this.
Everything here.
So.
If Mapp is having ICOM g.
Might not matter.
Everything is greater than zero, which is basically ideal condition.
Or G dot said color.
I'm going to set color cc0r dot.
Wait.
Why?
It's not this color that white, which is basically white color.
It's going to set to the bricks white.
And G dot.
Fill that rectangle.
Ignore this error.
It's giving me some kind of error of ID, so we will resolve it later.
But it needs to create that with brick width.
Not you with.
Yes.
Liquidity is for liquid plus 80.
With I start it should be mentioned with brick height, the height plus 50.
With which the and height as my main things.
So it will go with field rectangle or you can say creating whole the rectangle as my main part.
Now these things are done.
Now this.
With her to show I'm going to create that method separate.
Brick.
Game.
It is basically going to separate the brick and grime so it will clear another rectangle from it.
So you basically can still run without it also.
So it is for testing purpose.
You can check, but.
Very important method that stroke I need to mention stroke.
New.
Basic stroke.
WW 33.
I'm going to mention as three.
With which stroke is basically now state color method.
You are not.
Black.
I guess I.
Black first is Rachel G dot.
Now again I need to mention draw rectangular here.
So.
Rectangular.
And again the similar theme this.
I tried everything.
It's similar again.
With a D in everything.
Everything is similar.
No.
I created this, but I need to set brick value also so public.
Boyd set.
Brick.
We you.
In.
Which is basically I'm going to mention how much thing it's not to mention the raw slush in column.
And now in this column, I'm going to create map.
Raw.
Column.
Is equal to hell.
So it will create different things for me.
And I guess.
Wait a minute.
I closed the class, and that's not proper.
Now it's.
Now, if you go to these things.
You can check.
Starting me for the resolving any purpose.
And now you can check.
There are there will be no errors in our gameplay because I created a map generator function.
So this will create a map and this will create a functions.
Now what things are remaining?
I call this, but I won't set main method.
I'm not creating any main method.
So for that purpose I'm going to create one main method here.
Before that.
Okay.
Clear on and close.
So what I'm going to do is this is my generator function is done.
Game plays.
Function is done.
Now I need to mention your main function to call this map generator and gameplay functions in the main
method.
So I'm giving this main only.
In this mean?
Obviously to run any main method you need.
Public static void main you can check swim only swim is enough.
Public static point main it should be print.
Jeffrey.
Dear friend, I'm calling as an object here.
New frame.
You're like smitten or Java effects.
You can check it.
Gameplay.
So it's my default class gameplay.
With gameplay, I'm going to create your gameplay.
But what I'm going to do is hear gameplay camel case.
I'm going to use your gameplay with new obviously gameplay default package.
Now I need to mention the boundaries of my object.
Object?
Which set bounds.
With a rectangular, which is basically my rectangular ten by ten by height.
I'm going to mention this will be the.
Of width and height, x ray, width and height.
Now I need to mention object title for this title.
So subtitle name changes.
Mm.
Break.
Hope.
Ball.
Game, which in my title breakout one game.
Oh no, said Resizable, which is basically disguising the part and don't want to do that.
So I'm mentioning as false.
If you are going to resize, it will default.
It will be create deformities in mapping functions which is basically creating this.
So I'm mentioning as this as should be avoided and set visible, which is basically creating a visible
now it should be true while running.
It should be true.
Now I need to mention your running function.
So for this object dot state.
Default.
Close operation, which is basically closing Operation J Frame.
Jeffrey.
With.
Except on clothes is basically going to fix it.
So if I close, it should be closed and object.
Which I'm going to add basically gameplay.
And again.
It visible.
And it should be, too.
No I created this main so gameplay is I'm going to create here map generator is going to generate a
map and main method is going to load this.
So let us run this.
So you can check here.
It's running for me.
So it's given me the running condition.
So it will take time to build and do everything but hope our code is correct.
Otherwise we will be buggered in a short way and we will check what things are errors or what are the
errors in this.
But I guess our code is perfectly fine.
It's passing everything.
The beautiful thing of Java X-Wing is you should not be mentioned any Java fixings, which is basically
VM options or anything.
It will load directly in your console only, which is very similar to the you can check here.
It's my running and you can check here.
My code is started or this is my ballgame.
So as you can see, I mentioned no resizable.
So as you can check here.
My these things are remaining, but my ball is not moving, so let us debug it.
I guess we made error in our for loop so we will check it.
But you can check here.
My these things are working and this is not going to the this part and this is remaining to this part.
So you can check here.
It's not moving like a portion downwards.
It just moving from here to there.
If I close this, it's going to me finish code with this.
So now it's working.
But we made some errors in for loop, so first we will debug it.
Okay.
I found one error in this, which is very common error.
I started this for loop here, which is basically my for loop.
And before I change.
No, but before that, I'm closing it in earlier, which is basically I'm moving it upwards with this
for so practically this for loop is going out of this.
So it's not going to move at all.
That's obvious thing.
So do one thing here is just move this below this map, which is basically and now let us run it again.
Let us check whether it's working or not.
So window appears.
And if I press this now, you can check my ball is moving and it's going to bounce at these boundaries.
Also you can check and my these things are also reappearing while recording this you can check there
is some lag due to some system configuration or otherwise.
It's moving very fine.
And you can check here.
It's giving me this.
And you can check if it goes down, it is going to down.
If I press enter again, it will create me another map.
Another map means a new map.
Now it's bounced to the right part.
You can check.
This is going right.
This is going left because I mentioned it's this slip.
So if it hits this position at this part, so it will go to.
Right.
So now it's moving to the right.
Now you can check this.
So it's working very fine.
Work.
All is working very successfully.
So now it's moving in that way only.
And our code is working fine now.
It's very critical condition to bring that game.
And as you can see, my squad is 85 and you can press enter it again to resume from that, but hope
you understand the exit for the breakout ball.
So now what you can do in this is, as I'm creating from the scratch that exposition, my position,
what you can do, you can create some illustrations here and you can add it directly as I'm creating
here a single player game.
You can create your multiplayer games.
Also, you can create animation, you can add sound also in this game.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.
So this is a very basic game I created to learn how the RW teachings works here.
And what is the basic mechanism of RW.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.