So till now we have created four classes inside this project.
The main class, the contact class, the repository and the object repository class.
And all these four classes have covered almost the functioning of the tree.
Now we are going to create the frame which will be like consist all the input fields, buttons and everything.
So in this we are going to feed everything inside the frame at how actually things should be up there
inside the frame.
So in order to do so, firstly let us create a new file inside this RC folder.
We are going to name it as GSC Frame, not Java and I.
Yes, this is going to be the GSC.
And this is going to contain all the information regarding the frame.
So on hitting enter a class or public class, GSC frame is being created.
Now we will extend this to us as we are going to use the Java string package for the making of this
frame basically.
So Java X dot string dot z frame is the way to extend this class in the form of a frame.
So swing the frame and yes, head it is.
So in order to do so.
We have to.
Yes.
Import one thing inside the.
Class import Java X-Wing.
Not the default list model.
So everything here is displayed in the form of a list model.
The contact list are listed here in the form of yes, it is basically listed here in the form of a list,
whether it be the list of the names or the things inside the form.
So yes, public class C frame is extended to Java showing frame.
Now inside this, we will be declaring like some global variables which we will use in this like file
later I repository which we have created.
And the arguments inside this are going to be contact and integer.
The key value we have already like mentioned it earlier and it is going to be a repository.
So yes, this is a repository we have created inside the frame.
Now, the second thing is going to be the list model.
So private, the default list model.
And that list model is going to contain the contact.
So contact and list model.
So list model.
It is.
Now we have declared two global variables, the repository and the list model inside the GSC Frame class.
Now we are going to create a new form inside the frame.
So how to create this form?
Firstly, we will like creating a constructor called GSC Frame.
So public GC Frame and the arguments inside this are going to be the repository, of course, contact
integer again.
Contact comma integer and then closing this.
So yes.
And the name is going to be Depositary, of course.
So this is going to create a new form inside the JSC frame.
This dot repository will help us to access the repository we have created declared as a global variable.
So yes, the next thing is going to be the list model.
List model new default list.
Yes.
The default list model.
So the default list model has been like called inside the constructor.
Now we will be creating init components.
Fail list items are two functions.
So first let us name them here init components and.
The Phillies list items.
This is written like this.
So these two functions we will be creating.
Stay tuned in this
contact.
Set the model.
So the list model is going to be the structure of the model, like the frame we are going to create.
Yes.
So yes, this is like a new form inside the GC frame.
Now we will be in the next step creating order in the component function.
So in order to do so, coming outside this and creating that private void init component.
Yes that's suggestions are already eager to create this.
So after the creation of this init component inside this unit components, we have to like declare all
of the components of the form and the frame.
So firstly we have to create a panel for the contents, then a scroll pen and it is this panel and also
it is going to be like a scroll pane.
Once this frame is full, then we can scroll in order to move to different like below mentioned contents.
So yes, things are going to be like a panel, a scroll pane and the list of contacts, which is like
this one, two, three, four.
It is going to be stored in the form of a list, then a label for the first name, the last name, the
address, the address, whatever it was, everything has to be firstly had declared inside the frame
so that we can add it to the frame later.
So inside this init components function, we have initialized all that required like whether it be the
label, the panel, the scroll pane, the list, we have mentioned it inside the init component.
Basically we have initialized all of the requisites of this frame inside this init components function.
There is a panel that is a scroll pane, a list of contacts, first name, last name.
And similarly we have a label for the first name and a text like this, a label containing string,
first name and then a text field.
So yes, everything is written in a paired manner without label industrial text field.
All seven of them are to note.
And then for the button we are using Java String Button component.
The button is a component of string library for buttons.
So overall we have three buttons, remove update and add.
So yes, these all are the are declarations inside the init component function.
Now in the next step, we are going to set the detailing of the frame like whether it be the name of
the title.
So it is like mentioned here in the form of a label component and also this heading contacts.
So yes, head it is set default close operation.
So we are setting our default close operation.
So whenever the user hits this close button, then they will escape out of this frame and also set title
we have set title as Java String Container Contact and name as GSC Frame.
So this in the contact title is Java String Contact.
And similarly we have set the frame to resizable as false.
So we will remove this as we want to resize the phone.
To maximize it and minimize it.
We want to keep this function working.
If we set it to false, then it will like become disabled.
And we will not be able to maximize or minimize this window.
So after removing this ad window listener, Oxo window listener is attached here to listen all the actions,
whether it be the closing or maximizing minimizing.
So that operation are like handled by the window adapter.
The window event listening is covering that closing or maximizing minimizing function.
Now inside this.
Okay, so we are done with the title.
Now inside the frame we are having panels.
Okay.
So headed to J panel contact.
So we have setup border and it is we have a border for this repository.
And inside the border, the white thing you can see on your screen is a parent.
So, yes, inside the border, we have certain layout.
These are the dimensions for the contact frame.
So, yes, this contact panel is containing the heading as contacts.
And inside the border, we have set the layout for the like contact repository window.
The panels are dimensions and layouts are covered with the help of this part.
Now the next part is to, like, handle the scroll pin.
So yes, once this list is full, then a scroller will appear, which will enable us to scroll through
the contacts and yes, have a through all of them.
Now we have added event listener to all of them.
Like once we click on any of the contacts, then it will highlight change its color.
So yes, whichever contacts is selected, then the color will change.
So we have added events to all of them.
Regarding to all of the highlights we have set our separator layout also now after this.
After completing that, contact the repository panel we have inside this contact information panel and
that contact information panel is containing heading as contact information.
So from here we are covering the consistence of the form.
This is the label for the first name.
Last name.
So yes, all the labels are listed inside the frame with the help of this.
Now after this for like we have set the size for the column as well and set a line.
So once we will enter something the line is full, then it will automatically change its line and start
up adding in that name.
So for that reason, the note we have done that.
Line drafting and size for the column, like what could be the maximum length for the line to be filled
and then start executing from the next line.
So yes, inside this contact information form, we have set the labels for everything and how the input
should be fed inside it in the form of a text.
So our using dot set text enables to enter the text inside the text field.
So after the contact formal labels for the button part we are having remove and then update buttons.
So that remove button is containing US dedicated functionalities which will remove the action performed.
So yes, this Remove Action Performed event enables.
To remove that specific selected row from the repository.
Similarly with the update button, it is calling the update action perform functionality.
So the action listener is attached to all three of the buttons remove, update and add, and the actions
that will be performed on the click of that specific button is listed inside this void function.
So public void function for all of them action perform all three of them and are event attached to that
buttons.
So add action, update action and remove action.
So after creating all the requisites of this flame, whether it be the contact side or the form side,
now we will be adding all of them to the frame with the help of dot and keyword.
So yes, we will cover this in the next step.