So here is the flight info class, which is also defined inside the package airline and.
Inside it.
We have first imported the package that is a net protein bit protein, a dot SQL utils.
If you know about this package, that's better.
But I will tell you, this package will be used to maintain the better formatting of tables in our window.
That J table does not provide that functionality much efficient as this package will provide.
So it will we will use it.
We will be using its set model method to frame our function, frame our tables and it is defined and
provided.
This library are as two examples are.
So make sure that this library present in your library folder.
Otherwise it will show you through you error.
Of class not found.
Then we have imported the package.
Our .8. asterisk used to define graphical user interface and develop graphical user interface desktop
based applications.
And then we have imported the package, a WTA event, not as strict.
This package will help us to handle the events on our buttons in this class, so that's why we have
imported it.
Also Java dot dot asterisk.
This will help us to maintain a connection with our database, update the database or retrieve information
from the database.
After that, we have defined the sorry.
We have imported the Java export string package, which is a modified version of the Abstract Vendor
Toolkit and it provides better functionality.
Then the Abstract Mental Toolkit Package.
Now we have defined the public class flight info, which is extending frame.
Inside, which we have to find a private type of table and stance named as table.
Another private type of text field and stance labeled as text field.
And then we have defined the void, static void, main method.
Inside which we have.
Created the instance of the current class.
Flight info and setup visibility of the class as true.
Visibility of that object is through too, so that the window must be visible whenever we run this flight
in for class.
After that we have defined the flight info non parameterized constructor.
Inside which we have set up background color of the.
Window as white and.
Said the fun type of whole window as fond family as the homophone type as plain and font size as 13.
Setting the default close operation by within j from not exit on clause size of the frame as 860 cross
523 layout as null and its visibility as true.
Then we have defined a label f code.
Labeled as flight code.
And set the.
Fond of that flight code label font family as the humor font type as plain and font size as 17.
After that, we have set the bound for that label.
X and Y values are 50 and 100 and its size is 200.
Cross 30, adding that F code label to our J frame.
Then we have defined on the label of labeled as flight information.
Set the font for the flight information label family is Tahoma type s plane and its size as.
31.
Setting the foreground.
Color for that label by using the RGB value and the color class passing value of RS hundred green as
149 and blue as to 37, setting the bound for that flight details as x as 50 by as 20 and its size as
570.
Cross 35.
Adding that flight detail label to our.
J frame or window.
After that we have defined a button labelled as show and.
But I'm sure setting the font for it font family as Tahoma font type as plain and font size as 20.
Now we will be adding action list.
Now button.
To our.
For the baton show and we'll be performing action event a and.
His string code is equal to text, field or text.
This will fetch the text from text field and store it into a string type of variable code.
Then we have inside the try block.
We have defined the connection object by using our common class, and after that we have defined a string.
That's a string select f chord f name as r c source destination capacity class code class name from
flight comma sector where flight code is equals to code.
So where code matches, we will select these from the respective tables, flight and sector from our
database, the results that will be used to execute those queries and this table set model db utils
start table set to table model RS.
This will help us to create a table in the form of our database.
So that's why we have imported the package, which is inside of us to examine the job.
Catch block will handle any exception if occurs.
After that, we have set a bond for our button location as to when to cross 150 and its size as 120
cross 30, adding that button to our J frame and window.
Next we have initialize the table.
Its background colour as white and it's bound as location as 23, close to 50 and its size as 800.
Glow cross 300.
Then we have defined the scroll panel, so the table must be scrollable, either horizontally or vertically.
So for that we have defined the table and setting the bound for the table.
Location of the table is 23, close to 50.
Height and width is.
308 hundred respectively.
Setting the background color as white.
Adding that to over.
Jay Freeman, Wendell.
Text field.
Another text field.
Setting the mound for it.
Location has to 20 cross hundred width 200 high 30.
Adding the text field to our frame.
Then there is a.
On the label as flight code setting it font family as Tahoma.
Font type as plane font size as 13.
Setting the bond for that label.
Flight code location is 23, close to 20, and its size is 126.
Cross 14.
Adding that label to J frame window.
After that, we have defined another label that is a flight name.
We have set the font for the flight name whose font family has Tahoma font type as plane and.
Size 13.
After that, we have set the bound for the flight.
Name location is one 1245.
Comma 220.
Size is 120.
Class 14.
Adding that to our j frame.
Then there is another label source labeled as source.
Setting the font for the source whose font family stoma font type is plane.
Font size is 13.
Setting bond for it, whose location is to 75, comma to 20 and it sizes 104 cross 14.
Adding Labor to our frame.
After that, we have defined the J label destination, which is a new J label labeled as destination
setting the font for it.
Font family is Tahoma.
Font size is 13 and font type is as plain.
Setting the bound for the.
Our destination label location is 367, comma 220 and sizes 120, class 14 adding the destination to
our DJ frame under the label as capacity.
Setting the font for it was found families Tahoma font type is plane and font size is 13.
Setting the bond for the dos location is for 97 comma to 20 and it sizes 111 cross 14, adding the capacity.
To our frame, our window.
Then there is another label as class code setting the font for it labelled as Tahoma sorry whose font
families Tahoma font size is 13 and font type as plain.
Then there is a class code which is the label setting bound for it whose location is 557 close to 20
and its size is 120, class 14.
Adding it to our frame at last we have the last label labeled as class name.
Also setting the font for it was font families.
Tahoma font size is 13 and font type is as plain setting.
The bound is whose location is seven and comma to 20 and its size is 111 cross 14.
Adding the class name to our frame.
Setting the default close operation of the frame by using j from j frame height on close and setting
the size for it, which is 900 plus 657 the visibility of the window S2 and setting the location of
the window as 400.
Comma 200.
So this is about flight info java class which will be used to.
Have a look on the information of all the available flights and our airline system management.
So let's have a look on the run of this project.
A run of this class.
So I'll be running from the login again.
Let's run the login file.
I'll be entering validating.
My username and password.
That's the dashboard page.
From here, I'll be flight info.
So this will be the output of the flight info class.
This is the output.
We can enter flight code here and click on show that will show the.
All the.
Details of the flight which you have entered here.
So that will be the output of the class.