So in this video, we will be talking about the next three classes, which is book intensity gap, fill
the Gap and will enter the gap.
So the first class is about inter-city cab.
It is defined inside the package cab booking system.
We are imported the necessary packages.
After that, we have defined the class intensity gap, which is extending the frame.
Inside, which we have a table type of instance named as table.
Then there is a J label instance, three G label instances, and there is a buttons, three buttons
and two choices.
After that, we have inside the main section, we have defined the called our class with the null values
and then we have defined our parameter constructor book intensity gap with the string username, set
the title as book gap.
And after that we have to get content paints at the background color as white and set the default close
operation or for that window.
Then there is a label for both Intercity Cat for which you have set the as blue and set the font family
and type for that label and edit, set the size and location for that label and edit that or frame after
that.
Set the layout as null.
And inside the source label we have restoring the source and setting font family size for that and adding
the location and size of that label.
And after that, we have added that source label to our.
Frame.
After that, there is a destination label we have defined for the destination, setting its font bound
and adding that to our frame.
After that, there is a choice instance we have setting a location size and adding that to our frame.
Similarly, for the C2 choice.
Then there is a label for the name setting its font, its size, location, adding the doorframe.
Similarly, there is a label setting as font size and adding that to a frame.
Then there is a label for the user name, setting its font size and adding that frame.
Then there's a label setting its font size and adding that also over frame.
Then inside the tree block what we are doing, creating a connection, executing the query.
Select a string source and destination from the intensity table and we are adding all those sources
and destination into our of choices.
Then we will be executing query select extract from account where username event will match and we will
print the user name will label tenant tenant label respectively.
Name and user name of the.
Customer.
After that, there is a label for the type setting its font size and adding that to our frame.
Then there's a label choice C3 for which we can select the type of the card that can be my micro mini
or SUV type of cars for the intensity caps.
So then after that, we are setting the location for that choice and adding that to our frame.
After that, there is a show button for the details setting as background color for color and setting
its size and location and adding that to our frame.
After that, there are a label for the card setting its font size and adding that to the label.
Then there's a label setting its font size, adding that to our frame.
Then there is a label for the driver setting its font size and adding that to our frame.
Similarly, there is a label setting its font size and adding that to our frame, a label for the price,
setting its font type, family size and location and size, and adding that to our frame.
After that, there is a label for that which is storing null value, setting its font size type and
ending that total frame.
Then we have loaded an image to make the page attractive and added an image to the label.
Setting it font, setting its size and location and adding that to our frame.
After that, there is another label for the different number, setting its font size and adding that
to our frame.
After that, there is a label, a label setting its font type size family and its location and size
and adding that to our frame.
Then there is a random variable R, which will be used to generate a reference number.
After that, in the show button, we have defined public void action performed inside which we have
stored the selected items from those events to our source and destination.
Then we have created the instance of our connection class and stored the two queries.
SDR inside the and SDR to the queries will be select as from customer, where username will match and
select asset from intercity, where destination and type will be matched from the 33. get selected item.
We will be executing a string to query and after that, for the next row in that table from our database,
we will be setting the values of L six and L four labels with the driver, price and car name.
And after that we will be executing the STR query.
For that we will be setting the name of the user in our written label and in user name in our L 12 label
can block the landline exception.
If occurs, then there is a button vocab foreground, color as white and background color as back setting
its location and size and adding that to our frame.
For that button, we have stored the selected items from the choices and text in our different string
variables and created a connection with our classes.
And we will be executing the query that delete from the app.
So we'll be deleting all the previous values.
In our interactive table and we will insert the current values or the fresh values which will have just
inserted by the user and which will be stored in our Interac app.
Then we'll execute that query.
And so the dialog box that can book successfully.
After that, there is a back button for the console which will help us to create the set, the visibility
of the current window as false, and then the sizes aged 60 plus 600 and its location 500, comma 2020
and its visibility as true.
So this is all about the intensity cap from which we will be working intensity types of caps.
Let's go to the Billboard cap to Java file, which will help us to show all the interest types of cap
details.
So this is a cap booking system defined inside the package cap booking system.
We have imported the necessary package for this class and we have defined extending the frame.
And then there is a private type of panel content and choice.
Even inside the main function, we have defined the public void method inside which we have created
the current and current instance of the class and set the visibility as true.
Then we have defined its parameter as constructor.
Set the boundaries for 50 comma 20 2000 size will be one fifth 1050 cross 600.
After that, we have loaded an image and scaled this instance and then added that image to our label
and set its size and location for that label, adding that label to our frame.
After that there is a label named as well cap details and setting its font family size and setting its
location and adding that our frame.
Then there is a label, a customer name setting its location size and adding that to the label.
Then there is another label setting this location size, adding that label.
Then there's a label named as driver name, setting its location size, adding that to a label, setting
another label, setting its location size, and adding that also to our label.
Similarly for the source label, destination label, car label, we are doing the same thing and for
the ID label as well, just the location for each and every label will be different to formatted better
in our window.
Similarly for the phone label, address label.
Then there is a label for the price label arriving in label reference number label and.
Then inside the tribe.
Look, we have created the connection and we have executed the result set very inside which we are passing
liquids select extract from an app where username will match.
So from the Interac app we will be selecting the user name and for all the records for that particular
record where the username will match, what we are doing is we are storing the values in our null labels.
L2 Inside l23, four, five, l, nine and l 11.
After that we are executing the query that select extract from the customer will user name will match.
So for that particular username, we are restoring the values in L1 in name in L1 ID type with the reference
number in L six and inside L seven phone number and inside L address.
It will be used to define the random number and then we will be closing the connection.
After that, there is a button exit which will help us to move back from this window.
Similarly, we have defined the action performance inside, which set the visibility of the current
windows false and set setting the location size for that window.
Background colours black foreground colour is white and adding that button to our content pane and background
colour as white.
So this is the will book, the Captain Java file.
After that, there is a blue intensity gap.
So with the help of this class, we will be having a look at the gap of type intensity.
So this is also defined inside the package.
Lookup booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages.
I defined our class, which is extending the frame.
There is a content pane and see my choice inside the wide run method.
We have defined the correct distance and the visibility has to.
After that we have defined its parameterized constructor and set the size and location for the frame.
Then we have loaded the image to make the webpage application page more attractive and adding that image
to our lens and label and set the location and size for that label.
Adding that label to our frame.
Now similarly, as we have did that, I added the details in our book CAP.
We are doing the same thing in the inner city boot camp.
The only difference will be I'll be showing you.
Till then we are adding a label, its font, family type size, setting its location and adding that
to content.
Similarly, we are doing for the here for the customer name.
It's a label in which the customer name will be stored from the database.
Then the driver name its respect on a label, then the source label.
It's respect to the label.
Similarly for the destination, it's respect on a level car name.
It's respect on a level.
Then there is a type.
Now this label is new because in intercity vocab there is a type of the cars as well.
So the type can be of a mini micro or SUV.
So that label is extra here in this class and then it's respect to label for that type.
Then the phone number of the user, it's respect to label and it's address, it's respect to label price
and respect to label for the price arriving in respect to label for the arriving in label, then there
is a reference number, respect to label for the reference number.
Now we have created the connection statement, connection and stance of our icon class inside the results
and we are executing the query select extract from interactive where username will match and we are
storing the respective values like drive value of the name of the driver in L to source an l three destination
in L for car name in l five type in l six call price in l nine and car reference number in l11.
Then we will be executing the query from selecting extract from customer where user username will match.
So what we are doing in this is storing the value of one a name in one phone in HL7 and addressing it.
Then we have defined the random variable are.
Four the minutes to generate few minutes in which the car is arriving.
Then we will be closing the connection.
After that, there is a button exit in which we have defined the set visibility of the current window
as false, setting the bound location and size for that window.
Background color and foreground color for that button.
And adding that button to our content pane.
And at last we have defined.
The complete color for the background window as white.
So this is all about the three classes which we have discussed in this video.
These classes were booking the intensity gap, showing the details of the intensity gap and then showing
the details for the build intensity type of mode gap.
So this is all in this video.
We will be talking about the next classes in our next videos.