So in the previous part parts, what we did is we creating we created one class with some scanner method,
private strings, first name, last name, department email or the email generation application.
Or we can say email administration application.
Inside this we created one constructor name as email.
We created some methods for generate email asking departments, then generate random password.
This is a very important method to how we are using random thing here.
Random is user not.
It's not user defined, it's system defined.
Or we can say java defined already library in Java then set password here.
This is also very important and I can say for this very lengthy part of our project.
So what we did is from the user, it will ask for password, it will ask for the current password.
If password matches, it will tell that user you can change the new password, but if not, your current
password is wrong.
It will throw that error incorrect password and you will be out of the that part.
So.
Let's see how we can use this part, like how we can run this part before that we are not running this
part.
But if you want to run this part, you need to create main method.
So why I'm using your object oriented, you can see this is email.
I can just put this like I created main method here and I can invoke this, but it is not very good
practice as this code is already very lengthy as you can see.
Now, what I can do, I can create one another class in that I can create one object for this email.
It will very helpful to execute also and very helpful to understand including this.
I can use that methods again then again.
So this is very significant method in Java for the object oriented design.
Now how we can create one another class is very simple as we created that email class.
Now similarly like that, just go to this email package, email package, right click here.
It will give the options.
Wait a minute.
Right.
Click here.
This part.
This should give your all the options.
Now, wait a minute.
It will take time to load everything.
This right here.
As you can see, new part I want to create Java class here.
Java class.
And I'm going to put names, email.
At.
So as you can see, both in other similar package and our app is created or our classes created this
package email app and our app is created.
So before proceeding with this, I will import the important method import java dot util.
As you can see, this is very important library and we are already done with this library.
No.
In this, I'm going to create a main method which is basically PSV and public static void public and
it will run our program.
Again.
I'm going to create a scanner.
A see.
Or you can say it's similar to that scanner.
System not in.
Yeah.
Then after this.
What I will do.
I will ask for a user to put your name and their first name.
Then string.
Written string.
If Nim is equal to a lot, also is not next.
So or you can use next line also here or you can use next year also.
So I'm going to use next only not the next line or something.
Then again system dot dot println.
Enter LastName.
And then lastly.
Then
string.
Any name is equal to as dot.
Next.
That's it.
So we are done with this.
Now I want to create some.
New employee.
I want to generate new employee.
So we already created this email.
Now I want to invoke it this class to this class, that email class.
All I can do is I will first put here, like in here only.
Oh user.
In full.
Like this.
No.
Creating object.
Or.
E.M. Glass.
Email that email part e mail M1 or I can say object one I'm going to put your M1 is equal to new.
Email.
That's it.
But remember, before that, what I'm putting is here problem is this this constant constructor, first
name and last name.
That's why I'm asking user to put the first name and last name.
So I will put here like this.
If name.
And that last part.
Now.
There is no error in this part.
So it will generate new.
First name and last name.
But before that, you remember we created too many methods for generating new password and then alternate
mail mailbox capacity.
And we are going to go to further also to see how we can proceed with this.
What I can do is I will put your choice.
I'm putting you is equal to minus one because you can use it to flag also thing.
But I want to invoke it again and again.
So for this I will use do y loop do y loop is similarly like that we created already system.
Dot dot println.
Then in this next line that starts to start something like then enter your choice or symbol.
Again, I'm putting Slash in here.
And this is only for the what I can say.
Do you part or not?
Did you?
But for some user interface only.
Want to show info.
I'm putting it like that.
When?
For sure.
In full.
Then.
Two for change password.
Three, four.
Change.
Mail box capacity.
Smashing.
Fought for money to build the spaces.
Set alternate men.
And FYI for exit, I want to create one exit method also by front exit slash and you exit.
That's it.
Now we are done with this.
Now inside this, do I?
Look, I'm going to ask choice.
Choice is equal to as dot next.
As this is integer part.
It's not an accent switch case.
Choice.
And.
This one.
Is this when he's showing.
So, as you know, we created this variable.
Now what I can do is just m one.
That object.
Dot, we know we have method get info.
In that part, we know we have one method called get info we already created.
So I'm just using that method.
After this.
Don't forget to put brakes statement.
Otherwise it will show again and again that method.
Then this too.
This too, is.
Change password.
In one set password.
Mr..
Think again.
Yes.
Three.
In one dot.
Set male capacity again.
Break statement here.
Then this all.
What is this case for?
For setting alternate mind set.
Alternate methods alternate my only.
Back again.
Recruitment.
And I guess for you it's nothing but just for exiting part.
So what I can do is for you.
System.
Lord.
Oh, Ritalin.
Thank.
You for using system.
Or I guess it application.
And after this break.
And there should be one default condition here.
As you can see, it is very good practice to create default condition.
System.
Not.
Dot printed in.
In her choice.
And third, but.
Choice again.
Before that I will put your slash and.
To our.
This.
Joyce.
Joyce again.
Okay.
So we are done with this.
Now I want to exit this part.
Already created this file.
So while I already explain to you about how we can use.
And that for you, if I put you, it will exceed that.
So we are done with this part.
So we can run this part.
But thing is, we are remaining with our creating file and storing into that file and creating one executable
file.
So I'm going to show you or I'm going to run this part.
In simple scenario.
To running.
You can go to this also this all over the strip, top strip and you can see there is run.
Our shortcut is all shift f10 windows or you can check for other systems also.
Or you can use add configuration but simply wait.
That is you can see here that the green arrow to run this part.
So it will ask me run email about me.
So it will run this email app.
And as you can see, configuration director, it will automatically detect configuration.
It will set that configuration.
Now in this part, you can see.
All the building process here.
This is output and everything.
So what application is building?
So it will take time to compile, then configuration, then directories and checking all everything.
So as you can see.
In this run configuration, our app is successfully deployed or I can say running.
So this is a very simple app.
You can enhance it to more something like web app or something like that.
But this is just the back end of our app.
So I will put here like.
James.
My last name is.
B, James.
B only.
So new employees.
James V.
Oh, no.
What is its department?
I'm sitting through the sales department.
Now I want to show you your info.
So as you can see, he's in for James.
Don't be company, as I told you.
Name is James.
V password is this mailbox capacity.
And I'm not printing any.
So in the further part I will show you how to you can modify this also.
So this is for just, I'm sure about how we can run.
So I just stop this process.
You're only.
So let us see how we can.
Move further.
So I just created one simple scenario here.
Let us add some this also because there is some mistakes here also.
Emile said then.
New employee.
Also, there is one mistake that there is no gap between two.
This.
So this will help.
So now let's run that method again.
So as you can see, this is very back end or this is very primary.
But here what we understood that how we can create object oriented design, how we can create system
default methods, use random gems be.
Or I'm pulling for three accounting department now.
Now for this, you can see all the information.
Let us see how we can use change password and enter current password.
So this is current password.
Currently I'm copy pasting this part only because I want don't want to waste time on that.
So it will ask for me and a new password.
So I will put one, two, three.
Plus.
Password change successfully.
Now, if I'm showing the info, you can see one, two, three, plus the password is changed.
And I'm not putting any alternate.
You can set alternate.
Let's put alternate gems.
Be at the rate gmail.com.
And if I'm putting that, you can see alternate set.
You can set everything.
Let's change mailbox capacity and put in your 1000 mailbox capacity changed again, you can see 1000.
So we created this.
So this is back end part of our project.