So inside this video, in this video, we will be talking about the Puzzle Java file.
So it is defined inside the package apps and we have imported the necessary package like Java, Java
dot dot event and Java exports thing.
After that, we have defined public class puzzle, which is extending the frame and implementing action.
Now after that, we have defined the buttons b1, b2, b three, B, four, five, six, seven and B
eight and B nine.
So it is a number type of puzzle game which we'll have in which we have to set the numbers in the sequence
from like one, two, three, four, five, six, six, seven, eight, nine.
Then we have set the static and count variable as it goes to zero.
Then we have defined the two labels, Albi and Albi two, and there are the long variables before and
after.
Now we have defined the non parameterized constructor of this class.
Highlight it as puzzle game.
After that, we have defined the label LBW so that it's bound as location to 30, comma 50 and its size
as one eight across 20.
After that there is another label limit to its location is as 230 comma 100 and its size as one comma
20.
Then for we have defined the button for a label as one and set its location.
Similarly, we have defined the button for the two to its location will be 110, comma 510, sizes 50
plus 50.
Similarly for the button three, its location will be 170, comma 50.
Then there is a button null labelled as nothing.
That's a button.
Its size will be 50 plus 50 and its location will be 50.
Comma 110.
Then there is a button five labeled as five.
Its location.
110110.
And its size is 50.
Comma 50.
After that, there is a button six labeled as six.
It's bound will be 170, comma 110 and its size will be 50 plus 50.
Similarly for the button seven, we will be having its size as 50 plus 5000 pounds, 50, comma, 170
and then the button 811011 700 size is 5050.
After that, we will be there is another button button nine which is labeled as for its bound will be
one 7170 and its size will be 50 cross 50.
After that, what we are doing, we are adding all of these buttons.
Then we are adding these labels and buttons to our frames and setting the size as 400, comma, 400
and the layout as null and setting the visibility as true.
After that.
What we are doing is we have defined the action, the method by passing the action event object into
it.
And if the count is, it goes to zero.
If the count is close to zero.
We are stating before it goes to system that current time is.
This will set the current time into the for variable which is of long time.
Then set taxes goes to total clicks.
So in this level we will be showing the total number of clicks which the user will be clicking on to
change or set the current puzzle to correct them.
A method or a sequence like one, two, three, four, five.
So for that we will be clicking and we'll be showing its total number of clicks.
You have performed well now you don't get resources.
It goes to be one of the resources from B one.
What we'll be doing is setting the spring label as it goes to be one point get text and if the way to
get text is goes to null, then be two dot set text or we will be setting text off label and we will
not set text or null.
Now if we don't get text as equals to null, what we are doing is setting before the set text label
and be one set text null.
Now if the button resources from V to.
Then we set the label as be to not get text if the people don't get texts.
So we will set and set text to label and we will be to set external tonal.
If the three don't get text is equals to null, then we will set the better target.
Set text is equals to label and b to null.
So if b five is null, what we are setting b five to the value, setting value to the B five and B two
to null.
Now, if the source of button is from V three, what we are doing is is storing inside the label.
Pete.
We get text and.
If the veto is null, then we will set the value to the B-2 and make the B three null.
If B six is null, then we will set the value to B six and make the B three null.
If the.
Source of the button is from V4.
What we are doing is we are installing a light bulb for point, get text into our existing label.
If we want to get text or DOT equals as equals to null, then we will be doing the one point set text
to label.
So we will set the text in the be one equals two label and before the set text to null.
So we'll be making the value of the before as null.
Then v seven dot get text is equal to null.
Set the BB7 set text to label and we make the default set text to NULL.
After that, if I don't get text or equals to null, then if I've not set text as goes to label and
before the set text to null.
Similarly, we are doing for the b five is storing the b five dot get text in our string label and then
if the b two dot get text as equals to null.
We said the bar to set text label and be five set text null if the B4 is null.
We will be setting a value of a string in before and setting the b five as null.
After that, if the b six is null, what we are doing is setting the value in b six and setting the
B five as null.
If the B eight is equals to null, we will setting the label in be it and set the text for the B five
as null after that eight point get source is equals two equals to be six.
Then what we are doing is a string label is going to be six to get text and be not get texts was to
null.
Then what we are doing is being in set text to label and making the basics null.
If b three is null, then we will be b three dot set text as equals to label and b making basics null.
If p five is equals to null, then we will set text label.
MI five subtext to label and music starts at Texas Coast Tunnel so why we are doing it's for every button
like whenever we click the button.
So there is only one gap space.
It's suppose there are nine or ten values, so there will be one gap space.
So for one gap space, whenever we click on a button, so button, we'll move to that gap.
Space and gap will move to the upper place.
So for every button we will be considering all the scenarios and we'll be doing these things like if
B five dot text is null whenever the button b six is pressed.
So if the button V six is pressed and V five is null.
So what we are doing is setting the B five label.
So where we will be finding the null will be placing that button six to there.
So what we are doing is setting the B five point set text label so the base value of the B six will
be placed in in the place of the B five.
And what we are doing is making the B six null.
So because the value of basics have been moved to the B five and so now the null value containing button
must be six.
So this is how we are considering all the scenarios for that particular puzzle.
Similarly we are doing for the button salmon as well is turning its value into the label and before
dot get text is close to nulls.
If v4 is null then we will be storing the value of the B7 and V four and making the B seminal.
If B eight is null, then we'll be storing the value of B7 to be it and making the B seminal.
Similarly for the B eight.
What we are doing is is storing the value of b it in label and if the B9 is null, then will restore
the value of b it in re nine and set the B8 as null.
Similarly, if the B7 is null, then we'll set the value of B8 in b7 make the B8 null.
If the B5 is null, then we set the value of B.
Five said the value of B five, sorry, b a to B five and B eight as null.
So if the get resources from B nine, what we are doing is storing into the IT label and if B6 do not
get taxed as equals to null, then we will be set b six to the value of the B9 and make the B9 to null.
After that, if we don't get taxed as equals to null, so we'll be setting b eight to the value of the
B9 and make the B9 as null.
After.
So this is the after valuable in the before variable we have stored.
Let me see you.
So this is before is equals to system not current mills.
So this will show the current time in store in the current before variable and after the completion
of any one of these operations inside.
If a statement what we are doing is after this goes to system current mills so this will again store
the current time in the after variable.
Now long second is close to after minus before four divided by thousand.
This will be calculating the seconds and LP two point set text.
So in the label to we will be showing the time which you will the user will be using to complete this
puzzle.
Now if we want to get taxed as equals to one two.
So this is the correct format.
So inside the basement we must have one in.
We two must have two in b three must have three B for must have 4b5, 5p6, 6b7, seven, b eight,
eight and b99.
So this must be the correct format.
And inside the B nine, we must have null value.
So this for this current format, if we found that correct format.
So what we are doing is we are showing the dialog box like congratulation you want and we will show
that Total Clicks which will be stored in the count variable and the total time in seconds which we
have stored in our second variable.
After that we will make the count as close to zero before it goes to zero and after as it goes to zero.
Now inside the public static void main, we have called our new puzzle.
Uh, glass.
And so this is all about our puzzle class, which will be a number puzzle game to set the numbers in
the required format and desired format.
That is one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So this is all about from.