So in this video we will be talking about the more classes these are deposit class and withdrawal class.
So let's start.
So this in deposit class will be used whenever a customer or account holder will deposit some account
in it's in his account.
So this class is defined inside the package bank.
We have imported the necessary packages like a Java JWT, which will help us to create graphical user
interface for this class and a blue dot event which will let us handle events on our buttons.
And then Java starts thing which will also is a modified version of JWT class.
JWT package and then total package.
Then after that we have defined the hourglass deposit, which is extending frame and implementing accent
listener.
Now inside this class we have two text fields that is 22 and we have two buttons B one and bb2.
So there are three buttons, b one between B three.
Then there are three labels as well.
L1, L2 and L3.
Then there is a string type of variable, a pin.
Then inside the deposit.
A Parameterized constructor.
We have passed that a string variable pin.
And what we did is is to store the past variable of pin into the current instance variable of a string
type of variable pin.
So after that, what we have created an image icon with the help of the class loader that gets system
results by passing the argument of the location of that image.
Now, after that, we have scaled the instance of that image and set its size.
And after that we have again stored that image into our image icon object type three, and then we pass
that image.
I can object to our label L three.
After that, we have set the location of the label that is zero zero and its size will be 960 cross
1080 and adding that label to our frame.
What we did after that is we have defined a label named as interim and you want to depose it and set
its foreground color as white.
And after that we have set its font properties, font family system, font type is bold and its font
size is 16.
After that, we have defined a text field to one and set its font properties like font families.
Railway font type is bold and its font size is 22.
And next what we did is there is a be one button deposit.
Labeled as deposit and there's ab2 button labelled as back.
So these will be the two buttons which will handle events.
Then we have set the layout as null and after the way that we have set the bound or location for the
L1, so its location will be 190, comma 350 and its size will be 400 cross 35 and added that to our.
L-3 then we have defined the text field and its bound.
So it's bound will be 190, comma 420, but its location and its size will be 320 plus 25.
And then again that added that text field to the L three.
After that, there is a setting the button bound for that button location will be 390, comma 558 and
its size will be 150 cross 35, adding that also to over L three.
After that, what we did is there is a setting bound for the button to its location will be 390 comma
633.
And its size will be 150 across 35.
After that, we have added that button to our label L three.
Now we will not add action, so we will be adding action in this one button as well as for this be two
button also.
After that, what we are doing is setting the size of the frame.
Like 960 across 1080 and after that setting the recorded property as true, then set location as 500
comma zero.
And after that we have set the visibility as true.
Now inside the action performance method, we are passing an action event object E and inside the drive
log we have defined a string amount which will fetching the details from the t one text field and get
with the help of get text method method.
And after that we have defined the data object.
Now if the source of the event is from B1, then what we are doing is if the get text equals null,
we are showing that please enter the amount you want to deposit.
So if the amount deposit text field is null, then we will show the message that please enter the amount
you want to deposit.
Otherwise, what we are doing.
If that field is not null, then we will establish the connection with the database with the help of
our database class, which is gone and we will execute similar text, then execute, update and pass
the query which is inserted into bank value.
So bank bank will be I have told you that bank will be storing the values whenever a user or account
will.
Deposit some values into into his account.
So that will contain the values, pin data and amount.
So these values will be inserted into the bank table and we will show a message dialog box that the
amount which he will she will enter at will be deposited successfully set the visibility of the current
window as false.
And we will move back to the control of the program, to the new transaction class and set the visibility
as true.
If the source is from B2, then we will set the visibility of the current window as false and pass the
new transaction.
Call the new transaction class and send the possibility of that classes through now inside that inside
the cash block.
We will handle an exception if occur and inside the public static void main, they will be calling the
new deposit class with the null values and send the results to.
So this is about the deposit class.
Let's have a look on the withdrawal class as well.
So this class is also defined inside the package bank.
We have imported the necessary package, our JWT, which will help us create the graphical user interface
Java JWT event which will help us to handle events over the button's Java exports thing, which is a
modified version of the JWT package.
Then Java util date which will help us to create an object of data and Java exploit aspect which will
help us to establish connection with our database and interact with the database.
Then this is a public class withdrawal which is extending the frame and implementing excellent listener.
This this class containing two text field 22 and three buttons, B1, B2 and B three.
And there are four labels and one, two, three and four and a string type of variable pin.
Inside the parameter constructor of the bedrock.
What we are doing is the setting, the current instance of into to the past instance of a string variable
pin.
After that, we will be adding an image icon with the help of class or get system result and pass the
location of the location of the picture which we want to is stored then storing its size with the help
of image icon.
Again storing that image into the image icon and adding that image to icon to the label.
Then we have fixed the location for that label, which is zero zero, and that size will be 960, 180,
adding that label to our frame, what we are.
So this label one is showing that the maximum withdrawal is 10,000.
Setting its foreground color as white and setting its font as font type familiar system font is bold,
type is bold and size is 16.
Then there is another label as please enter your amount and its foreground color will be color of white
and its font will be of family as system type as bold, and its size will be 16.
Then there will be the respective text field for the entering amount and its font.
Properties will be like railway font bolt and its size will be 25.
Then there will be two buttons with draw button and a back button.
Setting the layout of the frame as null after that, setting the bound or location for the label as
190 comma 350 ended size will be 400 across 20 and adding that two over three then setting the bound
for the L to those location will be one 9400 in size will be 400 cross 20 adding that 1203 Then there
is a setting bound for the event text field whose location will be one 9450 and setting its size as
330 cross 30.
And then there is a button with one setting bound for it will be 390, comma, 588 and its size will
be 150 cross 35.
Then there is a button b two whose location will be 391 or 633 and its size will be 150 cross 35 adding
that to our L three.
Then we will be adding the action listener to our both of the buttons, setting the size of the window
as 90, 61, 81 080 and setting the location as 500 comma zero.
Set the recorded property of the frame as true and the visibility as to.
After that inside the action perform method.
What we are doing is.
Inside the trialogue, we will restoring the text filled from the table into account and creating a
new date object.
And if the source of the event is from B1, what we are doing is if the text field is null, we will
show that presented the amount you want to withdraw.
And inside the block, inside the we will create the object of the con class and inside the results
that are as is equals.
To see one point as execute query select extract from bank where pain is equals to pin.
So this will be executing the query and updating inside the bank where the pin will be matched and end
balances equals to initially will be zero and while asked next as we iterate over the record for that
particular pin and if I start get a string mode dot equals deposit.
So if the mode is equal to deposit then balance plus integer dot pass and get the string amount.
So we will be storing that amount in our balance integer variable and if otherwise what we are doing,
we will be subtracting that balance amount from the result set into the balance.
And then what we are doing is balance is less than integer percent.
So if the value of the balance is less than the amount, then it will show that amount in sufficient
balance.
Otherwise what we will do is we will execute the insert into back bank values, pain, date, withdrawal
and the amount.
And we will show that the dialogue box that debited successfully set the visibility of the current window
as false and call the new transaction with the argument pane and send the visibility as false.
If the source of the button is from B to what we will do to close the current window and open the new
transaction with the window, with the and with the pin value and set the visibility as to inside the
cash block will be handling an exception if occurs.
And public static void men will be handling new withdrawal with the null values and set visible as true.
So this is all about the three classes.
Sorry, there are two classes.
Deposit and withdrawal.