So here is the employed Java file which is defined inside the package hotel, adding the necessary packages
which are required.
In this class.
Now, here we have defined the class which is extending the frame and initializing the connection variable
as null.
Then we have here a panel labelled as content pane or table, and for more panels here, these are the
private instance variables of this class.
So inside the main function, we have executed the event queue to invoke later.
Reasonable method void run.
Define the void run.
Inside which we have created the current object of this class and setting its visibility as true.
Now, inside the closed method, we have disposed to this window.
This will close the window.
Then there is the parameter non parameter constructor which is throwing a SQL exception.
If any occurs, then there is a default setting the default close operation of this window which is
exit on closed, setting the bound for it, creating a new panel, setting the bound for it, adding
that panel to the frame, setting the layout of the panel as null.
Then there is a table setting the bound for the table, adding that table to our panel.
Then there is a button as load data adding action listener to the load data which will be handled,
handling the event on the button, initializing the connection with the database, selecting a strict
form employ, executing the query which will fetch all the record from the employee data.
As this button will be used to see the data of employer.
So this will be executing the query and fetching the record from our database.
And this will this statement will set the.
Model of our table.
Then there is a setting.
We have set the bound for the button and its background, colour and foreground color.
Then we have added that button to our panel.
Next button is exit bag button adding action performed method defining for it.
So it will just move us back to the reception page and setting this visibility of the current window
as false.
Now for the moving we have defined the bound for that exit button background color, foreground color
and adding it to our panel next.
Next, we have label off name bound for it.
Adding that to our panel, a label as H, setting the bound for it.
Adding that to our panel, a label as gender setting bound for it, adding to our panel.
Then there is a job label setting bound for it.
And adding to that, our panel.
Then there is a salary label.
Adding bomb for it and adding it to our panel.
Then there is a label phone bound of it and adding to our panel.
Then there is a higher number.
Bound for it and adding it to a panel, similarly for the G.M. as well.
So this is the employed Java, which is used to fetch or show the record of IMPLY.
At last we have setting in the background color of the window as white.
Let's move on to the customer info class.
So package is defined inside the hotel.
We have imported the necessary package.
Customer info is extending JW frame connection as null j11j panel of private instance.
And there are seven labels and one table type of private instance.
Inside the main method, we have invoked the event Q Invoke letter inside which we have defined the
public void run method and.
Inside which we have defined the current object of the class, which is customer info and setting the
visibility of it as true.
And then we have defined the public quite close method which is will be used to close the application.
Then there is a non parameterized constructor of the current class, setting the default operation,
setting the bound for the frame, creating a new panel, setting border of it, adding that to the frame
and setting the layout of the panel as null.
Then there is a button back adding the action listener to it, defining the action.
Perform the event on which it will take us back to the reception page.
Setting the visibility of the current window as false.
Setting the bounds of the button.
Setting the background color of the button.
Setting the foreground color of the button, and then adding that button to our panel.
In the next we have a load data button, so that will load the customer information inside the action
performed method of it.
We have initialize the connection with the database.
A strange query which takes select aspect from customer.
Then we have using the results set object we have created.
Executed the query.
And we have set the model for the table which on which the data will be shown.
Then we have shown the set, the bound for the button and.
Setting the background color of the button and foreground color of the button.
Then we have added that button to our panel.
Then there is another panel.
I'd setting Bond for it, adding that to our panel.
Then there is a label number sitting bound for it, adding to it that our panel.
Then there is a name setting bound for it and adding to that our panel.
Then there's a gender setting bound for it, adding it to a panel.
Then there's a new table setting bound for the table and adding that table to our panel.
Similarly, for the country, bound of it and adding to a panel similarly for the room number, bound
for it and adding it to our panel.
Similarly for that check and status, that could be either yes or no bound for it and adding it to a
panel.
Then there is a deposit label, adding it bound and setting, adding it to our panel, then setting
the bound background color of the window as white.
So let's move to the last class of this video that is a manager in full class.
So this is defined inside the package hotel.
We have imported the necessary packages.
Then we have defined the class, which is extending frame connection as null.
There are one panel object, one table instance, and the food labels.
For the launching of application.
Inside the main method we have defined the public void run inside the event queue dot invoke later enable
and inside the try.
We have created the object of the current class, setting the visibility of the frame as true and catching
the exception, if any occurs.
White close method is defined inside this dot display.
So current instance will be disposed and the window will be closed by this method.
Then we have manager info class.
Whose constructor is defined here.
That is a non parameterized constructor.
Setting the default close operation for it, setting the bounds of the frame in creating the new instance
of the panel.
Model for the panel, adding it to the frame, setting the layout of the panel, then instance in the
table, setting bound of the table, adding the table to our panel.
Creating a button instance that is labelled as low data defining action performed method for the button
inside dry block.
Creating the connection.
Object.
Then we have creating a string select abstract from employ where job is equals to manager.
So this will bring the data where job is equals to manager.
So inside the employ table there will be multiple employs, but it will only fetch those records where
job fill is equal to manager.
Then we will execute this query using the results set statement table.
The set model will set the model for the table and catch the exception by using the catch block, setting
the bound for that load data button, background color of the button and foreground color of the button.
Then we have added that button to our panel.
Then there is an exit button.
Nevertheless back.
Defining action performed method to that button inside which we have a new reception, setting the visibility
of the reception as true and setting the visibility of the current method.
Current clock.
Sorry.
Current window as false.
Setting the bounds of the button, background, color of the button, foreground color of the button,
and adding the content, adding that button to our panel.
Next, there is a label labeled as name setting, the bound for the name, adding that label named to
our panel.
Then there is a label edge labeled as H, setting the bound for the label, adding that label to a panel.
Then there is a gender label.
Setting the bounds for the gender label.
Adding that gender label to our panel.
Then there is a label job setting the bound for that label, adding that label to our panel.
Then there is the label salary, adding that bound, setting the bound for the label salary and adding
it to our panel.
Then there is a label as phone setting the bound for that.
Adding that label to our panel.
Then there is a label as the heart setting bound for it, adding it to our panel.
The last label has Gmail of the manager, adding it to our bound and adding it to our.
Panel.
At last we have defined the white colour which set as the background for this window of the manager
info.
So this is all about the description of the codes of these three classes.
Let's have a look on the.
How these classes will be showing.
What is the output of these classes?
So let's run the first class employed on Java.
So when this file.
So this is look like this.
As employed.
Our file is used to load data, so when we click on load data, there should be data of the employer
should be shown.
So when we click on load data, nothing.
Comes in front of this window, we can see nothing because we haven't added any data.
So we will add data and see the complete run of this program in our last video.
So let's see the output of the second one.
Customer info.
Then this file.
So this is how it looks.
It will also not show any data when we click on load data as there is not any data till now in our database,
we have not added.
So low data will do nothing.
It will not show anything.
We close this one also.
Then manager info will look similar to the other two classes as well.
We run the file, we got it, we click on load data.
There will be no data as we have not added that yet.