Previously I told you how we already created and just here Ajax is basically asynchronous java x JavaScript
XML for you.
And we already done with this part.
So Ajax and everything is mentioned.
Now let me tell you what is the GBC database connection, which is basically Java database connection.
GBK stands for Java database connectivity.
It's a Java API to connect the database, execute the query with the database, form the update, execute
update everything related to the database we can perform in Java.
So it is a part of Java is C Java Standard Edition, gdb C API uses gdb C drivers to connect with the
database.
For different drivers, we are using currently a driver because we are performing Oracle in our database.
So let us see with this database what we can use.
We can use GBK API to access tabular data stored in the relational database by the help of gdb API.
We can say delete update fetch data from the database.
So it's basically API API to connect the GBK driver and create a Java application.
So that's the GBC.
Here.
I'm going to show you how we can develop this part.
So after doing that part related to log in, I need to create part four register for that purpose.
I created here everything related to the register, which is basically quite similar to this with address
blank and everything I'm going to mention here.
With the location, everything.
Unable to connect us over everything I'm going to mention.
So that's it.
I'm going to provide this, but this is it.
I am going to create my front end part.
So this is the register.
But this I need to create a register process.
So for this process, I'm going to create one block and I'm going to specify these names.
Now, I created this database.
If you want to create tables manually, you have to enter in the skill that commands and create tables
manually.
But I'm providing this only.
So if you want to create this database, what you are going to do is go to the service file.
Just go to this database.
Create a new connection and you can check for the Oracle, OCI or Oracle team.
You can choose and you can create new connections if the driver is missing.
You have to choose that new drivers or latest drivers.
There are different things.
You can add it here, but we are going with Oracle.
My speed is already deployed.
You can check for that purpose, but Oracle is newly deployed.
If you want to disconnect, let me delete this part also because there may be some errors.
Also when.
Doing this.
So let's see it about the services part.
But in the projects only, we need to create a register process to create registration part, then develop
this on that part and we are going to create one JSP file related to this.
So this is how I'm going to store it using this string user name.
Get parameter to that.
I'm going to specify this.
Then in this.
This is just for fronting part, as you can see.
Let me scroll upwards.
This is just for printed part.
I'm going to develop this.
But in this I'm adding one more thing, which is basically using this GVC.
What I'm going to do, I'm going to fetch some data like these.
Select these IDs and everything.
I'm going to select and I'm going to create.
So in this part, I'm going to test this as connection.
That's really simple thing I'm going to do.
Let me show you how we can.
Create a connection.
Well, first, let me delete this connection, which I already created.
Okay.
So it is not deleting.
So let me add one more thing here.
So why it is not deleting because it's currently under use.
So it's not deleting the disconnect first and let me do it.
So now you can not see anything here, but do your database.
Create a new connection.
No, you can.
You can do more because.
So this is Oracle.
Where is Oracle team?
Now you can see this is then I already added driver for this.
Please continue.
You can check for this x change this to your system name.
I in this for system only.
If you want to change, you can change.
And password is for creating connection.
Then you test connection.
You can see connection is like connection is there is a connection between this so no need to change
anything.
If you want to remember password next.
Then select ski mask.
Why is our system only fitting next?
System on default schema.
So you can say finish.
So now our database connection is finished within this.
So we don't need to create anything.
If you are deploying in a server like Heroku, you need to mention the protection which is basically
property XML in that file.
You need to mention Postgres dependency, which is related to that part.
But this is all the things how you can deploy or on this part.
So let us go to the test DB part, which is quite similar to this, which is select image from ID and
I'm going to put this and I'm going to try and put in that part.
So that's it how I can do.
But this is again JSP And also if you want to create Java file, you can create for that purpose.
So.
Again, go to the upload for uploading part.
To this day and each and every day.
Upload image part I already created here so that should here.
And if you want to use you can use this directly.
Upload a pic and everything I mentioned already here.
So now let us go to project web pages.
So connect to global clean and be.
So let's go to window and click here.
Output, as you can see.
So what?
Okay.
Forcefully unregistered.
So I registered this part and will be successful.
Close this.
Now what I'm going to do.
I'm going to run this project.
So it will take time.
In my building successful.
So.
You would do this.
Okay.
Now you can see my deployment is successful.
If I put your admin as my admin part, I can go to the admin page.
I hit enter to go to the admin page.
Sometimes you take time to scroll down through each part, but as you can see, this is loading part.
It's working very fine, very smooth.
Then this lock in place process.
And I'm going to specify this.
So if you want to check, you can check here or log process.
So this is the logging process.
Which is going to use your login process and which is going to deploy everything here.
Then currently I don't have anything there, so it's not showing me anything.
But if I go to the admin page again.
You can check if I'm using new user.
So login as admin support here admin.
I mean.
And it's log in page.
I'm going to go with to go.
So here is who I'm going to create this part.
So this is my admin page so chrome supports because I data is basically I mean this is the beautiful
thing I can go this is all the things that is the things and I can check for this register discourse,
your device, your area post report you can check here.
So that's it how I'm going to develop this for portal.
So Post Report is basically you are going to post the report with your app or anything you can do.
Like you can post your report pending executed, you can perform.
So I'm considering only your one country.
And two, if you want to add, you can add more.
Dropdown menu means if I hit logout it will be log out from my page.
Currently, my system is performing very heavy load obligations, so there may be some times in that
then administrator, if I enter new user method here, it will show me the new user.
You can add the new files.
Also, as you can see, this is all the things I can do.
Then there is one discourse forum.
Also, you can do your advice.
Also you can add your your area.
So this is just like old website for globe you can use your.
So let's see how we can develop this project.
If we want to add some more different things here, you can add.
It's your wish to add more things, but you can see please log in first.
You can do here.
Then if you status you have to view status and everything.
So that's it.
How we are going to perform this.
So I hope you understand this part in further.
So this is the full deployment of the server.
If you want to extend it more like you want to deploy on the servers, what you are going to do.
Heroku is one of the famous platform for this.
So let me show you this.
So Heroku is when I'm the cloud application platform, you can perform.
So this is the Heroku website you can perform.
So it supports many languages using these go by time and you can use Java.
So it supports which is basically Java web.
So what you are going to do, you have to sign up this first.
But let me go to the one thing here.
Which is basically documentation for part.
So in the documentation part, you can choose documentation for Java.
And in Java.
What are you going to do?
You are going to deploy.
Java apps on Roku.
So you can search HTTP port for Java applications.
You can do everything here, but remember you need to install Heroku CLI and my entry as I mentioned,
the three, you have to install that and you need to add some form or XML.
Everything is available on this Roku platform.
Once this is done, you can get the website and you can proceed with that part.
So this is it.
We are going to perform.
So I deployed it on the server, which is basically local, but if you want, you can level up on Heroku
platform, but it's needed my library, so we created a Connect Globe application using Java.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.