So we already look out this part, which is basically we created the one controller, part two handling
the controlling part.
So let me do one thing.
Let me close all these things.
We created one controller to perform the controlling actions, as you can see here.
Is for the controlling all the things we created.
One, the model which is handling the GPA part in the repository, this is the repository to store the
JPEG files and everything it's going to create.
As you can see here, this is auto wired things now in the services.
I created one service with list which is going to scroll in that list with some gate, all employee
save and all the things here.
And this is one another method which is implementing this interface as a class here and which is calling
all those things and putting the data here.
And this is my main method which is going to run and doing everything.
So as you know, this is the stuff I'm going to create, but I haven't mentioned how we can create the
database.
So that's the.
Come back in part here then.
Now let us see.
I created one front in part also.
So go to resources here, as you can see, go to the resources tab and here resources in this then go
to the templates, create one folder directory templates and create these three HTML files.
So I will explain what are these three HTML files here?
First is in html.
Remember the loading should be indexed dot html always type with team leaf as my ex html thing here
with head employ management system I'm mentioning.
Then this is the stylesheet I'm mentioning which is bootstrap stylesheet with some SHA256 integrity.
You can check online that part.
I'm mentioning the employee list employees list with the show new employee form current page.
So these are the team for each of things I'm accessing here.
Then list of employees, total pages and current page I'm mentioning.
If your page is exceeding more than this in the new employee, it's very simple again form which save
employee as my thing.
Then I'm mentioning this and update employee for the updating part I'm going to create here.
It's truly, as you can see here, this is for the updating part.
So these are the all the things related to how I created the front end part here.
So you can use these directly and these things are very important.
The same employee I'm accessing the methods with the objects.
So remember the annotations, dollars, symbols, then sometimes stars.
You need to find the hidden part with text and controller and I'm giving the button with some this class
which is already default in this stack but with bootstrap BCD and you can check here with the back of
home page by the slash page.
So that's it I created.
So let us see how we can create one database here.
So for the database, what you needed, you needed one.
My skill workbench.
I'm using my skill thing so it's very important.
You should need by my skill or otherwise you can choose your software.
You need localhost server because I'm accessing the localhost database only here.
So let us see how we can create here.
So let me create one database first.
Here, create.
Database.
So it will give me the database here.
I'm mentioning as employee.
So employee is my database.
Use database I need to mention here or you can use directly or also employee.
So I'm accessing that employee.
Yet.
I'm using that employee, so I'm not accessing again and again.
I'm going to deploy it directly.
I'm not accessing it again and again.
So I'm mentioning now create table.
So.
Merely table name as MP.
With this.
If you know the scale, you should use this.
Or idem mentioning with end.
Not.
NULL.
But I am mentioning the primary key, as you can see, primary key.
Let me move this primary key.
I'm going to mention.
Or to increment so or to increment for the increment purpose.
Default.
Now, I need to mention first name here.
And remember why I'm putting first name as this.
So if you go to the ID part and just look out your model thing.
Model the employee part here.
So this name and this name, the column name should be similar.
So I need to create assigned data source later.
But remember this name and column name should be same.
So for that purpose I'm mentioning this column name and I'm mentioning as a character.
So let me mention worker here.
Worker, let me mention this.
Or you can say string.
So I'm putting this knot in alignment and putting here not.
Then again, last name.
We were together.
Let me mention for you 500.
So it's very useful and I'm not giving the normal constraint here and email I am again giving the normal
constraint so it will again work and it's then not null.
So this is all you need to create regarding to skill sequel and with the creation of database and everything.
This is administration part and go to the schemas to choose this path.
So select all this and hit the that script of everything.
So it's lightning icon.
So in the output thing you can check all the outputs are currently creating and all the outputs are
created, but we cannot see the schemas here.
So just right click here and click refresh all.
Once you refresh all you can check your our database is here and it's showing me the all the things
ID email name.
It shows me the foreign keys also indexes so indexes is basically primary key and mentioning so everything
is now created.
So now you are you can close this because we don't require this MySQL.
So the later part how I'm going to tell you how I'm going to work with this let us move to ID so if
you closely look, we created this, I assume that we already created the database and we are accessing,
but we haven't mentioned what accessing I'm giving I'm not mentioning the properties here.
So for that purpose we need one properties part.
So properties are nothing but you can say like accessing and giving that unique database identities.
So.
Let me go to the application properties here.
Distinct application properties.
And let me mention so it's not like it's property.
So it's very simple.
My SQL database, I'm going to mention first my SQL database as my application properties in that I'm
mentioning first DB name.
So now.
Instead this db.
It's very easy spring.
Not data source and dimension.
So data source.
Lord, you are ill.
So these are the default things you need to mention.
Data source url.
Now remember while you are in gdb see again it's a java database connected only dot.
I guess you have to use semicolon.
Yes.
Simple.
In my SQL, I'm accessing the skilled database.
Then local host.
Because my mind is placed on localhost at least to check for yours.
Link.
3306 is the default port number of my SQL 3306 and your database name.
So my database name is employee.
As I told you, you need to mention the data source you are first.
Now you need to mention the driver plus name.
So it's really easy.
Again.
Spring River class name.
And wait a minute.
I forgot to mention this.
Okay.
Spinning Dot.
Driver or.
Data source driver class name, basically.
Or.
So, Michael, C.J., you need to mention C.J., not remember this.
You need to always give the C.J. thing, not your defaulting.
Then spring again.
Not.
Again this spring.
Data Source username.
You need to check.
So let me put your actual data.
So don't you use a name?
Username.
So for me the username is rude.
And Spring board data.
So it's not password, basically.
Not.
This isn't my password for my database.
So we created this, but I haven't mentioned the spring JP property, so you need to mention the JP
properties also here.
So.
Hibernate GP a proper PS you need to mention here.
So first properties spring.
So.
Expanding GPA.
Also you need to mention the strategy and everything here.
So properties don't have properties.
Dot.
I don't think you should mention, but.
Let me check whether it's there or not.
Okay.
Not to mention the spring hibernate.
Dilate my skull, which is basically my skin dilating.
So.
Spring proper.
These.
BGP properties dot you need to mention the data source basically.
So.
Data is not property.
So let me do one thing.
Database.
If we check database platform and it's my my SQL.
So you need to mention this hibernate.
Then I'm accessing some default things here.
So let me tell you, what is these things?
So these things you need to mention in the application properties, this is for the DB and accessing
the DB part here and this is for the putting the JPA and putting in the these things with the and it's
going to create a scale, show scale and everything here also.
So that's about how we can perform this.
So let us check how I'm going to deploy this.
So deployment is very easy.
Go to this.
It's actually already loaded in on the top here.
Also, you can run on this also, but you can click this top.
So this is the first time building.
So for the first time building, it will take time to build everything.
You can check your block also.
So let us check blog and let us check how it's going to work.
Ford is currently running the task and it's going to perform.
So it will take time to build.
The beautiful thing about this, it will not access the not used libraries.
It will not taken in the part of that.
So as you can see, it's passing the Java, it's creating the model and it's checking the compilation
pattern build is not successful.
Now the thing is, in the run part, run console part.
You can check or it will default in the spring here.
Now.
It will create some things and it will check here.
So wait for some time to create different things.
So now my program is finished.
I am going to tell you we need to mention some auto factory research things here.
So.
Let me check one thing here.
Okay.
So springboard application debug is enabled.
So we need to display that part also and with the entity managing factor also.
So we will definitely not going to do that.
So let us check who.
I'm going to change that part here.
So maybe there is one error with dot XML.
That's why it's giving me the error.
Sometimes dependencies are not involved directly.
So let me move to the XML.
So if you are.
No.
This part you can check here, but.
Let me put here again.
So it will analyze the bar.
It's in the scoping text and everything.
Well, again, you can check here.
It's currently loading.
So again, use the time to perform these actions.
So as you're going to see, it's the.
Different, different things.
So this is the post PostgreSQL.
So I don't need that dependency.
Then this is the springboard.
The team.
I did all the things.
Snapshots I'm adding.
Okay.
Now let us.
But then this command line again.
And let us have a look.
What is the different?
What is the spring errors?
I'm getting here?
So XML will minimize this.
So let us check whether it's going to minimize or not.
Okay.
I found the error, basically.
So let me one stop this build part.
So it's very common error.
You need to give the just this thing to.
You that look local part.
So let me do it again.
So remember, this is your URL.
You can check on that.
My skill workbench also, if it's giving the error.
Now, it will deploy it very beautifully.
As I told you in the spring, but also it will deploy directly.
Now, the spring is now running spring application.
So wait for some time to boot up the spring spring boot.
Ignore these errors because my hot spot 64 bit and it's deprecated to JDK 13 but I'm using another JDK
so there is maybe sometimes.
So as you can see, my software is now started.
It's giving the time configuration indexes, it's creating all these things with context part but with
now you can check here.
Let me show you
here also.
It's giving all the details with the Web interfaces and all the things default.
It's loaded on localhost 88 directly.
Now it's currently running and you can check here.
Port is 88.
It's always the local host.
So Tomcat is already started.
My web server.
So your thing is just basically go to your any browser.
I'm on Chrome.
They peer localhost 88 and hit enter.
So wait for some time.
It will load the pot.
Now this is my employ management system, as I told you then in this I need to mention first add employee
I need to add the employee.
So let me mention name as John employee last name as James or let me mention as ah so ah John.
Or Dot John the.
Gmail.com.
Let me hit the save button.
As you can see, I'm going to this part.
So you will ask whether this is added on database or not.
So for that purpose, let me show you.
It's already added in the database.
So for that purpose, I'm going to access my my skill workbench.
So you can check your update.
But also.
So I need to mention as John.
Not are.
Its name is John.
You.
So let me change this, John.
An update.
You can check here.
It's updated.
You can check your delete part also.
So first, let us see whether it's added on the database or is just catching from the catcher part or
the list part.
So for that purpose, go to your my skill workbench.
This is my.
Defaulting.
Connect to local instance.
My.
This is my root server.
So it is opening me.
The route server is opening for me.
So we had for some time.
So it will check whether my action is correct.
Yes, my action is connected and you can check your your.
This thing is already stored here already.
So I don't want this part because I already created the database and I don't want this.
So now what I needed, I needed to select start from.
MP This is my table.
So this is my table.
So I need to mention and let me execute this.
And so as in this you can check here or this ID is already created form you can check here.
This is my ID, John.
You, you and you.
John at Gmail is already added for me.
So let me go to the chrome again and let me delete this part.
So as you can see, there is nothing here.
And let me go to this again and let me execute this command line again.
You can check.
There is nothing here.
So my the defaulting is now working, and I'm working with the database.
If you want to add it again, just go to your ADD employees.
Now, I'm going to mention as James.
G.
Then J.
James J.
Andrade gmail.com.
I'm going to mention I'm doing the same so as you can see is added.
And if I go to the my skill workbench again, if I enter it again.
So you can check.
So let me tell you why it's putting the two here, because it's on auto increment.
So it will auto increment by default if you want to give that ID, not default the ID part.
So you need to mention that later.
But due to auto increment you need you are getting this.
So that's it about this project.
So let me give one overview about this.
What I created is just let me turn off this.
So I created the application properties.
You need to mention you are here with the class.
Name this driver name with the user username with the password.
Now the GPU properties with these.
So these things with updates on part two, these things come out.
XML is also important thing here.
So that's it.
You need to create.
So hope you understand.
And we created this project employee service.
So what you can do, you can deploy this employee service with some another database using PostgreSQL
on Heroku also available.
So this is the basic structure.
But while deploying on this, you should remember you need to change this application properties with
username, password, driver and URL.
Also, what you need to change.
You need to change the XML dependencies.
You need to add that dependencies like PostgreSQL dependencies here.
So that's available on that documentation part also.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.