So now the jetpack coalition pilot can collide with a wall or with a common object or with another baggage.
The baggage can be moved only if it collides with a circle and does not collide with another package
or a wall.
So when the packages move, it will be time to check if the level is completed or not.
So we will check it by calling our matter which we have created is completed method.
So here I will write some switch cases here.
So take switch to the variable type here.
Under this.
Start with the left coalition here.
Or for loop first hand I will take for.
Canada's first have to start.
Okay.
So we will start with the equal to zero here and I should be less than two.
Back start.
Price and I should be plus, plus and no need to take the package back to
my start site.
We need to get you the next.
It will check if so-called dirt is left.
Okay.
New snapped coalition.
You're not collusion on the parameter to the bag here.
I know this.
No dual use, so I need to give another for loop with the eight variable in the g equal to zero and
J should be less than with the back start size here and G will be incremented.
Now what can we do?
We will take back each item and just say two bags.
Now get.
G next here now we will take.
And if condition.
Okay.
So here I will write if back is left coalition.
So get the parameter to the item here and just simply return true here.
And top of this need to check one condition.
Give the back and type not.
Okay here I will kill the left coalition.
Left coalition here.
Just simply return.
True.
What does this look?
Okay, we have the.
We have got to back.
Okay.
Just simply we have to remove this first.
We?
Before that, we have to check with another coalition if back door equals item or not.
Under that, we will define this.
We?
Now, I'll start here.
Just.
Simply caught this beast here and it simply goes, okay, now we have to move our back.
Simply, we will right back.
Move with the minus space variable we need.
We need the space variable here, comma zero.
And we will call the completed matter here.
Okay.
So what else?
After that, we will return.
True?
No, we have to return.
False.
No.
Same thing which we have to do.
We will do with the case.
Right.
Collision.
So here I will try to write Coalition.
Same condition is here.
We need to check for the four.
And I is equal to zero.
I should be less than two back start size and I should be plus plus out of which we will take the baggage
bag is equal to bag store get I index and next we will check if so-called not is right coalition.
Here.
You get the argument of bank here for what it will do.
It will create an inter for loop here because a baggage can collide with a wall or of an object or another
object also means the baggage.
So the baggage can move only if it collides with the one and it does not collide with another baggage
on a wall.
So here, what we can do,
we will write.
We have the right collision here.
Okay.
We have derived what we have done in the previous year.
So,
okay, so cool.
Do try it.
Okay.
So we need to take and in the loop here with the chart variable which will be equal to zero and g should
be less than two backs.
Not size here.
My exercise and simply C++ on which we will take the package item is equal to bag start get at index.
Now here we will take if is not the bad dot equals.
Yeah.
I don't want it simply it will check with the bag is right collected or not.
So here I will write if.
Back.
Lord is right.
Coalition here.
Give the parameter with the item
and simply return true?
No.
Here.
After that it will check for the calculation also.
So go with the moral coalition and give the argument with the bad and simply the right coalition.
And a notice it will return.
True?
No.
We have to move our bag also.
So here I will give the space.
Comma zero here.
And.
Also we have to check the level is completed by calling the is completed material.
Who is completed matter.
Okay.
So we have done.
And after that, we have to return.
False.
Same thing.
Here it goes with the top and the bottom coalition to.
So next thing which we have to do is we have to complete our is completed matter.
And these are the top and the bottom.