So in the previous video we have talked about the total money and part getting it and updating it.
Now we will discuss about the total money spent.
Like if a school will pay to the teachers, we have to return it by a function.
Total money spent.
So let's write it.
So the total money spent is returned through this function.
Returns total money spent by the school?
Yes.
So this returns the total money spent by the school for paying the salary of teachers or anything like
so.
Now, suppose if our school earns 20,000 and the salary of the teacher is 700.
So if the school pays 700 to the teacher, what will be the fund left with the school?
So it would be like 2000 -700.
And this will equals to 1300 bucks.
So this part does the calculation for that only public static void update total money spent.
So this updates the money spent.
Yes.
So.
Explaining this.
Subtraction part.
Like suppose initially the total money earned by the spent by the school was zero.
So the total money earned would be like.
Oh, here it is.
Spent.
So yes, I suppose initially the total money spent was zero.
So it was written.
Suppose that the total money spent is zero zero is equal to.
Zero.
-700.
Or we can assume that in the beginning the school has spent nothing.
But when the school has earned a fund of 2000 bucks, school has now 2000 to spend.
So it would be like 2000 minus the argument past.
There is money spent.
Suppose we have spent 700.
So the output for this variable will be 1300.
This is like.
Subtracting the money spent and what is left with the school.
So, yes.
It would become 1300.
The variable will be updated with a value of 1300.
Yes.
So in this way we can construct this class of school with our teacher student.
Total money earned and total money spent throughout.
Now we have successfully completed this school class.
Moving forward towards the main class.
This is the main part responsible for running our school funds management system.
So let's begin with this.
So this main class is responsible for testing and running this Java program.
So initializing it as a main function, passing a string argument.
Let us declare a teacher object or let us create a teacher.
Let her call Samantha.
Yes.
And it is a new teacher.
We are adding the teacher to the dataset.
Yes.
And.
As far as I did not pass anything to this teacher object.
It is asking me for an ID string name and the salary.
Yes.
So get the.
As far you declare a teacher object, it will ask you for these variables until you do not declare it.
They will keep asking for it and showing an error.
So let us give her ID one.
Name her as Samantha.
And set a salary of, I think about 5000.
Yes, fine.
Now, let us add a new teacher to the list.
I will copy that data from here and paste it.
Sorry.
Bested her two times.
I'm going to add two more teachers.
So let's name those seven second teachers.
Like Mahler?
Yes.
So the second teacher is Mahler.
Her idea is to.
The string of name asks and the salary.
Suppose she gets 9000.
She is an experienced teacher.
The third one is one.
So they've.
Yes.
So the third picture is possibly currently it is three, as we haven't called it anywhere in the program.
Then we will call this.
The color will automatically change.
So name the teacher.
Set the ID and.
The expected salary for the third one is about 6000.
So now in the seminary, we are going to add a few students to this main class.
Suppose student one Name her someone.
Yes.
So we have declared the object.
Student Name that object.
Suppose the student is new.
So new student.
And in a similar way it is asking for ID name and the fees to be paid.
So yes, the ID for the mana is suppose one.
Name is.
Someone nozzle
inside a string, inverted comma, I mean, and the grade.
Suppose she scored 40 out of 100.
She may improve it later.
And why not let me copy the student variable two times, same as the teacher and name the second student.
Four.
Should we name her?
Suppose she is rather?
Yes.
The string to her name and the.
Suppose she scored 70 or 200.
And the third one is.
Jonah?
Yes.
So I forgot to change it forever.
It is to die before you die is three.
String to her name.
And.
Rates for June could be what?
50.
We can say that, yes.
So we have successfully created three new teachers and three new students.
Now where to store them?
A question may arise in your mind.
So go to the previous part and.
Remember when we talked about adding like we talked about at least remember.
Yes.
So had the use of ArrayList arises.
The significance of our list is felt here.
Now creating a list or teacher as we want to add teachers.
Right.
So, yes.
We created a list named Teacher List.
You name it, teacher list.
You can name it whatever you want to name it.
So, yes, now.
No analyst is created
list.
Yes.
So you can see that the ArrayList is imported automatically.
So that list for teacher is created now.
We will add teachers to this list.
Now that sin taxes as teacher list dot and like we were adding numbers in their demo dot java file 515
and so on.
So we will add teachers in the same way, add some money to the list, add Mahler to the list and add
to the list and Mala.
Marla.
And the third one.
Feature list, third and verse.
Yes.
So the teachers are successfully added to the list, or at least you can say it now in a similar way,
we will add students to the list.
So after successfully adding students and teachers to the list, now here we have to create a school
where the teachers and students will consist.
So let us name the school as ABC.
And this school contains teacher list and student list, which we made earlier.
Now we have to check whether the.
Function is running properly or not.
So let us add this out, that the school has learned what what the school has earned in the beginning.
So I want to run and expecting a zero output as nobody had paid the fees or nobody is credited with
the salary.
So on running.
Yes.
So the school has earned rupees.
Zero.
Perfect.
So yes.
In the beginning, the money earned by the school is zero.
So let us add something to the fund box.
It's like the Mona dot.
Base fees.
And it is what?
Peacekeeping.
Suppose he paid 60,000.
So, yes.
So firstly we have to create the spaces in the student Java, like if the student pays the fees.
What changes are there?
So yes, when a student pays fees, we have created a function for it.
This updates like let me specify this update the fees of student.
Suppose the total fees for the year is 30,000 and student pays 20,000 in the beginning.
So the amount left to be paid is 30,000, -20,000.
So yes, we have created this pay fees function here.
Now, getting back to this, I hope now this.
Yes.
So now after running this show on running this function.
We should receive an output of the fees paid by the mana, which will be the fees earned by the school.
So yes, perfect.
School has earned rupees.
60,000.
A student named Tamanna has paid the fees and it is added to the total money earned by the school.
So, yes, that's all for this.
In the next video, we will talk about adding more teachers and more funds to the school.