And see.
We have checked.
We have checked that.
And also, if you did not put or give the input to the text field, so we have to show a message.
So here we have, right?
You must like both countries and must input amount and it will be an error message.
So here we have tried the text first country and get the text if it is null and the text second country
read also done.
So we will show the message dialog here and simply what we will do.
We will check this thing and run the our program here.
So here if the user select Brazil and suppose you but do not give any input here so simply click on
convert here we get our error message information message.
You must like both countries and must out.
So what we will do, we will try 23 and simply write convert.
We started.
They shouldn't even be on Syria.
So we should remove this.
We simply run this.
So.
Notice we look at it and simply no input.
So you must select an input.
So here we will write 34 and convert and record our answer and simply click Reset.
All things are reset here.
Suppose let's choose India to Nigeria.
We write 45 and we call our answer convert and simply click on exit.
So this is all our project.