So by far in this project we have covered the download manager class and the progress render class.
Our next concern is to cover the like table model class.
So firstly, we have to create our download table model class in order to add like structures to the
table.
How actually the table model is going to look inside the frame.
So the class is created for download table model.
Now inside this class we will be like, firstly, we have to import some of the packages in order to
use the.
Components of those specific packages.
So Java utils is the first component we are going to use after this.
The second package is okay, so it is import.
And the second package we are going to use is Java string.
So import Java X string and.
After this, we are going to import Java exchange table.
So it is going to be similar.
So we will copy this and just that tab table to it.
Yes.
So Java X-Wing, table dot, Astrid.
So all the components are going to be imported.
That's why we have added Astrid to all three of the packages.
Now we will be extending this download table model class to abstract table model component of the frame.
So abstract table model.
I'm headed this.
So inside this download table model class, we will be like adding a string array for the names of the
columns.
We have already discussed that we have eight tables.
Suppose it like we had it for URL size progress rendered part speed part and average speed and after
which are elapsed time and remaining time and add the last for the status.
So we will be like creating a string array private static.
Final spring.
And square braces to.
Like initialize the area.
So column names is going to be the name for the city and the consistency of this area is going to be
u.
R.
L.
The second one is going to be okay.
So we have all of them the size in MP progress, speed, average speed and both the times it is remaining
time.
And the status.
So it is like this.
After this, we have to like set classes for each column in order to thread a specific input for each
class.
Like suppose that you are l is going to contain a string format input.
The size is going to contain like integer inputs and be not integers.
The size could be in decimal.
So we will be using like a float data type for storing the size.
And similarly for progress and speed we are using the like.
Similarly, the float data time.
Similarly for the time and the remaining time and the status is going to be a string which will be showing
downloading completed post error and all of them.
So yes, after this, we are going to contain classes for each of them.
Private static.
Final class.
And in a similar way, it is going to be an editor and the name is going to be the column class's.
Call them classes.
It is not slow.
We will be copying it from here.
And so, yes, this is, again, going to be.
So we can simply set all of them to string in order to, like, avoid any kind of inconvenience.
String takes all of the inputs, whether it be a numerical value or not.
So we will be using strings as at last everything is going to be displayed in the form of string.
So we are going to copy it and paste for all of them.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven and eight.
We have.
So we will copy it seven more times and.
And we have done it for five, six and seven.
So, yes, this is done.
We have created a string class for all the columns in the format of an edit.
After this, we are going to like create a tables list of download.
We are adding rows.
So what is going to be the method to add the URLs to the frame?
We will be using ArrayList.
We have already discussed what ArrayList is in the previous series, so I am quickly summarizing and
ArrayList is a data type which we use in Java.
It is basically a type of array, but it is resizable.
We can input any number of like data to this list.
There is no fixed size.
We can increase the size according to the need.
It is going to be like an infinite size array, so that makes it more useful.
We can use this ArrayList for storing like a thing which is not fixed to a specific like what we can
say a specific limit.
So calling this ArrayList as download and the name is going to be download list.
So download list is going to be the name of the object and a new ArrayList downloads will be created.
So inside this we are using download again.
And this is going to add the downloads to this list.
Yes.
So here we are.
We have created two arrays for all the columns in the table model.
We have created array list for the downloads.
Now our next step will be creating a new download for the table.
So a new download function we are going to create.
Now, after creating this list for all the others to be stored inside this ArrayList.
Now we are adding new downloads to that table, which is going to be like visible in the window.
So we are creating this add download function which is taking download as argument and this is going
to add that specific download to the list after which we have to like set account for all the rows like
this file table row insertion notification is decreasing the row count whenever a new download URL is
added to the account, and after which we add like getting a download for a specific specified room.
So yes.
So this is the table model.
Suppose our task is downloading and it is completed.
So what happens after this is completed?
It will be showing hundred percent here.
We will be seeing a completed in the status thing so that specific row will be downloaded.
Now no actions are need to be performed otherwise of clearing it and that specific row is like finished
action thing.
Now the next part is to remove that down, remove a download from the list.
So suppose if we want to remove the specific row, so we have to first select the download and then
only we can remove the download.
So how to get the download?
So once the download is completed or suppose if the download is taking place so we can firstly get a
download by selecting that specific row and then we can perform actions like removing that specific
row from the list.
So this is doing that only.
So after getting a specified row and removing the download from the list, that row will be removed
and the row count will be changed to minus one.
So suppose initially we had three rows, we have cleared the third row, then the row count is going
to be three minus one, which is two at the end.
After which what's left like we have covered the getting and removing our specific row or the deleting
part.
We have seen now get table columns count.
So we have like a column thing, we have eight columns.
We have already discussed it.
So forgetting the column count, we are using this get column count function which is going to return
the length of the column.
Similarly for the names we are using this string get column name function which is taking column as
the input and going to return that specific index of the column names class.
Suppose if we are talking about the status then this index of this column names, it will be returned
similarly for row count.
So we are like increasing the number of rows once we are adding a new download to the list.
So this is going to like return the size of the row which is present in the table model at present.
Now after getting all the things for columns now like discussing what actually happening inside each
of the column to check what is going to like, we are using this switch case for every column.
We have total eight cases from 0 to 7 for all the indexes of the column after which we are using this
get through.
So for a specific row we have to get all these eight columns like in a unique way.
So what you are is going to return.
So the case zero is going to return this.
You are l for that specific row.
Suppose you are talking about this first row.
So if we select the first row, we are talking about the first row, then we will be returned with the
URL, size, progress, speed and everything of this row.
So this switch case is doing so.
It is going to return all of the values of the column, things like whether it be you are the size,
the progress, render, and there are data.
But all of them like we have slowed for the download.
We are going to return the speed.
We are going to return the time.
And similarly the status that whether it is completed or not.
So all of this is coming from the Download Manager class.
We have already talked about the status and time thing.
Now our next concern is to notify the user that what is actually happening with that specific rule.
So this update is called whenever a download notifies its observers of any changes.
So we have done this in the previous part.
Also, we have used this sort of observation observable function as an argument for the update.
We have used it in the progress render, I think.
Okay.
So it was in the.
Let us check the download manager.
Yes.
So we have called this update.
Whenever there is a change, any update, then this update function is going to be called in all of
the functions.
Similarly, we are doing this for the download table model plus also and this is going to like return
the index of that specific column wherever the index is mean or suppose that it is the second row and
the fifth column.
So we will be concerned about this average speed.
One, two, three, four.
Yes, we will be concerned about the average speed update of that specific URL, which we are talking
about.
So by far we have completed this download table functions now.
Yes.
So that download table model class is completed.
Now the last part is going to cover everything which is left.
We are going to conclude everything about this code execution part in the next video and it is going
to cover about the speed time.
Like you can see that everything which is showing a red underline will be vanished after the creation
of that download class.
So it will be covering the status, time, speed and the size functionalities and we will be looking
up to it in the next part.
So see you in the next.