Okay.
So till the last part, we have covered everything about the actual listeners to the buttons save rename
new new folder on the back button.
And also we have covered how this tree hierarchy is changing itself whenever there is update.
So we were discussing about this scroll, so how this affects scrolling working.
So suppose if we expand this so this like we can say that as a vertical split between these two panels
and this will show the information on the viewport, the names of the folders or these, and it will
be adjusted self accordingly.
So we have like setting the size accordingly, the new dimensions.
Whenever we scroll the show panel to the longer space, then it will readjust its size accordingly.
And we have set opaque to force as it is going to be a translucent window.
The background is currently visible.
We can see that the background is visible from these folders blocks.
It is basically a grid layout.
All the folders are containing inside this in the form of a grid layout.
And this is how the scroller was working.
Now coming to the attic listener.
So we are adding carelessness to the application.
We are adding some of the shortcuts for like if we want to make that return button work, a keyboard
shortcut is attached.
So here is the return button.
So suppose you want to do this with the help of keyboard and not with the mouse.
Then there are shortcuts for all of them.
So here you can see that for written button we are using the backspace.
Okay.
So for add folder button we are using control and we can press control and from the keyboard and now
we can create a new folder.
Or similarly for renaming we can press controller and new of all new files.
A new folder will be created with the help of control and our renaming will take place with the help
of controller.
Similarly with the backspace or the back button will be enabled with Turkey listeners.
So we have added Krsna function in order to do so and frame validate is called here.
So what this frame validate is.
So suppose we are taking like making actions with the help of carelessness.
So the frame should also be updated accordingly.
Suppose we are creating a new folder with the help of the keyboard.
Then the folder structure should also be updated in that manner.
So for that we are using this validate.
So whatever changes taking place should be validated to this hierarchy which is already present.
So the new folder which is being added or whether we are renaming any folder or file, then it should
be updated here in the tree hierarchy directory.
So to keeping all the things in mind, we are adding functions accordingly, whether it be the key listener
or the mouse motion listener.
And also we are setting this frame to set visible to true as by default it is false now coming to the
paint component.
So what this paint component is actually doing.
So this paint component is actually taking care of how things are going to be look on the frame.
So here you can see that we are having a background image for the display panel, a background image
for the show panel.
Also, the things are appearing in a non opaque manner.
The background is visible from behind the folders.
There are blocks.
Folders are like presented in the form of a blocks layout.
So this paint component is taking care of all the graphics which are on the frame.
So here we have to draw, draw, image, function.
So this is stored for this graphics.
This graphics is also an import we have made above header.
You can see that we have imported the graphics from the Java String Library.
So here you can see that here we have already imported the graphics and we are using it now.
So yes, we are using the graphics to set the background for both the panels.
This get the image is getting the image for the show panel.
And the second one, the background download page is setting the background for this display panel.
So there is some width and height for that background which we have set in the form of graphics and.
We are like repainting it whenever a new folder or file is added or deleted or renamed.
So this background should be repainted.
Repainted is basically updating whenever a change is taking place.
So it is a kind of like refreshing the graphics whenever a change is taking place.
So this was all about the paint component function.
Now coming to the open file.
So if we have created a file or if there is a already present file, then it should be open.
So how the file is opening, that should be a function for opening the file also.
So this public void open file is responsible for opening the file.
So if file exists.
So suppose we are trying to open a file which is already existing.
Then the show panel should like.
So here is the show panel.
We want to open a file.
Then it should open that file in the display panel side.
And if the file is not in the directory, then we can return the tab undetermined, which means that
we are trying to access a file which is not present in the directory.
So if the file type is not null, then that file should be opened here.
Whether it is an image in the dot jpg format, whether it is a text file or it is a PDF.
So we should open.
If the file path is not null, there is a valid path for the file which we want to open then.
Okay.
So suppose if the file tech file is containing a text file, then a text editor should open in the display
panel where we can read the file or right in the file.
Basically, we can work in the file as a text editor, so we will be creating a read file function also,
which will open that how the read file is going to look inside the frame.
Currently, we are concerned with opening the file only.
So yes, if the file is text, then we can open in the form of a like text editor.
If we try to open a pdf, then that pdf should open in the PDF view of the system.
Okay.
So the application is not containing any PDF reader till now.
We can also try to add a PDF reader also, but right now it will try to open the PDF in the PDF viewer
of your system.
Similarly, if there is an image which we are trying to open, then it will open the image in the form
of like display panel.
It will open the image in the form of a white background, and the image will appear on your display
panel side.
If that image is supported by this application, if the image is not supported by the system in which
you are trying to open, that, then unsupported image will appear on your screen, which will say that
the image you are trying to open is unsupported.
You must have encountered this earlier.
Also, if you try to open any corrupted, unsupportable file in your system, then I cannot pass on
your screen saying that this image is unsupported.
So try opening some other image or you can try to redownload the image.
So yes, this was how this open function was working.
Open file function.
It was opening the file in the.
Applications interface.
So this statement is taking into consideration that what if the image is not open?
So when any file will open in this display panel, then this footer, we can say that will appear below
the file, which is open and otherwise, if the statement will like work, then the list of files will
appear in this manner only, and no files will be open and this folder will be attached to it.
So this footer info label will remain the same.
Whether a file is open or not.
We will try to check how things are working when we will run the application.
Okay.
So yes, and the and show pane is basically filling the show pane.
So this is the show panel which is filled right now.
Whenever we try to open a file, it will expand this key.
Suppose we are opening a file from this file browser folder.
So this is how we are filling things inside our show panel here.
You can see that for the folders we are having a yellow colored icon for all the folders for the files.
Accordingly, we are having or like basically we can call it as icons.
So for the image we are having an image icon and for all the related files they are containing icons
respective to them.
So this is very simple.
Shopping is basically for filling the show pane, how the show pane should appear, how the icon should
be attached.
So here you can see that we are having image icon.
Suppose if we have an image file so that should contain our image icon which will open the image and
the icon will be in the form of our image only.
Similarly for the folders, the folders icons are appearing in the show panel.
So this field shopping is working for the show panel side only that how things should appear.
Basically it is a tree structure.
We have already discussed it and the look is decided in the field panel function, which we are talking
about.
Okay.
So this is about all the size and dimensions of how long they should be expanded to what should be their
height and width and everything.
And this is the dimension for the.
Suppose we made that choice then the dimensions are going to be different.
They should be like slightly shifted towards the right hand.
You can see that if we expand any folder then the channel should shift slightly towards the right.
So this is how the show pane is filling, how things are like, adjusting themselves accordingly that
they should appear in a hierarchical manner.
There is also a key attached to all the folder and the key is like moving in a diagonal manner whenever
we are traversing through that child of that group.
So that is all about the show panel feeling and now coming to the read file function.
So we have already covered like this, covered the open file function that what should happen when we
try to open a file.
Now suppose we are opening a text file then how it should appear on your display panel.
So once we open a text file then it should contain a feature that we can read and write in that text
editor we have already like worked how writing and reading work in that text editor So this is the function
for reading and writing.
So for reading, suppose initially it is containing empty text.
We can try writing something and with the help of buffer reader buffer, there is a component basically
from the String and NWT Library which enables us to read whatever, whatever is present inside the text
file.
So yes, if the display panel will support, we are having a 20 line of statement and this is a ten
line of it.
Only then it should automatically move it to the next line, the ten lines in ten words in a first row
and the second ten lines in the second row.
So basically this is adjusting the content in the text file according to the size of the display panel
and now click.
Okay, so if we close the reader, then we should exit and we'll come back to this folder structure
only.
So yes, this is how it is done, how the editing function is working.
We have discussed it and if there is any kind of exception is opening the file, the readable file.
Then our error occurred while reading the stream.
Should be a pair in the form of a string which are like different.
Like describe that the file which we are trying to read is like somewhere not able to be open in our
application.
Okay.
So this read file is going to return the number of lines.
It is non, non or non void function.
So something to return.
A function should return something if it is not void.
Okay.
So coming to the right file function, we can write something inside the file, we can modify the file
and if there is an empty file which we have just created, then also we can write something on the file
and save that file on hitting the save button.
So yes, this is how the right file function is work.
So after the reading and writing file function, we are here to creating children to the root.
So suppose we are in our folder which is empty.
So suppose we are in this folder and currently it is empty.
Then we have to create children's to this.
So basically we are creating this in a tree like structure.
So inside this print the subfolders will be created.
Suppose we are trying to create four folders.
Then this will take place with the help of this create children function, which is like we have past
default table three node as the argument and definitely they are going to create nodes to that three
three like structure of course.
So yes, on creating nodes, the subfolders, maybe they can be folders or they can be files, so they
will be created inside that root, which we have selected for.
So this Create Children is working in that manner.
So this for loop is working in a manner to attach new nodes to the already existing folders or files
inside the parent.
And the self statement is returning.
Suppose we do not want to add any child then this else block will take into working and no nodes will
be added to that default.
Multiple three node function.