So by far we have covering the contents inside the frame like we have been creating the contents of
the frame by initializing the frame after which the settings panel inside the frame.
Like attaching to it.
We have set a background color to the panel.
Like initially we have created three panels.
We can take a look like this is the panel one.
This is the first panel now this is the second where it is.
So we have three panels.
This is third panel and above it we have the second panel.
So in total we have three panels till now and like buttons attached to all of all three of them.
And all the three, four buttons are functional.
Like we have action listener attached to that button and some event is going to be performed after clicking
on that specific button.
So now let us take a look at the window of running the programme and check whether everything is working
fine till now or there are any exceptions.
So let and let us take a look at the function.
So getting to this and try running Java and waiting for the programme to execute.
So yes, we have our frame, we can maximise it, minimise it, as I already told you, that the frame
is like resizable so we can resize it and it will adjust accordingly.
So yes.
So we have three panels, we already talked about it like the three panels have a button attached to
them.
This is between one, this is between two and this is between three.
And if we click like by default, that equal signal case keyboard was responsible for starting the game
with the X character initially.
So if I click here, I am getting an x symbol with a red colour and font size, then a font width and
a specific font style which we have set in the programme.
So the first button is working perfectly fine.
Now, taking a look at the second one.
So after the is chance, the chance transforms automatically to or in the next button.
And similarly for the third button, the chance is transferred to X.
So till now three panels are created, three buttons are created and action listeners are attached to
those buttons respectively.
But what is going to happen after the click of the buttons?
Like one by one?
We have covered all the panels and the buttons are looking at that here.
We have already set the font style, the font board, like the weight of the font and everything.
So in total we have like 15 buttons in the like frame, so we have to set total 15 panels and a button
attached to them.
And then actually it's not attached to that button respectively.
Now that after completing the three panels successfully getting into the fourth panel configuration
and this is responsible for creating like a new panel and we have some dimensions to the panel, some
colours on that panel is added to the frame, of course, for the functioning and panel for layout is
set to zero zero initially jailable.
And the fourth panel is what actually doing.
So the panel is responsible for like handling a label which is going to contain the score of the player.
So we have two panels for the score thing.
This is like a name of the player and this is for the score.
Updation So in this we are covering the name part like on running this, you will be get a clear idea
about what I am actually talking about.
So waiting for the execution.
So yes, this panel is created.
This is the panel we created right now.
And this player is containing a text called Player X.
And this is going to be this thing and this is going to look like we in our row and handling the score
of.
So we are done with this now.
We will close this and try to like add a similar thing for player also.
Afterwards, we will like the score updation block also for both of the players.
So you may be wondering that why I said this fifth panel, two X count set columns like this is going
to count the score of the Player X and I am setting it to the 10th column in the row as we have nine
grid layout columns reserved for the chances to be played by both the players.
So this is going to be placed like this here after the nine blocks so that this player playing like
window will not get affected by the score thing.
This is a separate thing like this nine and this six are separate thing.
They are outside the game window.
They are not going to be changed by the players anyway after this.
Like similarly adding we have like successfully added panels.
Now after this we are going to like taking into consideration that how the chances of the players are
shifting after each play play chance.
So for this we will be going to initialize a button calling it button four and new button for that,
of course.
Initially the button is going to contain empty strings and inside this we are going to like add actual
listeners.
So the button four is going to consist action listener and we are going to add action listener to the
button.
We are going to choose it from the suggestions of course, and new action listener is going to be placed.
So action is not.
Listener.
Yes, so we have actually a listener for the weekend for and after which we are going to like create
a function.
Initialize a function of course.
Now this is something.
We have placed this at the wrong place, I think.
Yes.
So there was a bracket.
Missing.
We have to place this here now again, creating the same button.
And yes, this is the actual listener added to the beeping for and what actually it is doing.
So this public void action performed function which contains action event energy zero as the argument
and the action attached to the event like we are calling the button says event and what event is going
to be performed on clicking the button?
So the game is set to start game in the initial stage.
Like by default, the game is going to start without like escaping or closing when we will hit the close
button like it will be closed after that only.
So inside this if statement we have initially like already set the first play as x and the button colour
is set to red.
Yes.
So before is set to one initially.
So suppose that the first chance is played at the fourth, like let me show you.
Yes.
So this is the fourth column, fourth button V, whatever we call it.
So when X is going to play its chance here, so we are setting a colour to the font and we are implementing
the I like the next spread is going to play that chance after that that only so before it is going to
be placed here and after it the chance is going to be played here.
Not this place is incremented.
So we have already set conditions for return one.
We tend to be two and three.
Now we are done with B10 four and I is incremented so we have total of nine eyes like I is from 1 to
9 and already we are like implementing four.
I took four.
Now if as like suppose this zero is playing the chance at before, suppose zero is playing its chances
before.
So that color that will be reflected to the text is blue and b four will reflect zero like before will
be storing zero at its place like similar this similar to this.
Yes and choose player winning game is called after this like this.
What are the minimum care like chances to be played to make a specific player wins so minimum four chances
are to be played.
Suppose X platelets chance and zero predicts chance in the second chance and after which explanation.
Now the next chance is transferred to zero.
So we have already covered like four blocks, two of a specific pair.
Now the fifth chance is going to be like the decider.
If support X has already placed two in a column and only one is left for X to make it win.
So we are calling Choose Player and winning game after this only.
And suppose the x comes in a row, then the game will be over, x will win and a popup will appear that
x wins.
Congratulations.
So now in this similar way after waiting for, we have set conditions for the beaten five and the panel
is also updating like suppose here we have a panel of 15 buttons so one two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight.
So what actually we ten six is so from the panel, it is like five, six, seven, eight like eight
panel is considering the like a grid layout of 991 was covered in the frame of panel and the panel of
the eighth one is going to be considered as held the six to be ten six.
So yes, we have retained six and after we have initialized the panel eight so we are like setting panels
and then we are setting buttons.
So initially we had three panels either on the program and show it to you.
So we had three panels and three buttons.
Now we started incrementing that thing.
We made the buttons to 15 and the panels to 15 also, and each panel has a button attached to it and
that is performing some specific tasks.
So we are like checking these nine panels first like.
Suppose the what are the actual checking of the we're checking that if a player and then a villa pair
they six are kept away in the initial state if any player even then only we are going to update the
scores.
So initially we are going to like listen to the action of these nine blocks.
And these six are like we have a complete panel, but only six or nine buttons are going to be listen
for making a player win.
So there are differences.
So we have action is not attached to all the nine buttons.
Yes, we have a like a line border, border layout and everything for every panel and between all the
actions are listen, we have colors red for the x and blue for the O's and we are choosing the player
every time, like every time action is.
Listen, every time we are choosing a player.
So suppose action is listen for the player race.
We are choosing the player o and similar way for the or like actually listen for all we are choosing
the player x and this choose player is the function we have created above hair.
So it was created very early stage I think.
So where it was.
Let me find it for you all so that we can take a look.
So here it was so like we are choosing a player.
Initially it was set to X, so by default and if X plays a chance then zero is transferred with the
next john and as X is transferred with the next.
So we are calling this choose player again and again, and after which we are calling this winning function
again and again.
So the winning function was taking into consideration that what if Player X wins and or player wins?
We discussed earlier.
So again and again we are calling these two functions.
Only inside the action is nurse of the buttons.
Now we will try to like run the program and see what are the actual frame layout till now after completing
this part of the code.