Private one line down, which we have seen in the previous.
We have the fallen Tetris piece and we finishes the falling and the piece dropped is called So here
we will create the matter one line down and name and then create parent curly bracket.
And here we will provide some condition with if is not try move with the piece.
Oh, my God.
X, comma y.
These are the current hold ups and minus one sided to the minus one.
And under this we will call that matter piece dropped here.
So it's done.
It's done.
And now we have to clear the board also.
So we.
Okay, we have already done just a second here.
We have to write the body as well here.
So what we will do, I think in the one I don't matter, we are trying to move the following piece down
one line until it is fully dropped.
So, so clear.
More matter.
First, we have to work with the clear board method and here we will write.
Just a second.
We will do we will write here a word loop.
A clear board method fills the board with empty terminal no ship.
This will later use collision detection.
So here we need the for loop.
We write int I equal to zero and I is less than to board.
We need the board height which is multiplied by the board width.
Do the posting element of I and it's done.
And under this we will set the Iot index to the equal do that drum that to me no doubt no shape.
This is right now we have to write the body of the peace drop method as well.
So here we will do the piece.
Drop method puts the following piece into the border.
So once again, the board holds on the squares of the pieces and remains the pieces that has finished
falling.
So when the piece has finished falling, it is time to check if we can remove some lines of the board
or not.
So this is the job of the remove fool.
Okay, so we have to read full, full lines, right?
So we will create another matter and limit as the remove lines.
Then we create a new piece or more precisely, we try to create a new piece under this.
What do we have to do?
We will write for an equal to zero and I should be less than two four and do the increment of the AI.
And under this we will write in x equal to call it to x plus plus piece.
Sorry, good piece and set it to dot x and provide a similar to that.
And y or y.
And here we will not add up.
We will subtract the current piece or divide and provide it to the index.
Okay, so this is done.
We have to write one more thing board and here we have to write y multiplied by board word and it will
be add up with the x.
It should be go with the current piece, not get shape method.
Okay.
This thing is done and we have to create another method.
Remove the second.
Remove full line.
So we will name it as remove full lines.
This is done.
And we will create we will see this its body afterwards and here what we will do.
We have to check one condition.
So we write if is not following.
No falling.
Finished.
So this.
We have to create a new piece.
This one.
So once again, I will explain.
Now, please draw method puts the following piece into the border.
So once again, the board holds all the squares of the pieces and remains the pieces that has finished
falling.
When the piece has finished falling, it is time to check if we can remove some lines on the wall.
And this is the job of the remove lines matter.
Then we created a new piece.
Or more precisely, we are trying to create a new piece here.
So in this map, a new piece.
What we have to write.
We have to write.
It's creating a new Tetris piece.
The piece gets a new random shape.
So then we have to compute the initial current X and the current Y values so we cannot move to the initial
positions.
The game is over the top out.
The timer is the and we display game over string containing the score on the status bar.
So what we will do, we will do.
I think.
Okay, so we have to set the current PS current.
We start set random trip.
This is done and we need current X and set it to the board width and divided by two and a total of one.
Sorry.
Add it to the one and semicolon.
And then what?
We will do the current y and set it to the board.
Height, I think height and subtracted to the minus one add of the current piece.
Greenpeace start, we need the minimum out y.
Okay, so this is also done.
So new bass method creates a new Tetris piece here and it's all done.
Now what we have to do, we have to decide the random.
No, we have to.
Firstly, only we have compute the initial current X in the current Y values.
But if we cannot move to the initial position, the game is over.
We drop out.
So we have to function the timer as well.
The timer is drop and we display game over string containing the score on the status bar.
So what we will do next, we will write.
Here, if not equal to try move on here.
We will provide the current piece and comma index comma.
Right.
And here would set it to the parentheses and read current piece with dot set shape and we check the
terminal.
Listen.
So that through me?
No, not no shape.
After this, the timer has to stop.
Here.
This one.
This thing is done and we have to display game over string containing the score on the status bar.
Okay.
So here we need the variable message and we have to write.
String we need.
It's not all.
I think it starts from the echo.
Yeah.
This one.
The format here we will write.
Came over and we need.
Score, which is your percentage?
DX This is done and here what we will do, we will do.
We will call the lines removed.
So here done.
And we have to score on the status word, right?
So here we will write status but not set text.
And we didn't write the message here.
So here these things are done and now we have to go to the tribal matter as well.
So here we have to write other things.
Firstly, we have to change the parameters.
It should be new piece.
We need the new piece.
Right.
The Prime move matter tries to move the Tetris piece.
The matter returns the false if it has reached the board boundaries or it is adjacent to the already
fallen Tetris pieces.
So here we need a new piece and it is set to the new X and it should reset it to the new Y.
Listen here.
We will do need a for loop here.
We need an eye equal to zero.
And I should be less than four.
And I plus.
Plus in this we need x equal to new x plus.
Newbies not ex with I am similar to this.
And why do new I.
Sorry.
It should be subtracted with the new piece so not why.
And give it to the eye and done.
And it should be at my mistake.
It should be add and its turn.
Now we have to change the conditions so we will write if X is less than two zero.
No.
You need some binary processing arithmetic operations here.
So here we have to write good word for word, and then this one, and then we have to set.
Why is less than zero this one?
Then why should we greater equal to good height?
I think we have good height and then we should go and return false here.
And another condition will be if she bad.
Here.
The shape and X should be the same.
And it should not be.
Be equal to that terminal or no shape here.
And under this condition, we should return.
False.
This is done.
And after this, we has to write.
We have to set the current piece to the new piece here.
So we will write current piece equal to new piece and done current x.
Equal to new X.
The current Y equals the new Y, and these are done and we have to repaint.
So we will call the method repaint and we have to return.
And it.
Now what we have to do.
We have to write the body of this matter.