So in this video we will talk about another two Java files, update product and delete product.
The update product file will be used to update the details of the product, while delayed product class
will be used to delete and record from our database about the product.
So let's have a look at the first class, which is update product.
This class is defined inside the package store and we have imported the necessary packages like import
a dot font for setting the font type family and size.
Then there is a swing j button to add any button in our frame.
Then there is a J label for adding label, menu and menu item to add any menu bar or menu item or menu
element.
Then there is a g option pane which will help us to sway any dialog box.
Then there is a J panel which will be added in our frame.
Then there's a scroll panel which we can add in our text area or any table model.
Then there is a text area.
Which is a field where we can set this property like a table or false central.
Then there's a text field to get the text from the user.
Then there is a combo box to select from multiple values.
And then there's the action listener, which will help us to perform our handle any action over the
buttons or menu item.
Then there's the key event and key listener.
Then there's the array list, which will help us to store the similar type of element in a single variable
as a list.
And there's the action event.
Which will help us to handle any event over the text area, text field buttons or.
Menu items.
After that, we have defined our update product class, which is extending panel and it is there inside
which we have a text field.
For instance, I'd field a text area, instance a text button, sorry, g button and a J combo box of
named as company or text field or label and three IDs ID detail and company and one integer type of
variable quantity to be stored a quantity of the product.
Then there is a message into the product ID and quantity.
After that we have defined the non parameter as constructor for that update product class set the frame
or layout as null.
After that, we have defined the bound for that frame 100, 100 and its size as eight 4619.
Then we have defined the label.
Update product renamed as update product set the bound for it was location will be three 2845 and size
will be 182 across 21 setting the font for it font, family font type and font size.
Then we adding that product to our label or frame, adding that label to our.
Ban a lot of rain.
Then there is another label as product setting font for it, font, family type and size.
Then setting the bound for that label whose location will be 246 comma 136 and size will be 124 across
21, adding that label to our frame or panel.
Similarly, there is another label named as product details, setting the font for it, font type font
family and font size, then adding the bound for it to its location will be to 46, comma, one, 68
and size as 139 or cross 21 then adding that product or adding that label to our panel or frame.
After that, we have defined the text field to enter the ID.
Setting bond for the tax bill.
The size will be 136, cross 20 and its location will be 449 comma 137 adding that field to our frame.
And then we have defined the.
Bacteria fail to store the details, setting the bound for it with location 449 168 and size will be
136 across 58, adding that text field to over.
Frame after that we have defined.
The scroll panel or whatever text field or sorry over the text area setting the bound for that scroll
panel 449 comma 168 and its size as 136 cross 58 and adding that scroll panel to our frame.
After that, we have defined the label a label company.
Setting bond for it and setting bond for it.
Who size is 124 for cross 21 and it's we can say location is to what is X comma to 41 adding that to
also well panel then we have defined the key listener over the ID field and then we have defined the
key type, the method or key event which is taking a key event.
E Now inside this method we have initialized our ID string variable which is equal to ID field.
Get text or trim plus eight or get keycap.
So this will get the text from our field and stored into the ID variable ID string variable also with
the character key which is pressed.
Then there is the ArrayList string data, which is a storing the values from the DB searsport id.
So we have called the search p method of the DB class by passing the ID argument into that method.
And the result of that or the return of that method will be stored in the ArrayList type of string named
as data.
Now data dot sizes equals two is close to three.
So if the data dot size is equal to is equals to three.
Then what we are doing is we are setting the details of the product in that text area field by with
the help of data zero and the quantity field with the help of data or get to and switch.
If such will be taken case of get data or get one.
And inside the get one we will be case general.
So to settle the field of the get one, which is the type of the company so we have what we have did
this case, general.
So we will select the company to get selected zero.
And if case matched and drugs, then we will select index one from the company combo box.
Either we will select that to.
So this is the key event over the ID.
These are the two key released our key press event, which are auto generated.
And after that, we have defined the button product to update the product.
We have defined the action perform method.
If the quantity field or the ID field is null, we will show the error message.
Otherwise we will be storing the ID from the ID field into our ID variable.
Typecasting the quantity from our corn field, converting it into text and typecasting it to the integer,
sorting into our integer variable and restoring the details of the product in detail variable type of
company in our company string.
And then we will call the DB dot update product to database method, which will update the product by
taking the argument added detail, company and quantity.
So this will update our product.
Which is the requirement of this class then but an update product this will set the bound for that product
location will be 449 comma 338 and the size will be 136.
Class 23 adding that button to our panel, then we will have defined the one field text field where
we will be writing the quantity.
So this is the set bound.
For that one field.
I think that compared to the frame up that we have defines the item, a valuable label setting font
for it, bound for it and ending that to our.
Panel.
After that, we have defined the company combo box and label and added the items in our company combo
box, General Maton Drugs and Nissan Electric.
So these are the.
Items of the company combo box, and this is the class of update product.
Now let's have a look at the delete product class, which will help us to delete any details of the
product.
So this class is also defined inside the package store.
We we have imported the necessary package like font J button j label panel, a scroll pane, text area,
text field color action listener action event.
After that, we have defined the public class delete product which is extending G panel that is a one
text field ID field a button button, delete, product label, L-A error and a string ID and other error
is close to enter product product ID.
Then we have defined the public delete product.
Inside which we have initialized the layout as null for the panel boundaries 100 100 and sizes 840 cross
699 then we have defined the label as a delete product, setting the bound for it, font for it, font
type font size and font family adding that.
Label to our panel.
Similarly, there is a product ID label setting font for it, bound for it, adding that to our panel.
After that, we have defined the ID field.
Which is of text field type.
Then we have set the bound for that text field, which is location is 449 comma 158 eight and it sizes
136, cross 20.
Then adding that field to our panel and set the maximum length for that.
After that, we have defined the button delete product which inside for which we have defined the action
for from the event which is taking action event argument.
A Now, if the text field is null, then we will show the error message.
Otherwise, if the text will contain some value, then we will store first the value of the ID field
into our ID string and pass that ID string to our DVD product to database method, which will help us
to delete the product from the database.
After that, we have defined the set bond method for that button.
So that location for the button will be 414 and comma to 19 and size will be 136 plus 23.
Then we have added that button to our frame after at last we have defined the label error and its foreground
color as red and it's bound as 349, comma 277 and its size will be to 17 cross 14 adding that error
label to our.
Panel.
So these are the two classes update product and the delete product which will be used.
Which will be used to add and delete product from our database.
So that's all in the.