Hello, everyone.
So till then, we have covered everything about the beverage, glass and coffee class and added everything
to the label.
Plus, we just have to attach the action to the events attached in the class.
So in order to make the things clear, firstly we have to create the juice, tea and water class.
Then only we can attach the actions to the label class, which is going to be responsible for testing
and running of the application.
So our next concern should be creating a new file inside the SRT folder, which will be called as Juice
dot Java.
So we have landed inside the juice file and this is containing a juice class.
So inside this juice class, we are going to create like objects private.
String and the flute like juices has flavor.
We have already discussed it in the working section, so private string flute and the flute is going
to be a string array basically, which is going to contain the types of the flute, which could be the
flavors of the juice, of course.
So a flute and this string called flute is going to contain three fruits in the beginning and that are
going to be suppose Apple.
And then an orange.
Okay, so it is right in that manner.
Double string.
So an orange and a pineapple.
Or should we have a look at it?
So changing this to double codes.
So the elements of the fruit is apple, orange and pineapple.
And the indexes of these are going to be zero, one and two, respectively.
So after the creation of this juice class and extending it to the beverage class, as we are going to
use the methods inside the beverage class, we have used the get and set method for this, only to make
use of that class inside another class.
So the get set method is used for that only to access private objects inside any other classes of the
folder.
So we have started it already.
Now we have declared the string, after which we have declared this juice object.
And the arguments inside the juice object is string size, integer, amount and label.
So these three are the same arguments as we have done inside the coffee class.
The difference inside the juice class is only that we have options like we are using the combo box,
like our option pin.
We can see that.
So option pane is displayed.
When we run the thing, we choose juice and then we add it to card.
Then our option pane appears asking for selecting of fruit.
So we have to select a fruit or as a flavor of our juice in order to complete the order.
So this try and catch will be responsible for exception handling like any kind of error.
If arises, then it will be cast inside the null pointer exception.
You have to select a flavor if you click no like do not select any flavor and cancel the dialog box,
then automatically the exception will be thrown that choose any of the flavors and then only you can
add it to CART.
So try inside this.
Try we are adding option pane and the label is containing a string.
Select our fruit.
So select the fruit and a question message is being a pear asking for a fruit.
So the option pane will be containing this fruit array head this fruit string array containing three
fruits, apple, orange and pineapple.
And by default the fruit will be displayed at the index.
At the index we have apple, so that apple will be displayed by default.
And you can choose it any, any way, like any of the three fruits you can choose.
Now, in the similar way we have done it for the coffee class, we have our side a double price and
we have our dedicated price for all the three sizes.
But in the juice we have three fruits.
Also, like there we had milk.
So in this we are having flavors.
So by default the flavor is apple.
So this five and seven and nine is the price for the apple juice.
Plus small apple juice is costing five.
Similarly, the medium one costs seven, as if not choosing the small and medium definitely will be
choosing the large glass.
So the price is going to be nine or and suppose if you are choosing orange and pineapple, then the
price is going to be multiplied with 1.25.
In those like dedicated classes, suppose you are choosing a small orange juice glass and then the price
is going to be multiplied with 1.25.
And for the pineapple, the size of the price is going to be multiplied with 1.5.
Similarly, the set price is used to set the like update the price.
Once you change your mind like adding two more glasses of coffee, then this set price method is used
to update this price later.
Okay, so this is done till now.
Now in the similar way of adding strings like a text.
In the form of string.
We have prize as a double and a amount as integer, so we have to convert all the text into a form of
a string.
So we are using this two string function calling the super dot to string to convert fruit juice to display
here like suppose we have choose the apple juice so it will be displayed that our five glasses of apple
juice is added.
So yes, this is responsible for converting everything in the form of a string now so that we have created
juice, glass, coffee, glass, beverage, glass.
Now our next concern should be creating a new file inside the RC folder and naming it as Java.
So this class is going to be responsible for adding of the functionalities of the P option in the menu
bar.
So this will be like initialize the public sorry private boolean or sugar and then and that sugar is
going to be the add on for the p option in the menu.
Now inside this, we are going to make a constructor call it as C and the arguments are going to be
string size, int amount and label B L in the similar way we have done it for the juice and the coffee
class.
So the constructor is created successfully.
Now inside this, in the similar way we'll be adding a super method and the super method will be containing
size and amount for the P and if statement will ask for whether we want to like attach sugar to our
tea or not.
So j option pane.
Dot a dialog box will appear asking for like whether we want to add and the parent component is going
to be the LP end and the message is going to be like, would you like to add sugar or something like
this?
So what, you like sugar?
Yes, it goes well.
What do you like, sugar in your tea?
Would you like sugar?
A question mark should be attached.
And after this sugar.
Okay.
So our option pane will appear after this, asking for like a better yes or no option.
So j option pane again dot yes.
No option.
We are going to select it from the suggestions.
So yes, no option.
We are going to add.
And this is going to be set as.
None in default.
And if this if statements is true, then the sugar boolean objective will be set to true in the beginning.
As if this is not true.
Then we will like change sugar to false like initially.
So what is.
False by default.
Now.
So that.
Okay.
So the double code is required for this also.
Now after this.
Now, in the similar way we are concerned, adding prices to the tea with sugar and without sugar.
So calling double prize here, if size equals small, the price for the is going to be 3.0 elseif.
Thus, if the size is medium, then the price for the t is going to be four.
And if we have not choosed small and medium then there is only one size left which is large.
So definitely for the large the prize is going to be five.
Now what if sugar is added?
So if and this boolean sugar is going to change itself to true and false.
So if true, like if sugar is present, sugar is added, then the price is going to be multiplied with
1.25.
And suppose we have choose the like the small size D, then three is going to be multiplied with 1.25
and the price is going to be 3.75.
So that total label report will show that you have added a small cup of tea and the price is 3.75 with
sugar.
So we have updated the price.
So according to the sizes we have changed.
Similarly, we have done it for the coffee and the juice class.
We are converting string and like other data types in the form of string.
So suppose if sugar returns super to string then divide with sugar.
So I suppose if we added sugar then we have to display that five glasses of five small glasses of P
is added with sugar.
So this is going to convert things in the form of string.
We have already like mentioned it in the previous classes also now so that we have covered everything
about the juice coffee beverage classes.
Now in the next part we will be covering about what the water class is going to be responsible for,
what is going to be the prices for all the size of what is going to be the, I don't think, attached
to water class.
And later on we will be adding like the action attached to every event inside the label class.
So yes, this is exactly we are going to do in the next part we will be creating the water class and
then concluding everything inside the label class.
We will be attaching actions to everything and then try running the project and see what actually happens
as the output.
Okay, so see you in the next part.