So here I have the Czech, Czech one coalition matter, which was created to ensure that those who command
our baggage do not pass the ball.
There are four types of collision.
These first one is the left, another is right on the top.
And the bottom collision here and now, the Czech back collision matter.
It will more involved in our game here.
A package can collide with a ball or with an object or with another package.
The baggage can be moved only if it collides with a soccer one and does not collide with another baggage
on a ball and the baggage is moved.
It is time to check if the level is completed.
My calling is completed matter.
So here we are calling that matter.
Now what we have to do the is completed matter check if the level is completed or not.
So we get the number of x.
We compare that with the x and y coordinates of all the x and the destination areas where it's time
to complete the body of this completed method.
So here we take in
number of bags.
Okay, so here I will take and Max, which will be equal to max, not size here.
Okay.
Now we need another variable to check.
The game is finished or not.
So here I will write in finished bags the truly equal to zero here and now we need a for loop.
So here I will take four and here I is equal to zero.
I should be less than two and backs and I plus plus
seven.
I will write baggage by equal to bag stored.
Get our thing next, of course.
Next thing, which we take another for loop with the jet variable which will set it to zero and should
be less than two number of bags here and we should be used to increment.
Now we need to.
Area, area which will be equal to areas toward GATT.
Now, the G8 annex here and here.
I will check the condition.
It will get the number of bags and we compare here the X and the Y coordinates of all the bags and the
destination areas.
So it will be checked with the f loop.
So here I will write if not x here.
If X coordinate of the back is equal to area dot x coordinate and need the backdoor to y.
Is equal to India.
Not why here.
So what it will do?
It will finished.
Bags set it to.
It will be plus one equal to one here.
Okay.
So.
Okay, so this part is done.
Now, what can we do after that?
If the finished mag is rest, stop.
Okay, so here.
What we have here is complete in matter.
Check of the level is completed.
So here we have got the number of packs and here we compare it with the x and y coordinates of all packs
and the destination areas.
So now when the game is finished, so the finished bag variable here equals total number of packs in
the game.
So it will here I will write if
X is equal to.
And Max, it will is completed here.
Set it to true first and then we need to repaint matter also.
So to restart that game and now we have the game is finished when the finished bag is equal to the number
of bag in the game.
So now what we have to do, if we do some bad move, we can restart that level.
So for that we have created a restart level material.
So here I will write first.
Firstly, areas not clear.
Next thing mastered.
Clear.
Next thing is, we all start clear.
Now, what we need is our main initial game will matter.
Okay.
So we need the initial material and check it for if it is completed.
Then here what it should say is completed will be invariable to the false.
So if we do some bad, we can restart that level and we delete all the objects from the list and initiate
the world again by calling this method initial world and that is completed variable set to the false
here.
This is our main board class.
Now we have to make the actor class.
In which we have to write all these bodies.