So now we are going to create the move function for Disney, which will be responsible for moving the
snake inside the frame.
So initializing the void, move, function and writing the functionalities inside the function.
Firstly, we will create A for loop and Z for the dots and if that is greater than zero.
Then Z minus minus.
So this will start to move in the left direction like we have 0 to 300.
So if the snake is that supposed 29 position, so it will start moving in the left direction.
So Z minus minus and setting the coordinates for the x and y axis like x isn't.
Is equal to.
X, z minus one.
And similarly for the Bible.
So I am copying for the Y coordinate.
So the snake is moving this way.
Yes.
Now the snake has started to move.
So what happens when the snake moves in either of the four directions, like left and right or up and
down?
So we have to update the coordinates, X and Y ones, if any of the move takes place.
So suppose if the snake moves in the left direction, then this will result to x zero as or decrease
in the dot size.
So x is zero minus dot size.
Dot size.
And here we are.
Now, similarly, we have to do this for four more times, like four total, four times.
So copying this and trying to paste it three more times for the other directions as.
Right.
Up and down.
So we have to cover all the four directions and what the consequences are going to be.
So if the snake moves in the left direction, the x coordinate decreases.
If it moves in the right direction, it is going to be increased.
Similarly, if it goes in upward direction, then the y coordinate is going to decrease.
And if went down direction, then the Y coordinate is going to increase.
Yes.
So here we are.
So I think the same thing.
Let's do this and do this here.
So this is for the like.
I think I have pasted it.
One extra time.
So this is for the first time.
Yes.
So the left direction is responsible for decreasing the dot size in the x coordinate and hence it will
be plus.
Now as a quick explanation if the snake move downwards.
So we are going to plus like in the comments I will show you, what is this actually like?
Suppose if currently the snake's position is at 240 in the Y coordinate and if it moves downward trying
this.
So yes, suppose this is Y is equal to 240 and if it moves in the downward direction, then suppose
it is moving ten units in the right direction.
Then this is the down key and we are we have to update the Y coordinate as plus ten.
So this is what we are actually doing.
So 240 plus ten is going to be 250.
And similarly, supposing this snake moves up direction, then the y coordinate is going to decrease,
not increase.
Like suppose the snake is head and it starts moving upward.
Not the slide but the snake.
So if the snake starts moving upwards, the y coordinate will decrease.
Here the y continued to zero and here the y coordinate is 300.
So obviously if the snake moves upward, the y coordinate will decrease.
And similar is the case for the left and right direction is if it moves in the x direction like left
direction, the x coordinate will decrease and for the right direction the x coordinate will increase
head it is zero x and this x is equal to 300.
So we are done with the move function.
Now as far as we have created all the function required in this Snake Board Java class, we will create
the action listener as.
Public void.
Action performed like what action is to be performed when any of the function is being called.
So action performed.
And so creating this action performed function and inside the parameter we are going to pass action
event as suppose a.
So inside this function we are going to check if the game is on like I call it as in game.
I call in game as game is on.
You must have heard me before.
So if that game is on then.
This is braces.
So check that the balance there.
Also check that the collision is performed or not like check collision.
And move the snake.
So let me explain this thing like what action is actually being performed.
So there are three functions check up, check technology and then move.
So I am going to explain this with the help of this frame.
So firstly, we have to check that there are police present or not.
Like if there is no apple, then where the snake is going to move.
So the first thing we have executed inside the action form thing is to check the apple.
Then we have checked the collision.
Like suppose that we have started the snake from this coordinate.
Then the snake is not going to move at all like the game will be over in the beginning.
So we have to check collision like if the snake is not collided till now.
So after checking that the apple is present, there is no collision.
We are going to move the snake.
Simply move the snake.
And what is actually moving?
So her moving the notes, we all know, moving up down left and right and coordinates are updated in
this way only.
So yes, the action performed.
Listen, event is also covered.
So after creating the action listener event, now we will come towards this paint component.
Like what actually is going to be done after the snake moves.
Like, suppose the snake moves, it's the apple and then what is going to happen?
So this paint component is calling the graphics like we have created the graphics here.
Above.
So this graphic is going to.
Yes, that is the graphic.
Okay.
So the graphic is going to add one more dot behind the tail of the snake.
So graphic, gee, super dot paint component helps us to add the image behind.
Like I already told you, there is no real snake.
We are just adding image after image.
And this we are going to do with the help of the paint component, the graphics and draw.
Three things are responsible for that.
Now so that we have created super paint component and draw and called draw.
Now the image will be drawn after the tail of the snake.
So inside the action listener part, like the a variable, as we said, we have to call repaint.
So the repaint is going to paint after the snake most any step like checks.
If there is apple, there are no collisions and the snake moves and each step then it will be paint
image after the tail of the snake.
So after covering everything, now add one more like let us try to run the function and check whether
the.
Now before this I am going to set focus table.
Like we are going to contain.
This project and control the project as.
Keyboard functionality is only so by setting focus able to through the app will open in the default
moment.
Like if they will click keyboard, then it will perform the action and before this nothing is going
to happen.
So try checking that the app is working or not.
Like if the snake is actually performing.
So yes, the snake has started to move from a run and the apple has appeared at a random position with
the help of the random we have created.
And the move function is also working correctly.
Like if we are pressing the up key, it is moving y minus like y coordinate is being subtracted.
If we are pressing the left key, the x coordinate is being subtracted.
If we are going right, the y coordinate, sorry, the x coordinate is being added.
So the snake has grown enough.
Now let us check with the collision part.
So hitting this against obstacle.
So the snake has entered the world and the pop up appears as game over.
So everything we have created by far is working fine.
The snake was moving.
Eating the apple and the size was increasing.
Like emails were being added one after the other.
And once the snake hits the obstacle, that game is over.
Now, one more functionality is to reject that whether the snake dies, if it hits itself or not.
So let us check that also for that, we have to grow the snake for minimum five pointers.
Before that, the snake is not going to collide itself.
Let us hope that it does not collide.
The walls mean in the meantime.
So let us try to hit the snake itself.
Let us grow it some more.
And now, yes, the game is over.
The head of the snake disappears and all the body parts are seen as the darts only and the game is over.
So let us summarise everything we have created.
We have created the snake class inside, which we have called a new board.
We have a frame pack and the resize ability abilities set to false like the app is not being maximized.
The size is fixed at 300 height n 300 width.
Now coming to the border of Java we have imported swing and WP packages have used the packages inside
them.
The components like action list and inside the action listener.
We have created dedicated actions for everything, like for moving for the keyboard keys, like controlling
the keys, for growing the snake, for the collision and everything.
We have successfully added the image icons, so make sure that you set the path correctly.
In order to the image appearance we have initiated the game, set a timer.
We have located the apple.
We have checked that if Apple is eaten or not eaten.
So increasing the dots accordingly.
We have created paint and graphics for adding images one behind another.
We have created a game over functionality.
So what should be the appear on the screen when the obstacle is hidden and what is the functionality
which we are going to face when the game is over?
We are checking the collisions.
If the snake hits itself or any of the four walls and the game is over and is stop.
So I hope you all must have gone properly through this project program and will try to make the game
on your own.
Thank you all for attending this session and we'll see you later with some next project.
Thank you.
See you in the next part.