In previous videos and tutorials.
I told you how we can create some JSP files here and we are done with our servlet patch, so we are
now focused only with JSP part.
So let me close this index.
What is HTML?
So we created one admin panel JSP for admin panel student list JSP for the student list instruction
list for that instruction purposes and question list for the question list purposes, let us see how
we can create an update student.
JSP Because we mentioned your update.
Student So we need to create updated student.
So.
Let me create one GSP student here.
Finish.
So bring this on me and.
Remember when you are writing Java files inside this?
You need to specify.
This FinTechs.
So let me create a student visa list.
Update student.
Then.
Let me show you so our page language Java studio because it contains that update student.
I'm using ArrayList here also.
So let me print your title update.
Don't.
I'm using bootstrap method in this.
Again.
With this, as usual, I'd be.
This is all about these things.
Then studio.
I'm using this method.
I'm invoking that ArrayList.
Then this all student.
It will fetch if request not get parameter username for that particular user if our great username which
is basically for that specific user, if that is correct, what it will be do it will go to the update.
Student No, no, what is that update?
Student Now, we already created updates to the JSP, so why we require so if I want to change the username,
if I want to change the name, if I want to change the password, there should be another JSP file to
process that purpose.
You can include in the same JSP file, but for some simpler purpose.
Or we can say for the user friendliness and managing purpose, I'm going to use this.
So again, get the username for this update student.
Which I already created, and this is for the student.
So this is very simple.
JS file as I told you.
You need to create only this part.
And if that for loop if that which means if that matches to that part only you can easily use this x
go with the specific that name only.
No need to change that because student is not available.
Simple.
So let us see how we can create a student in to part here.
So let me copy this.
I'm going to create another JSP here.
So as you can see, we have some more JSP files than.
Our part.
So this will contain basic logic of updating.
But so.
Let me.
Use this part of that student now.
And this is.
Instead of deciding what I'm going to put is.
The thing.
Student.
Inform.
I will bring this so it will use this student because I want to update in that part only with student
the model.
It will import this only and ArrayList and everything.
So what it will be do it will new user ID, new password, new name which original id you ID and everything.
If this is done like student space, we are already created student lives.
It will send direct to that part.
If not else, it will go in the that error in the database and everything then.
So this is all about how we can create a student notepad.
So this is just a logic, not very important.
Or you can say you can easily use in the student only.
But I just created another part.
So this is very important because this contains the logic of changing username, password and name.
Which original also.
So this is done with average students.
So let us see how we can create some dilute student part also here.
Let me create a JSP file here again.
Delete student.
We believe this part because this contains some default code.
While you are creating JSP.
So we don't want to print hello world in the student.
We need to create a logic for deleting students.
So let me create the student part here.
Delete student.
Just need to remove that part only.
So what we are going to do is just deleting that part.
Did the student list and delete record.
Delete record is already mentioned in that database and we are going to delete that record.
So let me change the title here also.
Okay.
Delete student.
Look, now we are done with that student part.
So we just created update student and student.
Update Student Contents.
Update Student.
Now JSP You can directly use these codes because I already created this part.
So remember what I mentioned here is student is with new, student with username.
This if the username is this, I'm going to delete records and it will send me to this.
If not, it should print it out there.
So that's it about how we can create delete student So now we are done with student list.
Let us see how we can create instruction list here or we need to create instruction, update instruction
and all these things.
Instruction.
Web pages or JSP file here I'm going to create.
So in further videos, I'm going to show you how we can create an answer.
And I agree methods so I don't I have very less time limit here.
Due to time constraint, I'm just doing this.
So let us see how we can create a best instruction method here.
So as we created an object student part, we need to create a Buddhist instruction methodology.
So again, I'm importing all these things.
Remember, I'm importing pages, all pages.
Let me change this.
A date.
Instructions.
With this number because it's an important instruction operation.
The operation is basically basically for the update part, it will get the parameter for that purpose.
If that insert part is equal, it will go to that part, or otherwise it will go to the delete part.
We update instructions and delete instructions.
Remember, I need to create update instruction now method also because it contains the logic of that
object instruction.
Similarly, as I created for.
Student list.
So result will contain all the result information for that student purpose.
Okay.
So update instruction now.
Let me save this post and let me show this first also.
So, as you know, update instructions students know contains this.
I will just copy this because I want to insert title here again.
I'm dating.
These options.
That's it.
Similarly, we created this.
I need to create this part again because if original then modified.
If yes instruction list it will send me to directly to that part.
If not, it shows me the error.
So this is basic logic for that update instruction.
Now what we require.
So we are done with this.
So now we are needed.
The lead instruction part.
Also, let me create another delete instruction.
Yes.
If I'll only.
Just be only.
Okay.
This.
New GSP.
Okay.
Remember the names here?
If you are mentioning some other names, it will not work.
No created.
Delete this.
Again.
Delivered instruction.
So let me read one instruction part also here.
Again, simple logic.
Or delete instruction.
Instruction is that instruction get parameter which basically in instruction if that delete record.
So where is the delete record I'm using is.
Delete instruction.
So this from the TV and that model.
Instructions.
So I'm deleting and I'm what I'm using delete record inside the instruction.
So now you can understand why I am using the solid part.
If I am not using different packages, it will take too much time for the creation of the solid.
So creating a servlet is a task for the developer, as you can see, because I need to create and I
need to mention everything inside that purpose.
So once I created this inside that model, it contains instruction to go to the delete record.
So I'm using that method in that part.
So as you can see inside the model instruction duo contains delete record method.
So now we are done with the instruction part.
So our remaining part is now the question list.
So let's see how we can use that question list again, because it also contains a question or question
list of that question.
It's a new GSP.
Similar things I'm using.
I'm using similar logic, but variables are different just because it contains all different.
And it's it is using the database.
So let me create.
And I already created.
Let us see how we can create.
This mental.
Okay.
So.
Update Christian method.
So now this is done only.
Oh, okay.
Now this is done.
But the update question now is remaining which contains logic and is very similar thing like.
These only.
And let me put here is that question.
And it will create this GSP and it's required this part also.
Similar thing.
Delete that part because it contains some default code.
Go do this part and.
So I am not deploying it again and again because at the end of this program or everything, I'm going
to deploy it a single time or I'm going to deploy in the single part.
So.
Let me use this one.
Okay, so similar thing.
I'm using this.
I'm dating.
Christians.
Okay.
So.
This will import everything and you importing only questions do you?
Because this is only required no need to import DB or anything.
Option An option B options the option DM importing.
If the answer, then if you are changing something.
Or to use questions it will redirect to this part.
If the status is not error error in the database, it's not exceptionally awkward.
You can put that part.
So this is all about how we can create instruction, video and everything.
In further part, I'm going to create some ad questions and everything, so I will just go through that
and I will deploy our project on the server.