So in this video, we will be talking about our tic tac toe game.
This will be the last video.
After that, we will show the live run of this project of every class.
So this tic tac toe.
Class is defined inside the package.
We have imported the necessary packages like Java, JWT, Java event and Java exports.
Fantastic.
So these will be the packages we will be importing.
After that, we have defined our one class extending frame and implementing item listener and both X
and listener interfaces.
Now inside the end variable we will be having ij ij x phi and this will be the integer variables we
will be having in this class.
Then we have an integer area in which we have a two dimensional in which we have stored these kinds
of.
Values.
This will be used to format our tic tac toe game effectively and there's even class also storing some
kind of values.
After that there is a boolean, a state type and set.
These will be three variables named as boolean type of boolean.
After that there is an icon.
I see, I see one, I see one I see two.
I can see I see one, one I see two, two.
Then there's a two checkboxes, two labels, but ten type of areas for eight buttons.
And actually it is from 0 to 8 that will be nine buttons and g button is close to reset.
Then what we are doing is defining a method public wide show button.
At initial what we are doing is accessible to ten boys, goes to ten and just goes to zero.
We are iterating over the high value.
High is equal to zero is less than is close to eight plus plus x plus is equals to 100 and g plus plus.
We are setting by is equal to new button.
Now if JS was equal to three, what we are doing is j is equal to zero, y is goes to Y plus hundred
and x is equal to ten.
Then we're setting inside the B.
I set the amount as x, y and its size will be hundred from 100.
Then we are adding that to our frame.
After that, we are adding the action to that button.
Now reset is goes to give it a new research setting its boundaries under 350 and its size will be 150.
Adding the reset button to our frame after that reset add action.
So this will add the action listener to our reset button.
After that.
This is end of Shorten class or it is a method actually.
End of show rejected the method.
After that we have defined the public void check, which is taking argument number one.
So instead which we have iterated for is close to zero, i.e. less than is close to seven plus plus,
then j for 1 to 3.
And inside it what we are doing is a comma goes to number one and then we will be showing a four is
equals to 11.
This is for the check method.
And then.
We are doing for the computer logic.
So in this tic tac toe game, we will be playing for the either with the computer or either with our
player or two players.
So public wide computer logic, which is taking antigen.
So first we will be iterating from 0 to 7.
And then there is a nested loop for the JV 1 to 3 because there will be three spaces in the tic tac
toe interface and then there is what we are doing is if Ajax goes to NUM, then what we are doing a
zero is goes to one one and a four is goes to one zero.
Now for one.
So what we are doing is, again, iterating from 0 to 7 and incrementing the loop and set as equals
to two.
So set value will be a boolean value.
So whose value we have set here is true.
Then if a four value is equals to ten, then encounters goes to zero.
And then we have again defined the nested loop.
J is equal to one and less.
Then it goes to three and g plus plus.
After that we have checked for the condition if b of a of ij minus one dot get I can not null so if
there is no icon actually will be placing an image of cross and zero.
So if there is no I can add that particular place and so that will be null if not null that there will
be icon.
So we will be incrementing the count plus plus if there is, I can then set.
Yes, now is close to this.
So inside the null will be storing the value of IAG.
Now if count is equals to zero.
So if count is equal to zero, what we are doing is be yes.
Nil is equals yes nil minus one is set i can to ICI two so it'll be setting icon in that particular
place and this dot check as equals to use null and we'll be storing this dot check passing that does
not check to yes now and set set as equals to false and then break.
After that inside the method.
What we are doing is if a zero is equal to ten, so we are iterating again from the G to three plus
plus.
So if again get icon for that particular place, if that is also if there is no icon, we will be setting
the AC to image to that icon to that place and pass to pass it to the distort check method and set the
value as false.
And then we'll be break again.
After that, if that is, it goes to fall.
So there will be break.
And then if that goes to false again, then we'll break.
So this statement will be respected for the above first statements.
So that's why we have defined it twice after that.
What we are doing is we are defining the constructor for that tic tac toe game class.
I did it as tic tac toe.
After that there is a checkbox rule CBJ new checkbox group.
Then we have defined the checkbox group as see when it goes to new checkbox versus computer.
CBG Falls City to see to is equal to new checkbox versus friend.
CBG comma falls.
SIMON We have set the bone and location for that.
SIMON That is 128 and it size will be 100 cross 40.
And for the sea to what we are doing is the location is one 2150 and its size is in Red Cross 14.
Adding both of these 72 to our.
Frame and seven segment ad item list, we will be adding item list to seven and see to respectively.
Then there is a state as close to two trip as equals to two and set goals to setting the both.
All the three variable variables to true.
Then inside the IAC, one will be collecting a new image icon with the class or get system resource
new ICI one jpg.
Similarly, new icon image here for the class will get sys resource ici two.
Similarly for the ESI one one.
And I see through two images we have a stored inside these variables of image I can type.
Then what we are doing is setting the layout as null, set the size as 3450 so the visibility as to
and default close operation for that frame.
After that we have defined the public void item is changed.
So if Simon does get a state is true, then we will be set type as opposed to false.
If we do not get a close to true, then we'll be type is close to true.
Remove seven and remove z to three.
Paint the complete frame 002 3450 and show the button we will be calling show button.
So show button will be will do what its repaint again with the new image values.
Then there is a I action performed method we have defined with the help of action event object and inside
the if type is equals to true.
So what we are doing is either get resources equals to reset then for is goes to 0 to 8 will set up
by to set.
I can null and else will be iterating over the 0 to 8.
And if the resources from B of A, then what we are doing is by is taken as close to nil.
So then really inside which what we are checking for, if state is true, we will be set icon to it
to and set the state to false else if the eyes else what we are doing is inside the icon, we will storing.
I see one image and set the status true at last.
What we are doing is inside the bar we will set the icon to that particular icon image.
So what we are checking for is that if the cross has been pasted, then we will be placing the zero.
If the zero has been placed pasted, then we'll be placing the cross.
After that.
This is for now.
If type is equals to false and if a resource is reset, then resetting by iterating over from 0 to 8
and set the icon as null.
Otherwise what we are doing is four eyes close to seven and inside it's a nested loop for 0 to 4 age
is close to a one ij again initializing area.
Then limited is for the computer logic for zero to less than is close to eight if to get resources from
B1.
We will not get ionesco's if the B1 icon is null.
There is no icon in the null.
Then we will set one set icon as opposed to AC one.
And if we don't get ionesco's smell, if there is no the b4 place, then will set before I to seek to.
Now this to check five.
So you'll be passing and following the check method with the argument five and ls this dot compute logic
to I so we'll be calling.
If the condition is not true, then be the computer losing method with the argument as I value.
After that.
What we have did is a.
For Isaac also less than seven.
This will be for checking that who won or not so will be studying icon icon one and by this so for this
place icon will be storing an icon one and I can do from this place and I can three from this place.
Now if icon one is equals to icon two, I can go to icon three and icon one not as well.
So if I can one not as close to null and I can, I can do a three as equals to same so and then what
if icon one goes to see one?
Now if icon one is close to see one means icon one is from the icy choice one.
Then what we are doing is setting the icon to see one, one, one, one and one one.
Every place we will set the icon to icy one, icy one, one, icy one, one and show them as a dialog
box that this dot you one click reset.
So if this condition will be true icy if the icon one matches to all the places with the icy one image
so then it will show you one click reset as icy one is close to icy two.
So if what's happening, if the image is from the icy two, then it will set the images first to icy
to two to 2 to 2 and then show the image, show the dialog box that computer one.
So if the image icy one match will be found from in any direction, then it will show that you want.
If the icy two image matches found in any direction, then it will show that computer one click reset.
Inside the main method we have defined the current instance of the class.
New Day one.
So whenever we run this class, run this file, the tic tac toe game will appear.
So that's all from this tic tac toe game.