So here is the checkout class which we are having.
Let's understand it's code.
So it is defined under the package hotel inside which we have imported the packages in the blue dot
border layout JWT Complete Package JWT Event Queue SQL Package Swing package swing dot bottom dot empty
broader package eight dot font package JWT Event package and AWG dot event.
Dot Action Event package.
Now we have defined the class, which is extending the frame.
And we have established the connection object as null instance as null.
Then there is a prepared statement and stands as null.
There is a private panel named as content pane and then there is a text field, the one which is also
of private type.
Then there is a choice.
Type variables.
See one then inside the main method we have invoked the event Q to invoke later inside which we have
defined the void run method.
Inside the try block, we have created the object of the current class that is checkout setting the
visibility of that frame as through and for the exception we will handle it using the catch block.
Then there is a void closed method which will dispose the current object and close that current of frame
and window.
Then there is a public check out non parameterized constructor of the class which is throws as well
exception.
If an exception will occur in this constructor, then it will handle by using throws.
Now we have said.
The operation, close operation of the windows, setting the bound of the window, initializing the
panel.
Then we have set the bar for the panel and setting the bar and adding that panel to the frame and adding
the layout of the panel as well.
Then we have added the image icon by using a icon, i.e. one converting it to the i3 by scaling its
instance from the object of I1.
Then we have created another image icon two to form the complete image from the image object.
Three.
Then there is a label l one.
In which we have added the.
Image icon.
So that label will be showing the image in the window, setting the label bound for that label and adding
that label to our frame.
Now, next is the another label label as check out.
Setting the font for it, its font family, its font type, and its font size, setting the bound of
that label.
And adding that label to our frame window.
Then there is a label name labels number, setting the bound for it, adding it to our panel.
And there is a one choice instance for the choice.
We have created a catch block inside which we have.
Initialize the connection by using our icon class, executing the result set query that is select as
from customer.
So it will start next will by loop that iterate over the rows of the customer and fetch the number of
the customer and add that to the choice object.
Then we have setting the bound for the choice and adding that to our panel.
After that, we have added an image and another button.
Then there is added an image to the button I added to and setting the button for Delta, adding that
button to our frame.
Then we have added the action list in the class and define the action, perform the method for the button
to so it is showing system dot then inside the drive log.
We have initialize the connection and a string number which is fetching the item from the choice executing
the query where the number is equals to number from the customer.
For the next 2 hours.
Start next.
Then system clicked and a room number.
Then there is a catch block after that.
Label or as room number, then we have set the bound for it, adding it to our panel text field for
the room number, adding to it our panel.
Then there's a button checkout.
This will define the action performed inside it to delete from the customer ID and it will update if
checkout will be check collect, then it will delete the record from the customer table and also from
the room and set the availability of that room which will be held by the customer till now.
Then insert right block.
We have delete a SQL query, executed the category, check out successful dialog box and move back to
our reception page.
Then we are bound for the button.
Background color of the button.
Foreground color of the button and adding that button to our panel.
Then there is a button.
Exit Nuland back.
Then there are channels now for that back button which will set the reception visibility as true and
current as false.
Bound for that button background.
Lot of the button for round a lot of the button adding that button to our panel at last we have.
Set the background color of the current complete window as white.
So let's look at the other class that is an update check or Java class.
So this is also defined inside the package hotel and we have imported the necessary packages.
Then we have defined the class update check, which is extending the frame connection type of object.
Initialize as null.
Then there's a prepared statement in slides as null panel and six text field here.
Two choices as well.
And inside the main function a string of.
Then we have defined the void run method inside which we have update, check frame and setting the visibility
of the current update check class as true inside the clause.
We will dispose the current object then inside it.
We have defined the non parameterized constructor which is throwing a SQL exception.
If it occurs, it will handle that setting the default close operation of the.
Current frame, setting the bound of the frame and setting the.
G panel.
Hiding the bottom of the G panel, adding it to the frame and setting its layout as null.
Then we have a label as checking details, setting the font for it, bound off it and adding it to our
panel.
Then there's the image icon we have created for the label element, setting the bound of it and adding
to our frame when under label as ID setting bound of it.
Adding it to our panel.
Then there is a choice object for the choice.
We have created the connection inside the tribe log executed the query select restrict from customer
and over the data or record inside database.
We have to.
We have it rated by using asked next and added the number inside the choice.
Then we have set the bound for the choice added to.
Panel, then we will answer the label as room number setting bound for it.
Adding it to.
Adding the label number.
To our content panel.
Then there is a text field sitting down for it.
Adding it to our panel.
Then there is a name label adding setting bound of that, adding it to our panel label as check in,
setting, bound off it, adding it to our panel label amount paid setting bound for it, adding it to
our panel label pending rupees setting bound off it and adding it to our panel.
Then there is a text field for text status bound of that adding to our panel.
Similarly for the text state here, that is for the text states adding bound of that, adding it to
a panel.
Similarly for the text field, that is time setting bound of it, adding the panel.
Text payment setting bound of it.
Adding to our panel.
Then there is a button update.
Define the action.
Perform method for it inside the action list now.
Inside the tribunal created the connection using the con class fetched the required.
Details from the text field and choices updated the.
Database of table customer for the room number, name, status deposit and the number.
Then we have showed as data updated successfully.
New reception object has been created as true and current.
Visibility as false, then we have set the bond for the button, foreground, background, color and
foreground.
Added that button to our panel.
Then there is a button exit.
Define the action performed for which we will move back to the reception window and current window will
be closed.
Then exit button bound.
It's background color, foreground color.
Then there is a check button whose accent performed event has been described here defined there is string
selected item which will select item from the choice.
Initialize the connection, execute the query select as from customer where number is close to s x as
one iterated over the records and fetched a.
Fetch the record from the text fields.
Then there is a string total.
As close to zero connection is lies the connection from the database.
Then there is an execute query we have selected from rule number where rule number is equal to text
id dot cat.
So it will select the room number from where it will match and we will total Isobel's to add to that
get press so it will use to fetch the price from that room number and paid is goes to text or get text.
So it will this will be the paid string, it will pass the paid string to the end and update the pending
variable.
Then we have added that button down.
It's background colour, it's foreground colour and added it to our panel.
Then at last we have defined the.
Background color of the window as white.
So let's see the output of these two classes.
Check out class.
Run this file.
Let's.
It will show look like this.
So here is nothing in that choice as we have not added any data till now and this is how it looks.
So let's close that and see the output of update check.
Run this file as well.
This is how update check will be.
Look like idea is not showing here as we have not added data till now.
These are three buttons, checkup data and back.