And so as far as we have covered everything about the download manager class, the Progress Renderer
class and the download table model class.
Now the last class which is going to like compile up everything is download dot java which is going
to create a class called download.
And inside this download class we are going to like initialize all the objects which are going to require
like suppose whether it be the size of the download buffer, whether it be the status names like downloading,
post, complete cancel or error.
So we are going to like initialize all the statuses, size and everything which are going to be required
inside it.
So yes, this is the like packages required to be imported.
Inside this download class.
We are going to extend this download class to observable and this is going to implement renewable inside
this suppose whenever or like table is concerned a specific column is concerned then status is going
to display whether downloading was complete, canceled or error.
So this is statuses is an error here containing five elements and the maximum buffer size for a specific
download is one 0 to 4.
After this it will be like convert.
Suppose that we are showing the size as a one for MVP, so once the buffer size is completing one 0
to 4 KB, we are showing the size in K.B., not the site size, the spreading, maybe the size that
is in MP.
So suppose one 0 to 4 and B is covered, then automatically the size is going to be increased by one.
So if it was for me, then it is going to be converted to five and it is displayed as the full float.
No.
The rest of the objects which are required inside this is your size.
Download it so all the members of the Yes we have declared this area.
So all the members of the array are declared as private global variables.
Inside this download class and I have added command to like signify what actually this declaration is
about.
We have declared everything globally in order to use later in this class.
Now the next part we are going to see is a constructor for the download.
So we have created this download constructor.
This is you use to access the URL.
We have declared the URL here.
So firstly we are accessing the URL, decreasing the size by like we have set the size initially minus
one.
So once the you are added, the index is starting from zero.
So we have said the size of minus one in the beginning, after which we have set the downloaded to zero
in the beginning as there are zero downloaded files in the beginning, the status is set to downloading
by default.
Otherwise, if any kind of changes or updates occur, then the status will be updated to weather error.
Initially, only downloading is going to be displayed if the successful download has started.
So inside this download class we have like declared everything the constructor is complete.
Now to begin the download we have called this download function.
So yes, this is like this.
Now the next part is to get everything declared here.
We have to get all the variables as we have the like declared it as private.
So in order to access this in other classes of like the download manager weather or the download table
model, if wishes to access the these objects of this download class, then we have to use get method
in Java in order to make these things accessible.
So yes, we will be setting get method for the you are then the size, the speed, the average speed
and all of the columns here.
Okay.
So we have a code of function for getting all the column names like you ordered size, speed, average
speed, elapsed time remaining time.
And with the help of this, we will be able to access all of them as like accessible variable.
This global variable is set to private.
So with the help of this method, we will be able to access all of them in any of the classes except
of this download class now so that we have used get method to access all of them.
Now our next concern is to like set the time how the format of time is going to be displayed.
We have two time column names.
They are remaining time and elapsed time and we are going to set our format in the form of a string
basically.
So the four time format is going to be displayed in the form of string.
So we are using like access pacifier, we have a like integer, so we are converting that integer to
a string or we can call it long.
Also long is a large version of an integer, nothing else.
So the time is showing in hours, minutes and seconds.
So we are multiplying the hours by 33600, the minutes by 60 and simply in like putting the seconds
directly.
So this is for formatting the time for both the remaining time and the elapse time.
Now after this, to get the download progress, we are multiplying the size by 100.
Like suppose the total size is suppose for 500 and we have downloaded hundred.
So we are going to like put up things like 100 divided by 500 in 200.
So it is going to be okay.
So it is going to be one by five and one by five.
If converted in the form of decimal, then it is 20%.
So 20% progress bar will display.
Everything is like sort of mathematically how the percent will be displayed, how the time will be displayed.
So as everything is written in a calculated manner now for us, like changing the status, like pausing,
resuming, cancelling a specific download, we are setting a specified functions for both.
What happens if we click on the pause?
Then the previous elapsed time will be equal to the elapsed time like everything should be freeze.
The elapsed time should not increase and the status which is already set to download in the beginning
is to be set as Paul and the stage change function is called.
Similarly, for the resume, the status is again, if said to pause, then it will be changed to downloading.
If we can sell any download, then previous elapsed time will be again equal to the elapsed time.
There will be no increase in the elapsed time again and the rest of the things will be remain same and
the status will be just updated from downloading to cancelled.
Okay, so what happens if.
The previous elapsed time is.
Yes.
So if there is an error, so the previous elapse time is going to change to previous elapsed time and
the status will be displaying error.
And again, the set change function is going to stay.
Change function is going to be called start or resuming the download again.
Suppose if the download is paused and we have to again resume so the resume function is going to like
create a thread.
A thread is a group of processes taking place.
So suppose our process has completed to 20%.
Then once we will resume it, it will again start from 21% and it is going to be like a thread.
Nothing will be like broken.
The download will not again start from the previous state.
It will simply like download from the where it was paused.
Now after the like.
Every checking we have marked the download error thing, we have talked about resuming the download.
Now what about the URL part?
So the you are part is going to be displayed in the form of string and how to check the validation.
Suppose that there is some like invalid invalidity error inside the link the URL.
Then are you as to pay your url connection part is going to throw an exception.
Suppose the download started and there is some error.
Then the catch block will be executed.
Otherwise this try will be like checking that if the connection is checked properly, the bytes are
correct.
Everything is connected.
The download manager is connected to the server from where the download is to be taken place and make
sure making sure that the connection is made in the range of 200.
So this is basically the network bandwidth terms.
We have to make the connections successfully in order to make the download take place correctly and
the content length should be less than one.
Then it should throw an error, so we should at least contain one URL in order to start the downloading
process.
So yes, this is about the validation of the URL part after this.
Now after this, we have to like change the size.
Accordingly, the progress is made.
Suppose that 220% of the download is complete, then the size should change accordingly that this size
is a flag.
We have to multiply the progress according to that.
In the order of streaming any download, we are connecting things to like making connections between
the server and the download manager window.
Then we have to make like streaming thing.
We have to make like check that whether the size do not increase the maximum buffer size that is above
our size, these all are like computer network things.
If you have studied computer networks, you must have been hard about these terms that how downloading,
buffering, like everything goes hand in hand in networking.
We have a time for every bit, every byte transition transmissions from the server to our system.
So that is going to be updated in that manner.
Buffering is taking place, so the download will be made in that manner.
Suppose 20% is complete.
Then the download manager will send a message to the server that we are completed 20%.
Now, if the user hits the pause button by selecting that specific row, then the download manager should
send a message to the server that stops sending the file.
The user has paused, so once the user will resume that I will inform you server, then only you can
start sending me bytes and the streaming should like resume from that time.
After this we are going to like check the status.
So the status is also going to update it in similar way.
We are changing the pausing and resuming thing.
We have to like notify the server also that currently we are downloading, we are complete, then we
have to change the steps.
So after this, once the download is complete, then we have to cut the connection from the server.
That way.
Yes, we are done with the download part now.
We are nothing to do with the server.
So connection is stopped and the download is like downloaded to your system.
You can check it whether it is downloaded inside your desktop or whether whatever the location is.
So yes, this is all about this.
Now we will try running that, whether everything is working correctly or not.
So for this we have to connect to network first and then check the downloading part.
So let's try running this download manager dot java class to check whether everything is working fine
or not.
So hitting on this run button.
The new window will open.
Yes, it is working perfectly fine.
We have a frame panels inside the frame.
Now let us try pasting a link.
This is a static control.
You are controlling so the link validation will work fine.
Now hitting a yes.
So the is showing in the string format the size, the progress.
And once the progress is completed, the status is updated to complete.
Now also check that whether the play pause button is working or not.
So selecting a specific row, pausing this row and then yes.
So button highlight is also working fine now resuming the download now pausing again.
Let us try to cancel this and the status is updated to cancel.
After this.
On clearing the row size is decreased by one.
So yes, everything is working perfectly fine.
Till now we have covered everything in this download manager.
Yes.
So all the classes are doing a special function containing a special functionality and everything is
like working in a proper way.
So I hope that you have gained more concepts about Java after the completion of this project.
Now try making this project on your own and practice all the concepts we have discussed in this tutorial.
And I hope after completing the project on your own, you will be an experienced Java project programmer
at the end.
So I am wishing you all the best for making and practicing this project and thanking you all for joining
this session.