So in previous careers I told you we created different solids.
And remember in this male client, which is my solid four solid.
So this email client, instead of accessing to the web XML which is basically controlling file what
I created, I added the annotation for creating the mappings.
So this is the mapping thing here, I added.
So if you don't know what is the mapping thing, it is just WebLogic smelting and just adding this here.
So.
This will at the back end for index launches.
This is my index GSP.
It was Monday.
So this then this then email message I created in the password text.
I'm going to add my password later.
And in this, what we created already created is just.
Our What we can say email utility thing.
So now what I'm going to do, I'm going to add here my email and I'm going to add my password off my
email in this letter.
So let me do one thing.
I added CC address, BCC address and everything here.
So what is the remaining thing is I just added this email address to length, but it's we need to create
one address to field because I created CC, BCC everything, so I need to create one for loop here.
So creating the for loop is very easy.
If you know this, what I'm going to do is very common thing.
I'm just going to travel to this list.
Using I need int is equal to zero initialize with variable.
I use less than email ids.
You have that email like this field ids dot length.
Land and what it is I lost.
So that's it I'm going to do.
And what I'm going to add here is.
When this is done addressed to field.
I needed addressed to Field.
Which.
I meant.
With water.
It is.
I need to add this new which is going to create one new object in here.
What it is.
Okay.
New and internet address.
Which internet address?
And an email in.
Email.
Ideas with.
Led by.
So do you create me the what you can say travels through that and it will assign this address to which
I had filled again and again so I don't require it to travel one by one.
It will automatically add both things.
Similarly, I need to create address field.
So let me do one thing here.
How I added this, I need to add this address and I created no similar thing I need to perform here,
which is basically the these things or one thing you can do, I'm adding in triggers because I need
to handle the exceptions.
But if you don't want to use triggers, you can really use your throws here.
So you can check out that part also.
But I'm using catch here I catch block for error an exception handling similar I'm going to perform
for in I is equal to zero.
I is less than email.
It is length basically.
Because it will travel through this again.
And I need to check that email.
It is now it's in the ladies CC.
Because CC field not the common field.
Then address cc.
I need to perform.
Let me copy the cc.
CC I feel is equal to new internet address.
I need to engineer again.
Similar thing to perform internet address.
Then this field again which is basically.
Or email IDs.
CC So this is.
You got?
No, no, no, no.
Not because I need to travel to this.
So let me mention here.
Do.
Actresses.
CC Pegasus is going to check.
Now, what is the main thing here I'm going to add this week so.
It may do one thing.
Let me directly copy which I already created a code because I don't want to focus it more because it's
commenting again and again.
I'm going to traverse after this.
What I needed is the more important thing is.
If address failed, which is addressed to length, basically addressed to length.
Is greater than zero, which is basically perfect condition.
I need to mention it.
Message dot set distribution open.
So I'm going to add the receiver in.
Yeah.
Dude, basically message my message not.
They are the type.
CC.
It will add type a CC.
Because my mail doesn't know that it's C C form or BC form.
So that's it.
I need to mention.
Known similar for weeks because.
Oh.
Okay.
Address to or.
Wait a minute.
This is for two adults, not be.
So do I need to mention now I have to create for CC because I created for CC first.
Now I need to mention for a CC length greater than zero.
I need to see your message.
Dorset again.
Similar things I need to mention.
Message and messages is nothing but that email feed here.
Or type c.
C.
And this is not address this is an should be this.
Oh.
And similarly for VC.
So let me just do one thing.
Let me copy this part because I need to change some variables on you.
Not everything here.
We?
She
is.
So.
Wait a minute.
Something is different here.
So whites asking me for.
Okay.
Let me check it again.
Whether there's error or something, there should not be any error.
Now it's done because I haven't decided.
So now we are done.
So I need to mention content with everything.
So this is my content type set subject to subject, subject and content type and.
Let it take that.
For using switch case, whether it's text or HTML or plain text.
So if it's email message, as you know, that is HTML and everything symbols, it will go with the HTML
tab tag.
If not, it will check for that purpose.
So.
This is my last function, which is going to transport my.
Function same meal, which is very, very easy function.
Transport Java X mean don't send direct message so it will directly handle my message.
So that's it.
Let me do one thing here.
Okay.
So.
Let me optimize my imports.
So now you can check here.
We are done with this part.
And now what I'm going to do, I'm going to add my password and email here.
So.
Are you doing this?
So here I'm going to get my email.
So let me do one thing.
Let me add my password.
Then let me add my emails.
So these are my received email.
I'm not sharing my ID thing because of safety, because I don't want to expose my ID and everything.
And if you want to check or give the full password field, I recommend you don't give just that password
or take in this.
Just try to give fully the location of your password.
So there may be some times there or not every time.
Sometimes there may be error by locating such files.
So my suggestion is give a fully fledged name to that password field.
Just copy that and you can go to go to paste that field.
So my feelings and everything is at it.
And this is the thing where I'm going to receive my email, another email.
So.
Now before proceeding with any project, let me tell you one thing here.
Always remember this bomb smell and everything we already created.
But try to turn on your or no one sitting in Gmail, which is basically very common setting allow or
least secure apps.
So our app security is very also allow it.
If you want to do this full fledged, you need to upload these files on Google Cloud.
Then you need to find the SHA256 key, you need to register everything.
So that's a complicated thing.
Instead of this, you can allow that temporary mail for that purpose, like allow the low secure apps
for your email.
So it is very helpful.
Now what I'm going to do is I need to edit configuration here.
I'm going to edit one condition.
If you don't want to do this, it's not at all required always.
But let me check my configuration.
Okay.
This is the configuration I hit click and hit run.
So it takes time to run sometimes because first time it's building where I open the ID first, this
is the first time it's going to open.
So this is the stressing part.
In the next tutorial I'm going to tell you how we can perform the receiver part.
So now you can check it's currently running and building everything, so it will take time to do this.
Once this is done, you can check here for the service purpose.
So currently my service is not started because my project is building.
So.
Forcing pool project to rebuild, basically.
So it takes time because we have too many modules surveyed for doing this all the stops.
So.
It will take time sometimes.
Don't try to interrupt this process because this is not very heavy application, but we added some normal
things also.
Then after those calls also, there may be errors as well.
I think now you can build a successful.
And you can check.
Services not started it, but it will start.
So it started the building output.
But.
Billy's completed first time, but now it's no need to run the service also.
So it may take time.
So wait for me to 3 seconds.
No, my.
You can check.
My tomcat is now running, so it will take time to run everything.
And it will give me the direct output of my team.
So wait for running part.
It will take time to run everything.
So currently it's running.
And.
It will take time for 3 seconds.
So as you can see, it's now running.
So you can see the server is connected, but artifact is now deploying on my team.
So our artifact is var and this is exploding.
So it will take time.
Two, 3 seconds to run everything.
So.
It's configuring everything.
As a hourglass preserver.
It doesn't have such power to do so.
Now you can check my email application is not working.
I need to put this mail message as test and email bodies just use.
Is X.
I mean, from Java application.
So once I click send or HTTP post is not supported by a URL because the thing is it's method not allowed
sometimes.
So in the further thing what I'm going to do, I'm going to review this and why this is showing the
error.
I will tell you this is not method alone, so we will rectify this error in lecture.
Thank you for this.
And in the further part, I'm going to explain everything and how I perform this.
I will tell you.
Hope you understand.
Thank you.