So in this video, we will be talking about the next three classes, which are bill caps, tracking
and tracking details.
So in view caps class, this class will be used to show the available caps type and their images.
So this class is defined inside the package cap booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages.
Part of this class.
And we have defined the public class webcast, which is extending the frame and implementing or enable,
and there will be 19 labels.
So these labels will be used to restore images basically, and the names as well.
And there is a label caption and there is a thread type of variability inside the public void run method.
What I am doing is visible through captioned or set multi Suzuki, so this is the name of that car and
adding that caption to the label and thread sleep for 2.8 second.
After that, setting the visibility of L two as false and for the L three as true.
So this has followed the for the one level l two.
So we will be doing the same thing for all the labels, like set the visibility of the L three as to
then will be setting its name, adding that name or caption to that label, setting the visibility of
that label as true and third slip for 2.8 second again, then set the visibility of the current label
as false.
Now for the next label, we will set the visibility as to set its caption and Toyota Fortuner then adding
that caption to that label, setting the tread slip for 2.8 second and set the visibility of the label
four as false.
Then we will be setting the visibility of the label five has true.
So its name will be Mato Suzuki Swift, adding that caption to the label tread slip for 2.8 seconds.
So this this process we will be doing for every car name.
So let me just move through this.
So this is for the Hyundai Central type of car, doing the same thing for the auto BMW x one for the
bike ride.
Then there is a guy named data is zip and DF mini truck the mini truck.
So this these will be the names of the gaps which are provided by this application.
Now what we are doing is there is the parameter is non parameter constructor of this class inside which
what we are doing is setting the bound or location and size for that frame.
And after that what we are doing is setting the background color of that frame with the help of the
RDB values and creating a new thread with the current instance and with the inside the caption There
is a new label.
We are setting the bound for that label, adding foreground and one type and family size for that,
and adding that to our frame.
After that we are creating image and adding that image to a label and setting that image location,
size, and adding that to the frame, setting the layout as null.
Now what we are doing is we are adding every image for every label, like for every car, we are adding
an image of that car.
So this is for the car one.
Similarly, this is for the car too.
And the label three.
Then there is a car three in level four.
Then there is a car four in level five.
Similarly, there is a car.
Five is stored.
Image is stored in the label.
L six.
Then there is a car six images stored in the label l seven.
Then there is a car seven images stored in the label.
LL eight.
Similarly for the car.
910 And this will be the image and in label it and then another track image and label 11.
So this is how the images are stored in the label and its names will be also stored in that particular
label.
And then we have started the thread to start, which will start running the run method and inside the
public static domain we have called the build caps dot set visible as true.
So this is how the vocab cap class will run.
We will be showing its output when we will run this project completely in our last video in the life
run video.
Now let's move on to the next class that is tracking Java.
This class will help us to book any type of truck if we want to export some heavy elements or things
so that we need a truck to export those things or goods.
So we have defined a cab booking system inside.
We have to find this class in that the cab booking system and imported the necessary packages.
After that, we have to find the trucking class, which is extending frame inside which we have a table
and three labels, three buttons and three choices.
Then we have called the new truck.
Inside the main function.
We have called the new training class with null values, then public trucking.
We have defined the parameter constructor for the trucking class.
Said the title has transport good content, a background color as color white and it said default or
close operation exit on close.
Then there's the label transport, good setting as foreground, colour as blue, setting its font,
family type size and labeling, setting its location and size and adding that to a frame.
After that, we are setting its layout as null.
Then there is a label for the source setting its font, family size, location, and the size for that
label and adding that to our frame.
Similarly, similar thing doing for the destination font, family size, location and size height width.
Adding that to our frame.
Then for the label lines defining its font and its location size and adding that our frame.
Then there is another label defining its font type size, setting its bound and adding that to our frame.
Then there is a second choice setting its bound names, bound size, location, adding that to our frame.
Then there is a C2 choice setting its bound location size, adding that to our frame.
Inside the block.
We have a stabilize the connection with our connection class and executed the results with se execute
queries query select abstract from transport so it will select the order data from the transport and
inside seven choice.
We will be adding a string from the source of that transport and destination for the transport.
All the source and destination which are provided in our transport table.
Then we will be executing our seller tax reform customer well, user name will match.
So for that particular user name, what we are doing, we are setting the names in our label anytime.
After that there is a label l11 which is for the weight.
So there will be weight also for the goods.
What like what is the weight range of the goods you want to transport or export?
Then font, family type and size and its setting, its location and size and adding that label to the
frame.
After that, there is ac3 new choice.
Hiding those choices to over adding the details to our choices.
Like 0 to 10 gives you 10 to 58, 50, 200, 300 to 50, 500 to 1000 or greater than 1000.
After then, we will set the location and size for that particular frame.
After that, there is show button setting background for one color and adding its location and size.
Then we have similarly like in previous classes we have defined for the label driver frame.
Driver name truck type truck name distance.
Price.
After that.
Header image inside the label, setting its location size and adding that to a frame.
Then we have defined the action performed inside which we inside destination.
We have stored the destination from the set of field and in its latest thing we have stored the.
Selected three from the C three choice.
After that we have executed the query select x2 from transport where destination will match and price
is close to zero.
So for that next record in the destination field destination table, we will set the driver name and
L2 field price and price is string.
Track naming and sex field and distancing.
Late label.
Then for the switch weight.
If the weight will match these cases, we will add extra prices over the default price with respect
to this price.
If the price is greater than 1000, then price will be plus 600.
L forgot sec text.
So we'll be setting the price in our label for after that there is a button one for the transport and
background and for one colour of that button setting its location of the button.
For that button.
We have defined and stored the required details in the respective end string, and after stabilizing
the connection with the database, we will delete the previous record in the table and end the latest
record with the help of this value in certain transport values.
These values will be inserted and we will execute that query.
After that, we will show that the successfully.
Then there is a cancel button which will be used to close this window.
Setting the size of the frame will be 1600 and its location for 15 to 20, setting as visibility as
true.
So this is all about how we can book our truck to export or send transport over the source and destinations.
So let's see the next class, which is the tracking details.
So it will show the tracking details of how many details you have booked.
It will show the latest booking detail, basically.
So we are this class is extending also frame inside which you have defined the panel content, pain
and even choice.
We have defined inside the main method public void run inside which we have created the current instance
of the indicated details, class and center as true.
After that, what we are doing is creating a parameterized.
Constructor for that class, setting the size for that content pane.
Defining the panel.
Adding it to our content pane and layout as well.
Then we are adding our image icon with the help of a label label on setting bound and location for that
label.
After that.
Similarly, as we did in the previous classes, we are creating a level, setting its font type size
and its location and size and adding that to our content pane.
Similarly, there is another for the customer name.
It's respect on a label from the driver name.
It's respect on a label.
For the source destination name.
Then there is a label for the weight, distance and price.
After that, what we are doing is creating a connection.
After that, inside the results that statement say dot execute query select extract from customer where
username will match will be storing null in the string name.
After that, we will set the text from the name field in our one label and store the name in our store
string name.
After that, we'll be executing select action from Internet in transport.
Their name will match and we will store the required details in our two, three, four, five, six
and l seven and eight table.
Now we will be generating a random number with the help of a random class.
And after that what we are doing is are stored close.
So actually this is not required, I think random because it is a view tracking details.
So we will not using that.
After that, what we are doing is we are closing the iris connection and there is a button exit which
will help us to move back from this window and send the possibility of the current window as false,
its location, setting as location and size and background and foreground, color as black and white
respectively, adding that to our content pane.
And then we will selecting the complete background color of the window as white.
So this is all about the three classes view caps.
So which view caps class will show us the variable details of the caps?
Tracking the file will help us to book a track to exporting or transporting any goods.
And after that, there is a of tracking details which will show us the latest detail of about the.
Track which we you have user have booked for the export exporting goods.
So this is all about these three classes in this video.