So in this part, we are going to create a currency converter using the Yahoo API.
So here we will go to the file menu and create our new project.
We made this converter.
Be.
And this source package will create a new freeform animators converter.
Now we will need to do a part here,
a panel here.
And now we will take a nibble here and you test this one here.
This will be the amount that you want to convert from.
It will ask and go to the editor and write in the amount.
And now we need a text field.
The Sun.
It's clear.
It will change to variable name
currency amount.
To make it some bigger.
Now we need to have the list for the currency fund.
So let's just this one here.
And it this currency from.
Another label to ask the currency to.
Currency to.
Can you guarantee from?
But one good got to know.
Now we will select where the list will be stored.
So.
So gonna scroll?
No.
We can take combo box here.
This one.
Simply put it to this duplicate.
We said it here.
No Google properties here.
Okay.
These days.
We have this one box of these.
And go do it.
And here you will set up a list.
I already have my list here.
Simply copy this.
Simply paste this list here.
This is done.
Same thing with this.
Born and raised here we have a list here.
We simply run this first.
Let me close.
So here we have a to basically.
Doing on our streets, which we have selected from this list.
The
same goes with this.
Who cares what we have done with that part?
Do we have a precise first?
So basically this is the list.
So here we have this kind of called the variable name.
And we.
Mm.
Couldn't see from.
And this will minimize the currency to.
This will be the currency to hear.
No.
We need to tenure.
This will really convert.
Change the variable name, then convert.
Listen, we didn't convert.
Now we need a label who basically have the value of the conversion.
So
we will put this on.
Teens already will need to
display.
Okay.
So it's done.
No.
We need to function this button first.
We will go to this button.
Convert action form.
We will write the code.
First it takes us a step to collect the actual values.
So basically let's have.
Let's get the amount first.
So will write
the amount first.
To convert.
So to take string.
Quoting the text.
So
to write.
Couldn't see a moon or get texture.
The sun.
No check for numbers only.
Another step we will take to check that it's number or not.
So check the numbers here.
So we will take the for loop here so I can do zero.
And I is less than.
Good is the amount text not length plus plus.
Not this for loop.
It check character is a digit.
So here we will write if.
I do not
institute.
So here, if it is not there, it's probably a number.
So you will try the currency amount?
Not.
Got at this one.
So we need a text box to convert.
So we need a dialogue to.
G option.
I'm sure.
Message.
Dialogue.
We need a message dialogue here.
Who need this.
In the evening will be
what we will write, please, and a valid amount.
First, we need to focus, of course.
So we will write.
Good into your mind.
Now I request focus.
Moonshine.
Okay.
Who we have in this part.
After this, we will set the focus and then return first.
This will be a.
And this will be written over text first and then now includes.
We have the text.
Let's see.
Reset the display result.
So after this, we will write this display, not text.
Get currency from the get currency to.
We will take.
We will leave a string.
Here we have the string.
So here we will write.
We need.
Careened from text.
We need a good and strong law to get selected text.
The third value would not speak to the value.
It slipped her index or the item first and then to string.
And after this we need the same thing.
But according to text here
Gooding, do not get select selected items not to strip.
Basically we get the selected value and the two string converts to the string.
So.
Who would we have done this thing?
I know.
So before we have now here's the thing.
The way current text is designed, this one, it saves you if it saves you an.
We get the actual code from the value, you will just say string area.
So what we need is a string array.
Mm.
And we know
that we need current phone banks and we need a split.
Hmm.
Could we get this?
Semicolon.
Basically, we need.
Trying.
Wouldn't.
We need I think we need a current from tax to.
So we are split that we need.
Going from title here.
So we'll go right from title
to this part.
After this.
We need string.
So we would have attempted this rule rewrite.
Current text.
No.
We need a current to text into text.
We need a current string
theory to.
We need new according to texture and set it to the temp zero position here.
And after this we need another string going to cool and set it to one position here.
So here we have done this on a temporary one.
Basically, we have the values of a tax to which to.
That will be the title here.
Now we can post a URL that we can access from Yahoo!
So we need your oral part under this.