In previous video, we learned how we can create method and how we can learn.
In further, I'm going to explain how we can store this information into one file.
So let us see.
I'm going to specify public void again.
Public void.
Store file.
Method.
Store file method.
This is just a method.
Now I want to I am going to use your file return for that I already use or imported this library java.
This is very important library for file method.
So.
Before file method, you should throw the user defined exception for that purpose.
I'm going to use your try.
Trick edge is very simple user defined exception methods.
Or we can say it is not very user defined.
We can say it is error handling method system dot dot println or the error handling.
So let us see inside this this how we can create file writer.
In is equal to new file writer.
You have to specify the is the.
And basically location of that file or you can say that info if you are not giving that part.
You can just put file name here, but it will create in the system default.
But in my case, I'm going to use your desktop location file, which I already created.
So just I'm putting the full part.
Always remember you should do the full part for.
In for texting while you're giving different file for that purpose.
If you are going to use the same file inside your project or you are going to create, you can just
put that name on file name.
After that.
I want to put that part in.
Right.
What I'm going to write is here is first name because there is no nothing mentioned that is first name
or something.
So.
Similarly, I'm putting your first name here.
Then not.
I'm not going to write it again.
I'm going to append it.
So I'm going to append it.
Your only.
Last name.
Okay.
You can put your slash in.
Always remember slash in.
This dot alarm.
Again, not open.
Similarly, I'm going to put everything here now.
Email every.
Everything.
So similarly, this.
Like that, you can put everything.
Email.
Then in not open.
Password.
Ideally, you should not store any password, but I'm considering this as a database.
So I'm putting this as.
In a password also.
Then what happened?
Smashing.
Or capacity again.
Capacity.
Let's.
This is not what his name is.
Male capacity.
Not.
Append.
Or alternate.
AlterNet made.
Let's.
Would this not alternate me?
Email.
What is the image?
That's it.
Now I'm going to close this.
Always remember, this is best practice.
To close everything.
And just system dot.
Outdoor rental in.
Data stored.
That's it.
Now.
This is what story we need to create for reading, but also similarly.
Reading.
While.
Method.
Public void.
It should not be public, but for.
System convenience.
I'm going to use this part really redefine.
Similarly you are going to use edge here for.
Exception handling exception E.
Sys node dot println e.
Instead this.
You're going to handle it.
Yet.
I'm going to use file reader.
Method Java you can use input stream.
These are very efficient thing your output stream input stream it will serialize it, serialize it.
These are very helpful but due to time constraint and also there is no need to put everything.
I'm just going to use this.
So file name as mentioned in the store file, I'm going to copy this part.
The Court also just based it.
And when the time comes.
And then just I'm creating polenta because it will loop through the characters.
And so it is very difficult to understand, but it is very helpful, vital for the small, small part
and project if name not.
There is some default till that.
What is that part?
Still.
Not equal to minus one, which is basically not null.
What it will do.
It will print system, dot, dot, print in the console.
What will you print?
It will print.
Correct stinks because it will access that in what we can say in the integer part.
But I want to print it as a character so it will ask for character.
Once this one is done.
I'm going to close.
Your connection is close.
And this part is done.
If you want, you can put your one system dot dot println statement just this to give the gap.
And we are done with this, but we haven't created anything in that main part.
So as you know, for this, I want I will extend that part.
So as 50 exist but now if part is for the store data in.
But you.
No sixth option is for.
Display data from.
And now the seven parties for exit.
Similarly, we are going to change this in this part.
Fifth part is as it is, but.
I'm going to change this statement.
To what?
To store that data.
M one dot.
Store, lady.
Then four after break condition is six.
Ian.
We're not.
Redefine.
Precondition again.
Then seven is no.
System Dot.
Old friend Ellen.
Thank you for using.
I would.
Application.
And then again.
But now we are going to change this condition also.
So now we are done with our project part.
Let's run this part and I will explain how you can create some Java file here with the Java Archive
file.
So let's run this part.
Arun.
So it will ask for first name.
James.
B So new employee his name is James.
B I'm setting it for sales department.
I will ask for the show info so it will show info.
Now you can understand each time this is different and it is not taking numbers.
Now you can see it is just putting some random variables and everything.
Spoonful.
Then I want to store it into the file store, into the data store.
As you can see, destroyed into the file.
If I'm putting display data, you can see now this is printing to this.
Now you will understand why this is printing to this.
So you need to change something here.
You will understand what we did.
Mistake here is as this is done.
But before that.
Or in the choice.
Wait a minute.
In the store file.
I'm printing this statement.
This will create some error so you can remove this part.
And also just remove this slash and also it will create step by step.
So it is very difficult to understand.
So always never give the slash in this part.
Now I will run it again and I will show you.
So.
This is all about our application.
I will put it in James V.
Sales department again.
It's stolen data file.
Display that data.
You can see our data is displaying.
Oh, now.
Let us see.
Wait a minute.
I made one error also print.
Just put print here.
And also you slash in here to our debt error.
Selection, selection, selection, selection and selection leather.
Let's run it again.
Now we debug with our problem.
As you can see, it's printing character by character because of the print statement.
No.
I'm going with print statement.
Jim's.
Me since department store into that data display data.
So as you can see, it is displaying the data capacity and everything.
So now we are done with our project, but let's see how we can create one single file or we can see
some single jar file Java archive file for executing this part.
We are already done with our project.
So as I told you, we are going to create one single executing file with our project.
So for this purpose, go to this file option project structure.
But.
In what you can see this first dialog box but go to artifacts here.
But this button jar file and we want to create with dependencies, modules, e-mail application.
So as you put something here, it will automatically detect this part.
Class.
We need to put in class.
Click.
Okay.
Once it is okay, click again.
It should be system default.
Don't change anything here.
Then click apply and then enter.
Okay.
Now the artifact is loaded, but we want to build it.
So go to build here and create this build artifacts.
So it will do optional.
Build what?
Rebuild clean.
Added something.
So build.
So it will take time to build as you can see in the dialog box here bottom.
It is building this and it is doing so.
It will take time to build.
As for our project requirements, our project requirements are very less in this.
So now you can see in the output and artifacts, you can see this email just by email application file.
So if you want to run this part, you can you have to edit the configuration.
So go to this table edit configuration part here.
You will see this dialog box click add new button here.
Then there is a huge list for this.
So go to down here.
Or inside this, you can.
You have to identify this job application.
Job application here.
Click enter.
You can give the name.
I'm going.
The name has email app, local machine and you the job part here.
So in this job part is always in out artifacts and this you can see what we can apply.
Now you can run this email app, but and as you can see, this is printing this everything.
So our job file is running.
That class we are running now.
We are running with Java.
Let's see how we can run the command prompt itself.
So I'm going to pause this part and I will show how we can
do this in the command prompt.
So let's run our.
Java, Java, slash Java.
And that name of your job.
You.
So you can see this is running.
I'm again putting this James be then as developmental and info as you can see in printing similarly
like that you can create one application.
So this is very basic application we are going to use, but you can move further with that any part
like you can create Java if you for this and anything.
So let us see what we achieve in this.
So as you can see, we created one part if name.
So for the overview of our project, we created one random method.
We use that to create email application.
So we created different methods and we are using this.
So this is all about our project Java application.
Thank you.