No.
The last condition to stop the game or to just keep playing when the user or the computer reach at the
five score.
So here we will take the condition.
If.
Your wins is equal to five or.
Computer wins is equal to five.
What we will do.
We will take a hint.
Yes.
No.
Okay.
So we will take a yes no and store.
No, we need we need to, we need to go with the option.
Right.
So we will write G option.
We need to show a confirm dialog first.
So here we will write.
We need the three parameters.
So we will take this one and here we will give null.
So it will come in the center of the window and give the message here.
The new game.
Okay.
Right.
We will give this plea again.
Last one.
Here.
The option will be our G option being not yes, no option.
And done so.
Okay.
So here you will write.
If.
Okay, we have to take the result in our variable also.
So here will give the name.
Yes.
No is equal to.
So if.
Yes.
No.
Is equal to zero.
So what do I do to change Apple Computer not set icon with none.
And when we said label.
And you, Lord said Pinecone, that no part on your wings is equal to zero and computer wings also equal
to zero.
Near the Chili Bowl score by your score, not subtext.
Give the parameter to string value and search it with your rules, which we have initialized with the
zero here and again.
Same goes with the computer score.
So here.
Computer score.
Dot set.
Text string note values.
Right of here.
The computer.
School.
We need computer rules.
So here, don't simply run our program here.
So here, take the questions.
So 108, the paper Scissor one one.
Now The Scissor versus Rogue.
One, two.
Paper versus rock.
Two, two rock versus a32 rock versus rock draw.
Simply here we get the result.
Rock and.
All courses through four to last one there.
Okay.
So here's the paperwork versus is of for three and the last condition is the scissor versus paper.
So we have the score five three.
So user wins.
So it will ask play a new party or whatever.
So simply press no, it will keep just being.
Then again ask.
So yes.
And it.
So this is our program.