So what we have done in our part, firstly we have done with the game design.
At this stage we have defined the properties the size, the size of the playing field and tiles, which
is the number of spots in the field.
The tiles is a tag which is one dimensional array of integers.
Each tag will receive a unique value in the range zero with the tiles, and here zero.
This zero denotes an empty square.
And another one is the blank pools which will the position of the empty square.
Now what is the game logic?
So we need to define a reset method used to initialize a new game position.
We have to define a reset method used to initialize a new position.
So we set the value for each element of the target.
Well, then we put blank position in the last question of where we put the blank position with the last
question of memory.
So we need to shuffle the matter in need the shuffle marker to shuffle an area of tag so we do not include
an empty tag in the shuffling process to leave it in the former position.
So after that shuffling method, since only half of the possible starting position of the puzzle have
a solution.
So we need to check the resulting mixing result to make sure that the current layout is generally solved.
So to do this, we define the solvable method here.
For solving the layout, the current layout, and check the mixing results.
So if a specific tag is preceded by the higher value here, this one.
This is considered an inversion, so an empty tag is in place.
The number of inversions must be even for the puzzle to be solvable.
So we found the number of inversions return true.
If the number is even here, the return true if the number is even and it's important to define the
is on this matter to check if our game of the is alignment is resolved or not.
So first we looked at the where?
The empty tag.
The blank tile.
Okay.
So we look at the empty tag as if the initial position, then the current alignment is a new one which
has not been decided before.
Then we iterate, then we treat with the tiles in the reverse order here.
And if the tag value differs from the corresponding plus one index, it will return false.
Otherwise it is time to return true at the end of the method because the puzzle has already been solved.
Now we need another method to define the new game.
Do we need another marker to define a new game?
It is required to create a new instance of the game.
So to do this, we reset the playing field, shuffle it, and then continue until the playing position
is resolvable.
So after that, finally, we need to program the movement of the spots in the area.
This code will be all set up all back to respond to cursor movement.
Our game will support multiple tile moves simultaneously.
Thus, after we converted the press position on the screen in the tag, we get the position of the amplitude
and look for the direction of movement to support several of its movement at the same time.
So here we have done that thing.
Now next thing, which we have done.
We have left the UI on the swing API.
So it's time to do the interface.
So first we take the G pattern class.
Here we have the cheap panel glass and we draw spots on the field.
So to calculate the grid size of each, we will use the data specified in constructor parameter of a
grid size equal to the minus two multiplied by margin, and the tile size is equal to the grid size,
which is divided by the size margin is also a parameter specified in the game constructor.
Now you need to now you need to define the draw grid method.
To draw the here, here.
So now we need to define the draw grid matter to draw a grid on the spots on the screen.
Analyze the array of tags and convert the coordinates to the coordinates of the user interface.
Then we draw each tag with the corresponding number in the center.
So here we have done that thing.
Now, finally, we define we redefine the paint component method, which is a derivative of the in class.
This one, it is a derivative of the JP class.
When we use the draw grid method and after that we use a draw start message method to display a message
promoting us to click to start again, click to start new green.
Or then we need, we need to respond to the user actions in the UI.
So we have already seen that part.
Through some of the user action in the UI.
In order for the game to take its course, it is necessary to process user actions in UI.
So to do this, we add the mouse listener here.
This one, the mouse listener implementation on the G panel and the core.
This one is the core for moving the already shown here.
So we place the code in the constructor of the game 15 class and at the very end here.
Here we call the new game method to start a new game.
So here we will see
this.
This output of our game.
So I have already solved half of the puzzle.
Now we need to see that part.
So here I will do EA three for c click to start new game on here.
And this is my solid puzzle here.
And I have done that part.
Now what we have to do.
Click the start menu now.
Simply click on it and it will start a new game here and already shuffle.
So this will be our project.