In previous tutorials, I told you about how we can create participants, sign up and everything.
So after the admin is log in and have to write to create event number, event name with coordinator,
name, coordinator, number, fee, venue, date and etc., etc..
So you can add your own things inside this.
It depends on your scenario, your creation.
So for this case, you need to create one HTML file so you can create one servlet file directly.
But simple case, you can create one HTML file.
So as I told you, as these are the event details and everything, so.
After the parties admin is login.
So I created one page name as admin event page basically like for creating and accepting everything
from the admin.
So in this disease and this admin event page or event details page and inside this admin event page,
what it shows, it shows event details and transaction details.
So this is very simple.
I created with links.
So for the event details, I need to create one event detail which shows the create event link and view
event link.
So these are again the links.
So for the creative end link, as I told you, create e dot html, i created one file.
So this is very important step here.
So for this purpose, what I created, I created a one form method.
What is the form inside?
This is I already told you.
Then I'm going to use one Soviet name as an event.
As you can see, add event here and method is boost again with event number.
Event name, coordinator number coordinator name everything.
Fee for registration.
Venue for event.
Date of event.
So I'm considering this all as a string.
Not considering anything you can consider as some date for a date field and as equal to that.
So for that purpose you need to change into the database connection and everything.
So this is very simple case I'm choosing here.
So this is just creating one form method inside HTML and action is add event.
So for the storing purpose, what I'm going to create, I'm going to create one package or servlet inside
the source packages.
So as I told you, what is this package, Java servlet.
So similarly like that we are going to create Java servlet.
But before that I'm going to tell you some methods in servlet, servlet interfaces then basically the
DVC connection and etc..
So in this create HTML, we just created one form method with ADD event.
So before that, you need to create one separate table or database for an event.
Also, I'm going to further tell you about that also, but I will add some images of creation of table
and everything inside this.
So before that, let's see what is the GBC connection and etc.?
We already gone through how we can create the GC connection, but we don't know about the basic scenario.
So for this purpose, I'm going to tell you the basic scenario about GBC connection.
So as I told you, we have already gone through with gate and post method in Java solid.
So these are the main methods inside the Java solid.
But we can use some other servlet interfaces also like servlet interfaces.
What are the solid interfaces?
Basically object of servlet request is used to provide the client request information to servlet such
as content type content length, parameter names, values header information attribute means the information
that you type on the HTML page or HTML scenario or HTML form.
We can use servlet request for that.
So like there are several different methods for servlet interfaces like public string git parameter
is one method parameter values this one method enumeration with git parameter names method means it
will use the parameter names for that purpose, get lent, then characters encoding, etc. etc. So there
are too many methods already created.
These are the by default method.
So we can say default method inside this.
So this is all about the servlet request interfaces.
So what is basically request dispatcher and this method works, I will tell you later.
But before that, let's see what is GDC connection?
So in GDC Java, GBC stands for Java Database Connectivity, GDB sees Java API to connect and execute
query related to the database.
So GBK is a very stable API since the database and Java are deployed, gbk is very standard Java API
we are going to use here.
So for different databases like my Haskell has a different VPC, then Oracle had different DBC for the
deployment on the servers.
PostgreSQL is also used or different nowadays.
MongoDB is also used for that purpose, so they have some different gives connection GBK drivers we
can say use.
So what we are using all jtbc's oracle GDC API basically.
So inside that oracle gbk java API the statements, skills, statements and related queries already
written.
So while just we are writing this, it will also use the user connection.
So it is java is C standard edition part and gdb c API uses GDB drivers to connect the database.
So now always remember there are four types of GBC drivers or DB bridge drivers which are basically
we are using the bridge connecting drivers.
So as we are using localhost, we are using this native drivers are basically specified to the specific
databases.
So our case is Oracle database, but it's not a native driver because these are some bridge drivers.
Native driver means if you created some dedicated database or your different database on some or storage,
then it's a native driver.
We are a network protocol driver and team driver we are going to use.
So again, there are two types like we are also using clean driver also of Oracle, not only the bridge
driver, we are also using the driver.
Three driver means it sets some minimum requirements and some minimalistic or simple kind of Java database
connection.
So we can use the Java A.C peer to access the tabular data stored in the relational databases.
So we are going to use relational databases.
Other than that, MongoDB is very advanced database, which is a new skill and everything.
So we are going to save update delete page data from the database through the GDB.
See so how the GBC works actually.
So this is GDC API.
This is our java application.
This is our end database.
So GBK API.
So through the Java application we are accessing both database driver for the database and GBK API.
So this is very simple.
So far, the GDP of Oracle database.
I already told you we have to create one driver class first or to access everything here.
Then we have to the Excel.
Always remember that is Oracle GDP driver, not Oracle driver.
Then our connection.
You are in connection URL for the Oracle thingy database.
You have to use this thing localhost with that portal port number.
Now remember, this port number is always the always XY Oracle service name and everything.
So you can check for that information.
DNS names.
Alright, that's a file inside the database file.
You can always, always find these information if your port is different for the local list.
User name for is very important.
Default is system.
I'm going to use your default username.
You can create your own user.
You can use the password also.
Before that, I already told you how you can change that sort of database.
We have to execute this thing for the changing the code.
But always remember, if you change the port, you have to see these file DNS names or a file inside
this to check your port number to change the connection you are also.
Other than that, you can change the classes forward.
So for this project I saw the error that are mostly the class.
Three servers cannot be deployed because it's using same port as Oracle.
It's also using 88 port and G+, which is also using 88 port.
You have to change the either port, like for the Oracle database or for the Class V server.
So the port changing the free server is very easy.
Just go to that config file and change it.
I already told you in the previous some lectures that how you can change this port to another port.
So I am going to use 2002 port in the last V server.
But before this, if you don't want to change that port, you can change this port.
Also using this query, execute the VMs and this is SDB.
This is please query basically to 2002.
You have to change this port.
But again, remember you have to change this into the connection you are also.
So before that you should know how we can create table and how you are inserting data, how you are
paging basic SQL basics things here.
So this is all about the ABC, so let us move how we can create the form method or how we can execute
this form method.
So let us see how we can see this.
So we already created this part for the for method using create event HTML and we are going to add event
in the HTML page.
Or on from the steam page to the database.
So simple method I'm going to use first.
Invoke all the libraries first, which is basically import import Java audio and all Java school and
servlet libraries.
Then public class advantage, HTTP servlet, which extends to that ADD event.
So this is called, as you can say, we are extended to the HTML.
So let's.
Class or default method or default class.
So I'm going to use your again public word dupes you can either use do it also here, but I'm using
too many things or I'm going to say too many things and do get method will restrict me for some time
or of some cases.
So I'm going to use Duplass method.
Always remember you have to create some table request and then HTTP response.
So late response which throws or solid exception.
So you have to handle the exceptions also here.
Then you have to create a response at content, time, text or email.
I told you the significance of this.
I am again telling you while you are writing some HTML tags inside Java.
So what it will do I want if the event is added, I want to show the event added theme or event added
length of all things.
So what you are going to do?
I'm going to invoke some tags here, like h two, h three inside the HTML.
But while using these tags it will show me the error like element or like inside that it will show for
the full tag, not the error, but it's a visual bug we can see.
So for that purpose, set content type is text or HTML.
So Java will take care that this is the HTML tag.
So we present on that HTML as HTML page.
Or if it's a text show, it says it takes page.
So print that for the response.
Get writer.
So for this purpose now I'm going to fetching the data from the HTML page.
Pitching data from HTML form.
Again, I'm telling always remember these names and these names should be always same.
These are all things.
Connection with database.
Again, we already have seen for the login why we have to use the track because.
It.
It makes you the some escalator.
So we have to handle that.
So you can either specify this inside.
Like this also throws exception, stability exception, glaucoma school exception.
But I don't want to explain everything.
So this is using close.
It will not show me the proper error.
So for showing the proper error and for the proper event, the error handling or exception handling,
I'm going to use your trick educator.
So class not for name reading class then connection URL string name username then connection driver
manager to establish the connection I will again come in this part also establish connection.
You can either put some out dot print statement also here that is System.out.println and that connection
is successful and everything.
But you have to check, always check the command prompt inside your ID or your executing part.
So I don't want to check everything again and again.
So statement I'm going to create one statement.
So to insert these into the event database.
That I have already created inside this.
To insert this into the event database, what I'm going to do, I'm going to execute very insert into
event what is the values.
So I'm going to insert these values.
So I'm putting a one, two, three, four, five, six, seven to the this and I'm going to insert inside
this similarly, like we are going to insert in our login page or sign up page or the participants similarly
like that, I'm going to use this 1a2838485 and 867.
I'm going to put always remember close this with semicolon then resource statement, query and all the
things include the database.
I'm going to include this event edit statement and it should remain on the same page then system of
println to print this to the command prompt that added to the database, committing that because it
will end that part there.
So it will not show any anomaly there and contact clause for closing the connection.
So that's it about how we can create this.
In further case, I'm going to tell you how we can create transaction history and everything, but also
what is the difference between include and forward?
So let us see how we can create that part also.