So till now we have covered everything about the class account class and inside the option menu.
Plus we have covered the logging part.
Then the choosing, the type of account like which type of account the user wants to make the transactions
into.
Now our next concern is to create a function or like separate functions for both the saving account
and our checking account.
So the options displayed by both of the accounts should be covered within the different like separate
function.
So this public void get saving is going to be the function for savings account.
And the argument we are going to pass is the account.
So the type of account is going to be the argument for this get saving function.
Now inside this in a similar way, we will be using a boolean data type for MN.
Initially it will be set to false.
So if we are in the working mode, we are inside the saving account so not is equal to end.
So when we are inside the savings account and we have not entered this process, so what will happen
using a drive lock?
And so we have to system dot dot print in all the five choices which are to be made in order to.
Oh, yes.
Make any specific tasks, whether it be New Balance, withdraw deposit funds or transfer funds to the
checking accounts.
So writing the choices, using this out for.
For the first function, the type one.
So that type one is for view balance.
So type one view balance.
So this is the first choice inside the savings account and other choices will be made in the similar
way.
Okay, so inside the get saving function, we have like set all the type, like the choices to be made
inside the savings account, whether it be view, balance, withdraw funds, deposit and transfer funds.
And these are the list of choices inside the savings accounts.
Now we are like using switch cases for any of the options.
If the user chooses, then what is going to happen?
So if the user chooses to view the balance, then it is going to like output savings account balance
and like the variable is used for get savings balance.
So we have already created the get saving balance thing inside the account class.
So it is going to like access that balance from that class inside this option menu class.
Now second case is to like withdraw saving money.
And the third one is forget saving deposit.
And the fourth one is the transfer input.
So we have created all of them inside the account class, whether it be the saving transfer calculation,
whether it be the saving withdraw input or the saving deposit input, the transfer input is going to
be the same in both, whether it be the checking account or the savings account.
So yes, this is going to be displayed whenever the user's calls for saving, withdraw or saving deposit
options.
After this, upward transfer inputs for savings.
And if the user hits five, then the process is going to be end and the user will like exit this drive
low.
And back to the main menu.
Like we have already encountered inside the working part.
So this is all about the saving class.
Now, our next concern is to create a similar class like this saving class for the checking class.
So, yes, we are going to make that class also.
So for the checking account type, it is going to display the similar choices as the savings account.
All the five choices are going to be similar or the difference will arrive just in the switch cases.
So if like it is going to display the balance, then the balance will be displayed for the get checking
balance.
It is going to call the get checking balance method inside the account.
Plus, we have created this.
So this is going to display the get checking balance function and it will be returned.
So yes, similarly for the to draw like checking with the draw input and checking deposit input.
So all of them are going to be accessed from the account plus as we have used the get method also for
the transfer input.
So if we want to transfer the input from the checking account to the savings account, then there is
a dedicated function inside the account or Java for transferring money.
We have a yes in the last part of the account.
Plus we have covered the transfer input thing, which is covering both the check checking and the savings
accounts.
So yes, this is going to like output the other choices accordingly, whether it be the checking and
the savings.
So we are covering right now the checking account.
Then this is going to happen.
Okay.
So we are done with both the get checking function and the get saving function.
So yes, navigating through the slides, savings accounts, these options.
So suppose if you choose this view balance, then this will be yes, the switch case will be executed.
And similarly for all the options, the get methods is like activated and that specific function will
be performed.
Now what's left like?
We have to create our account for the new user.
We have meant created a function right now like till now we have not created any function for creating
an account.
So our next concern is to create a function for creating a new account.
So yes, this public void create account is going to create a new account for our like not already existing
customer.
And we have like customer number which is initially set to zero.
And inside the try block, our user is asked to enter the customer number and like the iterator will
enter like get the entry by the customer and map it to that specific pin number so every customer number
will be mapped to his or her PIN number and which is going to be unique.
Like no other user can use that customer number again for making a new account.
So this is responsible for handling that.
And also the customer number could be an integer.
No other data type will be allowed for customer number.
Okay.
So this customer number is already registered will be displayed if our user inputs already existing
customer which we have already discussed that the customer number should be unique for every user now.
So if the user enters anything except integers, then it is going to be input.
Miss the mismatch exception and the invalid choice text will be displayed on the screen.
Now for the pin number in the similar way things will be checked, but a PIN number could be, you know,
like same for multiple users.
Just the customer number needs to be unique for every user.
So we are not checking things like this.
Customer number is already registered.
A pin can be like similar for more than one users.
So after the entering of customer number and pin number, your account will be successfully registered
to the system and now you can like use the benefits inside the ATM management system.
Now, after this, we are checking the main menu.
So the main menu is about.
Inside this.
This is the main menu.
So after the successful logging, what is going to be displayed?
Checking account, savings account and everything.
So whenever a user enters this atrium project, then two things will be displayed.
Type one for logging in and type two for creating a new account.
So inside the main menu we are using try and catch block for login and creating account.
So suppose if a user gets like logins, he or she is already existing user to the ATM system.
Then get login will be called from the account dot java class.
We have already created the get logging function inside this and similarly for creating account we have
just created.
So create account is going to simply navigate the user to create account.
And after this create account, everything will be transferred in the similar way for the get login
method we have created inside the account class.
So this is the main menu after which yes, we have exception.
Checking if the user enters wrong choices.
We have only two options type one and type two.
So anything apart from it will be like regarded as invalid.
And after the end, like suppose user enters.
So if the user enters exit in the end we have yes.
So account.
We do not want to access any of the account.
We simply want to exit the project.
So if we type three, then this system is going to print.
Thank you for using this item and the menu input is going to be closed and system will be exit.
So this is all about the options menu plus we have covered so far.
So we have options for everything from the start to begin.
We have covered everything the log in, the savings account, the checking account and everything with
the view, balance and withdraw, deposit and transfer and then exiting it.
So till now we have covered all the three classes that count, plus the main class and the options menu
plus.
Now let us try to like run this project and see that what actually happens.
Everything is working correctly or not, and if there will be any bugs, then we will be debug debugging
them and then again trying to run them.
So yes, this idiom, not Java, is responsible for testing and running.
So we are running the.
Glass.
And inside this we are going to suppose create a new account customer number.
PIN number and then redirected to logging.
Okay.
So I think we have entered the wrong.
So yes, let us check that section.
Okay.
So wrong customer number.
So exception is working correctly now.
Entering the right.
Been an customer number.
Now let us try to enter inside the checking account or deposit some money.
So suppose we want to deposit 10,000.
Then the balance is changed.
Now let us try to transfer some funds to the savings account.
Suppose we want to transfer 2000 then the current checking account balances updated to 8000.
And so let us try to exit and enter in the savings account and check the balance.
So perfect savings account balances 2000 Checking account balances is 8000.
The transferring is working correctly, the view balance feature is working correctly and navigating
between the type of account is also working correctly.
So till now we have covered everything about this ATM management system.
I hope that you all have gained much idea about what this project is trying to explain to us, what
are the concepts behind it?
And I encourage you all to make this project on your own and learn these concepts pretty well.
And I hope that after the successful completion of this project, you all must be aware about all the
concepts of Java ops classes and objects and everything about the data structure we have used, like
input output, exception, hash maps and the scanner in Java.
Like we are using the scanner in the most main thing inside this project.
So yes, the mapping the scanner and everything you will be aware about.
So I am completing this project on a good note and will thank you all for joining this session.
So yes, try this on your own and thank you.