Hello, everyone.
So till now, we have created all the classes which are going to be required inside this contact repository
interface application.
We have created the main class which will be responsible for testing and running of the application.
We have created this contact class, which is like performing the getting and setting, like accessing
and updating of the labels of the form.
We have created this repository and object repository class which are like handling the key value per
thing or listing every thing inside the form in the form of a key and a value.
So specific action is like attached to specific key.
So yes, this repository is helping us to update, remove and extract data which is stored inside the
repository or for specific saved content.
So this repository makes both the repository and object repository has made the extracting and storing
of the data very convenient.
Now in the last part we have created this GSC Frame class, which is basically the frame inside which
the yes, the concept stands, whether it be the repository or the form are contained inside.
So yes, this frame.
Is containing fields for all of.
Yes, this is for the contact site and this is for the contact information site.
We have a division between both of them.
The contacts and the contacts is one mission.
We have set our layout and our like size border everything to both of the sections inside the frame.
So inside the contact information, we have set of labels for the first name, last name and all of
the like required labels inside the form.
And also we have set the line drop and the for the notes and the address labels.
So the line rep is going to be work inside this.
Our line will be changed once this like we have set the size to 20.
So if this 20 is full, then the line will automatically change and the input will start appearing from
the next line.
So yes, till then we have covered all the three buttons we move, update and add.
We have now attached action to all three of them.
Now in this part we are going to add all the labels state fields repository to the contact frame, like
the contact frame we have created.
So once creating all the things we have to add in order to make them visible to the frame.
So yes, this layout is going to be like this, how things are going to be added.
So firstly, the panel, the title panel is going to be attached.
The contacts title and the contact information later to that are like we have to add a gap between them
here.
There is a short gap between both the sections and in the next part we are adding like the labels or
the first name.
Last name would send everything to the frame.
So this training helps us to that, like aligning of the elements inside the frame.
So once the there is the end of a line, then automatically it should change its alignment to the next
line.
So first name after that trailing then last name email.
For the phone number, for web address, for address, and for everything.
So we have used trailing for that purpose.
Yes.
So adding components inside the frame is done with the help of dot add keyword.
We have already discussed this in the previous part.
So yes, this add this adds a group.
So add group for the.
We have two sequences, contacts and contact information.
So basically there are two groups.
Now adding components helps us to like align things one by one, add components in a parallel group
with specified alignment.
So we have like a decided alignment above here.
Now after earning.
All of them inside the frame.
So the frame is looking like this.
There is a blob that is a vertical gap between this block and this block.
So this vertical grouping is done.
Ted.
Said Vertical group.
So between both the vertical groups are basically that are two vertical gaps, one between these two
blocks and one between this label and the text field.
So this vertical group is for the like, what's the gap between the label and the text field?
So that is label for all of them.
First name, last name, email.
And then after that text, we'll attach it to that.
So this related keyword is used to attach that text field and basically that label and the text field
are going to be related.
Like this first name is related to this text field or not or other text fields.
So all of the text fields are related to their specific labels and there should be no overlapping in
any manner.
That specific relation is unique for all of the labels and which is done here with the help of this
related.
Now, yes.
Till now we have covered all the groupings are in alignment.
Thanks.
Now in the next part.
Here it is, Java String Group layout.
So this group layout is managed inside this like a method layout function and this method is managing
the panels, whether it be this panel or this panel.
So the layout of the panels is managed inside.
This are the default size that is for both of the panels.
Here it is set to 208 by default.
So you can see that the panel is like a little distance from the left side and this much distance from
the bottom border.
So, yes, this is for the sizing of both the panels.
And later, we have used this back pivot in order to pack all of them inside the window.
So this pack keyword enables packing all of the panels inside the window itself.
So once we minimize our maximize it, it resizes itself accordingly.
With the help of this pack, now that we have set the layout and grid the layout of all of the panels
inside the frame.
So the next concern is to add action looseness to the button.
So we have created like text fields and three buttons.
So the actions attached to the buttons are going to be listed here.
So once we import any text inside the labels, the last name, first name, email are everything.
Then it should be added to the repository which is being created this side of the frame.
So yes, once we hit the enter on that, then it should be attached to that specific selection.
And on clicking that selection, it all should appear in the form of our repository and also the list
module.
So everything is added in the form of a list of course.
So we have called the repository dot add to add all of the inputs made by the user.
And also from closing a form window closing will appear after hitting update button and add button.
So this new form will appear once we close like this and that specific contact will be added to the
repository in the left side of the frame.
Now after this, we have created list contact value change.
So once there is any kind of update in the values of the text field, then it should be reflected inside
the selection.
So suppose if we click, we update, like in the working part, we have updated the web address of this
contact and once we click on this update button, then after opening the option contact again, the
updated value will be reflected in the form.
So yes, this is responsible for changing the value after that.
Yes, this is the update functionalities we have created above here the update button.
Yes, it is.
So the action performed function was created here and the action is listed here.
Over this part.
So yes, for the update and the remove.
So contact's value changed.
And the move action performed.
So all of the action perform are listed here inside this part of the snippet.
And all of them are actions attached to all three of the buttons.
Now.
So then we have attached a unique value change to all three of the buttons, whether it be the remove
button, we have a specific value chain, the function for that.
Similarly for the update button, a value chain function for that and the add above here.
So after completing all three of the action handling of the buttons now in the file, like a conclusion,
we are adding everything, whether it be the button, all three of them, the labels and the text fields
to the frame.
So here we are declaring the variables we have been using above there.
So the declaration pattern's done here for all of the variables, or we can call it as objects.
So these are the total objects which are being used inside this GC frame class, or they can be accessed
inside other classes also.
Okay, so at the end this will list items.
So once the list item is filled, we are using a for loop for getting all of them.
So once we click on a specific content, a for loop is attached for every contact.
So on clicking this a list, a full list will be accessed with the help of this.
Get all key word from the repository, of course.
Okay.
So this clear input is marking.
Like this whenever we hit the update and the clear input will appear.
So all of the text fields will again set to empty whenever we clear the input of any text field.
So once we hit on the update button, we will encounter that.
We will.
So we will encounter this when we will run this program.
So the overall programming execution part is completed.
Now we have completed all five of the classes which are required inside this application.
Now jump into the main class and trying to run this.
We will see that everything is working perfectly fine or not.
So this is working perfectly fine.
We will remove this.
And then this contact frame is open.
There is a panel for contact contact information.
The buttons, the text fields and the labels.
So let us try adding something.
So let us type something random only in order to check that everything is working fine or not.
The number should contain numbers.
Web address.
Dot com and the email should contain.
At the date like this format and.
Address could be anything any random text on hitting on this add button.
This is added.
On opening this, it appears now again hitting.
Let us try to change this to a new contact.
Okay.
So we have been trying to add a new contact to the list.
So we have added the second one.
Now, I like wanting to check the functionalities of this update and remove also.
So let us try to update this address to New Delhi.
And check that whether the upgrade functionality is working perfectly or not.
So hitting on this update and the input is clear, input for it is clear.
We have seen this in the last part we were discussing about it is yes, this clear input is called every
time when we.
I'll click on any button, so let us check that whether the address is updated or not.
So yes, the second one, the address is updated successfully, so the update is working perfectly fine.
We have added to contacts, so that key is also working perfectly fine.
Now let us try to remove one of them.
So, yes, selecting the first contact and hitting on this removed button.
So yes, it is removed.
So this application is working perfectly fine in every manner.
All the buttons are working perfectly, the text fields are taking input.
The repository site is also working like clicking this.
We are able to get all the information of that specific contact.
So yes, now we have covered everything in this project.
The testing and running part is also done successfully.
So I hope that you all have gained much idea about Java after the completion of this project.
Now I would encourage you all to try making this project on your own so that it will make you much aware
about these concepts we have applied inside this tutorial.
So thank you all for joining this session.
And once again, I would encourage you all to make this project on your own.
So thank you.