Okay.
So in the last part we were talking about this children function, which was creating the child to the
north.
We can see that the parent, they were adding notes to the tree like structure of this parent and this
if statement was checking that if files are not equal to not.
So suppose if a folder is empty then how new note should be added.
And otherwise, if it is not empty, then this statement will work.
If already files are present inside that folder, then simply new folders will be mutated inside the
three note structure.
Now are talking about this get image.
So suppose if we want to open an image file.
We already talked about opening files and inside that we were opening IMG extension or JPG extension.
So how that get image function is working.
We have used this get image in the open open file function here.
Here.
We have used this get EMG.
You can see that.
I have highlighted this.
So this get IMG is the function which is working like this.
So we have a task to try and catch.
So what I am doing is doing this get I am just simply taking the part of that image.
Basically, this is returning the part of that image we want to open.
Suppose you want to open this paint dot jpg then that get img function.
We'll call that.
So a part of that image which we want to open on the display panel.
And otherwise, if there is no image inside that file that is a fake file created, then it will show
simply that error image not found where we have an event like get message event.
So yes, it will return null as nothing will be returned in that display panel.
So this is how this get image is working.
Okay, so suppose if the get image has some images, then how the width and height of that images will
be adjusted to the scale.
So this is the scale.
Suppose that is image existing then it should adjust itself to this frame.
This is the display panel shop frame side and the image should adjust itself to this frame only.
So this function is responsible for like returning the image according to the size of the frame.
Okay, so this show a message dialog.
So dialog box are very important part of this applications we had having dialog, we are having g option
prints in almost all of the functionalities, whether we want to create a new folder or a new file or
we want to rename some folder and then this pop up menu is appearing, asking for some text or simply
if we want to like rename, then it will simply ask for a new name and it will also contain two button
so can cancel or also one a pop up menu.
We have seen when we are right clicking any of the files and folders which was containing options such
as Save, Rename and the important option inside that popup menu was open index.html.
So from that popup menu we were able to open any of the folders inside our desktop window or not in
the application window.
So with that option we can exit that application window which we are talking about and we will be navigated
to our desktop window.
Now basically the desktop files explorer.
So yes, talking about this search show message dialog.
So we are so here we are having mouse adapter function which is going to like listen to the actions
performed by the mouse, whether the mouse is pressed, the mouse is click and in that manner things
are going to be listened by the application according to the mouse.
So if the mouse is pressed, then a pop up should happen.
If the mouse is clicked on any of the option, then a like event is getting the source, whether or
wherever the mouse is getting click and it is going to click the count.
So how actually this click count is working.
So this Click Count is initially set to one and whenever this count is increasing, like suppose we
are clicking the mouse firstly head and then again inside itself subfolder then are the click is getting
count and what is happening with the help of the two or two things are getting updated with the clicks.
One is the pattern and second is the number of elements panel in the footer.
So two things are getting updated with the mouse motion is not a component.
We can see that that once the mouse is getting clicked, then the path and the element number of elements
should get updated.
So yes, this is how this mouse adapter function is working now coming to the pop up menu again.
So yes, I was talking about this pop up menu.
We are calling this pop up menu component of the string library.
This class is named pop up menu and this class is creating yes, this four options rename new folder,
new file and open index.html.
So we have encountered this pop up in the working of the application part.
Or once we tried to right click any of the folders, then a pop up menu was appearing asking for these
four options.
Rename new folder, new file and open index.html.
So we try.
Go open a folder in the backstop with the help of that pop up menu.
So yes, this is the pop up menu which we were like talking about, and this is basically the alignment
of the pop up menu.
So get text and get why is the distance from this pop distance of this pop up menu from the X and y
axis?
So yes, this is all about the layout part of the pop up menu.
Okay.
So yes, this is the private static final function basically.
And inside this function there are menu bar items.
So the pop up is appearing in the form of a menu that is a menu bar which is containing some of that
dishes.
We can say that here.
The dishes are the options inside the menu.
So the menu bar was a pairing containing four options, rename and folder file and open index.html.
And inside the gym this pop up menu function, we were adding mouse events.
So whenever the mouse will be clicked or basically a right click whenever made, then these four options
are going to be append related to any of that specific folder.
And what could happen?
What would happen when we click this rename new folder and new file option in the from the menu bar.
So if we click on the rename part, then simply the rename file button will get enabled which we have
already created above or similarly for the add folder and add file button.
Or that specifically created add file and folder button will be invoked.
Here we have created a dedicated function for adding files and folders.
There you can see that.
So yes, add file button and folder button.
So this specific action list will be invoked whenever we click any of the options from the menu bars.
So yes, this is how this pop up menu bar is working.
Yes.
So you can see that this is called again and again dot booklet.
So whenever our user clicks that the options from the menu bar, then that specific action list that
is going to take place.
Okay.
So yes, until now, this is all about the pop up menu bar now coming to the action perform.
So what is this action performed is related to?
So at this hour action performed is related to whenever we are trying to open any folder like suppose
if we are clicking right, clicking on any of the folder and hitting on this we name new file new.
But what if we are trying to open anything which is like not in any selected folder?
So suppose we want to like blindly click right click on any one of the folder, then this if our statement
is going to take place.
So suppose if we have like genuinely choosing a folder and trying to perform actions on it, then it
will open that file or folder in the display panel of course.
And if we are trying to choose any file or folder which is already selected, then our dialog message
box will appear showing that you choose Select File.
So basically you should choose us or select the file in order to perform any functionalities, whether
adding, renaming or opening index drop or anything, we have to firstly choose our file first, then
only we can or like perform any functionality on the folder or the file.
We can say that also.
Yes, at the last we have added all the four buttons to the name and folder, add file and open index.html
or to this pop up menu.
So yes, this was all about the pop up menu we chose appending on the right click now are coming to
the three cell renderer for a file.
So from the beginning we were talking about that.
All of the things like we are talking about here is that three we are talking about here, hierarchical
data structures.
There are roots that are nodes and like all three things we were talking about so long, so what?
Actually this tree is working.
How actually these trees are working basically.
So this file tree, cell render is a function which we are extending to default trees.
So this.
This is a Java string component default three cell renderer, which is going to render all of the files
and folders in the form of a tree which has made this application ready.
Or like we can say that simple and easy to be coded, and with the help of this component only we can
open this folder subfolders inside it and the files inside it very conveniently.
So this tree cell renderer is helping us to render all the files and folders inside the directory.
We can say that.
And that's in the form of objects.
So here we are talking everything in the form of objects.
We have created function and calling objects inside it.
So this tree cell renderer is converting all the childrens and the nodes in the form of objects and
that with also a feature that they are considered stored inside a tree.
So this tree is making all things in the form of a tree, but the object oriented program is applicable
to them.
Now, this is how this coding part is executed.
Now, let us try to run the application and see that if it is working correctly or not or there are
any bugs.
So perfect.
This application is open here.
You can see that there is a show panel, a display panel, all the four buttons, save the name, new
file, new folder, the count for the elements, the horizontal scroller.
So yes, the hierarchical structure we are just talking about.
Okay, so let us try to open something inside that drive.
So the path is updating.
Now, let's try to open this file browser.
Okay.
So we are inside this file browser and the path is updated.
Now let us try to open this text file so you can see that the text editor has opened inside the display
panel.
Only we can add any text inside it and try to save it and it will be saved.
Now I'm hitting on this back button here.
You can see the back button.
This is the panel for the back button.
And we are back to the previous window.
Now, let us again try to open this file.
You can see that the modified text is appearing here.
Now, again, let us try to remove this unwanted text and again, saving it.
You can see that the file size is also appearing in the below panel.
The footer now on saving it.
We can also back.
Now let us try to create a new folder.
So let us name this folder as hello and click on.
Okay.
And the folder is created.
Hello.
Now let us try to create a new file inside this.
So new file again, naming this file as hello.
And this will be created in the form of a text file and we can write and remove text from here also.
So I hope you can see that how conveniently that things are taking place, how conveniently we have
added everything inside our application, whether it be the buttons, the like, rendering of the tree
like structure, the notes and everything, the folder structure.
Once we open a file, the updated like this is also done with the help of the revalidate and repaint
function.
We have talked about it that once we update anything then that should be like a pat on the updated screen
also.
So initially there are only four folders.
Now we have added two of them.
Then this test and this hello is updating also in the modified frame structure.
So yes, this was all about this file browser interface application.
I hope that you all have gained much concepts to off Java through this application and I would encourage
you all to make this application on your own to learn more concepts.
And by practicing more and more on this project, it will definitely increase your skills in Java and
object oriented programming.
So I want to thank you all for joining this session.
And again, I would encourage you all to practice this on your own.
So thank you.