Okay.
So till now we have created all the classes which is going to be required inside the project, the main
class, the home class, the schedule class, the help and then class, and then this plot part.
We are going to conclude this project.
Basically, we are going to create the final class, the timeline class, which is going to contain
this timeline, which we can call the main part of the project head only.
We are like showing how the tasks are aligned inside this number line type of structure that is a done
button and a timer which is running at two places.
So this timeline class is going to contain our most important part of this project.
This is aligning the tasks accordingly we have set inside this scheduled class.
So let us start creating the timeline class inside the Z folder only.
So firstly, create a file timeline dot java.
And yes, so the timeline class is created, extending it to G panel first.
And inside this class, we are going to firstly set the ArrayList, which is going to be the yes.
So this ArrayList is going to contain this task B, C, D, and it is going to be this as well as we
do not know in the beginning how many tasks the user want to enter.
So we will be using ArrayList only in order to set that tasks.
So again, ArrayList and this ArrayList is going to be in a string format.
So calling string here, closing this list, and we will simply name this error list as S-T.
So is this text is going to contain the list of the tasks we are adding to the timeline, a string for
on top.
So there is a top timer.
We are having three panels.
Basically the top is containing a timer.
The middle is containing the number line kind of structure, which is like containing the clock 12 to
12 in the day and then 12 to 12 through the night.
So the middle has m the bottom should be B and.
Oh, find hours, find minute integer kind of data type should be declared here.
So integer find hours integer find minutes.
Like how many minutes and hours are left for a specific task to be completed?
And the base, of course.
So, yes, this is all we need to declare inside it.
And the message here or the message which we are displaying.
And then it should also be like taken from this timeline, only as once we hit the done button, then
only the message is updated.
There are wasted or saved left.
How many time we wasted or saved?
Now creating that constructor timeline.
And inside it we are going to pass again base B as the bottom is already set to be.
So base B.
And inside it we are going to call the base.
So the base will be showing this card layout which will contain this appearance.
So, yes.
On the next thing is the setting layout part.
So there are three layers the middle, the top and the bottom, as we have already discussed.
So setting the layout as grid layout.
And that great layout is going to be three ish to one basically as there are three parts in the frame.
So three ish to one a bracket inside it and a bracket again to close this new grid layout.
So we are setting this layout.
So set layout.
Okay.
So let us handle it first.
We just have to set the layout head only so new.
Great layout.
Please do one.
Comma one.
Perfect.
So this grade level part is set.
Now we have to declare variables for finding message hours and minutes.
So let us copy it from here.
Message and all three of them.
So pasting it and removing the data type.
And setting it to an empty string in the beginning.
So the message is not containing anything that our size zero and the minutes are also zero for the message.
So yes, this is all.
Also the.
Timeline is null in the beginning.
That is not passed since inside the timeline and the end page.
This end is for the end page.
Everything is declared as null in the beginning.
So yes, this is all we need to declare inside this timeline class.
Now let us move to this this setting colors like colors, type of structure inside the clock.
Number nine, let how the tasks should be attached inside this timeline.
Now coming to the layout of this timeline page first what it is actually containing, there are three
parts.
The above part is containing a timer which is continuously moving.
We have encountered it in the working of the application part.
These two timers are showing the same time.
That is a middle, middle of the frame which is containing a black border number clock line.
We can say that it is a clock number line and that is a bottom which is containing a done button.
So this done button is displaying the name of the task which we have created and a timer is also attached
to it also.
So inside this error list, we have attached all three of the panels, the top one, the middle one
and the bottom one, and added all three of them inside the frame.
This revalidate and repaint is updating it according to the user updates the tasks every day.
So suppose users enter a task.
So this will paint itself again.
And if the task is done then the new task is again created.
Then it will again repaint itself and revalidate.
So revalidate is basically for removing all of the layout which is present and then again repainting
it.
It is continuously changing whenever the user enters any new tasks.
And also we have encountered that the colors are also changing every time.
So revalidate and repainting that enables in Java to update the frame.
Now this top we are extending it as the panel also attaching action.
So this top is basically containing the frame, top timer.
The frame is containing a timer at the top and this timer is like a used with the help of timer import.
We have made our above header, simple date format and calendar which is taking the date like suppose
to this date the calendar takes checks the time or what is the time right now.
So check date and time is a component we have used from the AWP library.
So according to the today's date, whatever the date we have created our tasks.
This will update itself.
Suppose that we have created the tasks to today.
Right now it is suppose a 6 p.m. or so and we have created a task for 9 to 10 p.m..
Then this timer will update itself according to that date that yes, we have 4 hours, 2:10 p.m. and
3 hours to 9 p.m. right now if suppose it's 6 p.m..
So it will update itself accordingly.
And this is how this calendar function is updating the timer every time the user creates a new task.
Now this middle is containing a number type of layout.
We can see that a number clock line or a clock number line, whatever we call it.
And it is the setting of white color line.
And that specific interval which the user has set the tasks for will be painted in a different color.
So we have created that also with the help of this draw rectangle.
So basically it is a rectangle which we have drawn and there are pixels for the number of tasks we have
created.
The different colors rectangle are present for different number of tasks.
So this middle is responsible for that.
Now coming to the bottom.
So what this bottom part is, so we have a task, the action listener to the bottom.
We are not attaching actions to all of them, but just to the bottom.
So this bottom is containing a done button on hitting the done button that we are navigating to the
end page.
And it is showing a message that what is the number of time we have saved or wasted in order to complete
our tasks?
So the application is calculating the time on which we have hit the done button and it is setting itself
like any time minus time of hours.
So what was that time we have sent for the task to end basically the deadline we have sent and what
is the time right now it will subtracted self and then.
Sure the message to the end paid accordingly.
So this is showing the end page that whether the user has saved that time or wasted their time.
So, yes, and this is the reminder.
So suppose if the user is about to complete the task but haven't completed the task yet.
So a reminder will also shown in the frame on the top of the left panel.
So let us try running the application and check that how actually all of them are working.
So run Java.
Okay.
So there are some errors.
Let us try to debug it.
So we need a basis here to complete the whole class.
We missed this race and now let us again try to run the application in order to check that it is working
perfectly or not.
So are the open.
The image, a path linking is not working, so we will fix it.
Now let us try to check that whether the task adding is working perfectly or not.
So let us try to add one task A, B, C and set the time 9 p.m. for the task to 10 p.m. or we can say
11 p.m..
So yes, this time goes well.
This is a busy task we have created and hit can continue.
So perfect.
The task is created inside the timeline.
The time left for us to complete the task is four hour, 44 minutes and a beautiful clock number line
is appearing in the timeline dot java class.
So this is the title, this is the close operation, this is the resize button and the time.
So suppose we have already completed this task ABC and we want to hit on this done with ABC button to
check that what is the time we have saved or wasted in order to complete this task?
So I am writing this down button and the end pages are pairing, which is showing a message that you
have saved 4 hours and 42 minutes.
So this is showing a message that I have saved this time.
Now I will again go back to the home page and check that if the help page made perfectly or not.
So yes, this is the help page.
There are three questions which we have added to one, Q2, Q3 and the three answers to the question.
Again, there is a back to home page button on hitting this back to home page button.
We will be navigated back to the home page of our application.
Now let us try to fix the image issue that while the image is not appearing here, let us try to fix
it.
Okay, so coming back to the homework assignment, check what's wrong with the image linking.
So yes, this is the get image and the look at the path of this image.
So this image is located outside the services folder.
So to come out of this RC folder, we have to add a dot and a backslash or in order to link the image
properly.
Now let us try to run again and check that if image is coming or not perfect, the image is visible
now.
Now these are home pages are completely working fine.
That is a start now button.
We can add tasks again.
If we add five tasks then five add a list manner of tasks and it will be updating.
Also, this is for the mutability and resize ability check of this schedule class which we have created
here.
So this was all about this time management tool we were making today.
So this was the complete code of this project which we were discussing right now.
And I would encourage you all to try this project on your own to learn more and more about these concepts
we were looking up till now.
So I would thank you all for joining this session of Time Management Tool Project.
And again, I would suggest you all to try making this project on your own and learn this wonderful
application.
So thank you.
I wish you a happy learning.