So here this is back to class.
This class is a base class for other actors in the game.
It simply encapsulates the basic functionality of an object in this game here.
So firstly, what we will do here, I will write here.
Firstly, we will start with the the private final int and the space variable here to zero.
Okay.
Now next thing which we need is the private in x coordinate variable.
Next thing is a private and y coordinate variable
thing, which you need as a private image image to store the images.
So now we need our class constructor also here.
So I will write public actor.
Sorry, we need the actor.
Okay.
So now here, I need public actor.
Here in X, comma and Y here and now under this I will send this to x equal to x.
This Y is equal to y.
Now next thing is for public image.
Got image.
Here, it will return in.
So that part is done.
Now we have to set we get a remission or we have to set the image also.
So here I will write public white set image.
Take the parameter of the image image print on and I will write.
Image is equal to IMG here.
We will say the part of our images, in our words, to the public, int x and return x here.
Next thing, what we need is the public.
Okay, we have to take the public into y
take it with the return y here.
Now we need to.
We need the sector for the x and y coordinates also.
So here I will write public void state x if the parameter with the index here and simply write stored
x is equal to x here need same thing for the y.
Want to say to y.
Give the parameter to the y here.
So this y is equal to y here and now we have to complete our body of this matter which we have created.
So firstly, change the argument with the actor.
Actor here.
See, change this to this one.
So maybe some of the others will be gone from here.
He.
Here it goes.
So here firstly we will take to create the we have created all these the left, right and the top and
the bottom collision marker it because it will check if the actor collides with another actor.
It means the wall or the baggage or the one here to the left or to the right or to the top, to the
bottom.
So simply, we have to write only one line here what it will be.
We have to return in x minus space variable, which will be equal to astronaut x and.
Need the y is equal to actor, nor do I hear.
And the same goes with here also.
Okay.
Move this.
Here.
What should we write in the write coalition?
Here it will end up with this piece so written we need X and up to the space variable which will be
equal to astronaut X and y, which will be equal to astronaut Y here.
I'm done here.
Same goes with the top two.
Intersect with the y minus space variable which will equal to the actor.
First take astronaut y and here it will be x with the
third x here and now we need to check for the bottom one also.
So here I will write X, Y and z up with the space variable which really equal or not.
So note y and x here will be equal to after dot x here.
And so all these matter check if the actor collide with another wall baggage or this one to the left
or to the right or to the top or to the bottom here.
Now the next thing which we have to do is to create the world class here.
And I will create the world class it will inherit from the actor class.