Inside this removal lines matter.
Firstly, we have to check if there is any fold room among all rows in the board.
If there is at least one full line, it is removed.
So after finding a full line, we increase the counter.
We move all the lines above the full row.
One line down.
This way we can destroy the whole line in order to escape.
We use so-called gravity.
This means that the squares may be left floating above empty gaps.
So in this matter, we will write in the NUM four lines and set it to zero.
And we need another for loop.
And here we write an equal to good height minus one.
And then we need a greater than equal to zero.
Set it to.
And here we need the element of the I.
I decreased and we need boolean blindness for this one.
Okay.
Just second line is full.
So I could do the true need the true.
And this is John.
We need another for loop.
This one and we need another four which needs the integer g said to the zero.
JS Let's turn to the board with.
Here.
We need the chain agreement here.
And what we will do, we will check with the conditions if she at G meet her need.
J Comma, no di comma j j i is equal to that terminal dot no shape.
It's done.
And we need Linus to set it to the false here.
And then we have to break.
Okay.
So here we have done this thing.
And after words, we need another condition.
So we will write.
If so, if line is full, you will check with this condition and then we will increase it.
So now four lines plus.
And then what we have to do?
If there is at least one foul line, it is removed.
Right.
So here we will do with the new one and for loop and here we will say in K equal to I and K should be
less than to board height and minus one and k should plus plus.
And this is done and we need another for loop and say in g equal to zero and g should be less than the
board width and this is run and need the incremental.
And here we will see board.
Need to need this one multiplied with the bold word.
And then we add J here.
And what do we have to do?
Equal to shape and height.
And here we will see G and here it set it to the cube plus one.
So all this is done here.
This thing is done.
Come out of this loop and we need one more condition.
If no lines is greater than zero, then do another thing.
We have to remove the lines.
Right.
So we will write
no lines.
Remove clause equal to no lines.
So not four lines and then 32.
And then we need the status bar and it should set text.
We need a trim, not value off, and it should set long lines removed.
So we have to set the is following finished variable to that.
True.
So set it to the true here.
Tony.
We need it to the truth and we need the current piece and it should set shape.
And here it will go through the terminal door.
No --.
This thing is done.
Now we have to go with the new draw square.
We have not created that method, so we will create here.
We need another method which will be a draw square method.
Every Tetris piece has four squares.
Each of these squares is drawn with the draw square method.
So we need another method named as the draw square.
So we will write private void draw square here and give the parameters to graphics.
G coma in x coma in my coma and certain to terminal shape.
It's done.
And here we have to give the colors.
Whatever you have to give, you can get.
So we will do color colors.
We need spectrometers.
So we set new color and give the 000.
We need new color and give the parameter.
Whatever you want to do.
What?
What do you wish?
You can give it.
And I will give on my own.
And here we have to.
Do the same things, but you have to change some colors.
And so copy paste, copy, paste, same as it is.
It's.
These are the seven shapes colours.
So.
It is of no shape and neither for the others.
So we will change.
You can change this.
What we are to do.
It's done here.
Now what?
We have every space of seven different colors.
Right, left on the top side of the square are drawn with a brighter color.
Similarly, the bottom and the right sides are drawn with the darker colors to tell with the 3D edge.
So you can do that.
So I will set the color here so brighter and.
Right.
So we have to go with the.
Okay.
100 to 1.
Then we will go meet this.
102 comma 204102.
Here, here we will write
1021102.
The brighter and the darker.
Right?
So this should be seen
204102 here and here should be 1021204204.
Here and here we will write 2181730.
And here we have to change it to 102204.
So now we will call no variable color equal to color shape third ordinal and third this G.
So set color.
And we need give it the parameter to the color and its tone.
And we have to not fill.
We need the red matter.
And here we will get the X plus one plus one.
It will be the.
Right.
So it should be worth.
Return.
It should be minus two and comma and under.
Really be this height.
Minus two.
It's done.
Then we need set colour again.
Think.
Okay.
We should do that later.
So we need another thing.
We have to write set color.
And here we have, right?
The color dot brighter, the brighter.
So here it's done.
We tried to draw the line, so we knew the line.
Whether X or Y should be the no.
Why should we add the square height here?
So we need the square.
Right.
But it should be subtracted with the minus one and x or y should be the same.
And we will copy this.
And again press enter pasted and change it with the here.
It should be the same.
Right.
It should course with the.
But one.
Nathan It should be X or Y, but it should be added with the x value, not the Y value.
So we will write x plus this one.
So it's done now we will do it.
Same for the brighter one.
Simply copy this and paste this and change it to the darker type.
Darker.
And here we will go with the x plus one Y plus squared minus one.
But here it should be x plus a square.
Square root subtracted to the one, and here it will be five plus
height and less than to the one here.
And for another one, it should go.
Okay.
We will copy this c and change it to this and added something.
We will lose x plus a square root here.
So we will write X plus square in the square root here.
So we will try to square ten minus one and it should be.
VI is glad, but here should be the height.
It should be the height here and drill the miners and then x we need so we need X plus we need the word
here.
Okay, so with time then minus one and then another parameter will be the Y plus one and it's done.
So here we have done.
Now we have to create the game cycle method.
I think we had created it earlier.
It's not then we have to create it again.
This one, this class, we have to create this class.
You need that.
So what we will do?
We have to write.
We have to write private class.
Game cycle.
We should implement.
Okay.
Action listener.
Under this map, we will override some methods.
What should be?
It should override the action perform method.
So we will hear in this game cycle we call the do game cycle method also to creating a game cycle.
So firstly, we will override the action perform method to we have to write public void action.
But from.
Okay.
I should have even done so.
Even under this, we will right over my third duty cycle here.
And it's done its name as I do game cycle and the game cycle.
Plus we call the game cycle matter to create a game cycle.
So under this we will go and we have to create this matter here.
Now we have to write its bodies.
Firstly, we have to we need to update one and the repeat here.
So the game is divided into game cycles.
A cycle updates a game and redraws the board.
So for the update one we need, we have to see the body.
So create a update and into this update.
Now it represents one step of the game.
The following piece goes one line down or a new piece is created and the previous one is finished following.
So what we have to write, if we have to first check if it is post this post and then return, it should
return simply afterwards.
It should check if it's following finished.
Then it said it's following finished variable to top false so equal to false.
And then we will call our new piece method here and it will create the new piece or else what can we
do?
We need another method which we have created.
It should be the one line done.
This one afterwards we have created the we have to create another class which we have used here.
I think the de and after this one, this one, the de and after.
So we have to create this class as well.
So what should we do now?
We will create class.
Sorry.
Private class.
Being an after.
And to an extent.
And it's and after this, the game is controlled with a cursor keys.
We check for key events in the key.
So here we will.
This will be our last stand.
So we will override the matter key.
So we will call our master key pressed here and we provide the key event with name E and into this we
will check for some condition.
If current piece not get shape.
Is equal to the
that owned or no shape.
If there is no shape, then simply return.
Or else.
No.
Yeah.
We don't need anything else.
So after this, we will create another variable key code and set it to the.
Erin TONER I think we need to get key that key goal, the key goal of pressing key.
So what we need some switch statement.
So here we will use the Java switch expressions.
Through here what we will do.
We need switch.
Check it for the key code here.
This one, I think we get the key here with the get key code method.
Then with the Java 12 switch expression, we bind key events to methods.
For instance, with the space key, we draw down the following Tetris piece.
So here this will be our last step in this class.
So we will create the case.
Keys.
Kieran.
Ian Lord, we need to.
We.
Me, me, me.
It should be this one.
P simply goose.
It should be passed.
We will settle our cases here.
Copy paste paste will change this here.
The key moment when we needed the left one.
We need the next here.
This one.
It should call the prime move method.
Current pace and the cold.
Here goes the current x -132, and here the key code goes with the current Y.
And here it should be.
Here it will call the right one.
This one.
Not sure.
Gonna try.
Move.
Current piece, but it goes with the current x value which should add with one year and.
This will change it for the.
Got it right.
And here we go.
The left turn right when you score.
It goes with the down one.
We need to down one.
And here we need the upper one.
Here, this one and another one, which you really need is the space.
And the last one which we need is that one line down.
Here and we don't need any of that.
So what we do, we will call it dry move.
Sorry.
We need to dry move again.
Try.
Move
here, what we will do for them downwards.
We will set the current pace.
But it should rotate.
Right?
Comma.
Current X.
Current Y.
And this is done.
Another thing which we need for the upper one.
We need to try move it.
Should current base not rotate left and here we need a current X in the current y.
Here is one current tax and this will be rectified here and here.
We need for the space to drop down a third and d for the one line down.
This one.