Here is our classes.
That is a first class as a payment detail class.
So this class is defined inside the package airline and we have imported the necessary package, our
AWG and Java Auditability event to handle events on this window and Java as well to connect database
to our program.
And Java starts to provide more efficient graphical features.
The highlighted packages provided by the library address two examples to model the table from the database
into this window.
Public class payment details is extending the frame and we have defined the text field.
One text field variable.
Table instance, j label instance and another J labels are flight code capacity class, code, class,
name and label.
So now after that, inside the main function, we have initialized the object of the current class and.
Then inside the non parameterized constructor of payment details we have called the Initialize method.
So whenever the class object or object this class is called, it will first move to the constructor
and Insight's constructor.
It will find the Initialize method.
So let's check what is inside the initialize method that is of private void type initialize method.
First.
At first it is setting the title of the window payment details, and after that we have set the background
color as white.
And setting the size of the window at a 60 cross 46 layout as null.
Then we have defined the label could be an amber setting the font for that label which font family tahoma
plane and 17.
Setting the bound for that label and then adding that label to our frame.
After that we have defined respect to text field for that frame for that label and setting the bound
for that label and adding that.
Text filled to our frame.
After that, we have defined a new table setting bound for that table and adding that table to our frame.
After that, we have here creating the instance of the show that is a button setting font for the button,
background, color and foreground color of the button.
And after that we have set the bound for the button whose location is to end red comma 210 and sizes
150 cross 26 adding that button to our frame.
And after that we have defined the label sector which is containing the payment details for foreground
color as blue.
Its font family Tahoma type is plane size is 31 setting bound for it was location is 51, comma 17 and
size is 300 cross 39 adding it to our adding it to our frame.
Then we have defined our number labeled P number, setting the font family, setting it bound and adding
that label to our J frame another label as paid amount setting the font for it, which is Tahoma font
type plain 13 setting the bound for the plain location is 183 comma to 98 and its size is 92 cross 14.
Adding that to our frame under label as paid date setting font for the that label adding it setting
the bound of that label whose location is 322 comma 294 and size is 101 cross 24 adding that to our
frame.
Then there is another label check number as this is a paid payment detail class.
So it will have the check number as well font for that setting the bound for that adding it to our.
Frame.
Then there is another label which containing nothing which way, because it will be storing the image
setting bound for it and adding it to our j frame.
Then there is a card number label also setting font for it, adding bound of it, and adding it to our
j frame.
After that, there is a phone number that is the last label.
Setting point for it, bound for it, adding it to frame, setting the visibility of the frame as to
there is only one button that is shown.
Adding action is not on that.
Implementing the action performed method inside the trip log via fetch the text from the text field.
The code of the from the text field is showing in the string code, creating the connection from the.
Creating connection by using our connection class and defining the A string, which is a single select
number paid amount paid cheque number, card number, phone number from payment via number is equals
to the code.
So results is close to zero to execute query and table will set the model of the table on the basis
of results set.
Now that cash block will handle the any exception if occurs, setting the size of the frame has 960
plus 5590 location has 400 plus 200 setting the visibility of the frame as true.
So this will be the payment detail class.
Let's have a look on cancelled or Java class.
That will be the last class.
So this class is also defined inside the package airline and we have imported the package of starting
to define to develop graphical user interface.
Similarly JWT as well a W to that dot event to handle event and actual is not on our buttons and Java
dot SQL to.
Interact with the database which we have created.
This is the cancel class which is extending the frame.
Text filled here.
There are five text filled text filled text relevant text to text, fill three and text four.
Inside the main function.
We have just created an instance of this cancel class.
Inside the cancel we have initialize inside the cancel non parameterized constructor.
We have called the initialize method.
So whenever this class will be called so in the control goes to the constructor.
Inside the constructor we found the calling of initialized method so it will move to the initialize
method.
So now let's see what is inside this initialize method.
So.
Title.
First of all, setting the title as cancellation.
Background color as white.
Setting the bound of the.
Window layout is null.
Then there is a label cancellation, setting the font for it and bound for it and adding that to a window.
Then there is an image icon cancel dot png.
Inside the icon here is.
Image cancelled or this is it.
And then there is a.
Label, which is storing that image and setting the bound for that label, adding that label to our.
Geoffrey.
More window.
Then there is the passenger number label for the passenger numbers, setting the font type and size
of the font bound for the passenger number label location 6100 and its size as 132 plus 26, adding
the passenger number to our frame.
Then there is another label as cancellation number setting the font for that cancellation number whose
font family is Tahoma.
Type is plane and size 17 cancellation number not set.
LB will set the location that is 6150 and size as 150 cross 27 adding that cancellation number label
to our frame.
Then there is a label cancellation date and setting the font for it, adding the cancellation date label
setting bound for it as well.
Location 60 cross 200 and size one equals 27 and adding that cancellation date to our frame, let's
remove this which is not in use anymore.
Another label as flight code setting font for font for it and bound off it and then adding it to our
frame.
Then there is a button, cancel button.
Which will handle which will send that data of that cancer window to our database.
So setting the font for it, background color, black, white, foreground color as white, bound for
the button and adding it to the frame.
Then there are respective text fields let's remove which is not in use anymore.
Text field setting down for it, adding that text field similarly for the text field one, text field
two and text field three.
Let's move to the action performed.
So there is only one button that is canceled or that sells.
So we have a perform a defined action perform method inside which first let me remove it.
Inside which we have stored the these packages, these string variables inside which we have stored
the necessary details inside the passenger number we have imported or retrieved from the text field.
Inside cancellation number from the text field, one inside cancel cell date from the text field two
and inside flight code the string from the text field for now.
Inside the Tribe blog, we have created the connection object and also define the query a string str.
That's the query.
That it is insert into cancellation values, passenger number, cancellation number, cancellation date
and flight details.
So these details will be inserted in our cancellation table, which we have created in our, I think,
second video that is of database and libraries.
C dot dot executable that this will update or insert these values into our database.
As we have passed the string string query to that dialog box will appear that ticket cancelled and a
string that visibility that will visibility of the current window set will be false.
Cache block will handle any exception if occurs setting the size of the frame as 60 cross 500 and visibility
as true location as 400, comma 200.
So let me show you a run of these two classes.
So let me run the payment detail class.
So if I run this class.
Or you can say Java file.
That's how it will appear.
This is.
I will.
Right.
Any number.
Let's suppose.
Two, three, four, five.
Two, two, three, four, five.
As there is no pin number, I think not detail in the detail of that number.
So that's why it is not showing here.
Let's close it and have a look on the canceled Java file as well.
Uh, I file.
That's how it will appear.
The window of.
Cancellation me the passenger number and a random number.
I'll be writing it.
And cancellation number and a number as well.
Cancellation date.
Let's suppose 21.
One, two, two, two, two, one.
Flight code space.
a266.
Cancel that issuing ticket.
Cancel.
So this data, which I have just said, must be stored in our database as well.