So in this video, we will be talking about the last two classes of this project that is payroll system.
So these two classes will be first is update employee and the second class will be payslip.
So that slip will be for the salary purpose to show the record of that salary.
And after that, after this video, we will be having a look at the live run of this project.
So let's have a look at the update employed class.
So in this class we have imported the Java SQL package to interact with the database update and record
update and retrieve the data from the database.
Java X Swing method will help us to create a graphical user interface for that current class and a blue
dot event will help us to handle.
Events on the buttons.
After that we have defined our public class update employer, which is extending frame and implementing
action is not an item listener.
After that, we have defined J labels L1, L2, L, three, l47 labels and the label MP.
After that, we have defined seven text fields, two buttons and two choices.
Now we have defined our non parameterized constructor as a state employee and heading as a state employee.
After that, set the layout for that complete window or frame as null.
And after that, getting content paints the background color as white.
And C2 is close to a new choice.
We have created the instance for the C2.
And see to what set bond will set its location and size, which is one 6040 and its size will be 200
cross 20.
Inside the try block, we will try to add the elements to our C two instance.
For that, we have created the connection variable.
Our object of of our connection class and we have executed the query select abstract from employee with
the help of results set c dot as dot execute query.
Now we have iterated over the record of that employed table and added the idea of the every employee
in our choice and stance after that.
Inside the CAS block, we will handle any exception if occurs.
Now what we are doing is there is an AMP label which is stating select MP number and its setting its
bound and location and sizes.
Location is 40, comma, 40 and sizes in Red Cross 20 and adding that AMP label and C to choice both
to our frame.
Then we have defined the label as name and its respective text field of maximum size 15.
And then we have set the bound location and size for that respect to label and table t one.
And after that what we did is we have added both the label and text field to our frame.
Then we have defined a new choice for the gender that will be either male and female.
And the label for the label which contains then a string as gender.
After that there is a set the location and size for that label too.
And the choice one inside choice one.
What we are doing, we are setting its bound and location size for that particular choice.
After that we are adding the label to and choice one to our frame.
Now there is a label three address.
For that.
We have a particular text field setting the location and size for that.
Label three and t three and adding that L three and t three label and text field respectively to our
frame.
Now in l four, which is a state as a state so that t four and there is a respective text field for
it, which is a maximum size 15 for that state.
And then we have said the size and location of L four and P four, then adding that L four and three
four to our j frame.
After that.
What we are doing is there is a label five labeled as city and there is a text field five with maximum.
Text with the maximum number as 15.
And then we have set the size for that label 5.8 or text field of five.
And after that we have added both the labels and text field to our frame.
Similarly, there is another label for the email and its respect to text field.
And then we have set the bound for the email.
Contextually both, and adding that email and text file to our j frame.
After that there is a label phone and its respective text field and then we have set the bound for that
label L seven and seven and then respectively we have added that both the labels and text field to our
frame.
Then there is a button be one labeled as update and there's a button b two labeled as delete.
So but update button will be used to update the data and delete button will be used to delete the data
be one set bound.
We have said the location for the button B one and b two respectively, adding both the buttons to our
frame.
Then we want to set background color is equals to black.
And B one point said foreground color is equal to white.
And similarly for the B2 we have added background and foreground color.
Added the action listener to both of the buttons.
Then we have added items for our choice.
C To now set the visibility of the current window as to its size will be 400 plus 550 and its location
will be 600.
Comma 200.
After that, we have defined the action performed method, which is taking an action event argument
a.
Then if I don't get sources because was to be one so that if the source of the event is from one.
What we are doing is a string and as it goes to one point, get text so in the string and we are restoring
the content of the text field in a string.
G We are restoring the content of the.
C one selected item is a string.
A We are showing the content of the string, the content of the text field 53 Similarly in C four in
C 85 and in 86.
And in T seven.
Now we have created a query to update the details of the employ of the string named as Q Are we inside
which we have the statement update, employee set, name and address state city email phone where ID
will be key to get selected item.
So this will be the query.
Inside the Tribe blog.
We have created the connection by using our coupon class.
We have updated, we have executed called the execute update method by passing the Q or inside that.
Then we have shown that dialog box that employer related successfully console.log will handle any exception
if occurs.
Hey don't get sources close to the source of the button is from way too.
So what we need to do is we need to delete the detail of that particular employ.
For that, we need to stabilize the connection with the database.
Then we will be executing the query that delete from employee where IDs goes to see to get selected
item.
So this will be deleting complete record for that particular ID and we will show the dialog box that
employee deleted.
After that, we will set the current visibility of the window as false.
Then inside the item changed method.
We are taking the item event i.e. as object or argument for that particular method.
We are creating the instance of our common class which will help us to create a stabilize connection
with our database.
And we are executing the query that select extra from the employee where it will match.
So this will select the record of all the record, all record for that particular ID from our employee
table.
And we are restoring the respective details of that particular ID in our text fields.
The one, three, three, three, four, three, five, three, six and seven cache block will handle
any exception if occurs and inside the void public void string areas.
We are just creating the update employee class instance.
So this is all about the update employee class.
Let's look at the last class.
That is the payslip class.
So in this class we have first imported the necessary packages Java, Java, starting Java and Java
DOT Event Public Class Payslip, which is extending g frame and implementing action listener choices
equals to C one.
There is a one choice.
There is a one text area and there is the one button inside the non parameter constructor of this class.
What we are doing is we are setting the size of that window 800, comma, 700 and its location as foreign
comma 150.
Then there is a seven choice variable for that.
We have created the instance of the class and with the help of the results.
At instance, we are executing the query with the help of 7.. execute query.
We have passed select extract from Sally.
This will select all the record from the salary table and while others start next, we are adding that
ID of our employers from the salary table to our choice instance.
Then we have set the layout as the border layout.
Then we have created a panel panel.
Now inside the panel, we have added a label as Select ID, and inside the panel we have added the choice
and stance.
Also.
Now we have added the panel with north location in our frame and after that.
What we are doing is we are creating a a new test area of size 30, 80, and we are passing that text
area object into the scroll panel because text area must be scrollable if the details is little more
than the particular defined size.
So that's why we have added a scroll panel over that text area.
Then there is a font type of variable F one, which is setting the font that arial font family arial
font type bold and font sizes.
20.
Then what we are doing is that we want f one.
So for that particular text field, we have set the font as a fun and b when it goes to new button which
is generate payslip and adding that button to the south position in this frame.
And similarly we have added the GSP and added it to our centre that the scroll panel.
After that we have added action to our button.
Now what we are doing is that the action perform the method we have here is an argument action event
type of object inside this method.
Now inside that log, we are creating an instance of our icon class.
Inside the results that we are executing query select aspect from employee where it will be selected
item.
So for that particular selected and the record of the employee will be selected for our start next we
are installing the name and our string name.
We are closing the details, we are closing the address connection.
Then we will updating the address as equals to save or not execute.
Query to select all the details from the salary where it will match and we will be calculating double
crosses close to zero yet and double digit goes to zero till now.
After that we are creating the Java Date Day when it goes to a new Java date which will select the date
of the current date.
And then there is a month, which is one month.
After that it will be showing PT one set text.
This will for the formatting purpose we have.
I have shown you like this payslip for the month of that particular month or 2019.
So this is the detail.
And inside the D1 field we will be adding and after appending a new line to our text area, then for
the next record we will show the details like an employee ID by from getting a string from the ID employee
name from the name and even append this line and the new line will double HRA.
We will be showing a HRA.
Similarly, we will be showing the I made PFF and basic salary by calculating the addition of that all
the things then net salary will be gross minus PV.
After that, we will be showing the basic salary.
Then we will be sharing the details tags.
With the help of this, we are adding everything in our text area.
Then at last, the signature.
Inside the cancer block.
We will be handling any exception if occurs and then public static white men string args.
We are paying the slip that is creating the new payslip class instance and set the visibility as to.
So that's all from the Java classes of this project.
In the last video or the next video, we will be having a look at the library of this project.
So that's all in this video.