So this is the class fee structure or Java which is defined inside the package university and we have
imported the necessary packages Java to export swing and Java JWT.
Then we have defined the class fee structure extending frame.
After that, we have.
Besides the labels here, 17 labels and Ally.
There is another label and we have defined another many labels here.
We have defined for the two store the it will show a table table a representation of the structure of
the piece for multiple courses and semesters.
So and now inside the public fee structure that is a non parameterized constructor, we have set the
size for the window, location of the window and layout of the window.
Now there is a label which will show fee structure setting font for it, bound off it.
Then there is a label course setting bound for it, font for it and adding the label.
After that, there's a label and two which is showing for the Beat Font Pounder, everything for it.
And there's a label, VCA bound for it, font for it, and adding it to that.
But then there's another label for the course VBA.
Then there is a fees for the courses 25,000, 25,000, 25,000, 25,000 for the semesters.
And similarly then there is another course b.sc.
That will be of three years.
So this will be the average semester fees of the course.
P.S. 18,000, 18,000, 13,000, 18,000.
And then there is an MBA course label label for the MBA.
Then fees of the NBA that will be off for years.
So there are four semesters sorry MBAs of two years and for the it will have four semesters and.
So there are for 65,000 labels.
Then we have another label for the MSI, which will be.
Here for themselves.
55,000.
Then we have for the fees for them.
81,000.
Then we have labels for the semester here.
Level four semester.
One, two, three, four, five.
Six, seven, eight maximum semesters can be of hate that will be in b.tech and.
For the other courses.
We will not show the face of that.
Those semesters now be when we will be selecting a phase 43,000, 43,004.
That will be for the b.tech.
Yes, that will be for the B.tech.
There are eight labels for that, 43,000 fees.
Then there is 32,000 fees for the labels.
After that, there is a.
Background color of windows is white and the visibility is true.
Then there's the static Weidman method for which we have setting the fee structure visibility as true.
After that, let's have a look on a student fee formed on Java.
Imported the necessary package.
Sorry, it is defined inside the package.
University importing the necessary package JWT Swing Border, AWG dot event Java, Autodesk and Java
dot util.
Then the student fee form we have extending frame and implementing extend listener.
Then we have private panel content pane.
Private text field.
The one and the two, three, three.
Then we have private combo box four, combo box two buttons and one choice.
Then there's the public static Weidman string.
This new strain free form set visible as two.
Public student fee form.
Let's.
Head headed as student fee form, then setting the bond.
For that window and setting the new panel water for the panel, adding it to the frame, setting the
layout as null.
And then there is a new choice.
Foreground color.
Using the rugby and there is setting the font for it inside the trip log.
This will establish connection with our database allows you to select extract from a student and while
iterating over the record of that student table.
It will add role numbers in our the choice so that we can select choice whenever we want to fill the
form fees form.
After that cash block will handle exception.
Then there is a label 11 select roll number which will be used to select roll number, setting the foreground
font and bounds for it, adding that to our frame after that label and to name setting foreground color
font bound for it.
Adding a third panel.
Similarly for the label l three that is Father's name setting for one colour font bound and adding it
to the frame.
Similarly for the branch as well, setting foreground colour, background colour, font of it.
Bound of it and adding it to the.
Panel.
Then we have a level five semester for which the fees will be submitted for one color font for it,
bound for it, and adding it to the panel.
Then there's the label six, which is a total payable for one color for eight font for it, bound for
it, and adding the content pane.
That is a label.
Then setting the bond for it.
Bond for the choice, adding the choice to our panel.
Then there is a new text field for one setting, for one color for it, font for it, column bound and
lining it to the panel.
Another text field setting for one color for red font for it, column for it setting.
Bound for that table and adding that.
Next to our panel.
Inside that blog, we have initialized the connection and executed the query that is select as from
a student where rule number will be the selected item from the choice.
This will trade over the record of the students where rule number will match and store the name and
fathers name of the student in the 23 text field respectively.
Then there is a combo box to select from the branch.
And whose foreground color font bound and have been added here now combo box two which will be used
to select.
This will be used to select semesters.
So this will be used to select semesters.
New font.
We have set the font type.
Size and family of this combo box text, then foreground color bound for the combo box.
And I think it to that our panel, then we have a new text field setting foreground color for it.
Font for it.
Columns for it and bounce for it.
Adding to that our frame as well.
Then there is a button.
Be excellent listener to the button, setting the font for it, bound for it, background color for
color and adding to adding that to panel.
After that, there is another button B to adding action listener to it, setting font font for it,
and setting the bound for that button, adding background color for regular and adding it to our panel.
After that there is another label as labeled cause setting back for rental for it using RDB values,
then setting font for it.
Bound for it and ending the.
Label to our panel.
Then there is a combo box to select from the course, which is from bootcamp taken by BBC, ABC and
a foreground colour for it.
Combo box for the font.
Bound for it and adding it to that, our panel.
Another panel whose setting its border named as free form and background color for it, using R&amp;B values
and bound for the.
Panel.
Then we have set the background color of the complete panel and the.
Panel and they will edit the panel to our panel.
I did this panel, which is showing the border to a world.
Panel.
After that, we have defined here the action performed method which is taking argument as action event.
Try if a dot get sources equals to from.
Even if the button event of the button is from one, then we will stabilize the connection with our
database and create the query select insert into fees.
So this will insert into the fees table the required values.
These are the values that is a prepared statement.
Pass the prepared statement.
Execute that prepared statement.
And we will.
Be fetching these.
Executing that prepared statement by suggesting first or get selected item and with respect to text
fill and selected item from the combo box and the choices we will update our in our database table that
is fee so entire is equals to start execute update so for I is greater than zero.
We will show successfully updated, so I will hold the associated execute update.
So if the statement executed successfully, it will restore one which will be greater than zero.
So it will so successfully paid.
If does not update it successfully, then it will be less than zero.
That will be minus one.
So.
It will go to else option and it also the error cache block will handle any exception if occurs and
if the source is from B2, then we will set the visibility of the current window as false and catch
any expression in the catch block.
So this is about all the.
This is about the class's fee structure and student fee form.
And this.
Now this will complete all the introduction explanation of the Java classes in our next video.
We will be having a look in the at the library of this project, which will help us to understand the
relativity and relativity of these classes database that how they are working.
The data has been updated or in database or not.
Data is fetching from the database correctly or not, so that those all things will be understanding
in our next video, which will be on the library of this project that is university management system.
So for till now, let me show you the output of these two classes.
I will be running from the login.
I'll run the login class.
I'll be writing admin.
Kellerman.
Then we click on log in.
Now.
We have fee structure.
I would be clicking on fee structure.
So that's how the pre structure looks like.
That's why we are having so much labels in this fee structure.
You can might also add this to the table in our database named as fee structure and then you can fetch
the card from there or also because the fee structure will not be changed in this project.
So that will be staying the same.
Or you can do that as well.
But I have initialized every field by using the label in our fee structure class.
So that's how it is look like and.
Now.
Now, wait a minute.
Estonian fee from stolen fee form will look like this.
We'll selecting the roll number.
The roll number will be displayed when we add the student's name for this name.
Select from the course branch and semesters as well.
Total payable amount you can write.
I'll be clicking on back.
So this is about all the classes.
Of this project.
In the next video, we will have a look on the live run of this project.