Now so that we have created actions performers for the print and exit button.
Let me explain what this is actually doing.
So suppose if your system has a printer attached, then this will try to print the text media and otherwise
this will catch an exception and show that it is an error.
The printer is not attached to the system, so try connecting a printer first and then try to print
your required text which you have typed for.
Similarly, on clicking on the exit button, there is a simple function system dot exit which takes
argument as null zero or false, whatever we call it.
So when we click exit, the system exits with the null exception.
Similarly for copy and cart, select and paste, we have in-built functions like for cut.
We have text area shortcut for copy.
Similarly, we have to paste this part only.
Like for copy we have text area.
Don't copy for paste.
We have extra dot paste.
An.
Select all.
We have text area not selectable similarly so yes we have done this everything now coming to the about
part what is going to be performed on clicking the about button.
So I'm clicking the about button.
A new about window will open which we have created here in the above Java class and the visibility of
this window should be set to true set visible.
Should be true.
Yes.
So here we are.
Now, let us try and run this.
Notepad dot java, run Java.
And then wait.
Yes.
So let us type something.
Hello, everyone.
We are here.
To learn core Java Soyuz.
Now let us try to click on the print button.
Perfect.
So I'm clinging clicking that print button.
A print window opens which asks that which printer you want to print it from and the format of this
print.
Similarly, it has many other options, also number of copies.
So the proper printing window is set with the help of this option.
Try and catch and get action.
Command equals ignored print.
Similarly on clicking the exit it will exit so the window is closed now running this again and try to
test the cut, copy and other windows buttons like hello.
Now let me try to select this and cut.
Yes, so it is cut.
Now let us try to paste it.
Hello is pasted.
Now select all of the text written here is selected with the help of this select button copy and then
try to paste it again, again and multiple times.
You wish it to be printed.
So we have created actual listeners for all the buttons here for the file, edit and help.
Now let us try to add some keyboard shortcuts with this button so that we can perform that task with
the help of keyboard itself while typing.
So there will be no need to click on the button, leaving your keyboard and coming to your mouse.
You can do everything with the help of your keyboard only.
So let's start adding the shortcuts.
Yes.
So below this we are going to add the keyboard shortcuts attached with every button in the menu bar.
So for the new file, we are going to set it as set accelerator.
Set accelerator is used for the keyboard shortcuts.
It has an argument as keystroke.
After which call get keystroke.
Get Keystroke and the required characters.
So key events.
Key events.
And.
After key events.
We have to.
Collector's Dot Vicki her.
We can, as we want control end to be the shortcut of this.
So suppose we are writing it as key event dot dot mn and the modifier will be as the event.
Key event control down mask.
The event.
Donald Musk Yes.
So we have successfully created a shortcut key for the new file option.
Now, let me copy this for all the buttons like we have it earlier, it was one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, 19.
So pasting it ten more times and replacing for each button.
Again.
And I think let us try to change open file.
Save file.
Print exit for the print button.
The shortcut will be different for exit button.
The shortcut is a different key from your keyboard shortcut.
Copy.
Based and select all.
So ignore the typos and select all.
Select all.
I think we have one more option about so about will also contain a shortcut attached with it.
Now think about some keys from your keyboard, like for opening the file.
It could be.
Or for saving.
It could be as control as for printing.
It could be paid for.
It could be W for exit.
Cut should be x and copy should be control c.
Page should be P.
For selecting all.
We use a.
And similarly for the about option, let us suppose we are using the J key on our keyboard.
So yes.
Now let us try to run this and see if we are okay.
Okay.
So if we are able to add.
No shortcuts.
Yes.
Perfect.
So we are able to add shortcuts with every key.
Like for new we have n0s print p exit w similarly for the edit options cut copy paste.
So let us try to check this.
Like if I am inputting hello and trying to cut this with the help of my keyboard print typing like it
does control x.
So it should be selected and cut.
So yes, I am able to cut it.
Now let me try to paste this with the help of my keyboard control.
Be so perfect.
The shortcuts are working perfectly fine.
Okay, so in the window of the notepad, we can see that there is a not so good double bottom lining.
So let us try to remove this with the help of some functions.
So search for the scroll area which we have created.
And try to add something which could vanish the double lining there.
So, yes.
At this place, I am going to add a scroll pen.
Yes.
Above this line, I'm going to add a scroll pane dot set border.
Said border and the border will be like border factory.
Don't create empty border as we do not want any border between the title and the menubar.
So create.
Empty border.
Selecting this.
Now let us try to run this and check if we are able to edit or not run Java.
And yes, the double border is managed.
So the application is almost ready.
One more modification.
I want to do this.
Suppose that we click on Control Open.
Our.
I suppose like when the file chooser option opens in the save and open button, this very old design
model of the file chooser opens.
So I want to give it a good look.
A modern file choose chooser should open.
So yes.
So the file chooser you should be involving to the user.
So I am going to add a UI manager dot set look and see said look and feel option inside which UI manager
again and get system look and feel class name get system look and feel class.
Yes.
So this will throw an exception when there is an error.
So throwing exception.
Yes.
So let us go and take a look that the file chooser is still the old one or it is updated running the
notepad java again.
And waiting for it to be executed.
Now let us try to type something.
Random tags and clicking and suppose say so often.
This is the modern trial style which opens and we want it in this way.
Only the old one was not so good and involving for the user.
So closing this now as far as I can say that we have covered almost everything in the notepad.
So giving this project a conclusion as we have created our about class app app named Notepad and after
which we have added actions to the buttons.
We have created menu bar inside the frame using the JWT library.
So overall, this project teaches us all the concepts about a simple Java UI application, and I hope
you all are going to make this project on your own and learn these concepts too, not only by viewing
this lecture, but making the project by your own is the best way to learn and practice the language
learning process.
So I hope you all have enjoyed this series of project and thanking you.
All for joining this.
Goodbye.