So in this video, we will be talking about the last three remaining classes of this project, that
is cab booking system.
So the first class here is the payment class, which will be used to perform the payment or for that
booking which the user have performed, booked or done.
Then it is defined, the payment class is defined inside the cab booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages like a duplicate color, a dot container, font, image, accent,
event, excellence, start and swing.
Inside the payment class, which is extending the frame and we have defined the parameterized or non
parameterized constructor for the payment class.
Set the layout as null.
After that, we have defined the size for that payment class and its location.
Its location will be 600, comma, 2 to 0 and its size will be 800, cross 600.
After that, we have defined a label like Pay the payment and setting its font family size.
Setting its font, family size, font type as.
Fond type as railway fond type font, family as railway font type as bold and font size as 40.
After that, what we are doing is we have set the label for the.
Uh.
Set the label bound for that label 50, comma 20 and its size as 350, comma 45.
Adding that label to our frame.
After that, we have defined the image icon in image icon and scaled its instance and after that added
that image to our.
Level four.
And after that what we are doing is adding the bond for that label so that we can locate that level
and setting its size.
After that, there is a button pay which will handle an event for the pay button, and inside the play
button we will click the button.
We will simply show that our dialog box that the page successfully.
Now pay don't set bond will set the location for that payment and size of that pay button.
Inside the g button, new G button back, we are adding an action element.
We will set the current visibility of the window as false and after that we are setting the bound for
that back button as 510 comma 2000 size will be eight plus 40, adding that back button to our frame.
After that we have defined the background color for that button current window as white and set the
visibility as true.
So inside the public static void main, we are defined new payments and the visibility as true.
Now for the check bill.
So this is the check bill class.
What we are doing in the check bill class that we are defined inside the package care booking system
and boards our school district for the interaction with our database and AWP event classes for our particular
handling events over the buttons and graphical user interface.
Then what we are doing is public class segment, which is extending the frame and public static void
main inside the public static void main.
We have defined the instance of the check bill class with the null values and set the visibility as
true.
We have created a parameterized constructor for that check string username and located the bound for
that frame as 550 comma to 20 and its size as 900 cross 600.
After that, we will set the visibility of the.
Were frame as true.
Then we are setting the price one, price two and price three as zero.
So the price one will be showing the price for that intensity.
Back caps booked price two will show the price for the intensity type of bugs and price three will show
the price for the transportation and truck user have booked for transporting the goods.
Now inside the trip log, what we are doing is we are creating a connection variable of our class and
executing a query from select district from interactive where username will be username.
While for that particular user name record price one is goes to we will store the price from that enter
enter ccap table now address is goes to see dot x execute query select extract from Interac app.
So for that particular Interac app table, we will be storing the required for that particular username
and for price two inside the price to a string, we will be storing the price for the Interac.
Now inside the string name, we will be storing the name of that particular customer from with the help
of its user name.
So for that we will be storing name is also asked string name and we will store the name in our name
a string.
After that we will be executing select action from in transport where name will be matched.
So where the user name will match in in transport table, we will store the price of that transport
in our price.
Train a string.
After that there is a string array of package one inside which what we are doing is package one point
PMG intercity cable and price one.
So we have defined a string array type of package one inside which we have defined for the image of
that package name as intercity cable and that particular price.
Similarly for the intercity, we are doing the same thing.
I defined package two for the intercity cable image for that particular and the price of that particular
price too.
Similarly for the package three, we have defined the package three jpg that will be image name and
transportable and its respective price.
Now there is where we have defined the tab.
The pain and G8 panel defined a panel which will be create package and package one.
We have defined the create package method here.
We will be discussing about it just after discussing this.
So tabbed pane.
Inter-City cab complement.
Similarly, there is a pay to create package.
Pass that package to intercity intercity and LP to and similarly for the Japan LP three.
Transport LP three.
I did that tapped with the border layout as central to our frame.
Now we have defined here a type of panel type of method create package inside which we have passed the
is string named as pack.
So we have defined a panel piva and let us lay out that null and background color as white.
So inside the image we have, first initialize the image by adding the pack zero.
So what we have is stored in our every package.
The first element is the name of the image.
So that's why we are adding the path and adding that pack zero so that this will load the image.
Adding that image to our label, setting its location and size, and adding that to our panel.
After that, what we are doing is we are for the particular label name.
We are showing that text like intensity care or intensity care setting is font size and location and
adding that to our panel.
Similarly, for that transfer cap setting its font size, foreground color, label bound, setting its
bounds and ending that word panel, then we are showing the total bill.
And after that total bill, we will show the price which is stored at the total location.
So that index too, and setting its font type family, adding the foreground color, its location size
and adding that to our panel.
After that, there is a label to be as per that.
That's just for the formalities.
I have added that text to make transporters reliable, running water everywhere and for everyone.
So this is for the just reference purpose, setting the font family type for it and adding that bound
and adding that to our panel and returning the that label.
Sorry genotype so returning that panel so this will return those panels and added with the tab the pane
with the border layout center.
So this is all about the check class.
Let me tell you about the last class, which is about our Java file.
So this will tell us about the project when we will click on that menu item.
If you remember, we have discussed in our when we were discussing our home Java file, so it is inside
the define inside the cab booking system.
We have imported the necessary packages.
After that we have defined our about class which is extending frame and implementing Excel.
Now there is a one button, one label, three font and one text area and one string.
Inside the non parameterized constructor of this class we have set the layout as null.
There is a be one button setting labeled as exit add one button.
To our frame, locating our B-1 battalion, setting its size, adding action listener to that be one
button, then font as it goes to new font railway font dot bold.
So this is the type of font which will appear.
Inside the string as we have defined these the.
Information about the project.
A brief introduction about that project and.
After that we have defined define the text area inside which we have passed that string.
It's string size, text size for the text area and a scroll bar vertical.
So the text area will be a scrollable vertical, also its editable property as false.
And then we have set the location and size for that particular text area.
After that, we have added the text area to our frame.
Then there is a defined the font font, bold 16 set font for that particular text area.
Then inside the container content pane, we have added defined a new text area and for the label about
project, this will be shown as about project added that label to our frame and set it set its bound
location, size and foreground color as read.
Then there is a font to really be font bold and 20.
Set the font for that label about project.
Then setting the location for the frame and after setting the layout as null and visibility as true.
Now inside the action perform method, we will be disposing the current instance and a static void when
we will be calling new about and set the visibility as true.
So this is all about from these last three classes.
In next video we will be having a look on our the library for this project.
So that's all from this video.