So now we are fully developed with our code.
So I will explain what I'm going to do here.
So consider these all the libraries I'm going to use.
But instead of this, I created one class, which is name as public class server.
So while creating any application, client and server part are very important, like server is for the
catching all the part of clients in the chat system.
So client is going to attach with server and to the server we are going to send the message.
That's the basic thing we are going to see here.
So first I'm creating your vector using this syntax.
So I will tell you what is the function here.
So vector is going to hold the instance of all the classes with the handlers.
So I'm creating your static vector with client handler.
You can see as an object, which is reasonable.
I will tell you you can check your classes now this and extents to object and I'm giving the name as
socket.
So socket is just like electrical sockets client is going to attach there.
So I'm mentioning as a socket now to run any method in or for the running purpose, we need method which
is main method to running our server which is going to draw input output exception.
That's a common exception we can find in server also.
Then server socket is I'm creating your socket with server socket.
So you may ask me like what is this server socket?
So it is basically java dot net package.
You can use your which is the default package in Java and you can use your server socket.
Then I'm giving which is I'm going to later increment it later because I need to name the client's IDs
as one to incrementing.
So I'm currently giving as a zero.
Then it will print in command, prompt or console that it's waiting for connection.
Our server is waiting for client connection.
Now current client count is depends on socket size.
If a while too, which is basically pinging the server or for the opening ports of server is always
true.
So server will always assert life on the network.
So I'm considering network as not an internet.
It's a network I'm considering as it's a loop of networks and server is always live there.
Then for that purpose I'm giving the file to then what is the significance between this system dot dot
println and what is this thing?
So basically current client count I'm giving as a sockets dot size.
So as a socket size our vector which is list here I'm using vector as a list here so we can use the
size as defining the client size.
Then socket connection.
I'm creating connection as object and which is going to accept the clients.
Then client IDs is going to plus one, which is basically I'm adding the client IDs here.
Then?
Print Writer I'm using your print writer output to get the output as an output stream connection point
output stream width then input stream I'm going to create here, which is buffer reader because clients
need to input and output both things.
So I need to mention that then this is client handler is going to hold some default things which is
basically client name or connection is basically our except connection.
Output is for output stream and input is for input stream.
Then add C is basically I'm going to add the client and you may ask what is this?
So this is the client handler and I created your thread and I'm starting the thread so via the thread.
So currently I'm deploying it on local.
So I'm going to specify clients on my own.
I'm not going to disclose it later.
Like I'm not going to I'm going to choose only my own clients as my for this deployment.
But working on current systems of multi chat systems, you can assume that to clients wants to get connection
to the server at the same time.
Like if you call someone you may get busy, but while chat system you should not get that busy calls
in the server part.
So for that purpose we need to create thread so each client connection will be handling by a thread.
So thread is basically small part of process.
I told you earlier and I'm going to start here.
So this is just part of connection, but I need to print it out as a client, handler, methods and
everything.
So this is just for close streams and everything I created.
But for that purpose, what I'm going to create, I'm going to create your public run method to create
a one enable interface.
So again with try and catch block, I'm going to accept the exceptions.
But in the file too, I'm accepting the message with resume method and receive is basically input dot
read line, which is basically input stream method and client handler.
Again, the connection and I'm mentioning as well, this is as my constructor for client handler.
And this is for the renewable interface is going to class it's going to use here and for that purpose
I created.
So this is done with the server part.
So remember while giving the server, this is your server port.
I'm mentioning as 2020 as my server port.
Now let us see.
What is the client here?
Oh.
So forgot about all these things and let us see what I'm going to do.
So in the text field, I'm going to use our text chat window.
I'm going to mention I mentioned your two frames, f one and F two.
F one is just for putting the name and F two is full message, connection and everything I'm going to
specify.
Then I'm creating here for setup with string host as argument.
Then f one is new frame which server host and I'm going to assign it.
So I created your text area text field with the button and everything I explained to you and I'm just
giving a recap for this.
Then I created your bottom panel and everything, and the bottom panel is for the bottom purpose.
I'm giving the bottom panel button also there for accepting the connections and everything.
Now let us see how we can run this.
So running is very easiest part here.
So first is I'm going to ping my server so.
For any purpose you need to run for server, then you can run clients.
So I'm now currently running my server.
So wait for some time.
It will give me the build and it will deploy my server.
Again.
Server is always live.
So it will accept connection at any time.
Like I'm not giving any or date time date time to server, so it will not at all stop for any time.
So it will always accept the clients.
So it's building.
Sometimes it may take time to build everything.
So it will take the resources and it will take everything.
It depends upon your system speed.
Without any like client methods or server methods, you cannot run any direct methods like.
Well.
So what needs to deploy force on your system or you can check on your local host.
So now build is successful.
My build is successful and you can check server is waiting for connection and current plan count is
zero.
That's usual.
I haven't created any client here.
Now let us move to my client and let me run client command here.
So if you can check here, I'm going to run my client, which is client start running.
I will tell you what is this host later.
But if I'm currently running on my local host so there is no errors I'm now getting because it's a direct
part.
So now you can check.
Currently my.
This is running.
And this is my.
Or client check system.
So I'm mentioning as A, B, C as my name and I'm submitting it so it will open me the next things.
So this is my client when and if I pressed hi here.
So ABC will be hired.
Now why protocol mismatch.
I will tell you.
And what's I'm getting your error.
It will run on your localhost, no problem.
But the thing is, I'm mentioning as my defaulting.
So you can check here.
If I run again, it will give me another climb.
So currently it's giving me the error because of this host because I mentioned the host 60 TCP and you
and what is this?
I will tell you.
But the thing is, my client is not running on localhost.
It is running on some other interface.
And this is my server which is running on and client is not connected actually.
So that's an error in my program.
So how I'm going to use that because creating on a local machine, it's not very useful case for multi
thread chat system connection between establishing between two systems or between two friends.
Chatting with two friends is the full approach of this.
So let me stop all the processes here currently.
So it is getting stocked and you can check your like.
Let me stop this also.
This is a stop button you can check here and now I'm stopped.
So what is this?
I will tell you.
So indie rock is a free service.
You can check here.
Indie Europe is a free service which is useful to forward your network or for your local host on the
Internet.
So it's a local like exposing your local host on the Internet, but it's a secure channel.
It's not like any cybersecurity, but it is very secure in directing.
And you can connect to services and you can establish the connections from anywhere.
So I downloaded it for my system, which is basically for Windows.
I'm downloading it.
You can unzip and you can use different things or you can sign up also here with your IDs and login
utilities and you can pass your token also.
So let me move in this ID and let me show you how the engine off is going to work.
So this is the engine window once you open so you can check here.
Different, different ports are giving you an example already given HTTP, then TCP also given.
So my protocol is TCP, TCP, which is I'm going to use your TCP traffic to handle TCP traffic.
And what is my port?
It's basically 2020 my server port.
Right.
Is so let me mention this command engine PCB 2020.
So sometimes what thing I forgot is basically.
I haven't mentioned that or two or three things.
So let me open and you talk again.
So it will accept.
My thing.
So let me open it again because I haven't mentioned the Indigo Dot XY PCB.
And 2020.
So.
Okay.
So I'm getting the error as in your local port is not available, so.
Let me open it again.
And.
Let me check it again.
In zero.
DCB be.
20.
Okay.
Now my server is like, you can check here.
My server is low.
So this is the web interface.
You can check it later.
But what we required, we required this line.
So this is my TCP protocol.
Then this is my host IO till IO.
This is my host and this is my port.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this part.
Well, you can copy the control.
See here, you can copy this.
Go to your ID.
You need to make changes to client only.
Let me print out this so I will use it later.
Now copy paste it.
So I will use it later.
And let me comment on this.
So it will not useful.
So what we need require we need to paste this six to this six so it will static always.
So I already mine is six only.
So I need to check this port and let me copy this.
And you need to mention about that, about the port, as I told you.
You need to change the port about.
So let me check.
Where is that all?
Okay.
So in the void connect to server.
I need to change the port to which I got.
Which is.
Basically this board, you can check your web interface and you can check for that purpose also.
But for me, it's going to work.
And now we are done.
Now we are done.
And now what I'm going to do is, as I told you, I need to run my server first.
When my server is running one 2020 port with the local host what it will be do in zero and drop pull
up that local host 2020 server request to that client part which is basically to this.
To this, it will pull up and now my client is now connected to this.
So basically server is running on my machine, but or it is connected to my machine.
So my machine is act as a server part, but client is not on my server.
So let me do one thing here in the client part.
Let me run this and let me show you how I'm going to use it.
So this is my client I'm going to use.
Yeah.
And which is I'm going to use in currently running currently client.
So it will take time to build once it is built, fully built, it will run the task and it will deploy
me one window, as you can see here.
So this is my window and let me mention his name, ABC here and let me submit this.
So now you can check connected to this IP, which is basically.
This bought this IP.
Now I'm connected connection and let me mention as high.
Now you cannot see your any messages like there is no error.
This is my build output.
But if I go to run part and if I go to server part, you can check my client when it's connected.
So I want to connect another client on my system only.
You can check with your friends.
Also, you can connect between two friends, but I need to deploy on my machine for that instance.
I need to edit the configuration here.
If you want to check, you need to install one plugin intel idea which is multi run plugin.
So go to plus icon here in order and debug configuration, then go to downward and check for multi run
as I'm doing here.
Multi run.
Let me view the name as.
Client one This is my client.
Let me add one thing.
Run client.
Which is my method.
Or don't give anything after launch and anything.
Click, apply and hit.
Okay.
So in this now you can check.
This is my main methods, but this is my multi run.
So what it will do, it will create an one another instances for client and it will call that so you
can the basic purpose of these things.
I can use another window also.
So currently in this you can check this is my ABC and this is my another window which is I'm going giving
the name X, Y, Z, and I'm entering this.
Now what you can check if I am quoting here by you can check your x y z also is printing by if I'm printing
here.
Hi x, y, z.
You can check.
I'm getting high x, y, z in another window.
So this is my x y z window and this is my ABC window.
And in the server this thing you can check the client counts.
So server is basically giving, not giving any view purpose because it's command line interface just
but for the clients I created when.