So here is the update room.
Java class.
It is defined inside the package hotel and we have imported the necessary packages.
These are the packages which contains a D border layout scale, swing, swing frame, empty border font,
everything which will be needed.
And there is a class update room which is extending frame initializing the connection variable as null.
Prepare the statement as null and one g panel and for text field.
These are all private instances of this class and the choice variable as c one.
Then there is a main function.
Inside, which we have called the current stance of this class and setting it to frame invisibility
as true.
Then inside the closed method, we have disclosed disposed to the object and inside the public update
room through which is throwing as well exception.
This is the non parameterized constructor of this class and we have set the default close operation
setting the bound of it and content pane that is a new J panel bottom layout of this panel and then
adding it to the frame and adding its layout as null.
Then we have added an image icon by using a label and image icon objects.
That label is I2 and adding the label is L one, setting it bound and adding it to a frame.
Then there is a label slave state which is stating update room status setting font for it and setting
the bound for it as well.
Then we have added that to our panel label under the label as guest ID.
Setting the bond for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there is a choice inside the tribe.
We have created a connection with our database, executing the query select from customer but will iterate
over our restart next while we'll trade over the rows or the data records of the customer inside the
customer table and add the number of those customers to the choice.
Then setting the bound for the choice and adding that choice to our panel.
Then there is a label availability stating as availability, label setting the bound for the data adding
to our panel.
Then there is another label as clean status, setting the bound for it and adding to our panel.
Then there is another text field with respect to the above those labels.
Sitting down for the text, adding that to our panel.
And similarly for another text field, that is for a status setting bound for it, adding it to our
panel.
Then there is a text field for the respective room label and setting the bound for it and adding it
to our panel.
Then there is J button which is check.
We have defined X and perform limit for it.
His string as one will get the selected item from the choice.
And we have defined a connection here.
Executed the query which is select extra from customer where number is equal to S1.
So for that particular number, the data from the customer table will be fetched and over that record
it will add text room.
So in the text field it will send the text from the room number of that particular result set.
And similarly for another type log, it will execute the text from room number.
So for the room number from the room, it will select the record from the room, from the fetch current
room number which will be selected or that data or record.
It will iterate and set the availability as availability from the record and clean status from clean
status from the record.
Setting the.
Brown of the button foreground color and background color.
Then there is an update button on which we have upon the action event, which will update the status.
So a clean status here updated by executing the query.
A dialog box will appear after the addition that is updated, successful.
And after that we have bound for the button updated the background.
Calories.
Black for calories white.
And.
Added that baton to our panel.
Then there is another button as exit.
For which action profound method inside which we have defined a new reception set visibility as true
and correct visibility as false.
It is bounce off button background color of button, foreground color of button, adding that the label
and there is a last label as room number setting the bound for the room number adding the to that our
panel and then there is a.
Setting of background, color of the complete frame.
Let's look at the next class, which is a pick up Java class.
Define inside the package hotel.
We have imported the necessary packages.
Then we have defined the class.
Which is extending from our connection very well as a prepared statement, as null results that has
null private channel content pane, private label table and the choice events are the main function.
We have defined public void run method, which is initializing the current class object and setting
its visibility as true inside the dispo close.
We are disposing the current object.
Then we have defined the non parameterized constructor which is throwing a SQL exception, setting the
default close operation of the frame bounds for the frame, and initializing a new panel border for
that panel.
Setting the current.
Adding that panel to the frame.
Setting the layout of the panel.
Then there is a label as pickup service, setting the font for that label.
Adding the bound for that label and adding it to our panel.
Next level is the type of car setting the bond for it, adding it to the panel.
Then there's a second choice inside which the choice will be selected from the database for which we
have initialize the connection from the connection class.
Then there is a result set inside the result set.
We have executed a query select exit from driver so as it has a pick up class.
So it will take the data from the driver class.
It will trade over the record of the driver.
Using Aristotle next after that seven point ad.
So it will add the choices, brands of cars into the choice.
Then there is a setting the bound for that choice and adding it to our panel.
Then there is a label label for.
Hiding the label.
Setting the bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there's a button labelled as display.
Defining action performed on that button.
Huh?
There is a grocery store in the string as well.
So that Astrovan driver brand is able to select a brand from the choice inside.
Right.
Initializing the connection, executing that query and setting the table model.
Then setting the bound for that button.
Background color.
Foreground color.
And that's.
Adding it to that our panel.
Then there is a button exit defining it's action performed.
New reception will be true and can visibility as false defining it's bound for the background color,
foreground color and adding it to our panel.
Then there is a G panel defining its bound, adding it to our panel similarly for the label age.
Label gender.
Label company.
And.
The label brand.
Label available and then at last label location, we have set the bound for all these labels and add
it to our panel.
At last there is a get content pane which is setting the background color as white for that complete
window or frame.
The last class of this project is search room.
Define inside the package hotel imported the necessary package of that for that class.
Class is defined which is extending the frame.
Connection 11 a prepared statement as null results set as null age panel or text field or table at choice
inside main, we have created the current NSA instance.
Setting the visibility of the instance as true.
Then inside the closed method we have closed disposed the current object of the class.
Then there is a non parameterized constructor of this class.
Setting the default close operation of the frame, bound for the frame and standing.
And another panel creating the border of the panel.
Adding it to the frame, then adding its layout.
Then there is a label search for room setting, font for it.
Bound for it.
And.
Adding it to our panel.
Then there is a room, bed type, room, bed type setting bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Then there is a label room number sitting bound for it, adding it to our panel.
Similarly, there is availability setting, bound for it, adding to our panel.
Similarly, for the price setting, bound for it and adding to our panel.
Then there is a bedtime setting bound for it, adding to our panel and there is a checkbox only display
available.
So this we have added to our panel set after setting bound and its background color.
Then there is one choice either can we see a single bed or double bed setting bound for it and add it
to our panel as well.
Then for the button search, we have performed the action performed inside which we have created the
SQL query, which is a state that select as the reform room where by type.
So the type which will be selected, it will fetch the record from the room for that particular type.
Second query will fetch the record from the room where availability is equal to available and that type
is equal to selected type.
After that, inside a type log we have initialize the connection, executed the scale query and the
setup result in our model table inside which if the checksum is selected, then we have executed the
query SQL to.
And said that to our table its catalog will handle any exception.
If, of course, then we have.
Set the tone for the button background color of the button for one color of the button, adding it to
our panel.
Then there's the exit button.
Exit button, which is labeled as back.
And it's action performance that has been defined here, which is a new reception will be true and current
visibility as follows setting it down and setting the foreground for it, background color for it,
and adding that button.
To our panel.
Then there is a table sitting bound, bound for the table, adding the table to all.
Panel.
Then there is the label.
Claim status bound of the label, adding to our panel, then setting the background color of the complete
window as white.
So these are the last three classes of this project.
In the next video, we will going to take a look on the complete run of this project, how this project
is running, and also displaying that the data is actually changing in the database as well.
We will do anything from this standalone application or a desktop based application for the hotel management
system.
So in this video, let's have a look at the running of these three classes.
So if I run this update room or Java, it will look like this.
Don't have any study because haven't added any data yet.
The three buttons check or update or Mac.
Now let's close this.
How we look at the pick up to watch our final run.
Let's run this file.
This is how pickup service will look like.
Till now.
No data because I haven't edited it.
I will be showing the complete run in the next video.
Close it.
The inside search room.
We will run this file as well.
So this is how the search room will look if you click on only display available, so only the available
rooms will be displayed.
If you uncheck it, then the available and occupied both type of rooms will be displayed either against
select single bed or double bed from here.
So that's all about the last three classes of this project.