So now in this else part, you're the number three was run.
So our third option was to run.
Now in this instance, we are going to give a feedback to the user telling when they run away and then
we are going to reiterate the loop and that's why we have the scheme loop here.
This one, I will explain the reason in just a second.
So in this case of the user typing in the number three, you are going to go ahead and do a firstly,
we will do a system or not print all in here and simply we are going to go ahead and say tab, just
try to you run away from the.
Simply write to me here.
Okay, then.
Okay.
So this just.
So here we are going to go ahead and see you.
Let's see you run away from the enemy.
Here, the enemy of the the name of the enemy.
And then add on the again.
The name is still in scope.
So we declare it all appear and we are still inside the same value.
See my look, this one.
So here we run away from whatever enemy it was and we will concatenate on the exclamation mark here
at the end.
So there is no now there is where we need to label.
We are going to continue working or what continue.
Thus it moves to the next integration of the loop.
It says, okay, not everything.
So firstly just add the label here which was the first continue and we have the label game here, right?
And the next thing.
Just here in the Els part blue.
This else would be this point.
Just go back to the start of the loop.
The problem is we're already inside of loop, okay?
And we don't want to go back and do this one because.
Hmm.
Yeah.
One, one.
Okay, so we.
We are in the combat loop.
We are fighting the same enemy.
We are actually want to go one further back into the main game loop so we can generate a new enemy.
Okay.
So firstly here I will try it system not not print a linear.
Not not print Alan and just put invalid.
Come on.
Okay.
We have done the invited.
Come on, now.
Here it is.
I have already said we are already in the loop and we don't want to go back into this one.
We have already defined our three cases.
So one, because this is the combat law where we are fighting the same enemy.
We actually want to go one further up, back into the main game loop so we can generate a new enemy
and start the combat again.
So this label right here, this game label, we are labeling this.
Okay, the final book.
Here.
Here, the main one, we are just labeling it game.
So when we come down and we can continue we can continue the game and then just for the label game.
Okay.
So we are currently in so we had come back up to here, go back to the here and.
Then we wouldn't be running from the army.
We would just be refreshing the whole combat cycle and we'd be offered the same options again.
And so by saying continue game here, we are going to break out of this loop here and we are going to
continue on.
It's going to find a new enemy and we forgot where we fought the enemy in the first place.
So that's why we have that label here.
So and that's a third option.
So the final statement, if the user did not type in one, two or three, if they typed in random stuff
or they didn't type a valid number.
So we are just going to give them simple feedback and we are just going to say invalid command or the
invalid input.
And this is fine just to say this because basically we managed to reach this.
LS Here, see invalid command we are going to go ahead.
It's because it's a while loop.
Nothing happens.
So we will head straight back up to the top.
We will just be offered the options again.
So the user has another chance to look at the options they have and then do whatever they want to do.
So we have got quite a lot going on here at the moment.
So we have started our menu, we have initialized the anime,
we have initialized the anime and we have said, well, the enemy's health is greater.
Okay.
So just start with the hand is greater than the zero.
We are going to offer the use of these options and.
Okay.
So we are going to offer the use of this option and then we are going to go ahead and get their input.
So we are going to go ahead and say if done equals two.
Okay.
So one of the the first one.
Firstly what it will do here.
Firstly, it will be equals first.
Here I will take the just we have initialize with initialize with the enemy.
We have said so.
We have said the while the enemy's health is greater than zero, we are going to offer the use of these
options here.
We are going to go ahead and get their input here and then we are going to go ahead and see what I will
say.
Okay.
So it will say attack.
So everyday equals the first one is the attack.
So the pick, the first one we are going to go ahead and attack.
But if it is equal to we are going to do here, we are going to do this if it is equal to three here.
So we are going to do this.
And so let's go ahead and come out of this loop.
Okay.
And.
Come out of this loop now.
Just making sure I've got the facts right now.
Okay.
This coming up, this file.
The first thing we are going to track for is once we are out here, we need to check why we broke out
this loop.
Did we break out the loop?
Out the loop because we defeated an enemy or did we break out because our health went to zero?
So you can see if our health is less than one.
We go ahead.
Okay.
And C break so we have broken out of.
Firstly, I will start with this and I will say this certain one.
Just make it one zero.
So here I will write this less than one.
Here I will write system, not dot print alone and under this.
Okay.
Just we will put the statement here.
You are too weak.
To lead the battle.
Okay.
And then just simply break the.
We have broken out of the loop right here.
So the first thing we are going to check is our player is dead.
You're going to see health is less than one and we are going to say system not out of print.
And it see, we are going to add a descriptive sentence such as anything you want to do, just simply
right.
You are too weak to play the battle.
Okay, so there's the little thing that we do.
If our health is blue one, we say you are too weak to play the battle.
And then we go ahead and break the spell break.
There we go.
Okay, so break it.
So here we will break out of the main loop while running loop, and then it will come out.
Okay to why?
Okay.
So then it will come down here.
We're going to add some messages first.
Just simply write system, not dot.
Print a line here.
Just copy this print.
See?
Okay.
First.
Who's this?
Okay, just copy this.
Some of this astronaut outdoor talent.
Oh, exterminate.
We have the three.
Okay.
We have added these one.
This simply.
Make it long.
Okay.
Firstly.
We are going to add a message to.
And at the end we will say thanks for playing or something you like.
So the first thing we checked, if our health was less than one, we do the description and break up.
The loop over health was not less than one.
We have broke out and break out the loop and here it must have mean we defeated the enemy.
So we still have all the enemies.
Okay, so.
Firstly, I will start with the.
Just a minute.
I will firstly write.
And then.
I know this.
I will write.
Just use symbol.
I will use hash here.
Just simply write me those was Richard.
Okay.
Was defeated.
Just simply this.
Okay.
So the next one.
I know this.
We have to show.
Right.
You have.
And.
Plus.
And here I will write actually left.
Okay.
Just simply write this.
Just honored that options which we can have here is not what you.
Like to do not.
Okay.
So then.
And this.
I will give some names.
Continue fighting.
And I decided right to not accept again
and copy this and.
After this line just added.
Okay.
So we have checked our health was less than one.
We do the description and break of the look.
If health was not less than one, we have proved the loop broke out the loop and here it must have weaned.
We have defeated the enemy.
So we still have all the enemy state up here and it name and stop so we can use still them down here.
Remember, if we haven't, we have initialized them here.
We have done the whole combat loop and then we have OC so.
Firstly here I have concatenated the name of the enemy and was defeated.
Okay.
So you will see when we actually run this how formatting makes it look like.
So.
Next thing, the actual game for the user is fairly reasonable.
So we will add another print line here.
In this line I did not explain it.
We basically just added that formatting said army was defeated so the name of the enemy was defeated.
Go ahead and add some more formatting and we are going to tell them you have we are going to tell our
we are going to tell our player how much help so how much help they have left.
So you have left you have held HP left.
So we have told them they defeat the enemy.
We have told them how much HP they have left.
No.
So now we are going to go ahead and add a random drop chance.
So now we need our condition after this.
We just.
We have to add our chance.
So firstly, I will start, I will write and then simply explain that.
Okay.
So here I am in right or next end and just give the parameter to the 200 and just simplified option
or options under this the num health portions plus plus.
Simply write system.
Yeah.
System not print, Alan.
And under this what I can do.
It is simply the.
And anime
dropped health.
Bush.
And ocean here.
I'm just done.
System dot dot, print linear.
And now I will just simply write.
You have.
No health potions.
Portions.
Hmm.
Okay.
So then.
So what I have done here.
We have not only we have defeated the enemy and how much HP we have now, we are going to go ahead and
just simply add our random drop chance.
Remember, we have a percentage here.
Here on this one.
The percentage, you are right.
So we are going to use we are going to use that percentage.
And here the health interruptions.
If we defeat an enemy, we want a 50% transforms, drop a health potion.
Again, you could change this percentage to whatever you want.
Okay.
So the question we are going to use here if.
Here what I will say just if our next then we are going to go in here.
I am right or not next end and then we are going to put 100 in is greater than health potion drop drop.
So firstly we are generating a random number between 0 to 100.
And if the random number is greater than the percentage chance, if the number is greater than the percentage
chance for drop and actually it should be less then not greater than.
Okay.
So if the number between not one 100 is less than the drop chance, it means the random number landed
in that area.
So it means making the number high will be more likely.
So if I make the drop chance, 99%, obviously a number between a random number, not a 100.
So highly likely to be less than 99, which means that the chance is higher.
And so I'm going to keep that 50 so you can change it and similarly say I will do ten.
A random number between not ten and 100 is much more likely to be greater than ten as opposed to less
than ten.
And so I will go ahead and change this.
And just say to the 50 so a percentage drop trumps work so inside.
Then if the statement here we can see health portion and just plus plus just add up the health portion
and we will add one health portion and we will give the feedback to the user they want to know they
have actually received or not.
So here I have at the end we dropped our health push and then we will just do some more useful feedback
for the player.
We will just tell them now the total number of health portions they have after the drop you.
So you have portion.
It could be ambiguous so we can just add the brackets.
Okay.
So we have added the health portion and give the user feedback.
So that's the random dropdowns for the health portion.
So we have said enemy was defeated, how much help they have left.
We have a randomizer drop off the healthier.
And told them if they have received one or we are going to go ahead and add a little separator here
and we are going to give the user some more option.
We are going to go ahead and say system not that println and we are going to say what would you like
to do now?
And we will have the two more options and we will first name it as the continue fighting and we are
going to have number two as the exit again.
So after we have every time we defeat an enemy, we are going to be presented with these two option
here, these two options.
So, so let's go ahead and do the same thing we did above.
And we are going to go ahead and get the string.