Now this will be our main class.
Finally minesweeper down Java here we have to take firstly our class extends three and now under this
we need a private label name as a status bar
and now we need a public constructor, the minesweeper.
And under that we need to create a method by the name initial UI, which will be the layout of our game.
Here I have created my master by the name initially.
Right here I will take the to spot and set it to the new label and this.
Inverted commas.
And then now we have to add and need status more comma, more than layout.
Don't we need to set in the sound string?
And then.
Now we need to add a board here.
So I will write new bold to the status bar, need the set resizable matter and set it to the phones
by default and need the pack method here.
Now we need to send the titles of our game.
Here I will write Minesweeper and we need to output of our game in the middle of the screen.
So set.
Related
set.
Here I will write said location relative to if to the null and here will need to default close operation
also.
So here I will write g frame not exit down close.
Done.
Now we need to define the main matter also.
So after that I will write public static void mean.
Read the string.
Air Chiefs here and here.
I will need an event.
Q.
I need to give the parentheses, the hyphen and don curly bracket open here I will take the variable
x add it to the new the class name here and x not.
Sent visible to infected with the true value here and here we have created the window has fixed the
size.
So for this we have to use the resizable multilayer and this will be our main class.
So we will run our program.
Okay.
So here we have got everyone on board the Swan Hill here.
So yeah, you can see now here this to the game.
Last pitch.
Okay.
Bits and pieces.
Yeah, it's working.
Okay.
Yeah.
So we had Brutus perfectly in the way, and now we can.
We should see what we have done.
So that will be our first, last and final output.
So we have the world class here.
There are 13 images used in this game.
A cell can be surrounded by a maximum of eight mind.
So we need numbers one through eight.
We need images for an empty mind, a covered cell and a cell.
And finally, for a wrongly marked cell, the size of each of the images is of 15 cross, 15 trucks
and a mile field is an array of numbers.
So the mindset represents a cell that contains a mind.
The coal mine centers used to fill that cover and contains a mine.
Among the mines here, it's covered mine, so that was marked by the user.
These constraints determine whether to draw mine a mine, cover a market, or only sell the mine here.
So the mine field in our game has 40 hidden mines.
So what you don't mind is the 16 rules on the 16 columns here in the field.
So there will be 226 cells together in the mine field.
Here the field is an array of numbers we have and now we have.
The individual variable determines whether we are in the game or the game is over and the mines left
variable the number of mines to be marked left here.
Reload here.
We load our images into the imagery and the next thing we will we have done we have a new game master
which will initiate the minesweeper game.
These lines are a minefield.
Every cell covered by default in the wine cycle here we randomly push all mines in the field and here
we have turned in the find empty cell method.
We find empty cell.
If the player clicks on a mind cell, the game is over.
If it clicks on the cell adjacent to a mine, he uncovers a number indicating how many mines the cells
adjacent to.
So the clicking on an empty cell leads to uncovering many other empty cells, plus cells with a number
that form a border around the space of empty borders.
So we use a recursive algorithm to find these empty cells.
So in this one, this line or the code, we check the cell that is located to the left to an empty cell.
If it is not empty, it is uncovered.
If it is empty, we repeat the whole process here by recursively calling the find empty cell.
And we have the paint component matter, which will turn snowmen into images here.
The game is over and we lost.
We should all uncover the mines, if any, and show all wrongly mob cells, if any.
So the score line draws every cell on the window, the sun and what we have done.
Okay.
So if there is nothing left to uncover, even if the in-game variable was set to false.
We have lost in the mouse pressed matter how we react to mouse click the mouse.
The minesweeper game is controlled solely by mouse.
We react to left and right mouse clicks.
We have determined the x and y coordinates of the mouse pointer.
We compute the corresponding column and row of the minefield and we check that we are located in the
area of the minefield or not.
The uncovering of the mice is done with the right mouse button and if right click on unmarked side,
we add mark to the number representing the cell.
This leads to drawing a curve itself with a mark in the paint component method.
So if we left click on a cell that has been already marked, we remove the mark and increase the number
of cells to be mark.
So then nothing happens.
If we click on the uncovered and the mark, then it must first uncovered by the right click, and only
then it is possible to left click on it and let also a left click because it removes a cover from the
cell.
In case we left click on the mine.
The game is over.
If we left, click on an empty cell.
We call the final result method, which recursively finds all adjacent empty cell.
Here this.
See the.
That's right.
Click here.
You will see that.
If you right click
on the cell, we add mark for cell to the number representing the cell.
This leads to drawing a covered cell with a mark in the paint component and if left, click on cell
that has been removed.
We remove the mark on.
The we remove the mark and increase the number of cell.
We marked.
This one.
Okay.
So if nothing happens, if we click on the cover in the map, it must be first uncovered by another
right click here.
Can you see this?
Yeah.
This one left click remove the cover cover from the cell in case we left click on a mine.
The game is over here.
The game lost.
This is the game is over.
Every left click on an empty cell.
We call the find empty cell matter, which recursively finds all empty cells here.
See who we are marking this.
Now, if I click on see here, can you see?
So the board needs to be repainted, for instance, or a marker set or removed.
We call the repaint method here.
So this is on our project.
This has our output.