In this video, we will have a look at the live run of this project.
So we'll be running all these classes one by one and see how these classes are performing and executing
those operations for which purpose we have been created.
These so let me run this first class, which is a CAD count or Java class, which will be used to count
the characters and words in the provided text area.
So I'll be running this file.
So here the window has been appeared.
So this is the window for the cardboard count tool.
So I'll be entering here.
Let's suppose I am entering this.
Project contains.
Beauty ladies like.
Uh, font chooser.
Sorry.
Font chooser.
I'll be fine.
Calculator.
Or online test.
Puzzle.
And.
Take.
Back to.
Now, let me check for.
Let me first change the pad color.
So as soon as soon as I clicking on bad color, it is showing us these color options where I can select
colors.
So this will be the bad color from HSV.
You can choose the edge, saturation and value.
Also with these lines Excel or in the form of RDB.
Also you can choose and in the form of CMYK you can also choose.
So I will be selecting from the swatches.
So let's suppose any random color, I'll be selecting this color and I'll click on.
Okay, so the background has been changed to the color which I have selected.
Now let me change the color of the text.
So let's suppose I want to change the color of the text to something white.
So let me click on.
Okay.
So now this is appearing like this.
So the color changing has been working fine for the both background and the front of this text area.
Now if I click on Count.
If I am clicking on count.
So it is showing that words are 18 and characters on 113.
So this is how this character word count tool is working.
It is working pretty fine.
So this is our first class.
Let me close this.
And.
I'll be running now.
The next class, I will be closing this.
That is a font chooser class.
So let me click run this file.
So this is how the font chooser is appearing.
Let me check you if we can edit this.
Yes, we can edit this also.
So let me edit this.
Let the things will be two lines.
This will be perfect to check for any.
Now I'll be clicking on set font.
So this will take us to this where this another dialog box that is a choose font.
So there is the list of the fonts and it is scrollable also.
So there is a list of fonts you can select from this, and here is the size you can select regular italic,
bold, bold italic as well.
And there is the size ten, 12, 14, 16, 18, 20, 68 and 64.
So I'll be selecting some.
Let's suppose I'll be selecting.
Dubai light and bold italic let's suppose bold only and its size.
Let's suppose 20.
So if I click on okay so that things have been reflected, every font type family and size have been
reflected here in our text as well.
If I am writing something, then this is also in the same font size type and family.
So that's how this font user class is working in which we can set the font type for the text, which
we have written in our area, and we can choose font family font style and font size and.
And that's how it is working.
So let's move on the third class, which is of IP finder class.
So let me close this and run that IP finder class.
So here is our IP finder class.
So let me run this one.
So here the IP finder tool has been appeared.
This is the dialog box.
In this text field we have to enter our UDL so it will present you the IP of that.
I'll be entering a URL here.
So that is w w w dot google dot com.
That's a general url.
I'll click on find ip.
So it is showing that ip of w w w dot google.com is this here it is shown.
Let me click on.
Okay, let me check for the another one that is a Gmail dot com.
Gmail.com.
So it is showing the IP of the Gmail as well.
To run this project, you must have been connected to the internet.
That's then it will be run.
Otherwise it will not show you the IP and it will show you the exception.
So that's how this IP finder tool is working.
Now let me run the another file that is my calculator or Java file.
So I will be running this file.
So here the calculator has been shown the output.
This is the output of the my calculator.
I'll be entering a value.
Let's suppose I have a selected eight multiplied by two, so I will click on.
Okay, so that is showing 16.
I'll click on clear.
So it is zero.
Let's check for any point values.
Also 2.8.
Minus one equals 21.7999.
So that is showing that values something, some values.
So that's the output of this minus.
And let me check for divide also eight divided by two.
So that is four.
So this is the calculator, how this is working.
So this is the output of the calculator which we have created.
Now let's check for the online test java file.
So if I am running this online test or Java file, let's check what the output of this file.
Run file.
So here the quiz has been appeared online test of java.
So I am selecting random things here.
So next.
Now suppose if I want to bookmark this question, I'll click on bookmark.
So bookmark has been added to and we have moved to the next question.
Let's select.
I am selecting random things.
Let's suppose I want to bookmark this so I will be looking at this mark or this also class next anything,
any options?
I have said I've been selected randomly.
And I'll be bookmarking this question as well.
So three bookmarks have been added this.
Let's suppose this.
And.
I'll click on next.
So what happening here is we have reached of the ten questions but we have to I if I click on result
so it is showing that correct answers one but we can and I click on okay so the app has been closed.
We can also go for the bookmark questions by clicking on those bookmark buttons because we have bookmarked
those questions to answer after completing all the questions.
So that's how the online test class is running.
And let me show you the remaining two classes.
That is a puzzle on Java.
So I'll be running this puzzle dot Java file as well.
So one file.
So this is how the puzzle game will appear.
There is a one block back end.
So if I click on Phi Phi Phi will be shifted on this block.
This is the total click and time will be shown in seconds.
If I then click, then it will update the time with the respect of the time, which will be using if
I click on for the full value shift table.
So that's how this game is working.
We will want if is able to set these values in correct order like one, two, three and four or five,
six.
So to do that, let me try.
Uh.
This is how I can do it.
Now for has been come to the right place.
Uh.
What we need to do is.
So that's how you can do that.
It's.
Ready.
So you have to do that too, so that the boxes come at the right place.
Then it will show you that you want.
So that's how it is working.
Currently, I'm not able to arrange it, so that's how it is working.
Puzzle game and let's there is a last game which is a tic tac toe game.
Let me run it so I'll be on file.
So this shows us the two radio buttons either versus computer.
So I'll be clicking on versus computer.
Now my choice.
I'll be feeling energized.
I feel here so I'll feel cross the zero will appear automatically.
Let's I will be feeling cross here.
The zero paired here I'll be filling cross here zero paid here.
Now I can put either the here or here I will be one.
So it's the message shown you one click reset.
So I'll click reset.
So the game will be reset again.
You can play this game again.
So this is how the all of these classes, which we have defined and implemented in this project, are
working very fine.
The objective or purpose of this project was to.
I understand the basic concept of the AWP and the swing framework of Java.
So that's what we have done in this project.
So that's all from this.