Now let us start adding some more specifications to this code.
So.
Let us try to find.
What happens after Marla receives her salary.
Marla receives salary?
Yes.
So the function is called and invoking the method get salary?
So let's try to run this.
And see what output we are going to receive.
Okay.
So it is showing an error.
That teacher name is me writing, not Marla.
Marla is the student one of the students.
So.
Yes.
Rena is the teacher here.
So now I'm going to run this again.
So yes, there is no change as we haven't seen this out anything.
So let us try to suss out.
Again after paying it to Marla.
Sorry.
It's me.
90.
Confusing with the names.
So, yes.
Let us do the same for who we know is the right.
So replacing this head.
Yes.
So now, again, if we try to run this code.
The money earned will be updated.
So yes, school has spent a salary of RS 9000 and left with 90,000.
Now let us do a different thing.
Let us try to.
This out.
A student's face like.
Yes.
So here we are trying to say.
So, Rana, what is rather rather is a student here.
So let us see what its output is.
So you can see that there is a garbage value after student.
Suppose if we try to print what is it that has fees?
So we can write it as the fees paid by.
Closing it.
And then.
Bases.
Yes.
So if we try to run this.
So actually, you know what?
Let us remain this as.
Grab only and try to explore something more.
Currently it is giving a garbage value as this four.
So let's get back to the student or zero part and.
Try to create a override to string function so we can write it as over.
Write.
Public string.
And the toasting method.
I will show you what this toasting method does.
Once after it is executed.
You will relate it with the garbage that you are receiving after calling the student.
So what is return by this function?
Student's name student.
Name.
Suppose student's name is Rana?
We call it their student name.
And.
A colon.
The name variable.
Yes.
And the total fees paid.
Total fees paid.
Still no word on the total fees paid over all but total fees paid till now.
In rupees.
So suppose I write.
Yes.
And the face brain function.
So calling it and closing it.
So, yes.
We are here with this two string function override two string function and let us call this again in
May not so sister dot println rather let us try to run it again.
So, yes.
Buffer students name rather.
Total fees payday loans ₹50,000.
So yes, initially it was returning guard value but with the use of two string function.
Yes.
So with this use of this tool string function, the garbage value is vanished.
So, yes, this is the use of this two string function.
We learn to.
More function by far till now says you can try print other student also.
Yes.
Let us call it for one of the student.
Juba.
So that will be received as the total fees paid by Jodi Arias.
So Jodi has total fees paid till now is zero, as in now only two students have paid the fees, Tamanna
and Rana.
So it is a perfect output.
The total fees paid is zero rather.
Total fees paid is 50,000 now.
Okay.
So we have learned so many things by far in this project.
One more thing I would like to add is that this was the basic concept we were learning to this project.
One more thing that we can do with this is make a desktop window, interface it.
The output will open in a separate window like.
Not in the terminal.
There will be a separate window.
So if you want to explore more, you can do that.
It is a very simple task.
The main focus of this project was to teach you the basic concept of Java ops and classes and methods
in Java.
So let us quickly summarize what we have learned through this project by far.
Okay.
So before summarizing, we would also like to add the override to script.
For the teachers as well.
So, yes.
Adding the override.
Let me copy it from the student part.
Yes.
So yes, this is our right to strength function.
We have created it for the students.
Now we are creating it for the teachers also.
And in the teachers we have salary.
Get 77.
So it is like the name of the teacher.
The name of the pitcher.
Total salary earned so far.
So both sanity on and.
And then sadly on Soyuz.
Now let us try to test this.
Since out.
Now among the teachers is Samantha.
Mother.
Let us try to run this.
It has some errors.
Let me try to fix it.
So diabetes in that patient.
Oh, yes.
We missed the base.
We are following the principle of learning by doing.
I am learning.
Meanwhile, teaching you to make this project.
So if we miss something, we should learn this by solving the errors.
Solving the bugs is the best way to learn any language or make any project.
So yes, after fixing this error, we will go back and try to run this again.
So I guess my last total salary until now is as we haven't paid anything to Marla.
If we try to run it for another day, like.
Suppose it's.
Yes.
So if you try to run it for Russell, they.
But also the total salary until now is 6000.
This is done with the help of the override tool string function.
This helps us to return the salaries until now and rest of the things.
So yes.
Now summarizing this project what we have learned so far.
We learn to create a school payment management system.
Like we manage the salary credited to the teachers.
The fees submitted by the students.
We have created four classes main class, school class, student class and teacher class.
For the school class.
We calculated the total money, spent the total money by creating a separate method in the student class.
We have created the object, set aside name grade fees, paid fees total and similarly for the teachers.
So overall, we have learned the basic of Java and its oops concept head oops denotes object oriented
programming.
So after completing this project successfully, I hope you all will grasp will gain a good grasp at
this Java Basic Oops concept.
That's all.
Ending this and wishing you a good day.
Thank you.