If you are so take it strong.
You are simply.
And you are simply copying this.
Just beat this line and don't.
So we have.
Take this.
You are in.
And now we have.
Get the Yahoo!
String results.
So.
Right.
Try and take the string results here.
MP
you are in.
Mehmet Oz took the page on the New York.
Do you want to?
PWD.
This is done.
Now we need a buffer reader.
Florida in New we need Florida's.
And give it a new
input string reader, this one.
And after this, rewrite the page, not stream this one.
So we import this also.
Okay.
We will create a class first.
So basically we have the page as the input stream and we do a new input stream on it and the new and
restore it.
And basically the operator that we have done.
So what we do now, we have this stream for the input line.
So let's take the stream input.
Nine.
Right?
Right.
What line?
It grew in the heart.
Read line.
Snotty girl, too, to no.
You know.
We strong?
So here's one thing.
We need bodies.
Who will do results equal to results?
You could line.
This.
So we have all these other here.
So let's just include all the files that we actually need.
The first of all, we need to issue.
So here we have the Java material and another one which we need to read.
Here we will write import java load.
You.
Both Foot reader,
rehab and stream reader also.
We have the you ought to be kind of a reader.
We need the sync results,
so we will write our note.
Swing.
Start on.
So we will set this thing.
And then don't need me have power, don't you?
Lord rejects.
We need a pattern.
We have the pattern also, and we need a method to write down.
You do not write checks?
Not.
Mature
this mature.
Okay.
We have all these.
No.
I don't know.
Maybe assuming that probably we just have to do it.
Okay, so
we do the last.
The mind of a reader.
I'll.
Ki.
So you.
Keynesian is incompatible types.
So we will firstly close the puffer reader first so we don't lose and we need a catch.
It's already here.
So after this.
We have to handle the other also.
So basically we will write.
Except she.
So who'd.
So to society.
This is what we need.
Okay.
Move used.
It's done.
No.
We have to write attachment here.
So we will write
children being not sure.
Message dialogue.
So here we will write this.
After this, we will give a message.
Disable write disable to connect to your we will try disable to connect to Yahoo!
This thing is done and here we have the error handling part also.
So.
We have got the results, so we have to get the results.
We need a pattern matching here.
So we write pattern finding pattern.
Equal to pattern, not compile.
Okay.
So.
To say, let's exhale after this.
We need I have already righted this.
This will be the read this one to simply write and paste.
It will going to match the actual text that we're going to read.
So let's roll it in number.
So it's going to be 0 to 9 here.
This one could be more than one number.
And also, it might be a decimal.
So we have the thought as well.
This is going to match the pattern that the user gave.
So for this, we need much, much find.
Final button, no matter.
I mean, right
now we have to match.
Find you and you.
We need.
The Sun.
Okay.
So here.
No, the matching.
The pattern is matched.
So now we have to match fine.
And we have to execute the regular expression.
So we are going to spread the currency first.
We need to match.
Find.
No, it's fine.
So we take the well and we write our rate equal to double, not value of.
We actually want to do the thing from the match find here.
So we will.
Right, match.
Fine.
So do the group first.
So we write group and I know that will value.
This is how the conversion rate on.
Growth rate.
From Groupon.
Okay.
Now.
We need to get in the middle of this one so we will write.
We need to learn to convert and we will write our rate multiplied
the
value of here.
We will write a good amount here and start.
You get taxed.
Okay.
We will change the variable name.
Currency amount will need a currency amount not get taxed.
And.
Not.
We value.
Who do?
Mr..
And.
The normal value of my point.
So here.
Done.
This is done.
So now we have converted.
We we actually have the value to conversion everything we need to get the current rate and amount.
So we have to create time matching also.
So, so just copy this and.
Here.
We will know we need.
This one.
You even tried.
Final Brighton.
This should be removed.
And then here we will write.
This one.
Simply copy and paste this.
Now we are going to take anything, the Spaniard, if you like it.
So it's going to have it's going to be this type.
This will at first underscore it.
And this can be any number of letter equal to X.
So that will be the actual pattern of that we need to match.
So.
We have this much fun.
Thing is, we need
to display that text.