What I'm on here.
We can work till five Canadian dollar to the euro and we go down to 3.45 here.
So what we have done and the last thing and it's still fluid here, we have automatic string to the
floor and it's going to be total convert.
So we have this here, the total convert.
Okay.
So the result is split time.
That's the set text that's trailing time and that it's going to see current trade that day and that
we are going to do match and find that group one, the first group of the result.
That's basically it.
We have the whole application here.
This is the result and we can here we have done this thing and after thing what we have done, we can
import export our project also.
So here I have done this export.
So here we have caught our attention.
This is John here.
The school.
Okay.
Not good here.
We got our converter API.
We.
Here we are to our class.