But now we need a string here.
Just remove this.
God.
Okay.
So now we need firstly I will write and then simply explain it to you what I'm doing here.
So here I will write next line and just to get here.
And after that, I need a wide loop, which is not equal to the input, not equals.
Okay.
So which will not equal to the one here?
A neat anecdote and in art equals ritual, not this.
To so simply I will write system, not dot print, Alan.
No, it will be invalid.
Right.
So invalid, commander.
Just simply pick up the input equal.
Next line.
Okay.
Sure need.
Okay, so after this while loop, we need another condition, which really we have equals.
One.
We are handling this situation only because these are only loved ones.
So simply I will write system note here.
I will write system, not our friend trend and I will write.
You can continue on your adventure.
Okay.
So next condition for us if.
In what it equals.
Here.
The output will be the input of the tool.
Under this I will write.
System, not our friend Alan.
And for that too.
So for the two part, I will write.
You have successfully exited your so I can you have.
Successfully.
I thought.
The game.
Okay.
Done simply trick.
Now we need some of the lines.
Okay.
So what I will do.
No.
Just add up and line here and just write.
Thanks for being the scheme.
So simply what we have done here.
Here we got the string Collingwood and set it on equal to the in the dot in the next line.
That's the input of the user.
Then we are going to say while and we are going to set up a little wide loop here.
And if you remember from the loop, if the enemy entered invalid information, we have the final statement
here which says the invalid command.
So here it saved the invalid command.
It will reiterate back to the top and just print out options again.
We need to do something similar.
So here, because if we don't validate the input from the user, we are going to write back up to the
top.
So the user types in something wrong.
It wouldn't say invalid command.
So here it's straight back up to like fighting a new enemy.
So we need to make sure we are going to make a Y loop and we are going to basically say while the input
user providing is not equal to one or two or while the user is not inputting valid information.
So we are just going to keep looping and asking them what they want to do.
They are going to say, well, that is not equal to equals, exclamation mark, meaning not.
So of course, while is not equal to one, it's not equal to two.
Then we are going to go ahead and say systems are ordered by invalid command and then just go ahead
and set input equal to the next line.
So the validation here, we grab the input the user put in the while, which is not equal to one or
two and it's simply printed.
So we have some options down here.
First one is to continue fighting.
Continue fighting.
And the next one is the exit game.
So for one, we can say you can continue on your adventure here.
And the next one in this case, in the case the user defeated the enemies and how the player wants to
exit the dungeon.
So this is like the victory screen.
Basically, you exit the adventure game from your.
No, it's basically like you exited the jungle game from your adventure and you can add like a school
or just a simple system.
Okay, so if you want, again, this is fully customizable and you can play around with this.
And now being after that we have take the truth option or the user if they choose to exit, we obviously
need to break and just show up a little feedback.
You have successfully exit the case, just you have successfully exited the game.
So then again, I use the break.
It will break out of the loop.
And finally, just we have running just we got a message here.
Which will say the last one for thanks for playing this game.
Just like here, we have used the welcome to the jungle here.
Welcome to the jungle.
And it will simply show.
Thanks for playing this game.
Okay.
So now what we can do?
Firstly, we will just see the running of the whole program.
Okay, just simply run.
Okay.
So here, firstly, what I will do.
Just dive in.
See, we have the Health Potion 100 and session's HP six because a session has appeared here.
It is a randomized number.
So firstly, I will put it with the first attack.
So here you strike the four for damage, you receive 20 in retaliation it randomize the damage out,
damage taken.
And what I will do firstly I will hit just run away because I don't want to kill so I have run here
it show you run away from the assassin not assassin has appeared.
Firstly, I will drink a health potion first again drink health potion and now firstly I will attack
the Now you would try to strike the assassin for seven damage.
It's not doing so.
Just run, run now the warrior has appeared now just simply I will attack it.
And you could see Warrior was defeated.
You have one in the HP left here.
It has not dropped the health potion because I have said that it will be a 50% chance.
So let's see in the next part what it will do.
I will continue fighting and just simply for storing the health potion.
Now here it to me.
You have one health potion left and one for free amount of HP.
Okay.
Just.
I will just run.
Suki Waterhouse.
Okay.
See here, I have got the option.
You run away from the session.
Warrior has appeared and Warrior was defeated.
It's simply the randomize thing.
Okay, so you have 150 health potion left here.
When I defeated the warrior, it dropped the health potion.
You have to do health potions now because I have had it there and now again, just session has appeared
run.
So here I have tried this action for 22 damage and you see 29 points and I have defeated them and it
does not provide me the options because it's a 50% chance here.
So here I have done with my game.
Just a minute and potions dropped.
King, which is not coming in good way.
You have to hand.
Just a simple.
And just again, run.
Just again on our program here, Warrior has a rival attack on him.
You strike the warrior.
I have not just simply run because I don't want to kill you.
Now the zombie has appeared.
First, I will drink my health potion.
Now I will attack my zombie.
You strike.
Okay, just run.
Because I have not just run.
Now the skeleton is out there, so somebody just.
I will attack on him.
Okay, just run.
Skeleton has appeared.
Okay.
Here.
The skeleton was defeated.
You have 62% left.
The skeleton drop the health portion.
So now I have four health potions here.
So you want to continue fighting or exit the game?
Now, I will do exit the key.
So it will show you have successfully exited the game here and thanks for playing this game.
So this is our game here.