Last class, but I trust our job right here.
We set up the game, we create a board here on which we play the game.
We created a status bar here.
This one, the score is displayed in a label which is located at the bottom of the board.
So here the variable board is called a new board, the reference ad board board star method.
So the hair board is created and added to the container.
The start method starts the Tetra scheme and here this will return the status bar and all the things
which we have created here.
It should go with our game.
So this was the Tetris game.
Now we will see the output of it.
So what we have to do now, so we will simply run our game and see here what I will press the p.
It should print the policy right now what I will do I will press the it should coming up coming down
c dee dee dee dee.
It's coming down here coming, coming, coming.
One line down here which we have done.
Think so what?
The next thing which we have created, we have to go with the next one.
This is the right one.
This is the rotate left, rotate right, rotate left.
This is with the up and the down key.
I'm doing this.
The key pressed even of the keyboard.
So here, David, for the one line down here, this one, one line down here, this rotated.
And these are the one line down and this is space for the game over and the score is zero.
So here, this is our game, which we have created and it is called as the pointer game or the Tetris
game, which you can see.