Hey guys, welcome to lecture 38.
This lecture will be on renaming indexes.
I'll call it rename index.
So we're gonna import the usual.
Gonna import numpy as np.
Import pandas as PD.
And then from pandas,
we'll import Series, DataFrame.
All right, so now that we've done that,
let's go ahead and make a DataFrame.
We'll say dframe equals Dataframe.
Let's go ahead and get some numbers.
A number matrix to fill out some values.
So we'll say np.arange.
And then I'll reshape this array
into a three by four matrix.
After that, I'll just set my index
equal to some city initials.
And then I'll set the columns,
equal to just some letter values.
I'll say A, B, C, D.
Okay.
Now we have our data frame.
Just like a series,
axis indexes can also map.
So we can use map to lower case the city's
initials, so how can I do that?
I'll show you.
So for instance we can say dframe.index.
And then I'll call a map on the index.
And using that map i'll
input the command str.lower.
So this will lower case that index.
And so now my array is the lower case.
Of each of those cities' names,
or initials, I should say.
If I want to assign this
to the actual index.
I can use dframe.index equal
to the value I wrote about.
Index.map, and str.lower,
to lowercase everything in that index.
And now if I look at my dframe
the effect will be permanent.
Cool.
I can also use rename if I wanna
create a transformed version,
without modifying the original version.
So, if I want to do that I
could say deframe.rename.
And this is where we're going to
learn more about renaming indexes.
And then I'll say index=str.title.
That's the way to make it capitalized.
And then I'll set my
columns equal to str.lower.
So I'll lower case the column letters.
Lets see if that works.
And so now using title.
Its capitalized the first
letter of the row index values.
Ny, La, Sf, and
then it's lower case the column names.
So I can use rename to create the
transformed version of that data frame.
I can also use rename
to insert dictionaries.
Providing new values.
So I can say dframe.rename.
And then I can pass an index
equal to, let's say a dictionary, ny.
And then I'll call it New York.
Get the full name.
Then I can also pass columns= A.
And then I can rename that as Alpha.
So what I'm doing here,
is I'm passing dictionaries with
the arguments index and columns.
Using the rename method.
So it's going to rename my index,
and my column.
So let's go ahead and see what happens.
So as we expected now NY has
been renamed to New York.
And that a has been renamed to alpha.
Cool.
So you can actually edit
the data set in place.
The way to do that is I can say dframe.
Well I'll show you what I mean first.
Let's just take a look at
the original data frame.
So those effects weren't permanent.
If I want to make them permanent,
I can say dframe.rename.
Input the original
stuff we just did.
NEW YORK finishes that dictionary.
And then since I want to make
an edit to the data set in place.
I can just set inplace argument = True.
And I wanna call my dframe.
Those effects are permanent.
So it actually edited
the data frame in place.
So that's about it for renaming indexes.
So, just to go over it,
you can map things to an index to edit it.
But you can also just use rename.
And you rename in input arguments index.
Either a dictionary for renaming, or
you can pass arguments or
methods onto the index columns themselves.
Such as lowering or upper casing
the column, or index values and names.
All right.
So up next we'll learn.