Hey everyone, welcome to part two
of the election data project.
In the last part,
the first video of this project, we just
took a look at what imports we had to do,
to analyze the data, as well as
looking into requests in StringIO.
We grabbed our data straight from
the Internet, as a csv file,
used StringIO to convert it to a data
frame, checked out the data frame, and
then we did some quick visualization
analysis of who was being polled,
what the population looked like, and also
who was more in favor of Obama or Romney.
And we also saw this asset of
undecided voters still, and
then we wanted to take that into account.
So our polls indicated it
was a fairly close race.
But we also had this factor
of undecided voters.
And we'll know most of
them will likely vote for
one of the candidates
once the election occurs.
So we'll look into how we
can take that into account,
by maybe splitting the difference,
between Obama and Romney.
And that should give us some sort of
unbiased estimate of the final difference.
So I'm going to hop over
back to the live Code, and
before we go into calculating the
difference, let's see, if we wanted to,
how we could do a quick time series
analysis of voter sentiment,
by plotting Obama, Romney favor,
versus the poll end dates.
So let's go ahead and
check out our data frame again,
poll_df.
I'll do it .head to get
the first five rows.
So we have the percentage of people
that wanted to vote for Obama, and
the percentage of people that
wanted to vote for Romney,
and we also have the end
date of that poll.
So what we can do is a very quick,
a bit of a messy plot,
but we can do it straight up in pandas,
and
plot the favor of Obama, Romney,
undecided voters through time.
So to show you what I mean by that,
I will take our data frame,
poll_df and
I can call the plot method on it, and
in this case I wanna plot on my X axis,
that end date column.
And then what I want to plot on Y,
is Obama's,
Romney's, and the undecided voters.
So what I'll do is I'll pass a list.
Obama.
Romney, and undecided.
So I'll have three different
quantities on my Y axis.
And then since I don't want a line,
I'll say my line style is just
equal to an empty string.
That way no lines show up.
And then I'll set a marker.
Equal to just an o., there.
Let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
And so now you can see,
we've done a quick time analysis of
the voter sentiment for each of
the candidates, and the undecided voters.
Now, something to note here,
is we actually plotted this in reverse, so
on the right hand side
are the earlier dates, and
on the left hand side are the later dates.
Which kind of makes sense, cuz you can see
the trend of undecided voters start to go
down, as you get closer to the election.
So that makes sense because the undecided
voters, as you got closer to the election,
would have probably chosen a candidate.
And what's interesting is Obama and
Romney,
as you go closer to the election date on
the left hand side, they get closer and
closer, so that's an interesting.
So that's just a bit of a messy
way to just give you a quick idea.
If we want to get a better visualization,
what we probably have to do is
edit the actual data frame.
So to lead you along the right path for
plotting, we'll go ahead and
answer another question related to
plotting, the sentiment versus time.
So what we're gonna do now is plot out
the difference, between Obama and Romney.
And see how that changes
as time moves along.
So what I mean by that is, if you look at
this first poll here, this political poll.
Obama and Romney both have 47%
of whoever was polled said
they would vote for them, so
that means their difference would be zero.
And then if you go down to the next one,
you have 49 and 48, so
Obama would be leading by just
one percentage point there.
So, what we're gonna do is create a new
column to track that difference, and
then plot that difference versus time,
which would be a cleaner way of
visualizing that kind of data.
So let's go ahead and
start with an import, so
I'm gonna say from datetime,
import datetime.
We've seen this before in
previous data projects,
I'm just going to use it as a time stamp.
So now we'll define a new
column in our poll data frame,
to take into account the difference
between Romney and Obama in the polls.
So I'll create a new column, poll_df and
I'll call this column Difference.
And then I'll say.
This is equal to the Obama column,
minus the Romney column.
And then remember to
divide it by 100 because
we're speaking in terms
of percentage points.
So, after we create that column,
what I'm gonna do is just
preview the data frame again.
So what we're gonna do is scroll
all the way to the right, and
we should see our new column here.
Great, so now we see the percentage point
difference, between the two candidates.
So remember that first one was zero,
since they both had 47% of the voters.
Great.
So, keep in mind that the difference
column is Obama minus Romney.
So a positive difference indicates
a leaning towards Obama in the polls.
And a negative difference means
a leaning towards Romney.
So let's go ahead and see if we can
visualize how this sentiment, and
difference changes over time.
So we're gonna start by using Group By, to
group the polls by their start date, and
then sorting it by that start date.
So to show you what I mean by that,
let's go ahead and
get our data frame, and now we're
gonna set it equal to the group by.
What I mean by that is grab your data
frame, And then we're gonna group it by.
The start date.
So I'm going to group
it by the start date.
I'm gonna set the index,
as index equal to false.
And what that does,
is it keeps the current index.
So, they'll keep the 0, 1, 2, 3, 4 index,
that you see in our current data frame.
So if I scroll to the left of our data
frame, you already have this index here.
You can see it: 0, 1, 2, 3, 4.
So I'll keep as index equal to false, so
when I group by the start date,
isn't the index.
We just keep our 0, 1, 2, 3, 4 index.
If I put as index equals true,
then the start date would be the index,
which isn't what we want in this case.
We want to keep that 0, 1, 2, 3, 4 index.
And then, I'll just take the mean
of the polls on that day.
So if we look back at our data frame,
notice that multiple polls
have the same end date.
So what this command is doing,
it's saying, take your full data frame,
group it by the start dates,
and then set the as_index
equal to false, so you keep the 0, 1, 2,
3, 4 index, and then take the mean, or
the average, of all the results of
those polls on that start date.
So after doing that, I'm also gonna say
poll_df.head so we can see a preview.
And there you have it, so
we have a nice start date.
Look how we kept our original index here.
We took the average of all the poles
on that particular start date,
and then we also have
our difference column.
Which is great.
So now we can start plotting
the difference versus time.
So this will actually be
pretty straight forward.
So I'm going to set pole_df.plot, whoops.
And I'm going to plot my start date.
Versus my difference.
I'm gonna set my figsize equal
to the tuple 12 by 4 just so
it's a little more readable.
Again, depending on your computer screen
you can set whatever figure size you want,
you can mess around with
it until it looks good.
I'll set my marker equal to a point,
just a lowercase o in this case.
I'll set my line style equal to a dash.
Now, remember, as far as marker,
line style, and color choices,
you're free to choose whatever you want.
This is where you can kind of wear
your data visualization hat, or
graphic design hat, and really mess
around with what looks good to you.
But now, in this case we can see
the percent change over time, so
here on the very left we have 2009,
January, February, March 2009,
and then here have October 2012,
so right before the election.
And it looks like Obama was in
the lead for most of the year.
Or actually,
most of the past three years, or
whenever the polls happened to take place.
Cuz remember, since we're doing Obama
minus Romney as the difference,
anything positive means people were more
in favor of Obama in that particular pole.
Now what's interesting is you see
these two big negative marks,
which means Romney, for
whatever reason on those dates,
something happened where he
got a big win in the poles.
So it might be interesting to look
back on those particular dates,
maybe use minimum, or some other function
to find those particular dates and
look up in the news
what happened that day.
So I'll leave that to you, to go and
find out why Romney polls were so
strong on these two particular dates.
So we know that some events did happened,
we know that the debates happened,
the October 3rd, October 11th and October
22nd of 2012, there were some debates.
So, what we're gonna do, is go ahead and
mark down those debates.
So, we're gonna plot
some lines as markers and
then zoom in on the one month of
October when the debates took place.
So, in order to find where to
set the X limits For the figure.
We need to find out where the index for
the month of October in 2012 is.
I'll show you what I mean by that.
I'll make a simple for
loop to find that row.
So what I can do is say row_in.
That'll be my row index.
And I'll set my x-limit
to be an empty list.
And now what I'm going to do is if
we look back at our data frame,
I'm going to cycle through this
index until it finds 2012-10,
meaning October of 2012, because
that's when the debates took place.
Then it's going to print the row index,
so I'm going to say for
dates in poll_df Start Date, oops.
If the first seven terms
of that start date are equal to 2012-10.
So I'm cycling through the index and
I'm saying,
hey if the date in that Start Date
happened to be 2012-10, so in October.
My xlimit,
since we're gonna be plotting this.
I'm going to append, row in.
So the current index, and
then I'm gonna say row_in.
I'll add a 1 to its value.
Otherwise if it didn't find
the October start date, go ahead and
keep my counter running.
So what row_n is doing is it's basically
counting the index row as it
goes through that four loop.
And then what we can do after
that is print the minimum value
of xlimit and
print the max value of xlimit.
So I'm going to run this
and let me just break down one more
time what this for loop was doing.
So we needed to find out where to set
the xlimits in this upper figure,
right here,
to only get the month of October.
Now remember xlimit, we can define it
by using the index in our data frame.
So we're trying to find where the start
date was equal to October 2012.
So what I did was,
I made a for loop that said for
every date in that start date column,
if the first seven terms of that
start date were equal to 2012-10, or
October 2012, go ahead and
append to my xlimit empty
list that row index and then add one to
the row index to keep my count going.
Otherwise, if you didn't find anything,
just add one to my row index.
And then I'm gonna have xlimit be a list
of basically the index of the entire
month of Of October and then I'll have
329 as the minimum and 356 as the max.
So to show you why we need to do
that lets go ahead and plot out
our first plot so I'm going to edit
copy edit paste what we did up here.
Edit copy.
And I'm gonna paste it here.
We're keeping everything the same except
now, I know where to set my xlimits.
I'll set my xlimits at the first index,
329, and then set my second xlimit at 356,
because remember that's what the minimum
and the max were for my xlimits.
Limits in that four loop.
And then I need to close off that
parenthesis, let's go ahead and, Run that.
Looks like I'm forgetting
a parenthesis here.
So we have,
a non key word after argument key word.
We need to set x-limit
equal to that tuple.
Now let's run it, here we go.
Okay great.
So we did that four loop.
We found where the index is
equal to the month of October,
both the start and the end.
And then I repeated that same plot here,
except I set my X limits to
those index points, 329 and 356.
And I can see we have
the entire month of October.
October first on the left all the way
to October thirty-first on the right.
Great so looking up on Wikipedia I saw
the debate dates were on October third,
October 11th and October 22nd.
So, now we're gonna plot some lines
on top of this plot right here,
and see where we can find
the markers of the debates and
if there we any changes to
the sentiment in the voters.
So, I'm going to keep doing
it in the above cell,
so i'm gonna say, plt., and
to do a vertical line,
I can just say axvline.
And we're going to be
making three of these.
So I'm going to copy and
paste this three times.
So this first one is going to
be the debate on October 3rd.
The second one's gonna be
the debate on October 11th.
And the third one's gonna be
the debate on October 22nd.
So what do I need to put in here?
Well, I'll need to set my X marker to
where that line is actually gonna occur.
So where should I put my vertical line?
Well, for October 3rd I know my index for
October 1st was at 329
with that four loop.
So if that's It's the first then
I just need to add two days to it
to get to October 3rd,
and then I'll set my line
width equal to four.
And I'll set it's color equal to grey.
And remember, you can set the line width
and colors to whatever you feel like.
Go ahead and mess around with it,
just mess with your visualizations.
So I'm going to copy and paste that
information into the rest of
the vertical line arguments.
But remember,
now I have to just change the dates.
So if I'm looking at October 11th,
that's gonna be the first
index plus ten more days.
And if I'm looking at October 22nd,
that's gonna be that first
October 1st index plus 21 days.
Let's go ahead and run that.
And there you have it,
now we have markers at every debate point.
So it's interesting here is it
looks like after the first debate,
sentiment for Obama increased.
Which is kind of surprising to me.
And after the second debate,
it looks like Mitt Romney was
more favorable in that pole.
And after the third debate,
everyone was pretty even.
This surprises me given that
if you remember how the candidates
performed at the debates.
I remember Obama performing
poorly in the first debate and
much better in the second two.
But, that's not what the polls here
show as far as letter sentiment.
But it's important to keep in
mind the geographical location
of people who are being polled and
what their occupations were, etc etc.
So, there's a lot of the various factors
that could go into the poll data.
So let's really remember to remember,
excuse me,
it's really important to remember all
the different factors that can go
into the people being polled and
their sentiment.
So I'll stop that here, and I'll let you
go ahead and mess around morph this poll
data and see if you can get any more
insights that you want to answer your own
questions to, and in the next video
we'll look at the donor data set.
Okay.
Thanks, and I'll see you there.