Hey, guys.
Welcome to lecture 7.
In this lecture,
we'll be learning how to create arrays.
I'm going to call it Creating Arrays.
A big part of data analysis,
as far as this course goes,
will be array based and matrix based.
So in order to do that,
we're going to learn how to use
numpy to create these arrays.
So the first thing we're gonna
do is import numpy as np.
This will save us from having
to type numpy every single time.
We can just write np instead.
One way to make an array is
by converting from a list.
So I will say make an object
called my_list1 and
let's make a list of 1, 2, 3, and 4.
Okay, so now that we have our
list we can make an array.
So I will make an array called my_array1.
And the way we can make
an array is by using
np.array, and
then we can pass that list as an object.
So we can my_list1.
And let's go ahead and
see what that ended up being.
Great, so now we have an array
that we made from the list.
So that's one of the ways
we can make the array.
So let's go ahead and make another list.
We'll call it my_list2.
And in this case,
we'll just have it be 11, 22, 33 and 44.
And now we're gonna make a list
combining those two lists we just made.
I will call it my_lists = my_list1,
as the first object in that list and
then I'm going to say my_list2 as
the second object in that list.
And it looks like I forgot the underscore,
let me add that.
And there we go, okay.
So now we have a list of
the two lists we made.
We can make a multi-dimensional array or
a matrix using this.
So I can say my_array2 = np.array, and
I'm gonna pass that
list of multiple lists.
So I can say my_lists.
There we go.
And let's go ahead and
see what that multidimensional array
look like, otherwise known as a matrix.
Great.
So you can see now we have
both lists in the array.
It's 1, 2, 3, 4, 11, 22, 33, 44.
And let's go ahead and
see what the shape of that array is.
So since it's multidimensional, I can ask
numpy what shape it is
by saying .shape method.
And so it looks like it's a two by four,
which makes sense.
So that means every list you passed in
that list of lists created a new row.
So here was your first row and
then here is your second row.
All right, great.
So now we know how to make an array and
a multidimensional array from a list.
So we can also find out
the data type of the array, and
I can do that in the same way
I asked what the shape was.
I can ask for
the dtype by passing the dtype method and
it will tell me type of objects
that are in that array.
There is also special case arrays,
so for instance,
if you wanted an array of all zeros,
you could say np.zeros and
then just indicate the shape
of the array you wanted.
So if I wanted an array, just a one by
five of zeros, so just a straight vector.
And there I have it, my five zeros.
And if you notice,
there's a decimal point there, and
that's because they're a floating type.
So to show you what I mean by that,
I can say my_zeros_array = np.zeros[5].
And then I can check the type,
so I can say my_zeroes_array,
and we just learned how to check the type,
so let's go ahead and
make sure they're floating.
And they are.
So they're floating numbers, which means
they have that decimal point there.
Excellent.
Another special case array is an array of
ones, and I can do that by saying np.ones.
And I can pass the shape here too, so
I can say, for instance, a five by five.
So I'll make a matrix of ones.
And there you have it,
a five by five multidimensional array.
I can also create an empty array.
I can do that just by saying np.empty.
And that'll be the same thing
as just asking for zeros there.
Okay.
And then last but not least, we can make
an identity matrix, or identity array.
And it's almost always gonna be
a full matrix, multidimensional.
And you can make the identity
matrix by using eye, E-Y-E.
And since it's a matrix,
you'll have to input just a square matrix,
so it's gonna be a five by five in this
case if I input just the number 5.
So I can say Alt+Enter.
And then here's my identity matrix,
which is just a diagonal of a 1 and
then everything else filled in with 0s.
And then one way we can
make an array that we'll be
using a ton in this
course is by np.arrange.
And what that does is you can input
a start and a stop and a step size,
and it's going to return evenly spaced
values within that given interval.
I can say just 5, and in this case
it's going to output 0, 1, 2, 3, 4.
Excellent, and to get more specific, I
could say something like start at 5, stop
at 50, and do it in steps of 2.
Let's see if it can make evenly spaced.
There we go.
So, 5, 7, 9, etc., etc.,
all the way in spaces of 2.
So we'll be using this arrange
method a lot throughout the course.
Okay, so that's how you can create arrays.
Just to do a quick overview, you can pass
a list using np.array and input the list.
You can check the shape and the type of
objects for those matrices or arrays.
And then your special case
arrays you can say zeros, ones,
empty, eye, and then you can also
create an array by also using arrange.
All right, that's it for creating arrays.
I'll see you in the next lecture.