Hello everyone and welcome to
the first lecture in machine learning.
In this lecture we're going to be learning
about supervised learning methods and
specifically we'll be learning
about linear regression.
So I have my iPython notebook open as
well as the LiveCoding notebook open.
So we'll be hopping back and
forth between both of them.
So just to give you a quick introduction,
we're going to go over how to use
the scikit-learn regression model.
As well as how to train the regresser
using the fit method and
we'll see that later.
And we'll also learn how to predict
new labels using the predict method.
So we're gonna be analyzing a data set
consisting of house prices in Boston and
that data sets actually
built into scikit-learn.
And we'll learn how to access it.
And then we're gonna start off with
a single variable linear regression.
So just an x and y.
And we'll use numb pie to do that.
Then we'll move on to a multi-variable
regression, using scikit-learn.
As we're going through this, we'll do
a quick overview of the mathematics behind
the methods we're using.
But mostly we're gonna dive deeper into
practical hands-on coding lessons.
So if you're interested in deeper
mathematics of linear regression methods,
you can go ahead and
check out this Wikipedia page link.
And like I mentioned before in
the introduction you can also check out
these really nice lectures for
free on YouTube.
Check out this link here.
And then the linear regression link
on Wikipedia is also very good.
So jumping back here, we're gonna go and
do this through nine steps.
So you can almost think
of this as micro-project.
The first step is gonna be getting and
setting up the data.
Then we're gonna visualize
that current data.
After that, step three, the mathematics
behind the Least Square Methods.
That's the method we're gonna be using,
in order to do this linear regression so
we'll go over some of
the mathematics behind the method.
Then in step 4 we'll use numpy for
a univariate linear regression.
And what univariate
linear regression means.
It's just using a single variable to
do that that linear regression and
we'll dive deeper into that later.
Step five, we'll see how we can
get the error of our analysis.
And then step six.
We'll switch from using Numpy to
using scikit-learn to implement
multivariate regression using multiple
data variables from our data set.
And then after that, we'll set up
the training invalidation data sets.
And then the next two steps,
the final steps after that are predicting
prices and then making a residual plot.
Now we'll dive deeper into all
those topics as we get to them.
So, step one, getting up and
setting up the data.
We'll start by looking at an example
data set from scikit-learn.
So first we're gonna import our
usual data analysis import.
So let's go ahead and hop over to the
LiveCoding and start going through that.
So I'm going to import numpy as np.
Going to import pandas as pd.
And then from pandas import series and
data frame.
After that I'm going to get my imports for
plotting.
So I'm going to import
matplotlib.pyplot as plt.
Then I'm going to import Seaborn as SNS.
And then like we did in previous videos,
I'm gonna set the style for
Seaborn as a white grid style.
So we can see a white grid background.
Again you can set style
however you please.
And then just to make sure
we always see our plots,
I'm going to call matplotlib inline.
So now what we're gonna do is we're gonna
import a data set from scikit-learn,
as well as the linear model module.
So just a quick note you
may have to run a download,
scikit-learn may read
an error when you do this.
And if you read an error and
it prompts you something around the lines
of you need to run download models.
Go ahead and just follow the directions.
And you can go ahead and
always make a discussion in case you're
confused by the directions that pop up.
But once you have them you can just
say from sklearn.datasets import.
And in this case,
I'm gonna import load_boston.
And that's importing a Boston data set.
So in order to load the data set, I'm
just gonna make an object called Boston.
And have it be equal to
that imported data set.
So let's see what the data set contains.
If you went into the documentation
of scikit-learn.
And looked up the Boston data sets, you'll
be able to read there that they've built
in a special describe method into
that data set capital DESCR.
So if you call that method
on the Boston data set,
it'll actually print out
a really nice description of it.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
Looks like we have 506
instances in this data set.
We have 13 different attributes, and
the median value of the attributes
14 is usually the target.
So if we look at what kind of
information is in this data set.
We have a per capita crime rate by town,
and
notice it's giving you the labels
here of each of these attributes.
So we also have the proportion
of residential lands owned for
lots over 25,000 square feet.
We have a bunch of
different attributes here.
We also have the index of
accessibility to radial highways,
the pupil-teacher ratio in town,
average number of rooms per dwelling.
So a bunch of different attributes for
these houses.
And if you notice the last one here is
the median value of ower-occupied homes
in thousands of dollars.
We're gonna treat this guy,
this median value,
as the target and sometimes you
also call the target the label.
We have all these different
features of a house.
So a house can have different number
of rooms, different proportions
of non-retail business acres per
town where that particular house is.
So your house can have a bunch
of different features, and
it has one label, or one target.
The median value of the owner-occupied
home in terms of thousands of dollars.
So this is actually a copy of a UC Irvine
Machine Learning housing data set.
So you can click this link and
find out more about it there.
But, moving on,
there's also references here in case
you're interested more into the data set.
What we're gonna is just a quick
visualization of the data.
So, you should always do a quick
visualization of the data you have
just to make sure everything looks
okay and nothing strange pops up.
Let's go ahead and
do a histogram of the prices.
So remember the prices is the current
target or label of our data set.
I'm gonna do that by calling plt.hist.
And I can call that target value
just by calling the target method.
So this is actually pretty
particular to this,
what they're called toy
data sets in scikit-learn.
Since this data set was actually built
into scikit-learn it's
a nice training data set.
As far as training yourself
to learn machine learning.
Not to be confused with training and
testing and validation data sets,
we'll get into that later.
But, as you can imagine not every
data sets gonna be very nice and
very clean and you're not going to be
able to call this target method on it.
But you will be able
to make histograms for
you own data given the skill sets
you learned so far in this course.
And I'm gonna make my X label equal
to prices in thousands of dollars.
And then I'm going to plot my Y label
to be equal to the number of houses.
Since we're doing histogram.
So we're just making a simple
histogram of all the houses.
I have created 50 bins because there were
up to 506 different housing instances.
So let's go ahead and run that,
see what it looks like.
Great.
So now we basically see the histogram,
or the distribution if you will,
of the average median price
in thousands of dollars.
And the number of houses that
are in that price bin, if you will.
Okay, so you can see there's
an average price between,
looks like, somewhere around
the $20,000-$25,000 range.
As far as this particular data set.
So, what might be interesting
to do is just see a scatter plot
of a single feature versus the target or
that label.
So we want to scatter plot
one feature versus a target.
So how about we scatter
plot the housing price
versus the number of
rooms in the dwelling.
So, in order to get the number
of rooms in the dwelling
I'm gonna scroll back up
here to the description.
And note here that RM is that label for
the average number of rooms per dwelling.
And it looks like it's one,
two, three, four, five,
six, down in the attribute information.
Notice that this information
was given to you in order.
So it's the sixth one down.
Which means if you're index starts
at zero, then it's gonna be zero,
one, two, three, four, five.
So, we're gonna wanna call
the column at the number five index
of our Boston data set.
So, to show you what I mean by that,
I'm gonna call a scatter plot method,
plt.scatter.
And then I'm gonna say boston.data, so
these were all those attributes we
were looking at, those 13 attributes.
And now I want every attribute
in that fifth column.
And that's what I want my X to be,
the average number of rooms.
And what I want my Y to be is the price.
So, I already know the price,
as we did last time was the target
method on that data set.
And always keep in mind,
we're working with this built in data set.
You're not gonna have nice methods
to call on your own data sets,
these lectures are really just to teach
you how to deal and manipulate with data.
And you may have to do some
cleaning on your own data.
So let's go ahead and
put in the labels real quick.
We'll call it price in thousands.
And we'll have our X label be
equal to the number of rooms.
So right here
And now let's go ahead and run that.
And there you go.
So you can make out
a bit of a slight trend
that the price increases along with
the number of rooms in that house.
Which intuitively that kinda makes sense.
You would expect as you get a higher
number of rooms in that house,
most likely that house is larger so
the price increases.
So you should see some sort of positive
correlation between the number of rooms
And the price of the house itself.
So how about we try to
do the following now.
Let's try to use Pandas to transform
this Boston data set into a data frame.
And then we'll use Seaborn to perform
an LM plot on that data frame.
To try to reproduce the scatter plot
we just did with a linear fit line.
So let's go ahead and
start off by resetting the data.
So I'll make an object called boston_df,
and I'll call the data frame method
just on the data of that Boston data
set not the actual target itself.
So I'm resetting all the data
as a Pandas data frame.
And then
I'm going to set the columns
of my data frame
equal to the feature names method.
So, like I said before, these are kind of
particular and specific things to this
data set, as far as calling the .data and
.feature names methods.
They're just here for convenience
because this it build into scikit-learn.
So let's go ahead and move on and just see
what that Boston data frame looks like.
Just going to call the first five rows.
And there you go.
Now we have a data frame consisting
of all those attributes or features.
Moving on now, let's go ahead and add the
target of the Boston data set, the price.
So we'll do that by creating
a new column in our data frame.
And we do that just by doing this.
And now I'm gonna set that equal to
the target of the data frame which was
the price.
And I can do that by
passing that target method.
And now let's go ahead see
the resulting data frame.
And there you have it.
So now we have a nice complete data frame
with all those different features and
finally our target price.
So If you remember your Seaborn lectures.
You might be reminded of the Seaborn LM
plot functions we used during
the visualization lectures when
you looked at the scatter plot.
So you can actually use it
here to do a linear fit or
a linear regression automatically.
So that's actually a nice
feature build into Seaborn.
So let's go ahead and try to do that So
we'll do that by sns.lmplot.
And remember you can review
the visualization lectures in case you're
a little fuzzy on this.
So what I did here is I'm using
Seaborn calling that linear plot.
It's gonna plot basically a linear
regression over that scatter plot,
just the first order line.
And I'm plotting that room
feature versus the price, and
setting my data as that data frame.
So, it's gonna be trying to reproduce
this exact same scatter plot here.
Except in Seaborn it gives
you a linear fit to it.
Run that, and there you go.
So now you have, just within Seaborn,
you've already done a very
simple linear fit model to your data.
Great.
So your not going to be able to do this
however when we get to more complicated
regression models.
So we're gonna stay focused on using
Numpy and the scikit-learn library
in order to really dive deeper
into actual machine learning.
So, I'll stop the video here
before we jump into the mathematics
behind the machine learning.
So, let's just do a quick
overview of what we done.
We've set up everything we
needed as far as the imports.
We've imported a particular data set,
the Boston data set fromscikit-learn.
And I encourage you to go
check out the documentation
on that particular data set from
the scikit-learn documentation.
We've gone ahead and
printed a description of that data set.
Looked around, looked at the different
attributes and variables.
Also looked at the target,
which was the median value.
So what we're gonna wanna do during
this data set analysis is try to predict
the price of a house based
on the input attributes.
Remember, this was supervised learning.
Then we did a quick histogram.
We did a scatter plot of the number
of rooms versus the price.
Then we set up a Pandas data frame.
And did the exact same thing in
Seaborn with an automatic regression
fitted to our data.
So in the next lecture,
we're gonna go and move on to learning
about the mathematics, just a quick
overview behind the Least Squares Method.
Which is what we're gonna be using
with Numpy and scikit-learn.
Alright, so
I'll see you at the next video.
Thanks guys.