Hey everyone.
Welcome to Python Overview Part 2.
If you saw the last
lecture, we went lists,
ranges and other things.
Again these Python overview videos
is just a rapid tutorial and
basically a crash course in
the Python programming language.
If this is your first
programming language or
if you don't have let's say
an engineering, science or
math background, I highly suggest
you check out the other resources.
They'll go through Python
programming at a slower pace and
you'll really be able to learn
the nitty gritty details of Python to
the level that you need to to finish
the rest of the data analysis course.
In the overviews,
I'm just giving you a quick crash course.
So let's go ahead and
continue where we left off.
So in this Python Overview Part 2,
I'm gonna be going over iteration,
indentation and blocks.
So, one of the most useful
things we can do with
lists that we went over last
time is iterate through them.
What that means is that we can just go
through each element one at a time.
So, to show you an example of this,
let's go ahead and make a list.
So, last time we made a cities list.
Let's go ahead and remake that list.
I'll say my cities are NY, LA, and SF.
So I make that list with brackets.
And let's say I wanted to print
every city in my cities list.
So to do that, I can use a for
statement or a for loop.
So I can say for
city in cities colon Enter.
Notice how it indented for
me automatically.
The indent and
that white space is important in Python.
The code won't run unless
you have the right spacing.
And then I say for city in cities
let's go ahead and print city.
So we should expect it to print NY LA SF.
Shift+Enter.
And there we have it.
You may be wondering why I chose city or
how Python knew city for each element
in cities, so you can actually just,
this is basically creating a variable,
so you can call this whatever you want.
I can call it qwe, so for
qwe in cities, print qwe, Q-W-E,
shift enter, and
it outputs the same thing.
So you can just choose
variables in the for
loops, the names that make sense to you.
So for city in cities print city.
That makes sense.
So let's go ahead and do that.
All right, so what else can we do?
We can say for day, let's see.
How about we make statements or
phrases with the for loops?
So I can say for
city in cities.
Let's go ahead and make a phrase.
And we'll have that phrase equal to I love
space and then plus that city name.
And then we'll go ahead and
print that phrase.
So let's think about what it's gonna do,
it's gonna say for
every element in that list create this
phrase and then print that phrase.
Shift+ Enter, and there you have it.
I love NY.
I love LA.
I love SF.
In the last overview of part one we
learned about the range command.
So the range command is really useful
if you want to execute loops for
a specified length.
So for instance, I can say for
n in range 10.
So remember this is a list of 10 elements,
0 through 9, colon.
Let's go ahead and print, let's say we
want to print the inverse of every n.
So I can say the inverse of quotation,
let's put a space in there, and
I'm gonna say The inverse of,
and I can use commas here,
since I'm gonna be putting in
a different, not a string object but
a number object.
I can say the inverse of 'n,' is,
and again a comma, and
I'm gonna have this be 1.0 divided by m.
Let's see if this works.
I flip division by zero.
So if you notice, the very first
number if we think about this,
n in range ten, is going to be zero.
So I can't start at zero.
So I'm gonna specify
that it starts at one.
We'll see what happens, and
now we have it working.
So we say the inverse of 1 is 1.0.
The inverse of 2 is 0.5.
So, that makes sense.
One over two is a half.
0.5, and they will continue printing
the rest of those inverses.
Great.
So that's how you can use range
in a four loop.
It's really useful in a lot of cases, and
we'll be using it throughout the other
lectures in the data analysis course.
So what else can we do?
So lists and strings have something in
common, they can be treated as sequences.
So you already know that you can
iterate through the elements of a list,
such as a city,
each individual city and cities.
You can do the same thing for
the letters in a string.
So let's go ahead and say for letter in,
and let's make a word here so
it will say hello.
Print letter.
So what is this gonna do?
It's gonna say for every letter in hello,
this string, it's gonna print that letter.
So just like in lists, we can iterate
through every letter in a string,
and there you go,
it printed every individual letter.
This is really only occasionally useful.
What's a little more useful is slicing.
The slicing option let's you grab or
index elements from a list.
So for instance I could say city 0 and
we went over this
in part one, but this should call that
first city over, and there we have it NY.
Great.
So what else can we do with Python?
We can use Booleans and truth testing.
So we've learned a couple data types
already, integers, floating numbers,
strings, and lists.
Another data type we can use is a Boolean
variable, which is either a true or false.
And the way to do that
is by creating them, so
let's go ahead and
see what that works like.
So let's say if city is equal to NY,
and notice I used double
equal signs there since I'm
using bullion logic there.
I can say print party.
And then I'm going to
make an else statement.
So otherwise so
if city equals NY, print party!,
else print Work.
So, what do we think is gonna happen here?
Let's find out.
Let's see if we've defined city.
So since city didn't equal New York,
we printed work.
Let's see what city actually is.
So city is equal to SF currently.
If we make city equal to NY, Shift+Enter.
Go ahead and see what happens.
And now we have a party.
And notice that in IPython Notebook, the
cell order didn't matter as long as you
clicked Shift+Enter the variable
has been changed for all the cells.
Great.
So let's go ahead and mess around a little
more in Boolean logic with these double
equal signs, so we can ask Python is 1 to
equal to 2, and this should display false.
Great.
Let's make a true statement.
So it's 2 double equal sign equal to 2.
Shift+Enter.
And you get true.
Other Boolean logics we can
use is greater or less than.
So we can ask is 3 greater than 4,
that's false.
We can ask is 4 less then 5,
Shift+Enter and that's true.
We can also do greater or less then or
greater equals to, so for instance,
I can say is 1 greater then or equal to 2.
Shift+Enter, we'll have be true.
We can also do not equals,
so we can say 1, the way to do not
equals is with an exclamation mark.
Is 1 not equal to 2, that's true.
And lastly we can say is 1 greater than or
equal to 0 and that's true.
So those are a bunch of Boolean operators.
Hopefully they're pretty self
explanatory about greater or
less than, greater than or
equal to, not equal to.
If you're having trouble
understanding this,
then I suggest you check out the other
resources such as the Code Academy.
It will bring you up to speed
on this in a slower fashion, but
if you're getting this so
far then you're good to go.
So, what else can we do
with Boolean testing?
We can do tests on lists.
So, I can make a list say of 1,1,1, and
ask python is it equal to
another list of 1,1,1.
Shift+Enter, and that's true.
If I change an item in that list,
let's see if it stays true, and
it's false since the lists aren't equal.
Great.
So that's about it for
this Python overview, part two.
We basically just learned how to use for
loops to iterate through lists,
and use range in additional for for
loop to also iterate through different
items, or different actions.
Quick if L statements, and then
the Boolean operators, true and false.
Okay.
I'll see you in Part 3 for
another quick crash course tutorial.
Again, if this is going too fast for
you, check out the Codecademy resources.
They'll be more your speed.
But if this is making sense to you and
you're going through it fine,
then go ahead and
keep continuing checking out Part 3.
All right.
I'll see you there.