Hello everyone and
welcome to the second lecture
in the Supervised Learning Linear
Regression lecture series.
So in this lecture we're gonna go ahead
look a little deeper into the mathematics
behind the Least Squares Method, which
is the method we're gonna be using for
our linear regression on our
Boston housing data sets.
So if we take a quick look at the plot
we made in the last lecture with C1.
You see that there's our best fit line and
your data points,
and what we kinda wanna
answer the question is,
how do we know when the line
is the best fit line?
How do we know it's not slanted or
has a different slope or
a different y intercept?
How do we actually find this
line with the best fit?
So if you look at each data point,
you know they're each gonna have
a coordinate in the form x and y.
In this case, price as your y and
room as your x.
So imagine drawing a line between
each point to your current choice
of your best fit line.
So to visualize this,
I've got an image from Wikipedia here.
So you have your current choice of your
curve fit line, your best fit line.
So you might be iterating through these
and now you have all your data points.
And you've drawn a line from
each data point to your
current choice of your best fit line.
So if you label each of these green
lines as having a distance d,
we can now define a best fit
line as having this property.
So the sum of each of
those distances squared.
If it's minimized for
each of the data points,
then we know we have a best fit line.
So basically you're looking for
the line or the sum of all these squares,
of these green lines,
the distance between your data points
to your current curve fit is minimized.
So how do you find this actual line?
So in the least square line
method of approximating.
You have your set of points, you have
X,Y1, you have all these coordinate
points, 2, 3, 4, 5, fo,r etcetera,
etcetera, for all your data points.
And you know the line has
the equation Y = mx + b.
And in this case, we can write this as
Y equals A naught plus a1, times X.
And you can actually solve for
these constants, a naught, and a1,
by simultaneously solving
these two equations.
The sum of all your Y values
equal to a naught times N
plus a1 times the sum
of all your X values.
And the sum of X times
Y equals to a naught,
sum of all your x plus a1 times
the sum of all your x square values.
So these are actually called the normal
equations for the least square lines.
There's actually quite a bit more as far
as the further steps you have to take and
rearranging these equations
in order to solve for Y.
But since we don't want to
go too much into the math,
I'll let scikit-learn do the rest
of the heavy lifting here.
If you're interested in how you can
continue learning more about this
particular equation and
what your N stands for And
how a naught a1 come to play,
I've linked a video here.
And in this video it's a great
video by a man named [INAUDIBLE].
And it just goes over
some basic statistics and
he'll go over the simple linear
regression as far common in statistics So
you can just go back [CROSSTALK].
So go ahead and check out that
video if your further interested
in the actual mathematics
behind this method.
But As far as what we're doing,
as far as an overview is we're basically
having NumPy scikit-learn do this for
us, finding where on your
best fit line is this D
squared value minimized, as far as
the sum of all these green lines.
So that's just a very basic overview.
If you're interested in more of
the mathematics, go ahead and check those
video links and
they'll fill you in on that information.
Moving along, now we're gonna to use NumPy
to create a univariate linear regression.
Now remember, univariate is just
a fancy way of saying single variable.
So were just gonna wanna
take one single variable or
one data type,
in this case average number of rooms, and
try to fit it to the price data, or
label that we have, that target data.
So the way we're gonna do this is we'll
start out by setting x and y arrays for
NumPy to take in.
And an important note for the x array.
NumPy expects a two-dimensional array,
the first dimension is
different example values, and the second
dimension is the attribute number, and
I'll show you that in a second.
So in this case we have our value as
the mean number of rooms per house, and
since this is a single attribute, so the
second dimension of the array is just one.
So we'll need to create a shape
array 506 by 1 since if you remember
the description of the Boston data set
it had 506 attributes for each feature.
So there's a few ways to do this,
but an easy way to do that is by
using Numpy's built in vertical stack
tool, which is just vstack method.
So let's go ahead and
actually go to the live coding so
I can show you what I mean
by everything I just said.
Remember, if I'm going a little to fast,
you can always pause the video,
slow it down, or just go ahead and
open up the iPython Notebook yourself, and
read along through all
the detailed explanations.
But if you want to move along
to the algorithmic stuff,
we can go ahead and start that.
So I'm gonna set up my X,
and I'm gonna set that up
as the median of the room value.
So if you remember from the dataframe
we made in the last video,
we have our boston_df.
All right,
remember we named all the columns.
So I'm just gonna call that room column,
set that up as my X.
And if we look at what X is right now,
it's just an array, or a series, in this
case, of all those pricing data points.
But NumPy,
for its linear algebra library,
it needs to have it in the form,
all your features and then how many
attributes there actually are.
So in order to do that,
I'm gonna set x equal to.
NumPy, or np dot the vstack method
And then I'm going to call
that on that room calls.
So this is what we're
actually gonna to need to do.
And if we see what x looks like now,
as far as the shape,
now we have a 506 by one.
And if we look at the shape of
the last one, it was just 506.
So, what NumPy needs is it needs
to know how many values you have,
and how many attributes there were.
So we have one attribute which
is the average room size and
we have 506 different values for
that particular attribute.
Let's go ahead and set up the Y.
The Y is actually straightforward,
it's just the target price of the houses.
I can that by calling price
column we made earlier.
And so now that we know and
have our x and y, we can go ahead and
use NumPy to create the single
variable linear regression.
So I'm gonna hop back over
to the iPython Notebook.
That's completed for us.
And if you remember,
the line has an equation of y = mx + b.
But we're gonna have to rewrite this,
using matrices.
And the way we can do that is have y equal
to A times p, where A is just x by 1.
And as you can imagine, we kind of already
have that here, in our X here 506 by 1.
And where P is equal to m times b,
or m, a matrix of m over b, a2 by 1.
So this is the same as the first equation
if you carry out the linear algebra.
So just in different forms
with these matrices.
And we'll start by creating
that A matrix here using NumPy.
And we'll do this by creating
a matrix of the form X1.
So we'll call every value in our
original X that we just made, and
use list comprehension to basically make
this x1 array, this is a one by two.
And we'll set up an array in the form X1.
So let me show you what I mean by that.
So I need to create an array,
right now we have our x,
let me show you what it looks like here.
So that was actually the original x,
let me show you what it looks
like after we run that vstack.
There we go, so
that's what our x currently looks like.
The previous x I showed was actually
just that boston_df, room column, where
remember, we had to use that np.vstack to
get it get into this form, the 506 by 1.
And what I wanna do
now is create a array
in the form of x1.
Right now I just have
a bunch of the X values and
I need to have it look like that
due to the matrix equations.
So the way to do that.
Is by,
there's different ways you can do this.
You can do this doing a for
loop, but in this case,
I'm gonna do it using
a list comprehension.
So I'll write it out and
then break it down.
Okay.
So what are we actually doing here?
So if we look at what x
looks like right now.
Just gonna go ahead and
print it out for you.
X basically just looks like
a bunch of x's, all those values.
And I want it to look like this,
to match our equation here,
this matrix of 1 by 2, x and 1.
So the way to do that is I'm gonna
use the list comprehension, and
I'm gonna say, basically, this is just
kind of a different way of writing a for
loop almost that just builds a list.
So I'm going to say, for
every value in my x, so
go through this array,
so every value here.
Set it up as the value comma 1, so
it matches this form here, that A matrix.
And then make an array
of all those values.
So if I run that now,
let's go ahead see what x looks like.
And now it looks exactly the same
except now there's that 1 attached.
And remember,
we need that one because NumPy needs
to know how many attributes you have.
And in this case, it's just a simple
single variable linear regression so
we have one attribute,
the average room number.
Okay, and now that we have all that,
that's actually all we need and
we can get our best fit values.
So again, you can always review everything
we just did in the IPython Notebook.
But continuing on for now,
we can go ahead and get the m and
b values for our best fit line.
And the way you do this is like this.
You set up two new objects, m and
b, and then the NumPy method
we're going to use is
in the linear algebra library, which
is this, linalg, and then we're using
the least square methods and
that's just lstq.
Then you call your X and Y.
And we
actually only want
the first index value at 0.
The reason for
that is just the format that
linear algebra least squares
methods spits it out.
If you're interested in that,
just go ahead and
Google np.linalgs.leastsquares and
check out the documentation there.
If I Google it right now,
I'll go ahead and Google it.
Go to the documentation, and
there's actually almost like
a little mini tutorial here.
And you can see, just like I mentioned,
you can rewrite the line equation, y = ap,
as these two different matrix equations,
and they kind of also build it out here.
So go ahead and check out
the documentation in case you want
some more resources on what
NumPy's actually doing, but
in this case we just wanna crank it out.
Go ahead and run that.
And, whoops, I messed,
oh, it's actually lstsq,
I'm sorry, least squares,
so lstsq, I apologize.
So now that we have that,
we can plot it all together.
So note that we're gonna use the original
format of the Boston information.
So we only did our matrix transformations
to utilize the NumPy least square method.
So let's go ahead and
plot the original points.
So I am going to say plt.
Oops, let me get back here, okay.
So looking back I am going to say plt.
Let me make, okay, .plot.
And I'm gonna say boston_df.RM,
boston_df.Price.
So, that's gonna create our scatterplot.
It's just gonna make a marker for
every average number of room and
the price associated with it.
And that's what I was actually
meaning before when we were
using the original format
of the Boston information.
Okay, and now let's go ahead and
plot our best fit line that
we just made using NumPy.
And what I'm gonna do for
that is I'm gonna set lowercase x.
Equal to that room column.
And then I'm gonna say plt.plot.
I'm gonna have all my x
values be those x values.
And then I'm just gonna put in the
equation of a line here using the m and
b we just obtained from our NumPy least
squares method in the linear algebra
library.
I'll go ahead and make this a red
line by passing the r as a string.
And then I'll label it, best fit line.
So let's just break down what we've
done so far before I plot this out.
We are trying to use the NumPy
linear algebra library to
perform a least square method.
So we needed our data in the form
of a 506 by 1 shape array,
since NumPy needs to know both,
every single value, but
it also needs to know what
the attribute number for that is.
And since we're only using
a single variable or
a single attribute,
it's just 1 there, so 506 by 1.
We used vstack to make it two dimensional.
We needed to rewrite our equation of
a line in this matrix form in order for
NumPy to accept it using linear algebra.
So we use that list creation, or
list comprehension, excuse me,
to create that list and then transform
it into an array using np.array.
Then we can finally pass it using
np.linalg.lstsq and our x y values.
And we only needed that
first index value of that.
And you can go ahead and
check out that documentation as far as
how exactly your values are outputted.
All we really care about is that m and
b to make our equation for
the line y = mx +b.
And then after that,
we made a scatter plot.
And we're about to recreate it
here on our live coding session.
So scrolling down here,
we have our scatter plot and
we also plotted an x and
that linear fit line.
And there you have it.
So we did it.
If we scroll back up here, we basically
manually recreated this seaborn plot.
So this is just a simple
linear regression.
Seaborn did this automatically for us.
But we were also able to do it on our own,
through some matrix tricks and
NumPy, by using the least squares method.
Okay, so in the next steps,
what we're gonna do is get the error and
then move on to using scikit-learn to
implement a multivariate regression.
So, remember our data set didn't just have
the median number of rooms as a feature,
it had a bunch of
different features to it.
And now we wanna take all of those
into account when trying to predict
a house price.
Okay, so I'll stop this video here and
I'll see you at the next video.
Thanks guys.