Hey everybody, welcome to lecture eight.
So in this lecture we're gonna be
learning how to use arrays and scalars.
Okay.
So first off,
we're just gonna import numpy as np.
And then something we can do is say,
let's check five divided by two.
So in Python version two,
if you were to input this command, 5/2.
Notice you just get a whole integer there.
You're not going to get
2.5 as it should be.
If you clarify it to be a floating point
by saying 5.0, and we run this again.
ALT + ENTER then we do
get the true answer.
It treats that as a floating point.
In order to take care of that
we can import from the future,
I know it sounds crazy,
but we can totally do it.
So we can save from __future__
we can import division.
So if you're running on Python 3.whatever
x, you won't have to worry about this.
It's already gonna be standard.
But, if you're running on Python 2,
you're gonna have to import
in division from the future
to take care of that problem.
So now let's go ahead and
see five divided by two and we get 2.5.
Excellent.
All right, so let's go ahead and create an
array like we've done in the last lecture.
We can say we're gonna
call this array arr1 and
I'm gonna say np.array.
And like we learned in the last lecture,
we can do it with a list
of multiple lists.
So I'm gonna do just that.
I'm gonna say 1, 2, 3, 4.
That's be the first list that I input,
and then the second list that
I input will be 8, 9, 10, 11.
Okay.
So now we got that.
Let's go ahead and see what that
multi-dimensional array looks like.
So we have a two by four here, excellent.
So what can we do with that?
We can try multiplying arrays.
So in this case,
we can say array 1 times array, oh.
Array 1 times array 1, excuse me.
So what do we get here?
So if you do this kind of command it's
going to multiply every value in the same
spot of one array by the value of
the other one in the same spot.
So for instance, one times one is one.
Two times two is four.
Nine times nine is 81,
et cetera, et cetera.
So you can do some scalar
operations there in a sense.
You can also do subtraction so
we can say array 1 minus r1.
There we go.
And you'll get a zero, which makes sense
because it's 1-1, 2-2, etcetera, etcetera.
And then you can do arithmetic
operations with scalers on the array.
So, for instance, if I wanted to,
say one divided by every
value in that array.
This would be the same thing as saying
every value in the array to power of -1.
So, creating it as
the reciprocal of a fraction.
There we go.
And, that's what we got.
So, if we look at the original array.
One divided by one should be one.
And then we say one divided
by two should be 0.5.
And if you look at some other values here,
one divided by ten should be 0.1.
So that makes sense,
the same as one over ten.
So you can do that as well.
And then lastly you can also
do exponential operations.
So you could say that array
to the power of three.
So, every element in that array to the
power of three, and that's what you get.
So, one to the power of three is just one,
two to the power of three is,
et cetera, et cetera.
So that's how you can do some
mathematical operations on arrays and
also arithmetic operations using scalars.
Okay, so we'll be using
these throughout the course.
Go ahead and do an overview,
make sure you understand it.
Otherwise I will see you in lecture nine.
See you there.