Hey guys, welcome to lecture 32.
Your going to learn how to combine,
data frames.
Alright, let's get started.
So.
We'll import the usual.
Import numpy as np.
Import pandas as pd.
And then from pandas,
import series and data frame.
Let's go ahead and take a look.
Okay.
Let's make some series to work with.
So ser1 Series.
Let's go ahead and
pass a list of values.
I'm gonna put some null values in there so
we can see how Panda's deals with that.
So I have a total of six values there.
And then let's give it an index.
And we'll just make that index Q, R, S.
Oops.
T, U, and V.
Alright, and then we'll check that out.
Okay, and then let's go ahead and
make another series.
The series.
We're just going to get a number.
So we'll say np.arrange.
And to make it the same
length as series one.
We'll just do LAN the length function.
On our first series,
and then we'll specify,
pass the argument dtype, and
then we'll specify the type of object.
So we'll say np, float64 to specify
that they're floating numbers.
And then index, we'll copy and
paste the same index from before.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Okay.
And then let's type to make sure that
everything worked out correctly.
Alright so we have zero one two three
four five and then q r s t u v.
Awesome.
So now that we have those two series,
let's get a series where
the value of series one is
chosen if series two is null.
Otherwise we'll let
the value be series one.
So I'll show you how to
create that kind of series.
I'll call the series command.
And I'm gonna use np.where method.
So, I'm going to say np dot where,
so I'll say...
Pd.isnull, so where pandas is null it will
put in series one as the argument,
select a value from series two.
and we'll say otherwise select
the value from series one and
then we'll set the index to equal
the index of the first series so
let's just look at this
before we click enter here.
We using np.where so
we're saying np.where and
then wherever Series 1 is null,
put in the Series 2 value.
And if not, then just put in Series 1.
Okay, so let's see what we got then.
So, now I have Q, R, S, T, U, V.
Two, one, four, three, six, five.
So, if we look at the null values for
series 1, it was on the R,
the T, and the V, and
now if we look at the R, the T, and
the V, those values have now been
obtained from the second series, scr2.
So, that's how you can use np.where
command to do a little bit of logic.
Just take a moment to make sure you
really understand what happened here with
asking for the null and then choosing
scr2, otherwise choosing scr1.
We can do the exact same thing
using the combined first method,
which is build into pandas.
So, I showed you the long way and
now I'll show you the short cut.
So the shortcut is just
combine_first ser2.
So this will do the exact same
thing as that work command.
It'll say "take series one,
combine it with series two, but
if there's a null value there,
then use the value from series two" And
we get the exact same results.
That's kind of the short cut
method to this longer version
using the np.where method.
So that's what works on series.
Let's go ahead and take a look
at how it works on data frames.
So, we'll make a dframe and
we'll call it dframe.
Odds.
And then we will pass
a dictionary into data frame.
So we'll say X and we'll give it a list.
We're going to say one,
we'll put in a null value.
And in fact what I'll do, since we're
going to be using a lot of null
values here, I'll set NAN equal to
NP.NAN so I don't have to type as much.
Going back to that dictionary,
we'll go one dot,
put in a null, 3, the dots are to signify,
indicate the floating numbers and
then another nan and value.
And then we'll have another null value.
Of five.
A null value.
And a 7.
And then the last entry will be Z.
So we have x, y, z.
And then we'll make it have a null value,
a 9,
a null value, and 11.
So this data frame only has odd numbers.
Let's go ahead and make sure it took.
Okay.
And now let's make a dataframe
called dframe_evens,
and we'll pass another dictionary
through that, and this case,
we'll just say X,
we'll set it equal to two.
Let's say four,
I'll put in a null value, six, eight,
and then we'll make Y with its entries
list be a null value,
10, whoops, 12, 14, and let's just say 16.
Okay, and we'll skip the Z on that one.
And let's make sure it took.
All right.
So let's go ahead and show them.
We got dframe odds.
All right,
there's our dataframe X Y Z columns.
With the odd values and
then let's get the evens one.
Okay.
X, y columns.
Only even values, couple of null
values spattered throughout.
So, let's combine them now.
So, we'll say dFrame_odds,
and we're gonna do the exact same
thing we did on the series, so
we'll say combine_first,
and then we'll pass dFrame
evens object through it.
So take a minute to think what
the result should be of this.
So it's going to take dframe odds and
where there's a null value,
it will pass dframe evens.
So, let's just imagine what that
first column should look like.
First column,
X we have a one null, three null.
So that means if we combine it,
we should get a 1.
We'll take a null, so then if we
look down here at the dframe even,
that should be a four.
The 2 we have a value so that one's good.
On the third index we have a null.
So that will be 6.
And then the fourth one doesn't
exist on dframe odds so
we'll input the dframe evens.
So, your first column after issuing
this command should be 1, 4, 3,
6, 8 and it should be, it'll carry
the same kind of operations on the Y and
Z columns, so let's go ahead and
see if we were right.
Yep, so the yes column like we expected,
1, 4, 3,
6, 8 and then you have the Y and
Z columns.
If there were null values on both of them,
then we'll keep the null values
in the combined first result.
You can go ahead and
make your own data frames, and
pass different combinations
using the combine_first method
just to make sure you really
understand how it's working.
So just to overview,
you could use np.where with
the isnull logic and specify the index.
But the shortcut method that pandas
has built in is combine_first,
and you can do that on dataframes as well.
So that's how you combine dataframes.
Next step we'll learn about
reshaping dataframes.
I'll see you there.