Hey everybody welcome to lecture 50,
Combining Plot Styles.
So in this lecture, we're gonna be
learning how to combine plot styles.
I've already copied and pasted
the imports we're gonna be using for
the data visualization section.
So you've got your normal inputs.
The stats library, and
then the plotting modules as well
as mat plot in line command.
So, this lecture will be quite a bit
shorter than the last lecture, and
we're gonna learn a lot.
So, we're gonna learn how to
combine different plot styles.
So, let's get something to plot.
Let's go ahead and make a data set.
We'll set that equal to this random 100.
So set's get 100 points.
And then to make a combined plot,
Seaborn has
a built in D-I-S-T, so distplot.
And this allows us to combine plots.
So if I pass my data set through this,
and I set my bins equal to 25.
By default bins are set to 10.
And seaborn, and hit Alt+Enter.
So by default, this distplot combines
a kernel density estimation plot,
this line that we discussed in
the previous lecture, with a histogram,
which we also discussed
in previous lectures.
Great.
So, we can also choose
whether it's a rug plot,
a kernel density estimation plot or
a histogram.
Those are all input
arguments to this plot.
And we can either turn those plots on or
off.
To show you what I'm talking about,
let's go ahead and call the distplot.
Call it on the data set.
Again, set your bins equal 25.
And now what I'm gonna do is,
I'm gonna set rug equal true,
so I can see a rug plot.
And I'm gonna set hist equal to false,
so I don't see the histogram anymore.
Let's go ahead and hit Alt+Enter.
And so now, by default, it showed the kde,
but I showed rug to true, so
it's showing my rug plot,
and it's not showing the histogram
anymore because I set hist to false.
Excellent.
So let's say, I want to control specific
plots within the combined plots.
So if I wanted to do,
maybe set a certain color to the rug plot,
or set certain parameters on the KDE plot.
I can do that by passing
dictionaries into distplot.
So I'll show you how to do that now.
So we can call S and S distplot,
call my dataset, set the number of bins,
let's call it 25.
And what I can do is I
can pass dictionaries.
So the way we can do is by having
a plot_ kws argument equal a dictionary.
So, what I mean by that is,
if I want to edit my KDE plot, and
hold on a second, I forgot the s there.
Like I was saying, if I want to
edit my KDE plot, I'll set KDE,
and then underscore kws for
those arguments, and
I'll set those arguments
equal to a dictionary.
So I have my color key, and
I can set that equal to a color,
so I'll select indianred, and
then I could also make a label
specifically for the KDE plot.
And set that key equal to KDE plot.
And then let's say,
I wanted also to edit my histogram
that came along with the distplot.
I can do that just by saying hist,
again underscore kws.
Equal, and then I can pass a dictionary
again with certain controls.
So let's set the histogram color to blue,
and let's label it, so set the label key.
And its value will be HIST.
Capitalize it.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and see if that worked.
Great.
So now you can individually control
the not quite sub plots, but
each individual plot in the combined plot.
Just by passing dictionary and
then the plot subname_kws.
Great.
All Right.
So again we've learned so
much about pandas.
And works really well with pandas.
We can use panda state objects for this.
So I can say from pandas let's
go ahead and import Series.
And let's create a series.
From my dataset, so I'm gonna say
ser1 equals Series from the dataset.
And I'll set that series name to
be the string my_data.
And then let's go ahead and
see what that series looks like.
[SOUND] So there's my series
made from those 100 points.
Great.
And now, we can use seaborn.
Sns.distplot.
You can pass a panda series.
And again, let's say bins 25.
And it will plot the pandas series.
So seaborn works fantastically
well with pandas.
It's a great,
great data visualization library
that works really well with pandas.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and
go to the next lecture where we're
gonna learn about box and violent box.
I'll see you there.