Hey, guys.
Welcome to lecture 45.
This is gonna be on using splitting,
applying, and combining.
So otherwise known as split,
apply, combine.
So we'll do the usual imports.
I'm just copying and pasting these from
the IPython Notebook viewer
link that I have for you guys.
All right.
So what is split, apply, combine?
The best way to look at this is just
through a visual demonstration.
So for instance,
you can have a data frame, or
just a data set,
split it up by a certain index.
So in this example,
this was split up by that letter in
the x column, so a's, b's, and c's.
You can apply something to
it to get a new value, and
then you can combine it back again.
So in this instance it looks like
the y column was averaged out, and so
you get the average of everything, and
you can do this by groupBy methods or
other ways using pandas.
So this is the general principle of split,
apply, combine, and
we're gonna learn about it a little more.
So let's go ahead and
get some data to work with.
use the same data frame we used in
the last lecture, the wine data frame.
And we'll open this up
by using pd.read_csv.
And saying, winequality_red.csv, and
remember the limiter/separator
was a semicolon in this case.
And then to make sure we
actually got it correct,
we'll just check out the first five rows.
All right, great.
Okay, so in the last lecture we kind of
explored alcohol content versus quality.
So what if we wanted to know
the highest alcohol content wine for
each quality range?
We can use groupby mechanics to do
a split apply combine procedure.
So, first what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
create a function that assigns a rank to
each wine based on alcohol content,
with 1 being the highest alcohol content.
So what I'm gonna do is
I'll make a function.
I'll call it ranker.
It's gonna take a data frame and
then from that data frame it
will set alc content rank.
And let's go ahead and make this
one term so the underscore is here.
So this is gonna create that column and
set it equal to arrange,
let's group the numbers by
the length of the data frame + 1.
And then it's gonna
return that data frame.
Okay, so
we'll be using this function later on.
Then let's go take a step back and
look at the dframe_wine.
So let's sort the data frame
by alcohol in ascending order.
So I'm gonna say dframe_wine.sorts.
I'm gonna sort it by alcohol.
Say ascending, pass that argument,
put it to false and then inplace=True so
it affects our data frame.
Okay, so now we have a data frame sorted.
Now we're gonna group by quality and
apply our ranking function.
So this is how we're gonna do this.
This is gonna be the split,
apply, combine technique.
So I take my data frame wine,
and I'm gonna set it equal to
dframe_wine.groupby, group it by quality.
And this is where the apply comes in.
I'm going to pass the method apply and
I'm gonna apply that ranker
function that we just created.
So again, this ranker function
assigns a rank to each wine based on
alcohol content,
with 1 being the highest alcohol content.
So I'm applying that ranking
function to the dataframe
as it's been grouped by quality.
Okay.
So
take a moment, think about what
the ranker function's actually doing,
why it's arranging by the length and
why it's adding that 1.
And then once you
understand it go ahead and
preview what your dataframe
is gonna look like.
So let's go ahead and
check the head of that dataframe.
Okay.
So what do we got for a dataframe now?
We can see that the index of
the rows has been jumbled up a bit.
But if we come over here and
look at the alc_content_rank,
it looks like your dataframe's been
sorted by the highest alcohol content.
So this is the number 1 alcohol
content for the quality of 5.
This is the number 1 alcohol content for
the quality of 8.
And you can see, these are pretty high
alcohol content wines,14.9%, 14%.
So we can now get closer to finding the
highest alcohol content for each ranking.
So how do we finish this up?
We can just call for the dataframe
where the alcohol content rank,
this last row right here equals 1.
So we can say, set an object
called num_of_qual =
dframe_wine Quality.
Value_counts.
And then let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
Okay, so what is this?
This is just the number of
lines in each quality count.
So at quality 5,
at quality 6, 7, 4, 8, and 3.
And this is, there's 681 wines
that have a quality rating of 5.
638 wines have a quality rating of 6,
etc., etc.
So let's go ahead and
show the combined information for
the wines that had the highest alcohol
content for their respective rank.
All right.
So, this is how we're gonna do that.
We'll take our dataframe,
and then say, dframe_wine,
call that last column we
made using our ranker,
content_rank and say = 1.
So, dframe_wine where your
alc_content_rank = 1.
So, where it's equal to 1, that means
it had the highest alcohol content
of any wine in its quality class,
if you will.
And then we'll just get the head of that.
And how many dframes do we wanna see?
Well, we just wanna see, or, I'm sorry,
how many rows do we wanna see?
We just wanna see the same number of
rows as there are quality batches.
So we'll say num_of_qual.
And looks like I forgot an E.
Okay, let's run it again.
All right, there we go.
So if you look at the alc_content_rank,
they're all equal to 1.
So there were six quality rankings
in total, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
And these are the row indexes of
the wines that had the highest
alcohol content for their quality class.
So you can see these all have
pretty high alcohol contents.
They're all the highest in the class, and
you can see how they relate to quality.
And so something we might wanna ask
ourselves is are there any trends between
the ranking of the wine and
the alcohol content?
You might start to wonder, is there a
ranking between a higher quality ranking,
and a higher alcohol percentage?
That might be an interesting
thing to investigate.
So the important thing about splitting,
applying,
combining, is that we were
able to get from a dataframe,
pass, and apply a function to it.
So you're able to use groupby to
do the splitting and combining.
And you're able to use .apply to
apply functions to your data frame.
All right, so that's it for that.
In lecture 46,
we're gonna learn about cross tabulation.
Okay.