Hey, welcome to lecture 46,
and this lecture will
be on cross tabulation.
So for this lecture we're just going
to need to import pandas as pd.
So this is gonna be a quick
lesson on cross tabulations.
They're basically just
a special case of pivot tables.
So let's create a quick data set, and
since this is gonna be such a quick
lesson, I'll show you a little
trick in addition to the lesson.
So I'm gonna from string IO, I'm going
to import string IO, and
that will allow me to
create some data like this.
So I'm gonna make some comments lines,
do a new line.
Set.
I'm setting right now the column
names as one line, and then,
for my sample animal intelligence columns,
I'm going to have sample number one.
The animal will be dog.
Its intelligence will be smart.
We'll have sample two.
It's gonna also be a dog.
It's also gonna be smart.
Sample three.
I'm gonna have a cat.
It's gonna be dumb.
Sample four,
gonna have cat it's also gonna be dumb.
And then sample five, let's make it a dog.
I guess we'll have one dog be dumb.
Sample six, we're gonna make it a cat,
and we'll have one smart cat.
And then I'm gonna end this just
by CC ing that comment chunk.
Okay.
So
this is just a little trick for
using string IO to read data.
So this data's just
basically a big comment.
And then I can store it as a D frame.
By saying pd dot reed underscore table,
and
this is where we're gonna use string IO.
It will analyze that data,
and then the separator is just
gonna be equal to backslash S plus.
So don't worry about this, you can explore
string IO documentation in Python if you
wish, this is just kind of a little
trick for creating data sets.
We won't be creating any
more data frames this way,
it's just that cross tabulation
lecture's gonna be pretty short, so
I figured I'd add a little trick there for
you.
Okay, and our data frame worked out well,
we got out sample numbers,
the animal type, dog or
cat, and its intelligence.
It's either smart or it's dumb.
Okay, so, now we can create
a cross tabulation table, and
it's basically just
the the frequency table.
so if we call pd, cross tab that's how
you can create a cross tabulation table,
and we're gonna create it
using the animal column
The intelligence column.
Has arguments, and
I'll set margins equal to true.
So what is this gonna do?
Well nothing apparently,
it will say I spelled something wrong.
Margin, should be margins, excuse me.
There we go, okay.
So what does this do?
It creates basically, a pivot table
that is almost like a frequency counter.
So it's counted the total number of cats.
It's created this all column.
It's counted the total number of dogs and
then the total number of all the items.
And then it's separated out by the second
input argument, which was intelligence.
So it's grabbed all the animals
as your first input.
It's separated them out by intelligence,
and then it's counted their frequencies.
So you have two dumb cats,
one smart cat, all of them are three.
You have one dumb dog, two smart dogs,
all of them together have three.
And then for all the animals,
you have three and three.
And all of them together is six.
You could of also done this
using a pivot table, but
cross tab is just a little shortcut for
this special case.
Okay, and
that's really it about cross tabulations.
We won't use them anymore throughout this
course, but it's important that you know
about them in case you find
yourself needing to use them.
Okay, and that's it.
The next lecture is lecture 47, and
we'll be learning how to install seaborn.
I'll see you there.