All right guys, welcome to lecture 18.
This will be about dropping entries
from data frames and series.
We'll just call it drop entry.
So let's take a look at how this works.
First off we're gonna import the usual.
You might just be copying and pasting now,
but I'll just always be typing it out.
Import numpy, and
then from pandas we're gonna
import Series and DataFrame.
And then we're gonna import pandas as pd.
Alt+Enter.
All right, great.
So let's create a new series to play with,
we'll call it ser1.
Call series, and
what are we gonna pass as the series?
Well, we'll just pass,
np.arange, function,
we'll have it just be three,
switch to be 0,1,2.
And then I'll set the index as a, b, c.
All right, let's go ahead and
show that series.
Cool, so we have our range 0, 1, 2,
those three points, and our index a, b, c.
So what if we wanted to drop an index?
How would we do that?
Well, in pandas,
it's actually pretty easy.
You just say,
call drop on your series, and
then put the object you wanna drop,
so that index label.
Say let's say we wanted to drop b, and
then boom, that whole row is dropped.
Anything that was indexed
with b is now dropped.
So, let's look at how this
works with a data frame.
In order to do that,
let's make a data frame.
So we'll make dframe1, call DataFrame.
And let's go ahead and
input, we'll use np.arange
to create a array of nine numbers, and
then, we'll call reshape on it
like we've done in the past.
And we'll just make it a 3 x 3 matrix.
Awesome.
So
now that we have our data value points,
let's create an index.
In this case,
I'm just gonna make the index
city initials just to mix it up a bit.
And last we just need to name the columns,
and
we do that by passing
the columns argument.
And let's make a list, so
I'll make one pop for population,
maybe another for size,
and then a year column.
We won't actually be filling
this with real data, so,
call them whatever you want.
And let's go ahead and show data,
the dframe1 to see what we got.
All right, so we have our arange of
nine points, 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8,
arranged or reshaped into a 3 x 3 matrix.
We have our index SF, LA, NY, and
the column names pop, size, and year.
So if we wanna drop a row, we do it
just like we did for a data frame.
We call a drop on the data frame, and then
I give the index of the row we wanna drop.
So if we wanted to drop the index LA row,
we'll do that,
and that will get rid of that.
So, this doesn't actually
permanently affect your array.
If you wanted that to happen,
you'd have to,
save another array, with the drop.
And now, if I see dframe2 and show it,
it's gonna drop it permanently.
But the original dframe, whoops sorry,
drame1, will still retain LA.
So what if we wanted to drop a column?
Well, it's a very similar process.
So dframe1, drop.
You give the column name, year, but
now since we're not gonna be dropping
arow we need to specify
which axis we wanna use, and
in this case the axis for
the columns is axis=1.
By default the drop uses axis=0,
which would be your rows.
The columns would be axis=1.
And so you can see we've dropped the year
column and now just have a 3 x 2.
And that's about it for dropping entries.
You just use .drop.
If you wanna drop a row,
you just gotta name the index of that row,
and it'll drop it for you.
If you wanna drop a column,
just gotta name the column, and
then specify that it's on the 1 axis,
or axis=1.
Cool.
So next we're gonna learn about
selecting entries in the data frame.
All right, I'll see you there.