Hello everyone, and
welcome to the next video in
the Supervised Learning
Linear Regression Series.
So in this video we're gonna be
doing is I'm gonna hop over back
to the completed IPython Notebook.
So we set up our data frame in the last
video with all different coefficients for
that linear regression we
made using scikit-learn.
So we did a multi-variable
linear regression.
And now what we're gonna do is move on to
step 7, using training and validation.
So, usually in a data set,
what you're gonna do, especially for
our regression model, is is have
a training set implemented to build
up the model and then a validation
set you use to validate the model.
So usually you don't use the entire
data set to do your analysis.
You're gonna split it up
into mostly training and
then some testing or validation points.
So the correct way to do this to
pick out your samples that for
testing and training is to do it randomly.
Fortunately, scikit-learn has
a built in function specifically for
this called train_test_split.
So what it does is it takes in your data
and it splits it into a training set and
a testing set.
So you'll run your analysis
on your training set and
see how well it matches up with
your testing or validation set.
So, this is how you can tell how good
your regression and your model was.
So the parameters passed are your x and y,
and then, optionally, you can also pass
a test size parameter as far as the train
test split method and scikit-learn.
And what the test size parameter does is
it represents the portion of the data set
to include in the test split,
so that test chunk.
And then you can also either
do a train size parameter,
which is how much of the data do
you want to be the training set.
So let's say you had a data set of
100 points, you could set, hey,
I want my testing size to
be 70 of those points, and
I want my training size to be 30
of those points, or vice versa.
You want a large training
set to be 70 points, and
then a testing set to be 30 points.
Usually you want your training set to be
as large as you reasonably can have it and
your testing set to be large enough
that you feel validated with your model.
So let's go ahead and
jump into the codes so
we can get a better idea of
what this actually looks like.
And again, there's also a link to
the documentation about the different
parameters you can check out as far
as the train test split method.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna say,
we're gonna call sklearn.
Sklearn and
then we're gonna call the cross
validation library from scikit-learn,
and this is used to do our
train test split analysis, and
then the data we wanna do this with
is that x data we made earlier.
Remember that array?
You can go ahead and
check back to the previous videos.
And then the next data set we
want is actually the target.
So that was just the price.
So what this will do is scikit-learn is
going to take all your X information, all
your y information, and in this case, it's
gonna be the multi-variable information,
and then split it up into
a training set and a testing set.
And the way it's gonna output this
is it's gonna output four things.
It's gonna output your X training and
your X testing, and
then your Y training and your Y testing.
So what we're gonna do is
now set up the outputs.
So we did this a little backwards just
to show you how to construct this.
But this is the order
it spits them out in.
And you can always check the documentation
in case you're confused.
Okay, great.
So, what we've done here is we've split
up all our data into a training set and
a testing set, and there's an X and
a Y for each of those respectively.
So let's go ahead and see what
the output of the train test split was.
And I'll do that just
with a print command.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna check the shape of each of
those that I just printed.
Or just set,
depending on how you wanna think about it.
Shape, and then for the Ys.
Okay, so I'm gonna print the shape
of my X training and my X testing,
and then my Y training and my Y testing.
So you can see here that
the majority of the data is
in the training sets so 379 points are in
the X training set and the Y training set.
And then 127 points are in
the testing data set.
So usually you want as much of your
data into the training set, and
scikit-learn does this automatically for
you.
It chooses what it thinks is the best
split, but you can go ahead as you learn
more about machine learning, or have
a particular data set you wanna work with.
You can decide how you
want that split to occur.
But again, I encourage you to check
out that link to the documentation
in your IPython Notebook.
So moving on, now that we have
our training and testing sets,
we can continue to predict the prices
based on the multiple of variables.
So in this next section, step 8,
we're going to predict prices.
So we have our training and testing sets.
Let's go ahead and
try to predict house prices with them.
So we'll use our training set for
the prediction and then use our testing
set for validation of that prediction.
So let's go ahead and
create a regression object again.
And we do this just by, whoops.
Calling that linear regression
that we imported earlier.
And then once again,
I'm gonna do a linear regression.
So I'm gonna do a fit.
But in this case,
I'm going to pass my training set first.
[COUGH] Excuse me.
Okay, so I'm fitting my training
data to this linear regression.
So let's go ahead and do that.
All right, fantastic.
Now I'm going to run what's called a
prediction on both the X training set and
the testing set.
So the way we can do that is just
by calling a prediction method.
On my X train.
And I'm gonna set that equal to Something,
just an object called PRED for
prediction_train.
So that's the prediction
from my X training sets, and
then I'm gonna set a prediction for
my testing set.
So we're gonna be using these four is to,
if we run a prediction with my training
set, how well does it
match with my testing set?
And hopefully the numbers
will be pretty close.
All right.
So if you remember, we've already
learned how to calculate the error.
We want the mean squared error, or
sometimes the root mean squared error.
Depending how you wanna calculate it.
So this case,
we'll just take the mean square error.
So what I'm gonna do here is
just print out a statement.
So I'm gonna say, fit a model x_train,
so fit a model with my x training sets,
and calculate the mean squared error.
In this case I'm not gonna do the root
mean squared error, it's up to you,
depending how you want
to evaluate your errors.
But in this case it
probably makes a little
more sense to use the mean squared error.
And you'll see why in a second
when there see the actual results.
And calculate the mean square
error with your Y training set.
In this case I will- Call
a floating point there.
And so
what do I actually wanna print out here?
Well, I wanna print out
the mean squared error.
So I wanna take the difference
between my Y training and
that prediction I made
earlier from my training set.
So I wanna take that, and
then what I wanna do is square it, and
then I wanna take the mean of that.
So what I can do is use NumPy's
mean method to do that,
np.mean.
Okay.
So I'm sorry I'm going off
a little bit off the cell here but
I'm taking the difference
between my Y training object and
my prediction training object, squaring
it, and then figuring out the mean.
And then you could square root that if
you wanted, the root mean square error.
But in this case it's not necessary.
And then the next thing I wanna do is fit
a model with my training data set and
calculate the mean squared error.
With my X testing sets and
my Y testing set.
And I'll leave that up to two places past
the decimal and so now what do I want?
So now we're gonna do basically
the exact same thing we did earlier
except we're gonna do it
with the Y testing data and
my linear regression prediction from
my testing on the X testing data so
that pred_test object we made earlier.
So I want my Y test data
Minus that prediction test data.
I'm gonna square it,
And then I'm gonna grab the mean.
So let's go ahead and
break down real quick before I print this.
Well, let me print it, and then I'll break
it down, just so it's easier to read.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and
break down what we just did here.
We took the scikit-learn's ability
to split our data into a training set and
a testing set.
So this is always really important
to do in your regression models.
And then we printed out the shape
to see what scikit-learn
decided how to split up your data.
So you have your X_training and
your X_testing.
Then we made a linear regression object.
We fit our training sets X and
Y train using the same methods we
described in previous lectures,
and then we ran a prediction.
We ran one linear regression prediction
using the training of the X data set.
And then we ran another prediction
using the testing set and
we set these as objects pred_train,
pred_test.
And then we made a little print statement
here for the mean squared error,
which is your Y training
minus your prediction.
So remember,
this is just basically the length of that
D line that we talked about earlier.
So if I go back to the IPython Notebook
here and scroll up a bit.
Remember this D object here, the length
of that line between your data and
that best fit curve?
That's what this is here.
It's basically, what was
the difference between your prediction
on that training set and
that actual Y training value?
And then square it, and find the average.
And remember,
you could also take the square root if
you wanted the root mean squared error of
this, like we did earlier.
And now,
we also wanna do the same thing, but
we wanna do it with the testings data
set and see how well they match.
So, we took our Y testing,
did a prediction on that testing data and
did the exact same thing.
So in this case with
this particular split,
it looks like we're not super close but
we're also not super far off.
And the question is how do you actually
know how significant this number is?
Is there a way to visualize how close
our prediction actually is between
our training set and our testing set?
Because these numbers can be a bit
nebulous if you're in different fields.
So what might be a good training and
testing model in neuroscience might not be
such a good testing and
training model for other fields like
if you're doing some sort of oil and
gas machine learning thing.
So what we're gonna do is do
something called the residual plot
to visualize how good our analysis was.
So I'm gonna hop over back to the IPython
Notebook that's already completed here.
And I'm gonna scroll down to step 9.
So keep going.
Okay.
So residual plots.
All right.
So in regression analysis the difference
between the observed value, the dependent
variable, that was our Y, and
the predicted value,
sometimes called Y hat,
with that little mark there,
is called the residual E.
So each data point has one residual.
It's the observed value
minus the predicted value.
So again, you can think of these
residuals in the same way as that D
value we discussed earlier.
However, remember we are looking
at multiple features.
So it's not just a simple line,
but it's still the residual.
You can just think of it in your mind as
that D value, but just keep in mind that
we are looking at multiple variables,
so that room size, that crime rate, etc.
So what a residual plot is a graph to show
the residuals on the vertical axis and
the independent variable, in this case
the price, on the horizontal axis.
So if the points and residual plot are
randomly dispersed around the horizontal
axis, a linear regression model
is appropriate for the data.
Otherwise a nonlinear
model is more appropriate.
So residual plots are a really nice way
to visualize the errors in your data.
And if you've done a good job,
then your data should be randomly
scattered around line zero.
So if there's some sort of
major structure or pattern,
that means your model's
not capturing something.
And there may be an interaction between
two variables that you're not considering.
Or you might be measuring
some time-dependent data.
So if this is the case,
you gotta go back to your model and
check your data set closely.
So, to learn a little more about the
residual plot, I left this nice link here,
and if you click it here,
I encourage you to read this,
it's basically why you need to check your
residual plots for regression analysis.
So this is what we're hoping
our residual plot looks like So
we have that residual and then we
have our prediction or fitted value.
And you can see they're kind
of randomly scattered about.
That's exactly what you're looking for
to know that your regression
was the right choice.
If you get something that
looks a little more like this,
you can see it almost
has a structure to it.
Almost like a squared function or
something like that.
Then you know this residual plot is
telling you that regression
was not the way to go.
So I encourage you to go ahead and
read through this article, and
it gives you a really nice understanding
of what we're actually doing here with
this residual plot.
So once you read that, come back and
we'll do the live coding.
So go ahead and
pause the video if you want and
check out that link, but in this case,
I'm just gonna continue.
So, what we're gonna do is
make that scatter plot or
that residual plot for the training data.
So I'm gonna say train equals
plt.scatter.
And I want my prediction data for
my training set.
And then what I wanna do is on the y,
is do my prediction training
minus the y training.
That residual value.
So remember that was
the definition of our residuals.
I'm going to set the color to blue,
just so my passing c equals the string b.
I'm going to say alpha = 0.5.
So hopefully you remember from
the visualization lectures,
alpha's just how see through something is,
and then I'm gonna set
a scatter plot with the testing data,
so I'm gonna say test plt.scatter.
And in this case, we're gonna do the same
thing, but with our testing data.
So we have our test prediction,
that pred test object we made, and
then I'm gonna say prediction test
minus the Y test, so that residual.
And I'm going to color this red.
And again, set alpha to about half way,
see through.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going
to plot a horizontal line access at
line equals zero.
And I can do that by calling plt.
H lines, so horizontal lines.
Set my y equal to 0 as an argument, and
the I'm going to set an x min and x max,
you'll have to play around and see what
the correct x min and x max are for you.
Finally, I wanna label my plot.
I'll give it a legend.
I'll have the legend be equal to those
train and test plots I just made.
So if you noticed, I set those
plots to objects, and I did that so
I can actually make a legend for them, and
then you'll also pass a tuple
argument here in your legend.
And you can go ahead and
just look up MatPlotLib
legend on the documentation to get all
the different things you can pass here.
But in this case, I just want to
pass two things: training and test.
And I'll set the location of
this equal to lower left.
And you the documentation and
set up the legend wherever you want.
Scroll down a bit and then finally my
plot title equal to residual plots.
Okay, and there you have it.
So if you notice,
my horizontal line value was
actually not big enough as far as the x
max, so let me go ahead and change that.
Looks like it goes up to 40.
And there we go, this is a little better.
So If you notice here, for the most part,
it looks like there
isn't any major pattern.
There's maybe this kind of line here
that's interesting to look at, but really,
if you think about how many data points
we had, we had over 500 data points.
Quite the majority is just scattered
randomly around this horizontal line.
So that's exactly the kind
of thing we're looking for.
So, it might be interesting to check out
what these variables were if you take out
certain features.
Does this line go away?
That's definitely something to consider
as you move on further in data science.
But as far as was the regression
the right choice?
Definitely.
Looks like this residual
plot supports that.
So, that's actually it for
this lesson in linear regression.
Linear regression is a super broad topic.
There's actually much more to it
than just our simple analysis here.
So there's tons of great information
on the scikit learn documentation.
So I encourage you to check out this
link that I left at the bottom here.
And if you check it out here, it'll go
over tons of generalized linear models.
So we went over.
Right here,
the ordinary least squares method.
It gives you a little example here,
but there's actually tons of
different types of regressions.
There's lasso, bridge regression, and
you can just keep going and scrolling
down, elastic net, multi-task lasso.
Least angle regression is another one,
and then different types of lassos.
So, there's a lot of information here and
documentation.
Like I said earlier, the scikit learn
has pretty amazing documentation and
there's examples for most everything here.
So I really encourage you to check it out.
As well as this linear
regression example here,
in case you want more examples as far
as linear regression is concerned.
But for now, I'll stop the video here and
let you explore on your own the different
worlds of linear regression.
And thank you so much and
congratulations for
finishing your first machine
learning lecture exercises.
All right guys.
Thanks, and
I'll see you at the next lecture.