Hey everybody.
In this video we're going to be
going over the Poisson distribution.
So before you check out this notebook
I suggest you learn about the binomial
distribution first.
Once you check that out come
back to this video and notebook.
So, Poisson Distributions focuses
on the number of discrete events or
occurrences over a specified interval.
So over a specified amount of time or
distance.
So what we're going to do in this notebook
is just look at the formal definition,
get a breakdown of what that actually
means, and then see an example.
Look at some of the characteristics
such as the mean and
standard deviation and then see how we
can use si pi to look at all of that.
Okay, so the formal definition is
that a discrete random variable,
x has a Poisson Distribution
with a parameter lambda.
If for k equals Zero, one,
two, et cetera, et cetera.
The probability of that mass
function of x is given by, so
here's the pmf for
the Poisson Distribution.
So the probability of x equal
to k is equal to lambda
to the power of k e to the power of
negative lambda over k factorial.
So e is equal to 2.718,
et cetera., et cetera,
to infinite amount of numbers, and
then k is the factorial, k factorial.
Okay.
So, Poisson Distribution has
the following characteristics, so,
it needs to have discrete outcomes.
So x in 0, 1, 2, 3,
just like the binomial distribution.
The number of occurrences can range
to zero to infinity, theoretically,
and you'll see what I mean by that in
a sentence, or in a second, excuse me.
It describes the distribution
of infrequent or rare events.
Each event is independent of other events.
And it describes discrete
events over an interval.
So it's just time or distance.
And the expected number of occurrences,
or E(X),
are assumed to be constant
throughout the experiment.
So I know that's a lot but
that's all pretty formal stuff.
So let's go ahead and
look at an example and
see what that actually breaks down like,
in an example problem.
So, what does an example
question look like?
Let's say the McDonald's has a lunch
rush from 12:30pm to 1:00pm.
And from looking at customer
sales from previous days,
we know that an average of 10 customers
enter during 12:30pm to 1:00pm.
So what's the probability the exactly
7 customers enter during lunch rush?
And then we'll also ask what's
the probability of that more than ten
customers arrive.
We can begin by thinking about
how many customers we expect
to come into McDonald's during lunch rush.
So we're actually already given
the information, it's ten.
This means that the mean is 10, and
that our expected value E(X)=10,
so excuse me for
writing a exclamation point there.
I just got excited.
It's not actually a factorial.
Okay.
In the Poisson Distribution,
this is Lambda.
So the Lambda is the mean for
a Poisson Distribution and
it's the expected number of occurrences
over the specified interval.
So, now that we know what Lambda is,
we can plug that information into pmf,
the probability mass function and
get an answer.
So let's use Python to see how that works.
And we'll start of by
answering the first question.
What's the probability that exactly
seven customers enter during lunch rush?
A quick note,
when you're working with Python,
don't use lambda as an object name.
It's already used for
special lambda functions in Python.
So, in this case,
setting lambda I use the object name lamb.
So, lambda's equal to ten.
Since we know That on average,
ten customers enter during lunch rush.
And we set K equal to seven,
since we want to know
what's the probability that exactly
seven customers enter during lunch rush.
I'm going to set up E and
factorial math statements.
So from math, I'm importing
the exponential and factorial.
And then from the future
I'm importing division, so
I don't have to worry about
floating point numbers.
And then I'm going to plug that
all in to that probability math
function we saw earlier.
And then I'm going to print it out,
times a hundred in percentage form.
So now I see there's a 9.01% chance
that exactly seven customers
show up at lunch rush.
So that's how we create the PMF manually.
But we can also do it
automatically with SciPi.
So from SciPi.stats,
you can just import poisson.
So we set our mean equal to ten.
So I'm going to say mu is equal to ten.
Customers for the lunch rush.
Remember that was just
equal to lambda as well.
And then we can get the mean and variance
by calling .stats method on the poisson.
So I can say poisson.stats import lambda,
and, set mean and variance equal to that.
So I can get the mean and
variance out of that.
I can also calculate the probability
mass function at certain points.
So for instance we wanted to know what are
the odds of exactly 7 customers arriving.
So I can pass the argument
7 Into the .pmf method.
So go ahead and
just print out those statements.
And we'll see that there's a 9.01%
chance that exactly 7 customers
show up at the lunch rush and
that the mean is 10.00.
So that's awesome,
because our manual results match up
perfectly with scipy's built-in
stats distribution generator.
Great.
So, instead of having to
write all this out, manually,
you can just use scipy.ststs and
import Poisson, great.
So what if I wanted to see
the entire distribution?
So we're going to need this information
to answer that second question.
And the second question was,
if we scroll back up here,
what is the probability that
more than ten customers arrive?
So if you scroll down here we want
to see the entire distribution, so
let's get the PMF and plot it out.
So first, the PMF looks like this.
We're going toa import numpy as np.
And let's see the PMF all
the way to 30 customers.
Remember theoretically an infinite number
of customers can come during lunch rush.
It's super unlikely, but
it's technically possible that
an infinite number of customers
come in during that lunch rush.
So I'm going to see the odds all
the way to 30 customers then I'm going
to say an average of ten customers for
the time interval.
So I'll set lamb = 10 again.
And the pmf will use the plot so
I'm going to say poisson.pmf.
And pass k in lambda arguments and
set that equal to
an object called pmf_pois.
And now if I want to plot it,
I can just simply say,
import matplotlib.pyplot as plt.
I'll import seaborn as sns.
And then remember if we want to see
the matplotlibs output inline your
notebook, you have to use
this special magic commands.
And then when you simply
just call that bar plot.
Plt.bar With k and pmf_pois.
And this is our output.
So now we see the probability
distribution for up to 30 customers.
So you can see as you
basically pass around 22-ish,
you get very, very,
very small probabilities.
And you can barely see them on this graph,
that that many customers arrives.
And that makes sense since
our average was ten.
So what's the probability that
more than ten customers arrive?
So in order to do that we would just need
to sum every value of the bars past ten.
We can just do this automatically using
a Cumulative Distribution Function,
also known as CDFs.
And this describes a probability that a
random variable x with a given probability
distribution, which is
the Poisson in our current case,
will be found to have a value less than or
equal to x.
So you can think of it as it's just
accumulating all the probability.
So it's just summing that all up.
So what this means is if we use
a CDF to calculate the probability.
of ten or less customers showing up,
we can take that probability and then
subtract it from the total probability
space which is always just one.
The sum of all probabilities for
every number of customers.
So, we're going to use scipy built in cdf.
So, again, I'll set k,mu.
So, K = 10 for ten customers, and the mean
is ten for the average of ten customers
during lunch rush and then I'm going
to say an object, the prob up to ten.
So the probability of up to ten customers
or less show up is polsson.cdf.
So the cumulative distribution
function with the arguments, KMU.
And now I know that
the probability of that ten or
less customer showing up is 58.3% but
remember the question was more than ten.
So, that's just going to be equal
to one minus probably up to ten.
So I'm going to say
the probability of more than ten,
equals one minus probability up to ten.
So I'm sorry for
these long object names but
I just want to make this really
clear what I'm doing here.
So now to answer that second question,
the probability that more than
ten customers show up during
lunch rush is 41.7%, great.
So that's just a quick overview.
Take your time and
go through the notebooks yourself.
There's a lot of extra stuff written
on them, and they're heavily commented.
This video is just a quick guide for you.
That's the basics of it, so
if you want more information you can check
out these sources here at the bottom.
There's the documentation for scipy,
as well as Wikipedia and Stat Trek for
just basic information on
the Poisson distribution.
Great.
So just remember, if we scroll up here,
the Poisson Distribution has a outcomes.
It's number of occurrences can range from
zero to infinity, theoretically speaking.
Each event is independent
of the other events, and
it describes events over and
interval such as the time or distance.
All right, great.
Thanks guys.