Okay, guys.
This is Lecture 11 now.
And this will be about
Universal Array Functions.
So, let's start off by importing numpy,
as np, Alt+Enter.
And let's go ahead and
make an array to start off with.
We'll just call 11 points and show it so
we can have zero through ten in our array.
So universal functions are basic functions
that you can apply to every value in
an array.
So for instance we can take
square roots by calling np.sqrt.
And we can call it an array.
And now we're taking the square
root of every value in the array.
So if we look at four,
we should have a two there, yep, and
a nine cuz you have three.
Cool.
So what other things can we do?
We could possibly take the exponential
of every value in the array.
So basically have e to the power of
the number, the value point in that array.
So if we run that, that's what we get.
First value makes sense.
Right?
Cuz e to the power of zero is just one.
So that worked out.
There are also binary functions.
Those will require two arrays
cuz of the term binary.
That makes sense.
So how about, in order to see that,
we'll create a random array.
In order to do that,
we'll call numpy, using np.
Then we'll call random
from the numpy library.
And then we'll call a random normal
distribution, and we'll have it be 10.
And let's go ahead and see that array.
And if you don't quite get
what we just did here,
we'll being going over it a lot
more throughout the course.
So don't worry about that too much.
Let's go ahead and Alt+Enter.
Cool.
So, now we have our array,
that's a normal distribution
of some random numbers.
Let's create another one.
np.random.randn of 10.
And let's go ahead and seed that as well.
Cool, there's our other guy.
So in order to do some binary functions.
All that means is functions
that use two arrays.
So for instance, adding arrays.
So this will add every
value A to every value B.
So this first value of A to
this first value of B.
Let's go ahead and see how that looks.
So we have negative 0.3,
blah, blah, blah, plus 0.11,
gets you negative 0.23,
et cetera, et cetera.
Other things we can do is find the max or
min between two arrays.
So in order to do that,
we can say np.maximum,
called two arrays.
And this will find the maximum
between the two array values.
So to see what I'm talking about here.
If we look at our original arrays, A and
B, it will compare
the values at each index.
So the first one was
negative 0.35 in array A,
and 0.11 in array B.
So it's gonna compare those and
see which one was the max and
then set that as the value for
that array you just called.
It's gonna do that for
each of the values comparing A and B.
And you can also check for
minimums just by calling np.minimum.
So, for a full extensive list
of all the universal functions
you can check out the documentation.
So I'm just gonna Edit > Copy and
Edit > Paste the website here.
And again like always,
you can just click on
the links to see the IPython
notebooks from GitHub.
If we wanna see this website, a little
trick we can do is import webbrowser
And then call webbrowser,
to open that website link.
Let's see if that works.
Yep, looks like it did.
So here, all the available math
operations, these universal functions.
So you can add, subtract,
multiply, divide.
Take the log of the sum of the exponents.
Find remainders, find signs.
There's a whole bunch of stuff you can do.
Take square roots, get the squares.
And we'll be using this as we need them.
And you can also do
trigonometric functions.
Get the sines of the values, the cosines,
the arctans, et cetera, et cetera.
The hyperbolics.
And then there's comparison functions
as well, which we'll look into later.
So you can go ahead and check out
the documentation on these universal
functions, in case you're looking for
extra ones or more info.
All right.
So that'll be the end of lecture 11 and
I'll see you at the next one.