Array processing.
In this lecture what we're gonna
do is mesh from those arrays so
we can get a grid plot and
see what that looks like, and
then we'll do some other
processing with arrays,
some statistical processing, and
then just messing around with
some bullion stuff as well.
So this is gonna be a little bit
longer lecture than the last two, but
Let's get to it.
We'll start off by importing numpy as np,
and then we're gonna import matplotlib
and we'll import the pyplot library
from it, and we'll import as plt.
So we're going to do this
because we're going to be
visualizing some of the grids and
meshes we'll be making.
And then in order to see those
visualizations in IPython Notebook,
we need to call matplotlib inline so
we can see it inline for everything.
Alt+Enter, and it's imported it.
Cool.
And, don't worry too much about
the matplotlib in general.
One of the last sections throughout
this course will go into much
greater detail into visualizing data.
So let's start with
the creation of a grid.
We'll do that by setting one
side of the grid, points.
So these'll be the points
along one side of the grid.
We'll do that by calling them np.arrange.
So we can do our start
stop in our step value.
So we'll start at negative five,
stop at positive five and
let's go in steps of point zero one.
Alt+Enter.
Cool.
So we have our points and
then we'll create our grid,
so our grid can be
a points by points grid.
So to show you what I mean by that,
we'll call dx and
dy, and from numpy we'll call meshgrid,
and what this will do is return coordinate
matrices from the vectors we give it.
So the vectors we're gonna give
it is just points by points.
And see what that actually did,
let's go ahead and take a look at dx.
Cool.
And you'll see that dx is basically
a matrix where all the rows go
from negative 5 all the way
to positive five, and
those zero point one steps.
And you'll see that dy
is the same thing, but now it just
goes along the columns instead.
So this will help us make our grid.
So how about we do an evaluating function.
So we'll say that z is
equal to np.sin of dx.
So we'll take the sin
of all the dx values.
If you remember from one of
the previous lectures this
is just a universal function.
Happens to be trigametric,
and we'll do np.sin,
then have all the d,y values too.
And then we'll see what
z actually looks like.
So Alt+Enter, cool.
So these are our
z values and.
We can plot this and
in order to plot this, we'll call plt and
we'll do an image show.
So that'll be imshow, which is a good
way to plot this kind of data,
basically a matrix, so,
we'll call it z to it.
See what that looks like.
Awesome.
So now you can see how this is basically
a sign along both the x and the y.
You can see how it has peaks and valleys.
If you wanna see what these colors
actually mean as far as values,
we can plot it with the color bar.
So let's call let's
call the imshow again.
Plot it with the color bar.
Then the last thing we're going
to do is also give it a title.
So we can do that by saying plt.title, and
we'll say that's the plot for
basically, sin of x plus sin of y.
Forgot to close that string there.
Nice, so now we can get a much
better idea of what this image
is actually showing us.
So we can see the peaks here in red and
the valleys.
The best thing is learning
how to use numpy where,
and in order to do that,
we'll create two arrays,
so let's create an A array, np.array, and
we'll make this just a simple 1, 2, 3, 4.
And then let's also make,
scroll down a bit, also make a B array.
And we'll say this is 100, 200, 300, 400.
That way we can tell the form but
also know which [INAUDIBLE]
values go with which array.
So we'll input those arrays, and
we'll create a Boolean array.
So Boolean will allow us to input true and
false conditions into an array.
So we'll call it condition.
And in this boolean array, what we're
going to do is just input boolean values.
So true, true And false false.
So we have our bullion array now,
and we can use this for
something called a list comprehension.
So what that will allow us to do is
let's say we wanna make an array where
we choose the A value if
the condition is true.
Otherwise we choose the B value.
So to show you what I mean by that,
we'll say
A_val If
condition is met else use the B_val.
Since we haven't defined what A_val or
cond or B_val is we'll say that's for
every a value, B val and cond in,
and we'll use zip to
input multiple arrays.
A B, and condition.
Oops.
Have some invalid syntax here.
4, let's get rid of that.
That actually goes at the end since
the whole answer isn't right.
So Alt+Enter.
Cool.
So, before I I show you the answer,
let's go ahead and
think about it,
see what we should be seeing.
So, answer is,
it's gonna say in this array,
show me the A value if
the condition is met, otherwise,
show me the B value, and
it defines A value, B value, and
condition as each value and
AB and condition array.
So we think about this,
let's see what that first value
of this array should look like.
A value if the condition, so,
it says choose the A value one
if your condition is true,
otherwise, choose the B value.
So you would expect, the first value of
this array to be one because that's true.
And then again if you go along to
the second value of that array A value,
2 if the condition is true.
Otherwise choose B, so
it should be 1, 2 and
then A value if condition, so
on the third one, the condition is false.
So we would expect it to
choose the B value there.
So we should see a 300.
And then last, on the fourth one,
again it's false, so
it's not gonna choose the A value,
it'll choose the B value.
So let's see if we're right.
We should see a 1, a 2, a 300, and a 400.
400.
And that's exactly what we see.
So just take a moment to really
understand what' s going on here.
We're just using a list comprehension to
have a little bit of Boolean logic in this
array for each of these values
in these three arrays here.
Cool.
So now we'll use NumPy where?
So to show you what that looks like,
we'll have another array
called answer2, np.where.
We'll pass the condition and
then we'll say a b.
So what this Numpy where does
is basically the short form
of this long list comprehension array.
So it's gonna say where my condition
is met, choose A, otherwise, choose B.
So, were my condition true,
choose A1, otherwise choose B.
So, we should expect doing this
command to see the exact same thing.
And let's see if that is true.
We'll do Alt+Enter, and
then we'll show answer2.
Yep, and that's the same thing.
So you can see using numpy,
you can get that same kind of logic
in a much more convenient fashion.
So take a moment to see if you
understand what just happened, and
try inputting different conditions,
different array values.
Play with it, see if you can
predict the right arrays that come
up onto the arrays for manipulation.
So from numpy.random,
I'm going to import the normal
random distribution
cuz we'll be using that in a bit and
now I'm gonna make an array.
Now I can just call randn without calling
np.random since I
imported it specifically.
And we'll make a 5 by 5 and let's go ahead
and show what that matrix looks like.
Cool.
So this matrix came from a random
normalized function.
Cool.
So, using this same kind
of where command and
logic, I can say something like
np.where.
We'll have to feed a condition,
so, we'll say where the array or
this matrix was less than 0,
make it a 0, otherwise,
leave that array value.
So, we have our condition.
The first option to replace it,
otherwise do that.
So, let's go ahead and see what happens.
Cool.
So if you look on the original array,
everything that was negative is now a 0.
So this is a useful tool if you
ever wanna clean up your data.
It's also used in Pandas, which is
a module we'll be learning about later.
And it's just a useful thing to
keep in the back of your mind.
Let's create another array to go deeper
into some other statistical
processing stuff we can do.
So we'll have np.array, and
let's make it 1, 2, 3.
Let's have it be a 3 by 3,
and then we'll say 4, 5, 6.
And then that last row will be 7, 8, 9.
And let's show it just to see
to make sure we did it right.
Yep, so it's a 3 by 3, 1,
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
And let's see what happens if
I call sum on that matrix.
I get 45.
so it summed up every
value in that matrix.
I can also do it along a specific axis.
So for instance, if I wanted to
sum up everything in the columns.
So I wanted to sum up 147, 258, 369.
I could say array sum and
specify that axis.
So we'll say along the 0 and
see what happens.
Yep.
And that's what we'd get.
So 1 plus 4 is 5 plus 7 is 12.
So this is just adding it up
along the columns itself.
There are other things we
can call such as the mean.
So this will give us some
statistical information.
So the average of all that is 5.
We can also call the standard
deviation using.
STD we got our standard deviation.
If you want you can also call
the variance using .var.
Do this.
So to show you how this works,
let's go ahead and
make a Boolean array np.array and
we'll have it be,
let's just say True, False,
True, so it alternates a bit.
We'll call that Boolean array.
And we'll call, any on this.
So any is gonna do is it's gonna
return a Boolean, either true or
false, if anything in that array was true.
So since there are trues in there,
we'll expect it to return true.
Let's see if that works.
Yes it does.
Similarly, we can call all.
And this will return true only
if all the values are true.
So we expect it to return false on
the Boolean array since there is a false
there.
And they're not all true.
And that's what we got.
Cool.
Finally you can sort arrays so
in order to see that,
I'm just going to put a little comma here.
So we can know where we are at.
We can say let's make
a array just a random 5.
And then we'll se it.
Alt+Enter.
Cool.
So you see it's not sorted right now.
So, in order to sort it
we can call .sort and
then we'll see what happens.
So now it sorted it
from least to greatest.
I know this is a lot already, but
we're almost done with this lecture.
We can use unique, so,
let's make an array called countries.
And let's say we have France,
Germany, let's get the US
of A in there as well.
Russia, we'll put USA again and
you'll see why in a second,
we'll put in Mexico,
and then finally Germany again.
Let's go ahead and input that.
So now we have this basically
this array of countries.
We inputed a list of countries and
transformed it into an array.
If I wanted to find out which
countries were unique in this array,
I could say I could call
a numpie.unique on countries and
it'll tell me which ones
only appeared once.
So, let's see what happens.
[SOUND] I'm sorry, it will tell
me which unique values you have.
You have 'France', 'Germany',
'Mexico', 'Russia', and 'USA'.
So it will give you each of
the unique values in that.
And last, we can also use an np.in1d.
So this can test the values in one array.
Show you how this works,
let's pass France,
USA, let's call it, I don't know,
Sweden, and countries.
So what this command will do in 1D,
it's gonna check if France, USA, and
Sweden are in this country's
one dimensional array.
So, it's gonna say is France in countries?
Is USA in countries?
Is Sweden in countries?
So, let's think about what it
should output before we see it.
Is France in countries?
Yes.
So it should output true there.
Is USA in countries?
Yes.
It should output true.
Sweden is not in the countries array,
so it should output false.
So we should get an array that says true,
true, false.
Let's see if it works.
Yup.
True, true, false.
All right.
Awesome.
So there was quite a bit in there.
We just learned a lot.
As always,
you can check out the link to the iPython
notebooks on GitHub, and look at them and
play around with some more stuff.
All right.
I'll see you in the next lecture.