Hello, everyone.
In this lecture,
we'll be going over sampling techniques.
So this is a little more
of a nebulous topic and
it doesn't have to do too much
with direct Python programming.
And it's mostly just text and
some equations, so
feel free to just check
out the nbviewer link and
just learn more about basics,
sampling techniques by reading over this.
So I'm just gonna do a quick overview, but
I won't be reading everything here since
you can just read that on your own.
So sampling theory is the study
of relationships existing between
a population and
the samples drawn from that population.
So for example, your population can be the
entire United States while the sample may
be 1,000 people you pulled for a survey
and we'll make sampling techniques and
theories.
So important is you wanna
know what the relationship
is between the sample you took and
the rest of the population.
So, one type of a question you can ask
pertaining to sample theory is whether
the observed difference
between two samples.
So, if you took two polls or two surveys.
If there was a difference
between those two samples,
what are the chances that
it's due to variation or
if it's significant due to statistics.
So these are sometimes known
as tests of significance and
we'll talk about about them later
in another Python Notebook.
So just a quick overview of the topics for
sampling techniques.
There's random samples and numbers.
So samples are chosen, so
they're representative of a population and
one method of doing this
is random sampling.
And you just do this by grabbing
random members of that population.
So, it can be as simple
picking names from a hat or
using pseudorandom number generators.
If you wanna learn more about that and
how Python does its own random stuff,
you can look at the documentation.
There's a link about it here.
You can also do sampling with and
without replacement.
So if you're drawing samples without
replacement from a finite source of
samples, that's considered
finite sampling.
But if your drawing samples from
a finite source with replacement,
you can consider that infinite.
So an example of that would be
tossing a coin n number of times, but
you're basically replacing it,
cuz you keep tossing the coin.
So there's infinite number
of possibilities of series.
Great.
Another one you can do is just
the sampling distribution of means.
So if you draw N samples from
a finite population of Np samples,
where the Np is the greater
than your sample of N and
then you can add specific means and
standard deviations denoted like this.
And that just relates the mean and
standard deviation taken out of your
sample to the total sample population.
So like we said before,
your sample survey and
you can relate that now to
the population of the United States.
And you can also do sampling
distributions of proportions.
So if the population is infinite and the
probability of success is denoted as p and
the probability of failure
is q equal to 1- p,
just like in a binomial distribution,
you condense the sampling distribution
of proportions has mean and
standard deviation that looks like this.
And then sampling distribution
of differences and sums.
So if you're given two sample
populations N1 and N2,
both of which happen to
be normally distributed.
You can obtain the mean and standard
deviation of the sampling distribution
of differences or
sums between the two statistics.
So for differences of statistics,
your means will be the differences in
the means of both statistical sets.
Well, your standard deviation will be the
square root of the sum of the squares of
those standard deviations.
If you're looking at the sum, then it's
actually going to be the sum of the means,
but standard deviation will
follow the same method.
So this is just a very quick,
I know I went through this quickly.
But really, just take the time and
read this yourself.
This is very, just a heavily statistical
analysis of techniques,
especially sample techniques.
You can go ahead and find out more
by checking out Wikipedia here,
just this link on sampling distributions.
Yeah, so go ahead and
take the time to read through that.
There's a lot of information here.
And then check out the last link,
if you have continued interest in
sampling theory and sampling techniques.
Thanks.