Hey guys, welcome to lecture 13.
This lecture will be just a quick
lecture on array input and output.
So how to save arrays and how to open
them, beyond just an IPython notebook.
So we'll start off by
importing numpy as np.
Let's go ahead and do that.
All right.
Let's just create a quick array.
We'll just say np.arange.
Just make it five points.
Take a look at what that looks like.
So we have our array of zero through four.
Five points.
If we wanted to save this array,
all we gotta do is call np.save and
we can save it as myarray and
then choose which array you wanna save.
So the actual object was arr.
And so now that's saved as an array.
To show that it saved this actual array,
let's go ahead and
make another array with the same name.
And we'll have it be ten points long and
show you what that looks like.
So now if I call arr,
it shows a ten-point array of 0 through 9.
Let's make sure that we did actually save
my original array which was 0 through 4.
And if we wanted to load that, we'd
just use np.load, and we call that file.
Now, in order to get the actual file,
you have to use the numpy extension,
which is .npy, so
this was the name of the file.
And then if you want to actually load it,
you gotta call the extension as well.
Let's see if that works, and it did.
Here's our original
array that we had saved.
You can also save multiple arrays, so
for instance, let's say arr1 =
np.load ('myarray.npy'), and
then we'll see what that looks like.
And then let's set arr2 = arr.
Let's go ahead and
see what that looks like.
So now I have two arrays.
If I wanted to save both of them, I can.
I can save them in a zip file.
We're gonna use save again but
this time save with a z, savez.
So this is gonna save as a zip file.
You're gonna name that zip file.
So we'll call this ziparray.
And the file extension you're
gonna use here is npz.
And then you're gonna choose
which arrays to save with it.
So we can call our first one.
We'll just say it's x and
that will be the first array and
we'll have the second one called y.
And that will be array two.
So let's go ahead and see if that worked.
Yep, it did.
If I wanted to load multiple arrays, I
can just do that using the load function.
So let's go ahead and
call it an archive of arrays.
And then I'm going to load
that zip file I just saved.
So it's gonna be ziparray.npz.
And let's see if this works.
So it did.
So let's say I wanted to look at that
first array since I saved it as x,
I can just call it.
Archive_array.
Just call x here, and
there's my first array.
And then similarly I can
call my y, and
I should get the second one, and I do.
So that worked out well.
And then, one last thing.
You can also save and
load text files in case you don't
want to save it as an array.
So let's just make an array.
Actually, let's make a matrix.
Using the array function.
So we'll just have it be a two by three.
So we'll say 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and
then let's just take a look
at what that looks like now.
Cool, we have a two by three.
And if we wanna save it as a .txt file,
a text file, we can say savetxt.
And then we'll give it a name.
We'll just say mytextarray.txt
since it's gonna be a text file.
We'll choose the array or
the matrix we're gonna save it as.
And then if we want to save it as a text
file, we can signify a delimiter.
So what the delimiter is, it's just
basically what's separating each value.
So in your text file, when you see it,
you're gonna see that it's just a bunch of
numbers, and they're all
separated by a symbol, or yeah.
Such as a comma.
So in this case, we'll signify
that the delimiter is a comma.
Just like a comma-separated variable file,
or a .csv.
Let's go ahead and
do that, see if it works.
Yep, cool.
And now let's just take
a look at what we saved.
So if we wanted to load a text file,
you can just say np.loadtext.
And let's load mytextarray.txt and
then I'll signify that my delimiter,
the symbol that's separating each
individual value was just a comma.
And then, let's see what that looks like.
So it says error,
numpy doesn't have a loadtxt.
Oh, text.
Sorry about that.
So it's loadtxt, not loadtext.
So let's try that again.
So we have a TXT file.
It should just be loadtxt.
My apologies for that, and there we go.
Now, it worked.
And these periods here, these dots,
it's just to signify that it's a floating
number, it's not a natural delimiter.
All right, cool.
So just a quick overview,
we learned how to load and
save arrays either as special
NumPy file formats, .npy,
or multiple arrays as .npz.
Or we can also load and
save them as text files, .txts.
And we'll learn more about loading and
other formats in future lectures,
such as Excel files.
I'll see you at the next lecture.