Hello everyone, and
welcome to the second data project.
So in this project, we're gonna be
doing a stock market data analysis.
Okay great.
So I'll be hopping a little bit back and
forth between
the completed IPython Notebook and
the live coding.
So let's go ahead and just check out what
we're gonna be doing in this project.
So in this project,
we're gonna be answering a few questions.
So we're gonna look at
various technology stocks and
the questions we're gonna answer along
the way are what was the daily change and
price and
what's your daily return on average.
So just basic stock information and we're
gonna learn how to use pandas to do that.
Then we're gonna look at what the moving
average of the various stocks for it, and
we'll learn about moving averages.
After that we'll look at different
correlations between different stocks.
So we'll look at the correlation
between their closing prices and
their daily returns and
see if we can get any insights there.
Afterwards, we'll look at how
much value do we put at risk
by investing in a particular stock.
So we'll learn about
the term value at risk, and
learn a little bit about risk analysis for
different stocks.
And finally, we're gonna see if we can
attempt to predict future stock behavior
based on previous stock behavior.
Okay, so let's go ahead and
get started with the coding.
And what I'm gonna do first is I'm just
gonna start off with all my imports.
So here we go, I'm gonna say let's
start off with my data import,
so import pandas as pd from pandas
import Series, DataFrame.
And then import numpy as np.
Go ahead and run that cell.
Now, I'm gonna import my visualization.
Libraries.
So I'll import matplotlib
dot pyplot as plt.
Then import seaborn as sns.
And then, what I'm gonna do
a little differently here is,
I'm going to set underscore
style method on cborne.
I'm gonna pass the string whitegrid,
one word.
And all that's doing is, if you looked
already into the documentation of cborne
in some previous visualization videos,
this is just gonna
give us a nice white grid background for
all our visualizations.
Then finally, in order to see our plots,
in the IPython notebook.
I'm gonna call matplotlib inline.
Okay, great, fantastic.
A couple more imports we have to do for
reading stock data from
the Internet using pandas.
I have to say.
From pandas.io.data, import data reader.
That's gonna allow us to read stock
information either from Google Finance or
Yahoo Finance.
We can actually decide and
we'll show you that later.
Then for time stamps, I am gonna
say from datetime import datetime.
And we'll be using datetime to set
the start and end date of our data grab.
Then finally from __future
future__ import division.
I'm just doing this so I don't have to
worry about floating numbers later on.
Or float numbers, I should say.
If you're using Python 3,
you don't have to worry about that.
That's already taken care of for you.
All right, fantastic.
So let's go ahead and use Yahoo and Pandas
to grab some data for some tech stocks.
So the tech stocks we'll use for
this analysis are gonna be just Apple,
Google, Microsoft, and Amazon.
So I'm gonna make a list,
tech_list equal to, and
now I'm gonna pass all the stock tickers
for the various technology stocks.
So I'm gonna say Apple, AAPL.
Google is GOOG.
Microsoft is MSFT.
And then Amazon is AMZN.
Great.
So now I have a list of technology stocks.
As far as our tickers.
Remember, they all have to be capitalized.
And next I'm gonna set up an end and
start time for DataGrab.
So my end date will be today.
So I'm gonna say datetime.now.
And my start date I'm gonna set it
to be a year ago from today's date.
And the way I can do that is
passing the year, the month, and
the day to daytime of my end date.
End year, end month, end.day.
But since I want it to be a year ago,
I will subtract 1 from my year.
So that allows my start date
to be today's year minus 1.
So exactly one year ago from todays date.
Great.
So, let's make a little for loop for
grabbing some finance data and
setting it as a dataframe.
So, I'm gonna say for stock in tech_list.
So, for every stock to grow
in that list that we made.
I'm gonna set the data frame
as the stock ticker name.
And I can do that using globals.
And I'll explain this in a second.
So, let's go ahead and call stock.
Okay.
And then DataReader(stock) Yahoo
as a string, and
then my start and my end date.
Go ahead and run that.
Great.
So let me break down what I just did here.
So I said for every stock in that tech
list, so for every ticker, Apple, Google,
MSFT, Amazon, let's start with
the right hand side of the equals sign.
I called data reader, and
data reader's gonna take four arguments.
It's gonna take the stock ticker.
It's gonna ask for
what finance website do you wanna use.
You can either use Google,
in this case I'm using Yahoo Finance.
And then it's gonna say what's your start
date, and then what's your end date for
grabbing that stock information.
And then what I did on the left hand side,
it's a bit of a sloppy way of doing this,
but it's quite simple actually.
I'm using globals And what globals does
is it's taking that stock ticker and
making it into a global variable.
Just taking that string, and
And what that allows me to do is this,
is now,
if I call that stock ticker APPL for
Apple, it's my data frame.
And that's what that was doing,
it was setting that string name
as the data frame variable, so
if I also call GOOG, let's say .head.
And there you have it.
So all globals()(stock) was doing
was it was setting that string name
as the data frame name.
All right, great.
So now we have four data frames and
it's all stock information.
So, let's go ahead and
play around with the Apple data
frame to get a feel for the data.
So I'll call AAPL and
I'm gonna call the describe method on it.
So let's go and see what we have here.
We got the opening price, the high,
the low that day, the closing price,
the volume traded that day and
then this adjusted closing price.
And what the adjusted closing price
means is it basically takes into account
any stock changes.
So, if there was a split stock or
something like that.
So it will adjust the closing
price accordingly.
So we're gonna be using this adjusted
close price to do some historical data
analysis.
Most people always use the adjusted
closing price for this.
It just takes into account
any changes in the stock.
All right.
And if we wanted some general
info on our data frame,
we could call the .info method.
And now I can see we have 250 entries so
rows, and there's a total of six columns.
Great.
Okay, so let's just do a little
bit of basic analysis.
We'll see a historical
view of the closing price.
So to do that.
I can just use Pandas.
So I'm gonna call the adjusted
closing price row.
Adj close, column I should say, excuse me.
So, call that adjusted closed column, and
then I can just use the plot
method that Pandas has.
And I'm gonna pass two arguments.
I'm gonna say the legend equals true,
just so we can see a little legend there.
And then I'm gonna set the figsize
equal to a 10 by 4 inches.
You don't have to do this, I'm just
doing this so it's a little readable.
Oh whoops you gotta put
an equal sign there.
Okay and there you have it.
And so we've just successfully mapped
out the adjusted closing price for
a years worth of Apple stock and we did
it in one line which is pretty nice.
So panda is really great for
this kind of financial analysis.
Now let's plot the total volume of stock
being traded each day over the past year.
So I'm gonna call volume.
Column.
And I'm gonna plot that out.
And again I'll set my
legend equal to true.
And I will set the figsize
equal to 10 x 4 inches.
Okay and there you have your
daily volume that was traded.
You can see there was definitely some
peaks where the stocks were really hot and
being traded quite a bit.
Notice the scale here, it's this number
of times 1, 2, times 10 to the 8th, 1E8.
Okay.
So now that we've seen the visualizations
for the closing price and
the volume traded each day.
We're gonna go ahead and
calculate the average, or
the moving average for the stock.
So for some more information
on the moving average,
you can check out the following links.
I'm gonna post them here.
And you can check them out actually,
well let me just hop back to
the completed IPython Notebook.
So we just did all this,
and remember the IPython Notebook
has a lot more commentary.
And we're gonna check
out the moving averages.
So you can check out these two links here,
investopedia.com
And go ahead and
read over these moving averages.
I'll explain it in the next video
when we tackle moving average, but
it's nice just to get a little
bit of an in-depth view of it.
Okay.
So I'll stop this video here now.
And in the next video we'll
go over the moving averages.
Okay.
I'll see you there.