Hey guys, welcome to Lecture 36 and
this lecture will be on Mapping.
So, we're gonna import the usual,
import numpy as np,
import pandas as pd and
then from pandas, import Series,DataFrame.
All right, so mapping is a great
way to add columns to dataframes.
And I'll show you what I
mean by that in a second.
So let's create a dataframe to work with.
We'll say dframe equals,
let's make a DataFrame.
And then we're gonna say,
let's have it be a column for
city, we'll pass a dictionary,
and then this key will have.
I'm just going to get some
information off Wikipedia.
These are some of the highest
elevation cities in the United States.
We got Alma, Brian Head, and Fox Park, and
let's create another entry,
another key in that dictionary.
We'll create altitude.
And here's the altitude for
each of these cities, 3,000 and
this is in meters I believe,
2762, all right.
And then let's go ahead and
show that data frame.
Cool, so now you have a data frame that
has the altitude of the cities, and
the city names themselves.
So let's say you wanted to add
a column to this data frame.
But you wanted to add a column for
each state that the city is in.
So you can use mapping to map the column,
so
that your states match and
map onto your cities.
So I'll show you what I mean by that.
So let's go ahead and create a dictionary.
Say state_map = curly brackets for
the dictionary.
So Alma is in Colorado.
Brian Head
is in Utah.
And Fox Park is in Wyoming.
All right.
So now we have our dictionary state map.
And then let's go ahead and
we'll call dframe.
We'll create a column,
say dframe ['state'] = dframe,
and this is how we're gonna map it.
We are going to say, call the city column,
and then pass the method .map.
And what we're gonna map to it is,
that dictionary we made called state_map.
So what we're doing right now is we're
creating a new column called state, and
we're calling the map method
onto the city column.
So now wherever these cities match
up in our state map dictionary,
it'll add the state into a state column.
So we'll do that, now let's see what our
dataframe looks like by calling dframe.
And so now we have an altitude,
the city, and the state.
And the states have been correctly
matched with their cities.
Cool.
So mapping is a great way to do
element wise transformations and
other data cleaning operations.
There's lots of different ways you can use
this, but as far as the overall method
the simplest way is just creating or
modifying a new column and
then using the .map method to
pass a dictionary object and
map it to a column that already
exists in your data frame.
Okay.
So that's it for mapping.
Next up,
we'll learn how to replace values.
I'll see you there.