Hey, everyone.
So in this video, we're just gonna
be looking over the t-distribution.
This is just part of
small sampling theory.
So before you learn about this, you should
learn about the normal distribution.
For previous distributions, your sample
size was assumed large, so N>30.
But for sample sizes that are less
than 30, you're gonna have to use
a t-distribution, which is sometimes
known as a student distribution.
So the t-distribution allows for
a use of small samples.
And the reason it can do this is it
does it by sacrificing certainty
with a margin of error tradeoff.
So the t-distribution takes into account
the sample size using n-1 degrees of
freedom, which means there's gonna
be a different t-distribution for
every different sample size.
So if you see the t-distribution
against the normal distribution,
you'll notice the tail ends increase and
the peak gets squished down.
Almost as if you have a larger standard
deviation than a normal distribution.
So what's really important to
know is that as your end or
your number of samples gets larger, the
t-distribution eventually will converge
into looking like a normal distribution.
And that cutoff occurs at about 30,
which is why when you have less than 30,
you should be using t-distribution above
that, it's okay to use the normal.
It really depends on your particular case.
So to further explain degrees of freedom
and how it relates to t-distribution,
you can think of degrees of freedom
as an adjustment to the sample size,
such as n-1 and this kind of connected to
the idea that we're estimating something
of a larger population.
And in practice, it gives us lightly
larger margin of error than the estimate.
So if you define this
new variable t as such,
it's analogous to the z
statistic given by this
equation here that we used
in the normal distribution.
So the distribution for a t or
a student distribution can
be obtained using this formula and
this gamma function is
defined as this here,
(n-1) factorial and v or mu,
depending on what you wanna call it is
the number of degrees of freedom and
is typically equal to
n-1 in t-distributions.
Similar to a Z-score table
with a normal distribution,
there is a t-distribution uses a t table
and knowing the degrees of freedom and
the desired cumulative probability.
For any example,
where your probability is greater than or
equal to t, you can find the value of t.
So you can,
here's an example of a lookup table link.
So if I just click this,
open it in a new tab.
This is what it looks like.
So here, you have your one tail or
two tails.
That just depends if you're looking
at the whole distribution or
half of distributions and then your
degrees of freedom on the left column and
then your cumulative probability
that you're looking for.
So what's your confidence level?
Does it fall between 90% of all values?
Et cetera, et cetera.
And you can use that table or
there's also online calculators.
So go ahead and
read up on the t-distribution.
If this wasn't enough for you,
you can check out the links down here for
the t-distribution.
And then real quickly,
I'll show you how we can get
the t-distribution in Python using psi pi.
So just like before,
I'm gonna import matplotlib.pyplot as PLT,
matplotlib in line to see the plots and
then from the stats library,
what you're gonna do is import just t.
That's all it is.
And then from numpy,
let's import numpy's np.
So, I'll create the x range.
In this case, I'll go from -5 to 5 and
I'll do it using linearly
spaced 100 digits there and
then I can just create a t
distribution of psi pi.
So in this case,
I'll I'll have that value be 3.
Three samples there and
then I can plot the PDF
versus the x range here.
And I do that just by saying, plt.plot
x and then I call that probability
density function, the rv, distribution
I just made for all the x values.
So go ahead and
take a look further into this.
Make sure you understand how it works.
And as an exercise to you,
what you should do is plot the normal
distribution versus the t-distribution and
then test out as you increase
the value of n for the t-distribution.
As it goes past 30, go ahead and see how
it converges to the normal distribution.
So again, there's additional resources
to be found at the bottom of this link.
Go ahead and check it out there.
Thanks, guys.