Hi everyone, my name is Kesha Williams, and welcome to my course,
Building Microservices REST APIs Using Spring Data REST.
I am a software engineering manager at Chick-fil-A.
Spring Data REST is one of Spring Data's most timesaving features.
It is a module that allows application developers to quickly port an existing
Spring Data repository to the web as a RESTful microservice.
In this course,
we are going to learn how to quickly standup RESTful
microservices without any extra coding or configuration.
It is actually pretty amazing.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include: exposing your
application's domain model using microservices,
designing a system using the microservices architecture,
modeling complex entity relationships, implementing custom search APIs,
and writing effective integration tests and generating documentation.
By the end of this course,
you'll have a solid foundation for developing
microservices using Spring Data REST,
and transitioning huge monoliths to the microservices architecture.
Before beginning the course, you should be familiar with Spring Data and Java.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn Spring Data REST,
with the Building Microservices REST APIs Using Spring Data REST course, at Pluralsight.