Standard CRUD functionality repositories usually have
queries on the underlying data source.
But with Spring Data, declaring those query methods become a multistep process.
Since we've already declared an interface extend in JpaRepository,
the next step would be to declare query methods on the interface.
I've added three methods to our ticket repository,
which I'll show you in a moment.
The next step would be to set up Spring to create
proxy instances for those interfaces,
which I've already done using the repository configuration file,
which we will also look at; and lastly,
the query is created behind the scenes using the method name by
essentially using everything after findBy,
so let's look at that.
There are three custom finder methods that I've added to our ticket repository.
The first is findByDescriptionIgnoreCaseContaining,
which is a finder method to search by description.
The second method is findByApplicationId,
which searches by the application ID, and then lastly,
findByTitleIgnoreCaseContaining, which is a finder method to search by the title.
The RepositoryConfiguration. java file configures Spring to create proxy instances for those methods.