So let's jump right into the demo.
First,
I will show you how I created modules to represent the
ApplicationCatalog and UserManagement microservices.
I will show you how to edit the run configuration for each microservice.
Then we will configure H2, and lastly,
we will test our new microservices from Postman.
Because we need to start adding additional microservices,
I've reorganized the IntelliJ project a bit.
I've separated each microservice into its own separate IntelliJ module.
We have the ApplicationCatalog module, the TicketManagement module,
and the UserManagement module.
So let's look at these modules in the project structure dialog.
So for example,
let's look at our ApplicationCatalog microservice; notice all
of the dependencies on the dependency tab.
If there's an additional dependency that you need to add,
simply click the plus sign here and add your dependency.
Notice,
I've added the three microservices into one parent
module called REST microservices,
this is just to better organize the microservices.
And then let's close this, let's do cancel,
and then just notice for the ApplicationCatalog module,
I've changed the name of the main application class from
BugTrackerApplication to ApplicationCatalogApplication,
and so I did that for each module, it just helps keep track of things.
Notice for the TicketManagement module,
I renamed the main class to TicketManagementApplication,
so there again it just helps me keep track of the different modules.
I did not want the main class for all of my microservices to have the same name.
So what I did next, I created run configurations for each module.
So let's take a look at one of them.
So here for the ApplicationCatalogApplication,
this is the run configuration, it's pretty straightforward,
notice I'm using the ApplicationCatalog module,
Java 9.
0.
What I do want to point out here is notice I've changed the server port,
and so this is important because I want all three of my
microservices to be able to run at the same time,
and so now I have each of them running on a different port.
So for the ApplicationCatalog microservice, it's set to run on port 8081.
Let's look at UserManagement.
Notice for UserManagement, I have the port set at 8082,
and for TicketManagement I did not pass in a value so it's
going to run on the default port of 8080.
So let's close this, and let's run our microservices.
So first let's run ApplicationCatalog, let's run UserManagement,
and let's run TicketManagement.
So notice if you look down here in the bottom pane,
we have three different windows that represent each
microservice; so ApplicationCatalog has started,
UserManagement has started, and TicketManagement has started,
and I do want to point out, under ApplicationCatalog,
I did make another change.
Under the resources,
I removed the custom database URL for the H2 in-memory database,
I removed what was there before and I'm just taking the default,
and I will show you a demo of that.
So we have our three microservices up and running,
so let's look at them in Postman.
Remember our UserManagement service is running on port 8082, so let's test that.
Let's click send, and so this just returns a list of people.
Now notice our ApplicationCatalog microservice is set to run on port 8081,
so let's click run, and here it just returns a list of applications,
and remember our TicketManagement service,
it's the one we've been using this entire time,
it's set to run on port 8080.
So let's click send,
and there we have three microservices running at the same time.
Now,
I do want to point out that the connection URL for the H2 in-memory
database for each microservice is now the default connection URL and
the port for application and UserManagement,
they've changed.
So let's look at that.
Let's bring up the web browser.
So here this is the connection URL for the
TicketManagement service because it's port 8080,
and notice the default JDBC URL, and let's click connect,
and notice we have our ticket table.
Let's see what's in our ticket table,
and now let's look at our application table.
Now remember that's set to run on port 8081,
so let's bring that up, and again, using the default JDBC URL,
let's click connect, and now we have our application table,
and lastly, let's look at our UserManagement service,
that's the one that we have running on port 8082.
So let's look at that.
Again, the JDBC URL, click connect, we have our person table,
and there you have it.
To recap what we saw in the demo,
we created new modules to represent each microservice,
we added each module to a parent for the entire group,
we set up each microservice to run on a different
port so they can all run at once, and lastly,
H2 now uses the default database URL.
The ApplicationCatalog microservice runs on port 8081, and this is the URL.
The TicketManagement service runs on port 8080, and this is the URL. The UserManagement microservice runs on port 8082, and this is the URL.