Paging and sorting is easy when using Spring Data's
PagingAndSortingRepository; however, up to this point,
we've discussed the CrudRepository and shown examples using JpaRepository.
What are the differences and how do they all fit together?
The JpaRepository extends the PagingAndSortingRepository,
and the PagingAndSortingRepository extends the CrudRepository.
CrudRepository provides CRUD functions.
PagingAndSortingRepository provides methods to do
pagination and sorting records, JpaRepository provides JPA related methods,
such as flushing the persistence context,
and deleting records in batch.
Because of this inheritance relationship,
the JpaRepository contains the full API of
CrudRepository and PagingAndSortingRepository,
which works for our needs.
Let's look more closely at the PagingAndSortingRepository,
which adds two overloaded versions of findAll,
which will be very useful to us; findAll takes a pageable object
and returns a page of entities meeting the paging restrictions
provided in the pageable object; findAll returns all entities sorted by the given options.