Spring Data REST is a part of the umbrella Spring Data project,
and makes it easy to build hypermedia driven REST web services
that connect to Spring Data repositories.
At the heart of Spring Data REST lies the need to expose data in one system
to another system as a hypermedia driven HTTP resource.
So when you think about Spring Data REST from a conceptual standpoint,
think about it in terms of it being a combination of Spring Data and REST APIs.
So this means you're existing Spring Data repositories can be
exposed as hypermedia driven RESTful web services.
Similar to Spring Data JPA,
which exposes APIs to access data in relational databases,
Spring Data REST builds on top of the repository abstraction,
and exposes data in relational databases via HTTP.
So what is a hypermedia driven RESTful API?
According to Roy Fielding, who first published the REST API specification,
an API's not truly RESTful unless it follows a uniform interface.
One of his constraints for a uniform interface is followed when
Hypermedia As an Engine of Application State,
or HATEOAS, is employed.
A RESTful API should do more than expose resource endpoints over HTTP,
it should also expose the API's documentation and
automatically provide navigation between resources.
Hypermedia driven APIs accomplish just that.
This is an example of TrackZilla's Hypermedia Driven APIs,
localhost:8080/profile is an active lent to the
documentation's API exposed by the microservice.
Spring Data REST employs the Hypermedia Application Language,
or HAL, standard to associate resource objects to one another.
Spring Data REST APIs are hypermedia driven out of the box,
no extra configuration needed.
What do you need in order to use Spring Data REST?
You should be using Spring Data repositories, such as the CrudRepository.
These are looked for at application startup.
Spring Data REST takes a way a lot of the manual work
usually associated with writing APIs,
and makes implementing basic CRUD functionality for web applications very simple.