The configuration of Swagger mainly centers around the docket bean.
I've created a configuration for the docket bean in the SwaggerConfig.
java.
So let's look at that now in IntelliJ.
So here is the SwaggerConfig file.
Swagger 2 is enabled through the @EnableSwagger2 annotation on line 22.
This configuration is enough to integrate Swagger 2
into existing Spring Boot projects.
For other Spring projects, some additional tuning is required,
and notice on line 23 the @import annotation imports the
SpringDataRestConfiguration to the API documentation,
and on line 26, this is where I configure the Docket bean.
There are some additional configurations within this
bean that we'll look at later.
Now the docket bean must be configured for each microservice independently. I'm walking you through the ApplicationCatalog microservice configuration.