This course is about building microservices REST APIs using Spring Data REST,
but it is not the best starting point if you are just getting into Spring,
Spring Boot, Spring Data, and microservices.
This course assumes viewers are proficient with the use of
IntelliJ or another Java IDE and Java 8.
At a minimum,
you need to have a thorough understanding of Spring
Data to be successful in this course, which includes JPA.
Fortunately, the Pluralsight library has several of these courses.
I would recommend the following courses for students to begin the
beginner level understanding required for this course.
Along with the basic knowledge highlighted in the learning path,
there are prerequisite tools needed on your machine: JDK 1.
8 or later, a favorite text editor or IDE,
for this course I will be using IntelliJ.
Maven 3.
0.
Maven runs in your IDE, but you can also run it from the command line,
which will require you to install Maven on your machine. Git, and Postman.