We've seen that Spring Data REST is a good way to abstract
away simple RESTful CRUD boilerplate code,
but sometimes you need to step in and override one of the request
handlers to do something slightly different.
In this case,
have the ApplicationCatalog service call the UserManagement service to get
the name and the role of the owner of the application.
The way to write a custom handler for a specific resource is to
use the @BasePathAwareController annotation,
which allows us to define a controller which takes precedence over a
repository in the event that both sit on the same path.
We are not using @RepositoryRestController to override the Spring Data
REST response handlers because this adds a new method to the repository
route rather than overriding an existing one. We use @BasePathAwareController to override an existing method.