Spring Data REST recognizes sorting parameters that are
supported by the PagingAndSortingRepository.
TO have your results sorted on a particular property,
add a sort URL parameter with the name of the property
you want to sort the results on.
You can control a direction of the sort by either
appending ascending or descending.
This first example sorts by description descending.
The second example sorts by description ascending.
To sort the results by more than one property,
keep adding as many sort property parameters as you need.
They will be added to the pageable in the order they appear in the query string.
In this example, we are first sorting by description descending, and then by title ascending.