The path is derived from the uncapitalized,
pluralized, simple class name of the domain class being managed.
It also exposes an item resource for each of the
items managed by the repository.
For example, this TicketRepository interface extends the JpaRepository.
For this repository,
Spring Data REST exposes a collection of resources at
http://localhost:8080/tickets/.
For the resources exposed,
we use a set of default status codes; 200 represents OK,
and it's for plain GET requests,
201 Created is for POST and PUT requests that create new resources,
204 No Content for PUT, PATCH,
and DELETE requests if the configuration is set not to return response bodies.
A core principle of Hypermedia As an Engine Of Application State,
HATEOAS,
is that resources should be discoverable through the publication
of links that point to the available resources.
There are a few competing defacto standards of how to represent links in JSON.
By default, Spring Data REST uses Hypertext Application Language,
HAL, to render responses.
HAL provides a set of conventions for expressing hyperlinks in JSON.
With Spring Data REST, the links are contained in the return document. Resource discovery starts at the top level of the application.