In our RepositoryConfiguration.
java file,
we've set up Spring to create proxy instances for the
query methods on the interface.
So now let's look at the query methods.
So let's open TicketRepository.
java, so here in the ticketRepository,
I've added three custom finder methods; findByDescriptionIgnoreCaseContaining,
findByApplicationId, findByTitleIgnoreCaseContaining,
and notice they each take parameters.
The application is already running, so let's test our endpoints through Postman.
So let's invoke our top level search,
and remember this shows all of the endpoints available,
and so here we should see three endpoints that map to
our three custom finder methods, and we do.
So let's invoke a few of the custom finder methods.
So let's click on this, and let's look at the endpoint.
So notice we are using the search URL and we are
invoking descriptionIgnoreCaseContaining,
and we're passing in the description that we're looking for,
and it's urgent.
So we should only see tickets with a description containing the keyword urgent.
So let's click send, and notice all of our descriptions contain the word urgent.
So let's do a quick search using titleIgnoreCaseContaining.
So notice we're looking for the title that contains App12,
that's what we're passing for the title parameter,
and let's click send, and notice we have response with the title containing App12.