So let's see this in action.
In our demo,
we will add a new overriding controller for the ApplicationCatalog microservice,
and that will call the UserManagement service to get
additional details about a person.
I've added a new overriding controller called ApplicationCatalogController.
So let's look at the code for this.
Notice we have a method called getApplications,
we are using the applicationRepository to find all of the applications,
and then for each application, we are calling the getPersonInfo method.
So let's look at that,
and here the getPersonInfo method is calling our UserManagement
service to get additional details about the person.
Here on line 65 I have the URL hardcoded just for testing purposes.
In a real production application you would not want to hardcode the URL,
but notice here it's calling the userManagementService,
and on line 70 and 71, it's pulling out the name and the role,
and it's assigning that on the application on line 72 and 73.
So let's go back up, and then on line 44,
and 45, and 47, we are actually returning that updated list of applications.
Now I do want to show you my application class,
notice I've added on lines 22 and 25,
I've added two transient fields to the application
representing the owner name and the role.
Now these aren't persisted to the database,
they are queried in real time using the UserManagementService.
So let's go back to our application controller.
Now all requests going to applications will hit this controller,
returning the altered data.
Now before we see this in action,
there is another method that I've added to this custom controller that
returns a single application; we will talk about this in the next module
when we look at unit and integration testing,
but I just wanted to point it out now.
So here on line 52,
it's a custom method to return one specific application
based on the ID that's passed in,
and so there again it's going to call the getPersonInfo
adding the owner name and owner role.
So now let's see this in action.
We have to make sure that our ApplicationCatalog microservice is running.
We also have to make sure that our UserManagementService is running,
so let's click on that, and click run, and let's let the two of these come up.
So, UserManagement has started and ApplicationCatalog has started,
let's go to Postman.
Now what you see here is the old call from our previous demo
to retrieving the list of applications.
I do want to point out here on line seven, notice the ownerId is returned.
We do not see the name, and we do not see the role because that's the old result,
so now we've updated it to call that custom controller that will
add the additional information about a person.
So let's click send, and now notice in our result we have along with the ownerId, the ownerName and the ownerRole.