Hey guys welcome back to the artificial dungeon.
It is at four in the toilet.
I'm taking you on a walk through Africa.
How crazy is that.
Now while we're on this quick walk I wanted to also share a few.
A heads up the Eudemus system is very soon going to ask you to leave review for this course.
Now I know it can be difficult to judge the quality and value of a course this early on Homer.
Their system has simply changed and you to me is asking to leave review earlier and earlier on in the
course.
Now with that in mind we're going to ask you to leave a five surface course to go the go go there.
We're not going to ask you to feel sorry for this course but what I would like to ask is that if you're
not familiar with tutorials well enough to read this course a faster course than please scroll through
the topics of this course please have a look at the different artificial intelligence Algren's that
recovery goes into reinforcement learning CULE learning deep learning deep convolutional key learning
and even cover A-3 see and hopefully also you see all of these different and exciting things that you'll
learn as course.
It will give you the confidence to write this course of course.
If on the other hand you think that there's something wrong with the course if you're unsatisfied about
something then please do let us know before you rate the scores.
You can contact the superdense and supporting directly where you can leave as a short message in the
course Junee Your feedback is very valuable to us.
We will get back to war.
We will fix up whatever the issue is and then get back to you and hopefully that will give you the conference
or at this course of our course.
Now on that note if something's wrong of course then please do let us know.
Or another hands if you feel that everything is great for course if you're excited about the journey
ahead.
And if you're enjoying these tutorials if you feel that this a five star course then please do read
it appropriately so that the rest of the world will also know that this is a five star course on artificial
intelligence and they can learn everything they need to get started in the space.
Thanks so much guys for being part of artificial intelligence.
It is a very excited to have you on board and super pumped about the journey ahead of you and I look
forward to seeing your browser tutorial.
Until next time in Jarad a visual.