Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
In today's tutorial we're going to discuss the plan of attack for this amazing section on the most powerful
Ogger algorithm in artificial intelligence which is A-3 see at the moment.
So let's have a look.
Today we'll talk about the following things.
We'll start with the three A's of A3 C.
So we'll talk about what the abbreviation stands for and how are we going to deal with the three A's
and also we'll look at the actual article or the actual research paper that gave birth to A-3 see the
deep Google deep mind research paper and we'll have a quick look at it so that you are more comfortable
navigating in your free time.
Plus we will see exactly why the aid through see is the cutting edge most advanced algorithm on the
planet for individual intelligence.
At the moment and why it's so important to have this in your arsenal.
Next we're going to talk about the first day of A-3 which is actually critical.
Well it actually stands for a synchronous advantage active critic algorithm and so we're going through
the A's not in order but we're going through them in an order that makes sense for us that will help
us in our intuitive understanding.
Then we'll talk about the synchronous element in the A-380 algorithm and then we'll talk about that
Wantage and that's the tutorial where we'll put everything together and all start making sense.
So a quick word of caution that as you're going through these you might notice that after the active
critic and even after the synchronous or Tauriel you will still not exactly have the full picture of
full understanding of how this all ties in together.
And that's totally OK because they all these three elements they work in they indeed work together and
they require each other to function.
So just power through it and get to the third tutorial.
And in the Third World the advantage tural that's when it will all come together.
And if at that point you still don't quite understand something then you can just revise that specific
tutorial with this critical synchronous or that vonder tutorial to put all together.
But basically just don't get thrown off if after one of those tutorials you still feel that you need
someone information that's because they all work together to come to a to one function a 3D hologram
that's an advantage Tauriel that all ties in together very nicely.
And then finally we'll talk about some additions that you can add or some additional modules and elements
that you can add today through the algorithm.
The thing is that there's different versions of their algorithms different modifications and already
through the first four literals in the section Mool will we will see somewhat invocations and at the
end we will add in an extra one the long short term memory.
SDM.
Now here we won't go into a lot of detail.
Ellis Tam's that's a topic for another course but nevertheless you will get a overview of what LACMA
is and how those structures are or how those layers in your own networks work so that you have a better
understanding integration of the practical tutorials but very important also.
This will showcase how the A-380 algorithm can be modified to suit certain purposes.
So there we go that's the plan for this section.
Definitely it's going to be an exciting algorithm to look at because it's the top algorithm at the moment
in the world and we're going to be developing an intuitive understanding and then together with Adlon
after this you're going to be coding it which is very very exciting and I can't wait to see on the first
tutorial.
And until then enjoy AI.