Welcome to this module on Integrating AWS CodeCommit with AWS
Cloud9. In this module, we're going to see how to configure
users with the required policies so that they can access AWS
Cloud9. With the right policies,
you will see how to create a development environment,
share the environment with other users for collaborative programming, and
explore various other settings that are offered by AWS Cloud9. Then you
will learn how to connect the CodeCommit repository from Cloud9 environment
and learn how to clone the depository.
Then you will see how to create a branch,
perform changes, and commit the changes back to the repository all
from within the AWS Cloud9 environment. Before we start creating
the environment, let's quickly look at some of the key features of
AWS Cloud9. Traditionally,
developers install IDEs like IntelliJ and Eclipse to set up their build
environment. And every time they change their project,
they need to change their project setup manually.
Since the IDE is installed in a developer's local machine,
the hardware configuration plays a significant role
in a developer's productivity.
AWS Cloud9 overcomes this problem by making your browser as an IDE, and
you can code directly from the browser with the backing of a cloud
infrastructure. With many prebuilt environments that come as part of AWS
Cloud9, you can easily start new projects.
AWS Cloud9 also makes it a breeze to collaborate with other users during your
development process by sharing your environment with them. It provides a
seamless experience in developing serverless applications.
You can create a new function from within the environment, run and debug
it and its related resoursces all by staying in your development
environment. There are many different ways your AWS Cloud9 can be set up
depending on the size of the team.
Let's quickly look at three different setups that are very commonly used.
If you are the only individual using your AWS account, you can use individual
user setup. If you're a student and an individual user,
individual student setup option is available. If you're part
of a team and if all of them are part of a single AWS account,
you will be using a team setup, and this is what you will see in this course.
If you're part of a larger enterprise that has multiple AWS accounts, you'll be needing an enterprise setup.