Welcome to this module of core features of AWS CodeCommit. In this module,
we are going to look at some of the key features off AWS
CodeCommit and what makes it a serious contender for a
cloud‑based source control system, among others.
We will log into AWS Console and create an empty repository to begin with.
Start adding files, make changes to them, create branch, perform
pull request, and merge the changes back to master.
Not every day you will be creating a repository from scratch.
Most of the cases the project team will already be using one.
We will see how to migrate an existing Git repository to AWS
CodeCommit and create users and groups in AWS IAM and set up access
control to the repository that we are creating.
Before we jump into the specifics,
let's get acquainted to two important characters who will
play an active role in this course.
First, let's meet John, he is a project manager for Globomantics,
and he was instrumental in saving the infrastructure cost by
successfully migrating their on‑premise infrastructure to AWS.
Now, he is actively exploring other cost saving measures and cloud integration.
Steve is a team lead who works for John.
After a brainstorming session with Steve,
he finds out that AWS also offers rich development tools that can be
used for the development and delivery process.
He is currently assigned with the task off migrating the current
development tools to AWS. Let's take a look at the current development
tools that are being used by Steve's team.
They're using IntelliJ as their IDE and Git as a source control repository.
Jenkins is used for building and deploying purposes. As part of migration
process, Steve's proposal is to use AWS CloudNine as the IDE, AWS
CodeCommit as a version control repository, and AWS CodeBuild and
CodeDeploy for continuous integration and delivery.
In this course,
our focus will be on AWS CloudNine, AWS CodeCommit, and AWS CodeStar. AWS
CodeStar is another service provided by AWS that offers predefined
project template and a tool chain that enables the entire life cycle of
software development from code creation to deployment. Let's look at some
off the features of AWS CodeCommit. Since this is a cloud‑based service
hosted by AWS, CodeCommit provides a highly available and secure
repository.
As your project gets bigger, CodeCommit can scale to accommodate your
development needs and it can handle large number of files and maintain
multiple revision histories. AWS CodeCommit has no restrictions on the
size of the repositories or the size of the individual files that are
stored in them.
As you start making changes to your code and create pull requests,
it lets you collaborate with other developers, perform code review, and
merge the changes to the master branch. AWS CodeCommit is integrated
very well with other AWS services, like AWS IAM, AWS CloudNine, AWS
CodeStar, AWS SNS, and AWS Lambda, to name a few.
And you will see that as we proceed further in this course how the
integration happens. Since AWS CodeCommit supports all that Git commands that
developers currently use, the learning curve is very small and you can use the tools that you are already familiar with.