Hello there.
Welcome to the module of Monitor and Troubleshoot
AWS CodeCommit. In this module,
we will see how to set up notification rules to alert your
dev team once a developer makes any changes in the
repository, like checking in the code,
creating or deleting a branch, and so on. Many a times we may need more than a
simple notification. We may need to trigger downstream builds or other processes
when a change happens in the current repository.
For cases like these, AWS allows us to create triggers.
You can write a lambda function and have CodeCommit call this lambda function
when that specific action occurs. We will see how to write a simple lambda
function and set up a trigger to invoke this function. One of the important
requirements for any large enterprise is to maintain an audit trail so that we
can find out who did what action and when.
You will see how CodeCommit API calls are logged in CloudTrail and help
interpret it. Let's see a quick demo and learn how to create a
notification rule in AWS CodeCommit repository.
I just logged into AWS CodeCommit. Choose
Globomantics from the list of repositories.
Click on Settings and then Notifications, choose Create notification rules.
Let me enter Globomantics Notification under the Notification
name, and we have the option to include Basic details or Full
details in the notification message.
I'm going to select Full details. The next section list all the events
for which the notification needs to be triggered.
I'm going to select all. Under targets,we can select the Amazon SNS topic
to which you want to send the notifications. I'm going to select
Globomantics notification that I've already created.
You also have the option of selecting multiple targets if you want the
notification to be sent to more than one place. Click Submit, and you can see a
summary of the notification rule that you just created.
Let's go to SNS Service and check how this topic has been set up.
It shows four topics currently.
Let's select Globomantics notification, and you can see it
doesn't have any subscription set up here.
Click Create subscription, under Protocol select Email, and specify the
email address under Endpoint. Click Create subscription.
You can see the Status is Pending confirmation.
Let me switch to my email client, and here here you can see
the email that I just received from AWS,
asking me to confirm the subscription. Click Confirm subscription.
Once a subscription is confirmed,
you can see that the status is changed to Confirmed status. I'm going to
make a simple commit and test this notification rule. Let's go to CloudNine
console. We are currently in the Develop branch.
Let's open file1.txt, and I'm going to make some changes to this file.
Once completed, save the file.
Let's add the file to the local branch and commit the changes.
Let's push the changes to the remote branch.
I'm going to log back into my email client, and here is a
notification message that is triggered by the notification
rule that we initially set up.
You can see the repositoryName,
the branch name, and the user that performed the change and the type of change, as part of the email message.