In the following lessons, you will learn how to set up G unit in a Maven based project.
If you do not use Maven, then feel free to skip this lessons until you need them in the future.
Because in the following lessons I will also show you how to set up G Unit without using Maven.
All right.
So in this lesson, I will create a new Maven based project using intelligent development environment.
So to create a new project, I will click on New Project Button here in the top right corner.
Then from the left side panel, I will select Maven and will click on the next button to continue.
Here I will need to give my project a name.
For example Calculator Maven Project.
And using the field below, we can specify location where we want this project to be created.
So our copy of the project name and I will click on the folder button to choose a different location,
for example, a different folder and click on Open.
Now I will add forward, slash and paste the name of the project.
Now I will expand artifact coordinates by clicking on it, and we will need to fill in these fields.
Now, the very first one is group and group.
These usually reverse the mean name of your company or a project.
I have a project that is called Apps Developer Blog dot com, so a reverse domain name will be called
IBM's Developer BLOCK.
This.
The man belongs to me.
So I know that my project will not clash with others now.
Next will need to provide a value for artifact ID, which is usually a name of the current project.
So I will keep it as if I'm version of the project.
I will also keep these and will click on the finish button to create this project.
And here I have my new project created.
If I expand source folder, then here I have main folder and if I expand here I have a Java folder for
my application Java code and below on this same level with main folder, we have this folder with Java
folder as well where we're going to create test classes and we have bookmarks.
Example file which is currently opened, we will use this file to manage project dependencies.
All right.
So let's continue.
And in the following lesson will add the needed g.
You need five dependencies to this Java project.