In the following lessons, you will learn how to set them to unit in Gradle based project.
If you do not use Gradle, then feel free to skip these lessons until you need them in the future.
Because in the following lessons, I will also show you how to set up a unit in your project without
using Maven or Gradle.
All right, so in this lesson, I'll create a new Gradle based project using intelligent development
environment to create a new project.
I will click on this new project button that is in the top right corner.
And then from the left side panel, I will select Gradle, will select Java, and then click on Next
Button.
I will need to give my project a lean.
This time I will call it Calculator and Gradle Project.
And if needed, you can change location for this project by clicking on this folder button.
I will delete the location as is and will expand artifact coordinates by clicking on it.
Here we will need to fill in artifact coordinates that will uniquely identify our project.
And the first one is group I.D..
Group I.D. is usually a reverse domain name of your company or of your project.
For example, I have project that is called obstacle per block dot com.
So a river is the main name for this project will be IBM's developer block.
Because this domain belongs to me.
I know that this project will not conflict with other projects.
All right, so then we'll need to provide artifact I.D., which is usually name of the current project.
And that will keep it, as he's called, Co-leader, Green or Project.
And a version of this project I will also leave as is.
I will then click on the finish button to create this project.
We will need to give it a few seconds to finish its setup.
And now one set up is complete.
We have a new project in the source folder.
We have main Java folder for application, Java code and below on the same level with main folder,
we have test folder and in this test folder we have Java folder where we're going to create test classes.
And then we have built Gradle file which is currently opened and we will use this file to manage dependencies.
We do not really have to.
You need to find dependencies which are key.
You need to Peter API and change up their engine.
But in the following lesson we will add a different dependency which is going to be an aggregate of
this tool.