In the following video lessons, we will write test methods that will engage all three layers of our
application.
So this test methods are going to be integration tests because we will not mock and we will not fake
any object behavior.
Our test method will perform a CDP request to trigger code in the controller class and a method in the
controller class will invoke code in the service class and our code in the service class will actually
invoke code in the data layer and our code in the data layer will actually write and read information
from a database table.
This time we will not disable any security configuration, and this means that to communicate with protected
API endpoints, our HTTP request will need to include a valid JWT token.
All right.
So let's continue and let's write a few more integration tests.