In the following few lessons, he will learn how to write unit tests that accept input parameters.
Notice that most of the units that we have written so far, they do not accept any input parameters.
This test method does not accept any input parameters.
This test method does not accept any input parameters and integer subtraction, and it also does not
accept any input parameters.
This is because we do not really invoke unit tests from our own code as we do it with regular Java methods.
And we do not really parse input parameters to unit test methods as we do it with regular GI methods.
But G unit does provide us with a way to invoke test method and make it accept input parameters.
So let's see how it works.
For this demonstration, I will use the integer subtraction method and in its current state this method
will run only one time with a single pair of values.
We have defined menu and we have defined subtree and inside of this method as a local variables.
And then we use these local variables as input parameters into our integer subtraction method, which
is our method under the test.
But we can make our unit around with more input parameter variations than this too.
And to do that, we will need to change our test annotation to be parameter each test.
Like this.
It is still going to be a test method, but it now can accept parameters and to provide multiple different
variations of input parameters.
But we'll need to add in another annotation and it is called method source.
And in the double quotes provide a name of the method that will be used to provide input arguments.
Let's say this method will be called integer subtraction input parameters.
And now I will need to create a method with this line.
So I will copy its name and I will create a new method.
Now, this method will need to be static and it will need to return a stream of arguments.
I'll make it private.
It will return a stream of arguments and it would need to be called integer subtraction parameters,
just as we named it here in this method.
Source annotation.
Let's define the return value.
And input stream from Java audio stream package and input arguments from work to unit.
Jupyter params provided a package.
Now let's think of arguments that we want our integer subtraction method this one to accept.
We want it to accept monument and we wanted to accept settlement and to be able to compare expected
result with the actual result.
We also wanted to accept the expected result value.
So I will define this as method arguments.
I will define monument.
I will define settlement.
And I will define expected result.
And now I can provide these arguments in the return value of my stream.
33.
As imminent as the first mental argument, then one as second method argument, which is going to be
my set hand, and then expect that the result which is going to be 32 and it is a third argument that
my integer subtraction method accepts.
And now because I do have menu and subtract an expected result defined as method arguments here I can
delete these local warren and from my method.
All right, so let's add a few more arguments.
I will copy and paste this line as a second list of arguments I will provide.
I'd say 24 takeaway one will be 23.
And then one more least of arguments like, for example, 54 and then take away one, it will be equal
to 53.
Whoops, I have actually changed an existing list.
Let's add one more.
This one is going to be 24 as mentioned, one as separate and and then 23 as expected result like this.
All right.
So now if I run this this method, it will run three times each time with a different set of arguments.
First time with this set of arguments, second time with this set of arguments and third time with this
set of arguments.
But before I do, I will have to do this planning of this method, because currently the display name
mentions only one set of parameters with I'm using it with multiple different parameters, so I will
rename it to be something like this.
Integer subtraction.
And then maybe in brackets I will provide menu and.
Sceptre hand and then expected result.
Something like this.
All right.
And now I can run it.
So I will click on the run button which is next to test meant that name.
And now I have the same method executed three times and all have successfully passed mount.
Notice that in the methods or sanitation we have included the name of the method that is being used
as a source of input parameters.
If the name of this method is exactly the same as a test method name to use, it allows us to remove
this name from a method source annotation.
So what I can do, I can delete this name from here, and then I can rename the method source to be
exactly integer subtraction.
So I will rename this myth here to be the same as my G Union test name.
So when these two are the same, two unique knows that they work together and my test method will still
work.
So let's try.
I will save changes and I will run my test method one more time.
And it still works.
And maybe as a final change, I will change this line because currently the heart codes, the values
here.
So I will change 3 to 3 to be admitted argument instead and then take away scepter hand and equals to
expected result.
Like this.
And now if I run it, it should make more sense.
So I'll save changes, and I will run my test method one more time.
Now I have a first iteration with 33.
Take away 1/2 iteration with 54, take a11 and then throw iteration with 24, take away one.
Now I do use System.out.println in my unit test method, but this is just for demonstration purposes.
Usually we do not print anything in the test method, or if we do print something then it should be
temporary and we should not rely on the information that we print using System.out.println in our test
method.
All right.
So this was example of a method that accepts multiple variations of input parameters, and it was pretty
advanced.
Now, there's another way how we can do the same, but by using a different annotation.
Let's have a look at what works in the following lesson.