In previous lessons, you have learned to write unit tests for a regular job application.
In this lesson, we'll talk about unit testing, but this time in a spring boot application.
Now let's say we have springboard application that exposes a few the API endpoints, and this application
has three layers.
The first layer is a web layer or presentation layer where we also sometimes call it UI layer or user
facing layer.
So this is where we have our risk controller class with methods that handle HTTP requests.
For example, one of the methods will be to handle GDB gate request and return a list of users.
There will be more methods that this controller class will have, like for example, a method to create
user and a method to update you the details or delete user details.
But to keep this diagram simple, I will use just one get users method and then we have service layer
where we have users service class.
The service class contains methods that perform main business logic.
Any complex business logic like for example, sorting or filtering will be done in the service layer
class and to do its work, service layer might need to communicate with other sources, like, for example,
with a database.
And this is when our service layer class will involve classes and interfaces from data, where, for
example, in the data layer we will have data access objects or GP repositories to read and write information
into database.
Now let's assume that we need to unit test the git users method because I want to unit test the get
users method only this one single method.
This means that I want to isolate the business logic that is inside of this and get use this method
from all external dependencies.
And this means that I want to isolate the git users method from executing real business logic that is
in a service or in a data layer.
And to do that, I will need to more user service.
And if I mock user service, then users repository will also not be invoked to test my get users method
in isolation.
I will also not start the web server because when I'm unit testing, I'm not sending real requests.
And this means that annotations like risk controller or git mapping, they will also not be involved.
My production application code will have this annotations, but my unit tests will not use them.
In fact, one unit testing code in springboard application we will not even load sprint application
context.
So none of these annotations will really be used, including service annotation in the service layer.
Because I'm not going to start a web server and because sprint application context will not be created
and business logic in other layers like service layer and data layer will not even be involved.
I will be able to unit test my get users method in isolation from all other layers and from all other
dependencies.
So that's unit testing.
But sometimes we do need to test if our code is properly integrated with Sprint framework and this is
when we will start writing integration tests.
So let's continue.
And in the following lecture we will talk about integration testing in Sprint application.