In this lesson, we will run our unit test and we will generate code coverage, report for it.
And to do that, you can open any of your existing projects that have units created.
Now, there are different ways to run unit tests and generate code cartridge report.
And one of the ways is to simply do right mouse click and the open test class and then choose run unit
test with coverage.
If I do right mouse click outside of test method name.
It should go for me to run all unit tests in the selected class with coverage.
And then the way to run unit tests with coverage, I can simply do right mouse click on the test clause
and then choose a run with this selected class with coverage.
Or there's another icon on the toolbar above here.
It looks like a water shield with a play button.
I can click it to execute all union tests in the currently open text class and generate code coverage
reports for it.
Let's try.
I will click on this icon.
Whole unit tests run.
And in the top right corner here, we have a new panel with a code coverage report.
Now, this is the same panel screenshots of which you have seen in previous video that said it displays
code coverage report organized by package, and you can double click on the package to see code coverage
support for each class.
Let me expand the panel a little bit.
So here we have a package name.
We have class method and line section.
And if I go into the package here, I see a list of classes for which we have test coverage, support
on the left side.
And on the right side, we see test coverage report related to each class methods in this class and
lines of code in this class.
And a similar code college report you will see on the left side here in the project panel.
Let's minimize the bottom panel so that we can see it better.
So here we have code college report displayed for those classes that were involved during unit test
execution and classes that were not involved during the test method execution.
They do not have the code coverage report generated.
So user repository and user reports, the implementation do not have a code camera ship or displayed
for them.
Now, if I open one of these classes that does have code coverage report generated for it, for example,
user series implementation, if I open it, then here on the left side panel, I can see green bar for
those line numbers that were executed during unit test execution.
And if there are lines of code that were not executed, then there will be a red bar.
But I don't have any red pass at the moment, so let's create one.
I will type a new method.
For example, public point test.
Or let's not confuse it with test.
Let's call it demo method.
And System.out.println.
For example, that moment.
Not because I did not have a unit test for this.
--, I meant it.
And because this demo method is not called by any other of my methods in this class, if I run unit
tests with coverage, this method should have a red bar indicator on the left side.
Let's try.
So I will run unit tests with coverage again.
And that will minimize the panel under the bottom and I will minimize the, quote, coverage report
panel.
And here is my read bar.
We have green bar indicator for those lines of code that were executed by unit test.
And we have a red bar for those lines of code that were not covered by unit test, which tells me that
this code is not tested and I might want to create a unit test for it.
Now, if you don't like the color used here indicator, then you can change it.
And to do that, it will click on the bar itself and then choose settings icon to edit coverage colors.
And here you can choose a different color for the bar for those lines that were not covered, partially
covered or fully covered.
For example, I will change a color for those lines of code that are fully covered.
And to do that for the foreground option, I'll choose the color option, and that will make it just
a little bit brighter.
GREEN Now I will click on.
Okay.
Will minimize code coverage report.
And now I have a bright green color in the country for those lines of code that are fully covered with
unit tests.
All right.
So now you know how to generate code coverage.
You produce an intelligent development environment, and it should help you find classes and methods
in your application that have not been covered with unit tests.
Now let's continue and in the following lesson, you will learn how to export this report in each HTML
format so that you can share it with your team members or even publish on corporate intranet for others
to see.