In this lesson we will start testing query methods in our GPA repository and I will start by creating
a new test class in the same package.
I o.
I will create a new class.
And I will call it users repository test.
And because I'm going to test only GPA layer of my application, I will annotate this class with the
GPA test annotation.
Like this.
All right, so now I will create a new test method.
Let's input test annotation.
I'm going to test one of the test methods in my user ship history.
So let's have a look at it and we'll scroll up and I will open up users repository.
So here's my users repository and currently it has a few methods.
Most of these methods this three are query methods, meaning that Sprint framework will derive physical
query from the method name.
So for these methods to be able to communicate with a database, we do not need to write a scale query.
Spring Framework will read the method name and it will derive SQL query from the method name.
If the method name is complex, then it is possible that the method does compile and it does work.
But because it is complex, we made a mistake and when we started using it it does not return expected
result.
So it is good to test a method like this.
Most of my methods here are very simple, but since we're learning, we're going to create a couple
of test methods anyways.
So I will start with testing find by email method and I will go to my test class and we'll continue
with the test method name by including into it the name of my method and the test.
So I'm going to test find by email method for a condition.
When given a correct email address, then it should return user entity.
Something like that.
And that will create a range act and insert sections.
All right.
So in that range section, I'll need to prepare objects that are needed to perform this test method.
And with this test, I'm going to test a repository method that tries to find an existing record in
a database.
So for this method to pass my database table will need to have at least one record.
So in the arranged section, I will prepare a user entity object and that will persist it into a database
table.
Now to persist this entity object into a database table.
I need to use test entity manager.
So let's inject it into our class.
And now I will use this test entity manager to persist user entity into a database.
All right, so this was tor one user into a database table.
Now we can try testing if our query method can find this record.
And to do that, I will need to inject into my test class users repository.
Now I can use this user suppository to invoke my method on the test.
So I will use user suppository and I'm testing find by email.
So I will invoke it and I will need to give it email address as a parameter.
So I will use user get email like this and if all is good, this should return me a stored user record.
I will call it the steroid user.
Let's make it a little bit larger.
So we have invoked our method and the test, and now we can validate if the stored user record that
is returned does contain user details that we expect, and we can do it by checking if it contains correct
email address.
So in that search section I will use assertions.
The assertion that I will use will be assert equals expected value I will take from user object and
the actual value I will take from stored user object like this.
So these two must be equal.
Otherwise test method will fail.
And if it does fail, I will display a little message.
Something like returned email address does not match expected value.
Something like this.
All right.
So now we are ready to run this test method and see if it passes.
I'll click on a run button.
And it passes.
Let's try failing it and see if it works as an expected value.
I will provide something else.
Test at test three dot com, something like this.
And I will run it one more time.
And it fails, which is expected.
So let's make it pass again.
And now it passes.
All right.
So it looks like everything is working well for now.
And you now know how to test a very simple query method that you have added to your repository.