Now if we need to test the four get users method is properly integrated with Sprint framework and if
it works well in Sprint web player, we do not want to isolate or get users method completely.
We do want some of sprint framework features to be available to us, but only to a web player.
For example, we do want to test and make sure that gate users method can be triggered by HTTP get request
and that it can read HTTP request parameters.
So in this case we do want annotations like rest controller or git mapping or request mapping to be
enabled and to work.
So we do want actual integration with Sprint framework in the web player.
But because we're not testing other two layers, we are not testing service layer and we are not testing
data layer.
We do not need these layers to be enabled and we do not need them to be loaded into sprint application
context.
And the good news is that Sprint framework does allow us to test each layer of our application architecture
separately and there is a way for us to test web layer separately from service layer and from data layer.
So when we want to test a rest controllers only, we need to work with web layer.
Only other layers will not be involved.
And in this case, Sprint framework will create sprint application context for web layer only and only
those beans that are related to web layer will be created and will be loaded into sprint application
context and beans that are related to data layer.
Like for example, user repository.
They will not be created and they will not be loaded into application context.
So because other layers are not loaded and are not involved, our test will run faster.
The unit test that we will create in this case will be called integration test.
And this is because we are no longer testing the get users method in isolation.
This time we are testing gate users method and it's integration with Sprint framework.