Now that we have created a new Gradle based project.
We can configure it to use the needed unit to find dependencies.
To do that, we will need to open build to create file, which is currently already opened in my development
environment.
And here under the Dependencies section, we have two dependencies already added by default.
Now if you're working with an existing project, then you might not have this dependencies or they might
be of a different version.
So you might want to make sure that these dependencies are key.
You need to find dependencies and maybe empty their version.
So for the test implementation property we need to use, you need five Jupyter API dependency.
And if you have a different dependency here or you need to look up a newer version, then you can do
so by opening a new browser window and go into maven repository dot com.
Using Search bar at the top.
Search for G Unit Jupiter.
And click on the search button.
And here we have a list of who you need to be, the dependencies.
Now, if I go back to my project, the first dependency that I have here is key unit Jupyter API dependency.
It's currently version 5.8.1.
So if I want to obtain this version, I will go here and will look for key unit Jupyter API.
We'll click on it and then we'll click on the new version that I want to use.
For example, 5.8.2.
If I click on it, then here we have a panel with different types.
The first one is Me, Tom, and it has to copy Maven version of this dependency.
The second one is agreed on top, which we can already use, and the third one is agreed assured, which
is the format that is currently being used in our built gradle file.
So I will copy these shorter version of this dependency and I will go back to my project and will replace
an existing one with a new one I have just copied.
And similarly, we can update the version of the other dependency, which is a G unit, Jupiter engine,
because we already have this dependency here.
I can simply update its version.
I will change it from 5.8. 1 to 5 .8.2, and we cannot more dependencies if needed.
For example, let's go back to our even the repository dotcom and search for G unit Jupiter.
If our project needs to support parameterized Gini tests, for example, then we will need to add another
dependency to our project which is called G.
You need to be there params.
So I will click on it and then I will click on the latest version, will select Gradle at the top and
will copy this dependency to my project.
Like this.
All right.
So as you learn more about G-Unit and as you learn more about this than you ever could with other laborers,
you can use this build to gradle file to add the needed dependencies here one by one.
But when it comes to G unit, then instead of fighting these three dependencies separately, you can
also add a single dependency instead.
It is an aggregate dependency and it contains all these three dependencies in one.
So to find them dependency, I will go back to me when they point to dot com.
I will go back a couple of pages in history and the aggregate dependency that I'm looking for is called
G unit Jupiter aggregator.
That is dependency number three in this list.
So I will click on it and then I will copy its latest version.
I will select Greenall short panel and then I will copied this dependency to my project.
And instead of these three, I can add only one aggregator dependency.
All right.
And optionally, to enable the standard out and standard error streams, you can add the following property
to the test section.
So right under the use g unit platform, we can add test, log in and then show standard streams.
And then assign it a boolean value.
True.
Now because we have changed this built gradle file to making this changes, take a think.
I'll click on this button in the top right corner, which will load changes into anthology to make it
work correctly.
All right, so let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we can try running a very simple unit test and see if it works.