In this lesson, we will improve our unit test method and we will make it actually test the integer
division method that we have in our calculator class.
And this one to do that, I will go back to my calculator test and I will delete the fill assertion
and I will first create an instance of calculator class, an instance of class, the method in which
I am testing.
Now I can use this calculator object to call the integer division method.
As dividend, I will use value of four, for example, and as a divisor I will use two.
And this means that four will be divided by two.
And the result of this operation I will assign to a local variable, let's call it a result.
For example, now four divided by two is equal to two.
So I expect the result of this operation to be equal to two.
Let's verify if it's true.
To do it, I can use a special insertion that checks if the two values are equal, for example, assert
equals, and the very first parameter that assert equals assertion accept is the expected value.
So four divided by two should be equal to two.
So the expected result is two, and the next parameter that assert equal assertion accepts is the actual
value that will be returned from the integer division method.
We have assigned this value to a viable result so I can use it.
Like this.
So if the result is not going to be equal to two, this assertion will fail and the unit test will also
fail.
If the two values are both equal to two, then this assertion will get successful and unit test will
pass.
Let's try.
I will run this unit test.
And we have a passing unit test in the test report.
I have a calculator test class with a green checkmark and I have in the gene division test method with
a green checkmark as well.
Now I can try and intentionally break business logic inside of integer division method just to see how
it works.
So instead of division, I will use multiplication, for example.
I will save this business logic.
I will go to my integer division test method and we'll run it one more time.
And we have a failing unit test.
The unit test result is telling as that assertion has failed.
The expected value is two, but the actual value returned is eight.
All right, so let's fix it.
I will go to my integer division method, fix my code, save it and run my unit test one more time.
And we have a passing unit test.
And this is it, actually.
This is how simple it is to write a unit test meant it.
Now the business logic inside of the method that we are testing inside of this integer division method,
it could be very complex, but that does not matter to us.
We should not be afraid of the business logic inside of the method that we are testing seems to be very
complex.
The method under test can have many lines of code.
It can have a very complex business logic containing encryption and decryption algorithms.
But that does not matter much when we are writing a unit test method.
Even though the business logic inside of method under test can be very, very complex, our unit tests
can be very small.
So as a person who writes unit has made it, all you need to do is to verify that for a given input
parameters, the method under test returns expected result and that's it.
You do not really need to understand all the details of that complex business logic you are testing
or be able to write it yourself.
You just need to verify that for a given input parameters, it returns an expected result.
Personally, when I have realized this very important detail, my level of confidence has doubled.
I became very confident that I can write unit tests for any project, and it does not matter much how
complex that business logic is.
And I hope it also gives you some confidence that writing unit tests is not very difficult, but there
is more to learn.
Of course there are other use cases that we need to consider.
You need testing is not difficult, but you do need to learn more about it and there are other details
as well.
So let's continue and let's learn more about TE Unit API and how it works.