In the following lessons.
We are going to test GP entity and it is not often that developers write test methods to validate their
entity classes, but if needed you can tell GP entities as well.
So as an example we will use a user entity class which is a regular Java class with some properties
getter and setter methods, but it will also have GP annotations in it and you can find this class in
the i o package.
Here it is user entity in the project that is provided for this section.
So I have this class currently opened in my development environment and it has a few properties like
for example, user ID, first name, last name, email, encrypted password and it has some getter and
setter methods.
Now notice that this class is also annotated with some persistence annotations.
It is annotated with entity annotation which will mark this class as persistent entity.
And this means that we will be able to use Sprint data IGP framework to persist an object of this class
into a database table.
So how it will work is when we start our springboard application.
Spring Framework will scan all classes looking for classes with different annotations.
And once it finds a class with annotations, depending on what annotations this class is using, Spring
Framework will know how to deal with them.
It will create an object of this class and it will place this object as a bean into sprint application
context.
Now, when it finds class that is annotated with entity annotation, it will process this class and
will treat it as a persistent entity.
Notice that this class is also annotated with table annotation with a name users, and this means that
the framework will create a database table called users for us.
We do not need to create this database table manually by running SQL queries.
It will be created for us by the framework at the time when our application starts up.
So you can think of Entity as a Java class that describes database table, and each property in this
class is a database column.
Notice that each property in this class is also annotated with column annotation, and this means that
when users table is created for us, it will be created with these columns.
It will have a column, user ID, it will have a column, first name, last name, email and so on.
And it will also have a column ID which is on the top here.
And this column will be a value which will be out generated for us.
It will be a primary key with a value that will be auto generated.
And once this entity object is persisted, we will get a new row recorded in a database table.
So each entity object that you persist gets recorded as a new row in a database table.
Now notice that column annotation also accepts some additional parameters.
For example, we specified that the value of user's first name cannot be now and it cannot be longer
than 50 characters and the value of email address, for example.
It cannot be now and it cannot be longer than 120 characters.
So what we can do is we can write test methods to validate that these fields are configured correctly
and that if you try to persist an entity object that contains an invalid value, then you will get an
error message.
All right, so let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we will create a new test method to test this user entity.