In the following lessons you will learn about test driven development.
And in this section of the course, I will use a new project.
Now you can create your own Java project, or you can use my project that I have created and attached
to this lecture.
And my project is a Maven based Java project and it does not have any application or test code.
The test folder is empty and the main application java folder is also empty.
It is an empty project, but it does have two unique dependencies.
Inform example file.
So here's the key.
You need Jupyter dependency and it also has the Maven sure fire plugin added.
If you choose to use my project, then post this video as a now download the project that I have attached
to this lesson and open it in your development environment.
All right.
So in this lesson, I will create a new test class and a new test method to create a new test class.
I will select Java folder in a test directory and inside of Java folder I will create a new class.
I will call this Java class user service test.
And we'll create a New Testament that I will start with the test, annotation, void test.
And the very first method that I want to implement and test will be that I can successfully create a
new user.
So create user will be the name of my method and the test.
Now next comes the condition or the stage change.
And here I can see when user details provided.
Then they should indicate what should be the expected result when a user details are provided.
Then I'm expecting the create user return a user object.
So I will type return user function.
Find this test.
Create user minted when using the times provided returns user object and I will set the structure of
my test method right away.
Arrange, act and assert.
All right, so we have a new test class and we have a new test method created.
Now let's continue.
And in the following lecture we will implement the create user method.