In this lesson, we're going to create a new test method that will help us test if user entity object
can be persisted in a database table.
So I will start by creating a new test class.
I'll call this class user entity integration test.
And maybe I will move this class to IO package because my user entity is also in IO package.
So I'll do right mouse click on it, choose refactor and then we'll select move class to a package that
is called IO.
Like this and we'll click on Refactor.
Now I have my class in IO package.
All right, so to help me test on the data layer of my application, I will need to annotate this class
with data GPA, test annotation.
Let's input it.
Now when test classes are annotated with this annotation, spring framework will create application
context only for those beans that are related to spring data.
IGP Persistence Layer.
It will create a put into application context our user entity object and it will also create and put
into application context repository object, but it will not create any rest controllers for example.
Right.
So now that I have test class, I will create a new test method.
With this test method, I'm going to test use an entity object with valid user information first.
So my system under test or class under test will be user entity.
And they all tested for a condition when valid user details provided, then it should return stored
user details.
Mind this now let's make it a little bit wider and that will create a range act and insert sections.
In the arrange section, I will prepare a user entity object and this time with valid user details.
So I will first create a new instance of user entity.
And I will populate it with some sample data.
For example, I will generate user ID using you id.
I will said first name.
Last name.
Sample email address.
And encrypted password.
At this moment it will not be encrypted, but it's okay.
I'm not testing encryption for now and in the next section I'm going to persist this object into a database.
Now to persist entity object into a database table, I'll need to use test, entity, manager object
and to make this object available to my test method, I will need to authorize it so I will scroll up
and that will alter where my test entity manager object.
Like this.
Now this test entity manager object is an alternative object to entity manager and he will use it in
test classes when testing data layer.
It will allow us to persist information and then synchronize it with the database table right away.
All right.
So let's scroll down and let's use it in act section.
Now we'll use this entity manager and I will call method that is called persist and flash as a parameter.
It takes user entity object.
All right.
So if there is an issue with our entity object, it will not be persisted in a database.
We will get an exception and our test method will fail the persist and flash method.
It will return us back the source entity object, but it will be already updated with generated ID value
so we can validate if the database ID was generated for this record and is present.
So the data type of returned object will be also user entity and I will call it maybe stored user entity
like this.
And in the assert section I can validate the returned values.
For example, I can assert that the Alta increment ID field has been assigned to value.
And to do that I will use assertions I will maybe use assert true will take stored user entity object
and will get the value of a field like this.
Let's have a look at this ID now it is.
Annotated with ID annotation.
It is going to be a primary key and it is an auto generated value.
Now in my test method, I do not set this field any value.
I do not set an ID.
This ID will be auto generated for us and for this value to be auto generated, I use this generated
value annotation.
So when my entity object gets persisted into a database table as a row, the very first ID that this
row will have will have a value one.
And when we persist next object, the next row will have value two and so on.
All right, so let's go back to our test method.
And if I had only one test method that stores the user entity, then the value of this ID member variable
will be equal to one.
But because I'm going to have more than one test method in this test class, and because I do not know
which method will execute first, I cannot guarantee that the value that this ID method will return
will always be one.
So I will simply assume that this value is higher than zero, for example.
And next I can validate all the fields in stored user entity object and make sure that they exactly
the same as in the original user entity object that was persisted into a database table.
So I can use assertions.
And maybe use assert equals for each of them.
For example, the expected value can be taken from original user entity object.
Let's start with maybe get user ID and the actual value will be taken from stored user entity object.
And these two values must be equal.
And I will do exactly the same for the rest of the fields.
And now we can run our test method and see if it works and if it passes.
Okay.
So it works and it passes.
I can also assert that the ID value is exactly one because at this moment I have only one test method
so I can assert that the other generated value is exactly one.
Let's try.
And it passes because the auto generated ID value is exactly one.
But because I'm going to have all the test methods in this test class the next time I run my test methods,
this will fail because there will be more than one record in a database table.
So I will simply assert that it is greater than zero.
Let's run it one more time to make sure we did not break anything.
And it passes.
All right.
So let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we will write a new test method to test how our entity object will work
if we provide invalid value for one of these fields.