Now in previous lesson, we've added the needs of MAVEN dependency and we were able to execute our test
using our development environment.
However, it is not always that we need to execute unit test using development environment.
Sometimes we need our unit tests to be executed when we build our project using MAVEN.
Let me show you what I mean.
So if I open a terminal window by clicking on this button terminal and at least files to make sure that
I'm in the right directorate, I need to be able to see SML file.
So I'm in the home directory of my project.
So if I want to build or package my project using Maven, I will run the following command maven space
package and then hit enter.
And this will compile and package my project into a jar file.
And now they both are successful.
But notice that even though the build is successful, there are zero tests that get executed.
Now I can also run maven command to execute test phases separately.
Let's see if this works.
So the command is may one space and then test and hit enter.
And again, even though the build is successful, there are zero tests executed.
So Tony, will our application execute unit tests during in the MAVEN build lifecycle?
We need to add a plug in to pull maximum file.
So I will call the terminal window and I will go back to pull maximum file and right before the project
element ends.
So right after dependencies, I will add a new section that is called built.
Like this.
And inside of this build section, I will add plugins section.
And inside of plug ins section.
I will add a plug in.
The plugin is called Sure Fire, and you can look for it in the Maven repository as well.
So I will go back to my browser window and I will open me one repository dot com.
Let's go to its home page.
So it's Maven repository dotcom and then using this search bar at the top, I will search for Maven
a sure fire plug in and click on Search Button.
So the very first option at the top is what we need.
Maven Sure.
Fire a plug in.
So I will click on it.
I will select the latest version and from the Maven tab I will copy it.
Not the entire dependency, but its MAVEN coordinates only.
So I'll copy group any artifact.
The end version I will copy and will go back to my homework sample file and paste it here.
Now, because I have made changes to my following simple file, I will need to reload my Maven project
so that anyone can face this dependency and make it available in my project.
To do that, I will click on this button which is in the top right corner, or just like I did in my
previous videos.
And I can do right mouse click on my project or on public sample file and then choose Maven Reload Project.
And now I should be able to execute my unit test using medium and command as well.
Let's try.
I will open terminal window again and in the terminal window I will run maven space package and hit
enter.
Now they built a successful.
And this time I have one unit to execute it.
I can also execute my unit tests by invoking the test phase.
To do that, I will use maven, command maven, space test and hit enter.
And they built a successful again.
They have won a unit test that was successful.
Execute it.
All right.
And just in case you need to build or package your project, but you do not want your new test to be
executed.
You can do it this way.
Maven and then space package dash.
Capital D and then continue without any spaces.
Maven dot test.
That's.
Keep equals.
Through this will package your product, but it will not execute any tests.
Let's try.
Now the building is successful, but there are no tests that were executed.
All right.
So it all works well and we're good to contain.