In this video.
Listen, I'll show you how to create a new interest in eclipse through open environment.
If you do not use a crepes, then please feel free to skip this video lesson.
All right, so I have eclipse development environment opened, and I will start by creating a new project.
To do that, they will select file new and then I will select a simple Java project.
From the list of wizards.
I will select Java Project and will click on next.
Now I will give my project a name.
For example, calculator eclipse.
And the rest of the options I will leave unchanged and they will click on Next Button.
And finally we will click on Finish Button to create this project.
Eclipse offers me to open Java perspective.
This perspective was designed to support Java development.
Oh, click on Open Perspective and now I have a very simple Java project opened.
Let me expand to Project Folder and here I have source folder which is currently empty.
Let's create a new general class.
I will create a new class.
I will put it into a package.
For example, comm humps that will block.
And then the name of the class will be calculator and the rest of the options are will also leave unchanged.
I'll click on finish to screen this class.
And I have a new class created in IBM's developer block package.
Now I will add a method that I want to test, and it will be the same integer division method that I
have created in one of the previous video lessons.
Magnus Alright, so now that I have a method to test, I can create a unique test method for it.
Now, because it is a brand new project, I do not even have a test folder for my test classes.
So I will first create a test folder.
To do that, I will select the project and then I will do right mouse click will select new and then
choose source folder.
I will call this folder test and will click on Finish Button to create this folder.
Now I'm ready to create a new test class.
To do it, I will select calculator from my IBM's developer block from the sources folder.
I will do right mouse click on it, will select the new and then we'll select G unit test case.
And the top.
We have three different options that allow us to select the version of two units that we want to use.
I will select the latest new do you need to beta test the source folder that comes right below?
I want you to change it.
Currently says I so c I will change it to test and this will please the new test class into the test
folder that we have created.
All right.
So the package I will keep the scene and the name of the class will also stay the same.
It is a common convention to use test at the end of the class name to specify that this class is a test
class.
The next panel, it allows me to generate one of this methods.
I'm not going to do it at this moment.
Then we'll skip it.
We we'll talk about this method a little bit later and then we have class under test, which is calculator.
This is correct.
I'm not going to change it.
All right.
So now I can click on Finish Button to create this new test class.
Now.
Eclipse's letting me know that you need five is not on the growth path.
Do I want to add it?
And the answer is yes, I will need to add it.
So I will keep the perform following action selected to add to Unit five library on the built path and
will click on okay button.
And here we go.
Eclipse has created a new calculator quiz with an example of Test method, which currently doesn't test
anything.
If it wrong this method, it will fail because of this fail assertion.
And one of the ways to run test methods in this class is to select the test class itself and then do
right mouse click on it and then choose a run as and then select g unit test.
It tells me that my calculator class is not saved and invites me to save changes to my calculator class
whole week and the test all around now.
All right.
So it has failed on the left side.
Here we have a unique panel active and the bar at the top is present.
This means that the test has failed and it has failed because we have intentionally failed it with this
fail assertion.
All right.
So let's make it pass.
If you execute your unit test method and none of its assertions fail or it does not result in an exception
thrown, then this g unit test will pass.
It is a full g unit test behavior.
If it does not fail, then it passes.
All right, so to make it pass, I can simply comment out this fail assertion and let it print something
instead.
For example, we will add system out, print again and print the same message.
And now I can run it again.
I will switch to Package Explorer.
It's safe changes first and then I will select my calculator.
Test class will do right mouse click on it.
Run as g unit test.
And we have a passing unit test.
The bar on the unit panel is green and this means that all is good and that unit has passed.
If the bar is red, then this means that we have a failing test.
But if the bar is green, then the test is successful.
If I expand the calculator test, then here I have a single test method with a little checkmark in green
indicating that this test method is passing.
All right, so all this good and you now know how to create and how to run a very simple unit test method,
use an eclipse development environment.
Now, the unit test that is here, it doesn't really do anything.
It doesn't really test anything.
So let's continue.
And in the following lessons, we will create a test method that will actually test our integer division
method in the calculator class.
But for the rest of the course I will use intelligent development environment.