In previous lessons, we have created a user service project which I currently have opened in my development
environment, and this project has user service, implementation class and sign of service package.
Let's open it.
Now, on this moment, this method simply returns user object and it does not store user details anywhere.
In the following lessons, we will continue working on this method and we will continue testing this
method, but will start using Makita.
Now, Makita helps us create fake objects and mock objects to let us test or imitate under test in isolation
from those dependencies.
But at this moment, our Creator as a method doesn't have any dependencies.
It does not really depend on any other object.
For example, it does not use data on the subject to store user details in the database.
So let's make our method under test.
The create use limited depend on the data access object to store user details.
And to do that I will assume that I have a data access object or may be users repository and I will
use it to save user details.
Mind that instead of returning a new instance of user class, I will create a new user this way.
And then after storing it, I will return user object.
Now I do not have users repository yet in my project, so let's continue.
And in the following lesson we will create a very simple implementation for it.