So why do we want to write unit tests?
It's very quickly to run our application and just do manual testing to make sure that things work.
So why write code to make sure that another code works?
Why not test manually?
And there are a few very big advantages of writing unit tests to test our code.
We wrote unit tests to make sure that our code works.
Now this is obvious, but this is not the biggest advantage.
One of the reasons why we want to write unit tests is to make sure that the Java method we have written
works well with different input values.
We want to make sure that it works well with valid and pin valid input parameters.
Now we can do manual testing and manually provide valid and invalid input parameters.
But if we have a very large application with many features, then it is very easy to forget to test
one of the features with one of inviolate parameters, especially when we have many developers working
on the project, when changes to our application are made on a daily basis, and when we need to do
frequent tests, manual testing or application that has many features becomes very difficult and it
becomes very easy to forget to test the feature with a specific invalid input parameter.
Another very big reason why we want to write unit tests is to make sure that our code works well now
and in the future.
Imagine that you have written a very complex method.
This method is very useful and other developers started using it in their classes as well.
How do you make sure that other developers who want to make changes to your code do not break anything?
Unit tests that you have written for this method will give you confidence that future changes to this
method do not break existing functionality and that this method still works as expected with all valid
and invalid input parameters as it used to work before.
It is also called regression testing, and unit tests help you feel more confident that the new code
changes to existing application features do not break other working code.
If you make changes to one of the method and it breaks functionality in another existing and will test
that feature, then it is called regression.
So you will want to write unit tests to make sure that there is no regression and all features still
work as expected, even after you made the small change to existing and will work in code.