In this lesson, you will learn how to expert code coverage support in each demo format so that you
can share it with other team members if needed.
And to do that, you will need to first run our unit test and generate code coverage report.
So I will run my unit tests with code coverage.
Now that I have my code cover coverage generated, I can export it.
And to do that, I can either click on this button here in the test results report.
It's called export test results.
Or I can also click on this button here on the code coverage panel.
And the button looks exactly the same as in test results.
And if you move mouse over it, it says generate coverage report.
So I'll click on it.
And now I need to provide a path to a folder where I want to export code coverage reports in each more
format and if needed.
You can also select this checkbox here that says open generated each demo in the browser window.
So I will keep this checkbox selected and will click on Save Button.
And now I have my quote, courage report exploited in a shallow format and opened in a browser window.
Now, this report contains same code coverage information as I saw it in Anthology Development Environment.
I see a clickable package name and code coverage breakdown for class method and number of lines.
If I click on the package name, I will see a breakdown by each Java class and if I click on the class
name, for example, user service implementation, then I'll see source code of this class and lines
of code that have been covered with units will be highlighted with green, and lines of code that have
not been covered with unit tests will be highlighted with a red card.
All right.
So now let's check the folder where we have exported this HTML fonts.
I will bring in Finder Window and this is the folder where I have exported my report.
It's called Test Report and it has HMO files.
It has JavaScript images and CSS files.
If I need to publish this report on local intranet so that my other team members can see it, I can
do that.
Or I can simply zip this entire folder and send it over to other external third party so that they can
have a look at it.
All right.
So it all worked for us.
And now you know how to generate code, college support and how to export it in a demo format as well.
Let's continue.