We need to test how our method and the test works.
With all layers integrated, we will write a test method that is called integration test or some developers
also call it acceptance test.
And for this test to work, we will need all three layers integrated and we will not use any test doubles.
We will not use any mock objects, and we will not create any fake objects.
The test method we will write will test how our get user method works from end to end, meaning that
in the web layer, HTTP request will be handled and bin validation will be performed.
And in the service layer, a real production version of our code will be executed and in the data layer
and actual communication with the database will be performed.
So no mocking of any layer or any object will be done.
And for it to work we will need to start application context for all layers in our application.
And to do that, Sprint framework provides us with a special annotation that is called Springboard Test.
Springboard Test annotation will create application context that is very similar to the one we use in
production application, although by default it will not start a web server.
But even though a real web server will not be started by default, we can still test our code integrated
with all layers, but if needed we can configure Springwood test annotation to load a real web environment
with embedded server running on specific port number or even make it run on a random port number.
And in the following lessons I'll show you how to do it.
All right, so let's continue and let's write a few integration tests.