In previous lesson, we have introduced a dependency to our create user method and for creating the
method to work.
Now it needs to have a working user response to object.
So in this video we will create user repository and a very simple save method to store users in memory.
All right.
So to do that, I will create a new package, maybe data package.
And then this package concrete a new interface.
I will call this interface user see to.
And from the list of options I will select interface.
Now at this moment, this interface will have only one method and I will call it save.
It will accept user object and will return boolean value to or false but in producer only.
Okay.
So it will accept user object and it will return true if all is good and false.
If user details could not be persisted next to or create a very simple implementation.
And to do that, I will click on the interface name and then the right mouse click and choose show context
actions from the list of options I will select implement interface.
And I will give my interface in the I will call it the users repository simple, which stands for implementation.
And that will put it into the same theater package and we'll click on okay button will make sure that
my method is selected and click okay.
Okay.
So my development environment created for me a new class that implements users repository interface.
And now I need to write some general code to make this save method store user details in memory and
as a temporary storage, I will use hash map.
Like this.
That's impaired mop.
And now I can check your face, as Schwab does have user details.
If it doesn't, then it will put and you use an object there.
To do that, I will use if statement and will check if users contains an object with a key that is equal
to user ID and if it does not contain, I will add exclamation mark at the beginning.
If it does not contain user object then it will add it to my hash map.
Has a key.
I will use user ID.
And as the object it will be the user object.
I have compilation error and this is because my hash map is configured to have stream data type as a
key and stream and the object only to replace stream with user.
And once user details are in the map, I will introduce a new local wearable called return value and
will assign a boolean true to it and will make this method return this return value.
All right.
So let's save changes in this class.
Let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we will inject users repository as a dependency to our user serious class.