To my extreme framework around embedded server on the port number that you define, you will need to
use a different options for web environment.
So I will remove mock and from the list of options I will choose defined port.
And there are a couple of different ways to define a port.
Number one of the ways is to define port number in application properties file.
So on the left side in my project, I will look for resources folder.
And inside of resources we have application properties file.
If I open it here, we can define server port number and if we do not define any port number here,
then by default our embedded server will start on default port number 88.
Otherwise it will start in a port number that we define with server dot port property equals and then
port number that you want to have, for example, eight, eight, eight, eight.
Let's see if it works.
I will save changes in my application properties file will go back to my test class and I will add a
very simple test method.
Like this.
I have defined an empty test method that doesn't really test any of my application code.
But even though this test method is empty, spring framework will still launch an embedded server and
it will create application context.
So we will be able to see if our embedded server starts on a port number that we have defined.
Let's try.
I will run this test method.
And now if I scroll down the console.
And the bottom.
I should see that Tom got started on port number eight, eight, eight, eight, the port number that
I have defined in application properties file.
Now if you do not want to use port number that you have defined in application properties file and want
to use a different port number for your tests, then there is another way to make a tomcat start on
a different port number other than the one you have defined here.
And one of the ways to do it is to use property attribute of the same spring boot test annotation.
So right after define port on a new line, I will add a new property that is called properties.
And here in double quotes, I can provide a property name that I want to override.
For example, server port equals and then port number 8081.
So the port number that I defined here will override the value that is loaded from application properties
file and we'll have a higher priority.
Now if there are multiple properties that you want to override, then you will need to surround them
with.
Curly brackets, include property in double quotes, and then separate them with a comma.
So the second property will be separated with a comma, surrounded with double quotes.
And let's assume I want to use a different hostname for example, hostname equals two and then IP address.
So let's try and see if it works.
I will save changes and we'll click on a run button to run this test method.
And now I will scroll down and check the port number.
And the port number is now different.
The port number is 8081, which is the one that I have defined in the properties attribute of the same
Springwood test annotation.
Now there is another way you can override the defined port number or any other properties defined in
the application properties file.
Let's continue and in the following lesson you will see how it works.