Now that we have created user service, implementation class and user series interface, we can work
on the Create method in the ACT section.
I will use the object of user service to invoke the creators amended.
My code does not compile, which means that I need to stop writing unit test code and fix this problem
first.
And to fix this problem I will need to create the create user mounted and to do that that will open
user service interface and will define a new method here.
Now that I have updated my interface, I will update its implementation.
I will click on the yellow bulb here or I will do right Maules Creek and choose short context actions
and will choose implement method create user like this.
Now my user series interface implementation is updated with a new method that is called Create User.
Now I will save changes to my user service implementation and will go back to user service test class.
My test method now compiles no error and I can continue.
Now the next part of my test method name says that when user details provided, it should return the
user object.
So I need to provide user details to basically user method.
What are these details that I want to provide?
These are, for example, first name, last name, email and password.
So in the arrange section I will prepare this user details.
I will start with first name.
The last name.
Email.
And password.
And to make sure that there is no typo in the password, I will ask user to repeat their password.
Now I can provide this user details to my CLI to limit.
Mind it now my method does not compile again.
And this means that I need to stop writing unit test code and fix this problem first.
So to do that, that will update to create user method and will make it accept this parameters.
I will go to user service interface and will update it.
First name, last name, email.
Password and repeat password.
Now I will select these parameters and will update the series implementation class aswell by pasting
them here.
All right, so now let's save changes and go back to our user service test class.
My test method compiles and this means that I can continue working on it.
Now, the next part of my test method says that it should return user object.
And this means that when create user method is invoked, it should return user object.
So let's define user object and assign the result of create user method to the user object.
My test method does not compile again because I do not have this user class.
So I need to stop working on test method and create this user clause.
To do that in the main Java folder of my application, I will create a new Java class and I will call
it user.
The glass is created and I will move it to a model package.
To do that, they will select the class will do right most quick, will choose a factor and then move
class to a package that I will call.
Com hubs, developer block e-store and then model and will click on refactor button.
This package does not exist.
Do I want to create it?
Yes.
Destination directory is my source main java folder.
I'll click.
Okay.
And now I have a new package that is called model.
And inside of this package, I have a user class.
All right, so we have all user class.
Let's go back to user service test and import this class.
Now our method does not compile again.
And this is because the create user method that we have defined in user service interface is one.
Let's have a look at it.
I will open user series interface and it says that the user method is one.
So we need to update it and we need to make it return user object.
Let's import user class and now we need to update interface implementation as well.
To do that I will do right mouse click, choose show context functions and then we'll select update
implementation to reflect signature change.
When this annual quick update.
This will update the implementation of create user method inside of user service implementation class.
Here it is, but it does not compile.
We have an error because it does not return a user object.
So let's make it return an empty user object first.
Write it now or use a serious implementation class compact.
I will save changes to this course.
I will go to user service, save changes here and we'll go back to my user service test class and now
my test method also compiles and I have no error in the ACT section.
All right, so we're almost done with our method.
The last section is assert and here we want to make sure that this value user object is not.
Now to do that I will use assert not now assertion.
Let's input it.
From.
Org to uni jupiter api assertions.
The first parameter is our user object and the second parameter is optional error message.
For example, the create user method should not have returned.
No magnet.
Now I will save changes to my use a serious this class and we are ready to run this test method and
see if it works.
Let's try.
And we have a passing union test.
All right.
So now that we have a passing union test, the next step in the test, even development process, is
refactor.
I will minimize my panel here.
And at this moment, I have only one unit test.
It is very simple and I do not see much of code that I want to refactor at this moment.
So I'll simply continue and will implement one more test method.