When writing unit tests, developers tried to as much as possible for the first principle.
It is a combination of multiple principles and in this lecture you will learn about these principles.
The first letter in the first principle stands for fast unit tests are small pieces of code that perform
one specific task because units are small and unlike integration tests, unit tests do not communicate
over the network and do not perform database operations.
And because unit tests do not communicate with remote servers or databases, they run very fast.
The next letter in the first principle stands for independent.
Ideally, a unit should be independent from each other.
One unit test should not depend on the result produced by another unit test.
In fact, by default, unit tests run in order.
That is not obvious and we do not really know which we need.
Test will run first and the white unit test will run second.
The code you testing or the system under test should also be isolated from its dependencies, and this
is to make sure that the back end dependency ownership does not influence a unit test.
So dependencies are usually marked or stuffed with predefined data.
And this way communities can test the system under test in isolation from its dependencies and produce
a very accurate result.
The next letter in the first principle stands for repeatable units should be repeatable and if I run
the same unit test multiple times, it should produce the same result if unit test is run on a different
computer.
It should also produce the same result.
This is why unit tests are made independent from environment and from other unit tests.
The input parameters that the method under test requires are usually pretty find at hard coded, and
the method that you are testing needs to be tested with valid and invalid input parameters.
Then you will create two or three different unit tests.
Each training test will test the method and the test with its own set of predefined parameters.
And this way unit becomes repeatable.
And if we run it multiple times in different environments on a different computer or different operating
system, it will still produce the same result each time we run it.
The next letter stands for self validating and this means that to learn if unit has passed or not develop
or should not be doing any additional manual checks after the test completes, units will validate the
result.
That method under test has produced itself and it will itself make a decision whether this unit test
is bouncing or is failing.
So after unit test completes, the result will be clear and the next letter stands for thoro and developers
who practice test driven development will also spell it as timely.
Talking about Soto.
This means that when testing the method, we should consider happy path as well as negative scenario.
And this means that most of the time we create multiple unit tests to test a method that accepts input
parameters.
One unit test will test your method with while it can put parameters, and in other unit test will test
method within valid input parameters.
And if there is a range like minimum and maximum value, then we should create additional unit tests
to test for minimum and or maximum values as well.
And talking about time, it means that it is better to create unit test at the time you're working on
application feature.
This way you will have more confidence that the feature does work as expected, and there are less chances
that you will introduce a bank and that BAC will be released to production.
So before you promote your code to production, it should be covered with unit tests.