In this lesson we're going to test if the returned user object contains correct first name.
And I will start by creating a New Testament it.
I'm going to test the scene, create using method.
So method under test is create its user.
And this is why I'm starting the name of my test method test create user now then goes underscore and
then as condition or state change, I will continue when user is created.
I want the return to that object to contain correct or the same first name.
Something like this, and that will create mental structure by adding to it.
Three sections.
A wrench act and assert.
Now in this method, I'm going to invoke the create use method.
So the arrange section will be very much the same.
And what I can do, I can scroll up here and copy the entire orange section from my previous method
and paste it here.
Now that I have my arrange section prepared, I will use this information to invoke method under test.
And now that I have my act section ready, I will validate that the return to that object contains the
same first name.
And to do that I will use assert equals assertion.
Expected value is stored in a local variable first name and the actual value will read from the user
object.
Now my test method does not compile and this means that I need to switch to application code and implement
the get first name method first.
To do that, that will open the user class and will add one member variable.
I will also need and get the method for it so I will do right mouse click generate.
Get their.
And then select first thing.
Now I have I get a method for it.
If I save changes in this user class and go back to my test method, my code now compiles flow.
All right, so I have an assertion.
I don't have any completion there and they can try running this test and see if it works.
So let's try.
I will execute this test method.
And advance.
My assertion has failed because expected value is surging, but the actual value that was returned from
the user object is now.
It looks like the user's first name that has been returned by the get first name method is now, and
this means that the first name is not initialized.
So let's open create user method and have a look at it.
This is my interface.
I will go to implementation of my interface in the user service implementation class.
And here in this method that creates new user, I'm returning an empty user object.
It creates a new user option but does not initialize any properties.
So I will need to at least give it user first name for it to initialize it.
Now I will open the user class and I will create a constructor to initialize first name.
To do that I will do right mouse click and then choose generate and then select constructor and will.
So at first name click on okay.
And now I have constructor that initialize this first name, I'll save changes here.
I will go to a user service implementation, save changes here.
Now this line of code compiles and now I will go back to a user service test method and try running
this test method one more time.
And now it passes.
This means that this assertion successfully validates the expected value of first name, which is Sergei
is equal to the actual value that has been returned from the user object.
All right, so our test method passes, and the next step in the development process is to refactor.
Let's do it in the following lesson.