In this lesson, we will use an object of users repository implementation to save user details, and
we will do it in the user service implementation class.
Now there are different ways how we can make an object of this class available in our user service implementation.
And the easiest way will be to create an object with right the way inside of the create user method.
Like this.
Now that they have an object of a clause that implements users, it puts the I can call slave method
to proceed to say details.
But this will be incorrect because in this case, if I called the creators method from my test method
of the code inside of this save method will be executed and user will actually be persisted to no storage.
And in this case is going to be not unit test anymore, but integration test.
When writing the unit test to test this create user method, which is our method under test, we need
to isolate this method from all its dependencies because we are not actually testing code inside of
save method and we do not want to invoke a real save method.
So instead of using a real user supposedly object, we want to replace this real object with a more
chip.
But if I create an instance of users who oppose the implementation this way, then there is no way I
can make this method, create user method, use a mock object instead of a real one.
So we need to use dependency injection and instead of creating a new object of users who opposed the
implementation, this way we will need to inject it using constructor based dependency injection.
So I will define a new instance of users repository.
On a class level, it's going to be member variable and on create a constructor to initialize to do
that, that will do right mouse click then choose, generate and choose constructor.
Click.
Okay.
And now I have constructor for this class that will initialize user repository property.
And this way, when creating a new instance of user series implementation clause, I can pass here and
object of any clause as long as it implements user repository interface.
Okay.
And we'll use my key then to create a mock compute that implements this interface for answer chromatically.
All right.
So I will scroll down and I will delete this line and maybe add a little if statement to check for a
boolean power.
For example boolean resolve or boolean easy user Craig.
And then check of.
It's true he fuser was not created.
I will add exclamation mark.
Then I will throw a new, let's say, user service exception.
With a message like I could not create user.
Now I do not have user service exemption class in my project, so I will move mouse over the error message
and then click on more actions and choose create class user service exemption.
The destination package will be my absolute little bit block Easter service package and the target destination
directory will be main application folder and not the test but source main java and then service package.
And quick on.
Okay.
And now I have a new class.
You serious exemption created in the service package?
Yeah, it extends through Will.
I'll make it extend runtime exception.
I will remain parameter to be message and I will call super with this message.
So now I have a custom exception that I'm throwing from the create user method if user was not successfully
created.
Okay.
So our create user mentored now has a dependency.
It depends on user repository object.
We can now continue and use my to to create a more complete of users repository and use that mock object
instead of a real one.
To test this create user method.
Let's continue.