In previous lesson, you have learned how to configure Maven to exploit regular test reports in HTML
format.
And in this video lesson we will configure this same Maven based project to generate code coverage report
and export it in each HTML format around some to make MAVEN generate an expert code coverage report.
We will need to add to our project one more plug in and to find this plugin, I'll go back to my browser
window and we'll go to Maven repository dot com and we'll search for this plugin using this search bar
at the top.
The plugin is called Coco Maven plugin.
So the in that I'm looking for is called Jack Coco and it is number one in search result.
The name of the plug in Jack Coco stands for Java code coverage and it will help us exploit code coverage
report in a demo format when we execute our unique tests using MAVEN.
So I will open it and I will click on the latest version and we'll copy its example code snippet.
I'll go back to my sample file and we'll add it as a new plug in.
Now I will need to replace dependency with plug in.
And now that they have found this plug in, there are a couple of configurations that I need to make.
And the first configuration will go into execution section.
So inside of the plug in and a new section that is called Executions.
And I will add one execution.
The idea of this execution will be prepare agent, prepare a Dutch agent, and it will have a goal that
will need to go into goals section.
And the name of the goal is also called Prepare Agent.
That.
So this first execution is needed to do some initialization for Jack.
Okay.
Agent But the second execution that we are going to add will make Jack execute its report.
Go with me, then execute the test phase so I will add one more execution.
The idea of this execution will be called report and it will also have goals section and the name of
the goal is a report.
All right.
So here with this configuration, we are making Cocker execute this call that is called report during
and we even test face and the name of the phase I will on right after the I.D..
Okay.
So here with this new configuration, we are making a executed circle that is called report.
During the maven's test face execution and this is a we can now save our opponents camo font and triaging
the reading at this point let's click on this button in the top right corner to load menu and changes
and we're going to continue.