In previous lessons you have learnt about two different types of tests in your unit.
These are test methods that are annotated with test annotations and test methods that are annotated
with parameterized tests on a patient.
Now test methods that are annotated with test annotation.
These are regular test methods and when executed they run one time on test matters that are annotated
with parameterized test annotation.
They accept method arguments and they can execute multiple times depending on how many sets of arguments
we provide in other types of test methods is called a repeated test, and these test methods are annotated
with repeated test retention.
Let's actually create a new class for this demonstration.
I will create a new Java class and we'll call it demo.
Repeat a test.
I will add it to it and I will copy and paste one of the existing test methods.
For example, this one.
I will also need to copy code that initializes calculator object so I will copy before each method.
And we'll paste it into my demo repeat test class and we'll also define calculator property.
I think this.
All right.
So this is a regular test method and it is annotated with test annotation.
For this method to repeat multiple times, we will need to remove this test plantation and use repeated
test annotation instead.
So I will remove it and will use repeated test orientation instead.
Now, in the brackets of repeated test annotation, we will need to provide the number of times that
we want this test mandatory.
For example, three times.
Right?
So repeated test annotation allows us to repeat the same test method multiple times and make sure that
if it is repeated again, then it still passes.
And if I run this test method now, it should run not one time but three times, and I expected to pass
all three times.
I will click on the run button and will run this test method.
And here we go.
The test meter ran three times and each repetition is successful.
Now, each invocation of repeated test method behaves exactly like the execution of a regular test.
This means that for each repetition, the lifecycle methods like, for example, before each or after
each will also be executed.
In this test class, I have added a method that is annotated with before each annotation, and I see
a System.out.println in the console that this method has executed.
Now, if needed, we can also get access to reputation information inside of our test method.
And to do that unit allows us to inject repetition, formation object as a method argument to our test
method.
So let's do that.
I will inject repetition and formation.
We'll put it on a new one.
And now that they have repetition formation object injected into my test method, I can get repetition
information from it.
For example, if I try to access it, I can get the total repetitions number and they can get the kinds
repetition number and we can use this found in our test method if needed.
Let's print them out for now.
I will build in this line and maybe below I will add a new System.out.println and will print this values.
For example, repetition number.
And then I will add this number.
Repetition number.
And then I concatenate to you to the current repetition number of total repetitions.
Now, additionally to injecting the repetition information to our test method, we can also inject test
information, object and get information about the currently running test.
To do that, I will inject the second method argument, which is going to be this information.
And from this test information, I will rip the name of the currently running test method.
For example, I will edit the System.out.println line above and will say running and then will use test
information object and will get the test method name.
And from that test method name I can get the name itself, but I could also use this test information
object to access the display name of this test method.
All right, so let's run this test mounted again and see how it works.
And here's our output for each iteration we've printed, executing before each month, then a run in
and then the test method name, the actual name of our test method and then repetition one of three.
And then the cycle repeats again before each print in testament that name repetition to three and finally
repetition three of the.
So this confirms that these two lines work and we were able to get repetition information from the objects
we have injected has made the arguments.
Now you can also use repeated this limitation to change the display name of each repetition in the test
report here.
So currently the display name of the test method is division by zero.
We have it here, so that works well.
And then we have repetition, one of three, repetition to three and repetition three of three.
So we can change this, this point name as well.
And to do that, we will need to use a repeated test annotation and we can use its properties for example,
instead of three, I could say value equals three and then comma and to provide constant use plane name,
I will use name property and then in double quotes I'll provide the name and I can actually inject repetition
information a right into this plane name to do that that will use complete variables like for example,
in curly brackets, I will use this plane name.
Repetition.
And then another complete variable, which is current repetition.
Oh, and then another template article, which is going to be total repetitions.
Notice that to come up with a new display name, I have used template variables just plainly current
repetition and total repetitions.
These complete variables will be replaced with actual values and if you wonder what other template variables
are there, then at the time of recording this realism, these are the only three.
All right, so let's run our this method and see how it works.
And now we have a new name for each reputation division by zero reputation one of three division one
zero.
Reputation two of three and division by zero.
Reputation three of three.
All right.
So it works very well.
And you now know how to use repeated test annotation and make your test method repeat a specific number
of times to make sure that your method and the test still behaves consistently.
And four provided input parameters still works as expected, even if you run it multiple times.