In this lesson, I will give you a brief overview of how I have implemented this method to validate
that user ID column accepts only unique values and there are different ways to implement this test method.
And in this video lesson, I'll share with you just one of the ways.
And if you need my source code, then you can download this class from resources folder that is attached
to this video course.
All right, so I have called my new test method test user entity when existing user ID provided it should
throw exception.
And in the arranged section I set a very easy value for user ID and the entity object that I use and
persist into a database is created initially in the before each method.
So in the before each method I create one instance of user entity and in my test method I update this
instance with a very simple value one.
And then I persist this user entity into a database table.
But before that, in the same arranged section, I prepare a new user entity object and for this second
user entity object, I also set exactly the same value of user ID just one.
So now that I have two separate user entity objects with exactly the same value for user ID, if I attempt
to persist them, then I should expect the exception to take place in a range section.
I persist one instance of user entity and in the ACT section I persist the second instance of user entity
and it is okay to persist user entity in the range section because the arranged section is used to prepare
objects and systems state with information that is needed to test system under test.
And this is exactly what I do.
I prepare and persist one user entity.
So now my system under test is set up and then I persist another user entity to test the use case I'm
testing with this method.
So for this method to pass right after I attempt to persist a new user entity with exactly the same
value of user ID, I expect a persistence exception to take place.
If exception does not take place, then this test method will fail.
And this means that something is not right.
And our database table does accept record with a duplicate user id.
So let's try running this test method now.
And we have a passing test method.
Now let's assume that we have updated user entity and we have accidentally removed the constraint that
makes our user ID column unique.
So I will remove this constraint, save my user entity and I will run my test method one more time and
I expect my test method to catch this issue.
All right.
And now my test method fails because both entity objects were successfully stored in a database table
and no exception was thrown.
All right, so let's go back to our user entity object and let's resolve the issue by making user ID
column unique and go back to our test method and run it one more time.
And now it passes again.
All right.
So everything is working well and we are going to continue.