To avoid poor number conflicts in test environment, it is better to configure our web environment to
use a random port number.
So instead of a defined port, I will choose a random port.
This will make the embedded server always start on a random port number and it will allow different
integration tests to run in parallel.
Also, when using a random port number, there is no need to define specific port number in application
properties file or in application test properties.
So if I open the application properties file now even though we have a defined port number here, when
we run our test methods, our application will still start on a random port number.
This is because in our test class, in the Springwood test configuration, we have specified that we
want web environment to use a random port number and this configuration has a higher priority.
So behind the scenes Sprint framework will make this defined port number to be zero because this is
how we configure springboard applications to start on a random port number.
But at the end when our embedded server starts, it will not start on port number zero.
It will start on a random port number that will be available to use.
All right.
So I will undo this change.
Let's go back to our test class.
And if you need to know on which port number your embedded server is actually running, then you can
inject the running port number into test class and you do it this way.
There is a special annotation you can use that is called local server port and then you can assign this
value to a member variable like for example, a local server port.
So the locals report annotation.
It will pick up the actual port number on which your embedded server is running and it will assign this
value to this number.
And right.
So the value annotation will help us read value of server port property that is loaded from the properties
file and the local server port annotation will allow us to read value of actual port number on which
our server is running.
Let's print this value as well.
And let's run our test method to see how it works.
Now if I scroll down the console and read the port number on which my server has started, then I see
that my server started on port number 49440 and if I check the console of my test method, then it is
exactly the same port number that I'm printing using a local server port annotation.
All right, so it all worked for us and you now know how to configure your Springwood test web environment
to run on a random port number.
And this will help you avoid potential port number conflicts when you execute multiple integration tests
in the same test environment.
Let's continue.