In this lesson, we will create a new test class to start testing code in a rest controller.
I want my test class to be in the same package as the rest controller.
So I will go to test folder java and then route package of my application inside of the test folder.
And here I'll create a new package.
I will first open users controller and I will copy package name where I have placed this controller.
Now I will go back to my test package, will do right mouse click and will create new package with the
same name where I have placed my rest controller.
And here in this new package, I'll create a new test class.
I will call this class users controller and because I'm going to test web player only, I will add web
player.
And then at the end I will add test now to tell Sprint Framework that I want to create application context
only for those beans that are related to web player.
I will annotate this test class with a special annotation that is called a web MVC test.
Okay.
So now that I have annotated my test class with MVC annotation, if I execute test methods in this class,
then what spring framework will do is it will start scanning classes in my application looking for different
annotations.
And then depending on how I have annotated my application classes, spring framework will create bins
and it will put them into application context.
But because I have annotated my test class with NVC test annotation, it will tell Spring Framework
that I'm interested in testing web player only.
So it will make Spring Framework Scan my springboard application only for a limited number of classes,
classes that are related to web player only.
For example, it will scan and create controller bins, but it will not create data layer bins.
And this will make our test class run a bit faster than full integration test.
Now, since I'm interested in testing users controller only, only one controller class, I can limit
this annotation to work with one controller class that I need.
And to do this I will add the following property controllers equals and then the name of the controller
class users controller class.
Now my web visit test annotation is configured to work with the one controller class only, and even
if my application has more than one controller class only, this one controller will be placed into
application context.
But if I do not limit my web MVC annotation to one controller class only, then all controllers of my
springboard application will be included into application context.
Now, the current application that I'm testing uses Sprint security, and there is security filters
enabled.
At this moment, I'm testing web player only, and I'm not interested in those security filters at this
time so I can exclude them.
And to do that, I will add one more annotation.
It's called to configure more can be see and then I will add the property add filters equals to false.
Now this new annotation auto configure more can be see it is actually a part of web MVC test annotation
and normally we do not need to add all the configure mock MVC annotation separately.
If I open weapon visitor's annotation, then here above the interface, I see a list of annotations
that are already included and all the configure more can we see is one of them.
But I do add this annotation separately because I once print security to auto configure sprint MVC infrastructure
without including security filters.
Also, if I scroll up a little bit, all fun documentation for web MVC test annotation.
And here in this paragraph I read the use of the sanitation will disable full the configuration and
instead apply only configuration that is relevant to MVC tests.
I see that it will scan and create bins for controller controller advice, case and component converter,
generic converter filter VPC Configure and handler method argument resolver but bins for component service
or repository, these bins will not be created.
Okay, so let's close it for now.
Or I can exclude sprint security of the configuration.
This way I will comment out how to configure more.
Can we see annotation and I will edit weapon visit test annotation a little bit.
I will add comma here and I will add the following property.
Exclude all the configuration equals to and then in curly brackets I will provide security of the configuration
class.
All right.
So we have our new test class created and we have configured it to test web player only, excluding
Sprint security configuration.
Now let's continue.
And in the following lecture, we will start working on our first test method.