In this lesson, we will refactor the test method that we have just created.
And the first change that I would like to do is to update the assertion that I have here by adding a
message to it.
If this assertion fails, then I want my own custom message to be included in the lock.
For example, if the expected value of user first name does not match the actual value of user first
name that we are getting from the user object, then I want to log a message like for example, user's
first name is incorrect.
Something like this.
Now, if I look at these tests mounted and this second test method that they have here, then the RH
section in these two methods, these are section and these are in section I exactly the same.
And in this case, there are a couple of ways to go.
I can either take the string section into a lifecycle method that executes before each test method,
or if these two test methods are always the same, then I can merge them into one single test method.
And this is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to merge these two test methods into one.
And to do that, I will simply copy the assertion from my second test method into my first test method
and the second method here.
This one now becomes redundant and I can delete it.
All right.
So when doing test driven development and implementing application code step by step by writing in test
methods, first, you might come across these situations when one of test methods becomes redundant,
your application features complete your refactoring test method and it is possible that two test methods
will be almost exactly the same.
And it is a valid practice to merge these two test methods into one, but provided they are almost exactly
the same.
All right, so I have updated this test method.
I will also add a display name.
With a display name, something like user object created and I will run this test to make sure that
it still works.
And it passed.
All right.
So let's continue to the next lesson.