In this lesson, I will give you a brief overview of the new units that they have added to my calculator
class.
So the new unit test method that I have just added is called integer subtraction.
And this method is annotated with test annotation.
Inside of this method, I first create an instance of calculator class and then I use an object of calculator
class to invoke the integer subtraction method, which is my method.
Under test, I'm testing integer subtraction method and I give it to parameters and value of 33 and
after hand with value of one, one will be subtracted from 33 and the difference will be assigned to
a result.
Local learnable.
All right, so the integer subtraction method is my method under test.
It is this method that I'm testing with this unique test, and I want to make sure that this method
works well and that it returns an expected result.
So when one is taken away from 33.
I expect the result to be 32.
And to validate this, I use assert equals assertion to check if the result which is an actual value.
Second input parameter is equal to 32, which is expected result.
All right.
And if I go into integer subtraction method here, I have a very simple business logic where I simply
subtract one value from another.
So the logic is very, very simple.
But when writing unit test, I should not really worry how complex the business logic is inside of this
method under test.
Method under test can have long and complex code, but that should not worry me much.
All I care about is that this method that I'm testing returns an expected result for providing the input
parameters.
All right, so let's run this unit test and see if it works.
I will click on a run button, which is next to the method name and we'll choose a run integer subtraction
method.
And it passed.
Now, when testing our integer subtraction method or when testing integer division method or when this
than any other method under test, we should test it with both valid and invalid input parameters.
We should think of all the possible input values that can make our method under test break or produce
unexpected results.
Will it still work?
For example, if I give it values that are too large or values that are too small?
If input parameters are strings.
Then will it work if the string value is too short or if it is too long?
If the input parameter is an object, then will my method under test still work?
If I give it now instead of a real object and for each different, each case that can potentially make
my method under test would return unexpected result.
I should create a separate unit test method and this means that they can have several different test
methods, each testing the same method under test, but with different input parameters.
All right.
So we will add a couple of more unique methods here a bit later.
But for now, let's continue the next lecture.