In this lesson, we will configure our test class to order test methods execution by name.
And for this demonstration, I will create a new class as well.
I'll create a new course and I will call this new first class methods ordered by me.
Now our copy test methods from a previous test class.
And will paste them here.
And to configure, you need to execute methods in this class in a specific order.
I will annotate this class with test method order annotation.
To configure method execution order by mental theme.
I will use method order.
And from the older auctions I will choose method name.
Now with this configuration, two unions will order a method by their name and method arguments.
And to me this demonstration more obvious.
I intentionally use very simple test method names.
And what I will also do, I will change the order of this method a little bit.
For example, I will move method, test D and the top and then I will move test C method, be it right
after test A so that they appear in a random order in my test class.
All right, so let's run methods in this class and see if two units will sort execution order by method
name.
I will click on the run button.
And we have expected result the very first test method that Iran is test he second is to be test C and
test D.
All test methods are sorted by their name.
All right, so it all worked.
And you now know how to configure G-Unit to order method execution by method name.
Let's continue.