In this lesson you will learn how to stop a method using Mikita's built in arguments manager.
Now we have used more connotation to tell Mikita to create a mock object that implements users repository
interface because user's repository is now a mock object and it is not a real one.
We need to tell Mikita what to do when we invoke methods that are defined in this interface.
So let's do it in one of our test methods.
For example, the very first one, I do not have a range section here.
I have moved it to the init method so I will create a new one and in the orange section I will use a
special method that Mikita provides and it is called when.
Inside of this.
One minute I will invoke the save method.
I will use use.
Suppose the object.
And then I will quote save method on it.
Now, with this line of code, I see that when a save method is called on, uses three powers to object.
Then I wanted to do something.
And because save method returns above in volume, I will need to make it return a boolean value through.
Okay, so in this particular example, the save method that is defined the end user.
Suppose the interface returns a boolean value.
But if you look at other options, then you will see that you can also request Makita to throw an exception.
For example, when the saved method is called.
Or we can even request Makita to call a real method when this save method is invoked.
Right.
But for now, when the save method is invoked, I wanted to return a predefined value which is going
to be a boolean value.
True.
So with this line of code, I now see that when the saved method is called on the user repository object,
then I want Makita to return to.
Now the same method accepts a parameter, and in our case it is a user object.
And because I do not invoke real slave method, it does not really what I I'm going to pass here as
user object so we can create an object of user clause and then stub with with any values we want.
Okay.
So to start by I meant that in Makita we can use my built building arguments matcher and to do that
inside of save method has it parameter I will type my ketone and then any which is an argument matcher
and then I need to provide a data type or a name of the class which is going to be user class.
All right.
So with this line of code, we tell Makita that it can use any object of user clause and we do not really
care about values that user object has.
Okay, so let's save changes in this class and now we are ready to run our method and see if it passes.
So I will run only this one method.
And we have a and test method.
Now let's run this method again.
But this time we will configure save method to return value false.
Assuming that when save method was called, it could not proceed to the details and the result is a
boolean value false.
Let's see what happens.
I will save changes and then I will run this test method again.
And now a testament that fails because saved method returned false and according to how we have implemented
the create using method.
Here if the save method returns false, we through user service exception with a message could not create
user.
And this is what we have here.
A user service exception with the message could not create user.
Okay, so let's make our test method pass again.
And to do that, I will go back to my test method and will configure Makita to return.
True.
When saved method is involved now I will see changes and will run this test method again and now it
passes.
Now to see if the real save method is never called.
I can execute this test method in engine backbone and to do that I will open saved method and will add
in debugger breakpoint inside of saved method.
I'm doing it just to see that the real segment that is never included and my key to always use a smoke
object that I have created.
Now I will go back to use a service test and I will run this test method, Ingeborg mode.
I will click on the wrong button and then will choose debug.
My test meant did wrong.
It did pass, but a breakpoint in a real segment that never triggered.
Okay, so this confirms that the business logic inside of my creative romantic was tested in isolation
without invoking code dependencies, without executing real code inside of this save method.
Okay, so everything is working well and we're good to continue.