In this video lesson, we will start working on the test method that will test if the create user API
endpoint works and if we can create a new user.
So I will start creating a new method.
I will also add display name and the display name will be something like user can be created.
So this method will test create user method and this means that I will start my test method name with
void test create user, which is the name of my method on the test when valid user details provided,
then it should return the created user details.
Something like this test create user method when valid user details provided returns created user details
and they will also divide my method structure into arrange, act and assert.
Now let's have a quick look at the create user method in the controller class.
This one.
So to invoke creative as a method, we will need to send a HTTP post request because it is annotated
with post mapping to forward slash users API endpoint and this request will need to contain HTTP body
because this method accepts request body and the content of HTTP request body will be converted into
a Java object of user details, request, model, data type and the user details that we will need to
send in the body of this HTTP post request are first name, last name, email password and repeat password.
So let's prepare this HTTP request.
I'll go back to my test method and we'll work on the request.
Now when testing controller method with mock MVC, we are not going to send an actual relationship request
over the network.
Spring Framework provides us with a clause which we can use to configure a mortgage request and it is
called more MVC Request Builder.
More can we see request builders and then I can invoke a HTTP post with a URI and here I can simply
provide path to a user's API endpoint like this.
Now this is a builder and I can continue building this request.
For example, I can provide content type header, which in this case I want the application JSON.
And I can provide it should be Heather.
That's called accept which I also want to be application Jason.
Okay.
And now I will configure the content of HTTP body, which is going to be the JSON string with the user
details.
Now I can type JSON string manually or I can use user details, request model class to create a Java
object and then convert this Java object into a string.
And this is what I'm going to do.
So maybe above here I will create a new object of user details.
Request model.
Data type.
And we'll use certain methods to populate it with information.
I will set first name.
Last name.
Email and password.
And now I can use object mapper to convert this object into a string and set the string as a content
of http request by.
So I'll go back to my request builder and I will use a content method and now I will use object mapper
to convert Java object into a string.
And the object that I'm going to convert is my user details request model, and this will build as a
request builder object.
Now let's move mouse over, write value as a string and it wants us to add exception to our method signature.
So I'll do it.
And this will add throws adjacent process and exception to my test method signature.
All right, so request builder is ready.
And now in the ACT section, I can perform this request.
And to do that, I will need to use another object that is called Mock MVC.
I will scroll up and I will inject Mock MVC into my test class.
And now I will scroll down and I will use the smoke and visit to execute the request I have prepared.
And in response I want to get a result and the result is returned in a form of more result object.
All right.
So this line will execute the request object that we have prepared and it will return us MVC result
which we can use to read response object from and from this response object we can read content of response
body.
So let's do that.
I will first read the response object.
And now from this response object, I can get the status.
It should be headers and it should be response body.
So to get the content of response body, I will use the get content as string and this will return me
the response body as a string.
Now we have a couple of underlining if I move mouse over the perform method, it wants me to add one
more exception to the method signature.
I will do that.
Okay.
And now no more underlining.
So this response body as string variable, it will contain the details of newly created user.
And I can work now with this string and validate if it contains expected to the details.
So what I can do, I can convert it back into a data type that my controller method returns.
So let's have a look at what our controller method returns.
I'll go back to user controller and here's the method I'm testing.
And this method returns an object of user rest data type.
So when this method returns back, an object of user data type, spring framework will convert this
object back to adjacent string and then return it back in HTTP response body.
And I do have response bodies three now so I can convert it back to an object of user data type.
And to do that I will use object mapper.
I can.
And we'll use method that is called read value and it takes in the string that it needs to parse and
a data type that it needs to convert this string into.
And in my case, it is user arrest.
And as a result, we will get back user rest object.
I will call it created user.
Like this.
So now I can work with this created user object and validate if it contains correct user details.
So in that search section of my test method, I will add a few assertions.
I will first validate users first name and to do that I will use assert equals.
Expected value is inside of user details, request, model, object, and the actual value is inside
of the created user object.
And if these two values are not equal, then I know something went wrong.
I will provide a hint message.
Something like the returned user's first name is most likely incorrect.
And now I will add a few more insertions to the last name email and I will make sure that user ID was
also created and returned back.
And we'll make sure that user ID is not empty.
And if it is empty, I will display a hint message that user ID should not be empty.
Okay.
Something like this.
Now, before I run this test method, there is one more thing I want to do.
Let's go back to a controller class one more time.
This is our create user method that we're testing.
So this creative digital's method has a dependency on users service object because I'm testing integration
of my code with Sprint framework web layer only.
I'm not interested in invoking code in the service layer, and I'm not interested in invoking code in
the data layer.
So instead of using a real implementation of user service object, I will move this object and use a
mock object instead.
So let's work on it in the following lesson.