In previous lesson, we have prepared user details that we will use in a HTTP post request to create
a new user.
And in this lesson we will prepare and will perform this post request.
Now, our request might also need to include a HTTP headers and we can build the B headers this way.
Still in the arranged section, I will prepare a HTTP headers.
My this, and now that I have a hundred subject, I can use it to set up headers.
For example, one HTTP header that I might want to set is content type and it is going to be application
JSON.
And another header that I might want to set is accept header and it will also be application JSON.
But in this case I will need to set a list of headers, so I will use arrays as list and then provide
my HTTP header media type application.
Geez.
And now I'm ready to use this should be headers in a HTTP request and this time to send the request.
I will use a HTTP client that is called risk template.
So let's inject it into our test class.
I will use the word annotation and will inject my client.
Now I have mentioned that I'm going to use a rest template, but I have actually injected the stress
template.
If you are familiar with a rest template, then you know that it is an ACP client that allows us to
send the requests and receive packaged responses and we can use the rest client to test our API as well.
The test rest template object that I have injected here is an alternative to rest template.
And although these two objects are very similar, the test dress template is a different object and
it does not extend a regular template.
So although we can use both of these objects to test our application for testing, it is easier and
simpler to use test trace template, especially when user authentication is involved.
And we need to include username and password.
All right, so we have our recipe client and we can use it to send the request.
So let me scroll down and to send the request with test template object.
We need to put our headers and user details Jason into a single HTTP entity object.
So I will continue working with a range section and here I will prepare a HTTP entity object.
So the constructor of the entity that I'm using here accepts the user details as a string.
So this is going to be a JSON string.
And the HTTP headers that we have just prepared here, now that I have my entity object, I can use
it with the template object to send a HTTP post request.
So in the act section now I will use a test res template object to send the shape post request and get
back response entity.
And the method that I'm going to use is called post for entity.
I will need to provide URL path, which is going to be users.
I will need to provide request object that I have just prepared here and I will need to provide data
type of the object that I want to get back as a response.
So if I use string data type here, then in response back I will get JSON string which I can then convert
into Java object and work with that Java object.
Or I can ask my HTTP client test risk template to convert the JSON string to a needed Java object right
away.
So let's have a look at the rest controller and see what we are getting back.
When we send the HTTP post request to four slash users, I'll go back to users controller and here's
my create user method that handles HTTP post request and in response back it returns an object of a
user as data type.
This object will then be converted into a JSON string and returned in the body of response.
So we can ask our client object to convert this JSON string right into an object of user data type.
So let's go back to our test method and do that.
So as a return value, I will specify response entity.
That will hold user rest object and I will call it created user details and.
My intense let's put things on their own lines.
We have an underlining.
It says that I have incompatible times.
I'm expecting back user rest, but I have configured my rest template to return string data type so
I will replace string with a user rest.
Now the response entity object here will allow us to get information about HTTP response and we can
use this object to get a HTTP status code, HTTP headers and the HTTP response body and the way we can
get user rest object from a response entity object is this way.
I will take responsibility object.
And from this response and object I can get body of HTTP response and that body of which HTTP response
will contain my user rest object.
And now in the assert section I can check if this created user details object contains correct value
and if needed.
I can also validate HTTP response status code and headers.
But for now, let me just validate stored status code as an example.
The expected value is going to be HTTP status code 200, which is OC and the actual value I will read
from create user details entity object by calling get status code method.
And now I can validate that the return to the details object contains correct information, so I will
use assertions again.
Insert equals.
And now as an expected value, I will use user details, request cheese and the original object.
And from this object I can get a string value with key first name.
So this is an expected value, but the actual value will be in the created user details object.
We can get it by calling get first name like this.
And if these two values do not match, then we can display a hint message.
Like, for example, the returned user's first name seems to be incorrect.
Something like this.
So now I will add additional assertions to validate all the fields my class name, email and user ID.
All right.
So now I think we're ready to execute our test method and see how it works.
Let's do it.
And the following lesson.