Monk objects allow us to verify how many times the method in the mock object was called.
And this is very helpful, especially with the save method.
We want to make sure that the user mounted.
If I go inside, we want to make sure that the create user method invokes save method exactly one time.
If this same amount was not called at all, or it was called more than one time, then we have a problem.
So we want our test method to verify and make sure that this save method was called exactly one time.
Otherwise, our test method should fail.
And to do that with my kids, we can use a special market method that is called verify.
I will add it in the assertion section and the bottom.
My kids do it very fine.
The refinement that takes two parameters.
The first one is the more common, which is, in our case, user repository.
And the second parameter is verification mode.
And verification mode, which specified the desired number of method locations.
In this particular case, it is one time and finally at the end, we need to specify the method that
we expect to be called.
In our case, it is a save method, but the same method accepts user object as a parameter.
And to provide this parameter I will use my key this argument matcher.
Mikey to duck any and then the user across.
Let's put it on a new line.
So with this line of code, we ask my kid to verify that the same method that is in the users repository
mock object was called exactly one time.
Otherwise, this test method should fail.
So let's try.
If it works.
I will run this test.
And it passes.
Let's try to break it.
For example, instead of one time, I will specify zero times and write again.
And now it fails.
Let's make it fast again.
And now it passes over.
And let's assume that the safe method was never caught.
I will go inside of create user.
And will either comment out or let's say it was invoked accidentally two times one time.
And then again we made a mistake and we accidentally invoked save method two times.
I'll save changes, go back to my test method and run it again.
And now our test method fails with an error message that there were too many actual invocations.
All right, so let's make it pass again.
I will delete the extra line, save it and make my test method pass again.
Then it works.
Now there are other useful methods that allow us to verify the number of invocations.
For example, if I add my Quito, then there is, for example, at least, which is the first method
in the list.
And you will use this method to verify that this saved meant it was called at least the number of times
specified as the method argument.
For example, at least two times it could be called more, but not less than the specified number of
times.
Or you can use at most.
And you will use this method to verify that this save method was called not more than the specified
number of times.
It can be called less then, but not more than the number of times to specify as the parameter to this
method.
There is also at least one method, and you will use this method to verify that the saved method was
called at least one time, and there is also at most once, for example, and you will use this method
to verify that this save method was called maximum one time, if it was not called at all.
And then it is also fine for if we wanted to make sure that a certain method was never called, then
we could use, for example, never Mike either.
Never.
But in the case of this, this method, using Makita times to make sure that the save method was called
exactly one time is a better option.
So I will do read this one and there's one improvement that I can do to my method.
We have used static methods like for example, Makita times is a static method and Makita is a static
method.
Every time we call this static methods, we need to refer my key to class.
So instead of repeating Makita class, every time I need to call a static method, I will add a static
input statement to my class instead.
So I will scroll up and will add the static input.
Playing this and now I can delete my key the class from my test it.
So here when I use argument matcher, I can delete my kita and use just any.
And here as well, I can do with my kid.
Now let's execute this test method to make sure that it still works.
And it passes.
Now when we use myki to verify together with times verification mode, then if the value of the wanted
number of times is only one, we can actually omit verification mode altogether.
And this is because one is a default value.
So when it is number of times only one, I can actually delete verification lock and it should still
work and verify that the safe method was called exactly one time.
Now will run this method one more time.
And it works.
So with this configuration, when we now do not have verification mode, when we use default value,
if I accidentally invoke save method twice, it should also thing.
So let's try.
I'll go inside of create user method and I will add one more invocation of this save method.
Save it.
Go back to my test method and run it again.
And now it fails because there are too many actual implications.
All right.
So let's make it pass again.
I will go back to my user service implementation and we'll fix my code, save it, go back to my test
method and run it again.
And it works.
All right.
So now you know how to make sure that the dependency logic inside of the method that you are testing
is used once, more than once, or it was never used at all.
Well, let's continue to the next lesson.