In this lesson, you will learn how to make your test methods execute in any order you like.
Being able to control which this method executes first and which this method executes it second is very
helpful when you're working with integration tests, especially with those tests that need to save something
in the database and then find that same record, update that same record, and then delete that same
record.
In this case is being able to control which this method runs first and which this method runs second
easily.
So for this demonstration, I'll create a new tense class, and I will add to it same test methods.
So I will copy this test methods and I will create a new class and I will call this new test class.
Methods ordered by order index.
I will paste test methods and to continue to, you need to execute test methods in this test class in
a specific order.
I'll need to annotate this test class with test method.
Order annotation.
Mindless to specify a specific method order, I will use method, order, interface and then to be able
to order my test methods in any order I like, I will need to use order annotation like this.
Now, currently my test methods in a class appear in a random order, but if I remove test method order
annotation and execute this test methods, they will not execute in the order.
I have them in this test class in mind this class I have method test D restarts first and then a half
test a least it makes and then test C.
So if I run my test that's now, it will execute in a different order.
Let's try.
And in this report I see that the order in which these methods executed is different from what I have
in my class, in that this report meant that we executed first and met a be executed second.
So now I will use order annotation to make my test methods execute in the order that I have listed them
in my test class.
I want method tested to execute first.
So I will use order annotation within this one.
And because I'm using one as order index, this method will be executed first.
The second test method that I want to execute will be test A, so I will also annotated with order annotation.
And for this annotation I will use index to because I want this this method to execute second.
And now I will apply the same annotation with a different index for the rest of my test methods.
So I have or there one or the two or three or there four.
And now I will enable the test method or the annotation with method order set to order annotation.
And now I will save changes and this test class and I'm ready to run it and see how it works.
So I'll click on the run button.
And I have expected result.
Method test the executed first method test a executed second and so on.
All right.
So I hope it also worked very well for you.
And you now know how to execute your test methods in a specific order and the order that you need.
But remember, unless you absolutely need to use a specific execution order, most of the time it is
better that your test methods do not depend on each other and they can still work well, even if the
execution order is random.
Let's continue.