All right.
So I have added two more assertions to my test method and these are to check if the last name that the
user object contains is equal to the last name.
I have used to create this user object and an assertion to validate if the email address is also correct.
Now if I open user class then here I added two more instance variables a last name, an email address,
updated constructor to initialize this variables and I have added two more get them and to be able to
retrieve this values.
If I open user service implementation clause, then here I create a new instance of user clause using
the updated constructor that accepts last name on the email address as well.
All right.
So now I can go back to my user service test class and run this test method to see if it works.
And it successfully passes.
I hope you were also able to complete this exercise successfully and if needed.
You can download source code of this exercise.
I will attach it to this lecture.
All right, so let's continue.