In this lesson, you will learn about new annotation that is called Mock Bean, and we will use this
annotation to create a mock object for our user service.
Now, you might wonder, why are we going to create mock object again?
Are we not working on integration test in this section?
And the answer is yes, we are working on the integration test.
But in this section of the course we are testing web player only, only web slides of our application
and we are not testing service layer and we are not testing data layer.
We are testing if the create user method in the controller class is correctly integrated with a risk
controller and with spring framework features related to risk controller.
So because we are testing how our method under test which is create user works in integration with sprint
framework components in the web player, it will be called an integration test.
But I do agree because we start mocking dependencies, it does look like a unit test.
So to isolate web player related code, the code inside of create user method that is annotated with
post annotation from a real implementation of user service.
I will need to mock user service object and to do that I will use mock bean annotation.
So let's go back to our test method and I will scroll up a little bit and above the test method.
On the class level, I will add one more field, I will use more bean annotation and I'm going to mock
users service.
Okay.
So what this mock bean annotation will do is it will create a mock object for the object that implements
user service interface.
The user service is an interface and the only class that implements this interface is user service implementation.
If there are other classes that implement the same interface, they will need to use qualifier annotation.
Or you can also use mock bean annotation on the class level.
In this case, what you're going to do, you can copy mung bean annotation and then define it on the
class level.
Inside of curly brackets, you will provide a list of all classes that it needs to mock.
For example, in my case, it will be users service, implementation class, and then if there are more
classes, then I will add comma and list other classes here.
But I'm going to mock only one class and because I'm using mock bean here, then on the field level,
I will simply need to also the mock object that I have created here.
So it is either you list mock bins above the class and then auto wire them using auto annotation, or
you do not use mock bean at the class level and simply use a single mock bean annotation above the field.
So this will create a mock object for user service.
Now the difference between mock bean annotation and a regular mikita's mock annotation.
For example, in previous lessons we have used more connotation to create mock objects.
So the difference between these two is that mock bean annotation.
It will create mock object and it will automatically put this mock object into sprint application context.
But this regular mikita's mock annotation that we have used earlier, it will not automatically place
mock object into sprint application context, but because we're testing springboard application and
we do need more object in Sprint application context, we will use mock being annotation instead of
mock.
All right.
So now that we have created mock object for user service, we can mock its behavior.
So let's go back to our users controller class and see what it does.
So when our method in the controller class receives a HTTP post request sent to four slash users API
endpoint, it will invoke this method and it will use user service object to invoke create user method
on the service class because user's service is now a mock.
We want to mock the create user method and we want to make it return a predefined user DTO object.
So let's do that.
Let's create a predefined user data object and make our user service mock object return a predefined
object.
Instead, I'll go back to my test class.
We'll scroll down to the test method and maybe a right here and there user details request model.
I will create a new user data object.
And now I will use Setterfield to set user details information.
First name.
Last name.
Email and user ID.
Now here I create user data object and then I manually set each of the details separately.
I can go this way, or because I do have user details already in this object and these are exactly same
user details.
What I can do, I can map all information from this object into user detail object.
And this way my code will be shorter.
So what I can do instead.
Let me comment out this piece of code I can use model mapper.
And I can mop information from the source object, which is going to be my user details request model
to a new object of user DTO data type.
And this will give me a user DTO object.
This way my code is much shorter, but it doesn't have user ID, so I will need to set user ID manually.
Okay.
So now I can more create using method and make it return.
This user DTO object lets input static method from work marketer marketer one then return user DTO.
So when user service object is used to call create user method with any object of user DTO type as a
parameter, then we will return the user data object.
Let's input any.
As a static from arguments my interest package.
And now I think we can run this test method and see if it works.
Let's do it in the following video lesson.