Now there are different ways to create a project, and there are different tools to build and manage
dependencies in our project.
Which one of these tools you use?
I do not know, but there is a first class support for a unique platform that exists in popular ideas
like Anthology, Eclipse, NetBeans and the Visual Studio Code.
And there are many popular build tools that support G-Unit.
Some of them are made in the cradle and and for example.
So in this video, of course, I'll show you how to set up G unit in different types of projects.
You will learn how to score them G-Unit and Maven and Gradle based Jammer project, and they'll show
you how to create a new project and how to set up do union using popular development environments like
anthology and equips.
If you do not use Raven and Gradle, then you can simply skip those lessons until you need them in the
future.
In section of this course that teaches the basics of G in five, I'll show you how to create a Java
project and also how to set up G unit without using any of these tools as well.
All right.
So let's continue.