When it comes to naming the unit test methods, then technically you can give your union test method
any name you like.
But as you work with different teams and developers, you will notice that many developers follow a
specific naming convention to help them make test methods more descriptive.
And one of this common conventions I will share with you here in this lesson.
It is good to make the name of the test that descriptive and speak for itself.
And the goal is to understand what the test method is going to test just by looking at the method name
rather than by looking at the code it contains and try to figure it out from the code and the pattern
for naming testament that is this I will and then in the comments.
So it starts with the test and then the name of the system under test or the name of the method and
the test.
Underscore condition or state change.
Underscore and then expected result.
So this is the template that we are going to follow.
Let's apply this pattern to an integer division method.
So instead of naming my mentored integer division, I will start with a test.
Then I will continue with a name of the system under test or method.
And there test.
The method under test is integer division.
So I will continue test.
Integer division, then underscore.
Then after the underscore goes condition or state change, for example, I can continue with something
like when four is divided by two.
Or I could say when divisor is a valid integer, then again underscore and after the underscore goes
the expected result.
What should the integer division method do if four is divided by two?
The expected result is that it should return to.
Like this.
Let's consider and then get this and I will add a new test rate below.
And I'm going to test the same integer division method.
So I will start with test and then my method under the test is integer division.
Underscore and then there will continue with when dividend is divided by zero, then it's a true arithmetic
exemption.
And the expected result should throw an enigmatic exception.
All right.
So the idea here is to make the test method name descriptive so that they can figure out what this test
method is doing by reading its name and not by reading its code.
So when I look at this test method mean then I write test integers.
The reason I know that the system or the method under test is called integer division.
When dividend is divided by zero, then it should throw arithmetic exception.
And this sounds pretty clear to me.
Now you might say that it is pretty obvious what this test method is doing by looking at its code.
It is very small and simple, but believe me, not all test methods are short and simple like this one.
And this grouping of testing will be very helpful as basically when you're reviewing test methods written
by someone else.
And there is a lot more test methods in the class and there is much more code in the test method itself.
Now, one of the disadvantages of this approach is that a name of a test of length, this will look
very well-known in the test report.
Let's try running all of our tests in this class.
To do that, I will click on the run button, which is next to the class name.
I will run a calculator test.
And here is my test report.
And the names of these two methods now look very long.
But there is a way to make this names look shorter and less technical.
So let's continue.
And in the following lecture, you will learn about another very useful plantation that will help you
make the display name of your unit look better.