In this lesson, we will continue working with mock objects and we will try how exceptions type works.
The method and testing is create user and it has a dependency on users repository because we want to
test to create user method in isolation from its dependencies.
We have mock that user repository object so the user's repository is now a more common you.
Now let's open create user method for a moment.
In this lesson I want to test that might create user method returns expect that result even when this
save method throws an exception.
And because user repository is now a mock object, I can configure it to always throw specific exception
when the save method gets executed.
So make in my users repository mock object to always throw an exception when the save method is invoked
is called exception step.
Let's see how it works.
I'll go back to my test method and in this lesson I will test that the creators and method or method
under test returns expected result.
When the save method is invoked and throws an exception, I will actually create a new test method.
For that I will scroll down and will create a new test method.
I'm going to test the same creative semantics and then will test the use case that once saved method
returns any random exception.
Then it is called and the user series exception is thrown instead.
So I will continue when save method throws exception.
Then my method on the test throws use a serious exception.
Okay.
So I'm testing create as amended one save method throws exception.
Then my method under test throws users an exception and they will create method, structure, arrange
and assert.
Something like this.
Now, if you come up with a bird at this name, then it is even better.
And that will also include this information in a display name.
Simple like this, and in the arrange section I will work with my mock object and will do exemption
stamping.
I will use monkey this static method when then inside of one I will refer to more compute user repository
and will invoke the save method with any instance of user class as a parent and one segment that is
invoked on users repository object.
Then I want to throw an exception.
Now this project is currently not configured to work with any specific database, and I cannot fully
use any specific database exception here.
So for this demonstration, I'll make my segment that through a general runtime exception.
Like this.
And now in the ACT section, I will actually invoke my method under test and will assert that it throws
users areas exception.
And I will simply copy the invocation of Great Joseph from my different testament and pasted here and
there will also add an optional error message.
Something like this should have thrown use a service exemption instead.
If create user is invoked and user service exception was not thrown, I will see this message in the
report.
Should have thrown a user service exception instead.
All right.
So we have configured our save method to throw a runtime exception when it is invoked permitted under
test this create user.
So we invoke it and then we assert that these on vacation should throw user service exception.
If user service exception is not thrown, then we should see this error message in this report.
Let's try.
If it works, I will run this test method.
And it fails because user Sara's assumption is not wrong.
So let's minimize our test report and go inside of create user and have a look at it.
Now, if save method throws runtime exemption, then we need to catch it and instead we need to throw
user Sarah's exception.
So let's add this try and catch block here.
Something like this, except that maybe a piece in Stoicism is not required.
All right, so now I will save changes to my code, and we'll go back to my test method and run it again.
It worked.
I can also run this test method in a department and check if the user serious exception is indeed thrown.
I'll go back to my creators.
I meant it and we'll put a debugger breakpoint inside of Try and catch where I catch the runtime exception.
Now I'll go back to my test method and we'll run it in deep, dark mode.
And here's my debugger breakpoint triggered inside of cache block and this also proves that my exception
stabbing does work and the save method through runtime exception, just like I have configured it to
do.
All right, so let's resume programming as a cushion and switch back to console and unit test is now
passing.
All right.
So it all worked very well for us.
And you now know how to do more compute exception study with monkey to.