In this lesson, you will learn how to order execution of test classes.
And for this demonstration, I have created a separate project and I have attached to this lecture.
You can pose this video, lesson, download and open my project in your development environment.
Or you can watch this video, listen first and then try practicing with your own classes.
Now, once you open this project in your development environment, you'll see three test classes order
a service test, product service test and user service test.
We're going to order the execution of test methods in these three classes.
Now, although those classes typically should not rely on the order in which they're executed, there
are times when it is desirable to enforce a specific test class execution order.
You might want to specifically indicate that this class should execute unit tests in a random order.
For example, this is to ensure that there are no accidental dependencies between this test classes
or when doing integration testing.
You might want to control which this class executes first and which this class gets executed second.
You might also want to consider execution of your test classes just to make your test reports look more
organized.
In each of those classes that I have on this project, I have an empty test method and also one setup
method, and this attack method will run before test method and then class, and it will print a message.
For example, in this user service test class, then one such ease test methods related to user.
Similarly, in other test classes, for example, if I opened a product service test, the message that
will be printed says test methods related to product service and the event Auckland Order Service.
The message says Test methods related to Order Service.
Now if I execute all test classes in this project, I don't really know which one will run first and
which one will run second.
So let's try.
I will select test folder, I will do right click and then will choose run old tests.
Now, if I look at the test report, then I see that product really did test run first.
Then ordinarily two tests run first and then usually two tests at the end.
If I'm doing the integration testing, then I want to use the related tests to execute first.
Then this is because product cannot be ordered without an existing user account, for example.
So the order in which I want these tests to be executed is I want all user related tests to run first,
then I want product related tests to run first.
And at the end I want all the related tests current.
So to specify which this class will be executed first and which this class will be executed second,
I will use order annotation.
I will open user service test and will add order annotation above the class.
For this class I will use index one because I want user related tests to run first.
Once the user related unit tests complete, I want product related tests to run next.
So I will annotate product service test with order annotation with index two.
And at the end I want all the related tests to run and I will add order annotation above the order service
class name with index three.
Now I will save changes in all of my classes and in previous lessons we have used the method order to
configure the execution order of our test methods.
Now instead of configuring execution order for method or a class in each class g unit allows us to provide
this configuration for entire project globally.
And to do that we will use property from the property file will need to be placed into resources folder.
I don't have it yet so I will need to create it.
I will select test folder and will do right last week.
Choose new and then package.
I will call this package resources.
And now I will do right models, click on resources and will choose open module settings.
On the left side, I want modules to be selected then the current module.
And on this panel here I will select resources package which is under test directory.
And from the buttons above here I will click on Test Resources Button to mark this directory as a Test
Resources throughout.
Once I do it, the icon on the resources folder should slightly change once than I will click on a key
button to close this window and now inside of Resources package.
I will create a property file to do that I will do right mouse click, then choose new and then choose
resources bundle.
The name of this property file will be G Unit dash platform.
No need to add those two properties, just unit dash platform and click on okay button.
And so now I have two units planned for properties far created in this property file.
I'll need to add the following property to you and Dot Jupiter dot first class.
One word dot order dot default equals and the value is org dot g unit, dot jupiter dot api north and
then class order.
And finally I'll select order annotation like this.
Okay if I want those classes, those are cute.
Run them instead of using order annotation then I will use.
A random instead, or if I want the order to be controlled by the closely, then instead of choosing
a random, I will choose closely.
Okay.
But I will go with order annotation and will select order annotation.
Now you can use exactly the same approach to configure method execution globally and to do that instead
of death class.
Here you will provide the same property with instead of first class.
Here you will type this method right and the value will be org g unique jupyter and then API.
And then instead of class order you will choose method order and then dot and select method order.
For example, order annotation method, then a patient or random.
All right, so I'm not going to configure method order.
So I will do this and will continue only with the class order.
Now I will save changes to my G unit plot from Properties file and I'm ready to run all tests in this
project and see how it works.
To do that I will do right mouse click on the test folder and then choose a run.
All tests.
I got an error message and I wonder why it says class not found exemption order annotation.
Oh, I think I made a typo instead of dot.
I should have used the dollar sign between class order and order annotation.
So instead of gold here, we should use dollar sign.
Now let's save this and let's try running this test again.
Run all tests.
And now all of them pass.
The first class that got executed is user.
The second is product and last is order, which is correct.
All test classes got executed in the order that we have configured with order annotation.
All right.
So it is working very well.
And you now know how to control execution order of test classes as well.
All right.
So let's continue.