And this lesson will create a new test method to check if they create user method through correct exception
when one of the required fields is missing.
For example, if a user's first name is missing, then we want our create user method to throw an elegant
argument exception.
Right.
So let's work on it.
In this section I practice test driven development, so I will start writing test code first.
I will scroll down a little bit and here I will add a New Testament.
I'm testing the same create user method.
So the name of my method under test is create user.
Now the use case I want to test is when first name is empty.
So I will include it into the test method name as well when the first name is empty.
Underscore.
And the expected result is that the creators of minted in this case should throw an illegal argument
exception.
So I will continue throws illegal legal argument exemption.
Something like this.
I think I made a typo illegal.
All right.
And I will add this plane name as well.
For example, empty firstname cozies correct exception.
And I will create the arrange act and insert sections.
All right.
So I will need to call decreed using method and provide provided with the same parameters, which means
that the arrange section will be almost the same again.
So I will screw up and I will copy the arrange section from my previous test method.
But the first name should be empty, so I'll make it empty.
And now I can use the instance of user service implementation to invoke the method under test and provide
it with this parameters.
Create user and I will give it they needed parameters.
The first name, last name, email password.
Repeat password.
All right.
So now I need to assert that this call throws an argument exception and we can do it this way.
We will use assertions and then assert throws assertion.
The expected type is a legal argument exception.
And then I need to provide the executable, which is going to be a lander.
And at the end I will provide a message.
For example, empty first name should have caused a legal argument exception.
And I will move the invocation of my method under test inside of this alumni function.
All right, so we have invoked the method under test, and we have an assertion that will validate if
the call to create them entered through.
And then we an argument exception.
I'll change the section handler to act and assert.
Okay.
So at this point we did invoke method under test and we do have one assertion.
So it's a good time to run our test method and see if it passes.
Let's try.
And it fails.
Our assertion fails with a message.
Empty first names should have coast to legal argument.
Exception.
Expect the exception is a legal argument exception.
But nothing was thrown.
And the next step in the testing and development process is to fix this issue and make our test method
pass.
So I will go to each of them and it will open its implementation and I will check.
Why is it that it does not throw exception and it does not throw a legal argument exception because
there is no code for it, so let's implement it.
I will simply check it.
First name is not now.
Or if its lens is nonzero.
And if it is, I will throw an illegal argument exception.
With a message like user first name his empty.
Something like this.
Now our five changes to this class.
And now I will go back to my test method and try running it again.
And this time our test method passes.
And since the test method is passing, the next step in testing in development is to refactor this.
Test it.
So what is it that they can improve in the assessment?
What we can also check here is that the error message that the exception object contains is the one
that we expect in the user service implementation with through a legal argument exception with a specific
message so we can validate if our exception was which contains correct error message.
So let's do that and we'll assign the result of assert throws to a remote.
Something like this.
And now I can use this object to read the exception message and I will do it in the assert section.
I will use assert equals assertion and the first parameter that assert equals accepts is the expected
value.
The expected value I can take from user series implementation.
I will copy it from argument exception and pasted here.
Or I can actually create a new local variable in the arrange section.
For example expected.
Exception message.
My this and now I will use this local variable instead.
And the second parameter is the actual value and the actual value.
I will read from the exception object.
And now I can run my test method one more time and see if it works.
And it passes.
Let's minimize the panel and add an optional error message.
For example, accepting an error message is not correct.
I'll put it on a new line.
And we'll run my test minute one more time to make sure it works.
Okay.
So it is working well.
Now, if I look at this test method and if I look at this test method, then I see that the RNA section
is pretty much the same again.
So I can move some of the duplicate code into a lifecycle method that executes before each test.
So let's create before each method I will use before each annotation.
I will call it in it and I will use it to initialize the variable that my method under test needs.
I will cut everything from here and I will move it here and I will define instance variables above.
Like this.
And now I will delete data types from here.
Okay.
And now I can delete duplicate code from my test methods.
I have removed a range section from my first test method and I will do the same from for the second
test method.
But in this case, I will leave first name and I will leave the expected exception message because these
two local variables are unique to this test method.
All right, so now I can save changes in my test class, and I will run Old Testament ads in this test
class to make sure that all of them still work.
And both of my test methods pass use an object created and empty first name causes correct exception.
All right, so everything is working well, and we're good to continue.