To Stubbs save meant that with exception we've used my key this one then through method.
Now if this same method was a void method, then this line would not even combine to stub both method,
only to use slightly different approach.
So in the following lectures you will learn how to stop avoid methods.
Now, at this moment, I do not have any void methods in my project, so I'll create one.
Now let's assume that after a user was created and persisted in our storage, we need to send this user
an email message with request to confirm their email address.
And this new method will be avoid method.
All right, so let's quickly create a new service class inside of service package.
I will create a new interface.
And that will call it email verification series.
Inside of this interface, I'll define one method.
It's going to be VoIP and I will call it Scarjo.
Email confirmation.
So this new method is key to a male.
Confirmation will be used to put your details into a queue so that email message can be sent to this
user.
When it's a Now let's implement this interface, I will do right mouse click on the interface name and
then will choose implement interface.
I will call this interface email verification service implementation and I will put it into the same
destination package.
I'll put a little comment into this.
For example, put user details into email queue but will not write actual business logic for it.
Now, at this moment, even having this empty voice method will be enough for us to write a unit test.
But before we write our unit test, let's call this method from our user service implementation class.
So inside of create user method.
Right after a user was created.
Right after I check if user was successful.
Agreed, I will calls KGO email confirmation message and to do that they will need an instance of email
verification service.
And once they have it, he'll be able to call these kids your email confirmation method.
And we're also surrounded with try and catch.
All right.
So now we'll need to create an instance of email verification, service cost.
And to do that, they will need to first inject it into my user service implementation as dependency.
So I will define a new member vulnerable.
And I will initialize it in my constructor.
Like this.
So because I have injected email verification service as dependency into my user service implementation
clause, I can now more email verification service and inject its mock version instead.
This will allow me to test the user method in isolation from the real implementation of email notification
service.
Now it looks like I have a little typo here.
Let's fix it.
Scarjo.
Email confirmation.
And the app accepts user object as a parameter.
All right, so let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we will mock the email verification service object and will learn how
to stamp the ski to email confirmation void method with exception.
Let's continue.