In one of the previous video lessons, I have mentioned that by default you unit creates a new instance
of this class for each test method.
So if you have three test methods in a single test class, then when you run all test methods in this
test class for each test method, you unit will create a new instance of a class.
In this case, test methods are completely independent from each other and they can not share state.
You cannot share information between these test methods and the changes made to instant state by one
test method are not available in another test method.
This is default behavior and it helps to.
You need to run unit tests in isolation from each other.
Now this default behavior can be changed and if needed we can configure g unit to run test methods in
this same test instance.
If you prefer G, you need to execute all test methods on the same test instance.
Then you can annotate your test class with test instance annotation and indicate that instead of creating
a new class instance permitted, you want the new test instance per class.
When using this mode, only one test instance will be created per test class.
And this is very helpful when working with integration tests because now your test methods can share
state stored in object instance variables.
In one of previous video lessons, you have learned how to configure your test methods to run in order
one after another.
Running order tests in a single class instance and being able to share instance variables between test
methods gives you even more control when writing test methods that depend on each other.
All right, so let's continue and let's learn how to make good test methods run in a single instance
of a test class.