Now there are other this matters that you will need to write to complete the create user functionality.
For example, you can write a testimony to validate that an empty last name or empty email or empty
password also trigger a legal argument exemption.
And you can also write test method to validate if the password, for example, and repeated password
if they do not match, then an exception takes place.
And you can also implement test method to validate if the password he's eight characters long for example,
if it is alphanumeric and if it contains at least one special character.
Think of other use cases.
And then for each each case create a separate test method depending on the business requirement for
your application.
There can be many other features that you can develop following test during development.
For example, you can also implement a separate test method and make sure that users first name is longer
than one character and shorter than, let's say, 30 characters or even better.
You can follow the new and development process to implement a separate validator class, and this one
beta class will have methods that validate each of this user properties.
And then you can inject this validator class into create user method or even clause as dependency injection
and then use it in create user method to make sure that user details about it.
There are different ways how you can implement create user functionality right before continuing to
the next section as an exercise.
Try implementing a new test method to verify that an empty last name will also make this create user
method through an illegal argument exception but follow through and develop an approach and start writing
test code first.
And if you do need help, then you can download source code with a very simple solution that I will
attach to this lecture.