In this lesson, we will start working on a test method that will test if we can successfully log in
and then get back authorization access token in later lessons, we will then use this authorization
access token to communicate with protected API endpoints.
Right.
So let's start working on a new test method.
As a display name.
I will use something like logging works.
I'm going to test user login.
So I'm starting my test method name with test user login.
And then when valid user credentials are provided, it should return JWT access token in authorization
header.
So I will continue with something like when valid credentials provided.
Returns JWT in authorization header.
My intense and I will set a range act and insert sections.
Now in the arrange section, I'll need to prepare user login credentials and this is going to be JSON.
And if I were to type this JSON manually, it would look something like this or I can use JSON object
and set user login credentials using JSON object.
And this is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to use JS an object.
I will call it login credentials.
And they will set login credentials using this JSON object.
And this chase and strain, I can comment out.
Now I have a warning here and it wants me to add an exception to the method signature.
So I'll click and that will add those GS and exemption to my test method signature.
And now I can drop this user details into an HTTP entity so that I can use it in a HTTP request and
I will do it in the arranged section as well.
And in the ACT section I can perform this request.
So to do that, I will use my test arrest template object and I will call method post for entity.
Now this will need to be http post request.
So this is why I'm going to select post for entity.
And in response back it will give me a response entity object.
I could also use post for object method, but because in response I want to receive an object from which
I can read a status code.
I need to select post for entity.
So this method post entity accepts a few parameters.
And the first parameter we need to provide your role and your path will be users for login and it needs
to be users forward slash login because this is how I have configured it in my web security Java class
in my application.
So if I go to my application in the security package, I have web security, Java class.
If I open it and scroll down here, I have a method that is called get authentication filter and here
I configure the URL path to a login endpoint.
Now the default URL path is going to be just log in like this and it is provided to us by default by
sprint framework.
So we do not need to create a separate method in the controller class that handles.
This should be post request sent to for slash slogan.
So this is provided to us by default, but if needed we can change this default URL path to something
different.
And in my case I have changed it to forward slash users for slash login.
Okay, so let's close it and let's go back to our test method.
The next parameter that I'm going to provide will be request.
This is going to be our HTTP end here.
And finally, the data type to which I want the response body to be converted and because there will
be no JSON payload that will be sent back and the response body I will simply provide null here.
If user login is successful, then response status code will be 200 and my application will add a couple
of response headers and I do it in authentication filter in my application.
So if I go back to my application code again in the security package here, I have class that is called
authentication filter.
If I go there and scroll down a little bit, then I have a method that is called successful authentication.
So once user login is successful, Sprint framework will trigger this method for me.
And here in this method I generate JWT access token and then I add this JWT access token as authorization
header to the response and I also add user ID as additional HTTP header with a name user ID.
And the first header is called authorization because this stream is constant that I have created and
it holds value.
Authorization.
And so there's going to be authorization header with JWT token and user ID.
Header.
These two headers will be added to the response and return back.
So in my test method to check if user authentication is successful, I will check first if the status
code is to hungry and if it should be response contains these two headers.
Authorization header and header with a name user ID and if the values are not empty.
All right, so let's go back to our test method.
So once I perform this people's request in response, I'll get back response entity.
I will call it response.
Let's put things on separate lines like this.
And now that I have response and to the object, I can read from it.
HTTP response headers.
But first I will assert that HTTP status code is 200.
So in the assert section I will use assertions.
And I will use assert equals assertion as an expected value.
I expect http status code 200.
And this stands for OC.
And actually that is good value.
I will read from response object by calling get status code method and if these two values are not equal,
then I will display a hint message in the console.
Something like http status code should be 200.
All right.
So if this assertion is successful, then I can validate if a gdb response contains authorization header.
And I can also check if authorization header and user ID values are not empty.
So to do that I will use assert not non assertion.
And to access value of authorization header I will need to use response object, then get headers from
it, then get values as least.
And I will need to provide a name of the header that I want to read and this is going to be authorization.
Or I can actually use the same constant that I have used in my authentication filter.
So instead of hard coding authorization, I will use the same header name that I have used in authentication
filter.
Okay.
And finally, I will need to call get method with an index of zero to get its value.
And if this is null, then I will display a message in the console.
Like this.
And just the same way I can check if a response contains value of user ID.
So I will again use assertions assert not now to read user id header I will use response, get headers,
get values as least provide a name of the header and the name of the header I can copy from authentication
filter so I'll copy the name of the header and paste it here.
And go and get with an index zero.
All right.
And if this is now, I will provide a message.
Something like response should contain user ID in response header.
Something like this.
All right.
So it looks like we're done with the test method and we can try running it.
But if I do run it now, then there is no guarantee that it will pass.
And this is because for it to pass, there must be a user with this credentials in the database with
an email address that is equal to this email address and with this password.
And if this test method runs very first, then it will fail because there is no such user in the database
and my test method will fail.
So let's try.
I will scroll up and I will run all test methods in this test class.
And it fails.
I see that my login works test method did run very fast and if I check the reason why it failed.
Then I see that we are expecting a big response.
Dallas got 200, but the actual error code returned is 403.
And this is because this this method was executed first even before a new user was created.
So for this test method to pass, we will need to first create a new user and then perform a user login.
Or we could reorder these test methods so that the test method that validates user login is executed
after a new user is created.
So let's work on it in the following lesson.