When we execute test methods in a test class by default for each test method, do you need to create
a new instance of a class?
And the execution order of these methods by default is not obvious.
The best practice in most cases is to think that this meant that a run in a random order now during
the API also provides us with a few lifecycle methods.
These methods help us manage a record within G unit class and execute the record at specific phase in
at least lifecycle.
You have learnt from previous video lessons that a regular test method is annotated with test annotation.
If test class has a method that is not annotated with any annotation, then it is just a regular Java
method and it does not have to do anything with G unit test API, but test methods that invoke method
under test and assert results.
They are annotated with test annotation.
So if we go back to our little diagram, the three methods that we have here are annotated with test
annotation, but lifecycle methods are annotated with different annotations.
And one of the segmentations is, before all, a method that is annotated with before all annotation
will be executed, before all test methods in the class.
And you will use this method as a setup method to prepare and edit resources before any test methods
can execute.
For example, if you're working with a database, then this method can be used to create a database.
Another lifecycle method annotation is called after all, and a method that is annotated with this annotation
will be executed after all test methods at the very end.
So you can use this method for cleanup purposes, for example, to clean up any resources that were
needed for test methods to execute.
For example, you can use this method to develop a database that was created in and setup method in
that the lifecycle plantation is called before each and a method that they did with this annotation
will execute before each unit test meant you will use this method for setup purposes.
For example, if all of your test methods need to create the same object, then you will move this object
creation to a before each meant it.
This way you do not duplicate code in each of your test methods over and over again.
In other lines, that commendation is called after each and a method that is annotated with this annotation
will be executed after each unit test at it.
And you will use this method for cleanup purposes, for example, to close database connection that
was needed for test meant to execute.
All right, so we have four lifecycle methods.
The first one is called before all, and this method will execute before all test methods in a test
lifecycle.
The second lifecycle annotation is called before each and a method that is in the database with before
each intention will be executed.
Before each test meant that in a test class, the third line tachometer notation is called after each,
and a method that is annotated with this annotation will be executed after each.
This method in a test class and the fourth lifecycle method annotation is called after all, and it
will be executed after all test methods in the test class complete at the very end.
All right.
So let's continue.
And in the following lesson, we will see how each of this lifecycle, method and antigen works.