In the following lessons, we will look at one more example that demonstrates how you can use a single
instance with this class, and this example is more interesting and a little bit more complex than a
previous one.
We're going to test for methods.
We are going to test create user, we're going to test update user, we're going to test get user and
delete user.
In my development environment, I have a demo project opened that is called Test Lifecycle Per Class
Demo.
I have attached this project to this lecture and it would be good if you posed this video as a now.
Download this project and open it in your development environment.
This well are excellent.
This project has a single test class that is called User Service Implementation Test.
I have it opened right now and test methods in this class are currently use order annotation.
I have four test methods and each test method runs in order and the class itself is annotated with test
instance annotation that is configured to use test instance lifecycle per class.
This means that when I execute this test class, there will be only one instance of the class created
and all test meant that will share a single instance of this class.
This allows us to make this test methods depend on each other and share information between each other.
The first method is going to test create user.
The second test method is going to test code that updates existing user details and for it to work,
the first test method that creates user details needs to run first.
And this is why my test methods are ordered also to update you the details.
The second test method will need to have access to user ID, and this user idea will be created in the
first test method when it executes.
So all of this test methods depend on each other and need to be executed in specific order.
And this is why they are annotated with order annotation and for this test methods to be able to access
this same class instance variables.
These classes annotated with test instance annotation and test instance validation is configured to
use this instance lifecycle per class.
Now because there is going to be only one single instance of this class before all.
And after all, lifecycle test methods are not static.
It is that these two methods are no longer static.
If you remember from previous lessons for these two lifecycle methods to work, they needed to be static.
If I comment out the test instance annotation and enable the default behavior where a new instance of
a class is created for each test method.
Then in that case, the before and after all methods will need to be static.
But for a single instance of a class, or when you use this instance, lifecycle per class configuration,
these two methods do not need to be static.
All right.
So the business logic to create, update and delete user.
I have encapsulated in a service class.
In a service package, I have user service interface that defines four different methods.
Create user, update user, get user details and delete user.
And its implementation is in a user service implementation class.
This user service implementation class user service database that is injected into this class using
constructor based dependency injection.
And if I open user's database, this is also an interface that defines a few methods to initialize database,
to close database, and then a few methods to save user update user, find user and delete user.
And the implementation of this interface is inside of IO package.
It is a user database map implementation class and this is completely custom and my own implementation.
Instead of using actual database, I store users in a hash map that is kept in memory.
Please don't worry much about how or why I implemented this class in this particular way.
This is not important at this moment.
The goal of this demonstration, if I go back to a test class, is to give you another example that
demonstrate how you can use ordered test methods and a single instance of a test class which you enable
with the test instance annotation configurator to use this instance lifecycle per class.
All right.
So let's continue and in the following lessons, we will implement all of.
This four test methods.