In this lesson we will try how the life cycle method annotations work and I will start with annotation
that is called Before all I will screw up and at the top of my class will add a new annotation.
Before all and these are Bayesian will make your method execute one time only before old test methods.
So let's at and you it.
I will call this method set up and I will make it print something.
Executing before all method.
Also a method that is an updated with before all annotation will need to be static.
Now note is that this is not a test method.
It is not annotated with test annotation and this method will not be used to test anything.
You will use this method as a setup method, for example, to prepare resources that need to exist before
any test method can execute.
For example, if you're working with a database, then this method can be used to create that database.
All right.
And the next method that I will add will be annotated with, after all, annotation.
I will call this method clean up and I will also make it print something.
So after all annotation we'll make a method execute one time only after all test methods complete so
before all will be executed very first, then all of your test methods will execute and complete.
And at the very end we'll run the method that is annotated with, after all, annotation.
And you will use this method for cleanup purposes, for example, to clean up any resources that were
needed to be created for your test methods to execute.
If you needed a database to be created in setup method, then you can use cleanup method to delete that
database.
And also note, is that a method that is annotated with after all, annotation is also static.
So these are the methods before all and after all they need to be static.
The next method that I will add will be annotated with before each annotation.
And you will use this annotation for a method that you want to run before each test method.
So let's add a very simple method.
I will also make it print out something.
I will copy and paste this line and will replace after all annotation with before each annotation.
All right.
So you can use this method to initialize object or reset data to make sure that each test method works
with objects that have a new and clean state.
If you have code that needs to be executed before each test method, you can put this code here.
Now, our test classes are very simple and they do not have much code, but we do have something to
put here.
For example, each of our test methods, the test integer division method and the integer subtraction
method, both of this method create a new object of calculator class.
We create calculator class object here and we create a calculator class object here so we can use this
before each method to create a new instance of calculator class.
So let's do it.
I will first define a new property which is going to be a calculator.
And I will initialize it inside of before each test method.
And since there are calculated classes now created here instead of before each test method, we can
delete it from either test methods.
All right.
So before this test method executes, before each will be executed, and they will create a new calculator
object that will be used in a test mounted.
The same is true for this test method.
Before this test method executes, before each test method will run, calculator object will be created,
and my test method will work with a newly created calculator object.
All right.
And there is one more annotation that will make a method execute after each test method.
So let's add it as well.
And then we'll create a method for it.
I will also make it print out something.
And you will use this method if you need to run business logic, right?
After each this method completes like for example, closed database connection or clean up resources.
If you are running integration test for example, and your test method made some changes in the database
table, then you can use this method to delete those records.
All right.
So now we are ready to execute this test minutes and see how they work.
But before I do, I will add a little print statement to each of my test methods as well.
This one is for test integer division.
The next one is for division by zero.
And finally.
Integer subtraction.
And now I will save changes, crawl up and run old test methods in this class.
And here's my concern.
And if you trace the order in which these lines are printed, it should be according to the lifecycle
method used in this test class before all method was executed, then before each method was executed,
then we have a unit test.
Then we have after each and again a new cycle started before each.
Then we have g unit test executed.
And then we have after each.
And it looks like it is working very well.
All right.
So now that you're familiar with G unit lifecycle annotations, let's continue to the next lecture.