Previous lesson you have learned how to stamp avoid method with exception.
And to do that we have used mikita's do throw function.
Another very useful Makita, what is called do nothing and it is used to make void method do nothing
when it is invoked.
For example, here in this test method we have configured our email verification service mock object
to through email ID service exception when key your email confirmation method is called.
If I use do nothing right after it, then it will overwrite this consumer behavior and will make this
case.
Your email confirmation method do nothing when it is called.
Let's try.
So instead of do throw, I will use do nothing when email would ification service mock object is used
to invoke ski to email confirmation method with any object of user data that find this.
Now, if I ran this test meant it, then I expect it to fail because this Kishore Kumar confirmation
method will do nothing and it will not throw exception that we are expecting here.
So let's try.
And here we go.
Our test method fails with an error message that it should have thrown a user service exception instead.
We were expecting use a serious exception, but nothing was thrown.
All right.
So if in one of the lifecycle setup methods, for example, you have previously stubbed your void method
to throw an exception and you do not want this behavior in other test methods, then you can use do
nothing to explicitly tell my client that you do not want to invoke this method if it is called.
All right, so now let's and delete this to nothing and make our method pass again.
And we'll do it at save changes and run my test methods once again.
And now it passes.
All right.
So let's continue.