If you remember from early video lessons by default, test methods are executed in deterministic but
not obvious way.
And because we did not apply any specific order to our test methods, we cannot really guarantee which
test method will execute first and which test method will execute second.
So by default, we cannot guarantee that test method that creates a new user will execute first.
And the test method that performs user login will execute after the user is created.
And in this particular case, I rely on the order in which test methods are executed.
First, I want user to be created.
Second, I want to perform user login and get authorization access token.
And third, I want to use this access token to test communication with protected API endpoints.
And if the order is different, my test methods will start failing.
So in this lesson I will apply a specific order in which I want my test methods to execute.
And to do that I will scroll up and I will annotate my test class with test method.
Order annotation.
Like this and in the brackets how specify method order.
Which is going to be further annotation.
Like this, and now I can use order annotation to apply order to my test methods.
So I will scroll down to my very first method that creates a new user and I will add order annotation
with index one.
I want this method to execute first.
Once the user is created, I will then scroll down and I will execute this method that validates.
If JWT is missing, then my API endpoint responds back with four or three.
So I will execute this test method.
Second.
Next I will scroll down and I will make my test method that performs user log in to execute third.
All right.
So now that I have applied specific order to my test methods, I can run all of them and see if they
execute in this specific order.
So I will scroll all the way up.
And will execute all test methods in this test class.
And here we go.
My test methods are now being executed in the order that I wanted them to execute.
But Logan fails and it fails for the same reason we are expecting it should be status quo 200, but
we have received a HTTP status code for three and it could be because I'm using incorrect username and
password.
So I create user with email test test dot com and password is 1234, five, six, seven, eight.
Now let's scroll down and see which user credentials I use to log in.
Now email address is incorrect and password is correct.
I will save changes and I will run all test methods one more time, this time with correct email address
and correct password.
And now all of my test methods pass now because my application uses in-memory database at this moment,
after my test methods finish running, all data in in-memory database will be deleted.
And this means that I should be able to run the same test methods again and again and again, and they
should still pass.
Let's try running it one more time.
And they pass again.
All right.
So everything is working well and we're going to continue.