In this lesson, we will work on a test method that will test if we can fetch a list of users from protected
API endpoint.
So let's open risk controller for a minute.
Here's my risk controller.
And if I scroll down here, I have a method that is called get users.
And in this lesson we will write a test method that will test this API endpoint.
To invoke this method, we will need to send the HTTP, get request to a forward slash users URL path
that is defined with this request mapping at the top of our controller class.
This method also accepts to request parameters.
These are page and limit, and because these parameters have default values assigned to them, it is
optional to include them in our request.
And if our HTTP request does not include any of this request parameters, then these default values
will be used.
And if everything is good, this method will return us a list of users that are represented by user
rest data type.
If I open this class then every user will have user ID.
First name, last name and email.
Also because at this point, both application uses print security by default.
This API endpoint is protected and this means that for us to be able to invoke this method and to get
list of users, our HTTP get request will need to contain a valid JWT access token in authorization
header.
Otherwise, instead of receiving a list of users, we will get back as HTTP status code four three,
which stands for Forbidden.
All right, so let's go back to our test class and create a new test method.
Now because this test method will need to include authorization access token in http request.
I'll need to run it after I perform user login.
So after method number three.
So I will annotate this test method with annotation order and provide index four because I want this
method to run fourth.
Next, I will provide this display name and as display name value I will use something like get user
works, get for HTTP method, get forward slash users as URL path and just a label works something like
this.
And next I'll come up with a name for my test method.
Something like this test get users when valid JWT provided returns users and that will add a range act
and insert sections.
Now the HTTP request that this method will perform will need to include JWT access token in authorization
header.
So I will need to prepare a IP headers and I will do it in a range section.
And this time, just as an example, I will set the accept header using this set accept method.
It accepts list of media type, so I will use arrays as list and then will provide one media type which
will be application JSON like this.
Now I keep on adding this accept should be header, but it's actually optional because by default spring
framework supports JSON as a media type.
So if your application is not configured to use XML for example, as default media type, then you can
actually skip this header.
And next I will set authorization header with a token value.
And the way we can do it is to use set beer house method that accepts token as a parameter and I will
call it authorization token.
Maybe.
So this method will add a ship header with a beer as a prefix to visibility token.
And now we need to provide the token itself.
Now the value of authorization token we receive in the method that performs user login.
So if I scroll up, here's our method that tests user log in and when we receive response here in the
assertion, we read the value of a GDB header with a name.
Authorization.
Now for me to be able to use this authorization header in all the test methods, I will need to assign
it to a class member variable.
So let's do it.
I will create a class member variable on the top.
That will be private string and I will call it authorization token.
And now I will scroll down and I will assign in method number three that tests user log in this one
in method number three.
When I receive response, I can initialize this authorization token with a value that I read from the
response header like this.
And now I will use authorization token in that assertion.
And there is one more change that I will need to make to make it work.
Remember that by default for each test method that your unit executes, it creates a new instance of
a test class.
So once this test method test user login completes in the following test method, the value assigned
to this member variable will be null again.
And for this not to happen, I need to change the test instance lifecycle.
To do that I will scroll up and I will annotate my test class with additional annotation that is called
test instance.
So by default, g unit will create a new instance of a test class per test method.
So I will change this behavior to B per class.
Test instance life cycle per class.
And this will make all of our test methods in this class share the same instance of a class.
And this means that the value that I assign to this authorization token member variable can be used
in different test methods.
So we assign this value in test method.
Number three here we assign authorization token to a member variable and in the following method, method
number four, we can use this value.
So here I'm using authorization header member variable to set the value of authorization header.
And now I can put this headers into HTTP entity and use it in the request.
And next in the ACT section I can perform HDB get request.
In response back, I want to get a list of users.
So that's going to be a list of user arrest data type because this is what my method in the controller
class returns and this will give me a response entity with a list of users.
The same data type that I use here.
I will assign it to a response variable like this.
Let's give it a little more space.
And now that I have my response object in the assert section, I can assert that the HTTP response status
code is 200 because if the authorization access token that we are including here is missing or if it
is invalid in response back, we will get four or three.
But if everything is okay, our response status code will be to handle it.
So let's assert for that.
Expected value is a HTTP status code 200, which is okay.
And the actual HTP status code, I will read from response object.
And if these two values are not equal, how will this play an error message?
Should be status quo should be 200.
All right.
And as a second assertion, I will check if the number of users returned in HTTP response, if this
response contains at least one user, because there is only one user that we have created by executing
test method number one, this one.
So this will be the only user in our database.
So I will add an assertion.
Maybe assert true.
I will use a response object to read response body and response body will give me a list of objects
of user data type and because it is at least I can call size method on it and I want this size to be
exactly one.
And if it is not equal to one, I will display an error message that there should be exactly one user
in the list.
All right, so now we should be able to run this method and see if it passes.
So I will scroll up and I will run all test methods in this class.
Now my test method failed.
Let's look at the error message and it says that the status code is 403 forbidden.
And this is because I made a mistake here.
The test instance lifecycle should be set, not permitted, but per class, because by default g unit
will create a new instance of a test class per each method.
So if I want my test methods to share the same instance of a test class, I'll need to set the test
instance lifecycle two per class.
I made a mistake here so I will save changes now and I will run my test methods one more time.
And now it passes.
All right, so it worked.
Now let's make it fail.
I will scroll down and I will remove authorization header.
In our test method, we set authorization access token in authorization header.
So I will comment this line out and we'll see if my test method still works.
I expect it not to work because if authorization header is missing in response, I should receive a
http status code for three.
And it failed with an error message that HTTP status code should be to hang it.
But we have received for three forbidden, which is correct.
Now let's make it work again.
I will provide valid authorization, token save changes and run my test methods one more time.
And now my test method passes.
All right, so it all worked very well.
And you now know how to write a test method that includes authorization access token in HTTP request.