In this lesson, we're going to implement all four test methods in this class and I will start working
on the before all method first.
This method is not a test method and it is used to set up and prepare resources that are needed before
your test methods start executing.
And it is a good place to create a temporary database, for example, and establish a connection with
that database.
I do use user storage, so I will use this method to create an instance of that user storage.
I will define a new member of our Invoke Users database and I will initialize it inside of set up method.
I will also use this method to create a new instance of user service implementation class.
So I will define a second member variable.
And I will initialize it in the setup method.
Mindset and inside of.
After augmented, I can close data with connection or delete this database.
I do not really use realty that we storage, but I do have a close method that destroys user storage.
So I will use an object of users database until called the close method.
All right.
So now I can start working on a test method that creates new user.
And in the arranged section of this test method, I will prepare user details that I want to be stored.
In the ACT section, I will invoke my method under test.
The heat user meant it will return the idea of created user.
So I can check if this value is not now and I will do it in the search section.
My desk.
Now I can execute this method and see if it works.
And it works now to properly test the creed using a method.
Ideally, I should create additional test methods and test other details as well.
But properly testing this method is not a goal of this demonstration.
So I'll move on and we'll work on the update using method in the arranged section of test update using
entered and prepare information that I want this user to be updated with.
And this new user details.
I have changed the first name only and I have left the last name unchanged and in the ACT section I
will invoke method under test.
Now for this method to work for the update use I meant it to work.
I need to know the ID of already created user and to get this idea I will make first method the method
that creates user details to store the idea of created user as a member variable.
So I will scroll up and at the top of my class I will define a new member variable which is going to
be stream and I will call it created user ID and I will initialize it to an empty stream.
And now I will scroll down and in the first method I will delete the data type and I will make create
user, assign the return value to a member variable.
And in my second method that updates use a itself, I can now use this member variable the created user
ID to invoke the update user method to obtain the details of this earlier created user.
All right.
So the test method that runs first will create a user and it will store user ID and a member variable.
And the second method will use this user.
And now I have to test methods that are tightly coupled.
This second test method will only pass if the first method that creates user i.t execute successfully
and also passes.
All right.
So now let's go back to our second test method.
And in the assert section, I will assert that new user details matched the user details that were returned.
To do that I will use assert equals.
As expected value.
I will use the object of new user details and I will get its first name, for example, and I will compare
it with the actual first name that was returned after user was updated 9/10 and I will add an optional
message.
For example, the returned value of users first name is an correct input assert equals and they will
do the same for the last name.
All right.
So the second test method depends on the first test method, and it will not pass if I run it alone.
Let's try if I run this method.
It does not pass.
But if I execute all post methods in order, the second test method should pass.
So I will scroll up and I will run all test methods in this class.
And now I have all test methods passing the first two test methods to have assertions, but they still
pass.
And this proves that my test methods do run incorrect or they're one after another, and that these
two test methods, the first test method and the second test method, they share the same class instance,
the default g unit behavior where each test methods executes in its own instance of a test class has
been changed, and both test methods now share the same instance of a test class.
All right, now let's implement the find user details.
In the end section, I will invoke method under test.
And now I will assert that the return to object using details is not now.
And I will also assert that the return to object user details has correct user ID.
And now I have another dependent testament that I cannot execute this test testament at home and it
will only pass the first test that is successful.
So let's try running this test and that only.
And it fails.
But if there aren't alternate methods in the order, they are defined in this clause.
Then they will pass.
I will scroll up and we'll run all test methods.
And it works.
All right, so let's implement the last testament.
It.
Which is to test the delete user functionality.
In the ACT section, I will invoke method under test.
The delete user method is void and it does not return any value.
So to check of this user has been successfully deleted.
I will use the assert null assertion.
And that will make it validate the returned value of get user details.
And now I have another testament that needs to run in order.
If it runs first, second or third, it will make all the test methods fail.
And all test methods in this class will need to run in a single instance of a test class or everything
fails.
All right, so let's try executing this test along.
It fails.
And if I execute all test methods in this class.
I have all test methods passing.
All right.
So I hope that this demonstration was helpful to you and you now know how to make your test methods
execute in order and if needed, make them in a single instance of a test class.