In this lesson you will learn how to where you find the method you are testing throws exception.
And for this demonstration I will use the integer division method which we have disabled in a previous
video lesson.
All right, so what I'm going to do, I'm going to disable the disabled annotation or comment it out,
and I will remove the fail assertion as well.
I will also add the three sections arrange, act and insert.
Mind this the purpose of this testimony that I can read from insane tests integer division method.
When dividends is divided by zero, it should throw arithmetic exception.
So let's work on it in the arranged section.
I will prepare a few variables.
I will need dividend and divisor.
The dividend is going to be four and it is four.
That is going to be divided by zero.
And when we divide by zero and if medical exception takes place to invoke or a method under the test
integer division, we will need an instance of calculator class.
I can create an instance of calculator class here in the arranged section, but I don't need to do it
because it will be created in the method that runs before each test method.
Here in this method we already create a calculator object so I can use it to invoke my method under
test.
And that will give it the dividend and divisor.
And now I need to assert that if integer division method is invoked with these two input parameters
and arithmetic exception will get thrown.
To do that, that will use a special assertion that is called assert throws.
The first parameter that assert throws assertion accepts is the type or class name of the exception
that we are expecting.
We are expecting arithmetic exceptions.
So I will type here arithmetic exception like this.
The second parameter is executable and here I will provide lambda function that will invoke my method
under test.
I will create a new anchored section and here I will invoke my method under test.
So I will copy and paste it here inside of my lambda function and I will rename this section.
It will be act and assert like this.
And the third parameter that we can include in this assert through the assertion is the optional message
that will be printed.
If this assertion fails.
For example, as a message we can provide division by zero should have thrown a medical exception.
In the assert section here that is below.
I can check with the exception message that was returned is what I'm expecting to do.
This I will assign the result of this assertion to a local variable.
For example, I will create a local variable that is called actual exemption.
And now when I have this exemption object, I can read from the actual error message.
I will first create a new local variable that I will call expected exception message.
When the arithmetic exception takes place, the default error message looks usually like this.
It's a division signed by zero, division by zero, and it needs to be a string like this.
So now I can compare the expected exception message with the actual exception message in the assert
section.
To do that I will use assert equals assertion.
The expected error message is expected exception message and the actual error message I will use from
the face a local wearable that I have created.
Actual exception message get message my English and I can also provide a default error message that
will be printed if this assertion fails.
For example, I can say unexpected exception message.
Something like this.
All right, so now I can save changes in this test cause and they can run my test method and see if
it works.
To do that, that will click on this a run button, which is right next to the test name.
And my test meant that this passing that's minimized test reports and if I change the value of divisor
local variable and make it a valid integer, for example, two four divided by two will be two.
In this case, no exception will be thrown and this test method should fail.
So let's save changes and twists around this test method one more time.
And now we have a failing union test.
And if I look at the assertion error message, it says that the evasion by zero should have thrown if
medical exemption.
Which is an error message that we've provided and then a default error message that was provided by
two union.
Expected an immediate exception to be thrown, but nothing was thrown.
All right.
So it looks like it is working well.
Let's make it pass again.
I will change the value of Divisor Back to zero.
Save changes and run this test again.
And now we have a passing unity test.
All right.
So now you know how to verify if they meant that under the rules, correct the exception in the following
lectures, we might come back to this assertion, assert gross one more time and use it with different
unit tests.
But for now, let's continue.