Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course on Tableau. Today we're connecting
to our third data set for this
section which is population statistics
for Australia for the different
states.
Let's go ahead and do that, we go to the
advanced course folder then we've got to
this file here which is demographic
statistics and let's bring up Excel and
will open up this file.
Alright, so once again you can see that
this is an ABS file which stands for
Australian Bureau of Statistics and here
we've got the index for our data set
which and the data set is in the second
tab again which is here and in this data
set
we've got a bit of a few, fewer rows
and previously, so we've got I mean do we
have we have a hundred and forty six
rows in total, so hundred and thirty-six
observations and that is because the
data at this time is quarterly so it's
not monthly
as previously it's actually quarterly. So
June, Septermber, December, March, June and so on.
And what do we have? Here you can see
that we've got once again the name of
the indicator which is estimated
resident population and then the gender
male and then the state. So this is males
for all of the states then we've got
females over here and then we've got
finally we just got persons which is a
total male plus female. Alright and once
again these rows as you can see these
ones are here they're not changing as
you as I scroll through so we're going
to get rid of them and we're going to
get rid of series ID. So similar
procedure to what we did before if you
want to practice then feel free to pause
this video and go ahead and perform all
the same task we did previously,
to connect the data set including the
pivot and then we can meet up towards
the end of this video and see how we
went and see what additional things that
we need to do with this specific data
set. Otherwise, if you haven't paused the
video, I am going to continue now.
So first thing we must not forget is we
need to go back to our folder and create
a copy. So there we go and just going to
move this here so I'm just going to move
the copied file here. I'm really curious
if you did pause the video did you
remember that step.
It's always important to have a copy of
your original data source, or data
set because then you can always refer
to it in case there are any questions.
So there we go, so we've done that and
now we can safely remove the rows so
let's get rid of all of these control minus
and we're done. And now we're simply
going to go and save this file, close it
and we're going to go to Tableau and
connect to our new data source by clicking
this button up over here,
excel and here we're going to select our
data source which is this one. Click open
even a second and once again scroll to
the bottom find our data which is
here and now we want to perform the
pivot so we can see that everything has
a number so we don't need to hide any
columns which is good. So just select all
these and click the drop-down anywhere.
And could pivot and I'll pivot ready. We
just have to rename it so oh well
children and of course means to the
split so do the split here hide this
column we don't need it this one we're
going to rename to a gender and this one
we're going to rename to state. It's got
Australia, I think that's the total
if you go down you can see that then
it's got the state's there as well and
here we're going to rename this to
population.
Alright so that's good, can you see how
quickly that happens right so in Tableau
data preparation with these advanced
tools is just lightning fast you don't
have to do any pivots in Excel and so on
your data basis very quick very
convenient,
great! Now we' re going to add a data
source filter here and that is because
we have female, we have male and we have
persons right? so we don't want to all of
them, we just
and one specific category which is
persons we don't want female or male. In
fact you don't have to add it as a data
source filter because this is one of
those cases when further down the track
your executive board might say all we
want to just analyze the behavior of
females because maybe they shop more
with us or males or something that but
in our case we're going to assume that
females and males shop equally with us
and we're actually going to keep the
person's rather than females and males
at the data source level. Once again feel free not
to do it this way feel free to use a
filter in  the visualizations up but a
good opportunity to practice data  source of
filters and one more time. So we're going
to keep persons i'm going to click ok
and as you can see here we are applying
this filter off to the pivot's has
been done so that's that's kind of an
important thing. So here you can see that
these are pivoted fields or the fields
that we have after the pivot. If you perform,
if you don't do the pivot then you'll
have different fields that you can
filter on so we're going to keep persons
and there we go those are the records
that we're going to be working with.
Alright so that's all for today. That was a
good exercise for us to do and see how
to perform the pivots and splits and
data source filters one more time and in
the next tutorial we're going to talk
about some advanced blending which will
allow us to combine the two data sets
together. I look forward to seeing you
then and until next time happy analyzing.