Hello and welcome back to the advance
course on Tableau. In the previous tutorial,
we connected to our next data set which is
the population statistics and today
we're going to start blending to join
our existing association to that new
data set. So you can see the new data set
over here which is this one and
therefore it's highlighted in orange and
the left because it's not the primary
data source. The primary data source is the
industry data source which we really
connected to which are using here so
this is the secondary data source and
therefore it's orange.
Ok so what we're going to do. First of all,
first thing I would like to do is since
we're only working with these four
states let's go ahead re and reassign
the colors so it looks a bit better so
just going to click assign palette click
OK and it looks way better like this I
think and next we're going to duplicate
this tab so we're going to say duplicate
sheet and will rename it later once
we're ready and for now let's see how we
can blend these two data sets together.
Alright so first things first we need to
go and look at the relationships that
exist between the two datasets so we go
into it relationships as you can see
this is a primary data source of
Industry and this is the demographic
statistics data source which is our
secondary data source, the only
relationship they have right now is a
state and state so why is that? Well that's
because we renamed the column for date
in the primary data source to date. You
can see it over here and here you still have one,
what you can do is you can rename f1 to
date and then Tableau will pick it up
automatically but then you will have
another problem that Tableau pickup way
too many connections that are possible
between the two date fields like week,
month, year, day and so on everything,
and that is why I'm going to keep it as
f1 and I'm just going to create my
custom relationship between these two
data sets. So let's go ahead and click custom
and here we're going to add a new
error so on the left we have date and on
the right we're going to have f1. So how
we going to do this? We're going to look
at year of date and we're going to look
at a year of f1. That's that's a good
start and the next one we're going to
add is we're going to look at quarter
update and quarter f1 and I'll
explain this just now. So let's go ahead
and do that so we got state quarter and
year and click OK and now it's just
quickly checked that it's all still there.
It's all good and you can see this grey
icon appear here so why did we specify
exactly year and quarter and to look
into that further I've prepared a slide.
Let's go ahead and look at it. So this
our primary are set and there's our
second are set and both of them have a
Tableau and this is where we get to the
topic of advanced time series blending,
so here we've got some observations on
the f.. in the first data set in the
primary data set and they are for every
month so those letters are for months
so January, February, March, April, May and so
on and in the secondary data set we also
have observations but they're not for
every month there for every third month
so March, June, September, December ,March,
June, September, December and so on. So when
we're blending we want to somehow create
a connection between the two but as you
can see the secondary data set has
less data so how do we create that
connection?
Well the first condition we specified
the year, what does is it breaks our
datasets in two years and it says
alright so definitely make sure that
anything from let's say 2014 is only
connected to anything from 2014. The
primary data set and anything from 2015
is also only connected to anything from
2015 in the primary data set. So there's
no mix-up there will be no mix-up
between years because we specified that
year equals your condition.
Now what else we did is we specify the
quarter
equals quarter condition and that allows
us to break this matching into even more
detail and as you can see here what that
will do is it will make sure that only
data from the correct quarter is
specified to that corner in the primary
data set and it just so happens that our
secondary data set is so structured that
there's only one data point for each
quarter, because it is quarterly
observations and what will happen when
we create the blend when we execute the
blend is this.
So the information from the secondary
data source will be translated into more
blended with the primary data set in
this fashion and because as you remember
from the basic course on Tableau the
blend is a left join so here you can see
that our primary dataset on the left or
here's on the top and the secondary
data set is being joined to it and given
our conditions every single a month of
or every single observation in
the secondary data set will be joined to
three observations in the primary
data set and that is exactly what
you want. So if we were to go ahead and
specify additional conditions on top of
that,
let's say we would say make sure that
the month is equal then we would would
get the wrong thing because the data
from other observations from the
secondary data set will only be joined
to one observation of every or every
single observation for the second data
set would only be joined to one
observation from the primary data set
but that's not what we want because then we
would have observations and the primary
data set that would had would have no match.
That is why we're kind of ignoring the
month in the secondary data set we're
only looking at it from the level of
granularity of quarters which allows us
to duplicate or in this case triplicate
our data from the secondary set into
the primary data set and so that's what's
going on in the background or that's
what will be going in the background
when we will be executing this blend in
Tableau. Alright so let's move back
Tableau now, so to see this blend in action
what we're going to do is we're going to
remove the some states from here so
we're going to just leave New South Wales
for now and that will free up some
space and allow us to better understand
the blend as we are executing it.
Let's get rid of Queensland, Victoria and
Western Australia,  click ok so now we
only have New South Wales left, and now
let's go ahead and click this button to
confirm that we want this field in the
blend and now we're going to take the
population measure and we'll drag it
into our visualization. We'll put it
into rows here and what that uses is it
gives us the progression of course it's
not correct as you can see there's a
nowhere near 250 million people living
in Australia and that is because our
blend is not being executed correctly at
this stage and the reason being is that
the fields that we specified in our
blend the quarter and year of this
variable f1 they're not accessible to
Tableau in this aggregation so it cannot
blend on them right now. So what we need
to do is we need to take f1 and drag it
into detail and here we've got year of
f1 which is a good start and now we
want to drag f1 into detail again and as
you can see it already gives us quarter
of f1 automatically and so that is what
we want. So now I'm just going to get rid
of these trend lines show trendlines no,
no need in them well in this part of
the visualization anyway and so what we
can see here is we can see that for
every single month we've got a
population and it does look like this
these values are constantly increasing
but that's just a visual effect so if
you look closely if we look at one of
the quarters here you'll see that within
the quarter the values not changing so
the population here 6,530
then it's 6,530 and it's 6,530 again
and then for the next quarter increases
6,544 and then 6,544 and then it hold on a
6,544 and then one more time 6,544.
So we've got we've achieved the effect
that we wanted for every month in this
timeline and this timeline let's not
forget this timeline belongs to the
primary data source. It doesn't have an
orange icon here so for every month of
the primary data source, we have three
we have triplicated, no for every month
of the primary data source we have
extracted a population value from the
secondary data source and we were
extracted it is we've triplicated the
value that quarterly value that
we have. So as you can see the value
within every single quarter is the same
edit is equal to the value that we had
in the stops and we can check that we
can just go to view data so we're
looking for New South Wales and let's
look at one of the recent years so March
2007 there was 6,815
right? So let's find March 2007,
this is 2007 and March 2007
would be this one 6,815 so
you can see it's the same for January
2007, March, February 2007
and March 2007, we've
achieved the same exact figure of 6
million and 850,000 for New South Wales. So
there we go, so that's how we can blend
in this case. The only drawback of this
approach to blending is that because
we've added these fields in here you can
see that outline is now broken up like
it's it's broken and therefore the
is working into quarters and therefore
the visual aspect or this aesthetics of
this approach is its kind of not the
best like it's better to see a smooth
line. So you can keep it this way if you
like, but for practice sake what we're
going to do is we're going to adjust
this blend.
To actually create a different blend
because you can you can control the way
you blend this data and what we're
going to do is we're going to fix up
this blend so that now we won't we'll
have a smooth line and it'll actually be
blended a bit differently and the way it
will be blended is it will be blended
on a yearly level rather than a
quarter level and going back to our
presentation
what that means is that now we're going
to remove these restrictions for
quarterly and of course this is going to
go is to and in order for things not to
get mixed up
we cannot have that many observations in
our secondary data set because
otherwise there will be too much
duplication. What we will need to do is
we'll need to get rid of some
observations so we make sure that
there's only one observation left in
this secondary data set and that
observation will be joined to every
single observation for that same year in
the primary data set, and the reason why
we're going to choose March is because
it comes earlier than the other quarters
and therefore we won't miss out for
instance in the last year because the
last quarter might not be yet available
in our secondary data set, if we
re.. if we keep only that then for
the last year we might end up with a
situation where we won't have sufficient
information to visi.. visualize that last
year. So we want to keep the earlier
quarter and so that's exactly what we're
going to do now we're going to go ahead
and form this new blend in Tableau. Let's
go ahead and do that.
Alright so first of all as in the
presentation we're going to get rid of
this restriction on quarter so let's go
ahead and look at our relationships and
here we're going to get rid of this
restriction that the quarter has to equal
the quarter and as soon as I delete that
and click ok we'll look at the chart it
will change. So here what you can see in
the population is now in a ...like
huge numbers, 25 million and that is
definitely way too much and as you can
see here it drops off and that's
that's kind of very a good hint that
something is wrong.
Well what's happening here is we have
that the multiple duplication where
within a year we have four values. We
have four quarters and they're actually
being all joined to one field so here the
values four times greater than it should be
so 27 should be actually divided by 4, well
that's that's a very rough estimate
anyway. So now we're going to perform
that second aspect we talked about in
the presentation we're going to get rid
of all the other observations or all the
information that we don't need in the
secondary data source so let's go to a data
source and add another data source
filter. We're going to go add. We're going
to look at f1 and here we're going to
say months. So we only want March, we
don't want these other three months we
always only want much for every single
year.
Click ok and now here you can see that
we're going we're only left with March
and if we go back to data set you can
see it's all fixed up now. So now our
population is back to normal and now the
difference is that this step is not
three months it is actually every year
so as you can see the population doesn't
change within the year 6,735 for this
year, then here it's the same and that is
the March population taken from the
secondary data source.
So now what we can to do to get rid of
these gaps. We're just going to take
quarters out and we can also take years
out and that way now it is working
without any gaps and as you can see it
is nice and smooth.
Ok so that is how you perform different
types of blends always make sure to
check your work so by going to your
data set and clicking view data or
even better going to the original to
excel file and checking that. What you're
seeing on the chart is actually, what is,
What was given to you in the data set so
we can hear check 2013 New South Wales
should be 7, 3, 8, 6 so 2013, 7, 3, 8, 6 so
that's great!
And that brings us to the end of this
tutorial, hope you found this information
useful and it will give you some ideas
on how to do advanced blending in
Tableau and in next tutorial we will
continue with our investigations. I look
forward to seeing you then,
until next time, Happy Analyzing!