Hello this is Kirill and welcome back
to the advanced course on Tableau and
today we're going to build this
visualization. So as we discussed we're
going to use the population data set as
our primary data set for the blend in
Tableau and for that to happen we have
to use our first field in this dashboard
from this data set. So let's go ahead and
take population and we know that we want
population to be the size of the bubble
so let's drag it into size. Okay as you
can see there's a a blue indicator here,
telling us that this is now the
primary data source. Now that's great now
let's move on to the next one, fertility
rate let's connect to this data source
let's initiate the blend by clicking
these two indicators here and from this
data set we want the fertility rate and
we wanted to be on the horizontal axis.
Perfect let's move on to the next one.
Life expectancy at birth,
now from here we want the life
expectancy at birth indicator, I'm not
going to click these indicators to show
you what will happen if I drag it into
the vertical axis. We get an error
telling us that the blend has not been
initiated and that's because as you
remember the plan would only be
initiated automatically if you actually
use one of these fields in your
visualization. If that's not the case,
then you have to initiate the blend
yourself.
There we go that fixed up the error and
finally to this data set, the metadata
for countries we want the region and we
wanted it to be color. So let's drag it or
first let's initiate the blend and drag
region into color. Perfect now we've got
some colors for different regions and
this is all aggregated data. What we want
is a mark for every single country, so
let's go ahead and go back to our
original data set and here we're going
to take country name so you can annotate
country code, country name but we're going to
country name and we're going to drag it
into detail. Now this gives us lots of
marks and what is going on right now is
a not exactly what we want because here
you can see life expectancy at birth and
it's thousands of years and I hope you,
we wish, we must be live that long
but that's not the case and that is
because
the data has been summed for all of
the years and that's very easy to fix so
what we're going to do is we're going to
take a year and will drag it into
filters and we'll just select one year.
So let's start with 1960 and click OK,
and there we go now our data set is
correct. So a couple more things that we
need to do is of course fix up the size
and the mark we're using so instead of
empty circles are going to use filled
circles and we're going to increase the
size here a bit but as you can see as we
increase the size the tiny bubbles are
not getting that much bigger but the big
ones are really growing. So to fix that
what you want to do is go into this menu
here into this legend click the
drop-down and select edit sizes and
instead of saying automatically saved by
range and then increase this one a bit
on the left and click apply.
That's way too much just look at this
bubble over here and you can see how it
changes so that's way too much,
that's way too little but maybe that
should be about right maybe a bit, a bit
smaller than that.
Ok so that is looking a bit better maybe
make the big ones also a bit smaller now
it's too small.
That was actually better, alright so play
around with that and see what you're
comfortable with.
Next we want of you can see here that
they're kind of merging together and we
don't want that so we're going to give
us some transparency make it a 75 and
we're going to give it a border so black
is too rough,
usually I go not this black and not the
somewhere like either this one or this
one.
In this case I'm going to use this one.
So it still stands out, but it's not that
blunt. It's a bit gray, so that looks
good what else do I want to do and
finally want to change the colors, right?
So I've got some thoughts already I want
like Europe to be blue, like Latin
America to be orange, Middle East
let's select a maybe this but I want to
change it to more of this type of yellow,
North America maybe green, South Asia Brown,
can see brown,
Sub Saharan Africa maybe always make it
blue this blue, and finally East Asia
we're going to make it red here, click
apply and one final thing that we want
to do is go to analysis and uncheck
aggregate measures and even though that
doesn't do anything because we are at
the highest level of granularity at the
level of country, we still want to do
that just as a good practice kind of
approach so that the next person that's
looking at your dashboard he can right
away see that it's not aggregated these
measures are not aggregated and so there
we go the visualization is practically
ready.
It literally took us under 5 or 6
minutes to create all of that and that's
because we are at that advanced level of
Tableau we understand very very well
exactly what we're doing and that was
very fast.
The last thing that we have to do is add an
animation to this visual and we will do
that in the next tutorial. I look forward
to seeing you next time and until then,
happy analyzing.