Hello and welcome back to the advanced course
on Tableau. This is where we stopped off
last time. We created the box plots and
we finalized our analysis of the
competitor research. Today we're going to
move on to the next stage of our
analysis and we will look at the data
set for the different industries in the
different states of Australia. So let's
go ahead and get started, so first of all
I'm going to bring up the folder with
our data sets which is here section 4 and
let's go ahead and open up that data set.
So as you can see this is an official
data set taken from the Australian
Bureau of Statistics, I'll just assume in
a bit and in the first tab you can see
an index,  so what is telling you is what
the data set actually contains and
you can click any of these links and
I'll take you to the correct column in
the data set tab, so I'll just scroll to
the bottom you can see this quite a
lot. Here is the actual data set tab, so
if you look here you can see the label
then you got some more information,
got an ID and then you've got to the
dates on the left here, so these are new
separate months and here you've got the
turnover, so for instance here we've got
the turnover for the for New South Wales
for the industry which is called other
specialized food retailing, so there's
62.7 million dollars turnover in that
industry in June 1982 and
the dates range from 1982 all the way to
2015.
Ok so as you can see it's quite a large
data set. There isn't that mean you
rows right so if I go to the bottom so
let me zoom out, if I go to the bottom
here is only 411 rows in total but if we
scroll, if we scroll to the right so if
I'm just going to scroll to the right
you can see that there is a lot of
columns right, because is it a lot of
industries multiplied by quite a few states and that
gives us a lot of columns and therefore
it is quite a large data set because we
will have to
learn how to work with these columns we
will have to pivot them and prepare them
for analysis.
Finally the last tab is inquiries so it
just has information how you can get in
touch with the ABS to ask them some
questions, so let me show you how the
index works just for fun I can click any
link here and we'll highlight that
column that I need to that I was after
so if I want to find let's say
Queensland and I want to look at
newspaper and book retailing I click
that link and I go there. What we're not
actually going to use that in our
analysis I thought it was just pretty
cool thing to look at. Anyway so that's
our data set and what we want to do is
we want to prepare it before we actually
connect to it in Tableau and first thing
that jumps into mind or into attention
is that if you look at these rows over
here so just look at these rows as
I scroll to the right. You can see that
they're not changing right? Everything
else changing these rows are not
changing and that is because it's just
information that is common for the whole
spreadsheet or for this whole data set
so it's all measured in millions serious
type data types, so some additional
information, so where it starts, where it
ends, number of observations. We don't
actually need this information because
it's common for the whole data set we
can get rid of it and if we do need
anything like say millions we can just
remember that or somehow add to our
analysis we don't need it in every
single column. So let's go ahead and
select all of these rows by click clicking
shift-space and then press control minus to
get rid of them.
Ok now series ID, as you can see here,
what it is is a unique identifier of
each category and we actually don't
really needed either because we don't
know how to understand these years idea
these are kind of internal IDs for the
stranger of Statistics what we are after
is the text description which gives us
way more information and is way more
useful for us so there's a one-to-one
match here between series ID and this
text label so we don't need to keep this
series ID, we're not going to benefit
from it in any kind of way. So let's go
ahead and get rid of it as well. So
select that press control minus and there we go,
it's gone. Now before we save this
worksheet I wanted to give you a tip,
what I normally do is if I change
anything in my data source then I like
to have a copy of the original, so I
haven't saved it yet so let's copy this
file. There's a copy and that goes into
the archive folder here so if we have
any questions in the future we can
always revert back to the original.
Alright that's done, now we can save this
file and we can go ahead and connect it
in Tableau, but before we do I wanted to
outline what we're going to do today. So
today, I'm going to show you two things.
In this tutorial we will learn how to
first of all fix up our data set because
here you will see that if I scroll to
right some columns they don't have
values in them, So if I go down to the
bottom like this column does have values
eventually in it. Now let's go find
another one that doesn't, so here
turnover for liquor in Tasmania. You
can see that if i scroll to the top, if I
scroll to all still also has values to
find another one.
There you go, so turnover for department
stores  in Tasmania so you can
see that this column was completely empty
and that is going to cause issues for
our pivot and you'll see why, and I'll
show you how to deal with that in a
Tableau and the second thing, I will show
you how to perform today is how to deal
with large data sets. Now this isn't a
huge data set per say because it only has
401 rows but at the same time it has a
lot of columns so it might be slowing
down the work of Tableau depending on
your machine and I will show you how or
a quick trick that you can apply to
large data sets that will help you do your
analysis without having to wait a long
times for Tableau to load.
So that's what
we're going to do today and in the next
tutorial we're going to perform the
pivots and splits and so on. So let's go
ahead and save that
and once that saved we can close it and
we can go to Tableau. This is where we
left off last time, so let's go ahead and
add another data source, plus excel
file there's our data set
let's open that up as you can see here
you've got the named ranges so those are
the ones that allow those links to work
that we saw we don't need them we're not
going to use them as our data
sources. We're going to use data one
as our data source, so let's drag
that in here, as you can see it's already
taking a bit of time to load,
Ok so there is our data set. Now if
you scroll to the right here, you will
find that all these columns are numeric
except sometimes, you will see that
columns are recognized as ABC values. So
here you've got one, you've got another
one, another one and that's exactly what
I was talking about, so if I scroll down
to the bottom here you'll see that this
column is completely empty so Tableau
has no idea that numeric? Is that a text
column?  What is it? And it recognizes it
as a text column by default and what
will happen if we when we did our pivot
if we select all the columns and we
don't pivot Tableau will see they're
trying to combine numeric column and text
columns and will default to text in the
pivot and we don't want that. So there
are two ways of fixing it, you can go
back to the data set and replace his
nulls with zeros or on the other hand
because we know that we won't need these
columns and of course we also want to
learn some additional methods that we
can apply in Tableau. We're going to deal
with it here in Tableau. So the way to go
about it is to simply hide these columns,
so click the drop-down, select hide and
that column is gone. It's not going to be
participating in the analysis and the
faster way to do it is if you go to the
meta data and you scroll down and you
look for these columns here so that you
can see two of them just go ahead and
hide them.
Let's find some more, there's another one
right click and hide.
That's there's a few more so that's what
is that seven in total just have a look
through them, so now just have a look
through them is another one. That makes
it eight,
and make sure you've got all of the ABC
columns and there we go. We've prepared
for the pivot so now the pivot should
run fine but at the same time as we
discussed this data set is quite
large and depending on your machine when
you pivot this these columns it might
take a while and even if you have a fast
machine this is still a great chance
great opportunity to practice how to
deal with large data sets so when the
time comes when you're working for
million road data set you will know what
sneaky trick you can apply to help your
analysis. So and the sneaky trick is not
that complex it's actually applying a
data source filter. A data source filter is
applied by clicking this bottom-up over
here. So you click add and you'll be able
to add a filter that will remove rows
from your analysis and the difference
between a datasource filter and a normal
filter in Tableau is that the data source
filter is applied at the connection
level of to the data set and that means
that the data won't even be
imported in to Tableau and it's all of
your analysis from here onwards won't
even be able to access that data in any
sort of way so on one hand you're
limiting yourself to the amount of
data that you have to work with but on the
other hand you're really giving Tableau
opportunity to speed up so it will be
working faster because we working with
less data.  Now data source filters are this
is not the main use case for data source
filters but at the same time it is a
very handy trick that you can use when
your encounter when you've encountered a
large data set that is really slowing
down Tableau and what you'll be doing is
basically you filter out most of the
row. So I'll show you how to do that,
let's click add, let's click select this
f1 column over here which is the date
and here we'll just say range of dates,
next and we're going to say we only want
dates starting from 2010 so
forget about all these dates. We'll work
with these dates for now and then what
we'll do is after we've done the
connection we've done the pivot, after
we've created our visualizations, after
we've commence our analysis so we're
ready to actually draw inside,
then we will remove this filter and so
that will allow us to do all the
pre-work with this filter on which will
make things fast and Tableau will be
flying but then when we're ready we'll
remove the filter and all of the data
will be loaded and all pros and we'll go
through all the same visualization that
we've created. So that is how personally
I would go about dealing with a large
data set, so let's go ahead and click OK
and click OK again and you'll see how
this data set has now been filtered and
we have rows only starting from
2010 so we have very few more rows
compare to what we had and there we go
so that is how you remove columns that
you don't want to participate in now so
basically hide columns, by the way you
can see them here if you want to see
them you can click show hidden field and
it'll show you those fields where are
they so they are they're just a bit
greyed-out, but we don't want to see them
because we don't want to accidentally
include them in our analysis so let's
get rid of them again. So that's number
one, how to get rid of row columns that
you don't want and number two is that is
how to apply a datasource filter which
can help you deal with large datasets. So
that's all for today, in the next
tutorial, we will do the pivot and will
also do a split and I look forward to
seeing you next time.
Until then, happy analyzing!