Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. In today's tutorial, we will talk
about the direction of computation for
your table calculations. As you recall,
previously in order to get to the
direction of computation we would click
this drop-down and then would select
compute using and would either select
across or table down or we could go into
the table calculation and selected from
here. So compute using and currently it's
set to down now I would like to bring
your attention to the following fact
that this is an implicit way of
specifying the direction of computation
and in order to explain a bit better
what I mean, allow me to show you an
example,
so what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to right click the tab and say duplicate
sheet. Now on this copy of the sheet what
I'm going to do is click this button at
the top which is swap and what it will
do is it will swap the rows with the
columns so basically rows will become
columns, columns will become rows.
Let's go ahead and do that. Once you
click that swap button you can see the
same chart but now it's kind of an
inside and that is because the whole
table was flipped around in terms of
rows and columns and what you will
notice now is if you click the table
calculation and you go into edit table
calculation you will notice that it has
changed from table down to table across,
now why is that? Why has it changed to
table across? Well that is because
Tableau is smart it knows that
everything that used to be down on this
table or on in this visual has now
become across has become sideways so up
and down is now sideways and if you're
going to turn your head to the right you
can see the same table but it's just
it's that it's upside down. The blue used
to be at the top and it's also on its
side and well Tableau is smart so it's
changed that direction of computation
for us and that is what I mean when I
say that it is an implicit way to
specify your table calculation, so you're
basically telling Tableau in this
construction of our table. I want to
calculate the field downwards but then
when your construction of your table
changes like it did here, Tableau has to
automatically adjust and guess what you
were actually after and change your
Tableau calculation in the background and
so here my question to you is, Do you
really want to rely on Tableau adjusting
your table calculation for you every
single time something changes? It is kind
of a risky bet because maybe one day
your table calculation or your table
might change in a way that Tableau won't
adjust to table calculation and your table
calculation will therefore show
incorrect results. So in order to
minimize this risk or actually get rid
of it completely
the best way is to specify your table
calculations explicitly and now I'll
show you how to do that with your quick
table calculations like the one we see
here and with your table calculations
which are saved in your measures. By the
way, this is a calculated field which we
dragged here so if you put your mouse
over it says idle capacity percent pause
but at the same time it is reflected as
a table calculation and the control is
separate you'll see what I mean just now
when we change this one not necessarily
will your idle capacity percent change
so it is important to keep track of
these things and I'll explain what the
best way up to go about that is as well
but towards the end of this tutorial. So
to start off with, how can we make sure
that we specify explicitly the direction
of computation? Well it's pretty simple
if you go into your drop down here and
it's like computer using you'll see that
among all other options table
cross, table down and combinations and
pains and cells and so on.
You've got fields here at the bottom so
here we've got daytime which is this
field and machine which is this field
and same thing if we're going to edit
table calculation, you'll once again see
that from this drop-down you can select
your daytime or you can set your machine
and in this specific case we know that
daytime is our horizontal axis. Machine
is our vertical axis, so if you want to
to do the table calculation, let's say
across for to start with you
would like to do the table calculation
across, then instead of saying table
across it is better to say daytime. Click
apply, and there you can see the same
result that we solve for table across
because the calculation has been
performed across data, now if we want our
actual true result that we're after if
we click machine and we click apply
which you'll see here is that now we
have the correct result and this is the
same as table down but in this case it's
using the machine field and we can click
ok and if we now duplicate the sheet
again and we transpose it or swap it
around and now we go into the table
calculation, you will see that it is
still machine. So this is an explicit
specification of your computation
direction and Tableau respect that and
it will keep that regardless of how you
use this table calculation because it
doesn't have to guess anything. It knows
you telling it exactly what you want you
want to calculate it across this field
machine.
Ok so let's go back to our sheet, we can
actually delete this one so we don't we
don't get flooded with sheets. We'll
delete that on a bit later so there we
go so that's our original sheet, we've
changed this calculation but what you
will notice now is if I right click this,
it isn't reflected as a table
calculation here. It is a calculated
field, so it is using a table calculation
but it is reflected as a calculated
field and only becomes a table
calculation once I drag it into the
chart like what we did here. So in order
to change the table calculations so what
I'm trying to do now is I want to
specify that I want to calculate across
this specific field. I want to specify
that in my table calculation that is
saved. This wasn't the saved one. This was
the one that I see in the visual so how
do I specify that in the table
calculation? Well, you have to go to the
table calculation itself and go to edit
and here you will see that this is the
table calculation because it is using
table calculation formulas. We'll talk
more about these in the coming tutorials
in
this section but I'll quickly give you a
hint. So if you look at these formulas
like look up right, so that is the table
calculation, table formula here and if
you click the drop-down you go to table
calculation and all these formulas that
you see here which we once again we'll
discuss in the coming tutorials of this
section
these are table calculation formulas and
in this case the one that has been used
is look up. This formula has been
generated automatically for us and it is
using a table calculation formula and
therefore this is a Tableau a saved Tableau
calculation. Now for saved table
calculations, you'll see here a comment
which says how there is also being
computer? Results are computed a long
table down. So as you can tell even
though we change the computation method
here, it hasn't changed in the saved
table calculation that is important to
keep in mind. Sometimes people get this
wrong and they fix it up here or they
make changes to the table calculation
has been displayed but it's not actually
making changes to the save table
calculation so be careful of that. What we're
going to do now is we're going to update
this to make sure it's reflecting the
explicit specification of the
computation direction. So let's go and
click this button here default table
calculation. This is here specifically
for those reasons. It was only present
when you use table calculations and this
is exactly what it's for. It's for you to
be able to change your computation. So as
you can see, those that's the pretty much
only menu here and here we can specify
either daytime there for this table will
be there cross or we can specify the
machine which will be down for this
table. So let's go ahead and specify down,
click OK , click apply, click OK and now we
have actually fixed up our table
calculation the one that is saved and
good practice or a good habit to develop
is that once you've saved fixed up your
table calculation that is saved. It is a
good idea to update the table
calculation in your view so to do that
just drag the field that is here and
replace it again and what that does
sometimes is it gets rid of your reference
line, but that's not a problem. Just add
the reference line again so constant and
0.1 and we're doing that because once
you update your table calculation here,
it's not necessarily will be updated in
your view because as you noticed it it
doesn't work the better the other way
around backwards backwards when she
updated here does not be here so they
kind of separate it's always a good idea
to want to update your table calculation
here, if you do want updated in the
specific view, then do drag it back in
here and update your table calculation.
So there we go, that is how you
explicitly specify the direction of
computation for your table calculations
whether they are quick table
calculations present just in the view
in your view or they are actually saved
table calculations which are present in
your measures. Hope you found this
tutorial useful and I highly recommend
using this method wherever you can
because it will save you from any
potential errors that might occur when
you don't use explicit specification and
I look forward to seeing you in the next
tutorial.
Until then, Happy Analyzing!