Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course in Tableau. In today's tutorial
we're going to talk about the LOD or
level of detail calculation which is
type 2 exclude. So let's dive straight
into it. We're going to take our map,
I'm going to duplicate our map and here
we're going to say LOD exclude and
here we'll just say part 1 and I'll
explain why its part 1 in a second and
well there will be two parts. So we'll
actually see see it as we create it. Alright
so what we're going to do well we're
going to go to a higher level of
granularity. We're going to go to the
level of granularity of one individual
City and right away here we're going to
we're just going to keep profit as the
so we keep sum of profit as color and
here we're going to just quickly adjust
color going to set the transparency to
80% and so that we can see points that fall
behind each other and we'll also add a
border so that we can actually see our
points better.
Alright so what do we want to do? Well
what we want to do is we want to look at
the profit. So let's say we want to work
at the level of detail or level of
granularity or level of aggregation.
So our visualization should stay at this
level at the level of City but what we
want to do is we want to in a formula go
back to this level of State and from
here we want to extract these values so
we want to, let me just cancel that we want
to extract the sum of all of the sales
of all the profit for each individual
State. So we want to take the sum of
for this state, the sum of profit
for this state, for this state and we
will need that number back brought back
to our level of granularity
for City. Why we need that number we'll
find out in a bit but
now we know that that is our task. We
want to get to that number so even
though we're at the level of granularity
of City. How do we find out the profit
for the actual State? So let's say this
let's have a look here for North Dakota, a
total profit so sum of profit across
all items, in all orders, in all cities,
across all of the years is 7,002 dollars.
So how do we get that value seven
thousand and two dollars to this level
of granularity? How would we bring it
back? So that we can work with it at this
level of granularity. How do we display it
here?
Well that's what we're going to do and
for that we're going to need the exclude
level of detail calculation. So let's
quickly again create two
visualization side-by-side, so here we've
got just the normal profit right so this
one we're not going to change this is
going to be the visualization without
the level of detail calculation and here
we've got just the normal profit and
again it's not what we're looking for
this is just a profit for every single
City and this time it's very evident
that this is not what we're looking for
because in every State we want this
value to be the same across all the
Cities alright, so in North Dakota we
want 7,000 what was it
let's go back to this one here we want
7,002 dollars for this City, 7,002 dollars
for this City and 7,002 dollars for the
City. So each City should have the same
value as we can see that's not the case
so this is not the correct calculation.
So how do we do that? Well let's start
creating a level of detail calculation
we're going to create click here click
create calculated field, again we can
called LOD normally would call it
something like LOD state profit. In our
case I'm going to say be more explicit,
I'm going to say exclude, so this is the type of LOD what
we're using exclude and then state
profit is what we're after the final
result. So here again we going to start with
cur.. curly braces and similar syntax
to include but in this case we're going
to use the exclude keyword.
What do you want to explain? This is the
this is the interesting part. So we get,
we know that we are at the level of
detail of a City right and the way to
think about it more generic let's, let's
go back to the basics. The way to think
about it is look at all of the
dimensions, dimensions are these ones, the
blue ones look at all of the dimensions
that you have on your visualization. So
for this visualization and that's it's
not consider that I just opened this one
because we don't care about this other
visualization we don't care about
anything else we care about this
visualization look at everything all the
blue items how many dimensions you have,
country, state, city and don't treat them
as all together treat them as separate
right? They could have been a gender &amp;
region and category and ship mode. It
could be you could have lots of
different dimensions. So I'm going back
to the basics and trying to make this as
generic as possible so that you will see
that we don't have to work with
geographies. You can apply the same
principles with any type of dimensions.
So in this case, we have three dimensions
country, state and city that govern the
granularity of our visualization. That is
what's happening here. The green stuff,
don't mind the longitude latitude
there, they're a bit specific. The green
stuff here some profit that is measure
those measures they are the items that
get aggregated. So they don't so measures
don't impact your granularity and
aggregation level they just they are the
numbers that get aggregated. What impacts
your aggregation and granularity level
is your or are your dimensions so in this
case we've got three of them country,
state and city.  What we want to do is we
want to basically go back take this
visualization and remove city, go to this
visualization, grab this number,
grab the sum of profit and then go back
and bring it back to this visualization.
That's what we're going to do. So
basically what we want to do is we want
to exclude this blue item from
our visualization. This blue item is called
city, that's what we're going to say here
City and then we're going to put a colon
because that's the syntax. So we're
saying use the same level of aggregation
as a visualization but exclude city if
that item is present if that dimension
is present in our aggregation. Good so
that's what Tableau will do and then what
it wants to do for their or what we want
it to do is we want to take the sum of
profit one take the sum of profit
after we've gone so after Tableau does
this in the background take the sum of
profit. Great, you've grabbed it now bring
it back to this visualization. That's
what this expression means and click Ok
you can see calculations valid and now
what we want to do is we're going to
replace our sum of profit with our
level of detail exclusive and this is
the interesting part.
This is or second interesting part this
is where we'll see something familiar,
so let's drag it into here,
yep do you see what happened? Do you see that
the ATTR appeared and let's drag it into
here as well so replace that. Again,
ATTR appeared once more. So first let's
quickly check that the visualization is
now correct right? So if I zoom in, I like
that how the both map zoom in, so you're
controlling it's very handy I think.
You're controlling two maps at the same
time, very cool. Anyway, so let's go to
North Dakota you can see that here now
all of them have this 7,002 and even
though this one's not showing, you can just
right-click and not annotates just say
all the show from mark label it wasn't
showing because it's like overlapping
but there that's better. So you can see
that they all have 7,002 right or you can
you get the same color as opposed to
here. There are different or you can
scroll over to California and you can
see that over here all of them have
the same value which is 29,715,
the LOD exclude state profit, so this
shows us that we have achieved the
result that we wanted and every single
state we have been able to
capture the profit of the state and
bring it down to this more detailed
visualization which includes city and
display it there. So that's, that's a great
result congratulations on that. The only
question we have left is why is this
ATTR applied here? Well the answer is
actually rather simple, the answer is that
ATTR is applied because we need a level
we need some aggregation to occur so the
way Tableau works is we have a level of
granularity or level of detail for our
visualization and then all measures
should be aggregated at that level but
now there's a bit of a conundrum because
the LOD this few, this measure that
we're using LOD exclude state profit so
this measure actually comes from a
higher level of aggregation so from the
lower level of granularity it's coming
it's coming from this state
visualization so I'm just going to
remove city here so it's coming from
here right so and the thing is that
there's no point and there's no meaning
in aggregating this value 7,002
at the, at the city level
because it doesn't come so you when you
can when you aggregate, you aggregate
something like they say in the city
there's 50 orders, then you aggregate
them and you get a value that's what
aggregation is. That's when you use a sum
or average or a maximum or minimum sum
one of those functions but when
something is coming from a higher level
of aggregation so it is something is
already, even more aggregated than
your view so it's coming from the state
level to the city level then there is no
meaning in aggregating it because it is
unique for that this value 7,002 is it's
just that one value is unique for this
city it's you it's so this city doesn't
have more than one state that it belongs
to right only belongs to one state. Each
one of these any city belongs to only
one state so by default it will just get
that one value and there's no point in
doing the sum and that's what the
ATTR is telling us it's just saying that
ok cool we're just going to take the
value that we get from here and we just
going to apply it to the cities and
that's why when we were talking about
the ATTR that's why I mentioned that what
it does it actually applies or pastes the
value and it's so, this is similar to the
example when previously in our ATTR
investigation we took for the states.
What we did is we took country right we
took country and we put it into a
tooltip same thing ATTR of country was
applied because country actually comes
from here. Country comes from here
and it's a higher level of aggregation
and therefore there's no point in doing
a sum or anything but in this case it
was it wasn't even a measured with the
damage the only differences that now
we're dealing with measures it and
therefore might be a bit confusing but
principles the same that we're taking
something from a higher from an even
higher level of aggregation and
therefore ATTR is applied and I'll
demonstrate to you that it's is just the
way the Tableau specifies or and helps
you understand what's going on.
You can simply here just select measure
and changes this to sum and change this to
sum as well and nothing will change.
Why? Because well yes you are performing
an aggregation but you only have one
value your only summing across one
value which is 7,002 for the let's say
for this city, Mandan, the value 7,002,
and you summing 7,002, that's
it. There's no other value take the
average nothing will change again. So
therefore ATTR is applied because if
this value is coming from a higher level
of aggregation. Ok so hopefully that
makes sense?
It might say you take some time to get
used to ATTR but at least now we know
where it comes from and how it works and
also we have successfully applied our
level of detail calculation which is
exclude, now for now this was part one
because we only
got those values and this is quite a
useless visualization for at this stage
so what's the point of having this
profit for the state at level the city.
Well in part two, we will see how to
actually how we're going to use it in
our visualization. How we actually to
make this formula useful to give us
insights and I look forward to next time.
Until then, happy analyzing!