Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course on Tableau. I hope you had a chance
to play around with the visualization
that we've created and look at the
different industries in different states
and see what patterns you are able to
find and today the topic that we're
going to discuss is the primary use case
for data source filters. As you remember
previously we use the data source filter
to ease our work with a large data set
and that way we were able to restrict
the number of rows that we're creating a
visualization for and then remove the
restriction once the visualization was ready and
that's a handy trick for you to take
away and use whenever you're working with
large data sets and today we will learn
how to use the data source filter in its
primary purpose. And the primary purpose
for data source filters is to completely
remove categories or rows that
you're definitely not going to be using
in your analysis. So let's have a look
here, we already know that the only
industry that we're interested in in our
analysis is clothing retailing. We're not
interested in cafes, we're not even
interested in a clothing footwear and
personal accessory retailing because
that's a different industry. The one
we're interested in is clothing
retailing, so we don't need all of this
other information on our chart and the
natural way to get rid of it is to use a
filter. So you can take industry put into
filters select nothing and then just
leave clothing and re..clothing
and retailing and here you will have only
the desired industry for all the different
states. However, that's not the best way
to go about it because first of all now
we have a filter that we need to carry
around with us and probably the best way
to do it here is to apply to worksheets
and say all using this data source so
that you're different guaranteed that
this filter is applied across all of
your worksheets and plus like it's
already sitting in the filter shelf so
it's
distracting and taking up space and the
other thing is that Tableau is still
processing those rows so Tableau is
processing the rows and then applying a
filter every single time and that is
taking up processing power and of course
it's slowing down your dashboard. So we
want to get rid of those rows at the
data source level so Tableau doesn't
even know about them so they're not even
part of any calculation whatsoever so
that exclusion is done at the very
beginning and then it doesn't affect the
visualization at all. So that's where why
we're going to proceed back to our
data source we'll just right click here and
we'll say edit data source filters and
here we'll just add a filter and we will
say industry,
ok so same thing as we did just now
clothing retailing ok but now the
difference is that our filter is going
to be at the data source level we click
ok and as you'll see our visualization will
be updated in a second Tableau is
performing the pre calculations and
there you go, so that into those other
industries are gone and now even if you
want to visualize industries you will
see that there's only one industry so
I'll just create a new tab, I'll drag
industry here and you'll see that
there's only clothing and retailing.
There's no other options and note
there's no filter here. That means Tableau
doesn't even know about the other
industries because they'd be filtered out
at the data source level. So great, now
let's get rid of this. Delete sheet,
alright so that was the first example
how we're going to use data source filters.
The second one is going to come on just
now let's fix up the colors because as
we can see they're not the best right
now it's just orange everywhere, so
instead of industry here, we can
take industry completely out of our
visualization because it doesn't change
it's always the same industry. But now
into coloring, we're going take state and going to
drag it into color and this is much
better now.
Alright and the second thing is there's
a bit too many dates here.
The trends in the industry in the
nineties, in the or in the eighties in
the nineties,
doesn't, though they don't really affect
or they don't really impact how we see
the future for the industry now because
things were very different back then and
15 years
let's agree on this 15 years is more
than enough to make our prediction and
forecast so, let's take the past 15 years
and let's keep everything from a 2000
onwards and get rid of everything else.
Once again, what we can do is take date
and it's a range of dates and we will
filter from 2010, from 2000 so
somewhere from there, I'll just do it roughly
feel like that. We can do like that but
once again the filter will be here every
single time. We don't want that so we're
going to go and we will create a data
source filter so right click here edit
data source filters and add another one.
So here we're going to select date and
range of dates, we are going to go next and
here we just want 2000, first of first,
there we go so those are the dates that we're
going to keep, click OK and click OK
again and once again you see that the
correct dates are displayed and other
dates that were here behind, they are
gone. They're not even part of the data
set that we're visualizing. That is the
primary use case for data source filters,
it allows you to narrow down the data
that you're not analyzing. It's kind of
similar to taking excel and just getting
rid completely deleting the rows that
you're not you don't want to analyze or
the columns because we did do a pivot
but sometimes you can't but not always
you can do that because sometimes your
data might be in a database that you
can't modify and things like that so you
have to work with it somehow in Tableau and
that is a very powerful way to work with
it through data source filters.
Alright, so that's all for today and now
that we've prepared our data set and
we've trimmed it down to the rows that
we
you want to analyze, in the next tutorial
we will continue with our investigations.
And I look forward to seeing you next
time.