Hey Guys welcome to the first actual lecture of the course.
We're going to talk about Become a Product Manager,
why we made it,
what we're going to cover, what you should expect, and give you guys some tips with how you should go forward.
First, I thought we should just step back and answer the question "Why did we make this course?"
We've made this course because, as I got into my career as a product manager, there were so many people that
came up to me and were asking, "How do I become a product manager and what do I need to do?"
And, as you might know, product management is not something that you can study in school, there is no major for it.
There's very few formal education programs in order to get into product management.
Yeah. So I wanted to make Become a Product Manager because I have 11 courses on entrepreneurship
and I know that a lot of my students want to build a more well-rounded skill set with regards to starting
their own venture and product management is essential to that.
You need to have a basic understanding of product management if you're ever gonna be successful as an entrepreneur.
You know, there's a lot of skills that go into starting a venture, but then after it actually gets some
customers and it's off and it's running, it's now a product and you have to manage it.
You have to make hard day to day decisions about what features to drop, what feedback should you filter out or take,
how do you prioritize what metrics matter, all of this stuff is just crucial to being an entrepreneur.
Well, I mean we kind of alluded to it already, it's people who want to become a product manager, or
entrepreneurs, or graphic designers, even if you're just someone who has programming experience and you want to learn
this discipline because product management,
I mean, you'll see in the course it touches everything.
It's kind of at the center of all of the disciplines you will run into when you're in a startup.
It's also for people that are just now getting into product management and are wondering really how
to become a more advanced product manager or what are the rules and responsibilities and goals around
being a product manager at a company of various sizes,
because it does change.
We have 16 sections, something like that, so we cover an enormous amount of information.
It's divided into two different large sections essentially, modules we'll call it, the first one is learning
the discipline of product management, learning all of the concepts and the skills associated with it.
Then the second part is for those of you out there who want to get a job, we're going to take those skills and snowball
them into finding a job that fits,
angling yourself for that job, researching the company, writing your resume, getting the interview, and then nailing the interview,
getting the job, and then we even have a section on beyond that.
Yeah, we even cover some of the more of
minutia sorts of things like technology.
We're actually going to find all the technology that you'll need to know in order to interact with engineers more effectively,
and we talk about more granular things like metrics, and metrics that matter, and metrics that don't,
and give you practice and activities on all these lectures.
We also cover a lot of skills that are not absolutely necessary to being a product manager, but will make you a really good one.
We have an extensive section on building MVPs,
because that's my specialty.
So I'm teaching a hardcore version of how to build and test MVP experiments, we also do things like wireframing.
You might not necessarily need to know wireframing, but you're in a much better position if you know
how to.
We even have a section at the end that covers once you've got a job in product management,
again, we help you with your resume, and where to look, and all that sort of thing, but once you've got the job,
again, we help you with your resume, and where to look, and all that sort of thing, but once you've got the job, how do you excel?
What are the first things you should do as a product manager and then how do you sell? And this is stuff
that I've picked up over six plus years of
being a product manager myself.
All right, guys, so I hope you're excited to take the course.
We're excited to teach it.
There's a lot, a lot of information in here.
If you finish this thing, you will be insanely knowledgeable.
Yeah, you'll be in a really good spot, a much better spot,
I guarantee you, than I was in when I started out my career, or any number of current product managers, because
like I said, they all got into it in a roundabout way,
and only now are we getting to the point where
we can train people using courses online like this one.
All right, guys, see you in the next lecture.
See you in there!