Hey guys, welcome back.
Once you've prepared to look for product management
jobs, and you've got that good online brand, and you
think you can point to some relevant experience, you
have to know where to go to look for the jobs, and
really what you want to be looking for. In this lecture,
we're going to talk about three things: one, looking at your own company, two, networking, and three, looking online.
Firstly, it's important to understand that if you're really
serious about getting into product management,
then the best place by far that you can look
for a job is in your own company.
Trust me on that.
It's so much easier to move internally than it is to get a new job
as a product manager with no previous experience.
If you already have a product management team at your
office or your company, ask to shadow some product
managers in meetings to learn more about what they're
working on. What you should do here is demonstrate
that you're interested in helping them out and offer to
do some work in your spare time for their team.
The goal here is to learn as much as you can.
If you don't have a product team already at your company,
then you can still start offering to do tasks
and projects that will add to your product manager resume,
things like prioritization of initiatives, technical implementations, user interviews and research, and that kind of thing.
Secondly, it's very common for people to get jobs based
off of references rather than just applying to them.
This is the case with every type of job,
but so much more so for product management.
But in order to get references, you need to meet
people in the product management industry.
For that, I recommend you go to web sites like meetup.com
and look for product management or product
strategy meetups in your area.
You can go to these events, you can talk to people that
are product managers, you can find out who's hiring,
and maybe even meet somebody who would be willing
to provide you a reference for a job, or tell you about
an opening. Outside of finding product
management jobs through networking,
there's a few places I recommend you look online.
Number one, go to angellist.com, which has a big
focus on Silicon Valley tech companies, and look
for product management jobs.
Number two, go to Hacker News, and they have a tech,
it's a technology message board, basically, and you can
Google it or you can search on their site, because
they have a monthly thread called "Ask HN: Who is Hiring?"
Just Google it and you'll find the threads that I'm talking about.
They do this every month, and it's just full of
openings for product management positions.
The third place I would recommend is do a search on
Facebook for any local Facebook groups around your
city that involve any type of job,
but especially product or technology jobs.
These are really good to browse through and something
good to keep your eye on in case some listings come up.
I've seen a lot of product jobs go through
these types of groups.
Number four is mailing lists, and there
are some good ones out there.
I recommend a mailing list by a guy named Ken Norton.
You can go to kennorton.com, It's K-E-N-N-O-R-T-O-N,
and he's a really well-known product manager.
He has a great little newsletter, but he always
has job postings at the end of each e-mail.
Alright, so those are some tips on where to look for your
product management job if you're looking to get one.
And in the next lecture I'm going to give you a little
bit more inside advice on how to go about your
product management job hunt.
I'll see you there.