Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's dive into creating some hypotheses based off of
the assumptions we previously listed out.
You remember what goes into one of these, right?
No? You don't actually remember?
Well, let me tell you, because I only alluded to it before,
in the previous lecture, and you probably only heard
it if you were paying really close attention.
Pat yourself on the back if
you know what I'm about to say. The biggest difference
between an assumption and a hypothesis is that
a hypothesis is actionable. How exactly is it actionable?
Well, because it has specifics. We define a target group,
we're going to define an expected outcome
of our test, and we might even dabble with details
like why we expect our subjects to do something, or
how we plan to get them to do it.
So, target group, potential problem, an action,
and potentially even an expected outcome.
So we'll try writing out some of these formulas,
starting with the most basic and then building up to
more and more sophisticated versions. As a product manager,
you're probably going to run tests for a variety of scenarios.
You're thinking of launching a new product,
you're thinking of adding or removing a new feature
on your existing product, or you're looking to make
a significant change to the product features you already have.
We'll cover three different ways and you can choose
whichever one fits your needs for your exact situation.
Let's start with the most basic hypothesis.
It goes a little something like this: "We believe [...] will
[...] because [...]." The first blank is the subject.
We believe some group of people, some target group
of customers out there, the second blank, "will," is the
expected action we think they are going to do, maybe
they'll buy something from you, maybe they'll flock
to some new service, maybe they'll sign up for something, and then the "because" is the reason why we're predicting they'd do it.
Maybe it's because they want to save money, maybe
they don't like the competition - whatever it is we think,
that's what we're going to put there.
There you go. That's a hypothesis.
This one works great if you're building
a new product or you're an entrepreneur.
You want to establish, let's say, women ages 40-45
will sign up for weekly events newsletters because
they would like to stay informed about their city.
Yeah, I know it's nonsense, but if one the riskiest assumptions
was "Older women are interested in being
informed about news in their city," this would
pretty much nail it for you as a hypothesis.
Now, let's address some concerns.
Do we have to include or address a problem in our hypothesis?
Well, this is a bit complicated. At its core,
all products and all features stem from problems.
You're going to hear me saying this throughout the course.
Whatever it is, if you think long enough about it, you can
probably pinpoint some problem that it solves.
The problem with Google Glass, yes, is that you have to reach for your phone, right? As opposed to reaching for my phone,
I can have it up here.
I know, very trying times we live in, but it is still a problem,
regardless of the severity or the degree of the problem.
Whatever you think your users are going to do,
it's probably because you're going to solve or alleviate
some problem they have in some degree.
So if you want to be more accurate in your hypothesis
and do a better job, add a problem. And if you can't
think of a problem, it's okay. Instead, you can describe a benefit: [...] group would benefit by [...].
That doesn't necessarily get at the core reason why they
would benefit, because it's solving a problem at its core,
but sometimes that's something you really don't care about.
That extra bit of learning is really helpful,
but is it crucial? At this stage, not necessarily.
Ok, now that you have a hypothesis,
you would then go out and test that.
And this form is fine for this stage, because at this stage
you're just establishing that people are even interested at all.
You are completely waiting out from shore on this one
and you're just looking for a heartbeat of a demand.
This is what you might do if you were doing exploratory tests
that entrepreneurs are so familiar with.
But product managers might be managing an already
established customer base that has already established
that they want your product.
So we need to get more specific. Product managers are
often going to use MVP tests and hypotheses to make
changes to their existing product
in order to create a desired outcome.
In this use case, we're not just tacking on more product
to our product or creating a new product,
we're tinkering with what we already have built. Let's try
adding some criteria to accommodate for this type of scenario.
All right, new style of hypothesis:
"If we [...] we believe [...] will [...] because [...]."
Now we have an action.
If we change the color of the buy button, we believe
all users will buy more because they are busy and
often get distracted, like I do.
Now, that is something we can test.
But what about that word we used in there, "more"?
Well, you could actually use that word, and it's unideal,
but it can actually work, technically. Technically,
more means more, a larger number in some regard,
so it either goes up or it goes down,
which right now is fine. In the next lectures we're going
to talk about how you define what more means,
and it's called the minimum criteria for success.
I don't want to spoil it for you, but it's in the next couple of lectures.
But if we wanted to make it more specific at this point,
well, let's do that, and let's actually try to define
what "buy more" means, and let's just reorganize our
hypothesis to avoid making a nasty run off sentence.
Now, "buy more" could mean a lot of different things.
It could mean increased cart size for an e-commerce store.
It could mean they buy more often,
they return to purchase more often.
It could also mean that they buy the same amount of items,
but they are more expensive.
So, in this hypothesis, let's actually try to address that.
So let's say: "We believe [...] has a [...] because [...].
If we do [...] this [...] metric will be affected."
I know, this is kind of crazy, but all you have to do is
just fill in the blanks with what should go there, and
now you have a very easy template to use to make
a very specific and very actionable hypothesis.
Okay, now, in this scenario, we now have an action
we can take to solve a user problem that happens to a
specific group because of a reason we think. If we do this,
we assume this metric will then be affected.
And keep in mind that this is the product management
way of thinking: more specificity equals more focus.
Also, product managers love metrics, as you'll find out more later.
So, there you have it. Three different ways of writing
a hypothesis with varying degrees of complexity.
If you have to establish basic demand and basic validation,
i.e. new products or entrepreneurs, stick with the
short version of the hypothesis and just keep it simple.
If you're merely speculating on a way to change user behavior
and you're exploring this, then try the second type.
But if you want to manage a product, you've got to get used to
using the most specific one, which was the third type.
All right guys, you now know how to make a hypothesis.
Next lecture, we're going to do it for our example business, Zirx. See you then.