Hey guys, welcome back.
So, last lecture, we covered how to take your assumptions and then convert them into testable and easy to understand hypotheses.
And since we've been using that company called Zirx before,
as our example, let's go ahead and try out
making a hypothesis for Zirx.
Let's first go back a little bit and refresh ourselves on what
some of the assumptions we made about Zirx were.
Well, we were assuming a lot of different things.
We were assuming that parking in cities was going to be limited.
We were assuming that people thought garages
were too expensive.
Maybe they also thought that garages were inconvenient,
and we even had assumptions that were on the
supply side, where we assumed that people would
even want to park cars as part of our service.
Now, out of all of those ones we went over, we didn't cover
all of them in just that second, but do you remember
the biggest one, the one we were concerned about
the most, the riskiest one? The riskiest one was that
people will be okay letting an on demand valet park their car.
Well, let's try to think about how we would build a hypothesis
that turns this assumption into an actionable version of itself.
Well, we first need to define out the pieces of the hypothesis
and draw out our handy dandy template.
I'm using the shortened version because we're testing
a new service, so we're not really trying to tie
this to things like internal metrics, or, say, you know,
expecting this behavioral change because, well, we
don't have any data to compare the past behavior,
we're going to keep it simple.
Now, what are we to put in for the "who"?
Well, I'm guessing it's going to be people that have cars
and are probably in the age range of 30 to
50, potentially with incomes over, let's say, $80000 a year.
Really, I'm just spitballing.
Realistically, you would probably do some research here,
but this is a pretty plausible subject target.
Now, what's the action we're expecting them to do?
Well, it's let an on demand valet park their car.
Now, what's the problem we think we are solving?
Remember, again, we don't have to define the problem,
but I think it's helpful.
Well, you know, there could be a lot of different reasons,
and we highlighted them before in past lectures.
Let's just say that it's because garages are
too expensive and that's their problem.
We can even add a location if we wanted to add even more specificity to this, but that's completely optional.
They themselves actually launched in San Francisco,
so we could say San Francisco,
but really, it would be any city that has bad downtown parking.
Well, there you go.
We've pieced together a one sentence testable hypothesis,
and guess what? We got to wrap into that hypothesis
several other assumptions that were on our list.
See how that works?
If this hypothesis turns out to be true in its entirety,
then people do think garages are too expensive.
That was one of our assumptions. And if they end up completing a transaction where they use an MVP to book their first Zirx pickup,
well, then that also means that it's probably
not too difficult to use the service while driving.
Remember? That was also one of our assumptions.
Now, realistically, we could go at this in 100 different ways.
We could build a separate hypothesis for each
assumption and then consolidate them down when
we got to the stage of deciding how we need to test
each one. Or we could just do the biggest assumptions
in one big test and come back to the later ones
after we've done our first round of testing
and if we think it's absolutely necessary.
Like I said, many, many different ways of doing this.
We, in this case, started off with an assumption that
happened to be the riskiest, but it also happened
to be something that's pretty low difficulty.
So, according to our quadrant system, that is where
we would start anyway. In the next lecture we're going
to talk about how you measure whether or not
your tests end up being true.
It's a really, really important part of this entire MVP process.
See you then.