In the Agile app example, we took those 10 features we thought we wanted and we only selected a few that
we thought were the most important,
and we took those, and we researched them, designed them, developed them, and then released them and validated
whether or not those were the things that users were interested in.
Waterfall looks a little bit more something like this.
We take all 10 of those features that we think we want and we develop them all at the same time.
So we research, design, develop, and release
every single one of them all at once.
Doing things in a Waterfall way is sometimes pretty risky because your software product might have a
ton of features and when you have a ton of features it's going to take a long time to develop them all at once.
During that time your competitors may do something or you may find something else about the user needs
or market that makes it much harder to adapt.
You also might find that after you've developed it your users wanted something else that you spent little
time on and you spent the most time on stuff
that they're not actually going to be using.
So after all this trash talking on Waterfall development,
you might be thinking, "When is it ever useful?"
Well, there's actually a few specific use cases where Waterfall development is pretty useful, and we're
going to talk about those in the next lecture.