Hey guys, welcome back.
So let's make a real feature table.
Let's do it for my favorite company, GoPro.
Why they're my favorite? Because they're very easy to beat up on.
The true story, they're the most shorted company in the world.
If you don't know what that means, just Google "GoPro shorted company". Ok, let's see how this works in action.
Now, on the right we're going to put our actual product
as usual, we're going to put GoPro, and then
we're going to fill out the other competitors.
So, let me introduce the competitors. Now,
remember when we did this as an example and we wrote down some of the direct, and indirect, and substitute competitors?
Well, we're just going to make a feature table for the direct competitors, and I've just picked a handful
that I think would be worth comparing.
So, let me introduce the competitors. Ok.
Number one is Tom Tom Bandit.
This is the one that, yes, is made by that GPS company that was made obsolete the day Google Maps came out.
It also looks to me like a plastic hot dog.
But we're going to put it up there
because it actually sells pretty well.
Now, the next one is Veho. Now, that's the one
that looks exactly like GoPro.
They copied every single detail down to, like, the tiny little corners, and even the colors. I'm amazed they didn't get sued.
And the last one is going to be the Sony Franklin Delanor Roosevelt. They all have very strange names.
Ok, so stiff competition.
Now, we need to think about what are the most important factors for the people that need an extreme use action camera.
Now, if I were GoPro, I'd probably dip into
some of our data on customers,
I would research a very specific customer profile
I was going for, but for our purposes we'll give it our best guess.
I'm going to guess one of the aspects is going to be price.
Why?
Because I'm assuming a lot of our customers are broke surfers who don't want to spend too much if they don't have to.
Another one I think might be important is aesthetics.
Why?
Well, because with an action camera,
you're someone who does extreme things.
Perhaps you're a vain person - I'm making
judgments, maybe not true.
I think it's probably important that there's a cool factor to it.
You really don't want it looking like the Microsoft Zune.
The next one I'm going to put is weight. Kind of spitballing on this one, but I'm gonna guess since the idea is that
they're small and portable, you might wear it
on your head, or your chest, or something like that, that
you don't want it to infringe on your ability to
do whatever it is that you're trying to do.
So I'm going to guess you don't want something that has the weight of a bowling ball. I'm going to put 4K as well,
that is the new kind of cutting edge way of filming.
We are not shooting in 4K right now. If we were shooting in 4K, you would be able to zoom in and get into my pores.
But for people that are doing this I would imagine they want that. Why?
Because higher resolution makes your pictures
look better in general,
so I would imagine if you're going to do something extreme or cool, you want it to look as cool as possible.
The next one I'm going to put is Max FPS,
which means frames per second in camera speak.
What I'm getting at is, can it shoot in slow motion, right?
So right now we are shooting in 24 frames per second.
If I shot this in 60 frames per second
I would be moving really slowly in it.
It might look like some of those sequences
you see on commercials.
So I want to see how slow these can go. I think that's going to be interesting, because, again, people use these for action shots.
They want to slow down and watch the coolest parts.
The last thing I'm going to put is accessories.
Now, accessories I think are important, right?
Because a small action camera, it's small, it's kind of awkward,
you need to have an easy way of putting it on your wrist, on your head, on your chest, and using a lot
of tools to get what you need done.
You're not going to go grab a fork and duct tape it to it.
That's just not going to cut it.
Now, there are obviously some things I ignored, and these are just decisions I made. I ignored things like
battery life, I ignored things like the ability to edit on the actual camera, which is apparently a feature amongst the action cameras.
I also decided on camera controls probably weren't that important.
I don't really know how important it is to be able to scrub through your filming on the little box.
It just seems like all you need to do is press record and go.
Now, I'm making these judgments because
GoPro users probably want the cutting edge.
They want to film really cool stuff in short periods of time.
That's why I don't think battery life is going to be tops
for them - I could totally be wrong - and I don't
think editing on the thing is going to make sense because people who use GoPros probably want to make a
montage or a video that looks as good as possible.
That's not something you're going to get editing on a tiny little box.
Ok, I was lucky to get all this information
just from individual web sites
and a top 10 competitors comparison web site relatively easy. For you guys, it's going to be easy as well.
Just go to the actual competitors' web site,
they'll tell you everything you need to know.
Ok, in reality what I would probably do is go out, read consumer reviews, talk to customers, see what they
experienced, and most importantly,
I would play with the actual product.
There's no substitute for you actually using their product
and making a judgment.
All right. Let's fill it out for the GoPro. The GoPro costs close to $500, $499. Aesthetics - they're all kind of ugly.
I think it needs some improvement, but for the most part I think it's probably like a 7 out of 10. It's better than a lot of them.
Weight, 89 grams - that means nothing to me right now.
Does it shoot in 4K?
Yes, it actually does shoot in 4K, and I'm going to put a secondary piece of information which is that
it can shoot up to 30 frames per second
when it's in that high resolution format.
Max FPS, I just put yes because it can go above the normal FPS,
and it can go up to 120 if you're shooting in 1080p. For those of you who don't know what that means, just don't worry about it.
Accessories, I've put 100+ because when you search on Amazon, there are an enormous amount of accessories for GoPros.
Ok, cool. So now let's just start filling them out.
Tom Tom Bandit - this is what I gathered from their website.
They cost $349. Pretty expensive
but cheaper than the GoPro. Aesthetics, I would give them
a 4 out of 10. Again, I said they look like a plastic
hot dog, or a submarine with a big eyeball on the front.
I honestly don't know what they're going for.
Do you just run around with it like this and
you just point it at people like a laser pointer?
Weight, 190 grams.
I'm not sure what that means, but in relative comparison to the GoPro that's a big honkin item. 4K, yes it does do it.
But it only shoots in 12 frames per second. That's questionable.
The Max FPS is 60 frames per second, versus our 120.
And does it have accessories?
Yes, but not very many, only about 10 I could find.
Moving on to the Veho. The Veho is cheap, it's $200.
The aesthetics are very similar to the GoPro, it's just a little bit worse, so I'd give it a 6 out of 10.
The weight is 84 grams. Can it shoot in 4K?
No, it cannot. The Max FPS is, again, like our favorite plastic hot dog, it's about 60 frames per second.
Does it have accessories? More than the hot dog,
but still not a ton. I think I found around 15-ish.
And the last one, the Sony Franklin Delanor Roosevelt,
that one is probably the closest competitor.
This one is $399. Aesthetics - I give it a 6 out of ten. It doesn't look as good as the GoPro but it's not that bad.
Weight, it's 114 grams.
It can shoot in 4K and it can shoot up to 30 frames per second compared to the GoPro, they do the exact same thing.
The Max FPS is 120, and the number of accessories I could find was over the 25 range.
Ok. There you have it.
Now, what we could do is internalize this and understand,
are we beating our direct competitors?
Are we the obvious choice or
are we only appealing to one segment?
Are there areas we should focus our energy on improving?
Are there areas that we should just entirely ignore?
I would love to hear your guys thoughts on this.
Answer that question: what do you think?
What should GoPro do based off of what we just filled out?
Post it in the group discussion,
we'll talk about it.
In the next lecture,
we're going to do this again but we're going to do it
in a more granular way.
We're going to make a feature table for one specific proposed feature and we're going to use a platform
that everyone is familiar with: Udemy.
All right, see in the next lecture.