Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, so at this stage in the game we know
what we want to build ideally, whether it's a product,
feature, or a large change of the product we already have.
We also know what types of assumptions we need to test
to get to the truth and we also know roughly
what outcome we want to see out of this MVP test.
Let's now take a slight turn and start talking about
the ways and the tools that are available to us
to get this testing job done.
First off, when you run MVP experiments, you're always
going to present in some way, shape, or form something
that implies your new feature or product
is already real and/or coming very soon.
The reason why we do this, if you remember, is because
we need validated learning - we need our potential
customers or users to be in real life situations where they don't know they're being tested to see how they actually behave.
That is the data we crave and that is
the data that we have to rely on.
Now, it's obviously not the case that you have built
what you are saying you have, because internally
we haven't yet decided that. Now, the extent to which
you need to "fake it" in order to get the information
you need is what's going to determine what type of MVP you need.
So let's list them out and briefly discuss them.
In the following lectures, we'll cover each one a little
bit more in-depth, talk about pros and cons,
and when to use them. And in the spirit of faking it,
let's start, and let's start with the ones that are the most fake
and we'll get towards the end where we
talk about the ones that require less fakery.
All right, so the first MVP technique is what we call the email MVP.
It's the simplest one out there.
All you need to run an email MVP is an e-mail client,
some of your email list user base, and maybe some
basic wordsmithing skills. As an established company,
you already have a list of users, and most likely
you communicate with them on a frequent basis.
I can't really think of any company that doesn't use
e-mail marketing in at least some way.
So your users are already used to buying things,
or signing up for things, or engaging with the content
in the emails you send them.
They're already ready to have a test run on them.
By taking a small segment of your user population and
emailing them a pitch for a new feature or a new product,
you can see exactly how they'll react in a simulated
"this is real" scenario. Whether or
not this is a good idea as a PM is a different question, and we'll cover that in the lectures where we go more into depth,
but right now we're just covering what they are.
Product managers that are pre-product, also known as
early founders, can use this one quite effectively.
Even if you don't have an email list already, you can
gather a list of emails from potential customers
i.e. people that fit your target demographics, or your target customer segmentation and send this out
in much of the same way.
You'll probably take a much more personal tone
to avoid getting flagged as spam, but it's a very viable
way of testing and it is literally the simplest way of doing this.
If anyone is familiar with AppSumo, they sell
new products all the time in this way.
In fact, they're kind of like a daily deals website,
but for marketing and entrepreneurial tools. They
routinely test their new products by sending out
email MVPs before they acquire or build them.
They generally just say, "Hey, this is real.
Come sign up." And if they're even more brazen,
and I've seen this, they'll put an order button in the e-mail
and see if people actually buy right out of the e-mail.
All right, so that's an e-mail MVP.
The next one we're going to talk about it's called the shadow button MVP, and this is one that's very specific to product managers.
Shadow button MVP generally requires more resources to do
than an email MVP, but it's still, on the whole, very easy to pull off.
Now, what companies will do instead of building out
a new feature is they'll put a button within their
already made product that supposedly links the person
to this new feature. When the person clicks that
button, it registers that they did it,
and either, one, does nothing and just looks broken, or two,
shows text saying "Sorry, this is coming soon."
That is in essence a shadow button.
Again, people don't know if it's real,
so when we observe their behavior in this scenario,
we can generally consider it valid.
People act entirely differently when they think something is real versus if they don't have any reason
to think it's not real - you'll hear this over and over again.
Oftentimes you'll see shadow buttons be used
in mid-sized startups that are really trying to triage
their "nice to have features." Which login would you offer at first? Let's say you're a startup deciding
between email login, Facebook login, Twitter,
Google, and, let's say, LinkedIn log in.
Well, instead of implementing all of those, which is a
decently large task, you just put fake buttons for
them and record if people actually try to use them.
If they don't use them, then you know it's
not worth putting in just yet.
Now, is the shadow MVP a good idea?
Every time I say this, Cole just cringes.
Again, we'll talk about that in another lecture.
All MVPs depend on your organization, your size, and
some other factors we'll discuss. The next two types of MVPs
I've actually lumped together.
There's one that's called the 404 page.
And the two, which is called the "coming soon" page.
They're really similar to each other, but there's just slight variations, that's why we'll discuss them together. In this MVP tactic,
what you do is, again, act like you're adding a new feature
or a product, and when the user navigates to
the page that is designated as the new feature, or product,
or section of your site, it either displays
a 404 message - 404 meaning "server cannot find
this page," you'll find this anytime a server is
not working or you click to a page that's old and
it's no longer there - or a page that says "Thank you
for your interest, the product is coming soon." And then often
it'll ask them to sign up or display interest in some way.
Now, you might be thinking to yourself "Hey, this is way too scrappy. My big company, and our beautiful
brand, and bla-bla-bla, we can't use this possibly."
Well, guess what?
Guess who uses this technique every single day
to test demand for new products?
Amazon. Amazon.com is the king of using the 404 page or the coming soon sign up page. Amazon uses this extensively
to see if their existing user base is interested in a new side project or even a new category of goods
They track the interest against their criteria
of success and there you go.
That's how they know where to put their resources
and where to expand the Amazon empire.
It also works great for them because they have so many
random things attached to their brand that have
nothing to do with the core value proposition,
so it kind of makes sense.
Oculus Rift, if you guys are seeing that virtual reality
goggle system - we have an activity on it,
actually - is another great example of a company
that launched in a very similar way.
They just put up a pre-order page, and I'm sure you've seen
companies that have launched with Kickstarter pages.
They did the same thing. It's the same thing as a coming
soon page. "We're coming soon, sign up, or pre-order,
or get your foot in the door by paying us money."
The difference with Oculus Rift is that when they did that,
all they had was a very rough prototype, and
I don't honestly know if it even worked.
And the only other thing was a way to pay in advance,
so that pretty much is an MVP.
All right guys, let's take a break. Now that we've
learned three of them, try to digest that one.
Don't worry if you feel like you're a little bit lost on some of these, we're going to cover them in more depth later.
Feel free to pick which ones you want to dive into.
Take a break.
We'll start with the next batch in the next lecture.
See you then.