Hey everyone. This section was all about competition and market analysis. What you learned from Evan's lectures
is stuff that's really vital to understand if you're developing a new product or company from scratch.
However, if you're a product manager at a company or looking to get a job as one, this stuff will be extremely important to understand
from a theoretical level. Like we've mentioned before, if you're working as a product manager at a company
and they don't know who their competitors are,
then that's a red flag.
The people you work with and of course the executives will know exactly who the competitors currently
are or. if there are none yet. then they will know who is in a position to start competing with you soon.
The biggest tip I can give you as a product manager when it comes to competition and market analysis
is to stay on top of industry news and pay very close attention to the features that competitors build.
It's also great to look across industries at similar patterns even if the company does not directly compete with you.
Here's an example of that.
If I'm building social features for an app that lets people read books on their smartphone, I don't only
want to look at other smartphone book apps, I should also look at other apps that are social in general,
like Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram, to see what they have in common, how users are interacting with them,
and what I might learn from the lessons they've already learned, since they've already been doing social.
Overall, if you're always up to date on what competitors are doing and have informed opinions about where
they will go next, you will gain respect from co-workers and go really far in the role of product management.
So that's it for this one. I'll see you all in the next lecture.