Hey, everyone.
I'm with Dave Lifson of New York, VP of Product for  Homepolish,
and we're going to do a little bit of an interview here
on some product management topics.
And Dave has been, Dave,
you were at what? You were at Etsy before,
like, long ago, and what, Amazon as well?
Yeah, so my first job out of school was at Amazon,
I was a software developer, and then realized within
probably 15 months that I was made to be a product manager, and so I got to switch to the recommendations
team at Amazon, which is, you know, because you
bought these items, we recommend these others.
And I was at Amazon for a total of two years,
learned a ton, loved it there.
Then I had an opportunity I couldn't say no to to move to Brooklyn from Seattle and be the first Head of Product at Etsy.
So that was 2008, when Etsy was 50 people
and all three founders were there.
And I then did my own startup for three years
with the technical founders of Etsy,
we sold that company,
I joined General Assembly as employee 25 and grew
that from 400 when I left, over two and a half years.
I started running curriculum and then moved to
running a product design and engineering.
I spent a year a PopIn doing the same thing,
product design and engineering, and then now
I just started at Home Polish about a month ago.
Cool.
So this course has about, right now it's over 4000 students that are involved, and it's only been out for about a month,
and it's focused on people that are new to product
management or people that are in the role and
they're trying to get better.
And one of the recurring themes, as I know you know
from teaching at General Assembly, and that's one thing,
it's that product management, like, learning about it is
quite popular right now, because it's becoming a more
popular role, people are starting to learn kind of what what product managers are doing, they want to find out more,
but there's no good way to learn about it,
like, you know, in a formal way,
you can't get a degree,
you kind of, like you and I both just kind of happened
upon it, you know, I think most people end up doing that,
and I think, right now, due to things like General
Assembly or like, this course, you can,
you can learn about it formally from an actual product manager.
So, like, the first question I wanted to ask,
is, it's an interesting one, no matter who I ask,
it's like, if you had to sum up the role of product
management in a sentence or two, what would it be?
- What does product management mean to you?
- Oh wow, yeah, that's really great.
So what does product management mean to me?
I think the role of the product manager is to have a deep
understanding of the customer, a deep understanding
of the business, and marrying those two together
to identify opportunities and problems, prioritize
those opportunities, and then devise
the right solution for the right time.
And so, what's so challenging, I think, about product management is that we don't fit the mold of the individual contributor.
I think organizations historically have been structured
similar to, you know, how they were in the industrial
revolution, with manufacturing, where you just, you have
departments that have workers, and workers create
output, and coders write code, and marketers, you know,
create marketing, and designers create designs, and
product managers don't create anything.
[...] don't do anything in circles [...] for everyone else
that we work with in the organization
so that the quality that is produced is higher, and the solution is
sort of, you know, more efficient and more effective.
Okay.
And so, what did you think about the role
before you were actually a product manager?
Did you have any preconceived notions or
did you know anything about it?
Well, my first team at Amazon, I was in the
community group, which did user generated content.
And so, my little corner of it was this thing called List Mania,
where Amazon customers could create lists
of their favorite products,
you know, like your top 10 things to take with you
on a camping trip, or my favorite scary movies.
And we had no product manager,
it was just a bunch of engineers, and we just built
whatever the heck we wanted to build.
And so I ended up, Jeff Bezos had this idea,
this was back in 2006, where, you know, Facebook was becoming a thing, people were talking a lot about networks.
And so it was like, you know, what if we created a network
of product skews? You know, if products could
have relationships to each other, what would that look like?
And somehow that ended up like, on my desk,
as a 23-year old, and so we decided to
build this "hot or not" for products.
So essentially customers could vote on which of these
two shoes is more stylish, or which of these two
electrons are
easier to use, and as you voted,
we would use your votes to generate you a recommendation.
It was very expensive, we built the whole thing, we launched it, and it was a total disaster, the conversion rate was somewhere around
like half a percent.
And, you know, it was like such a clear example of
how product management could have saved the day,
and we just didn't know it.
- Yeah, working on the right thing rather than just something.
- Yeah,
or testing any assumptions, or doing any sort of
user research, or prototyping, you know.
And so, when I moved into the recommendations team,
which did have, you know, a track record of having strong
product managers, I was surrounded by people who could really show me the ropes, which is sort of how I learned.
So, something that we talked, because you mentioned this, like talking to users, or validating something, validating
your assumptions,
another thing that happens quite often to us as product managers is we talk to users, or we get feedback, and they send some sort of request,
or maybe for an internal product manager, you get basically what amounts to like, a feature request or a product spec request,
and oftentimes that thing that's being requested
is not what is actually the solution.
It happens to everyone, you know,
If you move two levels deeper, there's actually another
problem here that maybe that solution doesn't solve, and
so when you're receiving feedback from users,
you've got to, you know, dig in deeper. Do you have any, like,
war stories of like, these requests that are just absolutely,
they're just not the, you know, solution at first, that you
can share, and maybe what the real solution was?
Well, I don't know if I can tell you the real solution, because
I don't know, but I'll tell you a story of this exact thing,
except it wasn't a user, it was a founder.
So this was the end of 2012,
and the founders of...
- Hey, sorry about that.
So we had slight technical difficulties.
That's okay. Do want to ask question again?
No, no, we can just totally edit it in.
So you said it was the end of 2012 and that's all we got.
Yeah, so it was the end of 2012 and the founders were
really worried that the business model was looking
a lot like University of Phoenix, in the sense
that our revenue came from
adults coming to a classroom and learning,
snd so, revenue was really constrained by, one,
our ability to purchase or rent real estate,
and then, secondly, our sales ability to fill that real estate.
And so, they came to me and they said "We really need something
that is a subscription and can target customers
who don't live where we have classrooms,
and you have three months. Go build it."
And so, this is like, this was a big mistake for me because,
as a product manager, I should have recognized
immediately that there was no mention of the
customer here, or any sort of customer problem.
This was something that came out of a spreadsheet
and an analysis of sort of like market evaluations, and
"it would be really nice if, you know, this cell in our
Excel spreadsheet was twice as big."
And, in some cases, it is up to the
product manager to translate that into,
okay, well, then I'm going to go do some user research
and sort of discover what a customer problem is,
and then work towards product market fit.
But given the three months timeline on top of that,
we felt really pressured to just sort of look around
to see what assets we had available and what we could
package together, and so we did happen to have
a library of live streams that we had recorded
and stored away, and so we said,
"Okay, how about, for $25 a month,
you can have access to our library of videos?"
And we called that front row.
And so we built it, we launched it, it did okay, but no
matter how much we optimized the sign up flow,
the UX, optimized the acquisition marketing
channels, the LTV just really wasn't there.
I still today feel like, at its core, subscription is
just a very odd business model for education.
So yeah, that was always a tricky one.
Yeah.
I've got tons of stories myself.
But that's the one thing all PMs have in common,
so there's always these weird user requests.
And yeah, I think, in your early years, you're
probably just going to do those things,
and then you realize that a big part of your job is taking all of those, figuring out what the real underlying need here is, and
in another interview we did,
we were talking about that quote that,
I think, the Henry Ford quote, which was like,
you know, people would've asked for faster
horses instead of the car, back in the day,
because they just can't see past,
you know, not everyone is sitting back and thinking big all the time,
and Apple sort of takes advantage of this with their products,
by not asking users what they want, but rather seeing
what people want through usability testing, all that,
and then kind of giving them stuff that they didn't know
they wanted or needed.
Yeah, it's really, this is really the hardest thing, I think,
for a product manager, because when you're,
when you're starting out in your career, I think it's, like,
you want to get some traction, get some projects
under your belt, just sort of like, practice the process,
and so it's much easier to take things sort of after product
market fit, you're just, you're in optimization mode, right?
How can we take our sign up flow and
increase conversion by 10%?
And, in that case, you do your user testing, you, like,
suss out those steps in your funnel that are
giving you the most trouble,
and then you just tweak them, and so it's very, like,
here's my problem, here's my solution, and solve it.
But when it comes to like, inventing the iPhone, or,
you know, it's such a big open ended problem
that it requires I think a very different approach
where you really want to take more of that IDO
style, user centered design approach of
"Let's just like, in a very open mind,
just talk to people, and learn their context and their
situation, and then take these leaps of faith and
do a whole bunch of prototyping around it. Yeah, it's very difficult.
Okay.
So, just a couple more questions. One, because not only you're a teacher, you've taught product management in the past, but you also are
a hiring manager, now a VP, and before that,
Head of Product, if you were to look from the inside out
and say, if you were doing it all over again, and you didn't
kind of fall into the role, like you or I did, but
you were actively trying to get into the role,
let's say in a modern, like, you know, current day, how
would you recommend that someone with very little or
no experience who tries to work their way
towards getting a product role, like,
what skills maybe should they learn, or how
should they look at approaching it?
Yes.
So I think the way to do this is to really show
that you understand the product management
process and that you're able to apply that
process to a lot of different situations.
So, the process, in my mind is, you know, identifying
what you think the problem is, what you think the
customer is, what you think the solution is, going through
this iterative approach to getting to product market fit,
being able to draw upon a lot of different tools
in order to validate those assumptions,
all of those different MVPs that you want to use.
And I think that there's a lot of different ways in which
you can sort of demonstrate your understanding of that.
You can go to a Hackathon and work with people and just
sort of, you know, in the span of two days, apply the
process, or perhaps you work in marketing, or you
work as an analyst, like, you can still get involved in
the development process, at least perhaps in the
user research part, or the opportunity analysis part.
And so, you know, and that way you can then actually
structure your resume so that it highlights all of
those different steps of the process.
So as a hiring manager, I'm going to be like, "Okay, they
don't have the product manager title, but they completely
get sort of like what the five steps are, and they've
shown that they've done those steps in the past.
Yeah, okay, that's really good.
So this is some of the advice that I give
in terms of prepping for the role.
First of all, look internally, it's one of the easiest ways,
obviously, but if you're not able to do that, you're trying
to apply somewhere, then you should look at things you've done in the past that have to do with product management, and since
it's such a vague and wide ranging role, everyone has done something that a product manager will do at some point,
you know, like cross-team collaboration, or project management,
or coming up with a few different ideas, and
finding the best one with data.
Even people in, you know, community operations, and customer service marketing, people do some things in these roles that are
kind of product management style things, and then sort
of shape your resume to explain those things, that's
kind of what I'm hearing from you.
Yeah, I mean, let's say you're an account manager,
you know, you talk to customers all day.
So, put together what you think the product roadmap
should look like, and then support your proposal, like
what is the data behind your prioritization, what
is the user research behind your prioritization,
you know, what are the risks and assumptions that
you would want to validate for each of the ideas in
your roadmap so that, you know, you would feel confident
that executing those roadmap ideas would in fact
achieve the desired goals.
Yeah, absolutely.
Okay.
For the last question,
if someone is, let's say, very familiar with the stuff, and they're looking at just, they're just looking at learning real hard skills,
so either technology, or UX, or something like that,
let's say they're going to take a PM course somewhere
and then they're also going go learn a skill.
What skills would you recommend that people be like,
either really familiar with, like a technology,
or something that really stands out to you
as being a big benefit on someone's resume?
Well, certainly they're going to need to understand
just basic Agile project management principles, and
so, being able to break things down to user stories,
and sprint planning, and sprint retros, and, you know,
just the mechanics of that.
I think wireframing is something that they should be able to do.
They don't need to learn a tool like Sketch or OmniGraffle,
I think it's fine if you just grab a marker
and paper and just can draw.
But you need to be able to communicate what you see
in your head to other people through pictures. And
then on the technology side,
I think people have the most anxiety about the technology
piece, and what I would tell you is spend some
time understanding how the internet works.
So if you type a URL into your browser and click Go,
what happens? And you should be able to go
really, really, really deep on what happens, you know,
10-15 different steps between when you hit Go and when
the page shows up on your site or on your browser.
And you can,
and I would not feel like you need to learn a
programming language, you don't,
I don't think you need to learn HTML and CSS, I don't
think you need to learn Ruby on Rails, as much as it
is more important to just learn internet architecture and
just how do web servers work.
Yeah, and things like, in the course I talk a lot about, you just need to understand what front-end is versus back-end, and
where things are being calculated, like, where the logic is living, on the server, on the front-end, or how do things get to your browser
or your device.
Yeah, and I think, like, if you want extra credit, you could
probably spend some time learning SQL, because a lot
of times product managers need data.
And so, sometimes they have to go get it themselves,
because there's no data department to do it for them.
Right.
Awesome.
Okay, so I think we're just about out of time, because we're in different time zones, and you've got to get to work.
But thanks.
Thanks a ton for this.
And yeah, do you have, I don't know, web sites, or Twitter handles, or anything, blogs that you want to pitch, as the last thing,
for the students that want to follow you in there?
Follow me?
Oh, no.
I'm not much of a social media person.
I mean, no, sorry, I don't.
I mean, like,
you know, you can find me on Tumblr at caterpillarcowboy.com,
but it's just my personal blog, like
there's nothing on there that you're going to learn much from.
Yeah, that's good, that's what
I like hearing, to be honest, because it means you're
not on Medium, posting those, you know, life help, life
advice articles that a lot of people do.
Yeah, you know, and like, I don't know,
Twitter just stopped being exciting for me like five
years ago and so, but here I am, I'm happy to teach,
you know, and give back.
Cool.
All right.
Well, thanks.
Thanks a bunch.
- I really appreciate it.
- Yeah, you bet.
All right, catch you later.