So now that we understand what epics are in concept,
let's talk a little bit about how they work in reality.
Most project management software gives you the ability
to create an epic and then add features to that epic.
This really depends on the project management
software you are using,
but, in any case, epics always have documentation with them,
and it describes what it is you're building and
then why. This documentation is called an epic spec sheet and
it's sometimes referred to as a requirements document.
You can make one pretty much anywhere, like Google Docs, your project management tool, or anything else that you want.
It's just got to kind of be out there in the public for
people at your own company to look at. The purpose
of an epic spec sheet is to allow anyone in your company
to read it and understand exactly what you're building.
It also serves as a guide for your own team as you build things.
So what do these epic specs look like? Well,
they usually have four main areas: an introduction,
the product requirements, the design requirements, and
then the engineering requirements. As a product manager,
you're in charge of creating and maintaining
the whole epic spec sheet and the epic itself, but you're especially responsible for the first two sections, which, again, are the
introduction and the product requirements section.
Let's go through each section of a typical
epic spec sheet individually.
So, first, we've got the introduction. This is really just a
summary of what the feature or features you're
building are for and why you're building it.
What metrics are you trying to improve?
And you can also put in any links to supporting
documentation or other miscellaneous things like
marketing plans, legal requirements, and that kind of thing.
This is also where you can write down what a feature
or functionality looks like, some early wireframes,
and what it looks like in an ideal state down the road
versus what you're going to start out building
for your MVP, and then maybe what it looks like for a V2, etc.
So the second section is the product requirements.
And here we're talking about the features or
functionality that we're developing in detail.
We go deeper on what is required.
For instance, we might say that the feature has to be
fast, or it has to be available in a certain language,
or it must generate a certain type of data
and then store it for later use.
So the next section is the design requirements.
This section is to be filled out by both you
and the designer together,
but a little bit more emphasis is to come from
the designer here, since they're the experts.
Let's imagine that, for a particular feature, the designer
wants to display the user profile picture with
a really high resolution, because they think
that's the best design.
This is where that would be stated.
This is also where you and your designer will attach
any early wireframes, and sketches, or high fidelity
prototypes to help the engineers better understand
the requirements and what's got to be done here.
So now, onto the engineering requirements section of the spec sheet. This is the portion that is mostly filled out by your engineers
after you discuss the product and design requirements with them.
Here is where the engineers can write
out database and technology requirements, or outline
the series of things that must be done on the technology
side in order to support the new feature.
An example here would be developing a certain API
endpoint in order to get the high resolution picture
stated in the design requirements.
Or they could know that they need to work with another
team to access their database in order to get
the information that's required to make this feature.
So let's recap here.
Epics always have accompanying documentation or spec
sheets to inform other teams or guide ours as we build.
In most cases, this epic spec sheet will have a few major
sections, including introduction, product requirements,
design requirements, and engineering requirements.
It's important that your epic spec sheet is available to
anyone in the company so that they can easily
understand who is building what, like which teams are working
on what things, and why they're working on them.
I also want to mention that the way that companies do epic spec sheets is not the exact same from company to company.
Some companies will say "Our epic specs or requirements
docs need to have more information or less,"
and some companies don't even use them at all.
But this is the standard practice, and you absolutely
need to be familiar with it as a product manager.
So we've got the basic foundation of a new feature,
or functionality, or set of functionalities with epics
and epic spec sheets.
Let's find out in the next lecture where we go after that.