Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So, in this lecture,
we're going to start talking about the actual
customer interviews. In this lecture, we're going to cover
four different types of interviews,
talk about why we will be engaging with customers,
what we're trying to get out of them, and how in general these interviews are conducted. Now, as a product manager,
there are numerous reasons why you will want to engage
with your customers in an interview setting.
Entrepreneurs, on the other hand, generally will
talk to their customers at the beginning,
at the outset, just to figure out whether or not they're onto something, and they'll then use that information
to figure out how to build an MVP.
But there are other reasons why you might engage with the customer, and it kind of just depends on what
you need as an organization, as a product owner,
and where you are in your product's progress.
Now, the first type of interview is the exploratory interview.
Now, an exploratory interview is the most
freeform interview there is. The idea here is
you're really just waiting out to see,
talking to your customers, trying to establish whether or not
they have certain pain points, whether or
not they're open to certain solutions, and, in general, what do they feel like, what do they look like, and how do they operate.
The idea here is that you are exploring, you're fishing,
you're trying to find things your customers have
a problem with, are excited about, you're trying to find
things that they do differently than other people,
you're looking for any little clue or a hint that can give you
some type of insight about the product you
already have or the one that you're building.
This is often something you will do when you're trying to come up with ideas, ways of changing your product, ways of expanding it.
You will have a back log but you do have to
come up with new ideas.
When you talk to an actual customer, talk to them about their day, the context in which they use your
product or could use your product, they'll give you a million different things that you can build a solution for.
And the best part about doing this in person is
you can visually see how badly they want this solution
and whether or not they would pay for it.
Here are some example exploratory questions that
you might ask a customer. Let's say we're using an app
that has to do with getting directions. I might ask,
"What's the worst part of your commute?"
It's an open ended question, fishing for some type of pain,
and to understand the hierarchy of problems they have
within the context of a certain situation.
Another question I might ask is,
"When you get lost driving, what do you do?"
I'm fishing for substitutes for solving their problem, and, again,
they'll color in kind of my picture of what
normal consumers do when they're lost.
Now, the second type of interview is the validation interview,
and this is by far the most common one.
The purpose of a validation interview is that
you have a theory and you want to test it out.
Your theory might be that users will go bananas for feature X
or you might be pre-product and your theory
is that "My solution solves their problem."
That is always a theory until you launch, until you get validation, and until you reach product market fit.
Now, let's talk a little bit more about validation interviews,
because they are the biggest deal
of them all, you will do them as a product manager and
you will do them as an entrepreneur. Unavoidable.
Generally, validation interviews are run in a very specific way.
Because you have a theory and you want
it to be proven or disproven, you kind of
have to run it in a scientific way.
Now, do you think that in a validation interview you just
walk right in there and say, "This is my product,
or this is the feature I'm adding. What do you think? Do you like it?"
If I were standing right in front of your face like I am now,
coming through the screen, and I asked you,
"Do you like my web site? I spent six months working on it."
Do you think you're more likely to say yes or say no?
You're probably more likely to say yes because
you're probably a decent person and you want to please me,
and that's generally how human nature works.
Validation interviews are hypersensitive to bias,
so much so that they're run in a way that you don't
even introduce your idea, your theory, your product,
your new feature till the very, very end.
You spend the majority of the interview talking around the problem your product solves. When you do introduce it,
you don't hype the idea, you don't defend it,
you don't exaggerate what it is. You simply present it and then collect honest feedback and try to chart
how they react and how they think after it.
The problem is that if you bias their answers in any way,
if you infringe on their ability to think freely,
even if it's very subtle, you have essentially ruined the interview.
Any data you got from that is junk. It's poison.
So learn to zip it and let them do the talking.
Let them in their own words to describe the problem they have
and what they think of your proposed solution.
You spend  the majority of these interviews not pushing your customer, but corralling them in the right
direction, trying your best to get them to talk about the problem you are trying to solve in their own
words and to see if they themselves find it on their own.
Let's give some examples of a validation type question.
I might ask you,
"Do you ever lose things in your house?"
followed up by, "Do you ever lose your keys?"
What I'm doing there is I'm asking them about things they
lose in their house, seeing if they say anything
about their keys, and if they don't, I try to
narrow the focus down to keys, so then I ask them if
they lose their keys often to see if
that is actually something they do.
Now, that's a good pre-product question,
but what about a post product question?
Well, a post product validation question could be like,
"When you're using our app and you want to collaborate
with your co-workers, what do you end up doing?"
This might be on the heel of a feature that allows them to collaborate within your app and you're trying
to chart how they solve that problem, whether or not they have
that problem, or if it's even something they care about.
The third type of interview is a satisfaction oriented interview,
and satisfaction interviews, they're exactly
what they sound like. You're trying to dig out what parts of your products are working for your customers
and what parts of your product are not.
You're also trying to gauge in general what they think about your product. As a product manager, you need
to know whether or not opinions of your product are going south,
or if they're jumping ship and going to your competitors.
But more importantly than just knowing that, you need to understand why they are. So get at the root
of their dissatisfaction or figure out what exactly you are doing right.
Some example questions might be, "What should we stop doing?"
A great open ended question trying to get them
to tell us what exactly simply is not working.
If something's abrasive, if something is just
going against the grain for their experience,
they'll tell you. Another one I like to ask is "What's
one thing I could do to make this better for you?" If
they have something that is lacking, they will bring it up.
It's a great way of digging out the number one thing on the top of their mind and whatever is most important to them.
Now, the last type of interview is an efficiency interview.
In an efficiency interview, you're trying to
figure out how exactly your product ingrains into the life
of your customer and, as a function of that,
how can you improve it to better serve its purpose.
You're trying to get an idea for who uses your product, what do they do on it, when do they use it,
under what circumstances. And from that contextual learning,
you can figure out what parts are serving
them well, what parts are unnecessary or inefficient, and what parts are actually degrading from what they're trying to do.
You'll fish for things like, "Are they using X, Y, and Z feature?"
and "What are they using X, Y, and Z feature
for?" It's very common you'll find people not using
your features or your product exactly like you thought.
When you do find that, it's generally a sign that something
is broken in your process, either something is too
hard to understand, or the process is too inefficient,
or you're just targeting the wrong people.
Some example questions you might ask in an efficiency type interview is, "How easy is it for you to use
feature X?" You're just trying to figure out, in their own words,
is this something they enjoy using?
Is it easy for them to use? Is it easy to understand? All of it.
Another question might be something along the lines of,
"If you wanted to do [...], how would you do it in our product?
It's always interesting to ask customers to show you
how they would do something and you can see at
what point in time they got confused, misdirected, did something wrong, or figured out something you never thought of.
Ok, so those are the four different types of interviews,
and I know you're asking the question.
"Well, aren't there interviews that do both or a combination of them?" And yes, absolutely, so don't necessarily
think of them as just types of interviews.
They're more the purposes that you would use an interview for
or whatever your focus is on an interview.
You can definitely do a validation interview and an efficiency interview in the same setting. Alright, in the next
lecture, we're going to talk about best practices
when you are talking to your customers,
how can you make good questions, how can you tell
when you're asking the wrong questions,
and what in general do you want to shy away from.
Alright, see you in the next lecture.