Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Let's talk about explainer videos and how best to use them.
First off, let's answer the question
"Why do people use this technique versus others?"
Well, it's simple actually. Video converts
much better than just text pages.
This is what every company on the planet is figuring out
and it's the reason you're seeing more and more videos embedded everywhere, including your Facebook news feed.
Another reason we might choose this is because an
explainer video can do a really good job of getting
across a product that needs in-depth explaining.
Some products are just inherently complicated,
which makes pitching them difficult.
You can cover way more ground in a shorter time
through a shnazzy video.
The next question is "When should we use these?"
Well, an explainer video, as you remember me saying,
can be a lot of work to create.
They often need videographers, editors,
and potentially custom graphics.
On the flip side, they can really excite your user base,
if done well. Let's look at a couple examples.
Hello. This is Joe.
Joe runs his own business selling local goods,
but Joe has a big problem.
He's got too much to do and he can't find qualified help. Everywhere Joe has looked, he's only found unqualified
employees.
Then, one day, Joe called The Solution Company.
Over the phone, The Solution Company was able to analyze
Joe's needs and match him with qualified candidates.
Within days, Joe had a wide selection of qualified,
pre-screened workers to choose from.
Thanks to The Solution Company, Joe can now sit back, relax,
knowing he's got the right people for the right job.
Do you want to find the right people for your business?
Call The Solution Company today.
Let The Solution Company provide you with pre-screened
and qualified candidates to grow your business.
So how do you balance this exactly?
Well, like anything, it's going to come down
to your organizational profile.
Companies that rely heavily on video already use video
frequently with their users, and they're going
to be much more likely candidates to use this type of test.
Why?
Well, for one, you probably already have the infrastructure to create half decent videos without a significant
amount of work and outside recruitment.
Another reason is that if your users are used to seeing video,
then they're more likely to respond to video.
If you use a service like Wistia, you can see how many
of your users watch the entirety of your video.
Wistia, by the way, is just a platform that lets you
embed videos in web pages, emails, really anywhere,
and gives you detailed analytics about how people engage with it.
Very similar to the YouTube analytics system.
If you run a content web site that rarely uses video content,
throwing an explainer video for a new feature
is probably going to get ignored and skew the results of your test.
Same goes for web sites that simply have older demographics.
Old people and video are just not really a thing.
My grandma, for the most part, thinks the iPad is the
work of the devil, and videos just don't really register
with her. As a funny aside, check out our Oculus Rift
activity, if you haven't already.
There's a video of old people using Oculus Rift
and it's pretty hilarious.
I'm not going to electrocute myself.
A snorkeling mask? Something you would have in a wartime situation. It's a space mask, I don't know,
or something you wear for the Ebola crisis.
This could be some kind of mind control
hypnotic thing you're going to try to pull on me.
Oh my, walking without using my feet.
I mean, it's all very fake-looking, but it's beautiful.
Let's not do this.
What happened to the track?
We just jumped off the tracks! There were no tracks!
Other things to take into consideration are
your size and your users' expectations. If you have
no online presence at all,
i.e. you're in that entrepreneurial pre-product
scenario, then you can be a scrappy as you want.
My favorite way of making explainers in this case is to use just cheap softwares like PowToon, GoAnimate, or even
just hiring someone on Fiverr to make a video for me.
If you haven't set the bar for quality yet, you can get away
with whatever quality you can afford at the moment.
That flexibility is fantastic, and embrace it.
If you're larger, however, and you have already dabbled
in video in some way, be aware that you do have
a quality bar to get over.
If you make slick, fun videos that your users are used to,
then out of nowhere you create a poorly produced
screencast with low quality voice over, the difference
in what users expect and what they find will taint
their perception of whatever you're trying to pitch.
The key here is to try to be as ordinary as possible.
You don't want to stick out either way relative to
the other video content you use. Explainers
are an interesting way to go, but they're definitely something
you need to internally assess before you try it.
The bonus of using explainers is that, in general,
video is just more engaging with your users, and this
increases the likelihood of being shared, which is great.
The downside, obviously, though, is that it could
just simply not be your demographic.