Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Let's talk about one of the last types of MVPs that
we covered: the piecemeal MVP. Now, piecemeal,
if you remember, is when you piece together other
softwares to create the functionality that you need
To better help you visualize what this concept is,
because it's kind of confusing,
let's go over an example.
Let's say you had an online course, like Udemy.
You're on it right now watching the course.
Let's say you wanted to add a certificate of completion
so that anyone who finishes a course would get
e-mailed a PDF that says "Yay, you've finished the course!"
Well, instead of building an auto PDF generator
and setting it up to know when the user finished the course,
maybe you just add a link to the end of the course that
takes them to a form. They can then input their
name into that form with their email, and then they can
get a PDF certificate sent to them that way.
How you can make this work is by, let's say, using
Typeform, which is a form software, to create an
online form with a public access link.
Then you could have Typeform submit that
information into a Google sheet -
if you've never used Google sheet, it's just Excel but online -
which can then trigger something like Zoho invoice to create
an invoice with the information and send out an e-mail.
There you go.
It was one, two, three steps and you've accomplished your goals.
If you wanted to pursue this option, the best way
would probably be to physically write out what your
feature or product needs to do, and then use those
functions as just search terms in Google by adding
things like "software" or "online"
at the end of your search query. You would be amazed
at just how much you can get done with available
softwares that are out there.
Once you mark down what you think will do it,
then you just need to find what combination is going to
work the best and cooperate together. Typically, piecemeal MVPs are best suited for when you want to add
some functionality to your product that's relatively common.
If enough products and people start using, let's say,
text message reminders in their app, eventually there's
going to be an online software that tries to simplify
adding that process and then makes money by saving
companies the hassle and the money of
doing it from scratch themselves.
That's great and can be a seamless integration for you.
When a piecemeal MVP is not generally a good idea
to pursue is if you have, let's say, multiple
functionalities you need to implement, because, in general,
it's kind of a pain to get off the shelf software
to cooperate with each other. They can do it,
that's the hard part though, especially when you're chaining them together, it can get really complicated.
Oftentimes, you'll just end up running into dead ends,
trying to find some obscure software that needs
to send some obscure information to another obscure software.
It can become a hairball really quickly
and you'll wish you didn't get into that.
If you do for whatever reason decide
that this is what you want to do,
here are some tips.
Number one: piecemeal MVPs are becoming quite popular
and online softwares are so common that there
are systems cropping up that can actually help you facilitate interactions between all of these softwares.
The two that are worth checking out are Zapier,
which I can never pronounce, it's Zapier, Zapier,
and the other one is IFTTT, which stands for
If This Then That. In both of these, you can tell it
to, say, you know, "Every time a new note
with this text is created an Evernote, send information
to MailChimp," and then it can trigger MailChimp
to do something else. With some persistence, you can
actually daisy-chain together a whole list of these
different things and you can get quite a bit done,
and these softwares will make it a lot easier for you.
Number two: as a product manager, it's rarely the case
that you're going to get away with sending people
from one external app to another, and another.
Look for softwares that allow white labeling, as in, look for
ones that allow you to put in your own images, put in
your own colors, and put in your own fonts, or even
better, look for the softwares that can
integrate into your existing product, so
it looks like it's part of your product. That lowers
the chance for users to abandon the process,
and, in general, it just looks a lot more professional,
which is a problem with piecemeal MVPs.
Sometimes they just don't look that great, and people can tell
that you're just sticking a bunch of services together.
All right guys, so that's piecemeal MVPs.
Any questions, post in the Q&A and we'll jump on it.
Otherwise, moving on to the next lecture,
where we talk about concierge MVPs.