Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, so now you are pretty much up to your neck
in information about how PMs look at MVPs and what
they are from an academic sense. You understand now
that MVPs, they change depending on the size
of the organization, because organizations have
vastly different amounts of resources to work with.
So, in the next set of lectures in this section,
we're going to go down step by step the process that
a product manager would take to come up with
an MVP experiment, and run it, and then learn from it.
Now, I'm going to explain briefly how the general
flow of an MVP experiment is going to go.
There are seven steps and we'll start with the first one.
The first step in running an MVP experiment is just
figuring out what exactly your problem and solution
set is. We're not going to jump on this in this section,
because you should have done that in the last
two sections, where we talked about figuring out what problem
your product or feature is actually aiming to solve.
Now, you don't obviously need to know for a fact that that problem exists and that this solution is the best solution,
that's what we are going to use an MVP experiment for,
to figure out whether or not this is the right combo.
But once you do have on the table
what you want to try, the next step,
step number two is we need to identify the assumptions
associated with this problem - solution set.
Any time you launch a new product, come up with a new feature,
you are assuming a lot of things, there are
a lot of things you just take for granted,
and there's a lot of different things that go into the
success of a product. So we're going to systematically
set down and try to think of what are
all the things that have to go right
for this to be successful. And at the end of that process,
we're going to figure out which of these assumptions
is the riskiest, which is the gunpowder in the bottom deck
of your ship that could just sink the whole thing.
The next step, step number three, is once we have our assumptions, we're going to work on building testable
hypotheses out of them.
It's a relatively simple, straightforward technique.
We'll take the assumptions and we'll figure out
a way of stating what exactly we think they are and
then establish criteria for testing. Building a hypothesis
around an assumption is relatively easy.
All we're doing is building statements that we are
confident about and we want to test based off of the
assumption. In the next step, step number four,
we're going to set up what's called a minimum criteria
for success. If we're going to run an experiment, and try
to test our assumptions and prove our hypotheses,
we need to know what constitutes success
and what constitutes failure.
If you don't do this step, you have no idea if you succeeded
or you failed. We've got to draw a line in the sand
and then later we can look and say, "Ah, no,
I fell right before the line," or, you know, you actually
made it past it. The next step is picking
what type of MVP you're going to run. There's a lot of different ways of getting validation from your customers or potential customers.
It's just going to depend on what suits you, what suits the feature that you're going to propose and you're trying to build,
and it's also going to really matter on how big your organization is.
The last two steps are executing the MVP experiment,
running it, getting it out there, getting some real, live
data, then iterating on that, collecting the data,
and figuring out whether or not you succeeded,
what worked, what didn't, and what you would change if you
were going to redo this experiment. At that point, you'll
have a hard yes or no about whether or not this is
a viable option and it's worth your time compared
to other opportunities you might have.
All right guys, hope you're excited.
In the next lecture, we're going to start with
step number two, which is taking a problem-solution set
and identifying assumptions that we are making about it.
See you then.