Hey, guys, welcome back to the course. Hey, so I wanna
make a quick pit stop to talk to you a little bit
about how customer development is going to defer in your career as a product manager, and this will help
you understand how we teach this section.
So one thing you need to understand about customer development is that it evolves throughout the lifecycle
of your product. You, as a product manager,
your role is going to evolve as well as your product
goes from baby to teenager to adult.
Now, what you need to be aware of though in customer development is that there is a very large chasm
or divide between when you are validating a very new product
and reaching out to customers, or when you're
trying to improve an existing product
with an existing customer base.
Those are two roles that every product manager
will actually have to tackle.
However, we treat them a little bit differently.
Now, when you don't have a product and you're trying to figure out whether or not you're going to build
a product, you're primarily going to be running your customer development and running your customer development
interviews with potential customers,
and when you have a product, you're going to be running it
with existing customers. Now, it doesn't sound like
there's a huge difference but it's actually an enormous difference.
Potential customers do not know you.
They probably don't know of what you're trying to do, the information you going to try to get out of them is different.
The way that you have to reach out to them is different,
and in the second case it's also very, very different.
Your customers you're going to be talking to, you already know who they are, reaching out to them is generally easier.
And when you get them on the line or in person
it's an entirely different script.
Now, keep this in mind as we go through this section.
Customer development will vary in terms of purpose,
but very rarely in terms of form.
We still will use the same guiding principles we'll learn in the section for either pre-product or post product interviews.
The primary difference is the type of information
you're trying to get out of them.
So, as we go through this section, I'm going to be dividing
everything as pre-product, potential customer,
and post product, existing customer, and in a couple of cases
I'm going to explain one, next lecture explain the next one.
I suggest you learn both techniques.
But if you only want to learn the type of situation
you're in right now - say you're an entrepreneur and
you're launching a new product - then you can focus on
pre-product, potential customers, and if you're someone
who knows that you want to manage a product
that's already existing, you can focus on the other.
But again, I suggest both.
All right. See you in the next lecture.