Hey, welcome back.
So now we're going to talk about user stories and
acceptance criteria, which are underneath epics.
We already know that an epic has an epic spec sheet
associated with it to describe what we're doing
here, and what sorts of functionalities we need, and all that,
but we're going to talk about now how we actually get
that into the developer's hands and turn it into work.
So here we're going to assume we've made a decision
on what we want to build,
we've outlined the phases that we're going to build it in,
and we've put all that in the epic spec sheet.
Now, the task is to put this work into our project management software, so that the engineers can start working on it.
This is where user stories and acceptance criteria come in.
So, a user story is just a way to describe a thing we're going to build that delivers some type of functionality to the end user.
An example of a user story is "As a user, I want to
send pictures in a direct message to my friends, so
that I can share my favorite photos with them."
That's kind of a weird thing, right?
It's a weird format.
User stories always follow that format:
"As an X, I want to do Y, so that I can Z."
So why do we do this whole weird formatting thing?
Why are we describing work to be done in this weird way?
Do you remember how product managers are responsible
for the "what" and the "why," and the engineers and
designers are responsible for the "how"?
That's the reason that user stories follow this weird
format, because the product manager is usually
the person that writes them and puts them into the product management or the project management software.
By writing them this way, we can avoid saying how
something should be done on a technical level.
In other words, by writing in this format, we're
not telling engineers how to do their jobs,
we're just telling them functionally, as a user,
what we want the user to be able to do.
Okay, so where do we write user stories
and how did they get to your engineer?
Well, they belong inside your project management tool,
and no matter which software you're using for project management, there's probably some kind of place,
or card, or something where you can write the work
to be done, and then you can change that card or that
place into different statuses like "to do," "in progress," and then "done." These little cards or whatever you want to call them,
they're commonly called tickets in the product management world,
and it's where your user stories belong,
along with proper designs from the designer.
So, engineers take the user stories, they complete them,
and then they move on to the next one. However, before
we can say that a user story is complete,
we have to make sure that the functionality
does what we intended it to do.
This is where acceptance criteria comes in. Acceptance criteria
is just a set of conditions that software
must satisfy to be considered complete.
Typically, acceptance criteria is written inside of
the ticket with the user story and sounds a little
bit something like this: "Given I am a user and I click
the 'add picture' button in the direct message, I am
presented with a pop-up window to choose the file
I can upload, submit it with the upload button, and see a preview
of the uploaded image." And then, here's another one.
"Given I am a user who has successfully uploaded a photo
from my computer, when I click 'send,' the image
is sent to my friend through the direct message
and it appears in the chat."
This sounds really specific, right?
Well, the purpose of acceptance criteria is to be
very specific on how a feature should function.
It provides a list of things that you can test to make
sure it works before you release it to the public.
This is also extremely helpful for engineers, who like
everything to be very specific, so that they can
think through the process of engineering the stuff correctly.
As a product manager,
you are usually responsible for testing completed
tickets and stories before approving them to go to
the public or to go out live in your product.
So that's it.
Tickets inside of project management software have user
stories that describe what a user should be able to do,
followed by some acceptance criteria that really
spell out exactly how it should work. Okay,
look, if all of this is a little bit confusing to you,
don't worry. I'm going to show you a real life example coming up.
I will see you in there.