What's up? You've probably heard of the terms
front-end, back-end, and tech stack before.
So let's demystify these real quick.
It's not hard, it won't take us very long.
So we already talked about the Internet and how it works.
We know that when I type in google.com, my laptop
or phone, or smart internet fridge, or whatever else
is on the internet of things these days,
yeah, it connects to the Google servers through the internet.
If I use a web browser like Google Chrome and I go
to google.com and do a search, the web browser
on my laptop asks Google for the data I requested
and shows me the results that Google sends back.
Okay, in all of this, there's a couple things going on here
from the technology perspective, and I don't mean
the internet, I mean the code. Google is figuring out
what I'm requesting from them,
whatever I typed into the search bar, they're getting
that information from their database, and then
when they send it back to my web browser,
they're showing me the results.
Each of these levels has programming behind it that is often
referred to as front-end, back-end, and application layer.
So look, front-end is just a fancy term for
what the users see and interact with.
This is colors, text, and interactions I see on the webpage.
So there are programming languages that make up the front-end,
and they're most commonly used for the front-end,
especially on the internet things, like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
We're not going to go into those too much, but I'll
give you a super brief primer. HTML, you can think of,
like, the structure and content of a web site,
so it's the actual text. CSS is a language that is used
for styling that text and that structure.
So, okay, this font should be this color, and this big, and
this is how pictures should be stretched across the page.
And then you've got JavaScript, and that one is basically
in charge of the interactivity on the web site.
So, okay, when I click this button, it does this little animation,
or when the user types this, this happens over
here before it goes to the servers, that's what
JavaScript is doing. Anyways,
those are the three that really make up most web front-ends.
All right.
So back-end is a fancy term for information servers and databases that are located somewhere else - in the back-end.
So the technology that is used in the back-end is
things like MySQL, which is a database language,
combined with technology that hosts that database on
the internet, like Amazon S3. Amazon S3 is basically
servers for rent, basically that Amazon host, and
anyone can really just go in and sort of rent a server
from Amazon on the internet.
And this has, by the way, contributed to how quickly internet businesses have been able to grow or test
things without spending too much money, because in
the old days, you used to have to buy that server yourself, install
it, and put code on it, and all that sort of thing.
Now you just go to, like, Amazon AWS, Amazon Web Services,
and you just type in, "Okay, I want an S3 server
on the internet, I can put my code on it, and I can run
a website without actually ever owning a server myself."
Anyways, you might have heard that first term I mentioned, SQL.
I mentioned MySQL, but it's spelled M-Y-S-Q-L,
and the term SQL is also talked about a lot as
a query language, because SQL itself is a query language.
So if you hear SQL, or MySQL, they could be
talking about a query language.
This is just a way that we can structure a request to
a MySQL database to get information back.
By that, I mean, quite literally, a lot of people at
tech companies know how to query SQL.
They will say "Hmm, I wonder how many users we have
as of today?" and will just enter in a SQL query, and
something like "select all from the user database, count
number of users" and that will just spit out a number,
and says "Well, here's all the users in the database."
It's relatively simple to learn, so I do recommend you check it out.
Okay, so what if there's five different screens on
an app that all pull data from one database?
How does the front-end know where to get that data, or what if
it needs to do some sort of logic or calculation on it?
This is where the application layer comes in.
So the application layer is just a term for some code
or programming that does calculations to the data
from the front-end or the back-end and it sends it to the right place.
You can think of it as being in between
the front-end and the back-end,
but in reality you just have the front-end and the
back-end, but the application layer is the code,
and it usually lives on the front-end or the back-end,
but it's not always consistent, you know, where it lives.
All of this stuff really just has to do with how
the product or the app is programmed.
All right, let's go a little bit deeper into that.
If I'm using a web site like Amazon and I do a search
for products from highest price to lowest price,
the application layer takes my search,
it talks to the database, it gets the items I'm interested
in from the database, and then sorts them in
the correct order for the front-end to display
to me in my web browser.
The web browser is interpreting the front-end code
that gets generated and showing it to me.
So there's a lot of programming languages out there and
there's a lot of them that are used for this application layer.
Some examples though are things like Ruby, Python, or PHP.
You've probably heard of Ruby, by the way, because
you might have heard the phrase Ruby on Rails.
Well, that's not the same as Ruby,
but Rails is a framework for Ruby.
Anyways, I'm not going to talk about frameworks
right now, but we will talk about them,
I just wanted you to know that if you've heard it, that's why.
Okay, so we've got a good overview of the front-end,
the back-end, and the middle part or the calculations,
which is called the application layer.
So what is a tech stack?
All right.
A tech stack is just a way of saying the programming
languages or technology that make up a web site
or app from the front-end all the way to the back-end.
Some products use different databases or languages
to program the product and all the stuff that happens
there than others, because some languages have advantages
over others for certain types of work or services.
If you applied this whole tech stack concept to cars,
it would basically be the same as describing which
type of engine, tires, transmission, and what
kind of metal your car is built out of.
It's basically the same concept. Alright, easy stuff.
But one thing I want to mention lastly here is that
all of the stuff I've been talking about is the
same with mobile devices and mobile apps,
except that sometimes, instead of a web browser on a
mobile phone, like an iPhone or Android, you're using
a native mobile app, and instead of those, they have
mobile apps using HTML, and CSS, and JavaScript in
a web browser, the app likely uses a language like
Swift or, yeah, Swift is for iPhones, or Java for Android.
So those, in the case of mobile, serve as
the front-ends for mobile devices.
All right. Quick recap here.
The front-end is what users see and interact with,
with buttons, text, and colors.
The back-end holds all the information in a database
on the internets, and somewhere in between there's
some code that basically does some calculations
and sends things back and forth to the right places,
and this is called the application layer.
All right, the next logical topic to talk about is APIs,
and you're going to be using a lot of that in
product management, you'll hear it all the time.
So let's get to it. I'll see you in the next lecture.