Hey everyone.
So now we have a really good idea of how to
work and communicate with engineers.
Let's talk about designers. Designers, just like developers, often have certain ways of working that you should be aware of.
Here are some tips on working with them.
Number one: designers are very creative, and you want them to take a lot of creative freedom in the work that they do.
You want them to feel free to really stretch
the limits of their imagination. Because of this,
it's really important that you're clear about any limitations.
Let's say, for instance, that we're designing a new
profile page for users, and the designer wants to put
in some data that we don't have accessible at the moment from
the database, and it would take a lot of work to get.
It's important that we tell them about this early, because
one slight change could change their entire design.
Keep this in mind.
Number two: like developers, you should not be treating designers as an agency or someone who just makes things pretty.
This is a big mistake I see tons of product managers make.
90% of the time,
designers are going to know much more about user interactions than you.
Not only that, but it's their entire job to make sure
that what they are making fits well within the other
areas of the product, and the other designers,
and the stuff that they're doing as well. Always provide
designers an ample opportunity to give you feedback on
the core of the idea or the product that you're working on.
And I mean from the very product and idea perspective,
not just the wireframing and design part. Number
three: you and your designer should function as a team.
Again, this means that you should be giving them the opportunity
to tell you their opinion on the product and the feature,
but it also means that you should be giving them data
showing them user feedback, and not just saying
that this is the thing we're developing or building
"because I said so." That's really bad.
You need to basically be showing them the reasons
that you came up with this being the thing that we're
doing next. Number four: don't ever tell the designer what to do.
Remember, as a PM, you're responsible for the "what"
and the "why", but not the "how."
If you dislike something in particular about their work,
feel free to highlight it in broad terms, but don't
tell them what needs to be changed.
For instance, if you think that something is confusing
about their design, remind them that it's important
that the interface is as clear as possible, maybe user
research shows that the least technologically
adept people are a big part of your user base,
for instance. At the end of the day, you have the final say
on the product you release, but you should never
ever have to exercise that power.
Okay. Number five, and the last one here.
This is one of the best tips I can offer for working
with designers, and it's to always talk about user
problems first and solutions second.
In other words, don't say to them that a user should
be able to send photos in a message to another user,
because then you're just describing the solution.
Instead, talk about the fact that the problem that
users can't express themselves to one another with
photos or media in a message is the real issue.
You would be really surprised at how helpful this
technique is in finding the best solutions to actual
user problems, and designers really appreciate this approach.
Okay, so now that we've got a good idea of engineers
and designers, let's talk in the next lecture about
communicating with executives and other stakeholders.