Welcome back, everyone.
So in the last lecture we talked about all of the places where you can receive user feedback and ideas.
Once we have this list of ideas or feature requests,
do we just go build them?
Let's say that a user has given you some feedback and they want you to build a native mobile app for
your website, so you get that feedback
and you just go out and build it, right? No.
Being a product manager is about a lot more than just learning a few skills and applying those skills.
One of the most important things about being a product manager is having a product manager mindset, and
a big component of that is being able to understand the core pain points, the real problems behind what people ask you to do.
So, in this lecture, that's what we're going to learn,
how to get that essential skill.
Let's start off with an example. Let's say that I have a friend - and I don't really have any friends, so
this is an unrealistic example, but let's say that I do -
and they are standing outside in the rain, and
they're getting all wet, and they're upset about being wet,
and they say, "Cole, can you give me a towel?" And I give them a towel, and they dry off, and they get dry for a
few minutes or maybe a few seconds, and it's still raining,
so they keep getting wet. Did I really solve the problem?
Well, of course not.
They asked for a towel, so that's what I gave them.
That was the request to me.
But is that the actual problem?
No, the actual problem here is that they're in the rain.
So the actual solution would be to get them out of the rain.
So I know that example sounds pretty ridiculous,
but this sort of thing happens all the time in the world
of product management.
People are always asking you to build things or add features, and those things at first glance seem reasonable,
but actually they're merely symptoms of a real problem the user is having behind the scenes. Being a product
manager is all about finding a solution to a problem instead of trying to fit a problem to a solution
that you or someone else has thought of in the first place.
Given any request or feature idea,
the first thing I want you to do is think to yourself,
"Is this solving an actual problem?"
The second thing I want you to do is ask yourself,
"If we do this exactly as they ask without looking
any deeper, is it going to have any unintended side effects?"
I'll give you an example of an unintended side effect.
Everyone's familiar with Twitter, right?
They've got several hundred million users. The way Twitter works is you can type some characters and
send it out as a tweet that appears on your profile and it also appears in a news feed for everyone
that follows you. On Twitter, you can also re-tweet,
which is clicking a button on their tweet and it
puts it on your profile, and all of that also feeds into the news feed.
So if you're following a ton of people, then your news feed
can understandably get pretty busy.
One of the most common things people ask for on Twitter is the ability to just filter out re-tweets.
So the idea is that if the product managers and developers at Twitter just made a button where you
wouldn't see re-tweets on your timeline anymore,
it would make things a lot less messy.
Sounds pretty reasonable, right? Now, Twitter as a business model is a company that really just tries to
show everyone out there what is really popular right now.
So what are people around the world talking about?
Think about re-tweets for a moment.
When I re-tweet something it's like saying "I really like this."
I endorse it. I like it so much that I'm willing
to put it on my own profile.
So if we built this feature and it got pretty popular then we could have, say, 20% to 40% of people not seeing re-tweets at all.
What ends up happening here is less and less people re-tweet because there's not as large of an audience,
and then Twitter has less of an idea what people really strongly like or really strongly endorse.
This makes it even more difficult for them to
separate out signals on what's globally super popular.
This affects normal users as well.
So with less people re-tweeting, it's more difficult for them to tell what is super popular or what people really, really like.
So, remember, the request here was to allow us to filter out re-tweets on the Twitter timeline, and we've
just covered that might not be the best idea because it has some unintended consequences.
I'll give you an example from my career of a feature request that did not actually address the user problem.
A while ago I was a product manager at an e-commerce web site and we were working on building a new
content management system for the marketing team because they had outgrown the old one.
This is basically a system by which they can go and edit the photos and the text and that sort of thing
on the web site while the web site is live.
So I'm meeting with the marketing team and I'm writing down requirements and they're saying we need it
to do these things.
One of the things they mentioned was, they said they needed the ability to put up a small message on a
specific product web page to tell the users something and they wanted to be able to put that up and
take it down pretty quickly. At that point I could have said "Ok, I'll take that into account and I'll
make sure that whatever we do will give you that feature."
But instead what I did was ask them what's behind this request what did they actually want it to do.
So I asked why this was actually a requirement
and for what reason do they need this.
So it turns out that the merchandising department told the marketing department to tell me that this
was a requirement, and the reason was, it turns out, that they would hold sales on particular product pages
and on this short page in particular the sizing and pictures were a little bit misleading.
So when a lot of traffic went there, it ends up that a lot of people left because they were confused.
So what they wanted was a little, basically a message where users would know to call our customer service
line to better understand it.
So after hearing all of this it was pretty clear to me that the real problem wasn't that they needed
an ability to put up a message really quickly for customers.
The real problem was that the page was extremely misleading
and causing problems in the first place.
So after hearing this I went back to the designers and developers and told them about this and we went
to the drawing board and talked about
how we might make this a lot clearer for customers.
Once we had solved this on the web page it was not really a problem anymore for the merchandising department
and the customers didn't need to call
into customer service anymore.
So, problem solved.
But the real problem was solved, not the initial idea or requirement given to me by another team.
I want to show you a really easy way to get to the core issue of a request and see what the actual problem
is, and this is a technique that a lot of salespeople use
and have for a really long time.
So it's really easy. You just ask why.
But then you ask it two more times at least.
So if someone asks you to do something you say "Why?"
He'll tell you, you say "Why?" again,
and they'll tell you a reason that's a little bit closer to the truth.
And then you say "Why?" again,
and by the end of it they'll probably
have illustrated to you what the real pain point is.
It seems really obvious but in fact it's not.
And there's so many people that just skip over this simple step.
Ask why.
I once took a sales class back after college.
It was really, really good.
And this guy that taught the course was in his early 50s.
He had done some of the best sales jobs in the world and his number one piece of advice was to do this,
and this technique works with product management just as well.
So in this lecture we learned that the product manager's job
is not only to listen to the requests the
person is giving us but to find the real pain behind the request.
What is the real reason they're asking for this?
We also learned that the easiest way to get to that
is to continually ask why.