Hello, my friends.
So, welcome back, and we're going to talk here about APIs.
Look, in your work as a product manager, and in many
other roles in the technology industry, you're going
to hear this term API a lot.
Usually, you're going to hear some engineers talking
about it, and sometimes they'll be like, "Oh well, we
can't do that because the API doesn't allow us."
So let's demystify that.
What is an API?
API stands for application programming interface.
The easiest way to explain it is that it's the messenger that
takes requests and tells the system what you want to do.
Then it returns what you requested, the information, back to you.
Let's make it even more simple.
Imagine you're at a restaurant and you're looking at the menu,
and the kitchen has some delicious food,
probably some barbecue, if it were me, and I'm like, "I want
that barbecue" but I need a way to get that food from
the kitchen, because they've got to make it for me,
and then they've got to send me the food.
So I've got to request it, I've got to make it, I've got to send it, and what I need in this case, like, the missing link here is a waiter.
The waiter comes to me and says "Hello, how
many pounds of barbecue would you like, Cole?"
And I'm like "10 or 15 pounds."
And then he goes back to the kitchen, he gets me
15 pounds of barbecue, brings it back to my fat self.
So he's done all this translating to kitchen language
and bringing me the food.
And that waiter is like an API. Also, in this case, the kitchen
was a database - a database full of delicious barbecue
in our example. Okay, so there's two types of APIs.
I know, it seems like it's getting more complex,
but I promise, it's not that hard.
There's a public API and a private API. Public APIs are
provided by companies to allow products or services
to get data from their system.
A great example of this would be on a travel search
website like Kayak.com, where you can search for
a flight across different airlines for the cheapest price.
Kayak takes what you type in about what dates you want
to travel, and then using the public API of every
single airline, or at least most of them, it returns to
you the prices and availability for all the trips.
This is because Kayak does not have the information on
all airlines, at all times, and all flights, but they contact the
airlines' databases through the API.
They did this because the APIs for the airlines are
public, which means that they let anyone, like a
developer, like Kayak, and the engineers there, just dial in
and get that data, and provide some services based on it.
Why?
Because now they're making more money,
because if Kayak does a good job marketing, people are
going to come there, and they're going to search
for flights, and they're going to buy more stuff from the airlines.
So a lot of tech companies out there have public APIs to encourage developers to build products using their information. Here,
you can see a documentation page for Twitter's public API.
All right. So what's a private API?
Now, these are APIs that are available only to the developers inside of a company to get information from different internal systems.
It's example time again. At Facebook,
there's probably a database that holds the pictures,
and another database that holds the messages, and
there's probably a lot of databases for
a lot of different things at Facebook.
So if a developer on one team, let's say this developer
doesn't work on the photos team, or the pictures
team, but they want to code a new feature and they need access
to the pictures database somewhere inside of Facebook servers.
Then they will write what is called an API call in their code, and they will write this API call to what is called an API endpoint.
The database then sends back the pictures that they requested.
By the way, this API endpoint is just a fancy way of
saying "access window" or something like that.
It's an address that allows developers to get a certain type
of data, and sometimes the endpoints have limitations
to prevent problems, like, maybe they will say, "Okay, you
can only send a hundred requests per minute, because
if you go above that, it's going to overload our
systems, and things will crash, and things blow up.
Anyways, don't worry about that.
I just wanted to let you know that that exists. Alright, I told you
that was not very hard, but we're going to recap anyways.
Basically, APIs are just ways that developers can write
code to other systems and get data from them.
There are two major types of APIs, public APIs and
private APIs. Public ones are available to anybody,
including you, if you're a programmer, and then
private APIs are available only to people inside
of that company, which means not you, unless
you work at that company. Alright everyone,
I hope you're learning some stuff here.
I'm going to see you in the next lecture.