Hey everybody, what is up?
I wanted to take a moment to let you know what I would
recommend for you to look into further for technology
to really get the most you can out of a product management
role and really impress the people you're working
with with your technology knowledge and just
the breadth of stuff you're able to understand.
So here's my recommendations.
You should really look into some different programming languages,
and then the types of frameworks that are available around those.
I already mentioned before how Ruby is different from
Ruby on Rails, because Ruby on Rails is a framework for Ruby.
Really briefly on that, a framework is, well, you can
think of it like speed dial for programmers.
So instead of me having to remember which numbers
to type for calling a friend, I could just hit a button
and speed dial them with one key press. In a way,
this is what frameworks do for programmers. So,
imagine that you are going to use a language like Ruby
to make a web site where people can log in and
you're going to store the login information, and
the passwords, and all of that stuff in a database.
This kind of thing has been done so many times and
there are so many good practices to do that that
it's pretty safe to say that if someone just did it really
well one time and just provided an easy way
to kind of replicate it that it would be a benefit.
This is exactly what frameworks do.
And in this case, if I wanted to do that, I could use Ruby
on Rails, and use a few simple commands basically
and it's just going to auto generate a database for me
hosted somewhere, and it's going to generate all
I need to basically have users be able to log in, and,
you know, put in a password, and all that sort of thing.
So frameworks are things that are structured around
programming languages, it's like commonly done things
in programming that allow developers to work faster.
The more knowledgeable you are about these different
languages, like PHP, or Ruby, or Scala, or Java, it's
just going to help you, you don't have to learn them,
you should look up about them and
see what they are best used for.
It's going to help you out a ton, and then if you understand
the frameworks on top of that, it's going
to be really helpful.
Secondly, I already mentioned MySQL or SQL,
where MySQL is the database technology
and SQL is the query language for querying those databases.
If I was going to recommend you one thing that you
should really, really look into as a product manager,
it's going to be to learn how to query SQL databases
using SQL pretty proficiently.
Most companies are going to have SQL databases,
or MySQL databases, and it's going to be huge on your
resume to be able to make a query and get some data by yourself,
without having to bother engineers or data science people.
So I highly recommend looking into that.
Check out codecademy.com, because they have
a SQL course that is really good and will get you
to understand the fundamentals, this can be super helpful.
The third thing I want to say is that if you're really
serious about getting into data and looking at
and analyzing data, which you should be if you're a
product manager, then I recommend you check out some
data parsing and analysis languages.
Some examples would be things like Python, and Python
is both a language that has been adapted to actually
run programs on different clients like the web, or
on your computer, but it's also what is called a
scripting language, which means that you can basically
take a set of data and use Python to script or
basically write out what you want to do with that data,
and parse it out, or pull pieces of it out and
analyze it, and then send it to something like Excel or
some other type of visualization software for data.
This is going to be super helpful.
It's definitely an advanced thing as a product manager,
but if you really want to get into it, I recommend checking out some scripting languages, and I would probably start with Python.
Alright, so the forth thing I'm going to mention here
is that if you want to go even further, and you want
to get more technical, then you should look at the different
types of databases out there or how databases work.
So there are some things besides MySQL, and there's
different really categories of databases that
are things like relational databases versus non-relational
databases, and all that means is basically,
it's just the way that the databases store information,
and some of these databases are newer than others,
some of them are older but more proven,
some of them are faster, but, you know,
have some things you're not so good at.
So if you want some extra learning, go check out, you know, the differences between relational and non-relational databases,
things like MongoDB, for instance, versus MySQL,
and just get a good amount of information and
knowledge around that. It's going to help you out a ton
when you're talking to engineers and data scientists.
All right, so that's it for that part.
I just wanted to let you know what you could look into
if you're really interested in, and really, really
getting to be a really great technical product
manager, it's going to help you a lot
when you're talking to technical people in your company.
Got it? Good. I will see you in the next lecture.