What's up, everyone?
So I want to talk really quick about how we estimate
the time it's going to take to do a particular
software or project, or how to figure out how long it's
going to take to have us build something so that we can
say, "Okay, at this point in time, we're going to have this."
This is very much related to roadmapping,
so I want to bring it up before we talk about roadmapping.
First, let's talk about a real world situation, and this is going to
help you understand software estimation a little bit more.
Okay, imagine that you were taking your car to a mechanic,
and you say to the mechanic "I would like you
to replace my engine. I just want you
to take it out, put another one in."
Well, if your car is, let's say, a particular brand, and let's say
it's a BMW, because you're awesome, and BMW is
the best car out there - I think - and the mechanic, he's a BMW mechanic, so odds are that it's a BMW car, BMW mechanic,
he's probably done this a hundred or
a thousand times in his career,
he's going to be able to say "All right,
well, that will take me six hours, or maybe one day,
and I'll have it ready by tomorrow."
This is, you know, this is something that's probably very true,
it's very easy for someone who's done something
a thousand times to predict how long it's going to take.
Now, imagine that everyone on the entire planet has
a different car, and that all the mechanics are not
specialists in any one particular car brand, because
everyone's building the cars themselves out of stuff
they found at home, it's like everyone has a custom car.
Now, if you bring your car into a mechanic, do you think
they're going to be able to give you an accurate
estimate on how long it's going to take?
All right. Well, the answer there is no, because, okay,
they've never seen your car before, let alone worked
on it, and it's going to take them a while to get
in there and see how you built your car. Is your engine
like a steam engine, or a gas engine, or an electric
engine, or like, what is it?
And if they try to give you an estimation like "Okay, this
is going to take six hours," they're probably going to be wrong.
The best they could do is give a really conservative
estimate and just say like, "This is maybe going to
be like a week, and then I'll look into it, and if it looks
like it's going to be easier, then maybe it's
going to be a little bit before then. I'll call you and let you know."
So why is this analogy appropriate for software development?
It's appropriate because this is the way software actually works.
You have the engineers, who are pretty much
the mechanics in this situation,
and then you have the things they work on, the systems
and databases, and code bases that they work on,
which are almost always completely unique.
From company to company,
the engineers are building things in different ways,
in different languages and styles, depending on the
needs of the company. And to make it even worse,
that stuff, those code bases, is changing all the time.
So one day I could be an engineer working on a code
base, and then I come in next week and try to work
on the same code, and four engineers have edited it
in between that time, working on some other feature.
So things change and I have to get used to it.
This, in a nutshell, is why software estimation is very hard.
A lot of people say "Oh, engineers are terrible
at estimating software, like deadlines."
This is, it couldn't be further from the truth.
They're actually quite good given the complexity
of software, but the fact is here that you really
can't really say that "Okay, we know for sure that from
one estimation, from one engineer, that this thing
is going to be done on this date."
So how do we get around that?
The way we accurately or at least semi-accurately estimate
software is by figuring out what is called velocity.
So this goes directly into what we were talking about with sprints.
Now, I'm not showing you this inside a project management software, because the way that velocities and
all of this stuff works in different project management
software, it differs from software to software,
so instead, I'm going explain the concept to you,
so that you more clearly understand the theory behind this.
So, let's say we have a sprint and we are doing
five things in this sprint,
we're doing five user stories that are a part of an epic.
What happens is, before we start a sprint, we do something
called a sprint planning meeting or a scoping
meeting, and we ask the engineers "How long is
this going to take for this thing and this thing?"
We ask a few of them, not just one, we ask a couple of engineers on the team, and they come to some conclusion,
they say "It's going to take this amount of time."
The trouble is, if we ask them how long
it's going to take, it's still a little bit inaccurate.
So the trick is we say "How hard is it to do this?"
And the way we measure or way we quantify how hard something is is through numbers, and these are called story points.
So each story has some number assigned to it by an
engineer or a couple engineers, and they represent
the story points, they represent the difficulty.
Now, some teams and some companies use
different scales for story points.
You could have a scale like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, where
5 is the hardest and 1 is the easiest,
or you could have like a Fibonacci sequence,
where it's like, 1, 2, and 3, all the way up to like 21,
you can even have like 1 through 100.
It doesn't matter which scale you use.
What matters is that you're consistent with the scales,
you're always using the same scale and all the
engineers understand that, okay, a 5 means
super, super hard, and a 1 means very easy.
So what you do here is you estimate, you give
all of these things in your sprint an amount of
story points, basically, and then your sprint has what
is called, like, the total story points for that sprint.
Okay.
So at the end of the sprint, we see how many
things we actually did get done.
How many story points were the developers
able to actually complete?
So if we had five items and we only got three done,
but those things had a combined story point value of, let's say, 15, because there's only 3 things we did, but they were very hard,
so it's five points each,
we're using the 1 to 5 scale, then what we have at the end
of the sprint is what's called a velocity, and that velocity
now is 15, it's the number of story points we were
able to accomplish in a one period of sprint, like a one
two-week sprint period of time.
All right, so now you're wondering like,
"Okay, well, how does that help me?"
"Does that mean that I can do 15 points in the next sprint?"
Well, kind of, but I'll tell you how we do it even more accurately.
What we do is this process over many, many sprints.
So, back to the analogy of the mechanic, that first mechanic,
he was able to make an accurate estimation because
he had worked on, like, a hundred or a thousand
of these exact types of projects before.
Well, if we take our sprint velocity from one sprint
and then we go through let's say five more sprints
in the future, we take those velocities, we take all
these velocities and we average them out.
Then you have like a, basically a roundabout way of
seeing on average how much work can you get done
over a particular period of time.
So you have an average sprint velocity of,
let's say, like 12 or 16,
and then when you can do is say "All right, in the future,
we want to do this thing, and we talked to the
engineers, and they think it's this many story points
in order to do these things."
Well, we can extrapolate out and say that according
to our past average velocity, this is going to take
us one month or two months, and in the end this
ends up being pretty accurate, not 100% accurate,
but it's the most accurate you can get
for software development.
One more thing to mention here is about that
scoping and that estimation from the engineers.
Usually, this happens earlier before you start a project,
and we like to do it before we start a sprint, in either a sprint planning session, or even in the middle of the previous sprint,
we'll talk about what's coming up in the sprint after that,
and we will have the engineers and the engineering manager
talk about "Okay, how many story points are each
one of these tickets and user stories?"
All right, so that's it. That is really engineering
software estimation, in a nutshell.
And now you've learned about velocity,
and this, again, is why Scrum is pretty useful,
because on Kanban, it's a little bit more difficult to
predict this sort of stuff, because you don't time box
your work, like we've mentioned before.
That's why Scrum basically has these time boxes,
so that we can say "Okay, over a period of time, we're
able to get this amount of work done,"
and it contributes to accuracy in the long term.
All right, we'll see you guys in the next lecture.