Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, we're moving on to step two of the customer
development process: finding your potential interviewees.
Now, you can obviously gather feedback about your product
or your proposed product without actually talking
to a potential or an existing customer.
In this lecture, we're going to talk about pre-product scenarios, when we're looking for new customers
or people that are not already aware of us to interview.
Now, there are a lot of different places online or offline
that you can go to connect with people that
might be interested in your product.
But, for our sake, I've reduced it down to four different
places or types of places to look that consistently
can find you people that are interested. Now, in the
resources of this lecture, I've actually attached a great
article called "96 different ways to find people to interview"
and they go through literally every single
little thing you can think of. If you want to read that, check it out.
It's a little overkill for us. Now, at this stage of the game,
you know which target customer group you would
like to talk to, because we played "Three questions stud"
and you identified one of the three as probably
more worthwhile to go after and one that you'll
have more success reaching out to. Now, the first
place and I think probably the best place to start reaching out to potential customers that you can talk to is LinkedIn.
I'm sure most of you guys are familiar with LinkedIn.
It's an online social network that is primarily for networking.
It holds a lot of information about the people that
sign up and a lot of that information is public.
We generally get to see where people go to school, what their job is, what they've done in the past, where they live.
We also know generally interests they're in
and groups they participate in.
We also have endorsements that show us what skills they have.
So that is a treasure chest of different ways that you can narrow down on exactly the target customer you have in mind.
Now, for those of you out there that have a LinkedIn
account and you have lots of connections, this
works extremely well, for those of you that have an account,
but don't have a lot of connections, it still
works very well, and for those of you that don't have an account,
I suggest creating one and connecting
with some of the people you know.
It really will only take you 10-15 minutes,
and by this time tomorrow you can actually use it to find people.
Now, the best way to use LinkedIn is actually
just to use their search feature. Now, what the
search feature is going to do is it's going to search based off of
your connections and then your connections' connections.
That's why I say, if you only have a medium amount of connections, only 50 people, 20 people, it still works
because as long as you're connected to people that
have a lot of them, then the search has quite a large
group of people to look through.
So, if you define your customer group by,
let's say, their job type, this is perfect.
If you define it based off of their education, where they went to school, what location they live in, this also works very well.
So, let's use the example of the real estate agents,
if we were building a product that went after real
estate agents or appealed to them.
All that you have to do is, in the search bar, just
type in "real estate agent" and right at the top it says
I can pick between people, jobs, and groups.
Those are all very helpful, but I'm probably just going to pick people, because these are actually going to show me
people that have it in their title, meaning
right now they are a real estate agent.
And even down here it's already started to give me second degree connections, other people that are connected
to people that you are connected to that fit my criteria.
But I can click "people" and it'll give me an extensive list of people.
All right, so right off the bat, I have tons and tons of people -
10 different pages of people that I could reach out to.
If I then wanted to add some criteria about
where they live, I can use filtering criteria over here.
So maybe I only want to interview people that are near
where I live in San Francisco, within 50 miles.
All right, now I have a very good list of people
that I could start to connect with.
I could add in more criteria if I wanted to,
but, for our sake, let's not.
Now, if I wanted to contact these people, the way that
you would use LinkedIn is through one of two means.
One is you can send them what's called an InMail.
An InMail is a message that goes directly to their
message system - now, this is a paid option.
I don't think you pay a lot of money for it.
You probably have to do a subscription package
and it gives you a certain amount of InMails.
If this is something you frequently use,
then it's definitely worth doing.
So the second option is to just connect with them, because when you connect with them it'll give you the option of writing a message.
So click through to their profile and then you can hit "connect"
and in the message down here I can write
something along the lines of "This is what I'm doing and
I would like to talk to you" - we cover that in the next lecture.
How do we get them to actually talk to us? If they don't see this, they still will probably connect with you,
at which point you can then send them a direct message,
and that doesn't cost any money.
Alright, so the number two place that we're going to cover
are forums. Now what do I mean by forums?
Well, forums are generally just online communities
that are all built around some kind of theme.
Pretty much any type of affiliation, or job, or interest you can think of has a forum or an online community dedicated to it.
And the reason forums work so well is because there's a bunch of people talking about whatever subject or topic you picked,
and it's very easy to search them or find people that
have a problem that you are trying to solve,
have experience in the area you are trying to go into.
It's pretty much easy pickings, because people will talk about what they're interested in and they'll self-identify themselves.
The first place I like to start is a website called Reddit.
If you ever heard of Reddit, it's an
online forum and it's absolutely massive.
It's an online community, and the way that it works is
it's actually tons and tons of forums inside of
one forum. Reddit calls these subforums "subreddits"
and every subreddit in this website is going to
be based off of some type of theme, or topic, or subject.
So if you can identify some of the things that your target
customer group have in common, are interested
in, or anything that they would affiliate with,
you can find a subreddit for that.
The best way of doing that is to search through their search box and it will give you lists of subreddits
or what you can do is actually search through Google.
And if you use the code site:reddit.com
and then followed by searching for the topic you want,
you can do it that way as well - sometimes Google
is actually better than Reddit.
So, let's see how this works for the real estate idea.
All I'd have to do is say "real estate agents"
right there and see if it shows me.
And then, right off the bat, we have three subreddits right here,
and it gives you some gauge of how many
people are in it: 41 people, 20 people, 8 people. I can click next
and I can look at other ones, these get more and more specific.
But, for the most part, I can dive into any one of these,
start looking around, start interacting,
and then start reaching out to people.
Another great option is a web site called Quora.
Now, Quora, spelled Q-U-O-R-A.com, is essentially Yahoo Answers, but for adults. It's a web site where people will ask
questions and then people who have expertise in that
subject will answer them and it's a website where
people kind of trip over each other to give the best answer.
But because so many people have asked so many different questions, what you can do is look for specific
topics or groups of questions, and then look at the people
that are constantly talking in them, answering
questions, interacting, and replying.
So I could search for "real estate agents" and then right there
I can pick the actual topic, so it's going to
show me all the questions related to real estate agents.
So all I'd have to do is just jump into any
one of these and see if the people that are asking
the question or answering the question are people
that fit my target demographic - if they are, I can then
message them and try to make a connection.
Alright, the third place that I suggest using to find
potential customers to interview is Twitter.
Twitter is fantastic as a resource for finding people
that might be interested in your service.
The reason why it's so effective at this is similar
to the reason why forums are, in that people are
constantly talking on it, and people are constantly self-identifying themselves with things they're interested
in, things they affiliate themselves with,
and what they do for a living.
Twitter is also just a gigantic complaining fest, which is great because you can find people that potentially
have the problem you're trying to solve and reach out to them.
Now, the way that you'd use Twitter is you can just go to search.twitter.com, and it will allow you to just search through it.
What you're actually searching through when you use this feature is what people are saying and not specific details about the person.
So if I said "real estate agent" it might not actually be as effective. Why?
Because real estate agents on Twitter probably aren't saying
"real estate agent" over, and over, and over
again, it might still work but it's more effective to think
about things they might be saying and then
search for that. So a real estate agent might be saying
something along the lines of "Looking to buy a home."
And then we can scroll down and it looks like, right off the bat,
here's someone that says "Looking for a home?"
"Are you looking for a home?"
Lots of people here are self-identifying.
And the first one we captured right here is a man named Alan Todd.
He works as a real estate agent.
See how that worked?
Now that we know who they are, we can tweet at them or we can try to follow them in the hopes that they follow us back,
at which point we can send them a direct message.
All right, and the last go-to place for finding potential customers is...
It's actually your competitors, okay?
90% of the time, when you're launching a new product,
there are probably going to be competitors already there,
and if they're not doing the exact same thing,
they're probably doing at least part of what you propose to do,
or they're just servicing the same target customer group.
If you can identify your potential competitors right out of the gate, well, then it's relatively easy
to just go to their social media pages, see who is engaging,
and you can then figure out that those people
probably are customers or are interested customers
for your competitor, and you can contact them.
Let's say we were doing that real estate business, never
said what it was, but let's say one of our competitors
was Opendoor - it's a relatively well-known startup. We can find their page on Twitter and then just look for who is interacting with it.
We can see who is liking their page.
There's someone who likes it,  there's someone who likes it,
and these are people that interact with their page.
We can then go through these people's pages
and contact them in the same way.
Now, this works the same for Facebook,
this works the same for Twitter.
If your competitor has a blog, you can also go on there
and find people who are commenting on their blog,
that is also a goldmine for finding potential people to talk to.
All right. So, as of today, those are the four main categories that product managers are probably going to use to reach
out to potential customers that they can interview.
If you need more or are interested, check out the resources,
otherwise we're going to move on to step three, which is
how exactly do you get these people to talk to you?
All right, see you then.