Alright, so in the last lecture we discussed the first four phases of the product development process.
That company conceives the new product, they plan it out,
they develop it, and then they iterate on it before you even launch it, and you do this using the early
test feedback, or the Alphas and the Betas, and there's a few other types of things we can do to get that feedback.
But after that's done, we want to do three more things. We want to launch, then we want to hold it in a steady state,
and then after that we decide if we want to maintain it
or we kill the product.
So let's talk about launch.
* We have a lift up! * We want to work with the marketing team, and the legal team, the PR team, the sales team,
and we want to position this product for public launch.
Then we actually send it out there to the public,
we see what kind of reaction we get. Then the sixth major phase is called steady state or just basically
hold it in either a steady state or continue iterating on it.
During this time we're collecting metrics on how people are using it,
how often are people buying it,
we analyze the product, we optimize our metrics,
we try to get the maximum return for investment on it.
During this time we also have marketing continuing to market it and salespeople continuing to sell it.
We assess our continued efforts here to basically see how likely are we to continue moving forward with this.
Then we move on to the seventh and final phase of the product development process, maintain or kill.
At this point we decide, using all the data we've already gathered and especially from the last phase,
how frequently are people purchasing this,
are we staying on top of the market,
are we competitive with this product anymore?
And we look at, more importantly, how much money are we spending to maintain it,
to see, is it even paying for itself?
How is our return on investment?
If it's not doing so well then maybe we decide to kill it and we decide to move on to something new.
.
And one thing that's important to mention here is that it may not have anything to do with the revenue
of that product or maybe even the usage.
It could just not fit our company vision anymore.
Our executives and the people that are leading the company might decide just based on market circumstance
that the company is now going in a different direction.
So we need to go ahead and cut our losses on that product or go ahead and put it to bed.
.
If we decide to kill a product then we do what's called sunsetting.
You've probably heard this before.
This is a slow transition to the end of life of the product. We message our user base, we tell them what's
going on, and we have an end of life plan for the users and the people that may rely on it.
So if we have a company or a product that is storing data for people, for instance, then we may allow
them to backup their data before we shut down the product.
Everyone has probably seen a product that they love to use, you know, be killed and it's always very sad
but unfortunately sometimes there's not much you can do about it.
But I have had a lot of good experiences with products that are dying and being killed out,
but they'll still light, or bring out your data, or something like that.
This is really good practice. Alright.
So those are the seven main phases: conceive, plan, develop, iterate, launch, steady state, and then finally we maintain it or kill it.
One thing to mention here is that this might sound a little bit academic to you but it is because
it is actually pretty academic.
You know, this is a process that every product goes through, but you're not going to be actually using
these terms, you know, in the office every day. It's just very important as a product manager to understand
that every type of product or company
goes through these types of phases,
and there's things to consider about each.
So without any further ado, let's go into the next section.
I will see you there.