Hey everyone, what's up?
Now we're going to talk about roadmapping.
Okay, I'm sorry in advance, but I'm not going to actually
show you a real life roadmap right now, and there's
a good reason behind it. This is because every company you go to, every single company out there does roadmapping differently.
Furthermore, roadmaps are always, if not
mostly always, just inaccurate.
So we know about how Agile works.
So from what we know there, can we
think about why roadmaps are inaccurate?
Because if you're doing things in Agile fashion,
do you think you're going to be able to predict, you
know, three to four months out what we're
going to be doing at that point?
The whole purpose of Agile is to say that we're going
to try some stuff right around this period of time,
this is what's coming next for sure, because it's a big user problem,
we're going to try to solve it, but we may solve it now with this initiative, or maybe we don't and we get rid of that,
we do something else to solve that,
so these things can shift around.
So if you ever see roadmaps that say "In quarter one
we're doing this, in quarter two we're doing this,
in quarter three, this is what we're doing,"
It's okay to have those things as a general guide, in
terms of what might be coming, in what parts of the
year, the first half, the second half of the year, as a general guide,
but it's not going to be accurate down to the date that you say it is,
and if it is, then you are not being Agile.
So why do you ever see roadmaps that are like "In Q1
we're doing this, in Q2 we're doing this, in Q3 we're
doing this"? It's because, well, for a couple of reasons.
One, executives, and other departments, and investors,
they like to see these sorts of things,
but the good ones will realize that stuff that's like,
three quarters out there is not going to be accurate
if you're being Agile, right? It could be that it takes us
a whole quarter to figure out one problem through
a bunch of different user tests and solutions,
and it moves stuff back.
Or it could be that something becomes a non-problem,
maybe we were going to build something to compete
with another company and that company
goes away, or they go bankrupt.
Oh okay, now we don't have to do that anymore.
The second reason you sometimes see these roadmaps
that are, you know, Q1, Q2, Q3, that sort of thing, is
because sometimes, and especially in business to business
companies, you actually are going to be against
an actual real world deadline.
So large companies will do this a lot because they
have investors that say that they have to have a
certain thing, certain functionality to compete with
somebody, done by a certain date, or maybe you're at
a software as a service company, and your salespeople
sell a new feature that you haven't built yet to
a customer, and the customer is like,
"We need this by, you know, February."
So, at that point, you can put something like that on
a time based roadmap, and you've got to stick to
it, you've got to figure out how you can do it before that time.
But I just want to let you know that these types of roadmaps are generally inaccurate, but it's okay to still look at them,
just keep in mind that they're inaccurate.
So what's the alternative, like what do we do instead?
Well, what a lot of product managers do and a lot
of development teams do out there is they
just basically sort things into kind of priorities,
it's like "Here's what we're doing now,"
they'll have, like, a column and then, "Okay,
this is now, that's what we're doing immediately, in the next
few weeks and next month," and then they have another column
that's like mid-term,
"So here's the stuff we're going to do after that,"
and then they'll have another bucket that's called long term,
and "This is stuff that we want to get to eventually,
but it's not a huge priority right now."
So those three columns, the near term, mid-term, long term,
are usually pretty helpful because it intentionally
doesn't say any particular dates on there and it keeps everyone
in line by not expecting things by a certain date.
This three bucket model is something you're going to find
a lot at consumer tech companies, especially ones
that have the luxury of building products that, where they don't really have any deadlines, like Google and Facebook.
They - and even, like, Twitter - they're not really
having any financial trouble, so they can really take
as long or as little time as they want to do something,
they don't really have to put it into a certain
quarter, or a certain date, or a certain month.
So you'll see a lot of these things at the
really big money high tech companies.
So that's what I wanted to mention about roadmapping.
Don't worry, I really put plenty of resource guides and
articles to read about roadmapping, because you do
need to understand the ins and outs around it,
but those are the two major things about roadmapping.
One, the quarterly or monthly roadmaps are okay to
make and show as long as you are on the same page
as everyone else and you're telling people, like,
"Look, this stuff may change."
And then two, the more appropriate way or the more
product management, or lean way, or Agile way is to do
sort of a near term, mid-term, and long term bucket.
All right everyone, I'll catch you in the next lecture.