Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right. So, this far in the section, we figured out how to find competitors, how to compare them to ourselves,
how to compare potential features and potential products
we're thinking of to our competition, but now we need
to talk a little more broadly about, as a product
manager and as an entrepreneur, what in general do you have to keep tabs on with your competitors.
So I'm going introduce five separate criteria that are crucial for you as a product manager or entrepreneur
to understand about your competitors.
Now, a large part of what makes you successful as a product manager is your ability to keep tabs on your
competitors and make sure that you are ahead of the curve and know what exactly they're going to do.
One way of thinking about it is that it's kind of like a horse race,
and especially if you're working
on a team that has an established product, you're going to be constantly jockeying with your competitors
for users, features, press, funding, amongst a number of different things. And in order to be successful in this
jockeying game, you can't just keep tabs on them,
you have to have a deeper sense of what they can do.
So let's talk about five different dimensions that are absolutely crucial to understand about your competitors.
The first one I want to talk about is called the product core.
Now, it's a little confusing but what I mean by product core is the product team. I'm talking about whoever
on your competitor's side is in charge of making their product.
If it's a physical product, it's going
to be the physical engineers that are building it,
and if it's a, let's say, web application,
it's going to be the developers.
And the question we want to answer here is "How good is our competitor's product team?"
Mark Zuckerberg, the founder of Facebook, made a very notorious public statement when he said that any
day he would take one great engineer over 100 average engineers.
Now, that's obviously kind of counterintuitive, right?
You would assume more people can do more.
So what exactly does he mean here?
Well, what he means is that, especially in web development or development of applications, having a great
engineer actually can do a lot more for you than
a lot of people that can get low level work done. Top
notch engineers in general can outperform
larger groups of good engineers.
Instagram is a great example.
Instagram, when it was bought by Facebook for a billion dollars, you would think it was a huge company.
No, actually they only had 13 employees. I believe
only eight of them were product engineers.
So know how good their product core is.
Make strides and make attempts to figure out that question.
Now, why does this matter to you?
Well, if your competitor has, let's say, a better product team,
that means in general they can out-execute you,
they can out-engineer you, and they can outproduce you.
So if you're in a situation where you have a team
that's not as good as your competitors, you need to
take that into consideration and probably not wade into features or wade into product categories where
one of the key differentiators or the key components of it
is the engineering quality.
Of course, on the flip side, if you have a better product core,
it's the exact opposite.
You can wade into areas that rely heavily
on the quality of engineering,
and if you do that, that's something that your competitors
will have a hard time catching up to and imitating.
The second criteria we need to use when considering our competitors is to know the size of their user base.
Now, why does it matter how big your competitor's user base is, or how big their customer base is in the
case of more traditional businesses?
It's kind of counterintuitive, right?
And immediately it's hard to figure out what that would matter, right? Because if you have a large user base,
that doesn't necessarily mean you can build better products faster.
Well, actually this is a pretty important one.
Companies or competitors that have large user bases have certain advantages that companies with small user bases don't have.
Oftentimes, when a company has a large user base, anytime they launch a new feature or launch into a new
market, they have the potential to essentially dominate the market just by virtue of how many people they bring into it.
They also have an easier time getting press. In general, press and press coverage is going to be more
inclined to cover companies that are larger and more well-known.
Another advantage is that a large user base will allow you to strike deals with other companies more easily.
Much easier to negotiate when you say "I'm bringing X amount of users to the table. I'm the largest company in town."
And then the last thing is that size often is an advantage intrinsically. Think about, like, social products, right?
A social network is only as valuable
as however many people are in it.
So the larger one is inherently going to have a better product.
Now, here's the classic example, and it's Apple Music.
I don't know if you've heard this, but Apple's launching into the music space, specifically the subscription
music space, and they're going to compete
with Spotify and SoundCloud - sorry, Cole.
Now, can Apple make a better music player? We don't really know.
And are they at a disadvantage
because they're coming late to the market?
Actually, none of that matters,
because their user size is so large.
Consider this. Spotify and SoundCloud have something
around 30 million combined paying users.
Now think about Apple. How many users do they have?
It's actually 1 billion.
So even if Apple comes into that space, converts 1% of their market into their Apple music product,
they are a serious competitor.
So be aware, because in this case, size does matter.
All right, guys. Take a sec to think about those and I'll catch you in the next lecture, where we cover the next three.
See you then.