Welcome back, everyone.
So do you remember where I said that sometimes the people that pay for your product are not actually
the users of your product?
We're going to talk a little bit more about that right now.
So there's a difference between users and customers.
And if you work as a B2B or business to business product manager this might actually be pretty common.
So one of my first product management jobs was at a company that sold social media monitoring software
to companies that were interested
in identifying trends on social media.
So the company was called Mass Relevance and this product we sold, the ability to log into a platform
and check out all these social media trends, was something that cost like $200,000 to $500,000.
So it was not cheap.
So the people that bought this were major companies and the people that signed the checks for this were
directors of marketing or social media.
And when they bought it, they were not the ones using it, but they would give the logins to their underlings,
like the social media managers or the marketing managers.
And you can see how these are two totally different people.
So when we were getting feedback,
we would get feedback from two different groups.
We'd get macro level feedback on
what our product should be able to do in general,
this was from the higher ups, like the directors of marketing
and that sort of thing.
And then we had really granular feedback
from the users themselves.
These are the people that were logged in every day and they'd have feedback like "Oh, where's the button for this?"
"I would like to do this inside the platform."
Two separate user groups and two separate sets of feedback.
All right.
To sum it up, the users and the clients are sometimes two completely different groups with different sets of feedback,
but it's important to keep in mind.
Got it? Alright, moving on.