Hey guys, welcome back to the course. So let's round out
the rest of the five criteria that we need to
focus on as product managers.
Now, the third criteria is design.
Now, be aware of your competitor's ability or inability to make products that are aesthetically pleasing
or beautiful. It sounds shallow, but in general people are more inclined to use products that are well thought
out and well designed.
How many things do you use simply because it's easy to use and maybe it's pretty? And I'm sure you guys
in your head have figured out the next example.
Again, it's going to be Apple.
Apple's a great example, because they are so focused on design and usability that they are a threat to
virtually any market they enter.
Now, they are especially threatening to markets that use design and usability as a key differentiator.
Is Apple going to enter in the toaster market? Probably not.
But you just saw what they did to the watch market.
Another real life example is a company called Path.
Path was making a social network to compete with
Facebook and at a certain point I believe
they had something like 30 million users.
They stuck around for quite a long time solely based on
their ability to make a more beautiful product,
and their product was very nice.
If I were in a similar space, I would be weary about treading into a space controlled by a firm that has top notch design.
The number four is brand, and brand is kind of a funny thing.
We often think of it as something that's really abstract,
but when it comes to managing products and
your competitive advantage, it actually can be huge.
The perceptions that people have of you and the products you sell can determine what you can do in the future.
A brand can be a blessing and a curse.
It can allow you to be more effective in certain areas
and restricted in others.
In general, strong brands demand a much higher level of customer loyalty when they launch into a new market or a new initiative.
They're more likely to bring a large group of people to that.
They also have the advantage of
being able to charge higher prices.
A comparison of GoPro, we've probably thought, "GoPro, why are you charging $500 when other people are charging
$300 for the same thing?"
Well, because GoPro can do it. They have
the strongest brand in the space.
If you look at the market share, they are doing very well.
So be aware of the relative positioning between your brand
and the brand of your competitor, especially
as it specifically pertains to new products or new features.
If your competitor has the stronger brand, it can be
hard for you to catch up with any new initiative
or product that they built.
They're inevitably going to get more press, more funding,
and since they're a stronger brand, they're
going to get a better benefit of the doubt.
People in general are more flexible when they're trying on
a brand they already have an affinity for.
Now, on the flip side, what about in the case where your competitor has a weaker brand, maybe it's diminished,
or maybe it's actually conflicting?
It's really hard for a brand that's pigeonholed in one area to branch out into areas that people would perceive as unrelated.
Sony can make a TV, a camera, a toaster,
and a car if they wanted to.
Now, Lexus cannot make a toaster, they cannot make a TV, they can't make a camera, they can really just make cars.
So be aware, how highly regarded is the brand of your competitor
and what's the gap between the perception of your brand
and the perception of theirs?
Does that relative difference allow them certain advantages or certain avenues that you wouldn't be
able to take advantage of? And again,
be aware of any weaknesses to exploit.
Are there certain things your brand can do that theirs couldn't?
And the last thing we're going to discuss is speed. When your competitor sits down and starts working on a new
product or feature, how quickly can they build it,
turn it around, and "ship it," so to speak?
Try to get a sense of this because it's very relevant
in a lot of different situations.
Now, when is it most relevant? Well, this is most relevant in situations where your company or your competitor's
company is significantly larger.
In general, it's a natural consequence that as a company gets larger, and larger, and larger, they will
have more communication structures, more hierarchies, and more bureaucracies that will typically slow them down
in regards to what they're trying to execute on.
So be aware.
Are you getting so big and so slow that a small team that's more focused and more agile can beat you
to any new market feature or user base you're going after?
If that's the case, then you probably need to shy away from situations where the product success is directly
tied to the product launch date.
One of the reasons why MySpace is not the number one social network anymore is because Facebook started off
as a smaller group.
They were able to build features faster and they basically
just ran circles around MySpace while they
tried to catch up, and it took them forever, and it didn't work.
All right, so those are the five: product core, user base, size, speed, design, and brand. Get a decent understanding
of your competitors in each of these five different criteria.
That's what's going to allow you to make the right call.
In the next lecture, we are going to talk
about where do we go to get this information and what techniques can we use to constantly monitor it in case it changes.
All right, see you in the next lecture.