Welcome back.
So, by now, you should feel pretty confident about metrics,
about what they are, why they're important, and
a few ways you can go about choosing your own
metrics, and likely, if you're joining an established
company, on a team or something like this, you will
probably already have metrics to track, and they'll probably
already be actively tracked in the back-end.
So, in the case that you're working for one of these
companies and the metrics are already there, you'll
probably be working with an insights team, or analytics team,
or even a data science team to get the metrics
that you're looking for to report.
But let's imagine for a moment that you actually have
no metrics, and you've decided what you want to
track using the earlier lectures, but you have no idea.
Well, in this lecture, I wanted to talk about a couple of my favorite tools to track metrics, and they're really easy to use.
So the first one is probably one of the most popular
analytics tools out there, it's Google Analytics, and
this is a really easy thing to install and will give you
all sorts of tracking information on your website,
and they even have a component that delivers on mobile tracking.
So five stars for Google Analytics.
It is awesome.
I highly recommend it.
Secondly, there's a really cool tool for web sites
called CrazyEgg, and this gives you all sorts of click
data, where people are clicking and that sort of thing,
but it also gives you these really cool, like, heat
map things, where you can see with colors, like a heat map
of where people have been clicking and moving
their mouse and scrolling.
It is pretty cool and gives you a ton of insight.
The next one is Kissmetrics, and it is an awesome
solution for both web and mobile, and it provides a
ton of data, and you can set up custom metrics, and do calculations on the fly, and look at all sorts of crazy graphs.
It's really good, but it's not cheap.
So the fourth one is similar to Kissmetrics,
and, in fact, it's a big competitor.
I think it's probably about 50/50 split between the
people who like Kissmetrics versus Mixpanel, but
it's also not cheap, but it's extremely good to use for
both web and mobile, and has some really cool
features, like a calculator, and you can look up
individual user behavior.
You can even hook it up to stuff like e-mail and push notifications
so you can send users messages to try to retain them.
So the fifth one I'll recommend is Optimizely, and
Optimizely is actually more of an A/B testing tool,
but it also provides some really good click tracking
and that sort of thing that you can set up to
see how many people click where and where they're going.
It is really good and it is super easy to use compared
to a lot of other A/B testing tools out there.
I highly recommend it, and you can actually
just go demo it for free on their website.
So the last one I want to mention is one of my favorites, and that's because it's not a tool itself for metrics, but it's a metrics hub.
So if you imagine, you have all these metrics tools
out there, and they all integrate with either your
mobile app or your web site through an API, which we'll
talk about later, but you usually have to put a piece
of code on your site or in your app in order to track stuff,
and the problem is, if you switch metrics tools, then you will usually have to switch out that code, and then, to make it even worse,
let's say you have one metrics tool, and you have
a year of using that, and you have all this data in
there, and then you switch to another one to try it out.
Well, now you've lost all the historical data
because you're switching to a new tool.
Well, Segment solves this problem, because it's like a hub.
So you connect other services to it and then you
connect your app or your web site to Segment,
and this way, you can basically plug and unplug any
other solution, and it will just automatically send
the data to the tool that you would like.
So it's really good if you consider setting up with Segment first,
and then trying out a whole bunch of other tools.
It even keeps a backup of your data.
All right, so that's it for the metrics section.
And I hope you paid close attention, because this stuff
is super important as a product manager or an entrepreneur.
Everyone needs to know this stuff.
So the next sections, we're going to get even deeper into the world of product management. It's time to get our hands dirty.
I'll see you there.