All right, so welcome to the next section of the course.
In this section, we're going to start applying TypeScript to our actual view components.
So let's start with a really simple component.
We're going to begin with profile, image, dot view.
This is a good one to practice with.
Profile image view is a pretty simple component.
You can see here.
It still utilizes our old options API and this is the component that renders that little circular profile
image on the top right of our main now.
All right.
So the good news is we're able to use TypeScript with either the options API components or the composition
API components.
And the other bit of good news is we do not need to change the file name.
We only need to add a couple of lines of syntax.
Let me first show you here that TypeScript will not be enabled by default, and I'm going to prove this
to you by defining a method that's going to attempt to change the image linked property to a different
data type.
You do not have to follow along here because this is just for the sake of example.
So what I'm going to do right here.
Is type out my methods property.
This is my old options API.
And so here I can define a method.
I'm going to call it change image link.
And in the body of this method, I'm going to access my image link data property on this keyword.
So this, that image link and I'm going to assign it to an arbitrary number like five.
And notice that there are no violations in the file.
And this, of course, would not be promised permissible in TypeScript because TypeScript would say,
hey, you gave image link an initial string value.
Therefore, image like must stay a string and it would complain about it changing to a different data
type such as a number.
The fact that there are no errors in this file means we haven't configured TypeScript quite yet.
So how do we properly configure TypeScript?
We need to do two things.
The first is on the script tag right here on line number five.
We need to add an additional attribute and that attribute will be Lang Lang is short for language and
it allows us to specify the language that the TypeScript compiler and the View compiler as well will
interpret the section as having.
So by default, it thinks it's going to be JavaScript.
Now we're going to tell it that it's going to be TypeScript instead.
So it's always going to be lang.
And then we provide an equal sign.
And in double quotes we're always going to type T.S. That is short for TypeScript.
Notice that as soon as I write that, we now have the expected error.
And if I hover my mouse over this, you can see TypeScript will tell us, Hey, type number is not assignable
to type string.
So it has correctly inferred that image length should be a string from its original assignment.
And that's complaining that this is not a valid type.
So immediately you can see the benefits of TypeScript start to come out in components as well because
we avoid costly mistakes like this.
All right.
So that was strictly for the sake of example.
So we can go ahead and remove our methods object right here.
And there's one more thing we need to add to properly integrate TypeScript into a component.
What we need to do is to import a special function from the view library called define component.
So I'm going to do that right here.
Import define component.
And that is coming from view.
And what we need to do is we need to wrap our configuration object right here in the defined component
function call.
So the most common way you're going to see this is export default, followed by the invocation of defined
component passing in the object.
Right.
So as far as why we do this, I think the reason why we do this is to provide better typing or better
type safety for TypeScript.
Let me give you a very simple example.
If you think about the options API, which has things like name data, methods, etc., and you compare
it to the composition API, which has a single setup method which accepts its own set of parameters,
those are two completely different types of return values for our view configuration object.
So I think what divine component does behind the scenes is it provides all of those complex types and
all of those either or scenarios, either options API or Composition API, these properties which may
be optional, these properties which may be required.
It does all of that and just does a better job at communicating to TypeScript that we're working with
a specific view component configuration object rather than a regular JavaScript object that just happens
to have, for example, a name, property and a data method.
So it will validate, for example, that you provide values here that are valid to use in the options
API, because otherwise it's just going to be a plain JavaScript object and be interpreted as TypeScript
as such rather than a specific Vue configuration object that requires its own set of things that it
needs to have in order to work.
The key takeaway is anytime we're adding TypeScript to a component, we need to make the line equal
to T.S. and we need to import, define component and wrap the actual object in the defined component
function column.
All right.
A couple more things I want to talk about in this lesson.
We are able to use TypeScript syntax now within the body of this entire section, because we told TypeScript
that the entire section has a language of task.
So, for example, if I wanted to specify the return value of my data method, I can totally provide
a type annotation in line.
For example, I can put a colon right here and say that this will produce a return value of an object
with an image like property set to a string.
All right.
That's one way I can do it.
Alternatively, what I can do is provide a manual interface.
So, for example, right here I can define an interface called data, and data will look exactly the
same.
I'm going to say that a data object in this scenario will be an object with an image like property set
to a string.
And that allows me to use data right here and say that that is the return value of my data method.
However, what you'll come to discover is that TypeScript is actually going to be pretty good at correctly
identifying the return values of things like the data method, especially if it's really simple data
types like a simple string.
So technically we don't need this, it's not really required.
I do want to point out that if we hover our mouse over data, we're going to get this really, really
nasty output in this code that doesn't really communicate much.
But I'm going to show you later on how we can sort of identify that TypeScript has inferred the wrong
types.
In this case, it's inverted the correct types.
So technically speaking, we don't even need to tell it manually, explicitly that we have an image
like attribute set to a string because it's going to be able to figure that out.
So I'm going to remove this.
It's just to show you how we would add an interface or how we would add a general type annotation to
something like our data method.
And we can apply that to any one of our other things here, whether it be our props, whether it can
be our methods, object, etc. We can annotate as much as we want to specify the parameters, the return
values, etc..
All right.
Before we finish this lesson off, there's one more thing I want to do, of course, and that is update
the test suite.
Since we updated our component, I also want to update the test suite.
So I'm going to open up the corresponding test in profile image test that.
Yes, let me drag that to my right.
And then of course, we're going to change this component test file to be a typescript file.
So let's give it a test extension.
And one potential issue you may see is this one right here.
I saw this a lot when I was building this course out.
It's going to complain about the import.
It's going to say cannot find module components, navigation, profile, image.
All that is the problem here is that by default it's going to be looking for a test file because TypeScript
by default doesn't look for a short view file.
So what we can do to simply remove this error is to be more explicit here in our import and tell TypeScript
that the file has a dot view extension.
So right here I'm just going to add that view and that will make the problem go away.
TypeScript will understand that it's now importing a view component from a view file and that should
be up.
And with that, everything should still pass.
Let me quickly run our test suite right here.
I mean, do you and PM run test watch to see if we're able to get just this file.
Even a second all so there is profile image and I'm guessing main nav is running because may nav is
also mounting the profile image.
And you can see all of our tests are still passing.
Right.
So to summarize, the good news is whenever we are adding TypeScript to a component, we do not need
to change its file extension.
All we have to do is change the script section to have a lag of types and make sure to import, define
component and wrap your configuration object as the first argument to that define component invoked
function that just allows TypeScript to have a better understanding of what a view configuration object
can entail.
It can also notice here in this pop up, we finally get a somewhat reasonable message from TypeScript
and you can see here it understands that image length is going to be indeed a string.
So somewhere behind the scenes, there's a lot of complexity obviously going on.
But TypeScript understands that our data is going to have an image like property set to a string.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.