Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to install the View SEAL Eye and the acronym SEAL Eye is short for command
line interface.
So basically the view CLIA is going to run as your typical terminal or command line program.
You can think of something like get as a closed comparison.
And the purpose of this tool is to make it really easy to create, manage and update view projects.
And when I say view project, I basically just mean a web application built with the View Library.
So The View Seelye, for example, is going to make it really easy for us in the next lesson to execute
just one command and have a complete view project ready to go so it can generate project folders for
your project files, web pack configurations, basically sparing you the need to understand all of those
deep technical details that are required to get a View app up and running in the browser.
So instead of manually hardwiring all this plumbing, the view is going to make it really easy for us
to just get up and running really quickly and then later on in the course.
That usually is also going to help us with doing things like adding plug ins to view adding additional
NPM packages like view AX in Vue router.
And one advantage of the view Celia over NPM is not only does it download and fetch those packages from
NPM, but it also creates, for example, starter files with the basic boilerplate code.
You need to get started with some of those technologies.
So this is a command line interface that is specifically built for working with Vue.
All right.
So in a moment, I'll take you directly to my terminal and we'll install it.
But first, I want to give you a little bit of background on what we're going to do with NPM.
We're going to install Vue Sealey as a global NPM dependency.
So this is a regular NPM package.
It's a regular repository hosted on NPM, but we're not going to attach it to any specific project because
the view really is not really focused on being in a specific project.
Rather, it's a piece of software for helping us create and manage other projects, view projects.
So we're going to be installing it as a global dependency.
Now that basically means is when we run NPM install, we're going to attach a dash g flag that is short
for global and NPM is going to install it in some directory on your computer and then it's simply going
to be available in your terminal just like any other terminal based program.
So it's going to operate quote unquote, globally.
And all that globally means is it's not isolated to a specific project or a specific project folder.
It's just this global app that's installed on your computer, just like any other app on your computer.
The only difference is it's coming from NPM.
All right.
And I'll show you how to do that in just a second.
So with that, let's transition to the command line and we're going to go ahead and install The View
Seelye.
Okay.
So here I am in my terminal on a mac, but the command should be the exact same on your Windows computer.
And what I'm going to execute is NPM install, but I'm also going to add that dash g flag.
So Dash G and that of course is short for global.
So we're not attaching the package to a specific project, rather we're installing it globally.
So it is available to be used from any directory, from any folder on your computer.
So right now I'm executing this on my desktop folder, but you can basically be anywhere in your computer's
file structure.
As long as NPM is installed, this command should work.
All right.
So we're going to follow this up with the name of the actual package, and that's going to be act view.
That is the name of the actual organization that is hosting this repository.
Then slash C ally.
That is the actual name of the package itself.
All right.
Now, I am recording this video at the start of March 2022, and what I'd like to do now is pin down
a specific version number of the views really, because by default, if you run this command as is,
it's going to install the latest version, which may be different from the one that is the latest right
now.
And just to reduce the chances of possible errors or warnings, I want you to have a version that is
basically exactly like mine that just reduces the chances that there's updates or changes that are going
to lead to a different experience.
So I assure you that this is a pretty modern up to date version of the SEAL.
I and I will be monitoring this video as the course progresses in order to make sure that there isn't
a newer version released.
And if there is, I will do my best to update these videos as quickly as possible.
But for now, since we're just getting started with Vue, we don't really need to worry about this.
I just would like you to install a specific version to reduce all these chances of errors.
So in order to do that, we're going to add an app sign at the end, and that allows us to specify a
specific version number.
And we want to do 5.0.1.
And this is the latest version as of March 2022.
But if it's 5.0.2 tomorrow or 5.1 in a couple of months, don't worry, those changes are not going
to be that staggering.
And this CGI version will allow us to work with the latest and greatest version of Vue itself, which
is Vue three.
All right.
So we're going to install this global dependency and it might take a minute or two.
And when it's done, I want to try two different commands to verify that we have successfully installed
the view zeolite.
By the way, this program is going to be available on your command line with the command name view Yui.
So first step, what I want to show you here, I'm going to clear all this content is we can execute
the command and PM list followed by the Dash G flag that is once again short for global and that's going
to show you all installed global NPM dependencies.
So now you'll notice we have you still appear here with the exact same version number that we specified.
So that's great.
And then as I mentioned, we have this view command and if we want to add on a dash dash version flag
that will give you the version of the vehicle, I think we're going to get 5.0.1 here as well.
But the more important thing here is the mere fact that we are getting a number here means that this
command is working, which means Vue is now registered as a valid command, a valid program from the
terminal.
So that means everything has been installed correctly.
So what I'm going to do now is clear the content again, and now I'm just going to execute view by itself.
And that's going to bring up the documentation for this seal.
As I scroll up here, you can see it begins with a couple of options, including the version flag that
we just saw.
But here is really the heart of everything that Dave usually can do for you.
And the way it works is we begin with the view command, followed by a space and then one of these commands.
So for example, we can do view, create or view add or view invoke, etc. in each one of these commands
will do something different.
So for example, in the next lesson we're going to use, if you create in order to create a new project
powered by this usually service and you can also do something like if you add it to add a certain plug
in to the project, that's going to be something like View X and view router later on in the course.
So once again, this is just a basic command line software program to make it really easy to create
and spin up a view app from scratch.
If you're coming from the React ecosystem, this is very equivalent to something like Create React app,
but even more fleshed out and expanded.
All right, that's all there is to cover in this lesson now that the vehicle is installed, that we
can use it in the very next lesson to create our job search view app.
So pretty exciting stuff and I'll see you there.