All right.
So welcome to the next section of the course.
This section will continue our exploration of the View X Library.
So let's get right to it.
In this section, we don't have a new user story since most of our work is going to be pretty technical
as far as configuring view.
So I do want to give you a general sense of what we're trying to accomplish here and the new concepts
that we're going to introduce.
So so far we explored the idea of Store State and we explored the idea of mutations.
A mutation is a synchronous update that updates the stores state.
So when I say synchronous, what I'm saying is that it has to be immediate.
It has to be plain JavaScript code that doesn't take an amount of time to run.
So a mutation can absolutely set, for example, an object property to be a new value.
That is the kind of instantaneous operation that is synchronous that we are talking about.
Now, the question I have for you is how do we use Vue ex to handle asynchronous operations?
For example, what if we want to reach out to an API, get some data, and then once we receive that
data, store it in our view X Store.
Well, we cannot actually have asynchronous events happen in a mutation.
A mutation has to be synchronous.
So in order to accomplish anything asynchronous, we have to introduce a new idea called actions to
our View Store.
And action is going to be a method that commits a mutation, which sounds kind of silly because it's
just a method that commits a mutation that does something that we already know how to do.
What's the point?
Well, the general idea is that actions allow for asynchronous operations.
So you're typically going to do something.
And once that something completes, that's when you can tell the method to commit another mutation to
the store that will actually receive the data and do something with it in the store state.
So going back to our original example, let's say we want to make an API call, we want to fetch data
in the action which will learn how to write in this section.
That's where we make an API call and we can await it until we get the data.
Then once we have the data, we can commit a mutation.
We can issue a change to of the store that says, Hey, I now have this data already.
It's no longer an asynchronous operation.
I already have the data fetched.
Take this data and update the stores state.
So in summary, an action is a different construct that allows us to deal with asynchronous operations,
and that's how we're going to learn about in this section.
So what's the actual problem we're going to solve?
What's the refactor we're going to make to an app?
Well, currently our job listings component makes the request to our JSON server to get the job listings
array of 100 jobs.
Right.
What we're going to do is we're going to move our jobs array from being stored in the local data of
the job listings component to being stored in our view X Store.
Right.
So what we're going to do is we're going to actually isolate the API fetching logic to a separate tested
helper function that's going to reach out to the JSON server.
And then we're going to talk about how we can write a more an action rather that is going to use that
API fetch function to get our jobs array.
And once it receives the data, it's going to commit a mutation to save that to our store.
And once the store updates that change is going to reflect in our job listings component.
I know this is a lot to take in and it can be confusing.
The short story here is that we're going to move our data fetching and we're going to move our jobs
away from being stored locally in job listings to being stored more globally in the view store.
And that change is going to allow us to introduce all of the concepts that we care about.
All right.
So lots of fun up ahead.
And I will see you in the next lesson.