Welcome to the next section of the course.
In this section we're going to install the Tailwind CC Utility Library or CC framework and we're going
to be using Tailwind to help us write really quick, easy CC styles throughout the course.
Now you may be thinking about, Hey, this is a view course.
I don't want to learn about all this extra stuff, but remember, at the end of the day, we're building
a real world front end application.
So we are going to need to style it so that it looks like the inspiration from which it's coming, the
Google Careers website.
So we are going to need to write CC styles at some point throughout the course.
We're not going to obsess over it, but I think Tailwind is a really, really efficient, popular,
modern way to do it, to write our systems.
And it's going to be super simple.
This was actually my very first project practicing and using Tailwind CC and I found it to be an absolute
joy to use.
And it's also another modern technology that you can add to your resume alongside view.
So here we are on tailwinds official website and I want to talk to you quickly about what this library
is and what it adds.
So whenever you hear the words CSS library or CSS as framework, you might think of bootstrap.
So bootstrap, if you haven't heard of it, is a library that basically gives you pre-configured what
I call components styles.
So for example, if you want to add bootstrap to your app, you might get a access class called Button.
And when you apply that button style to a button in your app, it will apply a whole bunch of aesthetics
to that button.
For example, it might give it a blue background black text, it might give it rounded corners and a
certain box shadow, etc..
So the idea is that you don't have to build these pretty looking buttons out of the box.
Bootstrap gives you a class to apply those styles automatically.
So Bootstrap is focused on kind of the user facing components that an app might need, like a button
or like a nav bar or like an alert or an icon or a card.
Things that are actually part of the UI tailwind is not exactly the same thing.
It doesn't give you these pre-built aesthetic styles out of the box.
Rather, what it gives you is CSS utility classes.
So imagine that we just have a library that gives us hundreds of different sized classes that we can
apply as often as we want throughout our app.
And all of these classes are super small and compact, and they typically do just one thing.
So the idea behind Tailwind is that you apply a bunch of classes together, each one of them takes care
of one thing, and then when they're all combined together, you have the styles you need.
But you never actually have to worry about naming your own sizes, classes, gathering styles together,
etc. We're going to see an example of how this all plays out in our app shortly.
But I just want to give you a quick example here on this Web page.
You can see it says here Tailwind is a utility first class framework packed with classes like Flex for
Tech Center and Rotate 90.
So immediately we can tell from these from these names, this isn't things like button or form or card.
Rather, these are classes that apply direct CSR styles to whatever elements we add them to.
So for example, the flex utility class from the Tailwind CSR Library will apply Display Flex.
So it's a really easy way to add a Flexbox to a component.
If you have a DIV and you just want to make it a flexbox, you do class equals flex and tailwind gives
you that availability.
So now you have a flexbox, you no longer have to come up with a semantic name for that box.
Like you don't need to do header or center container or wrapper.
All you need to know is I have this class called Flex that's coming to me from the Tailwind Library.
I apply it to a did and now I have a Flexbox.
Right.
A similar idea here with Piti for Piti actually stands for padding top.
You don't have to memorize all of these little nicknames.
We'll talk more about them later.
But the idea is, hey, if you have an element and you want to add padding to the top of it, you can
do putty followed by some kind of number.
So starting with T1, that's the smallest amount of padding.
Then P2, P2 three, PD four, that adds padding to the top of whatever element you want.
Similarly, you can apply the CSS utility class text center the tail was just going to give us and that's
going to center align the text in an element.
So you can see here, as I scroll down, when we write our code, it's going to be primarily writing
a whole bunch of extra classes inside our H HTML.
So the advantage of this is that we don't need to write a lot of custom Caesar's classes.
We don't have to worry about things like nesting or sass or any of those kind of complexities, of course,
that make it difficult to keep scope limited.
We talked a little bit about Scope in the previous section when we talked about this scoped attribute
view, and this is a similar idea.
The idea is the Tailwind CFS library is going to give us pretty much.
All the utility classes we need to style our elements in a way that's going to look like the Google
Careers page.
It's going to look just like this.
We're going to have a DIV and we're just going to apply a whole bunch of helper classes to it.
They're going to add different styles to it, and that's going to immediately format the page in a way
that we want.
Now, the best way to experience Tailwind, of course, is to see it in action.
I certainly don't believe that I've made the case so far as to why this is a great framework.
I personally love it.
But I think as we continue writing success throughout the class, you're going to see how it helps us
really quickly.
Just get CSX up and running so that we don't have to worry about it and don't have to worry about cascading
conflicts and all of those other things and can focus primarily on the view concepts, right?
So this is a quick introduction to tailwind in the very next lesson, we're going to set it up in our
View project.