All right.
So in this lesson, we're going to add a new NPM package to our project, and it is called JSON server.
So JSON server allows us to create a fake backend.
We're not going to actually build any kind of real backend in this class.
And there's a couple of reasons for this.
Number one, building a backend is complex, usually involves setting up a database.
It usually involves some kind of framework or a library.
And there's a lot of variety as far as the programming languages and the libraries and the frameworks
that you could use.
I don't know where every student is coming from.
Some students, maybe JavaScript people, some may be Python people, Ruby people, Java people.
So rather than deal with the complexities of a specific framework, we're going to set up a fake backend.
We're going to install a package that's going to make it very simple to simulate a backend without actually
having to build a real one.
And that package that's going to enable us to do it to do that is called JSON server.
After we installed JSON server, what we can do is create a JSON file in our project directory and JSON,
if you're unaware, is just a file storage format.
It's basically a way to store data in a file and the format of JSON is very similar to how objects look
in JavaScript where it is a property and then a colon and then a value.
In fact, JSON is short for JavaScript object notation because it's notation or in other words, how
it looks comes directly from or is influenced by JavaScript.
So we're going to install this package right now and then I'll show you how to set up this file with
fake data in just a second, and I promise it'll all make sense then.
For now, let's begin by installing this dependency.
So I'm going to write NPM install and we need to add this not as a main dependency because it's not
going to be directly related to the bundle that the user will get in their browser.
It is a development dependency that we as developers need in order to fake a back end.
So it's only for development.
So in order to install a package as a dev dependency, we can add this include flag with two dashes.
So dash dash include then an equal sign and the word dev.
So we're telling NPM to install this package as a dev dependency rather than a regular user dependency.
And then the package is called JSON Dash server.
So I'm going to install this.
It should be pretty quick.
And in the very next lesson, we'll take a look at how we can set up this package to create a fake backend
for us at whatever URL we want and have it serve the data that we want, which for us is going to be
a listing of 100 fictional jobs.
All right.
So I will see you in the next lesson.