Welcome to the next section of the course.
In this section, we're going to learn all about views, directives.
We're going to define that term in just a moment.
Before we get there, though, I want to do a quick reminder of what our user story is.
What is it that we are working on?
It's always important to tie back to what value we are delivering for the user.
So our current user story is as a user, I'd like to navigate between the pages of the career site.
So the next thing we're going to be building out on our main NAV is going to be the various links that
allow the user to go to different pages on our website.
All right.
So let's begin let's imagine that I had a slice of data on my data object called u, r l.
So I'm going to define a URL right here and I'm going to set it to the website that inspired this entire
project, our Google Careers website.
So I'm just going to type here a full URL https.
Collins slash slash careers, Google dotcom.
And here's the question that I have for you.
You'll notice that we have this hyperlink right here.
That's a tag with an RF attribute, which sets where this hyperlink goes.
And my question is, how can we get this URL right here?
How can we inject this value of careers down Google.com into this position or assign it to this attribute
of ATRA?
So let me show you a couple approaches that you might be tempted to do, which are not going to prove
successful.
And then we're going to introduce the actual view solution to the problem.
So the first thing you might say is, well, maybe Vue is smart enough to recognize that if I put the
word URL here, it might be smart enough to recognize that we have a URL property on data and assign
it automatically there.
Well, if I head back to my browser, you'll notice when I open up my devtools and this is not going
to work.
Let me just refresh the page and select this element and you'll see that we are unfortunately going
to hard code.
The literal text you are URL that is not what we want.
So this first strategy does not work.
At which point you might say something like, well, we use this curly brace syntax in order to interpolate
the value of a data property like company with the same approach.
Work in a ref.
Well, let's try it out right here.
I'm going to use the curly brace syntax and I'm going to provide a URL.
Again, this is another property on our data object right here.
If I go back to my browser and take a look here, the browser is automatically refreshed.
I'm going to take a look here.
Unfortunately, the exact same result view is currently interpreting the value literally.
It literally thinks we want to.
Curly braces and the new URL and then to closing curly braces.
So no luck so far.
So how do we solve this problem?
In order to solve this problem, we're going to need to use something called a directive.
A directive is a special view command.
You can almost think of it like a command or a function in line in our HTML template that you can recognize
and that view knows is supposed to do something special.
All right.
So I'm going to remove this right here.
And what we want to use here is a directive called the bind.
All of you directives are going to start with the V letter with the v prefix.
So in this case the V bind.
And what the V bind directive allows us to do is to bind or in other words, connect a data value from
our view configuration object to an HTML attribute.
Right.
So this is a slightly different concept from what we did with our company property, because company
was just text that we interpolated directly onto the screen at the user could see this is different.
This is nothing that the user is going to necessarily see visually on the screen.
But we're still connecting some piece of our configuration object to some part of our template.
But in this case, it's an attribute on an HTML element.
We want to dynamically set the value of that attribute, the H of attribute honor anchor tag using a
value on our data object.
All right, so here's what the syntax is going to look like before a ref.
We're going to write V Bind Colon, and we're going to see this little Iceland violation.
Don't worry about this for now.
So the reason why we need to provide it before the attribute is because we can bind to any valid HTML
attribute.
So for example and a hyperlink may have attributes like h rough but it can also have class like we see
here.
It can have target whatever.
We can actually bind to whatever HTML attribute we want on any element.
But before the attribute, we're going to put the syntax, the dash behind colon.
Right?
And by itself, that is not enough because we have to tell you what we actually want to bind this value
to.
In other words, what should a view populate for the ref?
Well, now that we've provided the V bind syntax, we can in fact write our data property by itself.
So right here, I'm going to write a URL.
All right.
Once again, feel free to ignore the Iceland violation.
I think it's actually two different ones.
And the first one was telling us that we had no value within our double quotes.
Now we do.
So what we've now told you to do once I save this file, is to connect this new URL property to the
ref attribute.
Bind it, connect it, tie it to the age of attribute.
And the same rules apply as this, as the rules do for company.
If the value of this URL property changes, we will dynamically substitute the new value into the h
ref attribute value.
All right.
So now if I go back to my website.
And I click on this.
There we go.
We've successfully gone to careers that Google.com.
And if I head back to my original page and I click into this element and we observe it, let me refresh.
We're going to see here that now we have the age of actually populated with the URL value in our data
objects.
So behind the scenes, viewers substituted this value from Chrome's perspective.
When it looks into the HTML, all it sees is just the regular string of careers.
Got Google.com.
But here's the beautiful part.
Let me once again demonstrate using view devtools.
I'm going to head into my view devtools.
I'm going to identify the main nav component.
We have all of its properties right here and earlier on you may recall that we modified company and
observed how that affected the text right here.
Well, let's now go ahead and change the property here.
So instead of going to careers that Google.com, let's say I go somewhere else like WW dot yahoo.com
and save this right here with a little diskette.
Well now if I go back to my elements, you'll see that view has automatically changed the value.
So we have bound data to our view, but in a different way than we did with bubble careers.
This was binding text.
Now we are binding HTML attributes.
So now if I click on this, we're going to predictably go to Yahoo.com and it looks like we're running
into some kind of JavaScript error on Yahoo.com.
So those developers who definitely take care of it.
But the key takeaway here is that we have these directives in view.
These are commands, these are special things that we can add into our templates that are essentially
functions that tells you to do something.
So whenever we need to bind or connect an attribute to a piece of data, we use the V bind, attribute,
v dash bind.
All of our attributes will start with the v syntax, then a colon, and then the actual real world HTML
attribute that we want to connect to.
And then inside the double quotes, we can provide the value of the property.
That view should substitute right there.
All right.
That's really all there is to cover in this lesson.
In the next one, we're going to address the S lint violation that we see onscreen.
I will see you there.