All right.
So welcome to the next section of the course in this section will introduce some caveats regarding how
Vue and CSA work together.
So here I have my app dot view file and I want to begin by adding an H1 above our rendered hello world
component.
So right here I'm going to an H1 and I'm going to give it some sample text like Hello, I am in app
dot view and I'm going to save this and of course we're going to see those changes on the right hand
side here is the H1.
And so as I mentioned in the previous section, we have this style section in every component.
And of course the ideal is that we're going to use this section to provide CSR styles for the content
in our template section.
So you might think to yourself, I want to style my H1 tag, let's say we want to make this text right
here purple.
So what I'm going to do is go to my style section and I'm going to add my element or tag selector.
So we're going to target an H1 and this is all Valencia Sass.
And right here, I'm going to say that I want its color to be purple.
All right.
And when I save this file we're going to see indeed that the color of hello.
I am an apt w is indeed going to be purple.
We're also going to see some unintended consequences.
So let's save this file and see what happens.
All right.
So on the right hand side, we see indeed that our H1 is now in purple.
We have a little bit of a problem.
This helloworld text has also become purple.
So what is going on here?
Well, remember, in our app component, we are rendering our hello world component.
And if I open up that file so I'm going to open up the file using my file explorer, which you can access
with command P on a mac or control P on windows.
And so here I'm going to look for my Helloworld file.
In our Helloworld file, I'm going to scroll to the template section and right here at the very top.
Lo and behold, we are indeed rendering an H1.
So what is happening here?
Well, the styles from our app to view component right here are escaping from the confines of this component
and affecting the H1 in a totally separate component.
All right.
And that, of course, is a problem because it becomes pretty hard to determine where a given style
is coming from.
Right.
And this is not really ideal.
Though the whole purpose of you is that each component is its own isolated, independent chunk of logic
with its own styling.
If we write in H1 here and all of a sudden we accidentally affect three other H1 across three other
components and we don't know whether style changes came from.
That's obviously very problematic and very confusing.
So by default, whenever we declare styles in our components, even in the style section, by default
they are going to be global.
What it means to be global is they're going to apply to everything.
If we have an H1 here, even though the style is in this style section of this component app view,
this style and this CSR selector logic will apply to every H1 in the app.
All right.
And that is, of course, a problem.
We're going to talk about how to solve the problem in the very next lesson.
But for now, I also want to show you an alternative solution that some people might be tempted to pursue,
but that will also create its own share of potential problems.
So, of course, one very common way to solve a problem like this is by using more specific selectors.
So somebody might say something like this in the app component, they're going to say, okay, I can
give my H1 a class and I'll give it a sample class like header and then down below here.
Since this is valid CSR, I can target that element not by its tag, not by an H1 but by the header
class.
Right.
And so if I save that now you're going to see that indeed we get the desired result we have.
Hello, i'm an app dot view which is the H1 from our app file.
That one is colored in purple while the H1 in the helloworld component is not affected.
However, the problem here is that these styles are still global.
These styles are still applied to every single component in the app.
So it's not an unreasonable situation to imagine where somebody might be editing the Helloworld file
someday and they might be saying, okay, I want to solve this H1 and maybe an appropriate class to
give it to something like Header.
And then we're going to be completely shocked when they add a class like header here and don't provide
any additional styles at all.
And then when they saved the file, lo and behold, Helloworld is now in purple.
And of course, the reason is because this header class and its styles are coming from this declaration
right here in a totally separate file.
Right.
And this can be very confusing if you have 100 different components in your codebase.
So yes, CSR class selectors or even ID selectors are a little bit more specific and offer some degree
of protection, but they're not perfect because they still don't solve the fundamental problem that
all of these styles are going to be available in every component.
And thus, if we use the same named class anywhere else, we have a chance that it will inherit the
styles from the access declaration in a totally different file.
All right.
So that is the problem we are seeing now.
We're going to see how to solve this problem in the very next lesson.