Okay.
So welcome to the next section of the course and to a brand new user story.
I have a good feeling that this is probably going to be the last user feature we build for the app.
I think we've had a lot of practice with view and view and right now we sort of reached the point of
diminishing returns where there's not as many new concepts being introduced.
And I think that you've had a good exposure to the core concepts around view, view, view router.
So this will sort of be our last hurrah or last user story to implement.
There are going to be of course, some new features here and there.
But at this point I feel comfortable that if you've made it this far and you understand what's going
on, I think you would feel comfortable tackling a new view feature by yourself or supplementing your
knowledge with something else that is in either the View Library or the View Library, etc..
Of course, there's always something more to learn about testing, about components, about this library
or that.
But I think the heart of view has been captured and we've had a lot of practice with it.
So this will be kind of our last user feature and it should be a good one.
There's going to be some familiar stuff and some new stuff as well.
And as always, of course, a lot of testing to go along with that.
So here it is.
As a user, I'd like to search for a technical skill that I know so that I can find jobs that fit my
specialization.
So this feature is going to be similar to our past ones in the sense that we're going to use something
that the user does to filter the jobs on the right hand side.
What's going to make this feature a little bit distinct is we're now not going to be using checkboxes,
we're going to be using a text input.
So directly below that clear filters button that we fixed up in the previous section, we're going to
add a text input where the user can enter a skill.
And most of our fake jobs revolve around various front end technologies like Vue and Angular and React.
So the idea here is that the user will be able to type a technology like view or React or Angular,
and we want to show the jobs on the right hand side that fit that search criteria.
Now, we're going to keep things super simple, so we're only going to allow them to enter one term
at a time.
And we're going to search for that term in the name of the job, because remember, our job has a name
or a title.
It also has all the bullet points and we can get really granular and search in those.
For now, we're simply going to search for the user search term in the title to keep things as simple
as possible.
So we want this filtering feature, of course, to co-exist alongside all of our other filtering features
as well.
So the user should be able to select, for example, a job type, a degree type and organization and
then search for view as their search term and have jobs pop up on the right that fulfill all of those
criteria.
All right.
So this will be our final user story.
Congratulations on making it to the final kind of section or a final project section, at least of this
course, because I may add some later lessons on various view concepts not directly related to this
project, but congratulations on reaching this last section for a user feature.
And as always, let's, let's have a lot of fun together and let's learn more about Vue.
So we will start building out this feature in the very next lesson, and I will see you there.