Okay.
Welcome to the next section of the course.
In this section we're going to talk about named slots.
And just like their name suggests, a named slot is simply a view slot to which we assign a name, a
unique identifier.
What is the advantage of name slots?
Well, they allow us to have multiple slots within a single child component.
In other words, we can define multiple sections within the component where we would like the parent
to inject dynamic content.
So let me give you a use case for this from the official Google Careers website.
This is what we're going to be building out in this section.
So I'm going to head to the teams page right here on my main menu, and I want you to focus your eyes
on this section right here.
Consider this as a imaginary component.
Right here we have this box, and in the box we are centering a collection of text, right?
And that text consists of two sections.
We have this part right here, which we can call the title or the header, and then we have some text
below which we could consider the subtitle or the sub header.
Now, if every component looked exactly like this, then the way we can customize this text is by simply
providing two props one for the title and one for the subtitle.
Unfortunately, the situation on this website is a little bit more complex, so compare what you see
here to what you see on the allocations page.
All right.
We have a very similar design in some ways and a different design in others.
So we still have this idea of a centerpiece of text.
If we were to imagine this white box as a component, this component is very similar to the one on the
teams page.
It has a bunch of centered text consisting of a title and a subtitle.
However, the styles that we apply right here and right here are totally different compared to what
we see on the team's page.
So let me show you, if I flip back and forth, you can see they're totally different as far as the
font size, the bolding, maybe even the font, they're totally different, but they're kind of the
same in the sense of the components centering a title and a subtitle.
It gets even more interesting.
Let's say I head to my students page.
In my students page, I have a similar idea.
I have a component that centers text, but here it's almost like we have just the title without a subtitle.
So of course we can try to solve this problem with things like props, where we enable primary styles
and secondary styles like we did with our action button, for example.
But in this kind of scenario, I think that we would really benefit from an approach where we simply
allow a component to have multiple slots.
Imagine we defined a component where we had one slot right here and another slot down below, right?
And each parent component can specify not just the HTML, of course, but the HTML with the corresponding
access styles that they would like to apply for the header and the sub header and all that the child
component would be responsible for would be creating a reusable box that centers that content in the
middle, right?
That way we can have a single component to represent this box.
We can have this design right here where we have a slot and a slot and we can reuse that same component
right here, but simply provide a different chunk of HTML right here and right here.
And then on something like the student's page, we could simply provide one slot without providing anything
else to the other one and thus eliminate it entirely from the component.
So hopefully this gives you a sense of how slots can enable a lot of reusability interview components.
But of course, in order to enable this design, we need to be able to have two slots.
And in order to have two slots, we need to be able to uniquely identify each one.
And the way we do that is by assigning each one a name.
All right.
So we're going to build a component very similar to this starting in the very next lesson.