All right.
So welcome to the next section of the course which is entitled Intro to TypeScript.
In this section, we're going to take a break from our job search project to learn about the basics
of the typescript programming language.
Now, as a heads up, if you are already familiar with the basics of TypeScript, you can feel free
to skip this section and move on to the next one where we're going to pick back up on the project.
In this section, we're going to focus on TypeScript by itself in a separate, isolated environment
so we can learn the basics of the language by itself.
Now, if you're brand new to TypeScript, the first thought you may have is, Wait a minute, wait a
minute.
I don't want to learn another whole programming language.
That's a lot to take on in a view course, but it's okay.
And let me let me tell you why.
The first thing is, if you're familiar with JavaScript, you already know a lot about TypeScript.
Believe it or not, the way I can describe TypeScript is almost like an extension of JavaScript.
It's like an enhanced version of JavaScript.
It's not a brand new language with different syntax.
It's really the core JavaScript language, but with some extra syntax related to types.
All right.
And that's what I'm going to talk about in this section.
We're going to introduce what TypeScript is and what problems it helps us to solve.
That JavaScript does not.
So we're going to focus on this language in the section, just the basics, just what you need to get
going.
And then we're going to apply it to our View project in the next section.
The reason I wanted to include TypeScript in this course is because it's becoming very popular in frontend
development or in general, wherever you have JavaScript projects, a lot of developers are moving them
to TypeScript because of the benefits that TypeScript provides.
So let's talk about those benefits.
So first up, we have the word typescript and it has the word type in it.
What is a type?
So a type is just a type of data, a kind of data.
So JavaScript has many different types of data strings, numbers, booleans, arrays, objects, undefined,
null, etc., right?
So a type is just a category that a value belongs to, right?
It's kind of like this family of values that you belong to.
A type is abstract, it's not a concrete value, and that can be a kind of a vague expression.
So let's take a look at a couple examples here.
The integer or the number of five is a value.
It is concrete, it is specific.
It has some kind of value in the real world in a program five means something number in comparison is
what we might call the type of five it is the data type of what five is.
It is the family that five belongs to.
Five is a example of a number.
Ten is an example of a number 20 is an example of a number.
So number is the type.
It's the category.
It's the kind of data.
Similarly true is a concrete value while boolean is its type.
Similarly, the string hello is a specific string value, but its type is string.
Okay, so when we're writing plain JavaScript, JavaScript has no idea about what kind of type we're
working with.
If we have a variable and we assign it to a string, JavaScript doesn't know that that's a string.
It just knows that the variable is a name that's pointing to some kind of object which may be whatever
we want.
Right?
And so the problem with that is we can run into situations where we try to execute operations on invalid
objects and JavaScript won't discover that error until the program runs.
And that's because we don't have type declarations, which means we don't tell the language what type
something is.
And as as simple as that may sound, what that actually helps a language like TypeScript to do is to
help you figure out a whole bunch of errors.
So let me take you to an official example from the actual TypeScript website on the next slide.
So this is a example from the actual front page of the TypeScript website.
And you can see it says TypeScript is JavaScript with syntax for types.
So as I mentioned earlier, TypeScript is not some kind of brand new language with a totally different
syntax.
It's just like an enhanced version of JavaScript.
It's all the features that JavaScript has, plus some more features on top of it that help you avoid
a certain category of errors in your program.
To take a look at the example on the right hand side, we have a user object with three properties first
name, last name and role.
And more importantly than just having three properties, TypeScript can recognize that this object's
properties have certain types.
So TypeScript understands that the user object has a first name property that is a string, a last name
property that is a string and a row property that is a string.
Now take a look at what happens when we console.log.
User Name.
If this was a regular JavaScript program, the program would run just fine, but JavaScript would have
value to undefined and that might cause a problem in our program.
Most likely, this kind of error would occur when the developer is really trying to access either the
first name property or the last name property.
But they may accidentally forget and think it's called name and a JavaScript.
The language won't give you any concerns about it.
It won't tell you that that's an error in comparison.
In a language like TypeScript, it's going to warn you about this kind of error or this kind of potential
violation you can.
See here in the red error message on the right typescript will tell you the property name does not exist
on the type of object that I think user is an object with a first name property of string, a last name,
property of string and a roll of string.
It's going to say, Hey, I have three properties.
Name is not one of them.
That's problematic and you should look into this and that's all that type checking is and that's all
the typescript adds.
It's JavaScript with syntax for types.
In addition to that, TypeScript is also going to allow us to perform certain operations and prohibit
other operations.
For example, if it knows we're working with a string, it's going to allow us to use a string method
like two uppercase in comparison.
If it knows it, we have a number.
It's going to say you can't execute a method like two uppercase on a number because that's not a valid
method, right?
In JavaScript, again, these errors will pop up, but they're only going to pop up when we run the
program.
In comparison in TypeScript, we're going to be able to identify them earlier as we're actually coding
in our editor.
And I hope that the advantages of TypeScript become clear as we actually work more with it, because
sometimes it can be hard to understand the initial benefits simply from these kind of introductory examples.
So let's also talk about what a compiler is, because in order to use TypeScript, we're going to need
to use a TypeScript compiler.
So the first thing is TypeScript does not run in our browser.
We only use the language in our code editor like the code for the benefits of development.
So TypeScript exists to help us as developer, as developers.
It helps us catch bugs, it helps us reduce the chance of errors.
It's not for the end user of the product.
It's for us as developers now because our web browser, like Chrome, does not recognize TypeScript,
it only recognizes JavaScript.
We need something that's going to convert our TypeScript code into plain vanilla JavaScript that the
browser can understand.
And that piece of software, that program is the compiler.
A compiler is a basic piece of software that converts our TypeScript to JavaScript so that it runs in
our browser.
It's basically the exact same principle we have in our job search project when it comes to things like
Babel.
Babel looks at our view components and says, Hey, you have this file with a template section, a script
section and a style section.
That's not a regular HTML file.
But no, don't worry about that.
I'm going to take that and I'm going to convert it into plain HTML, CSS in JavaScript that your browser
can run.
It's the exact same idea here.
The compiler is just a program that takes one thing that the browser does not understand in this case
TypeScript, and then converts it into a language that it can understand.
All right.
So for this section, what we're going to do is rather than set up anything on our computer, because
that's always going to be a little bit more complex, we're simply going to be learning JavaScript on
its official typescript, that is on its official website.
The official TypeScript website has a really helpful playground.
Basically, it's going to be a window where we can type in TypeScript on the left hand side, we can
execute it and we can also see the corresponding compiled JavaScript on the right hand side.
I'll show you this in the next lesson, but the key takeaway here is it's going to make it super simple
for us to get started playing around with the language, because all you need to do is access the website
and type in some code.
You don't need to install any modules or set up anything in your code.
Editor All right.
And then in the next section, I'll actually show you how to add TypeScript specifically to our View
project.
So for now, to close this lesson off, what I'd like you to do is to go to this link that you see on
your screen, TypeScript Lang Dawgs play.
And then in the next section I'll show you the basics of how this playground works and we'll get started
exploring the basic syntax of TypeScript, I promise.
It's not that crazy, it's the syntax isn't difficult and it's not that much more.
You're not going to be learning a brand new language.
You're going to be learning what I think is an enhanced, better version of JavaScript that helps us
avoid a lot of errors as developers.
All right, so I hope you're excited to learn this really popular tool in the JavaScript ecosystem,
and I will see you in the next lesson.