All right, welcome to the next section of the course.
This section is dedicated to testing where first going to learn about the Just Test Runner library.
And we're going to learn its syntax and its ins and outs, and then we're going to learn how to integrate
it with view.
And the advantage of this is that we will be able to write tests for our view components outside of
our browser environment.
So we're going to talk about the benefits of testing, we're going to talk about the syntax of testing.
We're going to learn about something called test driven development in a couple lessons, lots of fun
testing, focused ideas in the section.
But before we get to all that, we have to define some key terms and terminology that I'll be using
throughout the upcoming lessons.
So there's actually a variety of different tests that we can write, and the one there are primarily
going to be writing is called a unit test.
So what is a unit test?
Well, a unit test tests a single piece of a program in isolation, and that definition is actually
subject to some degree of debate because developers disagree about what a single piece of our program
literally means.
Does it mean a single class?
Does it mean a single function or method?
Does it mean a single view component?
And I think it's important not to lose yourself in the semantics of what it is.
To me, a unit test simply means a small lightweight test that gives you some comfort and some feedback
that what you built is built correctly and it should run fast.
All right.
Another key feature of a unit test, besides the small scope of what it's covering, is that if there
are dependencies, the unit test should mock them or stub them out.
Now, if you're unfamiliar with what these terms mean, let me give you an example.
To mock or to stub something out means to replace a dependency with a substitute or a replacement that
pretends to be that thing.
So imagine that you have a view component and it reaches out to some kind of API, gets a JSON response
and renders that to the screen.
Now I know we haven't built that logic into our app yet, but we will in the future and you can sort
of imagine the process for how it works.
Well, we don't want our test to have to set up a view component and make sure the API is running and
test the entire flow because the test becomes very complex and very coupled.
A lot of things need to work correctly in order for the test to work right.
We need the API to be running.
We need to be able to make a request successfully.
We need to be able to get a response successfully and we need to be able to render it.
So we're testing a lot of different things and we have dependencies or other things that the view component
is dependent on in order to run.
So what we might do in a test like that to make it a unit test is say, well, our core unit is the
view component and we just want to test that.
Once it gets data, it's going to render it to the screen.
So what we might do is we might set up a fake API or pretend as if there is an API, not set up a real
one, but a fake one.
So that when our component makes a request to the API, we kind of intercept that call and just immediately
give it a plain, you know, JSON or JavaScript response.
We don't actually make any kind of asynchronous request.
We just pretend as if we did, and then we make sure that given the data, the view component renders
it correctly to the screen.
That way we've kept our scope small, we've removed the coupling with the API in our tests, and our
tests again are lightweight, they're focused and they should run fast because they're not dependent
on all of these additional factors or variables or dependencies hovering around our core unit.
So to me, a unit is just a small, testable piece of functionality in our program.
Again, it's not super important to get into the nitty gritty of is it a class is a function, etc.
We're going to see how we write tests and we're always going to come back to you, not whether it's
a proper unit, quote unquote, but rather is it providing some kind of value to us?
Is it giving us comfort that our view component is working as expected?
And is it reading well so that other developers can understand what we're testing and the benefits of
those tests?
Right.
So on this next slide, I have something famous called the testing pyramid, and it describes how your
app should incorporate various kinds of tests throughout.
So you'll notice the very bottom you have unit tests, and that comprises the largest chunk of the pyramid,
which suggests that unit tests should be the vast chunk or the biggest pie slice of the tests in your
app.
The majority of your tests in your app should be unit tests.
They should be small, lightweight, fast, independent tests that focus on small bits of functionality.
One level higher up than that, we have integration tests.
So as an example of what might be considered an integration testing of your app, if you have, for
example, a whole page being rendered and it renders 20 different view components together, that is
kind of its own distinct feature within the app that requires multiple different units to interact with
each other.
So in that scenario, you might say instead of just testing one view component by itself, I might render
a whole bunch of them.
Together in my tests just to see how the entire ecosystem of them works, how the integration or the
connections between the pieces of my program are interacting.
So integration is kind of one level higher just to incorporate multiple units interacting with each
other.
And of course, the more that different units are interacting with each other, the more there's a chance
for coupling, which means that there's more fault points, there's more places where something can
break, and thus the entire app could break down.
So integration tests are going to be what are called more flaky than unit tests.
There's simply more chances for error.
And so they're going to be more coupled.
They're generally going to run slower because they have to deal with more moving pieces and bringing
them up so that we can test them.
And so, as a result, you generally don't want as many of these tests in your app.
They're not going to be as fast.
They're more coupled, they're more difficult debug.
But you do want a couple of them to make sure your program is working as it's supposed to work with
all these little pieces talking to each other.
Right.
So the way you could think about it is a unit test is almost like a jigsaw puzzle.
It's like a little piece.
And you're just testing that piece of the puzzle.
Looks good by itself.
Then the integration test is adding a whole bunch of puzzle pieces together and making sure that you're
seeing the full picture and that it's working as expected.
Right.
And then at one level, higher up than that is what are called end to end tests.
And you could see UI testing and this is perhaps the most complex and slowest and most couple of tests
there are.
So an example of something like this might be rendering a full view app in an actual simulated browser
like Chrome, and then having a computer click through your app and walk through, for example, a feature.
Let's say you're building some kind of e-commerce site and you want the user to click on a product,
add it to their cart, go to the cart and check out.
And you want to simulate an actual user clicking through the app and navigating through multiple pieces,
you know, entering all their credentials correctly, checking out basically and tests are the slowest
and you really should use them for the most critical parts of your app, such as a checkout experience,
where it is imperative that everything work correctly and you really want that extra layer of testing
and security to make sure things are working proper.
You really can't cover usually your entire app and end to end tests because there's just a lot of potential
for them to break and become outdated.
There's so many points of failure that they're just become very brittle.
You really just want to keep them small.
And the number of entities small and focused on the most critical parts of your app, while the smaller
tests, like the unit tests, focus on the individual elements, the view components, the classes,
the functions, etc..
And then of course, in that little bubble above our testing pyramid, we have manual tests.
Those are the tests that we run ourselves by going into the browser and plugging into our app and making
sure everything works correctly.
Basically, the way that we've been testing so far throughout the course has been only manual testing,
and the idea of adding all these tests is we're going to automate some of that functionality.
We're going to let the computer or just run some tests to make sure our components are doing exactly
what they're supposed to.
And whenever we make changes, we don't have to go back and test every little thing.
We can just ensure that all of our components have not broken and are still doing their part to make
the app functional and cohesive.
All right.
So as a reminder, what tools are we going to use?
We're going to use that just testing library that is developed by Facebook.
It is agnostic of you.
So it's a testing library that you can use for other projects in JavaScript.
You can use it for testing React and you can use it for testing other types of technologies.
It's not specifically tied to view, it's just a general testing library.
And then in combination with that, we're going to introduce a library called Vue Test Utils.
And what that is going to allow us to do is set up our components within our testing files.
We're going to mount our components, which means we're going to basically render them just like our
browser does.
But in a non browser environment, in a node environment where we can simulate the component as if it
exists and then test it without actually having to open up a browser page and see the resulting HTML.
So those are going to be our tools throughout the project, and that's really all there is to cover
in this lesson.
And the very next lesson we're going to start exploring the syntax of just.
All right.
Hopefully this has been helpful.
So I will see you in the next lesson.