Welcome to the next section of the course which is entitled Reactivity.
In this section, we're actually going to take a break from our big project, from our job search website,
and we're going to explore a lot of view reactivity, ideas in depth, especially as they pertain to
the composition API that was introduced in Vue three point out.
Now to give you a big picture overview, what the composition API gives us is a bunch of helper functions
from the View Library that allow us to emulate the same reactivity ideas that we've previously explored,
but do so outside the confines of a specific component.
So now we can use these functions in plain JavaScript files, for example, but get the same benefits
of view reactivity.
And so throughout the upcoming lessons, we are going to be writing code, we're going to be doing it
in our Playground Digest file, which is our scratch pad for just experimenting with ideas.
And we're going to see how we can incorporate existing view functions, but not necessarily within the
context of a web app.
So let's begin with an actual review of what reactivity is and how JavaScript doesn't necessarily capture
all of that, and how view can help us capture that concept of reactivity.
So what I actually have open here is a Google Sheets spreadsheet, and this is identical to a piece
of software like Excel on a Windows Machine or numbers if you're on a mac computer.
This is a basic spreadsheet software, and this is actually one of the best examples I've ever seen
of reactivity.
So what I'm going to do here is place a couple of values in a bunch of cells.
And if you have never played around with spreadsheet software, don't worry.
It's it's a pretty simple idea.
I'm sure you'll grasp it quickly in this cell right here on the top left corner cell a one.
I'm going to put the number one and in the cell to the right of it, I'm going to put another value,
which is two.
All right.
I'm just going to center these values right here, if I can, just so they're pretty easy for us to
see.
All right.
And in this cell right here, see one?
What I want to do is create a formula that's going to add the two numbers on the left hand side.
So the way we do this in a program like Google Sheets is we put an equal sign.
We use a function in Google sheets called sum.
And here we can specify the cells that we want to sum the values of.
So I'm going to click into cell A1, put a comma here and specify cell be one, closed my sum function
and we're going to get a value of three to be expected, right?
This is basic math.
Hopefully you're not learning this for the very first time, but here is where the reactivity element
of Google sheets comes into play.
If we look at this cell right here, it's actually maintaining this idea of a permanent connection to
cells A1 and B1.
It's not just the static, constant final value of three.
It's actually retaining the idea of the sum of the two cells to the left.
And thus, if I change any of these values, take a look at what's going to happen in cell C one.
So, for example, if I go to my cell and I decided to change this to eight, as soon as I press enter
to lock this value into the cell, you'll notice that my value in C1 changes to ten.
So what is going on here?
Well, the cell here has recalculated or reacted to the change here because it knows to watch for the
values in A1 and B1 and whenever either one of them changes, it re calculates the subsequent sum.
Right.
So similarly, if I go into cell B one and I make this four, you'll see this evaluate to 12.
Right?
This is an example of reactivity because our cell C1 is reacting to a change elsewhere.
It's reacting to an event, an occurrence of something somewhere else in the spreadsheet.
Right.
And when it comes to things like data analysis, this is super helpful because we don't have to go back
to cell C one and re execute it every time we have this dynamic calculation that automatically recalculate
whenever something happens.
It's a very similar idea to what we have with computed properties in view.
For example, many times throughout the course we've connected our computed properties to data properties
and we saw that whenever the data property changed, the computed property re-evaluated itself.
So these concepts again already exist in view and the composition API gives us more of an API, more
available functions to emulate those same ideas, but outside the scope of components by themselves.
All right.
So we're going to separate this idea of reactivity specifically from being connected to our view configuration
objects.
That's the core benefit of the view composition API.
So what I'd like to do now is the transition to the code, and I want to open our Playground Digest
file.
This is as a reminder, our little scratch pad or little experimental file where we just write code
to experiment with with various features of JavaScript and view.
And if you have any code in here, feel free to delete it.
We're going to start from scratch here.
I want to compare what we just saw in Google sheets with how JavaScript works.
So I'm going to open up my terminal here just so I can run a node file.
Right here, and let's write out some quick code.
So I'm going to declare a variable and I'm going to call it a and the reason I'm using a letter here
is because I intend to change the value of a in just a moment.
And just like we did in the spreadsheet, I'm going to make a equal to one and I'm going to have another
variable called B, which I'll make equal to two, and then I'll declare a variable C, which I'll make
equal to the sum of A plus B, and I'm going to console.log the value of C.
So as you might expect, when we run this file and we output the value of C, we're going to get the
sum of A and B, which is the sum of one and two.
So we're going to get the value three output, right?
So on initial first glance, this works exactly the same way as it does in the spreadsheet.
But actually what JavaScript does behind the scenes is it does not establish this relationship with
the C variable in terms of saying C is always going to be equal to whatever A and B is.
That's not how JavaScript works.
Instead, the way JavaScript works is it evaluates the right side of the equals sign first.
So it looks for the value of a in our program.
It knows that the a variable is equal to one.
It knows that the B variable is equal to two.
So it comes up with one plus two.
It evaluates the right side A to a dynamic or to a value of three, a final value of three, and it
assigns the variable C to three.
So once C is assigned to three, C doesn't have any kind of connection to the original values of A and
B and B were just placeholders for actual numbers.
So thus if I change, for example, my value A to eight and we console.log, the value of C C is not
going to change to reflect the value of eight plus three.
Now the new value of a plus, the existing value of B, it's not going to update.
Instead, it's going to be its original value at the time that C was assigned, which is three.
So if I re execute this code, we're going to see if the C variable is still equal to three online.
At number seven, the changing of either the A variable or even the B variable, none of this is going
to edit or alter the value of C.
So C is not reactive.
It is not reacting to the changes in A and B, because this syntax in JavaScript does not mean connect
C to the permanent idea of whatever A's plus whatever B is.
It just simply does a one time some of the present value of A plus the present value of B.
So that is the difference between vanilla JavaScript and what we just saw in Google Sheets and in the
upcoming lessons.
We're going to see how we can use some helper functions from the Use Composition API to start mimicking
that behavior, that reactivity that we just saw in Google Sheets.
So I'll see you there.