All right.
Welcome to the next section of the course, which is called View X.
View X is a library for managing global state.
In view, it is a separate NPM library, so it's not to be confused with the core view library, but
View X is still a part of the larger view ecosystem and is an important tool in your toolbox as a view
developer.
So before we dive into the details of what this library does for us, I first want to introduce the
problem that this library is trying to solve.
So why do we need View X?
Let's review some of the basics that we've learned about so far in this course view.
Applications consist of state, and state is simply the data that our components rely upon.
Right?
We've seen all kinds of examples of data.
Data can be booleans, strings, arrays, etc. and primarily it's data that changes over time.
And the whole point of state and that data is that we exploit vue's reactivity system, which means
when the state changes view updates, they view the corresponding HTML template.
A perfect example from the last section is we had an empty array of jobs, so we rendered no job listings.
Then as soon as we received the listings from the back end view interpreted that change to the components
state and it re rendered the component and then forced the rendering of those job listings.
Right.
That's the whole idea behind how view works.
Our view, our template is connected to the data, right?
Here's where we start to run into some problems.
Complexity creeps into an application when multiple components share a common state.
So let me give you a few examples.
One very common high level example that is cited is something like dark mode.
You may see a lot of modern apps where you can flick a button and the app goes into dark mode.
So it changes the entire look and feel of the app in just a second.
Right.
That's the kind of data that doesn't really belong to a single component.
It's much more higher level, it's much more global.
It has the opportunity to impact a lot of different components throughout the app, and thus it just
doesn't feel right that that piece of data should live in some random component somewhere in the app
that tries to communicate it elsewhere, it feels higher than that.
Another example is something like the app's language.
Let's say you are conditionally rendering text in a specific language depending on some kind of user
setting like the app may be in English or may be in Spanish or maybe in German.
Well, it feels weird, right?
If a single component like Imagine or main now stores a piece of state like user language, right?
It doesn't feel like the right place to store that kind of important detail because it's the kind of
details, the kind of state that may affect many different components throughout the app.
A third example that I can give you and one that is pertinent to our app, is you may remember that
when we were building out the main nav component, we built a piece of state called is logged in and
that reflects whether the user profile image appears on the top right of our app and of course our app.
And the idea of being logged in was only limited to that individual change.
But as you might imagine, in the real world, the user being logged in or not logged in is a pretty
significant piece of data that's probably going to affect a lot of different components and what renders
throughout the app.
It kind of feels weird to hold that piece of data in the main nav component.
The main nav is supposed to show you the navigation items.
Why does it know this big piece of information about the user's log in status?
Right.
So we have this problem where many different components need some kind of information that may also
be updating over time.
But neither of those components really feels like the right place to store that important, pertinent,
higher level, more global piece of information.
So the solution there is Vue X, what is Vue X?
View X is a state management library for Vue applications, which I know when you first hear it might
be a little bit complex, but the simple way to describe it is it's basically a library that's going
to be responsible for storing that higher level state, for storing that higher level data.
So let me give you the official definition from the View X documentation and then I'm going to show
you a visual that that hopefully will give you a better understanding, because a lot of this jargon
can be pretty technical.
So Vue Access Documentation states that the UX serves as a centralized store for the components in an
application with rules ensuring that the state can only be mutated in a predictable fashion.
And the first part I'd like you to focus on here is this centralized store.
So let me take you to a visual.
And this is the best way that I can sort of describe Vue to somebody.
I like to think of you as almost like a cloud of global data that is hovering or floating above our
view application.
All right.
And I don't want you to be confused with the idea of a cloud application, like I'm not talking about
AWP or Google Cloud or anything.
I'm just talking more in a poetic sense.
Just imagine this kind of cloud of data that is floating above our view application.
Right?
And any component that wants to get data or set data simply talks to that cloud.
Now, that doesn't mean that you can't use local state in a component.
You certainly can.
But that local state should really be limited to just that component.
If it's something pertinent to how that component operates and it doesn't affect anything else in the
app.
You can still use local components state, you can still use data, you can still use computed properties,
etc. But whenever you have data that is more higher level, that is, you know, more global, that
has the ability to impact multiple components, you sort of extract it to this cloud, this view X blob
of data, and then you connect components to it.
If you think about it, it's almost the simplest way to solve this problem right in this diagram.
Imagine that component and component D both need the same piece of data when that piece of data updates
both component and component D need to update.
Well, it's kind of silly to store the data just in component eight or just in component D or to duplicate
it, which is the worst idea, because then you create multiple sources of truth.
The simple solution when you when you have the dependency is to extract it outwards and just allow one
single source of truth that is independent and separate from those components.
And that's exactly what view is.
So you can almost imagine view X like you can almost think of it like a simple JavaScript object with
data.
And whenever that the data in that object updates and let's say the components are dependent on it,
all components are alerted of that change.
So if component A and rely on a piece of you x data, the changes that you access.
Component A My date has changed.
Please update yourself.
Component D My component my data has changed.
Right.
Component B can be relying on the cloud for something totally different.
Right?
You may need some other piece of data for view X and component C in this example may not need any global
data.
Maybe it doesn't care about that global information like let's say the dark mode or the user's log in
status.
Maybe it's something simple like a button and it doesn't care.
So not every component has to connect to view X, not every component has to read or write from you
x, some can.
Some can get all of the information from The View Store.
Some can get partial information.
The point is, we've just extracted that global information to another separate entity in our app,
in our ecosystem, and then components talk to it in order to get that global data that it cares about.
Now as far as the other part of the definition, which is a the state can only be mutated in a predictable
fashion, all that basically means is that we put constraints as far as how we can change the data within
the View X Store, right?
So that we can't just update it however we want.
We can't just say add this property, delete this property.
We have to define the possible operations as far as how we can write the data.
And the benefit of that is that it allows us to have predictable changes so that components can know
that there is a subset of actions that can happen that can update them.
Basically, we're just putting constraints and boundaries on what can happen to the data in our app
to ensure that there's no errors encountered by accidentally deleting properties, adding properties,
changing them to something that they can't be, etc..
We'll talk more about that later.
But that's basically that definition is trying to say, so what are the benefits of UCS?
Well, one benefit is that we separate the data manipulation from the view.
So a lot of times a lot of those complex data manipulations, operations, filters, etc., we can move
that to the View store and the components will simply receive the final data and do something with it.
So the components become what are called dumb components.
They don't really care about where they're getting the data from or how it's calculated.
They just know how to render it visually in the HTML.
And that is a good component because it's simpler, it's lightweight, it's easier to test.
So view exists independently of the components.
It's a separate data store, so it can also be unit tested by itself.
It doesn't need components.
It doesn't have to know which components it is connected to or how many components it is connected to.
It's just its own blob of state, blob of data and with certain methods available that are going to
update that data in predictable ways.
Right?
We don't actually even need a view app technically in order to test view X because it's just a library
for managing a piece of state and updating it over time, right?
That's all it is.
We're just connecting components to it so that they can react to those changes in their own components.
Right.
So who makes view X?
View X is maintained by the Core View team.
That's one of my favorite features about it, because it integrates well with view, because it's built
specifically for view applications.
So in other ecosystems like React, for example, I love React, don't get me wrong, but there's no
official recommendation for what state management library you're supposed to use with with React.
So a common choice in that community is Redux, which follows very similar principles to view X.
But Redux is still not developed by the core react.
In comparison, the View team says, hey, state management is a common problem in modern single page
applications.
So we're going to give you this tool that works really well with view.
You don't have to use view checks at all if you don't want global state management.
There are still other solutions in the ecosystem or in the NPM marketplace if you want to try something
else.
But View X is still a really good solution with the support of the core of your team.
And of course, because it's being made by the same people, it just syncs up and works really well
together.
All right.
So I'm going to show you all the benefits of UX over time.
And we're going to start out by just using it in isolation separate from many components so you can
get to get a sense of how exactly it's supposed to work.
So I'm really excited.
I know slide decks are pretty boring, but we're going to get back to the code in the very next section
and we're going to see what makes Vue so special.