Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to talk about fallback content for our slots.
So earlier on, you may recall that I mentioned that if we do not provide any content in the parent
component to be rendered in our slot, then the component will simply ignore it.
So in other words, here we have an accordion where we are providing some sample slot content, this
paragraph.
And if I provide nothing between the opening and closing accordion tags, then viewers are simply going
to say, You didn't give me anything.
So right here where it's expecting slot content, it's literally going to put nothing because the parent
component didn't give it anything.
Right.
So that's something we talked about earlier.
And let me return this back to the original implementation.
Now, what we can do here, where we actually define this slot component is we can write some sample
HTML to use, but only to use if the parent component does not give us custom slot content.
Sunny, write this out and I promise you it's going to make immediate sense.
So in my accordion component, within my opening and closing slot component right here, I'm going to
add a sample paragraph tag.
This can be whatever time all we want.
And I'm going to say something like, whoops, somebody forgot to populate me.
So what am I doing here?
What I am specifying is content to render within my slot if and only if my parent does not give me any
slot content.
So on the left hand side, in our job filter sidebar, I want you to compare this accordion and this
accordion right here in that very first accordion.
We do not provide any slot content.
We do not nest any H10.
All right.
Here, between my opening and my closing accordion component tag, thus because we do not provide any
slot content view will fall back to this default of this paragraph tag with this text.
It will only use this if there is no slot content provided by the parent.
In comparison, when we render this accordion below this organization's accordion, we do provide slot
content.
So View will use this slot content right here.
It's going to completely ignore this paragraph tag and it's going to put this content right here.
So I went a little bit crazy here.
It's going to put this div right here are slot content directly where this paragraph targets.
So again, this will only render if and only if the parent does not provide any slot content.
That's all there is to it.
So if I go back to my browser.
We're going to see.
We did not provide any slot content here.
So what do we get?
We get that paragraph tag that we declared in my accordion component here.
We did provide slot content, so we see exactly what we specified.
So it's a way that we can provide a reasonable default to fall back to in case you want some default
content for the slot.
In case the parent doesn't give me anything, I'm going to use this value.
You may notice that we have a very similar idea when it comes to props.
Right.
We can provide a default value for a prop where if the parent component doesn't give me a prop value,
I can fall back or rely on a reasonable default.
It's the exact same principle, but using HTML content to specify the slots fallback content.
All right.
So to finish up this lesson, let me show you a couple examples side by side.
I'm going to return back to my original implementation here.
I'm going to have a paragraph with the text placeholder for now.
And above job types, I'm going to create yet another accordion.
And for this accordion, I'm actually going to use a self-closing tag.
Why am I going to do this?
I'm going to do this because if I have no slot content right here, I don't actually have a need to
use an open and closing tag at all.
Right.
So in this situation, I need an opening and closing accordion tag because the content that goes in
between becomes my slot content.
If I have no slot content like I have here, then I'm welcome to use a regular self-closing accordion
component.
Granted, I still have to give it a header.
Props.
So let me give it give it a header here of degree.
But these are all valid ways that we can use our accordion and the slot content within it.
We can render a self-closing component if we don't want to provide any slot content.
In which case we're going to fall back to this approach right here.
And as far as these next two accordions, because we are providing different content for each one,
this content is going to win over our fallback content here.
So these two are going to have their respective HTML so in the browser.
Just to make sure we understand only for a degree are we going to use the fallback for job types in
organizations that we're going to have their own custom content that we specify in the parent.
All right.
So lots of flexibility that Vue gives us.
So that is fallback content for slots.
And I will see you in the next lesson.