All right, so let's make our failing tests pass.
I'm going to drag this terminal window down just a little bit, and I'm going to open up my sub nav
test alongside my sub nav component.
There is my implementation on the left.
And what do we need to do?
Well, the first thing we need to do is to make sure we have the correct data property available.
So right here, I'm going to create a data method and that is going to return an object as always.
This specifies the data for the component, and I'm just going to copy the exact property we expect
to have here on the job results page.
And I'm going to start it off with a starter value of true just because I need some place to start.
Obviously, we're not going to have any way to change this.
And in the real world, we have to find a way to make this change as the user navigates from page to
page.
The browser and view should automatically figure this out.
But again, we don't know how to do that yet, so let's just pretend we have this property and it's
somehow been calculated and once we have it, we can use it in our template.
Let me actually shrink the size of this so we can see everything perfect.
And if we see here, we have this top level div that is encapsulating the font awesome icon as well
as the actual number of jobs matched.
And if you look at the Google Careers Web page, both of them are hidden whenever the user is not on
the job search results page or in other words, they are only present when the user is on the job results
page.
So when this is equal to true, so what we can do is add AVF here.
This will make this bit of HTML and all of its children only conditionally render.
And we're going to connect that to which property to our on job results page property.
So only if this is true.
In other words, only if the user is on the job results page do we want to render this logic right here.
So that is a good first step.
But that, of course, is not going to be enough because our tests are still looking for this data.
Test attribute on something in our template so that I can find it and make sure it is present.
So what we want to do is add our data test attribute right here.
And of course, I have to give it the expected value, which is job count.
So once again, this entire div will only render if the V.F. evaluates the true.
So in our very first test, it's only going to be able to find a valid job count element if it's able
to find that date of test attribute.
And it's only going to be able to find that that test attribute if we if has something that is true.
Because otherwise the way view is going to see this component is basically like this.
It's not going to see it at all.
It's going to be blank for from the test perspective.
And thus the first test is going to fail.
But now it's going to correctly find the job can attribute if the VFW it's the true which it will in
this case, because we are manually specifying that the data property on job results page is such a
true.
So this should get both tests to pass.
And indeed, if we look down here, it does.
However, we run into an issue which we saw in the previous lesson, and this is actually coming from
multiple tests, both our sub nav test and our main nav test.
And that is that our tests don't know what this font awesome icon is, right?
Because remember, there's going to be at least one test in this case.
It's the sub nav one right here where we are indeed going to render the div with the job match.
In fact, I misspoke.
Forgive me, it's going to be this one right here.
Whenever we have the sub nav being rendered and we have the job results being rendered, those job results
are using something called the font awesome icon global component.
But within our test ecosystem, as we're testing this, the tests don't know about our bigger picture
view app that we configured in main that yes, from the test perspective, we are mounting this sub
nav component in isolation.
So the tests have no clue about what font awesome icon is here.
And that's exactly what the message here is.
It's a warning.
It's not a failure, but it's a warning that says, hey, I failed to resolve this component that you're
using.
Font Awesome icon.
You are referencing some kind of component named font awesome icon, but I can't figure out what it
is.
Right.
And that makes sense because again, our tests are separate from our main view app where we've registered
the font awesome icon as a global component.
So we're going to talk about how to fix this problem in the upcoming lessons.