Okay.
So let's attach some query params to our job search form on the home page when the user submits it.
So I'm going to open up the job search form component.
As a reminder, this is where we build out the form that has the two input fields for the role and the
location and then the action button to submit.
And finally, it's storing the data that actually keeps track of the user's entered value for those
two input fields.
In these role and location data properties, so as a quick and obvious review view allows us to build
single page applications.
That means that we want to avoid complete page refreshes.
The goal is to give the user whatever JavaScript they need upfront and give them a seamless experience
by loading in information as they need it without forcing a complete page refresh.
Right.
And that's why the View Library gives us tools to prevent refreshes.
So by default.
Back in the old school web days before single page web apps, whenever you submitted a form that would
either reload the page or direct to a new page based on that form submission.
But we don't actually want that to happen.
We don't want the form to reload the page or take us anywhere else because that will force a refresh
or a reload of the entire view app.
So what we need to do is we need to react to the form being submitted but prevent the browser from actually
going with its natural flow and navigating the browser to a new page.
Right.
And I'll show you how to do that.
So we want to react to an event.
That event is a form submission.
Whenever you think about reacting to an event in view, you should always think about the VON Directive,
right?
Previously we used that directive to react to a button, click to a user typing a character into an
input field.
Those are all events.
Those are all examples of user interaction.
A user clicking a button to submit a form is also an example of an event.
It's a form submission event.
So we want to react to this event and it's actually going to come from our form.
So we're going to put it on our form h HTML element.
So right here we can either use the V on syntax or you may recall the shortcut is the app sign and then
we follow it up with the actual event that the browser will tell us.
So when a form is submitted, it emits an event called submit.
So that's what I want to react to.
But if we simply do this, as I mentioned, we're going to force the page navigation or the page refresh.
So there is a special syntax we can do here to prevent the browser from doing that.
And that is going to be a dot followed by prevent.
Okay.
So what this is called is an event modifier in view.
And the name kind of makes sense because submit is an event and this is a modifier which means it modifies
or changes or affects how that event works.
So it's still a submission event, but we are modifying it to prevent it from forcing that page reloading
or that page navigation.
And as far as the name Prevent, it's nice and short and sweet, really.
You know, if they went with something like Prevent, you know, page refresh, it would have been a
lot longer.
But that's why it's called Prevent, because it's preventing that natural form submission action from
happening.
We're still going to get the submit event.
We're still going to react to it by providing a method in just a second.
But we're going to prevent that browser page refresh, and that is why we need that event modifier.
So if you recall the VON Directive, what we provide, it is an equal sign and then the name of a method
in the double quotes and will define that method on our methods.
Object below in the JavaScript section of the component.
So let's call this method search for jobs, since that is fundamentally what the user means when they
click the submit the form.
So I'm going to navigate all the way down.
To hear.
And of course we want to define a methods property, honor, view, configuration, object, and we
need a method name that matches what we just wrote.
So that is going to be a search for jobs.
And so when the user submits the form, we're going to prevent a page refresh and we're going to instead
invoke this method.
Okay, so what do we want to do in this method?
We want to navigate the user to the job results view, and we also want to attach the role and location
from the data as query params so that the job results view has that information and can use it to filter
the relevant jobs.
So how do we navigate the user from a JavaScript perspective?
While you may recall that we have a router object and that router object has a push method.
So what I can do here is access that router object on my this keyword.
And of course that property begins with a dollar sign dollar sign router.
That again is a view detail.
It's the dollar sign is not technically relevant, it's just part of the name to differentiate it from
your own data and properties, etc. So that is the object.
That object is the same view router that we defined in our router index DSL.
And that object has a method called push.
Push navigates the user to a new URL you can even see in the description on the right programmatically
navigate to a new URL.
So we're going to invoke this method.
And as you may recall, it actually takes a variety of arguments.
We can give it a string, we can give it an object.
Let's go with the object approach.
So we'll provide a JavaScript object and there is a property we can provide called name and we could
set name equal to the name of a route.
So I'm going to go back to my router index that she has found and I want to go with this route name
job results right here to go to the job results page.
So it's going to put this right here and make sure we wrap it in double quotes.
And I think that is more stable and more reliable than providing a path or a URL because the path or
URL is more likely to change than the name of the route.
So this is a good place to start and this is what we did earlier in the course.
But how do we attach the query params to that URL?
Well, luckily for us if you can do it automatically so we do not need to create the concatenated string
with the dollar sign and the ampersand, the equal signs, all of that complexity of you can take care
of for us.
But we do need to provide a key here called query.
And for that property we provide a JavaScript object and the way it works is the key value pairs or
the properties in this object is what view will will combine together to attach as query params to the
end of this path, this URL.
So for example, if I want a query param of role as my key as my property, I simply provide role.
And then the value that I want to attach to that key will of course, the value that I want to attach
to that key is going to come from my data property of role, which I can access via the this keyword.
So this role will give me the role which is whatever the user has entered into that input fields at
that moment of form submission, I'm going to attach that as the value for that query parameter role
so this name can be entirely up to us, but I see no reason to keep it different from what we have in
this component.
That way it's the same terminology around the app.
So this will attach the role.
And the other thing that I want to attach to my query params is the location that the user searched
for.
So we'll add another property here of location and then of course that will be equal to whatever the
user has entered for the location input which were storing in the location data property which we can
access by this dot location.
All right.
And that is it.
Whenever the user submits a form, the form will emit an event called submit.
We're going to react to it by preventing it from forcing a page reload.
We're going to tell you to invoke the search for jobs method.
The search for jobs method is going to use the route or object to navigate the user to a new path and
new yourself are going to tell it to go to the route called job results and we're going to tell it to
attach to query params.
Role and location.
And you is going to create that necessary strength.
Let's take a look at this.
In the browser, we're going to navigate to our app and here we are and let's go ahead and type view
developer and let's say I want to look for that job in New York.
So I'm going to click the search button and here we go.
We do not have this page built out yet, but if we look at our URL, take a look.
We are indeed add slash job slash results.
That is great.
And notice at the very end we have that exact same familiar syntax.
We have the question mark, we have the key where the property, which is role, and then we have the
value which is view developer.
And this scenario notice that it's using a plus sign instead of the percentage time sign.
Don't worry about that.
That's just another internal detail of you.
It works either way.
And so we have attached the role key right here and we've also attached the location key right here.
And notice that that value is New York.
So viewers taking care of the creation of this string.
Here's the question mark.
Here is the key.
The equals sign, the separation of the spaces and the ampersand to separate the subsequent key value
params.
So it took care of everything for us.
All we needed to do was provide a object with a query property to that push method and it took care
of that for us.
Now, obviously we don't have any jobs on this page yet, so we can't filter it using our query params.
But we have set up everything we need to later in order to do that and we will do that later in the
course.
So with that, we are going to proceed to the next couple of lessons where we're going to test what
we just built out.