All right.
So this is going to be a quick lesson.
What I'd like to do in this lesson is add another brand color to our tailwind dot config case file,
so tailwind can generate some additional CC classes for us.
So let me open up my tailwind dot config that JS file.
As a reminder here we have our colors, which tailwind will use to generate things like font classes
and background color classes, etc..
And what we need to add here is another blue color because our secondary version of the button which
we saw is applied in the search form.
Whenever you hover your mouse over it, it's going to show a blue background.
And that blue background is a different blue color than the one we have here represented by brand a
blue one.
So I need to add that color and it's going to be the same process right below here.
I'm going to add a new key.
I'm going to call it brand blue, too.
It's another blue color that our brand uses.
And the hexadecimal code for it is going to be the hashtag and followed by 42, 80 5f4.
We can see that blew up here right there.
And I'm going to add a comma to the end here and save the file.
If you experience any kind of issues with something that working in the following lessons, just remember
you can restart your review app here usually, so you can cancel that process by pressing something
like Control D or Control C, I forget which one it is.
It's one of those combinations.
And then restarting the app using the command and pin reserve, and that will re-evaluate and re-import
these tailwind settings and tailwind will again regenerate those new CSS classes that you can then use
within your view components.
So now that we have this new brand blue to color, we can use it to model our secondary styles for the
button.
So I will see you and we will do that in the very next lesson.