Okay.
So in this lesson, let's add a test suite for our new job filter sidebar skills component.
So right here in tests unit, I'm going to find my components folder and job results and job filter
sidebar and I will create a new test file called Job Filter Sidebar Skills.
Dot test.
That's.
There we go.
And since this component is not rendering any child components, I think we're going to be okay with
a shallow amount.
So I'm going to begin by importing shallow amount that is going to come from you test utils.
Then we are utilizing our use store computed function right here from view export.
I meant composable function from view.
And we're going to need to mock it out.
So I am going to import it and immediately mock it out.
So right here, import, use store.
And that's going to come from view.
Then on the line below, I'm going to use just mock to mock up.
And finally, for typescript sake, I'm going to define a used or mock constant, which will be the
use store function now a just function, but properly treated as indeed a just mock function.
Then I'm going to import the actual component under test.
So right here we're going to import job filters, sidebar skills.
And that's going to come from the source directory components, job results, job filter, sidebar,
job filter, sidebar skills.
And then I'm going to add the view extension.
Then I'll create my described block for job filters.
Sidebar skills.
And then we can think about what we wanted to test here.
So the first thing that I want to test is the connection between the video store and my input.
I really want to test the read functionality, which is really this section right here, the Gap method
that accesses the state property Honor View Store, and then more specifically the skills search term
property and then connects it to my input.
So what I want to set up in my first test is a mock return value for use store that's going to return
an object like this.
And I want to make sure that whatever is on this property is what I can find populated in my input element.
So right here, I'll begin with the test description.
The component populates search input from store.
So we're going to take our store, Mark, and we are, of course, going to provide a mock return value
to overwrite just default of undefined.
And this is going to be an object.
And there's two things we need to support.
We need to support the get method logic right here and the set method logic right here.
So in order forget to be able to work our store right here, which we are returning, must have a state
property.
And that is going to be an object and that internal object is going to have a skills search term property.
So right here.
I'm going to add skill search term and I could set it to be whatever string I want.
Let's just go with something like programmer.
Then in order for my set method to be able to work, I need to make sure that my mock store right here
supports a commit method because I'm going to invoke commit whenever the user types.
So right here I'm going to provide commit.
And I'm just going to set it to a basic just function.
Now, technically speaking, if we don't directly interact with our input, our set logic may never
run and thus we may be able to get away with leaving out line 15.
But it kind of makes sense to put it, and I think it sort of makes me feel a little safer knowing that
all of the mock properties that the store needs are satisfied, even if this specific test is not going
to rely on this one right here.
All right.
So we're honoring this contract right here, and thus our mock store is good enough to play the role
of our real view store.
All right.
The next step, of course, is mounting our component.
So right here, content wrapper is going to be shallow, mounting our job builder sidebar scale's component.
And then the next thing I want to do is actually find my input right here.
So I'm going to find it by using my data test attribute.
So right here I'm going to say skills search input is going to be the invocation of wrapper find and
I'm going to pass a string argument.
I'm going to look for an attribute called data test.
And of course the value I provide to look for is up to us.
Let's just call it skills search input.
Of course, that does not exist just yet, but that's not a problem.
And then what the test utils is going to do is it's going to find this input as a DOM node and in order
to actually test that its value has been populated, what I basically to do is go to the actual HTML
element that is found within that DOM note.
Basically this goes back to kind of vanilla JavaScript in the browser.
We don't have the core value here.
We have the entire input object and I need to actually reach into that DOM node and extract the actual
core HTML element.
Basically what I'm going to do here is declare a concept called input element.
An on skill search input, which is going to be that view wrapper.
On that.
I have a property called element.
An element is going to be that actual input itself, this thing right here.
All right.
Now, TypeScript has no clue what we're working with here.
So it knows that it's going to get some kind of element.
But it can be any HTML element in the world.
It can be an input, it can be a paragraph, it can be a list item.
Right.
So in order to tell TypeScript what this is, so it knows what properties it supports, I'm going to
use the as keyword, the exact same thing we're using here.
And I'm going to tell TypeScript that I know something it does not that this is an H to not input element.
So right here this is a built in type into it built into TypeScript.
I can simply say this will be an HTML input element and there's a whole bunch of these defined in the
documentation for things like HTML image element.
Let's go down here.
They're going to be a whole bunch of other ones.
HTML paragraph element, I'm sure basically a here html i element html input element, H2 time a label
element.
Right.
So within the internals of TypeScript, it has all these preexisting types for those DOM nodes that
it can find in the browser.
And now we're explicitly telling TypeScript that this is not just a regular HTML element.
Please try type as specifically being of an input element, and that is what allows us to take that
input element and extract a special property on it called value.
Value is going to be the property on the input that actually represents what is currently entered into
that input box.
So once again, we're starting from the view wrapper around the DOM node.
We're getting that DOM node itself, which is the HTML input element.
And then from that DOM object representing an HTML input element or getting its value, which is the
text that is entered into the input right now.
And of course, what we expect is the value that is populated here should be the exact same value that
the input has.
Read it from my view store.
This is this logic right here.
So if everything is wired up correctly, we expect this to be the string programmer.
All right.
So whatever we provide here is exactly what the input should have inside it.
So of course this test will fail because we do not have the data test actually.
So let's go up and right here on my input, I'm going to provide that to test and then provide the exact
value that my test expects, which is skills, search input.
So that should allow my test to find this element rabbit interview wrapper object, then get the actual
domino, then get the value property on that object and that is indeed equal to the string programmer.
And our test is passing.
We can see right here that if I change it to something differently, like programmers, we're going
to see a failure.
And that's the failure we expect, which is just telling us, Hey, you told me to expect programmer,
but instead I'm receiving programmers.
So that is verifying that just end the component are correctly reading from this slice of the view store
state, which we have provided using a mock storm.
All right.
So I'm going to return this back to a passing test, and that is all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see the next one.