All right.
So in this lesson, I'd like to add one quality of life improvement for our user.
You'll notice that when we navigate to a page, for example, if I scroll down here and click next,
we sort of end up at the very bottom of the page, right?
And I think it'd be a really nice user experience if we scored automatically to the very top of the
next page of job results.
So the user could start with the top job on that page, right?
Because that way they can go through this batch of ten jobs and if they don't like what they see and
they go to the next page, we can immediately take them to the very top of their search results instead
of keeping them at the very bottom.
And as it turns out, this functionality is actually baked into view router.
Super simple to do.
So I'm going to head back to this code and I'm actually going to go into my router index dot gas file.
So my index not just file in my router folder.
Here is where we set up all of our routes and our lazy loading and things like that.
But you'll notice at the very bottom we are setting up our actual view router with this create router
function and we are exporting the router that it creates for us.
So what I can do in this setup object we only have to do it once is define a method called scroll behavior
and that is exactly as it sounds.
It specifies how the router is going to behave in regards to scrolling whenever there is a change in
route.
And the way this method works is we can actually return an object and that object is sort of like a
configuration object for these scrolling behavior.
So the way it works is we provide properties here that specify where we want to scroll to whenever we
have a change in route and whenever we change our query params, by the way, that counts as a change
in route.
We're still at the same slash jobs slash results page, but we are changing something about the route
and that is still considered to be a route change by view router.
So this logic will still run.
So if I wanted to go to the very top of my view, what I can do is provide two properties here, top
and left, and I can set them both to zero.
So this specifies where I want to scroll relative to the top and left of my screen.
So what I'm saying is zero pixels from the top and zero pixels from the left.
So basically I'm telling a view router to scroll automatically to the very top and to the very left,
right.
So basically to the top of the page as far as we're concerned.
All right.
And I found this, by the way, on the official view router documentation.
That's where we can find the documentation and some examples for how this works.
There's one more property I'd like to define here.
It's just going to be a customization property called Behavior, and I'm going to provide it with a
string of smooth that just ensures that it kind of almost has this animation effect where it gradually
and gracefully scrolls up instead of immediately taking the user within like a split second to the top,
which just gives the user a little less of a jarring experience.
It just looks like a more smooth, gentle scroll to the top instead of immediately taking them there.
That's what we're customizing with this behavior property.
So I'm going to go to the browser and test this out, and if it doesn't work, that's totally fine.
I recommend that you restart your view app, your view service in case it doesn't work.
But let's try it out and see if it automatically registers.
So as I scroll to the bottom, I'm on page three and I'm going to navigate to the next page by clicking
next and beautiful.
You just saw that it automatically scroll to the very top.
Let's try that in reverse.
So if I go to the previous page, you'll see it's going to scroll me all the way back to the top.
That's great.
One more time with previous.
Gracefully scroll to the top one more time with next perfect.
In fact, as we navigate to any page in our app, we're going to have this scroll behavior because we
set it up specifically for the entire view, rather, not just for any specific page, right?
So I think this definitely improves the experience and the you actually the UI for the user and we can
continue again chipping away at more functionality in the very next lesson.