Okay.
So now we are back inside our main nav component.
And the next thing that I want to show you how to do is how to connect our view instance data, our
JavaScript, in other words, to our template, to our HTML.
So what we can do inside our script tag is define certain pieces of data that are going to be available
to use within our HTML.
And the beautiful part about that design is the reactivity.
When our data changes, Vue will automatically update the corresponding h html.
So let's take a look at this in action in my configuration object for this component.
Right now we only have a single property called Name.
What I want to add here is a new method called data.
So this method name is not up to us.
It is a view requirement.
At this call data.
It's going to be a method that does not accept any parameters right now.
And here we're going to provide the curly braces to define the method.
And all this method is going to to do is return a plain JavaScript object.
So I'm going to return a JavaScript object right here.
And in this object, the properties that we define will be available to be added or injected or interpolated
whatever word you want to use.
We're going to have these keys available to reference within our HTML template.
So for example, right now on our screen, we only have a single bit of text which is Bobo Careers.
I would like to be able to define bubble careers as some kind of JavaScript data piece, a piece of
information that lives with our JavaScript and have you be responsible for taking that piece of data
and rendering it onto the screen so we do not have to manually type out Bobo careers.
So right here, let's say I have a property called the company and I'm going to set its value to Bobo
careers.
So what we're doing here in our configuration object is configuring any kind of data that this component
may need.
And this data can be anything.
It can be strings, it can be numbers, it can be arrays, it can be data that we get from the API.
It can be data that we, for example, me read off a disk somewhere.
The point is that we have some kind of piece of information, some data that is living in JavaScript.
And now I want to bind that data to the view.
I want to connect some piece of data to my actual HTML.
All right.
So obviously, the goal here is clear.
I want to replace Bobo Careers with some reference to this piece of information that I have called company.
So you might think that we might be able to get away with writing something like company here.
That, of course, will not work.
If I go back to my browser.
What we are instead going to see is the literal word company, right?
And that's why we can't just arbitrarily reference anything within our view, because view does not
know that we want to reference something specifically called company inside our data.
So how can we make that connection between our configuration object and our HTML?
We use a special syntax in view that consists of two curly braces before and after what we want to inject
into our timeout.
So right here I'm going to add to a opening pair of a curly braces and then a closing pair of curly
braces.
And the way it works is like this.
Any single property that we have in the object that we returned from our data method that is available
to use in our HTML.
So in other words, company is available to use within these curly braces too.
Right here.
I'm going to right company.
I'm going to save this file and I'm going to navigate back to the browser.
And we can see that Bobo Careers has appeared.
So we have bound the data from our JavaScript, from our view configuration to our HTML to our DOM.
This feature is called interpolation.
I just want to show you here the difference between how this appears in view and how it will appear
within our web page.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to bring up my developer tools and I'm going to go to my view dev
tools right here, and we can navigate into our main nav component.
Previously, when we clicked into any component, we didn't see anything on the right hand side because
none of our components had data.
They only had a name property, which by the way, corresponds to what we see right here.
The reason we see it labeled as main nav right here is because we gave this component a name property
of Main NAV within that view file.
That's why it's important to give each component a name.
And once I click into my main nav will be able to see its data right here on the screen.
So we can see that the company property belonging to the main NAV component has a value of bubble careers.
And that is what is rendering onto the screen.
And here's the beautiful part about view.
If I change the data, which I can do right here through the view, dev tools view and its whole responsibility
is to track those changes and react to them.
So if we've told the HTML to always render the value of the company property, if the company property
changes, then the view will also update to reflect that.
So if I change this to, for example, something else, and then I click this little diskette to save.
Lo and behold, as our view component date has changed, so has our actual representation on the page,
and that is the core of what view does for us and allows us to configure JavaScript and business logic
within a programming language and have view.
Take care of rendering any of those differences and changes to our HTML in a variety of different ways.
Here, it's literally outputting some text to the screen, but there's other ways that we can use this
to customize attributes, conditional components, appearing all kinds of different ways that we can
leverage the power of JavaScript and then have you take care of the actual visual results of that within
our template, right?
So that is what it looks like from the view side of the world.
However, if I go to my Elements tab and I click into here, we'll see that something else is written
in line right here.
So from the browsers perspective, the browser has no clue what Vue is doing for us.
The browser just sees an anchor tag that has the text of something else rendered inside it.
So Vue just injects the right content and takes care of that, and our browser has no clue about Vue
or whatever frontend library we happen to be using.
It just sees the final regular HTML and JavaScript that it knows how to parse and understand.
All right, that's the conversion that Vue takes care of for us.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.