Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we used the V model directive to connect our checkbox input to a local piece
of component data called selected organizations.
And if we go back long enough, way back in the course when we introduced the idea v model, remember,
what V model is doing for us is it's abstracting away a little bit of the complexity of working with
an input.
We can manually set up the logic of a V model using a couple other syntax options in view, but the
model makes it super simple.
It abstracts away the complexity of reacting to the browser's change event, and as a reminder, the
browser emits a change event whenever the user interacts with an input component.
So the model is basically just a layer above that.
It's an abstraction that hides away the complexity of capturing the browsers event and then saving it
to a local piece of data and then also making that direction a bi directional meaning.
Data Effects Template Template Effects Data.
However, just because we have a V model directive A doesn't prevent us from actually adding our own
event handler manually reacting to a change event and doing some additional logic whenever the user
interacts with an input.
And that's exactly what we need to do in this scenario because unfortunately, as as great as the model
is, it's still connected to local data in our component.
And we're going to need to find a way to get this data to view X because view X is the place where we
actually have our 100 jobs, and that is the collection of jobs that we're going to need to filter based
on the organizations that the user has selected.
Right.
Right now, this data is kind of scoped or bound or limited to this component.
So in here, it has no way of interacting with view X.
So we're going to need to communicate with View X and we're going to need to do that in a method and
we're going to need to update view X, obviously, whenever the user makes a change.
So if the user updates a checkbox, we need to tell that to the U.S. If the user selects another checkbox,
we need to react again, right?
As many times as the user interacts with a checkbox, we need to talk to the U.S., so we need to add
a event handler to our input component.
As a reminder, the way this works in view is we use a special directive called V on we provide a colon
and then the event that we want to react to.
In this case, I want to react to a change event.
And again, a change event is an event that occurs whenever the user interacts with an input in, in
any way.
So in regards to a checkbox, it means checking it, I'm checking it, etc. The way the syntax works
is we provide an equal sign and in double quotes we provide the name of a method for view to execute
whenever this event occurs.
So what I'm going to do here is define a method called select organization.
And of course this method does not yet exist.
But we're going to write it out in just a few moments in the methods object below.
But for now we're going to say, have you whenever a change event occurs on that change event, please
run this select organization method.
The reason we're getting an excellent violation here is because there is a shorthand syntax to do this
in view and that is replacing the VON Directive and the colon with an ADD sign.
It's still actually the vision directive behind the scenes.
There is no technical difference between the two.
Syntax is this one is just a little bit shorter.
The key idea remains the same.
We're telling view whenever a change event occurs, please run a select organization.
So with that we can scroll down below and we can define our methods.
Object right here.
And since we called our Method Select Organization above, we have to obviously call it select our organization
here as well.
So this is the method that you will run whenever the user interacts with a checkbox in any way.
We're still going to utilize the V model functionality, so Vue is still going to use the model to populate
the selected organization's array.
Here is where we're going to do some additional logic on top of that.
What I want to show you in this lesson is that we actually have the selected organization's data array.
It's going to be automatically updated by the time this method runs.
So in other words, our V model logic is going to run first.
And I want to show you that because I want to demonstrate that we're going to have our selected organizations
array populated with the values we care about, populated with the organization strings that we want
to send to our View X Store.
So for now, I just want to console.log this that selected organizations.
Remember every data property is available on the component via the this keyword.
I'm just logging out the value of the array as it currently is.
All right, so I'm going to save this and I'm going to transition to my browser.
And I'm going to refresh this page.
And here is my console.
And I want to show you what happens when I choose a checkbox.
We're going to click a checkbox, which means that we're going to trigger a change event, which means
we're going to run this select organization method that we justified, and we're going to see that output
in our console.
So here it is.
And you might be a little bit surprised because it's a proxy object rather than an array object.
But remember, the data structure that we provide to view is not the end of the line.
View needs to take that data structure and wrap it with additional functionality to enable the reactivity
right to connect it to our template and automatically update the template.
So in order to build the logic that watches for change, it needs to wrap our core data structure,
in this case, an array in this proxy object.
So basically to sum it up, this is an implementation detail, a view.
It is an array under the hood, but it's wrapped in a special helper object around it that adds extra
functionality.
However, we can still see that YouTube is present within this proxy object.
That means that we are console.log in that array.
We are seeing that it is storing the value that we care about.
And similarly, if I select another one like point of view, we can see that that proxy object updates
to have these two elements.
In fact, I think the numbers here represent the arrays index position.
So if YouTube in point of view are here and then if I remove YouTube, that's still an interaction,
that's still a change in that.
That's still going to run my select organization method.
So we're going to see that that output updates that just have the one that's selected.
So the key takeaway is whenever this method runs, our array is already going to store the most up to
date collection of organization strings.
And we want to take that array of organization strings and ship it off to the U.S., because as soon
as this change occurs right here, the U.S. needs to get the data and then run its filter logic to filter
its 100 jobs to only the ones that are going to have the organizations listed here.
So obviously, when we select point of view, we only want to see jobs on the right hand side that belong
to the point of view organization.
These jobs live in view X, so we're going to need to send a message to say, Hey, view X, you're
responsible for displaying these jobs, you're storing this data.
I'm going to need you to filter these 100 jobs based on this new selection of point of view.
And later on, if somebody selects view can do it, we need to once again send a message to view X to
say, Hey, the user now has two organizations point of view, and if you can do it, this is your new
array of true values.
Please use it to again filter what you see on the right hand side.
Because remember, every time the user interacts, every single time they select or select, we want
to automatically re render the right hand side to show only the jobs that fit that search criteria.
All right.
So now we've wired up a basic method that's going to run on every event.
And the next lesson, we're going to talk about how we can start connecting it to View X.