Okay.
So there's one more composable function left for us to migrate to TypeScript and it is used at previous
and next pages.
So let's open up that file right here.
Let's immediately change its extension to T.S. and on the right hand side, I will open up the corresponding
test file as well.
And that's going to be used previous index pages that test that.
Yes.
And since we have it open, let's also go ahead and change its extension to T.S. as well.
All right.
So as a reminder of how this works are use previous and next pages composable function accepts two parameters
current page and Max page and TypeScript cannot figure out what their types are.
And these are actually the view reactive objects.
They are the view reactive objects that have a value property on them.
You can see right here we are accessing current pages on value and right here we are accessing max page
value.
Now notice in our test we were able to get away with much simpler JavaScript objects that simply had
a value property rather than using the complete view reactive object that is returned to us, for example,
by using the ref function.
And I think that this is generally a good thing because that means we're using less view specific ideas
in our tests.
Our tests are working with the more basic vanilla JavaScript language or in this case, TypeScript,
which means we are more decoupled from the actual implementation.
If I were to instead change this to something like Ref eight, that certainly would make the test still
pass.
But then our tests would be coupled to the idea of using a reactive view object versus a much simpler
type of object, which is an object that happens to have a value property.
So while there are types and interfaces that we can import from view that allow us to declare a current
page and max page as a computed view, reactive objects or more specifically, give them the type or
the interface for such an object.
I argue we don't need to do that.
I argue we can be just okay with a very simple, much, much more lightweight interface that would also
allow us to keep the tests that we currently have right here.
There is no need to use a more complex, larger, complicated interface that introduces more additional
properties that we don't care about when a much simpler, smaller interface will suffice.
And again, if we tell TypeScript that we're using a view reactive object here specifically, then we'll
have to provide such an object right here in our test.
And that may require us to create an object that has way more properties and way more methods that we
care about.
Right?
We only care about an object having a value property.
So I'm going to define an interface here that says that and nothing more.
So it's going to look like this here.
I'm going to define an interface and I'm going to call it Simple Ref, because we know from the View
Library that we have our ref function and it defines a reactive object wrapping a value.
And I want basically a simple version of that.
And all that's going to be is a value property.
And we can see in this example that we're subtracting minus one and we are adding plus one.
Max paid is also going to be a number.
So I'm going to say that the value inside is going to simply be of type number.
All right.
So right here, I'm going to say that current page is of typed symbol ref and Max Page is a type symbol
ref as well.
All right.
So once again, I'm not importing a type from the View Library, even though I'm sure it does have some
kind of ref or computer ref type that also has a value property.
The problem I see with using that interface is that in addition to having a value property, it would
also have a whole bunch of additional properties or methods that we would have to implement, either
by having a very similar object here or by using ref in our tests.
And that's something that I simply do not want to do because it couples our tests closer to the implementation
and makes our tests as much more dependent on view itself.
The more that our tests can be separate from the framework and the library we're using and be tested
in isolation by using regular JavaScript, the better because it generally makes them much more easier
to transfer later.
If, for example, we decide to go to a different framework.
All right.
So with that said, we have our types annotated in our implementation on the left, and everything is
working.
And on the right hand side, it looks like we do not have any issues right here as I scroll.
So everything looks correct.
So I'm going to run NPM, run test, Colin, watch and see what that gets us.
It should detect the composable that we just updated, which is used previous in pages.
It looks like the job listings component is utilizing that composable as well.
But not a problem.
And you can see we have a bypassing test suite.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
And with that, we have converted all of our composable functions to utilize TypeScript.
So another big sign of progress.
All right.
So with that, I will see you in the next lesson.