Okay.
So in the previous lesson we added a selected degrees property to our view X Store State.
And of course, the reason all of these properties exist right here, selected organizations like and
job types and now selected degrees.
The reason they exist is so that we can use them to filter in our getters.
So let's open up our getters test file as well as the corresponding test file in getters that test.
That test, which I have on the right hand side.
And as a reminder, we have these two helper getters right here, include job by organization and include
job by job type.
And these are individual getters that are responsible for figuring out whether one given job matches
the criteria that is needed to include it.
And the final result of filter jobs, for example, in our include job by organization getter, we receive
a single job and then we check whether that job's individual organization, which we can get right here
on its organization property, we check whether that organization is present in the array of selected
organizations that the user has populated by selecting checkboxes.
And then our include job by job type getter works very similarly.
It similarly accepts a single job.
It looks at that jobs job type property right here and it checks whether that string is present in the
selected job types array of UCS store state, which itself is populated by the users selecting the job
types checkboxes.
So we need to do something very similar for include job by degree.
And then once we wire that up, of course we also have our filter jobs getter right here and this is
the one that actually iterates over the array of all the jobs and uses these helper getters to arrive
at the final array of the jobs that match all the criteria.
So the organization must match, the job type must match and the degree must match as well.
Remember as well that we have these if statements right here on lines 33 and 37.
And what that is saying is if the user has not selected any checkboxes, so if the user has not selected,
for example, any organization or any job type, we will include all jobs.
As the jobs flow through this check, all of them will pass because if none of them pass, then we'll
have no jobs to show the user.
So basically, if the user has not interacted with a checkbox group, every job will pass that test.
All right.
So in this case, if the user does not select any degrees, we don't want to show them zero jobs.
We want to show them all jobs because they haven't made a selection yet.
And that design allows us to incorporate all of these getters at the same time.
All right.
Now, as a quick reminder, if I open, it might be that JSON file and I scroll down to my jobs section
right here.
This is our jobs response on any given job object.
We're going to have a degree property.
So in this one, it's master's, for example.
And so this is the property we want to check on a given job object and see if that current jobs degree
is a string that is present in our selected degrees array.
If it is, then we want to include the job and if it's not present, then we want to exclude.
All right.
So again, very similar implementation to what we have here.
So I'm going to begin by writing a bunch of tests in my getters file and fact.
I'm going to copy and paste our collection of tests right here for include job by job type, because
my new ones are going to be very similar.
So I'm going to copy all this.
And in my case I have it collapsed.
If you have it on collapsed, not a problem.
Just make sure you copy all of the code for these two tests from above.
All right.
So let's change everything that we need to change.
So right here, instead of include job by job type, I'm going to change this to include job by degree.
And right here is a more specific scenario captured by a to describe when the user has not selected
any degrees.
This is a scenario where we automatically want to include a degree no matter what.
So here I'm going to start off with a state.
And of course the property we care about is selected degrees in this case.
So in this case we are creating a state where we have an empty array, which means the user has not
yet selected any degrees whatsoever from the eventual checkboxes on the screen, which means we want
to include every job as as this test or as this filter runs.
Right.
It doesn't mean we're not filtering by anything else.
It means when it comes to determining whether a job fulfills the degree requirements, the user has
not chosen any degrees.
So we want to include all jobs.
So right here, when we create a new job, we don't really care about the job type property anymore.
We care about the property we just saw in DV that JSON, which is going to be degree right here.
So this is going to be a degree and we're going to give it a value, let's say associate.
It doesn't really matter what it is.
Then here we have a concept called include job, which is going to invoke a group.
In this case, we don't want to use our job type getter.
We want to write the getter that we will eventually implement and that is going to be called include
job by degree.
Remember, the way this works is you have a getter, which is a method that accepts state.
And then that getter method returns a function that return that accepts whatever parameters you want.
So similar to what we have right here, here is our actual getter method.
And it returns this whole function right here.
And that function is what accepts the actual custom argument.
So here we are getting back a function from the getter method called including by degree, and we are
immediately invoking that function and passing in our job object from above.
So in this case, because we have no selected degrees, we expect that this job should be included.
So include job should be equal to true.
All right.
So this test will remain the same when the user has not made any checkbox selections, which would reflect
itself in having an empty selected degree slice of your store state.
We want to include the job here.
It says identifies if job is associated with given job types we care about with given degrees.
So let's now have a selected degrees array that is actually populated.
Let's let's give it a couple of values here.
Let's do, for example, Ph.D. and associate.
And then down here, we'll create a job with a degree that is going to be a value that is in this array.
So you can choose either Ph.D. or associate in this case, and it's going to do associate.
There we go.
So now we created a valid job object.
We've created a valid view store state by using our helper functions.
Again, that's the beauty of those functions is we don't have to worry about all this logic now.
It's all taken care of.
We only focus on the properties on each object that we care about.
In this case, selected degrees on a state and degree on a job.
So here we're going to once again invoke include job by degree.
We're going to pass in the view store state that is going to return a function.
We're going to invoke it with our job and we expect the job to be included because associate is indeed
found within this array.
All right.
So save that.
And of course, we're not going to get a passing test or even a running test suite because TypeScript
is going to say, hey, that property doesn't exist on your actual object that you're importing.
Totally fine.
We can now make that a reality.
So of course, in order to do that, we're going to need to have a constant for our getter name.
So I'm going to open up my constants file and let's add a constant right here.
So export const, we're going to call it include job by degree.
And right here, we're going to give it the exact string of include job by degree.
All right.
We're going to save that and we're going to transition back to our letters file.
And at the very top, we can import it right here, include job by degree.
And down here we can, of course, provide include job by degree.
And that is going to be a method.
It's going to be a method that accepts the View Store State as it currently is.
And we know that state is of type global state.
Global state is our interface and that method is going to return its own function and that function
is going to take an individual job.
I've type job and then here is where we actually have our body.
I'm just going to save this to make sure that TypeScript compiles correctly and simply says you're getting
the wrong return value, but by this point it should recognize the name of the actual getter method
itself.
So perfect.
You can see right here it's expecting to receive true same thing right here for both of these tests.
It's expecting to receive true, but instead it's receiving undefined because this include job by degree
method or more specifically the function that it's returns.
The function body doesn't do anything, so JavaScript and TypeScript implicitly return undefined.
And so I guess the test suite is telling us hey true is not equal to undefined.
Please fix this.
So of course we need to implement the exact same logic we have in our getters above.
So first step will take care of the scenario for when the user does not have any selected degrees.
So right here, if on my view store state I check the selected degrees property which is an array and
I check its length and it's equal to zero.
Then I know the user has not selected any degrees.
In that case, the current job that I'm iterating over is irrelevant.
I want to make sure it passes the validation check so I'm going to say return.
True to say yes it's true.
Please include this job by a degree requirements because every job will pass.
So if the user's not selected anything, we should get true and that should make our first test pass.
Then of course, the next line is going to be something very similar.
We're going to talk to our selected degrees array and double check if it includes the current jobs degree.
So right here, I'm going to return I'm going to take my extra state that has a property called Selected
Degrees.
That is an array.
An array in TypeScript has an includes method that checks whether an element is found within that given
array.
And for the job that I'm iterating over, I want to go into its degree property, which will be a string.
And if that job's degree property if that string is found in my user selected array of degrees, then
I know it should be included and includes will return to boolean, which is exactly what we want to
return from this getter.
So if the array includes it, it's going to return.
True, and that will make it pass.
And if the array does not include it, it's going to be false and it will not include the job by degree.
All right.
So now everything is passing, everything is looking good.
And in the very next lesson, we can wire up this letter to be used by our filter job.
Scatter.
I'll see you there.