Okay.
So we have made some pretty significant changes to our job listings component.
We are now fully reliant on the View X Store in order to read the Jobs property, which was formerly
part of the data of this component.
So let's run our test suite and see if anything has broken.
So right here I'm going to execute NPM, run at Tesco and watch and I am making a commit after every
lesson.
So I am going to get this message right here that says no tests found.
In this situation, you can always press the key to run all of your tests.
And when we run through all of our tests, we do see that we have one failing test suite and eight failing
tests.
And if I scroll all the way up to the top of this output, we will see that they're all coming from
our job listings dot test, dot file, which sort of makes sense.
So for example, if I look at this first output, this is coming from the computed property where we
are trying to slice the disk that jobs array, which now comes from the view store.
But in our test, we don't have any of U.S. store.
We don't have this property present.
And thus that creates an error when we try to slice on undefined.
So basically what we're going to need to do in our test suite is replace the view store with a mock
object that can play the role of a View store so that the jobless component will be able to work in
our test suite.
So let me open up job listings, dot, test, dot, J.S. And I'm going to drag that to the right hand
side.
So we'll begin with a little bit of cleanup.
You'll notice here in this test suite we are importing Axios and then marking it out.
We no longer need to do that.
The reason we were doing this before is because we were using Axios in job listings in order to make
the initial API request in our mounted lifecycle.
Look.
Now that logic is in our get jobs function so we don't care about Axios in regards to job listings.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to start by removing lines two and three, the import of Axios
and the mocking of Axios, which also allows us to clean up the before and after each.
Here's where we were mocking out the resolved value of the Axios get method to simulate a response.
We no longer need any of this or this, so let me delete that.
There's also going to be a couple sections down below where we are using Axios.
So for example, right here in this test, it fetches jobs.
This is no longer the responsibility of this component.
In fact, we have a test very similar to this for our get jobs tests themselves.
You can see here we're simply testing that Axios get has been called again this is now deprecated logic
so we can remove this entire fetch as job test.
Moving on forward, we can remove any references to Axios dot, get in further tests.
So right here I'm going to remove that line.
I'm going to remove any further lines.
I'm just looking for those red squiggles to indicate an incorrect reference.
So right here and right here.
All right.
So that moves us one step closer.
So now what we need to do is simulate a view store being available to this component of remember.
The way that View X makes his store available is via the dollar sign store property.
So what we can do is use the exact same strategy we used to mark out the dollar sign root object which
is provided by the router.
We simply use the Mocs property on our global property, on our configuration object, and we can provide
an object to represent the store.
So in every test we are running this create config function and currently we are allowing every test
to provide a simple route object.
And now my intent will be to make every test pass in a sample store object as well, so every test can
customize how it would like its own store to look for that test.
Of course, if we want to create a default value, we can right here in our parameter list.
But for now I'm going to make each test, have to provide its own store.
So I'm going to modify the create config function right here.
I'm going to add another parameter of dollar sign store and this will be the JavaScript object that
is supposed to represent our of the U.S. store.
So right here I'm going to add that dollar sign store to our max object.
I'm using elastic syntax.
So now my max object will have a dollar sign store property set to whatever object we pass in.
And that means we have to modify every test now to give two arguments to create config.
So in this lesson I just want to fix one failing test.
And then in the very next lesson we can focus on the rest of them.
So what I'm going to do here is for this very first test of it creates a job listing for a maximum of
ten jobs.
I'm going to focus on this test by using the fit function instead of the ID function.
So I'm going to save this.
And we should see just one failing test for the jobless test component.
There it is.
Can see one failed.
If I scroll up, we have just this one test and we can try to get it to pass and that'll be our experiment
before we adjust the other failures.
Okay, so what do we need in this test?
We need to create a store object that we can provide it to create config.
So right here, after our root object, I'm going to create a icons called Dollar Sign Store and I'm
going to set this equal to an object.
And this object will play the role of a view store.
Again, going back to all the ideas we talked about earlier, we could create a view store in line here,
but we don't need to because all we fundamentally need is something that is good enough to be a store.
So the first thing I want you to focus on is map state.
As a reminder, Map State takes the view store and it maps its properties to the components computer
properties.
So in order to do that, we're going to need to have a jobs property on our object.
But remember as well, we do not make that property a top level property because within our view store
there is also a state property and it is that state property that is an object with the actual view
store state.
You may have forgotten this because you may not recall it, but remember this store right here is the
top level big object.
It has methods like commit, it has methods like dispatch.
It's not the actual object that we define of our own view x global data.
We have to access the nested state property to get that.
So right here I'm going to define that state property and I'm going to have to give it a jobs property
so that my maps state will work over here.
Now what we set equal to jobs can be whatever we want.
So for now, what I'm just going to do is I'm going to use a technique we used earlier.
I'm going to use this capital array syntax.
I'm going to provide it an argument of 15, which means I'm going to create an array of 15 spots or
15 elements.
And then to specify what I want each element to be, I can invoke the fill method and provided a sample
argument.
So for example, if I simply provide an empty object, what I'm going to create is an array of 15 empty
objects, an array with 15 elements, each of which is an empty object.
So is this a real job?
No, but it doesn't have to be, because for the purposes of Map State to work, all we care about is
that Map State needs a jobs property and it needs to be something that it can iterate over because later
on it's going to slice it using this logic right here.
So I do need an array because an array has a slice method, but what that array contains doesn't really
matter for the purposes of what this component is doing.
It just needs an array it can slice an array of anything should suffice.
Okay, so now I need to provide that stored to my create config factory function and that will of course
feed it in.
And when it feeds it in, it's going to provide it to our max.
And so we're going to mark out this the dollar sign store in the component as this test is running.
All right.
So that moves us one step closer.
And if I scroll up, we should see that our original failure went away.
So we're having we're not having a problem with the slice functionality anymore.
However, you will see that we have another issue right here and it says this that stored that dispatch
is not a function.
So remember when our job listings component is mounted, it automatically runs the mounted lifecycle
hook, which turns to the dollars and store property, and it expects it to have a method called dispatch,
which it can invoke.
Now of course, in the real world, view X will give us the store object and it will have a dispatch
method.
But the problem in our test is our.
Mark store our JavaScript object that is pretending to be you doesn't have the dispatch method, so
it evaluates to undefined and thus it cannot invoke it and thus says Hey, that's not a function.
So all we have to do here is to make sure that our fig store does indeed have a dispatch property and
we get set that equal to an arrow function to any kind of function we want.
I think one of the simplest things that we can do here is simply make it equal to a just function that's
a perfect little replacement for a function, and that should do it.
So right here, I'm going to save this.
So now our component has a dollar sign store object.
That object will have a dispatch, which means our mounted lifecycle hunk will run.
It'll no longer have undefined because it will be able to find the dispatch method on our store object.
Granted, dispatch will be the just function, but that's totally fine because in this test all we really
care about is that we see the proper amount of job listings.
And so now we can see we have a view fake store with 15 jobs and we're double checking that we are rendering
ten job listings on the screen.
And that is exactly the original intent of this component and what the original test was testing for.
All right.
So this is a good walkthrough of our new implementation of a mock store and our new create config function,
which is expanded to use two arguments.
So using this approach, we're going to fix the remaining tests.
So before I call it a day, let me just get rid of this fit function and change it back to it.
And then in the very next lesson, we're going to continue hacking away at the other failing tests.