All right.
So I am super excited for this lesson.
This is going to be a special one.
In this lesson, we're finally going to wire up the logic to dynamically change our action verb every
couple of seconds when our app loads.
So the first thing I'd like you to focus on in our new headline component is this H1 right here.
It has the text build for everyone.
And what we want to do is swap this action verb every number of seconds.
We actually have four available options and they are build, create, design and code.
But what's interesting is if you look at the Google Careers website, this text afterwards does not
change.
It stays constant.
So the only part of the template that's actually dynamic is the very first word, the action verb.
All right, so let's start wiring up our logic to be able to replace that dynamically.
So if it's dynamic, we obviously need to use some bit of our JavaScript view component logic here.
So in our data object, instead of having a property called sample, I'm going to have a property called
Action Owl started off with the value built.
So now, instead of literally hard coding the word building here, I will of course reference our action
data property.
How do we do that?
Well, hopefully you should know by now it's going to be our double curly braces in here.
I'll render action.
All right.
So this should work.
This should display the text, build for everyone.
But of course, we're not actually doing anything to change it.
So now let's build that logic up.
So what I'm going to do is in created.
I could potentially put this logic.
But what I want to do is I want to incorporate into a component method and then have my created lifecycle
call that method.
So in here I'm going to call a method called change title.
So what this communicates to somebody reading this is whenever the component is created, I want the
view lifecycle hook to automatically register and trigger and it's going to run a method called this
that change title.
We know that we can define methods on a component methods property.
So right here I'm going to define a methods object and here I'll define a method with that name change
title.
So the name is entirely up to us, but change title feels like an appropriate name to me.
And again, the only reason why I did this is this method is going to take five or six lines.
And I don't want to cram all this logic into here.
I want to describe what I'm actually doing.
And this to me, is a little bit more elegant approach for organization.
Okay.
So let's begin by defining an array of strings and I'll call it actions.
And this will be the four action verbs that I want to alternate between.
So I'll start with build right here, then create, then design, then code.
Okay.
So what do I want to do?
Well, what I want to do is I want to find the current verb within my array.
So, for example, if my current action is build, I want to find build within my array and then I want
to move to the next one.
So if it's build, I move to create.
If it's create, I move to design.
The tricky part, of course, is towards the end, because when it's code, I want to move back to build
back to the beginning of the array.
So for now, let's define a constant called the current action index.
So this will be the index in the array of my current action verb.
So what I'm going to do is call in method available in JavaScript on an array called index of and that
will return the index of a given element.
What do I want to search for?
I want to search for my current action verb, which I have available on my action property in data which
I can access using the this keyword.
So I want to put in this dot action.
For example, when the component starts up, the action will be build.
So this will return an index of zero because that is the array index where build is.
All right.
The next thing I want to do is get the next action index.
So the index of the next action in line.
So you might think it would be as simple as saying, take my current action index and add one.
And that would work.
But that would only work some of the time because it would not work for code.
Code is index position three.
And if we add one, we're going to get to index position four, which does not exist in the array.
So this would only work for the first couple of elements.
So we can use a little bit of a mathematical trick here.
Which is I can wrap this in parentheses and I can do modulo four.
Okay, let me just show you how this is going to work.
But this is just going to ensure that we don't escape the confines of the array.
If we are on an action of code, then our current action index will be three.
Right.
Which means when we add one, two, three, we're going to get four.
But that index does not exist.
However, we're going to take the modulo of four, which means the remainder when four is divided by
four.
The remainder one four is divided by four is zero.
And zero is the actual array index we want, which is the array index of our built string.
So this will work when we're on code and if it's anything else, it's going to work as well.
So for example, let's imagine we're on the create string right here that sits at index one.
In that case, we're going to get index one plus one, which is going to be two.
Two modulo four is going to be the evaluation.
Whenever you have a situation like this where the left hand operand is smaller than the right hand operand,
the remainder when two is divided by four is actually two because four doesn't go into two at all.
So the closest full value that it goes into is technically zero.
So John Johnson says four goes into zero.
The remainder is going to be two.
So two modulo four is going to be two.
Three, modulo four is going to be three, etc. and four.
Modulo four will evaluate to zero, which is what we want.
So in short, this bit of logic right here will ensure that we always have a value between zero and
three inclusive, which means we're never going to escape the confines of the array.
So now that I have my next action index, I want to get my actual next action, my next string.
So what I want to do is say next action.
And given that I have my index, I can take my actions array and simply index into the next action index
and that'll get me my next string.
But we're not done yet.
We have to, of course, overwrite our action data property.
So of course, we can do that by referencing the this keyword, getting my action data property and
overriding it to my next action.
Okay.
So this is a good start, but we are not done quite yet.
Why not?
Well, the way it currently works is our created life cycle hook will run once, which means it's going
to run change title, which means we're going to change the data property from the action property to
be more specific from build to create.
But that's only going to run once.
We don't want it to run once.
We want it to continue running.
So how do we allow a bit of code to run on an interval?
That's a big hint.
We want to use the built in set interval JavaScript function.
So right here within change title, I'm going to say set interval.
All right.
And in here, I'm going to put my function.
And the second argument to say interval, of course, is the amount of milliseconds I want to wait between
each execution.
I believe on the official Google Google Careers website, just 5 seconds.
But just to keep it a little bit simpler and quicker for us in the browser, I'm going to do 3 seconds,
so I'll put 3000 milliseconds.
And of course what I want to do is create a line break here and copy this logic into my set interval
function like so.
All right.
So every 3 seconds, immediately consecutively, non stopping, we're going to tell JavaScript to rerun
this logic which will get the current action, whatever it is, get the next one or Intel view.
I'm changing the data property which should automatically render and keep this action changing every
3 seconds.
So this is a great place to start, but we are not done quite yet because as we talked about in the
previous lesson, if we just leave set animal like this, it's going to continue running.
We're not actually saving this interval anywhere and thus we can't force this component to stop this
logic whenever this component is, for example, uncounted when the user goes to another page and that
can lead to errors.
Whenever we start an interval, we always want to make sure that we shut it down.
But how can we shut it down?
Given that we don't have a reference to this interval?
We can, of course, get the return value of this and save it to a constant or a variable.
But that is going to be done running as soon as the change title method is done running well.
What we can do to solve this problem is save this interval as part of the components state.
So let me show you how that's going to work.
Let's imagine we have another data property called Interval.
And when the component is first starting up, I need some initial value and I'm just going to provide
the JavaScript value of now, which is sort of like nothing, right?
Interval is going to be set to two now.
And then when this change tidal method runs in, it's only going to run once this set interval function
is going to give me back an interval and I can save it in the component states.
I can reuse it later by simply doing this.
That interval equals that interval object that I get back.
And when I'm referencing this, that interval, I'm simply referencing this data property that is available
for me to write to.
I just want to reiterate, so because it's a little bit confusing here.
Change title is only going to run once when the component is created.
However, Change Title will invoke this interval JavaScript function, which behind the scenes will
tell JavaScript every 3 seconds.
Run this logic and that interval object will handle all of that execution.
We're going to save that interval object within this interval data property so we can always access
it in any other component method that we want.
So as you might guess, the final thing that we need to do is when the component is being encountered,
when the user, let's say, navigates away from this page, we want to get that interval and tell JavaScript
to clear it.
So I'm going to add another lifecycle hook.
We have not seen this one before, but it's before an amount and that's before the component is removed
from the DOM from the HTML.
What do we want to do here?
We want to clear our interval.
And how do we get reference to an interval if we defined it in this method?
Well, we save that interval object to this property on data.
So we can simply reference this interval right here.
And that is it.
So whenever our component is removed, we will clear this interval to ensure this logic doesn't continue
running in the background.
Now that it's no longer needed to change our properties.
All right, lots taken in this lesson, but that is everything there is to cover.
So let's see our results in the browser.
I'm going to navigate to our browser page.
Let me refresh quickly.
And build for everyone.
Let's wait a couple seconds.
There it is.
Create for everyone automatically.
Ooh, and there's design for everyone.
Can we wait a couple more seconds?
There is code for everyone.
Beautiful.
And let me just show you how this is working in our elements and in our dev tool.
So if I go to my.
Element of spectre here.
You can see here every 3 seconds, this word will change automatically.
Viewers going to inject it.
Because remember, our property, our action property on our data object is changing, which is forcing
view to re render every 3 seconds and thus it does the work for us.
Right?
We don't need to worry about how it's replacing elements and injecting elements.
It's going to take care of all that for us.
But we've made a lot of progress into getting what we want.
We start to worry about the color, by the way, but we'll get there eventually.
But now let me show you what's going on in The View DevTools.
If I go into my headline component, you can see the action here is changing every couple of seconds.
So there's design, there's code, etc. You'll notice that this interval is set to four.
You can ignore that it's actually storing the complete interval object, which we can clear whenever
we announced this component.
There's no real way for me to demonstrate this right now because we just have a single page and there's
no way for me to force the tear down of this, such as by navigating to another page.
But rest assured, whenever we remove or on mount this headline component from our DOM, then we're
going to run that clear interval function to clear this consecutive change in code so we can see our
action changing, we can see the results changing in the browser.
And this is a huge step forward.
So I hope you've had a lot of fun.
I certainly have done in this hour.
And we're going to continue chipping away at this and start working on the colors and the upcoming lessons.