All right.
So this should be a fun lesson.
In this lesson, we're finally going to see 100 different dynamic jobs populate on our job results page.
So all that is left to do is to walk through our job list and component and replace all of our former
hardcoded text with the dynamic properties available on the job object that flows in as a prop to this
job listing component.
In the previous lesson, we set up the validation for that job prop, so now we can use the job prop
anywhere in our template.
And we also set up this computed property of job page link to generate a dynamic URL to the individual
job page when the user clicks on the job listing.
So let's take care of this job page link computed property.
First, I'm going to scroll up and find my first router link right here.
The router link wraps basically all of the content in my job listing.
So if the user clicks anywhere in this box, it's going to navigate them to that page.
Right now we are navigating the user to a hardcoded root of slash job, slash result, slash one.
That's not what we want.
We want to navigate them to whatever the value of the job page link computed property happens to be.
Of course this will not work because view is going to think we're providing an actual string of job
page link.
We need to make this a dynamic reference to the computed property below, and in order to do that,
we have to bind to this to prop that the router link component expects.
So right here I'm going to add a colon and immediately you can see the syntax change my my voice code
editor recognizes that we're referencing the job page link computed property below.
We're going to do the exact same thing below.
There's one more router link right here, so I'm going to replace this to prop with a dynamic bound
to prop that is going to reference the job page link imputed property.
All right.
So the next thing we'd like to do is replace all of our former hardcoded text with properties from the
job object.
So right here, instead of technical program manager, I'm going to remove that.
And of course the way we can display or interpolate some kind of text on screen is by using the double
curly braces.
And here, how do we reference that object that we want while it is available as a prop called job and
we can reference that prop the same way that we would reference a data property or a computed property,
it's just available in line.
So here's my job prop.
That is an object.
And on that object we have a property called Title and that is going to give me the job title.
Now as a reminder, if you forget what properties are available on those job objects, you can either
look in the browser or you can navigate to the DB that JSON file and find all of those properties available
right here.
So this is all we're using and each one of these objects will flow down to one job listing component.
All right.
So that takes care of the title.
The next thing is going to be the organization, which is kind of the smaller company within the larger
company here.
I have hardcoded the text logo.
Instead I'm going to interpolate another property from my job object and that property is organization.
Great.
Let's move on a little bit further down.
So below what we formerly had is this hardcoded city of San Francisco, and that was made with the assumption
that a job would be limited to one city.
Well, it turns out from our data that we're actually going to be able to have jobs in multiple cities
or in other words, the same job can have a position open in two or three different cities.
So we're actually going to receive an array of cities and we need to iterate over that array and render
each of the jobs there.
So whenever you hear the word iteration and whenever you need to render a corresponding slice of HTML,
the immediate directive you should think about is the V for directive.
So right here I'm going to eliminate this former span.
I'm going to add an unordered list and I want to create a list item for each location that is available
in my locations array.
So I'm going to add an ally element, a list item.
I'm going to use the V for directive and what do I want to iterate over?
I want to iterate over each location and here's where I have to provide the actual collection or array
that I'm iterating over.
Well, now this collection of locations will come from the locations property on my job object.
So in job dot locations.
So it's the exact same v four directive that we're used to, except this time we're iterating over an
array that we get from a prop.
Usually we've been iterating over an array that we get from data.
We're in the previous lessons, we did it based on the API response.
This is another similar application, same idea.
We're just iterating over some array, but we're providing a different place or source for that array.
In this case, it's a prop that is flowing into job listing.
So whenever we use V four, we of course need to bind to a key property to give it a dynamic reference
to something that Vue could use as a unique identifier.
In this case, the location represents a string of a city, and that string is a perfect, unique identifier
because we're not going to have the same city represented twice in the same array.
So I'm just going to bind to location, which represents the dynamic string that I'm iterating over
right here.
Since I defined this variable right here, I can use that for my.
Binding to the key attribute.
There's a couple of classes I would like to add here just for style.
The first thing I want to add is in line.
BLOCK That's just going to ensure that the ally doesn't take up the whole width of the box, so it doesn't
force everything down onto the next line.
And between each city, I'd also like to add a little bit of margin.
So I'm going to add a right margin to each list item with the more five class from tailwind that is
going to add 20 pixels of margin on the right.
So because we are using V four, we're going to create however many list items there are for however
many locations we get, but we still need to render the location on the screen.
We have reference to this location variable that we defined.
This name is up to us.
And so given that we have access to that, I'm going to interpolate it or render it in our template
using curly braces.
So I'm going to use location here.
So again, you get to define whatever name you want to use here, but whatever you choose, here is
what you have to put inside curly braces because that's what V will recognize.
All right.
So moving on, the next thing that we need to take care of is our qualifications.
We previously had these three list items.
Those are all going to go now because we're not going to hard core them.
And once again, we're going to need to iterate over a property on our job object.
And that property is called minimum qualifications.
That is also an array of strings.
So once again, I'm going to add an ally and I'm going to use the V directive to iterate over every
qualification in job dot minimum qualifications.
So again, I think in case it isn't obvious, if I have an array of three items, I'm going to create
three list items.
If I have an array of two strings, I'm going to create two list items.
If I have an array of ten strings, I'm going to create ten list items, etc. Once again, I need to
provide some kind of unique identifier.
To my key attribute, I'm going to again use the V bind syntax to provide a dynamic value, and I'm
just going to provide my qualification in this case because my qualification is a unique string.
It's a unique job requirement that is long and lengthy and definitely unique because I'm guessing the
same job is not going to have two bullet points that are the exact same string.
So this should serve as enough of a unique identifier for you to establish each list item as unique.
Remember, we just need to provide it some kind of identifier that is unique.
Typically a simple value, like a string or a number.
All right.
And then I also need to actually render that qualification bullet on screen so I have access to my qualification
variable.
And right here, I'm going to interpolate it using the double curly braces within my list item.
All right.
And if I scroll from top to bottom, we already took care of this or link.
So I think that is all there is to change.
Everything now is dynamic.
We have no more hardcoded text or hardcoded links.
So let's check in in our browser and see what things are currently looking like.
All right.
And here we go.
Let me just refresh this page and there we go.
You can see all of these jobs are now different.
We have angular developer, Java coder, svelte ninja.
And if I scroll down, we're going to see 100 different jobs based on the array of 100 different job
listings that we got from our backend.
So now we're starting to see the power of view in action.
You'll notice that a couple of things are different from each listing to the following listing.
If I hover my mouse over the actual job listing, you'll notice in the bottom left corner of Chrome
we have the URL that is generated by job page link.
So this one is slash one, this one is slash two, this one is slash three, this one is slash four.
Again, it's using the ID property from each job object to generate the individual job show page so
each one will lead to a different page.
That's exactly what we want.
You'll notice that each one has a different title.
That's because we're interpolating that value.
Each one is a different organization.
That's going to be the very first item you see here down below.
So viewing me as a company View Tube, these are all puns, by the way, if you can do it, these are
all companies.
And then to the right we have the cities, so we use the V4 directive to iterate over that locations,
right?
So in this case, we have one city of Lisbon, so we render it right here in this array.
We have two cities in this array we have four cities.
So you can see we are using V4 to generate as much as we need in order to render all of those things
sequentially.
So view is powerful enough with that v four directive to dynamically react to however large that array
is.
Same thing goes with our qualifications bullets.
So right here we have an array from the back end with four strings, so we render four qualifications.
Here we have an array of three strings, so we get three of them rendered in that ally.
The V four is automatically dynamically reacting and rendering as much as it needs to based on however
many items or elements are in the array that we provide to v four.
So with that, if we scroll down, we can enjoy our handiwork.
Everything looks good.
We have 100 different jobs being rendered just like a real job site and it's looking pretty good.
So things are looking happy to me.
And in the very next lesson, we're going to talk a little bit about how we can test this.