All right.
So now we know more about the partial type in TypeScript, and I want to utilize that knowledge in our
mutations test file.
So here's what we're going to do.
We're going to define a factory function, and its responsibility will be to deliver a sample store
state.
So it's going to be very similar to what the state function here does already.
However, we're going to modify our factory function so that it can still accept whatever parameters
or properties it wants from any given test, which will allow every test to specify the properties it
cares about.
And we're going to be able to do it using the partial syntax that I showed in the previous lesson,
and I'll all come together.
So in my described block for mutations, I'm going to define a new arrow function and I'm going to call
it Create State.
All right, so here I'm going to provide my parameter parentheses, and I know that this function will
produce an object that honors the global state interface.
So here I'm going to provide my arrow function to actually implement the logic.
And all I'm going to do here is I'm going to invoke the state function that I imported in line two.
So let's call this something like initial state, and that's going to be the invocation of the state
function that is in the other file.
So that gives me the four default properties set to their starting values.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm immediately going to just structure the properties of my initial
state object, and I'm going to show you why in just a second.
Normally, if I was just returning initial state by itself, obviously we would not need to make a copy
on line eight.
But this approach is necessary for what we're about to add.
So if we simply use create state as we are doing right now, we would get the exact same thing as if
we invoked state right here.
Basically just gives us an object with those four properties.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to allow my my parameters here to accept an optional parameter called config.
Right.
And that type that I will assign to config is going to be a partial global state.
So right here, I'm going to use the exact same syntax as in the previous lesson.
I'm going to use the word partial and close it off.
And then within those brackets I'm going to write global state.
And then to actually provide the default assignment, I'm going to provide an equal sign and an empty
object.
And remember, an empty object satisfies the type right here because partial makes all the properties
on the global state object optional, which means an object doesn't have to provide them.
Then what I'm going to do is whatever config object I get, I'm going to destructor its properties right
here in line as well.
All right.
So what is the benefit of this approach?
The benefit of this approach is that we now have a default ready to go object right here represented
by initial state that honors the global state interface.
So the object that the create state function returns is something we're easily going to be able to pass
into any mutation we want because it's going to honor the promise that it's going to have an object
of global state that is being returned.
However, if any test wants to customize the values of those properties, it still has to provide those
properties with the right types.
However, if wants to swap it, those values are it can pass it into this config object.
And this partial type here will validate that it is going to have the right properties.
However, also validate that they are optional, which means a test is not obligated to pass them in.
In other words, if a test invokes create state with no argument, that's totally fine because we're
going to fall back to this empty object which honors this type and thus we're simply going to get the
default starting state.
However, if a test gives me a sample object that has, for example, only and is logged in property
or only a selected organization's property, or maybe two of those four properties, or maybe three
of those for as long as we provide the right types for those property names, this syntax will allow
us to feed an object that fits any of those criterias.
Zero out of four properties one property, two properties.
Three properties all the way to four properties, as many or as little as we want.
And we also have a reasonable fallback to go back to to satisfy the other properties that we may not
care about.
So, for example, what that is going to allow us to do right here is to get the best of both of these
worlds right here.
So what I'm going to do here is say const starting state and I'm going to invoke the function I have
above.
I'm going to provide here, create state.
I'm going to invoke that function.
And what I'm also going to provide right here is going to be a object, my config object right here
to communicate which properties I want to manually specify in this test.
Just have to communicate to a future reader what's important.
So right here I'm going to provide is logged in and I'm going to set it to false.
And that is going to pass TypeScript because type TYPEKIT is going to say, you're giving me an object
with a single is lodged in property.
But that's totally fine because he told me config right here is going to be a partial global state.
So it's a global state with all optional properties.
So you are not obligated to give me the three additional properties that Global State has right here.
You can just give me one of those four.
I'm going to take whatever you give me and I'm going to do structure right here.
So I'm going to get all of the necessary properties for my state function right here.
And whatever you give me, I'm going to overwrite.
And now the benefit is my test can communicate.
Hey, state matters and we need a real state right here to pass interpretation.
But the real component of the state that I care about is the is logged in property that is going to
start out as false.
And here I'm going to validate that when the test is done, it should be equal to true.
All right.
So with that, we can remove these two lines whenever we're comparing primitives.
It's also generally a good idea to use that to be match instead of the to equal matcher.
So I'm going to change that from to equal to two B and there we go.
So now I feel that we have a test that captures the best of all worlds.
We are able to create a state that is fully like the real world state, that honors the global state
interface, that has the four properties with the exact four types that they need.
However, in our test, we can also communicate which property we specifically care about, tell the
story of the beginning, the middle and the end, and do that using something that is completely valid.
TypeScript syntax, which is the partial keyword or the partial type that we learned about in the previous
lesson.
All right.
So things are looking pretty good and we'll continue chipping away at this test file in the next lesson.