All right.
So we have made a lot of progress.
We are now rendering a dynamic action verb every 3 seconds.
So the next thing I want to do is to add a different font color to every one of our action verbs.
So I'll begin by adding a style section to my view component, and that is the headline component.
So right here I'll add my new style tags, make sure you have an opening and closing one.
And as always, we'll add the scoped keyword in order to limit the styles to just this file.
What I'm going to do here is define forces as classes and their names are going to match our for actions.
So build, create, design and code and each success class will simply set one color.
Now, you may be thinking, shouldn't we put these colors into our tailwind config file?
And I think that that is totally fine.
But for now, given that this is the only place in our website where we're going to be utilizing these
four colors, I think it's okay to start out by defining them just here in this component and later
on moving them to our tailwind config file if we find that they are more universal in nature for now,
let's start here.
So I'll begin by defining a build the class and I'll define its color property and I'll set that to
this hashtag.
It's going to be 1a73e8.
It's going to be that blue color below there I will define a create class and same deal.
Here I'll have a color property and I'll set it to hashtag 34853.
That's going to be the green color for create then design.
It's color is going to be F nine, a, b00.
That's the orange color.
And finally it will have a code class and its color will be dd93025.
That's a red color.
All right.
So make sure we save that.
And the next thing I want to do, of course, is to wire up my object.
It's going to determine which class we're going to apply.
We're going to follow the same protocol we've used throughout the course, which is will define a computed
property, I'll call it action classes, and that property will return in object where the properties
are going to be access classes and the values are going to be booleans that reflect whether or not those
classes should be applied and to know which class will be applied.
I'm going to take a look at the current value of my action data property.
If it's build, for example, then we want to apply the Build CCS class.
If it is create, then we want to apply the creates, yes, as class and so on.
So let's begin.
I'm going to define my computed property right here.
And the view s land configuration prefers that we define computed after data but before our lifecycle
hooks.
So I'll define it right here.
And given that we are customizing the classes for our action verb or our action property, I'm going
to call my method here.
Action classes.
All right.
So computed is an object, remember?
And then in that object we define it methods.
So in action classes, I'll return a plain JavaScript object.
And here my keys of course will be my four sizes classes.
So let's start with build and when do I want to apply these CSS as build class that I just defined?
I want to do that when the value of my action data property is equal to the string built.
So when the page loads, for example, we're going to start out with build.
At that point this should have value to true and we should apply this color to our eventual header with
the action verb.
So we're going to define very similar logic for our other three classes.
So for create, I only want this to be true when the action is create and for my design class and only
want to apply that when the action data property is equal to design.
Keep in mind here, our property names are lowercase because we're matching the class names here while
the strings that we're matching with are going to be with the capital letter, because that's how we
defined these options right here from the array that we're choosing from.
And then finally we're going to have our code class and we want to apply that when the action is equal
to code.
So at any given moment in time during our complaints existence, the action properties only going to
be equal to one string at a time such as build.
So at any given moment, three of these properties will have a false value and one will have a true
value, and that will be the colour that we end up applying.
All right.
So now that we have the computed property set up and we have our CSF classes set up, the only thing
that's left to do is to wire up this logic in our template.
And as always, we're going to use V, bind and connect to our class attribute on a given H two element
in order to incorporate this logic.
So what I'd like to do here is actually expand on our implementation on line three.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to wrap the action verb itself in its own span.
So I'm actually going to break this up on a new line, and I'm going to create a span for the action
verb, and I'm going to move the span afterwards.
And then what they actually do on the Google website is they add a line break, they force a line break,
and I'll do that by creating my B tag.
That's a line break tag that forces the content onto the next line.
All right.
So inside our span, we're going to have a verb and then a line break and then a text for everyone.
And when I want to apply my styles is actually going to be on the span itself because we only want to
apply those colors to the action verb.
The for everyone keeps the original styles of the page.
So right here we know that we can either use a V bind or the shortcut, which is the colon.
We want to bind to the class attribute on our span two element.
And to this we can provide a JavaScript object and we know that Vue knows that it's going to apply that
logic of looking for the properties with a value of true and looking for those properties as CSS classes.
Right.
So of course I want to apply my action class as property.
That's a method.
But don't worry, you will invoke it to get this object.
And of course, because this computed property is dependent on the action data property, whenever the
action property changes, which it will every 3 seconds, this will rerun, which will lead to a new
access class and a new property having a value of true, which will in turn force you to re render this
and apply the different surface class and the different font color to the current action group.
So this should be enough.
So let's transition to our browser and see what we've done.
All right, so there's create in green and if we wait 3 seconds, beautiful, there is design in orange,
there is code in red.
And one more time we should see the other one.
There is build in blue.
Perfect.
So looking pretty good.
Of course we have to increase our font size and start emulating the actual look and feel of the real
page.
But this is exactly what we wanted.
Notice that we are getting Vue to dynamically apply a different CAC class every 3 seconds based on the
value of a data property, which is in turn dynamically altering the font color.
Awesome.
So we've made a lot of progress here and in the next couple of lessons, we can continue styling our
headline component.