Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we added some default content to our slot in our accordion component.
Let's now take a look at how we can test this functionality.
So here in my accordion test file, I'm going to create another described block nested within my first
one to provide some additional context.
And this scenario under which I'm testing is this one.
When we do not provide custom child content, what do we want to verify?
We want to verify that it renders default content.
And I'm going to provide a just arrow function here, and I am going to make this an async function
because I think for the most part, we can copy most of the test above.
So I'm going to scroll up and I'm going to copy everything here.
The entire test, in fact, and pace the blow.
Of course, we are going to make some significant changes.
So the first thing is we obviously do not want to provide a default slot value right here because we
want to see how the component will render when we do not specify the slot content.
So in my configuration object right here, I'm just going to remove the slots property entirely.
And similarly, we do not care about testing for minus the child right here.
What we can do is simply click on the clickable area and make sure that it has the text that we expect
and the text that we expect is not going to be anywhere in this test.
It's going to be our eventual implementation right here.
So I'm simply going to look for the text of, Woops, somebody forgot to populate me.
All right.
So I'm going to click that.
Save that.
Let's see what happens when we run it.
And we have a passing test week.
So that is how we can test for a default slot.
We simply do not provide that slot in our configuration object and verify that the component renders
whatever we want it to eventually render.