All right.
So in the previous lesson, we added a new composable function called Use Filter Jobs, which talks
to our View X Store and gets the filter jobs getter.
We then used the composable function in our sub nav component.
Now if you check up on your test suite, you'll find that our sub nav tests are still passing.
So what's happening is whenever we mount our sub nav component in a test, we're running through the
setup method and we're using the real use filter jobs composable.
So this logic right here and in our tests we are marking out use store.
So we're basically intercepting this call on line number seven whenever we're mounting a component and
we're replacing it with an object and thus our entire test is passing.
But as you can probably guess, I want to perform the exact same refactor we did a couple lessons ago.
I now don't want to worry about the internals of use filter jobs.
Rather, I just want to let it do its own business which is already tested and in the tests for subnet.
I now want to mark out, not use store but rather use filter jobs.
So rather than than marking out two steps away from where I am, I'm just going to mark out right where
I am.
Mock out the exact dependency that subnet is dependent on.
It's right here in my sub nav test.
We I'm no longer going to use you store and mark our view x.
So let's go ahead and remove that right here.
Instead, I'm going to mark out my own function, which has already been tested in a separate file.
So I'm going to import use filter jobs.
That is the exact same thing we introduced into our component in the previous lesson.
And this is going to come from the source store composable directory and by default that will import
it, which will allow us to, for example, set properties on it and things like that.
But it's not actually marked until we call just mark and we provide the directory or more specifically
the file name, which is the source directory store composable.
So with that once again just is going to loop through that file.
It's going to take use filter jobs and it's going to make it a mock just function that returns undefined
when invoked.
So now all we have to do is update our jobs to mark out the return value of use, filter jobs instead
of making out you store.
So as I scroll down, here is our first test.
You can see we were previously marking out the store to be an object that has a getters property, which
is an object that has a filter jobs property.
Now this logic is captured in our use filter jobs composable function.
We've abstracted away the knowledge of having to know all these details.
So all that use filter job is going to return to us is a reactive object holding an array of jobs.
Thus we can actually reduce this entire thing instead of marking out use store.
I want to instead mark out this thing right here.
So I'm going to say use filter jobs.
Mark the return value.
And we no longer need this object.
We no longer need the getters key.
We no longer need filter jobs.
So here is our array.
And again, going back to the discussion we had a couple lessons ago, if we wanted to, we could wrap
this array in the ref function call to make it a reactive object whose value property will be this array.
But remember, for the purposes of how this component works, this component simply expects some kind
of either iterable array or reactive object, holding an iterable right for what filter jobs represents.
The reason it has filter jobs is just because it needs an object who for whom it could take the length.
Remember, whenever we use a reactive object in the template view is going to automatically get the
underlying value being stored.
So filter jobs in this case is not a reactive object holding our array, it is the regular array.
Right?
So the point of that is we can actually get away in our test with using a plain array and everything
will still work because for the purposes of what set up needs, this will work and for the purposes
of what the template needs.
This template is just fine with filter jobs being an array.
We don't need to go through that extra step of having a reactive object, wrapping an array inside it.
All right.
So this, again, is a little bit of a sidestep of how the real world works, right?
Because in the real world, our use filter jobs function will return a reactive object from view that
is storing an array.
But for the purposes of our template in our test suite, a simple array not wrapped in a reactive object
is enough to verify that this test is going to pass.
So I argue there's no need to make it more complex by passing the array into a ref function call.
Although you're more than welcome to do that if you want to stay really close to how it works in the
exact component in the real world, same principle applies right here.
We're no longer going to need to mark out our use store.
We are no longer using use store.
Instead, we are using use filter jobs.
That is a just function so we can call mock return value.
So what should this return to our component in the setup method when it's invoked?
Well, we no longer care about this object.
We no longer care about the getters property.
We took care of that in the actual composable function.
We no longer care about the name of the getter that's all abstracted away.
It's all isolated in the separate composable function, which we tested in the last lesson.
All that we care about for the purposes of this component is what that getter actually returns, which
for this is just going to be an empty array.
So you'll notice if I just provide an empty array as my mock return value, that's what it's going to
return to the setup method.
Remove this collection of lines.
Save this.
Let the test run and everything passes.
And now notice how, by removing the former dependency on store and simply marking out our own composable
functions, even our tests become a lot more lightweight.
Not just our setup method right here, which is super simple three three lines of code.
But even our setup here has become a little bit simpler because instead of having to provide that deeply
nested mock store object in every test, we now just simply provide a simpler data structure, like
an array of objects or a simple array, right?
So we've kind of split up this test from just being in sub nav to being in subnet and in the tests for
the use filter jobs composable.
Right.
And since that is tested in the other test file, if we ever want to use use filter jobs in another
component, we can similarly follow this exact same approach and not have to worry about what use filter
jobs is doing in its own file in its own logic.
So even our tests become simpler with this approach super simple to read, we simply say, Hey, we
have two functions that we're using in our component use.
Confirm now use filter jobs.
Pretend as if they return these two things.
We're going to replace the real world implementation, substitute it with these mock functions that
are going to return values that are good enough to get the component to function.
Assuming you get those return values from those mock functions, test the actual logic of what the component
is supposed to be doing.
It's supposed to be displaying some text call to jobs matched.
If we give it an array of two objects, we're still verifying that we have two jobs matched.
That is testing the core logic of what this component is supposed to be doing on line eight.
Right?
So just because we're marking does not mean that we are running away from the real world and how the
component is supposed to work.
We're still testing the heart of this component, which is supposed to display how many jobs that have
been matched based on what filter jobs it has, based on what use filter jobs gives to it.
All right.
So hopefully all of this has been a really good exercise in teaching about how to create proper unit
tests that focus on one single unit, the smallest bit of functionality that we can target if we are
testing a component.
I just want to focus as much as I can on that component and not worry about all of the dependencies
that it has and all of the dependencies that those dependencies have and so on, because that could
go on forever.
You can have a component called function A which calls function B, which calls function C, you don't
want to let all those real functions run and makes a test slower and it makes more points of failure
in that chain.
Instead, you just intercept the very first one that your component uses.
Tell the test suite what it should return in its place and test the component.
Does the right thing with that data.
All right.
We still capture the heart of the components responsibility.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.