In the previous lesson, we saw how we could use the two ref function to restructure a single reactive
property from a reactive object.
So just to reiterate, because it is a tough concept to explain, this entire object is reactive, but
that doesn't mean that its individual properties are reactive.
When we reference person dot, first name view knows that that property is part of that object and it
knows that it has to track its reactivity.
But when we do structure first name by itself from person, that property is not reactive.
Vue doesn't automatically apply reactivity to that individual property that we take off the object.
So we saw this solution in the previous lesson.
But this is obviously pretty laborious, right?
What if our reactive object has ten different properties?
Do we really want to use ten different variables here and ten different invocations of the two ref function?
So because of that, there is another help helpful function in view.
It's a little bit confusing because it's very similarly named, but it's called two refs.
So I'm going to add an S here.
So, so so far we've learned ref, right?
We've learned to ref in the previous lesson and now we're learning two refs.
Okay.
So a little bit confusing because they all sound very similar.
But let me remove this code right here.
And the two refs function also accepts a reactive object like person.
But it's going to return an object where every individual property is going to be reactive.
And because every individual property is going to be reactive, we can restructure properties from this
object and have that original desired result.
So from here I can, for example, restructure first name and last name from the object returned by
the to Raf's function.
When we pass ID the complete person reactive object.
So this will work but with one caveat.
Okay.
And that caveat is first name is still not going to be the value.
Boris.
Right.
First name now is going to be again an object.
A reactive object with a value property is set to Boris.
So what this does behind the scenes is it takes this entire object we passed in and it basically goes
through every single property in this object, wraps it in its own reactive object, just like RAF does,
and then gives us back that new object.
So behind the scenes, it does something like this.
Right.
And then it wraps all of these together in that single object and returns.
So when we're do structuring first name, we are getting this reactive object with a value property.
So the code we have on line 12 will work right now.
But you cannot simply use first name or last thing by itself.
You have to use that value to get that nested value of boards passed.
So when I run this file, you'll notice our code works as expected.
Every time we change a property on a person reactive object by reaching into the full property like
we do here.
That will in turn get first name and last name to update, which will in turn get the computed function
to rerun and calculate the new string.
Just to show you once again, if I get rid of value right here, we're going to get that original object
object reference.
So here we go.
We're going to see it no longer returns a reactive string because there is no such thing in JavaScript.
It's always going to have to be an object built by the view team that encapsulates or wraps that actual
string or a value, whatever it is that is changing.
So I'm going to return this back to its original implementation.
And just because this concept can be pretty confusing, I want to remove all of this code down below.
And what I want to do is I want to show you the differences between the person object and the full reactive
object that the two are after the function returns.
So I'm going to call this ref person.
Okay.
So we can totally and fully understand the differences between what we're doing here, because it seems
very similar.
Right?
What's the difference between a reactive object versus an object where every single property is reactive?
So if I take a look at person dot first name right now, what we're going to see is going to be the
original string.
It's not some kind of complex object that's keeping track of reactivity.
Vue is only keeping track of the larger person object as a whole.
And it's reactivity.
If we change a property on it through a reference like person that first name, it will know.
But if we simply take first name from it, it will simply think that that's a regular old reference
to the string.
In comparison, if I console.log ref person dot first name, what we're going to see is that complex
object that the View team built that wraps that core, a value that is dynamically changing, which
is Borris Right.
So that's the difference between what two refs does for us.
It gives us an object where every single key, whether it be first name here or here's another example
I'm going to replace this with last name.
No matter which property I referenced on my ref person object, it's going to return another reactive
object, that story, its own internal value and tracking its changes in comparison to this syntax right
here, which is a single reactive object with a bunch of properties nested inside it.
First name does not link to a reactive value of Borris.
It's just a first name property inside an object that as a whole is reactive to view.
I know it's a pretty confusing concept, but hopefully this example of printing out the differences
between person and the ref person make sense and I will see you in the next lesson.