All right.
So we learned in the previous lesson that every component has access to a router property, and that
gives us the view router itself, which is the exact same object that we configured and exported out
of our index.
Just file in the router directory.
What I'd like to do in this lesson is actually invoke a method on this object and it's going to be the
push method.
What the push method does is it navigates the user to a new route, and usually we want to do this based
on some kind of user action.
So what I propose we do is add a button in this component, and whenever the user clicks, the button
will invoke a method, and that method will actually navigate the user from the job results view to
the home view.
So let's begin by removing our computed property.
We no longer need it.
And we can also remove this former H2 with that experiment property.
And here what I'll add is a button and let's give it some text like go to your home page.
And then of course what we want to configure is a click handler.
We want to configure a method that is going to execute on the click event whenever the user presses
the button.
So of course we are familiar with this by now.
It is the VON Directive which we can use a shortcut for, and that is the assign followed by the name
of the event.
We want to react to the browser's native click event and then we provide the method that we want to
invoke in double quotes.
So I want to invoke a method called Go to Home.
And of course I now need to define that method as part of the components methods property.
So right here I'll define my methods.
I'll provide a JavaScript object and I will provide a method with the expected name of Go to home.
All right.
So in my method body, I will have access to the this key word.
And we know from the previous lesson that we can access this dot dollar sign router that gives us a
whole object and that object has a whole bunch of methods.
The one I'm looking for here is push.
All right, now, push actually takes a variety of different arguments.
And the first and the simplest one is a string that specifies where to go to.
So our home route or our home view is available at the root root, which is just a forward slash.
So I can simply provide a string of a forward slash, save the file, and this should be good to go.
So I'm going to navigate to my browser.
And here I am on the job results page at slash jobs, slash results.
And here is my new button.
It's not very fancy.
It's Unstyled.
But you can see when I hover my mouse over, I do have that ability to click on it.
This will trigger the method which will use the router to navigate the user to my home route.
So this is very similar to a router link which we saw a little bit ago, except this is us manually
configuring the navigation by manually invoking the push method on the router.
We could also use, for example, a router link component instead of that button, and that would take
care of that magic for us.
So this is a little bit more of a verbose way and probably not even in the best ways since it's more
explicit.
But just want to show you how everything works behind the scenes.
So I also want to show you a couple alternate arguments that we can provide to the push method.
And they're all going to work.
They all work very similarly.
We can also provide a configuration object, so a JavaScript object and the property that we can provide
here is path.
So if we want to be a little bit more explicit about what this slash represents, it represents our
path.
We can provide a configuration object like this, and this will work the exact same way we will route
the user to a path of slash.
So if I go back to my job results page, let me just refresh and click this.
There we go.
We've been routed back to the home page at the root root.
And finally, the last option, which is probably my favorite here.
As I mentioned earlier, paths are pretty likely to change by our names, for our paths are probably
less likely to change.
As a reminder, if I go into my router index that yes file we gave every root a name so our root route
we call that the name of that route, the home route, and that connects to the slash path.
So what we can do here in our configuration object is provide a property called name, and instead of
providing the actual path itself, we can provide the name of that route.
So we called our route home right here.
So if I simply put home right here, this will work.
And if later on I go into my router index file and I change the path to something else like slash home,
this will continue to work.
It won't break because we're not hard coding the path.
We're hard coding a name that references that path.
And I like this approach because it describes more of where we want to head instead of how we want to
head there.
So it is a little bit more declarative than imperative in my from my perspective.
But regardless, the implementation will lead to the exact same result in the browser.
So if I go back to slash job slash results, click on this button we're able to navigate.
All right, so the push method is what allows us to navigate to the next route to the next path.
We simply provide it.
Any one of those arguments, either a string or a configuration object where we can provide prop properties
like name or path.
You can see it's all kind of logical.
It's all just a matter of memorizing those different ways that we can customize where we send the user
off to.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.