All right.
So we are back in our action button component and now we have everything we need to wire up our secondary
button style.
This is going to be the second version of the button, which is going to have a white background and
blue font.
And those two colors are going to be inverted whenever we hover our mouse over the button.
So the first thing I want to do is scroll down to the style section of my action button.
And here we have our button styles and our primary class styles.
And I'm going to add a new class here called Secondary.
And I'm once again going to use the tailwind to apply directive.
This is going to allow us to write down some tailwind access classes in line here, which will be applied
whenever we use the secondary access class on any of our HTML elements.
So let's begin with our text color.
So we're going to make our text brand blue one.
Then I want to make sure my background is going to be transparent.
So I'll use the big transparent class right here.
And then the only other detail we have to take over is our hover state.
So as a reminder, whenever we want to apply a tailwind class on hover, we need to prefix that class
with the hover keyword.
So on Hover, I want to have my new blue color serve as my background.
So I'm going to say here big brand blue too.
So as a reminder, in the previous lesson, we added this brand blue to color to our tailwind config
file, which means tailwind will automatically generate a new CSR class called Big Dash, whatever the
color is that we provided automatically.
And then we'll also prefix it with hover to make sure we only apply this whenever we hover our mouse
over whatever element where applying this class to.
So only on hover will we show a background that is our brand blue to color that we defined.
All right.
And also on hover, we want to switch up the text color.
And so we're going to have text dash white.
This is a built in tailwind utility class.
Makes sense.
It makes the text color white.
So I'm going to save this.
And now we have our secondary button style.
But of course, it's not being applied anywhere in our our template.
Right?
So in our template, we have this reference to button class, which is a computed property that returns
this JavaScript object.
And as a reminder, the way this works with the binding to the class attribute is if a given key here
has a value of true, then tailwind or rather view will apply that XSS class to the given element.
So if we have primary set to true, then the primary class will be applied to our button and then these
styles will be applied to the button.
Similarly, if we write down secondary right here and if we were to, for example, give it true and
hard code that then we would automatically always apply these secondary styles right here to the button.
Now, of course, what we want to do is to have only one of these two styles be applied.
We're always going to have either the primary styles, which is the first version of the button or the
secondary styles for the button, which is the alternate font color and background color, but never
both at the same time.
Right?
So we never want this to both be true.
So, for example, if I were to set this to this that primary, then right now the component would start
off with primary being evaluated to true, which means the evaluation here would lead to both the primary
and the secondary classes being applied, which is not what we want.
So what we can do is to invert the value that we provide to our secondary property.
So what I can do here is invert the Boolean with an exclamation point.
So the way this works is whatever boolean we have, the exclamation point will give you the opposite
one.
So for example, if primary is such a true right here as our initial data property, then this would
value to true.
And this will evaluate to the inverse or the opposite of true, which is false, which means view will
apply the primary class but not the secondary class to our button.
Conversely, if the primary data is set to false, well, this would lead to false and the inversion
of a boolean of false will be true.
So if the primary data key is set to false, we're going to get the secondary version of the button.
And if our primary key is set to true, then we're going to get the primary version of the button.
We're going to have two completely different styles be rendered by view based on the changing of the
primary data property.
Right.
And at each time, we're always going to apply these styles.
By the way, these generic button styles of padding and rounded corners will always be applied.
But now with this setup, we're only going to ever apply either one, but not both of the primary and
secondary classes.
So we can take a look at this in our browser.
I'm going to remove all these comments and go back to our browser and open up my view devtools.
So we start off of course with our primary version of the button.
And if I go to my view dev tools and I look at my component, we'll see that our data is primary set
to true.
So true activates the primary access class, which applies the traditional buttons down.
But let's look at what's going to happen when I edit this primary data property to false.
So a couple of changes are going to cascade.
Number one, our computed property will repeat because it is tracking the changes to our primary key
which.
Means these two properties in our button class will invert.
Primary will become false.
Secondary will become true as a result of data and the computed property changing view will rewrite
under the template.
And it's going to look at the newly generated button class and then it will know to apply the new secondary
class because now secondary will have a value of true.
Let's take a look at this in action.
We're going to see our button class flip.
There we go.
We can see these two values became inverted and now you can see we have the new button style appear
in the top right corner.
So here is the second version of the button, the secondary version.
And if I hover my mouse over it, we're going to see that now on hover.
It has those secondary styles applied, that new blue color background as well as the white font.
Right.
It's going to start off with a blue font on a white background and it's going to transition on hover
to a white font on a blue background.
This is big brand by big brand blue, too.
By the way, this is our second blue color that we added in the previous lesson.
And once again, if I again change my data back to true, once again, the computed properties will
reevaluate.
So our button class object that we're providing to our class attribute through the use of the buying
directive will update as well, which will again trigger a view to apply a different class class.
It's going to reapply the primary class, which will in turn apply some different tailwind asset classes
and once again change the value of this button back.
Right.
So we're starting to see how a button can be pretty dynamic, can be one of either of those two buttons,
either primary or secondary, but not both, while keeping the core structure of the button the same.
Right.
So we're kind of allowing it to serve two purposes.
Now, we haven't seen this button be used in two different scenarios one for primary, one for secondary.
But we are moving in that direction by building in the code to enable that kind of logic and also that
kind of switching.
All right.
So lots more to cover in this section.
And I will see you in the next lesson.