Okay.
So in this lesson, I finally want to come back to this s lint violation right here that we've had ever
since we used the omit method in our text input component.
And if I hover my mouse over, it will see the update model value event has been triggered but not declared
on emits option.
So what Vue is asking us to do is to do a validation similar to what we do with our props.
View wants to know the possible emission events that we can produce from the text input component,
and it's going to validate that anything we emit falls within the constraints of what we promised would
be an eligible event for that component to emit.
It's going to be super simple.
So what I need to do here on my configuration object for text input is to create a new property and
I'll add it above methods and it's called emits and emits.
I will set to an array and in that array I'm going to provide strings representing the available events
that this component can emit.
Because remember, a component can emit as many different events as it wants.
If we want it to emit a different event, we would still call the Emit method on the this keyword and
then provide a different name here so our component could react to different things a user input, a
user click, etc. Whenever we need to relay any message to our parent, we simply call the Emit method,
but we can emit as many different messages to our parents as we want.
So for right now we only have one possible event name and it's this one right here.
So I'm going to provide a string with that exact name.
So update colon model value.
And as soon as I do, that view says, okay.
This is the array of permissible events.
You are using that exact event right here.
So if I go into my browser right now, you're going to notice in my console when I refresh we previously
had.
Some errors and when I refresh, they should go away.
You can see there's nothing here and view is not complaining.
Now notice if instead.
I go here and I change this to a different non permitted events such as nonsense.
You're going to notice first up in my in my text editor that is we're going to notice that view says
the nonsense event has been triggered but not declared on minutes.
So it's saying, I'm not finding this anywhere in this array.
So that's not a valid event for you to omit.
Please add this to the array before you use it.
And furthermore, if I go into my browsers and I refresh.
Let's say I try to omit by typing something like this, you'll notice the typing triggers the emotion
of that event and it's saying component emitted an event called nonsense, but it is neither declared
in the emits option nor as an on nonsense prop.
So the key focus here is it is not declared in the emits option.
So as we're playing around with this component in our browser, the view warning will tell us the same
thing.
You are emitting some kind of message for the parent, but you have not told me to expect that message.
And the reason that is beneficial is it can watch out for something like typos, right?
If we accidentally mistype, if we type something like.
Updates, you know, model value, but maybe we do it all lowercase.
Well, we're going to get the exact same warning and we can say, okay, this is our ultimate source
of truth.
This is the only thing I'm allowed to omit.
And so I'm going to change this back to a passing value, and that is fine.
And thus, if we have multiple events that we can omit, you know, event A, event B, it's going to
double check similarly that whatever we omit, wherever we omit, it has to be one of these three values
in order for everything to pass.
All right.
So to close this lesson off, I'm going to remove these two arbitrary values.
We're going to keep the omits property with that array of strings.
And that is the validation we need to add to make that s lint warning go away.
And that is all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see in the next one.