All right, so let's add a test suite for our job listing view component.
As a reminder, this component is found in the job results directory and we have not created that directory
yet in our tests folder.
It's right here.
I want to go to tests unit components and here's where we have all of our feature folders that match
the folder layout in the associate directory.
And here is where I want to create a job results folder.
And in there just like an S or C is where I want to put my test file for the job listing component.
So this will be job listing forecast.
J.S. And as always, I'm going to move the test far to the right so we can see it alongside the implementation.
All right, so let's begin with our usual code.
I'm going to import the mount function from view test utils.
And then I'm going to import my component under test, which is the job listing component that is going
to come from these source directory components, job results and job listing dot view.
Perfect.
Then I'm going to write a describe function and describe that we are testing the job listing component.
And let's take a look at the component and think about what we want to test.
To me, the heart of this component is basically rendering the individual properties of the job object
that we passed in as a prop.
Now, this component doesn't care about where job comes from.
This component doesn't need to know that a job object is coming from a foreign API.
Right?
Because from this components perspective, all it knows is it's going to receive a prop called job.
That job object is going to have properties on it and it's going to take those properties and render
them to the screen.
And that's really all we need to test.
So I propose that we write a test where we mount this component.
We give it a sample job object.
And we test that we see on the screen exactly what that job object provides.
For example, we can provide a job object with a title argument or property, and then double check
that whatever title we provide is somewhere in this component's text.
And I think that captures the heart of this, which is really the primary part of this component logic.
So let me show you how that's going to work right here.
I'm going to write a small, simple test that are focused on one thing at a time.
So let's just first focus on this.
The job title, the job listing component will do what it renders job title.
So I'm going to provide my arrow function and I'm going to use my wrapper and I'm going to mount my
job listing component.
So how can we provide props to a test?
Well, we have to provide that second argument to mount, which is our configuration object.
And here we can provide a props property and that is going to be an object.
And there is where we can match the props that we expect this component to receive.
In this case, our component needs a job prop, so we need to provide a job right prop right here.
And for the purposes of testing title, we don't really need to pass in a full job.
Right.
We only want to make sure that this part renders correctly.
So all our job object needs to have in this test is just a title property.
And I'm just going to make it a view developer, although it can be whatever you want.
All right.
So, yes, the other properties are going to be missing.
So, yes, this, for example, is going to evaluate to undefined and it's not going to render.
But that's fine because in this test we only care about checking this thing.
And in a subsequent test, that's where we can write the logic to check for an organization or a location,
etc. We keep our test small with a single focus and ideally a single assertion and just validate that
it does everything kind of piecemeal, one small test at a time.
So I'm just testing the title right here.
So what I can do on my wrapper is I can invoke the text method that's going to give me all of the text
that is within the DOM, within the actual view that the user sees.
So just look at the actual text that's being rendered to the screen.
And I want to use the two match nature to validate that that text has some kind of string or substring
within it.
So somewhere in my text, what do I expect?
I expect my title.
So somewhere in here I should see the string view developer.
I don't care where, I just care that it's present.
That's exactly the point.
We just care that our job title is rendered somewhere.
So let me go ahead and bring up my terminal and we'll run our just tests in watch mode.
So right here and PM run, test, colon watch and let's see what we get.
It's running right now.
All right.
So we do have a passing test, which is great.
We do have a warning right here.
And that warning has failed to resolve component router link.
We have seen this issue before.
That is because we are not mounting our job listing component within our whole view app.
So our test suite has no clue about Vue router and what router link represents.
That's simple enough.
We can simply stub it out.
So as a reminder, in order to do that, we're going to import a second thing from our test utils library
and that is going to be our router link.
So it is a smaller, more lightweight component that can play the role of a stub or a specifically a
router link stub more effectively than the generic stub that the test provides to us.
And here, after the props property, I will provide a global property and here I will provide a stubs
property of set to an object.
Here, I'm going to state that I'd like to stub out the router link component wherever it occurs, and
I'd like the test to replace it with my router link stub that I imported about.
I'm going to save that let prettier at its commas.
And now our test passes and we have no warnings.
All right.
So going on this approach, let's write a very similar test for our organization.
In fact, I think we can even copy this test and paste it below and then modify it accordingly.
So right here, it renders job organization.
So now we need to provide a prop of job.
And we don't care about the title here.
We care about the organization property because that's what it's going to render.
And let's give a sample organization like Airbnb.
All right.
And we will keep this global code because we still need to stub out the router link.
And here somewhere in the wrappers text, we now care about seeing the organization, which is going
to be Airbnb.
So I'm going to save that.
Let's see if that works again.
Our tests are small and lightweight.
We're testing that.
The job listing renders a job title vendor is a job organization, so things are looking pretty good.
But I do think we are starting to see some redundancy from test the test.
So in the very next lesson, we're going to start with a little refactor of this test suite.