Okay.
So the next component we're going to focus on will be our spotlight component.
So let's open up spotlight that view and I will immediately open up to test we as well, which is in
spotlight that test that.
Yes, let me move that over to the right hand side and let's focus on our component first.
As always, we're going to need to add a lang output here and set it to test.
And we're also going to need to import, define component and make sure to wrap our object right here
in a defined component function call like so.
And there we go.
Now, we don't actually have any errors that TypeScript will show us in the outer, but I also think
that we can improve on the typing here because we can discover that it's not perfect.
So, for example, if I hover my mouse over spotlights, you'll see that TypeScript is assuming that
the array is going to be an array of never objects, which basically means it thinks it's an array that
will never be populated.
Now that is not true.
This is actually going to be an array of spotlight objects that we're going to get back from our backend.
Whenever this get spotlight's request executes, which is going to happen when that component mounts,
it's going to receive that array of spotlight objects.
It's going to overwrite our existing empty array with the data.
And as a reminder of what a spotlight looks like, I can always go to my DB that JSON file and here
we have our spotlights and points.
So we are eventually going to have an array of objects like this, not an array of never.
And so as always, it's going to be beneficial if we tell TypeScript this.
So it understands these details that it may not be able to infer.
So what I'm going to do is define an interface called spotlight in my component, and I'm just going
to tell it.
It's going to have these properties I'd set to a number and image title and description set two strings.
So right here in my component and maybe later on, if this is reused in many other places, we may move
this interface to its own separate TypeScript types file.
But for now, I think it's okay to keep it in here.
This, by the way, is valid TypeScript because we declared this on line 13.
So we can write any kind of valid TypeScript code in line here as well.
It's no longer just JavaScript code that's valid.
It's now TypeScript, so we can totally declare an interface right here in the script section and I'll
call it Spotlight.
And I will say that a spotlight object is going to have an ID, which is going to be a number, an IMG
or image property set to a string, a title property also set to a string and finally a description
property also set to a string.
And the way that I can clarify to view what the array is going to hold here is actually by providing
a generic argument type to this raft function call.
So with the way we provide a generic argument, remember when we learned how to do this with our own
functions is when we invoke the function, we provide the type so that TypeScript can provide that type
into the function definition and do type checking that way.
So where we invoke the function, we provide these brackets so the less than sine and the greater than
sine.
And in this case, the generic type argument we provide here will represent the type of the array that
the reactive object is going to wrap.
So right here I want not just a spotlight object, but a array of spotlight objects.
So at the very end here, I'm going to provide my square bracket syntax.
So what I'm saying here is this is always going to be an array of spotlight objects, and every spotlight
object must implement this interface.
So it must have these four properties.
And just because it's an empty array doesn't present a problem because Spotlight just says, okay,
this is an array with zero spotlight objects.
But right now we can see that it recognizes that it's going to be a ref that's during an array of objects
that have this type of shape ID image title description.
One additional place where we can provide more description to TypeScript about what it's receiving is
right here in the get method call.
By default, TypeScript is only looking at your code in the editor before it's actually running in the
browser.
So TypeScript cannot make an API request for you in this code and figure out what the shape of the response
from our end point is going to look like.
However, we know it's going to be this exact thing.
It's going to be a spotlight array so we can tell this to TypeScript, we can fill in the blanks.
The typescript is not able to figure out by itself.
So right here the get method from the Access Library also accepts a generic argument right here, and
it specifies what is going to be the a type of the response that we're going to get back from this spotlight's
endpoint.
And that's going to be the exact same thing as above.
It's going to be an array of spotlight objects.
So right here, spotlight like that.
And now we're basically validating with TypeScript that we're going to get this type of array back and
we are writing it to a reactive object that expects a data value of the exact same shape.
So we're allowing TypeScript to perform that check and if it finds any mismatches, then it will let
us know.
All right.
So that we can save this file and we are all set here.
Now, let's move on to our test file, the usual protocol.
So right here, I'm going to change the test to have a test extension that may present its own share
of problems.
We can see here it's the usual one of Microsoft value not working.
This is coming from us.
Mark resolving the value of the Axios get method.
We are marking out Axios right here after we imported online number two.
So I'm going to follow the same approach as always right here.
I'll declare a concept called Axios, get Mark and I'm going to get not just the Axios object, but
more specifically the get method on it.
And I will tell TypeScript to not treat it as its general inferred type, but rather to interpret it
as being of type.
Just Mark.
And that means down below here I have to replace Axios, get with my Axios, get mark reference.
Keeping in mind this is still the same object.
But with this constant, the advantage is that TypeScript interprets it as having a different type,
same object, but interpreted differently, understood differently by TypeScript as having this type
of just Mark.
And TypeScript knows that an object of type just Mark has a microsoft value, so that is a valid method
to invoke on it.
Scrolling down, it doesn't look like there are any more issues to be found here.
So I'm going to run NPM, run, test, call and watch to see if everything is good with our spotlight
component.
And there it is.
It's running and fingers crossed.
Give my slow computer a few seconds and there we go.
Everything is passing.
All right.
So that completes our refactor of the spotlight component.
And I will see you in the next lesson.