Alright.
So in the previous lesson we learned about the data method, we can add the data method to any of our
view configuration objects in a view component file and the data method returns a plain JavaScript object
whose properties we can use throughout our HTML template.
For example, if we want to directly inject the value of a property into our template as text, we can
use the curly brace syntax which we see right here with company.
Right now.
Of course, this object, our data object, is not just limited to one property.
We can add as many different properties to it as we want.
So let's practice this idea in this lesson and add a couple more properties and then see some edge cases
as we render them onto the screen.
So let's say I want to put my developer name onto the screen, I want to have my company, and then
let's say I want to have a little bit of text that says developed by followed by our name.
Right?
So I'm going to define another data property called author and I'm going to set it equal to my name,
Boris Pass Cavour.
And you, of course, are welcome to put your name here instead.
All right.
And I want to put this text right after our anchor tag with the company name.
So right below here, I'll add an H2.
And before I add my name, I want to apply some Tailwind classes to my H2.
So I'll just add my class right here.
We're going to make this a Flexbox with the flex class.
We're going to vertically center the content of the Flexbox by using the tailwind items center class.
I also want to make sure that the height of this H2 is the full height of its parent container.
So I'm going to apply the H4 class, which applies a height property set to 100%.
And then I want to add some margin to the left of this H2 element to create some spacing between it
and my company name.
So all of tailwinds margin classes are going to begin with the letter M and then you're going to have
some additional subsets of classes if you want to add margin on only a specific side of the container.
So for example, you're going to have an L for margin left and M are for margin right.
So for example, in this case, I want to add some margin to the left of my age to element.
So if I start with an L dash, these are my margin left utility classes.
You can see there's a whole bunch of them available here in Tailwind as I scroll through them.
You can see the differing values that it adds to the margin left property on the right hand side.
And if I settle on something like MLA eight, that is equal to two RAM or 32 pixels of margin on the
left side of my H2.
So that sounds good to me.
So I'm going to click this into place and then right here I want to combine some text that I have written
in line here in my HTML coupled with my dynamic property, which is author and whatever that happens
to be at the moment.
So I'm just going to write out, developed by and now I want to inject my author name.
So how do we do that?
Just like in the previous lesson, we need to write our curly braces, then write a valid data property.
In this case, author is available so developed by author close off the curly braces, save the file
and let's head to the browser to see the results.
And there you have it.
We have developed by Boris Pass Killer directly in our browser again to our HTML to visit to our browser.
It's just a plain piece of text, but to view it knows that it's combining or concatenating the developed
by text, static text with the dynamic value of the author property.
So here's an interesting question to ask you.
What do you think is going to happen if the author property is not actually defined?
So for example, if I comment out this line and save the file while our data object no longer has an
author property, well, whenever you try to access a property on an object in JavaScript and it's not
available, it doesn't exist, JavaScript returns undefined and the way that Vue interprets undefined
is blank space.
So what's going to happen now is we're not going to get an error on the screen, we're just going to
get nothing.
We're going to get developed by blank because the author property doesn't exist, it evaluates to undefined.
So if I head back to my browser to observe the changes here, you can see it's going to be developed
by blank.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and comment back in the author property and let's say I wanted to represent my name
a little bit differently.
Instead of having a plain string.
Let's say I wanted a extra JavaScript object, a JavaScript object with first name and last name properties.
Well, within this object that we return from our data method, we can provide any kind of value to
any of our properties.
As we mentioned in the previous lesson, we can have strings or numbers or arrays or other objects.
So for example, imagine that author was a nested object in here and we assigned first name and last
name properties.
So I'm once again going to write out my name to first name.
I'm going to assign the string Boris and to last name I'm going to assign my last name of past Cavour.
Although you are more than welcome to provide your own first name and last name here.
So now how do we reference something like this in our template?
Well, we can't just write first name here.
That's not going to work because first name is not available as a top level data property.
Rather, first name is available as a nested property under the author object.
So it's going to work the exact same way it does in vanilla JavaScript.
We first have to reference the author object or the author property, which is available at the top
level of our data object.
And then we can use the dot syntax to access a property on the author object called First Name.
Of course, that's just going to give me developed by Boris and I want to have my full name.
So in order to add another interpellation afterwards, I'm going to add another pair of curly braces
afterwards.
And then here, once again, we want to reference our author property.
We can only reference top level properties on data, and author is one of them.
And then on the author object that the property gives me, I'm going to have a last name property,
and that's what I want to interpolate.
I'm going to save this file and you can see once again, prettier is going to bring the contents onto
a new line.
So it's helping us with both the HTML formatting and the JavaScript formatting, which is great.
But if I head back to my browser.
We're going to see the exact same result.
We have the name of the company coming from the company property on data and my full name coming from
two nested properties on the author object.
All right.
And once again, just so that we are used to this process, this is something that you do a lot when
you're developing a you get used to going to your tools, to your inspector, to going to the view tools.
And it never hurts to check in on any component to make sure the state is what you expect it to be.
So if I click into me now, we can now see we have our company, we have our author, we have the properties
that are available on the object.
And of course we are more than welcome to edit them directly within our view dev tools by clicking this
little pencil icon added value.
And if I change this to something like Mr. Burrus, you can see immediately, even though the property
is nested view is able to understand that reactivity.
So we change the property and immediately view changes the resulting data as it's being rendered onto
our screen.
Right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.