Okay.
So we just ran into a bug in our browser where whenever we selected either an organization or a job
type by itself, we saw that we got no jobs on the right hand side.
So I'm assuming that the bug is going to come from our getter because all our component is doing is
really iterating over that filter job's getter anyway.
So I don't think this bug is going to come from job listings.
I think it's coming from our filter logic right here in this getter.
So at that point, I did a little bit of thinking and I figured out exactly what was going wrong here.
So let me show you the problem here.
I kind of thought about the exact scenario that we had in our browser where we had, for example, a
selected job type, but no selected organization.
So imagine we have a scenario like this in our state.
Imagine for a selected organizations, we have an empty array because the user has not yet selected
any organizations.
Then imagine for the job types, the user selects a job type like let's say, full time.
So we're going to populate that Iran.
We'll think about the logic that's going to happen here whenever we perform this this getter method.
So first, we're going to check if both the lengths of the selected organizations and the selected job
types array are equal to zero.
In this case, only one of them is equal to zero.
These selected organizations one.
But here we're doing it.
And a check, which means no selected organizations will be true, but no selected job types will be
false because we do have an actual job type.
The length of this array is one.
So because this if statement is going to validate to false, we're not going to return all of the jobs.
We're going to proceed to the filter operation down below.
So then we're going to get to this filter method.
But at this juncture, our selected organizations array is still empty.
And what happens when we call the includes method on empty array?
We saw this bug in a section or two ago.
We're always going to get false because an empty array cannot include any element.
It doesn't have any content.
So what happens is on this first filter method, call on line 47.
When we run this 100 times for our jobs, each one of those function invocations returns false.
So what we end up with at the end of this is going to be an array of nothing.
Then we call the filter method.
Here on an array of nothing, there's nothing left to filter.
So we end up with an array of nothing.
And that's what we return from this getter.
And when we have an array of nothing to iterate over on the right hand side, we have no jobs.
So that's the issue.
The problem is this check right here is not really capturing the scenario where we have just one category
of filter selected, such as either job types or either organizations.
It only works for when the page loads and there's nothing selected for both of them.
But when the user selects either one of them, then it breaks.
So why did our code work whenever the user selected both an organization and a job type?
Well, in that case, as soon as the user selected an organization, this array had something.
So once again, this thing would still evaluate to false.
So we would not return to states jobs.
But now we actually had an array of selected organizations to invoke includes on and an array of job
types to invoke includes on.
So when we had both of these selected, this logic would work as expected.
So we're basically handling two out of three scenarios correctly when the page loads and the user has
nothing selected and when the user selects for both an organization and the job type.
However, we do not have the correct logic for when the user selects either one.
So here's how I fix this problem.
What I decided to do is to expand each one of my filter methods to incorporate the check that was in
the original getters right here and right here.
So I removed this if statement, which was kind of an incorrect logic from the beginning.
And instead I did this.
I expanded my function right here.
So I'm going to expand up using curly braces.
So make sure you put a curly brace right here and a curly brace before the final practices.
And then I still want to return whether my selected organization's array includes the current jobs organization.
However, I put my F statement in here.
I said, if there are no selected organizations at all, if the user has not checked any organization
that they want to filter by, I know automatically that this job is something I should include.
Very similar to how we said right here.
If the user has no selected organizations, we want to include all the jobs because there are no filters
to apply.
Similar thing here I am in a filter method, which means I have to return a boolean either true or false
for the given job, but for any given job, for any of the 100 jobs that I'm iterating over.
If the user has not selected an organization for this filter for this check, I do always want to include
the job because I don't want to lose it.
So right here I said if no selected organizations always return.
True.
So if we have no selected organizations, this filter function will run 100 times and it's always going
to be caught online 44 and it's always going to return.
True.
So all of our jobs will pass the filter test.
Otherwise, if the user does have selected organizations, then we'll check whether they include the
current jobs organization.
All right.
And I'm going to apply the exact same logic for the filter below.
So right here, I'm going to expand this to a proper function instead of doing implicit returns.
So add the curly brace here.
Add the curly brace at the end.
Then I'm going to return this evaluation to check whether the current job's job type exists in the users
selected job types.
But I only want this line to run if there are actually selected job types.
If the user does not have any jobs have selected, I want the job that I'm iterating over to always
pass this filter function.
So if no selected job types.
I'm going to return.
True.
So now this is going to cover the scenario where the user has just organization filters or just job
filters or both or neither.
For example, if the user only has job type filters selected, well then I'm going to evaluate to true
right here 100 times for the first for all 100 jobs.
Then I'm going to get an array of hundred jobs right here and then I'm going to filter by just the job
types in reverse.
If the user has selected an organizational filter but not a job to filter, then for the organizational
filters, we're going to run this logic in line 45 for each job, then however many jobs we get and
the resulting array.
Since we have no job types as we filter that array, this line is going to always return true.
And so we're always going to get back the same array that we got from the previous filter operation.
And then if there are both selected organizations and select the job types, then we're simply going
to run this logic here and this logic right here for each of those hundred jobs.
More specifically, we're going to run it first here, get the smaller array, the smaller batch, the
smaller subset.
Then call filter on that array.
So we're going to get all the jobs that fit all the criteria or either one.
So this solution will work.
So if I transition back to my browser.
And now we can see we have a fresh page.
And if I go to job types and I select for something like part time, we can see it works exactly as
we expect.
And then if I go to something like organizations and do something like YouTube, we can see of YouTube
right here.
Everything is working.
And now when I select more ones like Intern, you can see that works part time temporary.
You can do it, you and me.
Everything seems to be updating on the right hand side as I remove these options.
So it looks like everything is working.
We're able to filter by just one filter, by both filter, and, of course, by none of them at all
as well.
All right.
So everything is looking great.
And I will see in the next lesson.