All right.
So we have added a lot of functionality to our job listings component.
We have added the current page.
We have added the conditional router links to the previous and next page.
And I do want to add tests for all of this functionality.
But before we get there, I want to make sure all of our tests are still passing.
So I'm going to go ahead and run NPM, run, test, colon, watch, just to run our full test sweep.
And if you get an issue like this where it says no tests found, that's simply related to your last
get commit.
If you ever see this, just press h run all your tests.
So I'm going to run all of my tests and we're going to see they're all passing.
But we are getting some warnings.
And if I scroll up, we'll see that they're all coming from our job listings tests.
And that's actually an issue that we've seen before several times throughout the course.
You can see the output tells me it failed to resolve component, root or link.
We added these router link components from the view router library.
But of course whenever you test utils mounts our job listings component, it has no clue that Vue router
exists.
So it doesn't know what these router link components are when we're rendering them.
It gets confused and offers us this warning.
So I'm going to open up my job listings test suite.
I'm going to drag it over here on the right.
And we're going to use the exact same solution that we used previously in the course.
We're going to stub out this child component with the available router link stub component from the
view test utils library.
So right here, I'm going to import router link stub that is available directly from view test utils
because replacing router link is such a common operation whenever we're testing a component that utilizes
that child component.
And then where we actually provide that stub is in this global object right here.
And we are getting that global object as part of the master configuration object that we get from calling
create config in every single one of our tests.
And the cool thing about this design is we can simply write our code once right here for the stabbing
and any test that we write moving forward that uses the create config function.
We'll never have to worry about it again.
So right here I'm going to add a new property in my global object called Stubs.
This is a JavaScript object.
And as a reminder, the way this works is the properties here represent the child components and the
value represents what we want to stub it out with, or in other words, what we want to replace it with.
So I want to replace every occurrence of router link.
And the only reason I'm writing this in quotes is because we need to specify the dash here, and that
is not valid syntax for a JavaScript property.
It is valid if it's in quotes, but it's not valid without them.
So I'm going to add that as the name of the component.
I want to step out and of course I want to replace every occurrence of it with router linked stub,
which I just imported from above.
All right.
So now we're going to see that Vue test utils is going to replace every occurrence of router link that
it sees with router link stub.
It knows what router link stub is.
So doesn't care any more about the occurrence of this right here.
It doesn't care where it came from because it's going to replace it anyway.
And you see now that all of our tests are passing and we're getting no warnings.
All right.
So this is a good place to leave off.
And in the very next lesson, we're going to start tackling the tests for all of this functionality.