All right.
So in this lesson, I want to show you how we can track the mutations to the view vector as well as
the view store state changes in our view DevTools in Chrome, it's one of my favorite features because
it allows us to debug the mutations as they flow through the app.
So here I am in my view tab and you'll notice right here we have this section called Components and
if I hover my mouse over it, we're going to see that we have this option called View X and if I click
this and then I click on this route right here, we're going to see our entire view store right here.
So here is our logged in property set to false.
Now the cool thing here is we can actually edit this in line so we can, for example, change this to
true and observe how the changes percolate through our app.
So for example, when I change to true, we're going to see that our main now is going to read that
new state and make these changes right here.
And similarly, if I change it back to false.
We can see how that returns it back to its original state.
But of course, the better way to interact with it is the same way that a user would, which is finding
ways to work with your app in the same way that somebody visiting your site would.
So I just want to show you here, when we click the sign in button, we're going to automatically trigger
that commit method to run and issue limitation of log in user.
And we're going to see the state change automatically.
So there we go.
We can see it flipped from false to true.
So of course, as you're playing around with your code and your implementation.
You can use the browser to make sure that the state is properly adjusting itself to what it should be.
Again, right now, these examples are kind of contrived because they're very simple and our story is
very simple.
We can obviously imagine if you have a very complex view store with 20 properties and multiple properties
are changing.
It's really helpful to look here and just double check that everything is working exactly as it should.
Okay.
There's one additional feature that I want to show you.
I'm just going to refresh the page to get us back to our starting state.
And right here, you'll notice we have this icon right here and this is called the timeline feature.
So if I click on the timeline, the way it works is we're going to see a visual representation here
of a timeline.
So this is just a graphic of time flowing from left to right.
You can see as I drag my mouse, you can see the time updating above down to the millisecond.
So Vue is keeping track of everything that is happening in our app, such as the mouse moving keyboard
events like the user typing component events like components, mounting lifecycle hooks, etc. And every
time we issue a mutation, what the devils are actually going to do is keep track of that mutation and
the corresponding change to your view store.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to select the View X Mutations category and then I'm
going to click the sign in button.
Let me see if I can select it again to refresh it.
There we go.
And you'll notice on the right hand side right here, we're going to see a list of all mutations in
the sequential order in which they happened through the app.
So before we because we clicked on that action button, we triggered the log in user mutation.
So that's going to be here at the very top of the list and then we're going to see how it changed the
View Store.
So at the end of that mutation, running our is logged in property was such a true.
And as we commit multiple mutations throughout the app, we're going to see them all laid out right
here along with their corresponding time.
So you're going to have a sense of how the app was used, what mutations were triggered, what it caused
to the View Store to look like, etc..
So obviously this can be a really cool tool for debugging.
If something is not properly rendering or if something is going wrong, you can walk through the individual
mutations in sequence and see, Oh, here's where I was expecting the store to be updated to this,
but it obviously wasn't.
So this is where something went wrong.
This is where my logic may be incorrect.
All right.
So this view X mutations feature in the timeline as well as the store in the actual inspector mode.
Inspector view is another way you can take a look at the state.
Both of these are really great tools and really awesome features of the view tools in Chrome that allow
you to debug your app very effectively.
All right.
So with that, I will see you next lesson.