Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to fix up our last four failing tests for our job listings component.
And as we can see here, these tests all deal with showing a link to either the previous page or the
next page in certain scenarios.
And all of this logic is now dependent on the previous page and next page properties that we get from
our used previous and next pages composable.
So this is going to be the most critical composable to mock out in these tests because these values
affect the logic up here that works with the VRF to determine whether we render a link to the previous
page and to the next page.
So once again, let me copy a sample section of marks from above.
So let's go to our first test.
I'm just going to copy this right here.
And once again, we're just going to need to modify it so it fits the current test that we are in.
So let's scroll down right here and paste this right here and think about what this test is telling
us self when the user is on the first page of job results.
So immediately what that tells me is our use current page composable right here can not have a value
of two.
It needs to have a value of one.
And once again, as we saw in the previous lesson, just to be safe right here, because this is something
that is going to be rendered to the DOM, instead of providing a mock object, I am going to use a real
rough object right here, a reactive object created by ref and I'm going to provide a value of one.
So this is honoring the scenario I've described in my describe when the user's on the first page of
job results and it does not show link to the previous page.
All right.
So do I care about filter jobs?
Not really.
My logic here for rendering that previous page is not dependent on filter jobs, so it can be an empty
array, not a problem.
Now use previous and next pages does matter because again I want to communicate to a reader a real world
scenario.
So if I'm currently on page one of job results, my previous page is not going to be one.
It's going to be undefined, and my next page is going to be whatever we want.
Let's say to in this scenario, it can also be undefined if we don't have a next page.
But in this case, let's do two.
Now, once again to remind you, if we want it to be super realistic, previous page would not just
be undefined.
It would be a reactive object with a value of undefined, and next page would not just be the number
two.
It would be a reactive object with a value of two, or at a bare minimum, any JavaScript object with
a value property set to two.
And if we get to that point where we have to use something like Ref, I'm okay with that, just like
we did in the previous lesson with use current page and using ref right here.
However, if I'm able to also get the test to pass without involving a real view reactive object and
instead relying on objects in my own domain, under my own control, my own mocks, I consider that
a victory.
So let's start out with this basic object and see if it's good enough to play the role.
Because in theory, if we simply do structure right here undefined for previous page and two for next
page, if we're not using this anywhere else where we need a value property and we're simply returning
those properties right here and then using them for a VRF, even if they're playing values like undefined
in to view, will still know how to deal with them in the same way that view will know how to deal with
the real reactive objects when we actually use the real composable.
Right.
But for the purposes of this test, it's okay to simply return the basic primitives that the reactive
object is covering up or wrapping.
Right?
So let's see if our test pass and if that in if it does, then that's great.
No need to make it more complex.
So right here we no longer care about query params.
We no longer care about our route or our create store.
We no longer care about the two arguments we are passing to our create config function.
Let's focus on this test and let's see what we get.
You can do that.
And it passes.
Wonderful.
So now let's repeat this exact same logic.
So I'm going to copy this one below.
And remember, our describe lock is once again the same.
So when users on the first page of job results.
So I'm going to keep most of this logic and let's see what's going to be different here in this test.
Okay.
So this test is concerned about the next page.
So it's looking for a totally different data test attribute of next page link in comparison to previous
page link.
So I actually think the good news here is that our set up remains exactly the same when user is on first
page of job results, we've got that covered with use current page returning one.
If the user is on page one and there is a next page too, then we should show a link to that next page
too.
So all of our set up here in our mocks looks good to me.
So all we can do here is clear out all of this former code.
We do not need the query params.
We don't need create root.
Here's our former mock store.
See how much we're cleaning up here and how easier it's making the test.
And so right here we can remove these two arguments, focus on this test right here with zip and save
that.
Let's see how that works.
And indeed, it passes, which is great news.
Okay.
And I just want to reiterate here, because we did kind of move from a factory function architecture
to a marking out in every test.
If for some reason you had a really complex object here that you wanted to use as your mock return value,
you're totally welcome to create a factory function that serves the exact purpose as it did earlier
in the course.
It may have, for example, five properties with default values, but also allow the acceptance of an
object whose properties you to structure so that each test has a reasonable default, but also can provide
custom values for properties that it cares about.
So we don't have to mark out everything in here.
We don't have to write and duplicate all of this logic in line.
We can totally extract it to you.
Factory functions.
At this point, I hope you've had enough experience seeing how we establish those earlier in the course
so that we don't have to worry about it.
But I'm just saying that as as a general take away, once again, if you see duplication and you think
that you can move it elsewhere and you don't require the user to scroll up to have to understand what
it means for the given test.
I think that's a victory and that's totally fine.
For now, these tests are to me at least pretty clean, pretty short, pretty easy to read.
And so I don't mind if I'm manually writing out all these marks and all the objects they return, the
reactive objects.
That is, I don't mind in line because they're not that complex.
And I still think it's pretty easy to read.
That's in comparison to our previous case where we had, for example, a really complex mock store which
had a getters property, you know, with its own complex object.
Or another example is our config object for these shall amount, right?
There's so many possible nested properties that we had there, a global mock stubs, props, etc.,
that it made sense to extract it to something like this.
But again, it's sort of your own value call when you want to make that move.
All right.
So let's go ahead and remove fit right here.
And now we only have two more tests to address.
So I'm going to copy what we have right here.
And bring it on down.
So what is the difference with this test?
This one is when a user is on the last page of job results.
So we kind of have to flip things around.
When the user is on the last page of job results, it does not show link to next page.
So let's say our current page is going to be two.
We do not care about filter jobs.
If the user is on page two, what we can say is the previous page is going to be one.
And if we want the user to be on the last page of job results, then there should be no next page.
We can't be on page two and also have a next page of two.
So as you may recall, from our implementation of use previous next pages, it returns undefined whenever
there is no next page in the same way that right here it returns undefined whenever there is no previous
page.
Now technically in JavaScript terms, I forgot to mention this having a property manually assigned to
undefined is the exact same as if we never included it in the first place.
So we could totally do this.
Just remove line eight.
But I want to be a little bit more explicit here, even if it's not JavaScript.
Best practice to write undefined.
Mainly just because once again, I care more about readability and making sure it's understood that
next page is undefined and that that is important for this test versus letting that be implicit logic
that the person has to know about the JavaScript programming language to understand.
All right, so even though accessing next page on an object without a next page property will always
get undefined, I'm going to manually define it right here.
So that reminds the person that there is no next page and that this composable is what's responsible
for why the component does not render a link to the next page.
All right.
So with that, once again, remove all this wonderful code.
Good to know.
Yeah.
And right here, we don't need these two parameters.
Save that.
Focus on it with fit.
Let's see if that works and indeed does.
Let's look fit.
Let's copy this logic below.
I think it's going to stay the exact same because once again, our setup logic is the same.
When user is on last page of job results, it shows link to previous page.
Our last page in this scenario is page two.
We have a previous page of one and that's ultimately what we're testing for that we are going to see
that link render somewhere.
So once again, let's remove query params, root our store and our two functions right here.
Once again, apologies not to functions, but to arguments to our function.
Save that.
And it looks like everything is passing right in my test window.
I'm just going to press you and press a we're going to run all of my tests that I have throughout my
entire test suite and now across 23 test suites, in other words, 23 files and 71 tests.
Everything is passing and on my end everything is passing in two and a half seconds.
So our tests are all running pretty quickly, which is a good sign, by the way, that we are marking
things out effectively and not dealing with a lot of complex operations.
This is, I think, pretty good to run 75 assertions or almost 75 assertions in less than two one half
seconds.
All right.
So that completes our fixing of the failing jobless things test sweep.
And I will see you in the next lesson.