Okay.
So moving right along.
The next thing I want to do is to write a test for the mutation that I want to add that's going to actually
accept the array of selected degrees and then overwrite the selected degree's property on my view store
state.
Now over the course of the last couple of lessons, I realize it may seem like we've been doing a lot
of work on the bookstore side of things the state, the mutations, the getters, etc. But I argue that
that is actually a good sign.
The fact that we haven't gotten to our component yet is a sign that we've moved a lot of this complexity
away from the component upwards, from the component into the bookstore state, where it can live as
much more simpler JavaScript functions and methods that can also be tested in isolation.
We are effectively decoupling ourselves more and more from the idea of a view component specifically
and storing all of our logic is in there, which overall is a pretty good thing because even though
we are relying on View X, which is its own dependency, all of this is, at the end of the day is just
core JavaScript or TypeScript code, and it would be a lot easier to migrate this into another library,
for example, because it's just vanilla JavaScript typescript, it's just a core language compared to
coupling ourselves to the actual view component itself.
So the fact that we've been mostly working in TypeScript files instead of view component files, I argue
is a good thing.
With that said, let's go ahead and wire up our new ADD selected degrees mutation.
And of course that will accept a string array of degrees based on the checkboxes that the user has currently
selected from our eventual component.
We don't have it yet, but we will have it shortly.
And then of course, we're going to overwrite our selected degrees property on the View Store State.
Remember, the way we designed this earlier is every time the user clicks a checkbox, it's going to
generate a brand new array with the most up to date selections.
And so we can always just overwrite the property.
We don't need to merge it with our previous selected degrees array or anything like that.
We can simply override it and it should just work.
All right, so right here in my mutations test, that's fine.
I'm going to scroll down.
And we have two very similar tests for our other mutations to add to the user selections.
So let's add another described block right here.
And I would call this eventual mutation add selected degrees.
And what will this mutation be responsible for?
It keeps track of which degrees the user has chosen to filter jobs by.
All right.
It's going to be very similar to what we have above.
We're going to have a starting state.
So I can say starting state.
For some reason, I think the O key on my keyboard is a little rebellious today, but we're going to
have a starting state.
We're going to use our create state helper function.
And of course, the property that we care about for this test is going to be selected degrees.
And we're going to clarify to a future reader that it's going to start out as an empty array, even
though that's the default.
And then, of course, I want to run my eventual mutation to mutations.
I'm going to run my new mutation, which doesn't exist yet, which is going to be called add selected
degrees.
And we know that mutation accepts as its first argument the current state as it is.
I'm going to pass in my starting state and then my second argument can be whatever I want and obviously
I want it to be my array of strings representing the selected degrees.
So maybe here I can provide an array of strings like masters and bachelors.
All right.
And then after the mutation runs, what do I expect?
I expect that my starting state's selected degrees property will be updated from an empty array to an
array of these two strings that I provided right here.
Expect starting state.
Dot selected degrees to now equal an array with the exact same values of master's and bachelor's.
All right.
So again, TypeScript is going to first complain that it doesn't realize this name.
Not a problem.
We need to add it.
Which means?
Which means we need to go to our constants file and add it.
Let's open up constants.
That's.
All right.
And in here, we can add a new one, and let's do it.
How about right here?
Export const, add selected degrees is going to be a string of add selected degrees.
There we go.
Save that file.
And that allows us to import it right here.
So right here I can add selected degrees as an import.
So now I have that constant name to represent my mutation method name.
So right here I'm going to add that method name, add selected degrees, and here I'm going to define
the body of my mutation method.
The first argument to any mutation is always going to be the current view or state that is so that the
mutation can update it.
That's the whole point of a mutation is to mutate, store state.
So that of course is going to be uptight global state.
And then the second and third parameters or however many we want is up to us.
Obviously, in this case I want to receive a string array and that is going to represent my degrees
that the user has selected it from the eventual checkboxes.
So right here I will say I will expect an array of degrees which is going to be a string array.
And then of course all that's left to do in the body is to overwrite the correct property.
So on my state, I'm going to have a certain amount of properties which TypeScript is also going to
validate for me.
So I know I have a selected degrees array and I'm simply going to overwrite it with my new degrees string.
A rate selected degrees, remember is not an array of degree objects, it is an array of strings.
So TypeScript says you're trying to overwrite an array of strings with a new array of strings that's
totally valid, the types match.
So I'm going to allow that.
And when I save that, we should now get a passing test.
We.
Give it a second to run.
And there we go.
Everything is passing.
All right.
So there is our mutation to actually update selected degrees.
Once we update the selected degrees array, we know that our getters will rerun, which includes the
filter jobs getter that we worked on in the previous lesson.
It will rerun.
It will now have a new selected degrees array to rely on in those helper getters that are checking whether
the actual array of selected degrees includes a given job's degree, etc..
So now all of the puzzle pieces are kind of starting to come together, all right?
And hopefully very soon we're going to be able to get to our actual component implementation.
And you're going to see how easy it's going to be, because so much of the logic is already written
on the view side of things.
So with that, I'll leave you to enjoy what we learned this lesson.
And I will see you in the next one.