Okay.
So our filter jobs getter is working effectively in the browser.
And this, I think, is a great first solution.
It's a great initial implementation, but I argue we can do a little bit better.
So first, let's talk about what I don't like within this getter method.
The primary thing that I don't like is that this getter method I think, knows a bit too much.
It's combining a lot of different concepts and filters together, and that is increasing the scope,
the size and the complexity of this getter.
So this getter needs to know about multiple properties of the View Store, like selected organizations
and selected job types.
It needs to know about different properties on the job object, such as organized organization and job
type.
And you can imagine that if we were to allow the user to filter by more criteria, that would result
in us adding more filter method calls and the method would continue to grow in size.
Another way that I can sort of make this argument or try to prove this to you is to ask you to consider
what a test suite would look like for this filter jobs getter.
When we were starting out, I initially skipped writing tests for this getter.
So this getter is currently untested and I would ask you to consider all of the different pathways of
logic, all of the different branches and all of the different permutations and combinations of ways
that this method could work and thus be tested right.
In our tests, we would have to cover a scenario where there are no selected organizations and where
there are.
I would need to cover a scenario where there are selected job types and where there are not.
Then scenarios where the selected organization's array does include the jobs organization and where
it does not.
Scenarios where the selected job types does include the jobs, job type and not.
And if you start mixing all those scenarios, that's a lot of different permutations and combinations.
There's actually multiple responsibilities in this getter, if you think about it, right, in order
to figure out whether a job should be included by its organization.
We do need to know that it has an organization property and we do need to know about these selected
organizations, part of the bookstore.
But we don't really care about the job types or the job type property on the job.
So these two filter pieces of logic are kind of separate.
They're kind of independent, but yet we've packed them into this method.
And that was fine initially because that was our original goal.
We had two separate independent getters and we're trying to combine them into one and we succeeded.
But now we sort of have this own kind of new problem of increasing complexity.
The basic takeaway here is I think there's a way we can build this to be a little bit leaner and meaner
and to keep the best of all worlds, to have smaller getter methods that focus on one responsibility,
such as just organizations or just job types, but then combine them into a larger getter like filter
jobs.
So the first key takeaway that I have for you is that in a getter method in Vue X, we can actually
invoke or call other getter methods.
We have not done this yet because all of our getters so far have been single independent operations.
But we can actually transfer control to another getter.
We can call another getter just like we call another method within a single method in JavaScript.
So knowing that we can create smaller getter methods.
The next question is what kind of getter method do we want to create?
Well, I'm going to propose a solution to you right now, and then we're going to implement it.
And it may not seem readily apparent at the beginning how it's going to help, but I promise you it's
going to slim down the complexity of this implementation.
So what I propose we do is to create a getter whose responsibility it will be to tell us whether a single
job should be included based on its organization being present in this selected organization.
Slice of the View Store.
That will be the first small getter that we're going to write.
Then I also want to write a second smaller getter method, and its responsibility will be to tell me
whether a single job should be included in the filter jobs based on that jobs job type being present
in selected job types.
So currently all of our getters are relying on the view extra state and they're getting all of the jobs
from state jobs.
However, imagine that we had a getter that only focused on one job at a time.
It would still get the View Store state and it would get one job at a time and it would simply give
me back a boolean, true or false, whether that job should or should not be included based on its correct
validation within the right property in the view X Store State.
So I know it's a little bit complex, but let's start building out and hopefully it'll all come together
as we make our solution over the next couple lessons.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go to my constant status farm and here I'm going to define two
new constants for the two new getter methods that we're going to eventually write.
And we're going to invoke those getter methods in our filter jobs getter eventually.
For now, we're just going to write them out.
So my first getter that I'm going to write is going to be called in.
Job by organization.
My goal with this name is to say this letter will tell me whether or not I should or should not include
a job by its organization.
So this getter will be responsible for using the jobs organization and checking with these selected
organizations.
Slice of the View Store.
So I'm going to call this constant like so and I'm going to give it my texture of include job by organization.
The name here isn't perfect, but I'm saying I include job by its organization.
Similarly here, I'm going to have another constant called include job by job type.
So this is going to be eventually a getter that's going to tell me whether I should include a single
job by its job type.
So I'm going to say include job by job type.
All right.
So I'm going to close my concerns file.
And here we are on getters and we can start by importing our two getter constants above.
So our two new ones are called include job by organization.
And include job by job type.
All right.
So I'm going to start writing those get our methods in just a second.
But first, I want to take you to the official view X documentation in the browser, because the syntax
for writing a getter that's going to accept an additional argument is a little bit different from what
you might expect and certainly different from what we've done before with things like mutations.
So let me transition immediately to the View X documentation.
And here we have an example.
You can see here it says you can pass arguments to getters by returning a function from the getter.
Okay?
So typically the getters that we've written so far have returned data structures like sets or arrays
or objects, but we can also return functions from our getters and view.
X knows that whenever we return a function, it needs to invoke that function with whatever arguments
we pass to the original getter method.
Okay.
It's a little bit confusing, but let's take a look at this example right here and the syntax and then
we'll implemented in a relevant example in our code.
So in this example in the docs, we have a getter called get to do by ID.
And what we're doing here is actually using ES6 arrow syntax to define a method.
This is still a method for using an alternate syntax to define it.
So here you can see, just like any getter method, this getter would receive the state as the very
first parameter to that getter method.
However, what we're doing here or what the documentation is doing is it's implicitly returning a function.
All right.
So right here, what I have here with this arrow selected and this idea, this is a single arrow function
that accepts an IED parameter.
And then here is the function body.
So to reiterate, get to do buy ID is a getter method whose return value is a function that accepts
an ID parameter.
So this function body right here is the body of the function that is returned.
It is not in itself the body of the getter method.
The getter method returns the function that has this body.
Okay.
And it is in the returned function that we returned from the getter method that we can define whatever
parameter we want.
In this case, the developers define a parameter called ID.
And due to a JavaScript feature called closures in the nested function body, here we are able to use
parameters from any functions, either at this scope or any functions at a scope above.
So in the body of the return function, we're going to have access to the view or state parameter from
our original getter method and also to the ID parameter from the returned function, from the getter
method.
As you can see here, we're using ID right here that's coming from here and we're using state which
is coming from here.
So down below we have an example of an invocation of the letter.
We're accessing the getters property in our store.
We're invoking the get to do by I'd getter notice that we do not have to pass in the view X or state
because view X does that for us automatically.
Instead, what we pass in is the arguments to the returned function from the getter.
So this two represents the argument for the i d parameter.
Basically, the way that view x works is it looks at your getter method and says, okay, you're returning
a function.
So I'm going to treat that function as the function I have to invoke to get the effective return value.
And that's the function to which I'm going to pass the arguments that you're going to give me.
So behind the scenes, View X is still going to run the getter.
It's going to give the state automatically the View X Store as it is.
It's going to get back a return value of a function.
And then to that function is what it's going to pass the arguments that are provided in line here.
In this case, the number two is going to go to ID, right?
So the key takeaway here is if we define a getter that is a method that returns a function, that is
how we can incorporate arguments into getters.
And what we want to do in this code is allow our getter to receive a single job as an argument.
So let's transition back to this code.
And let's say right here above filter jobs, I can write the first of my two getters.
So my first getter is called include Job.
My organization, and I'm going to use that special syntax, which is the colon, and then I'm going
to define my arrow function.
So here I am defining my first parameter, which is always going to be the View Store State.
And if I wanted to, I can do a regular function body like so and treat this like a regular getter.
I could return, you know, a basic data structure here, like an array.
This is totally valid syntax.
This is just to demonstrate the alternative way that we can define a method compared to the one that
we did above or below where we do not have arrow function syntax.
So this is totally valid, but we don't want this getter to return an array.
We want it to return a function that's going to return something else.
So we're going to make our getter method return a function with a body.
And in this arrow function, we're going to define a single parameter called job.
So in the body here of that return function, we can assume that we're going to have access to the View
X Store state via the name state and to a single job, via the name job.
We haven't talked yet about how we're going to invoke this getter and feed it a job.
We'll talk more about that later.
But let's assume now that we're going to have a single job object and we have the View Store State,
which means we have everything we need to determine whether or not we should include that job or not.
So I'm going to have this getter return a boolean, either true or false.
And the logic is basically going to be a copy of the organization logic right here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is on my state, I'm going to look at these selected organizations,
right?
I'm going to check its length and I'm going to see if it's zero.
If it's zero, then the user has not selected any organizations.
So I always want to include this job.
I don't want to accidentally leave it out.
I want to say this job should always be included.
I don't even care about its property of organization.
I always want to include it because the user is not filtered by any specific organizations.
So I'm going to return.
True.
Basically what we're doing here is the exact same logic that we implemented right here in line 49.
We're just moving it to a separate function up above a separate getter.
Then what I want to do is repeat this exact same logic I have in line FIFO, so I'm just going to copy
and paste it right here.
So what I'm going to do is for the individual single job that I get excuse me, for the individual job
that I'm going to get, I'm going to look at it's organization property, and I'm going to see if that
is found within selected organizations, which I have access to because I have the View Store State.
So this getter is going to return a true or a false, and that's the entire responsibility of the getter.
All right.
I'm going to repeat this process by running a similar getter for my include job by job type getter or
constant.
So once again, this is going to be a getter that's going to receive state.
And it's going to return a function.
All right.
And that function's going to accept the single job as a parameter.
And the responsibility of this function will be to return a boolean that reflects whether or not the
job should be included by its job type.
So once again, it's going to be very similar to what we have above where first going to check.
If these selected job types array on my view x store state is empty.
If that is the case, then I want to return true because I don't care about the specifics of the job.
I always want to return true to make sure I include that job in the event in the eventual array of filter
jobs.
And then I'm just going to copy this line right here on line 58.
Otherwise, if the user has selected job types or to be more technical, if our view store state selected
job types property has values, check whether the current job's job type is found.
And so this will return true or false.
So no matter which line we end on, I'm always going to produce a boolean, either true or false for
both of these getters.
All right.
So we have started to slowly extract the logic from here into smaller getters that take care of a single
job.
We haven't actually used these getters yet, but hopefully the basic beginning of the picture is starting
to become clearer in the sense that we're starting to isolate the logic that we have here in much smaller
getters that we're eventually going to utilize in our filter jobs getter method.
All right.
So we're going to chip away more at this approach in upcoming lessons.
But first, let's write some tests for our brand new getter methods.
I'll see you in the next lesson.