Okay.
So our job listings component is now utilizing the composition API.
We've moved a lot of logic into smaller, more lightweight, more easily tested composable functions,
and you can see the setup method has diminished in size significantly.
Now as a reminder, the way job listings works is it gets to filter jobs from you.
And then it uses the displayed jobs computed function here to slice the correct array of ten jobs from
the original array of filter jobs.
And once it has that array of ten job objects, it iterates over them using the V4 directive and it
renders a job listing component for each one of them.
And if I go to the job listing component right here in job listing, that view and I scroll to the bottom,
will see that this component is still utilizing the Options API.
But luckily it's super simple.
It just has a single computed property.
So it's going to be really quick for us to quickly move this to the composition API.
All right.
So once again, I'm going to comment this out right here.
I'm going to provide a setup method.
We are going to need to utilize props right here because this one is relying on the job prop.
You can see job is an object that flows in and it has an idea property that we care about.
So right here, I'm going to provide my props as the first argument and I'm going to need to define
a computed evaluation right here since this one is using something called job page link.
That's what I'll call my constant here as well.
So constant job page link.
And in order to have something that reevaluates whenever the props update, I'll need to use a computed
function.
So right here I will import computed.
From view.
And right here, I'm going to say that it's going to be a computed function that we're going to reevaluate
whenever we get a new prop value.
And right here, I'm simply going to return and interpolate string the exact same thing I have right
here.
So I want slash jobs, slash results, and then I'm going to interpolate something.
We no longer have access to this that job, but we do have access to props dot job and that is a reactive
object.
So we can simply reference it or any properties on it like so.
And because we're not de structuring and the object is reactive, whenever the job object changes or
even when the props object changes, this thing will re-evaluate and give us a new computed URL, which
is the job page link.
And then all we have to do is return it right here as an available property in the object right here.
Return that which allows us to get rid of computed properties.
Save that and now we have a new composition API implementation.
The only reason I really wanted to do that is just because this is so critical to how job listings works.
And since we are using Composition API here, I also wanted to make sure we were using Composition API
in the child component.
And with that, all of our tests are passing.
And if I navigate back to my browser because it's been a while since we've been in here, everything
is still working on this page.
So I'm going to refresh it.
We're going to start out with 100 jobs in the page here on my job types.
You can see as I select them, the jobs in the right are going to update accordingly.
Everything is still working as far as the next page is working or the next page link, the previous
page link as well, it's going to scroll in to the top.
The key takeaway, of course, is that all of our transition to composable functions and everything
we've been working on in this section, everything is still functioning.
Everything, everything is still working for our job listings component and still providing value to
the user.
All right.
So with that, we have wrapped up our third section on the composition API.
And hopefully this has been a lot of practice and a lot of reaped a lot of benefits as far as getting
a chance to write a lot of these composable functions is a lot of the helper functions that Vue gives
us, like I use route, use, store, use router, etc. and with that we are good to wrap up the section
in the very next lesson.
I will see you there.