Okay.
So as always, I think it'd be a good idea to refactor our test suite by relying on a factory function
to generate our configuration object for the mount function that will allow us to remove some duplication
from each test, such as this set up right here, which focuses on the stubbing of the font.
Awesome icon.
That is some required configuration that we really don't want each test to have to worry about.
So here inside my first described block, I will create a new arrow function which I will call create
config.
I will allow my function to accept a single config parameter and I will give config a default argument
of a empty JavaScript object.
And then using this syntax, I will implicitly return a JavaScript object and I think we can start by
copying this code from our very first test.
This seems like a reasonable setup, so I'm going to paste that above and then of course I'm going to
allow each test to customize its properties on my configuration object by structuring the config parameter
that I pass in.
So if any test wants to give me a custom global property or a custom props property or a custom slots
property, it totally can.
All right.
So down below here.
We can once again have a discussion in which things matter for this test.
Do I really care about the stubbing out of awesome icon to test that the component renders the child?
I do not.
Do I really care about the props?
What I really care about is the use of this section right here, that whatever slot I provide this component,
it's able to render it within the accordion.
Right.
So what I'm going to do is come up with a compromise right here.
I'm going to create a slots object.
I'm going to give it this default property with our original H3 right here.
And then I'm going to create my custom config object, which will just be my slots object above.
And then finally, I'm going to create my wrapper and I'm going to mount my accordion.
Invoke create config from above and pass in my custom config object.
So what's going to happen?
We're going to pass in an argument of slots, which means we're going to keep all of this original content.
And then my config object destruction is going to overwrite the slots right here.
Granted, I am overwriting it with the exact same thing as it is originally in my factory, but I'm
totally okay with this.
And the reason I'm okay with this is because I want the test to communicate what matters and what matters
is.
Here I have this content of my nested child.
That's exactly what I'm testing for right here.
And so I'm giving a future reader a better understanding of how this test is working.
Okay, so with the elimination of our setup, we can remove our former assignment right here.
Make it a little bit cleaner.
Save that we can do something very similar down below in this test.
I don't care about the idea of slots because the idea is I want to test that I'm falling back to a default.
So right here I'm going to create a slots object, but this time it's simply going to be empty.
I'm trying to communicate that the slots are irrelevant or not configured for this test.
I'm going to create my config object.
I'm similarly going to give it the slots property using s syntax to reference the empty object above.
And then instead of our former code right here.
I'm going to create a wrapper that is going to be the result of mounting my accordion and passing in
a configuration object which I will generate using my create config function above passing in my custom
config that I configured just for this test.
Save this a test to become a little bit leaner, a little bit easier to read and are still communicating
the importance of each one.
In this one, the slots do not matter.
In this one the slots do, and all of the other kind of redundant work like having to provide some kind
of prop having to stop out the font.
Awesome icon.
I'm going to leave that up in the file.
If a developer wants to scroll up and find out this extra information, it is helpful, but it is not
required to understand what each individual test is doing.
So with that, and I'm feeling pretty good about our accordion test, we and I will see in the next
lesson.