All right.
So there's just one more detail that I'd like to mention about the two refs function, and that is that
it only accepts a reactive object as its argument.
It cannot accept a plain JavaScript object.
So we saw this example in the previous lesson we were able to pass in person to the two refs.
The function because person is a reactive object from the reactive function in view.
So let's see what happens if I remove this reactive function call and I reduce person back to a plane
JavaScript object.
If I now try to pass this in to two refs, we're actually going to get a warning.
It's going to say to refs expects a reactive object but received a plain one.
So the object that we passed the two refs must already be reactive so that the function can iterate
over its properties, take each individual one and its respective value and make all of them reactive.
To give you back a brand new object where each individual property is reactive compared to the whole
original reactive object, which is just one reactive reference to a whole object.
Of course, if you wanted something like this to work, it's not a problem.
We can just wrap our person object in the reactive function that will return a reactive object whose
properties we will then make all reactive using the two refs function.
So this syntax will work just fine.
It's the exact same ideas what we did in the previous lesson, except we're all doing it in a single
line.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.