All right.
So at the end of the previous lesson, we saw that we were still seeing an error in this code whenever
we were testing our job search form component.
And to be honest, when I was developing these lessons, I was a little bit confused myself.
I wasn't sure what was going on because the test looked good to me.
So of course I did what any good developer does.
I went to Google and I tried to find some help on a site like Stack Overflow.
So the term I searched for was Vue test form submit because one I want to test is the submission form
specifically in Vue.
And of course I found this page right here in StackOverflow.
And let me show you exactly the process that I followed to solve this issue.
I read through this a query or question that a user posted and it said, Is there a way to actually
trigger the submission of a form by clicking on a submit button in a view unit test?
Let's take this simple component.
They have a template with a form and a button.
You can see they're also using that submit prevent event modifier and they say, I want to test that
submit prevents gets triggered when the button is clicked and therefore the event is emitted.
When I run this in the browser, everything works as expected.
The exact same thing is true for us.
But the following test fails.
Right?
And we can sort of see that the problem is very similar to ours.
So I scroll down a little bit, looked at the very first solution, and I said, the issue is that Vue
test utils does not attach DOM nodes to the document by default.
I'm guessing because the idea of a form submission has something to do with rendering this actual view
component in the browser.
We're not technically doing that in a view test utils test because it's kind of mounting the component
in isolation, not necessarily in the browser environment.
That's kind of what the issue is coming from.
And I actually didn't even read through most of this statement.
I saw that there was a link to this complementary helper method called Attach to document.
So I went to this link which actually took me to the view test utils documentation and unfortunately
the recommended approach which was attached to document is deprecated and it will be removed in future
releases.
So I was thinking to myself, great, whatever the recommended approaches is apparently deprecated,
but I saw here that it said is deprecated.
However we can use attached to instead, for example, if you need to attach the component to the document
body.
So the document of course is the core object within a browser.
It represents the web page.
And I think what this is trying to do is to force the component to simulate the mounting of it to an
actual element in a simulated document, in a simulated browser environment, which of course doesn't
actually practically exist in our test.
So I just saw this code right here attached to a document body in the configuration object that was
passed to a mount function.
And I said to myself, Let me try this out.
Let me see if this actually works in my tests.
So I simply copy this code and I went back to my component.
And right here, this is not within my global object, this is still part of our configuration object,
but not inside that nested one.
So I simply attach to document that body, save the file and we ran and was able to get the to pass.
So I think my hunch is that this is somehow attaching this mounted component to a simulated browser
document.
I'm not exactly sure, but it did get the test to pass.
And furthermore, I think it's not it wasn't super important for me to understand every nitty gritty
detail of what it did as long as it made the test pass.
And as long as I could verify that the test was testing exactly what I expected, then I would feel
pretty good that we were testing the right functionality of the component.
And by the way, whenever you have a situation like this, when a test is passing, it's generally a
good idea to try to modify your test suite to make sure that it fails, just to make sure that you're
not getting a false positive.
So for example, I can add an extra Z here and save this just to make sure that we do get a proper failure.
We can see here that we do have a number of calls equal to one, which means our push method is correctly
being invoked at least once.
And then right here we can see that the view or rather the view test utils ingest can identify that
the issue is that we were expecting to get Vue developers with a Z, but the actual component gave us
view developer as expected.
So by seeing this failure, we can be certain that our positive assertion or our test passing is working
as expected rather than just accidentally passing.
For example, if you have sometimes an asynchronous problem where the test finishes up before the actual
session is run, I'd seen that happen before.
That can give you a false positive.
That can give you a green test that is passing, that is not actually testing anything.
By ensuring that we have the expected failure here, we can sort of be certain that our test is running
through the component, properly setting the values, invoking the push method, etc. And once we have
that confidence that it is failing properly, then we can indeed get it to pass as expected.
So I'm going to remove that Z, bring us back to a passing test and that is where we want to be with
the job search form test.
So I think this is a good place to leave off this section.
We have built this job search form component.
We have correctly captured the user's input in these text input components.
We have packaged it up and routed it to our next page, which is the job results page.
And we have attached those properties which exist as data on this component as part of the query params
on that other route.
So we have found a way to transfer information from one view to the other and we have also tested it.
All right.
So this is a good place to leave off, and I will see you in the next lesson.