Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to add a third test, and I might consider this test to be a little bit excessive.
I'm not always going to be a fan of this test, but I do want to double check that we are correctly
trimming the input.
In other words, I want to validate that if the user gives me an input with whitespace, I want to make
sure that the value I am sending to the View X Store does not have it.
The reason this is technically not a great test is because we are testing core view functionality.
We are validating that the trim input modifier is working as expected and it is not our job or responsibility
to test the view library.
Those tests belong in view.
They're not specific to our app, however, because this functionality is so critical to how our logic
in the store is going to work to filter the jobs correctly.
Just for my own sanity, I feel comfortable kind of violating that best practice and just adding a single
test to make sure my term is being trimmed.
And the good news is, it's going to be pretty simple to write this test.
So what I'm going to do is copy my previous test from the last lesson, paste the below, and I'm going
to change my description here to be.
It removes whitespace from user input and most of my test setup is going to stay exactly the same.
So I'm going to keep track of my commit just function.
I'm going to mount the component, look for the input and enter a value.
And the key difference here is in going to modify this value, of course, to have a whole bunch of
spaces.
It doesn't matter how many you put, let's just put a couple at the very beginning and very end.
And we're going to verify that what we send off to our View X Store, which of course is testing what
commit has been invoked with, should be not this string but the trend string.
So these arguments are going to be the exact same as they were in the previous lesson.
Just view developer with no space at the beginning or end.
So we are testing that view as correctly removing this.
All right.
So say that that should correctly work.
There we go.
And if we want to validate that that is not working, we can, of course, remove trim and that should
get it to fail because View X should receive the full string.
Right now you can see it's going to say, Hey, you told me to expect this string, but instead I'm
getting the original string, which proves that trim is working correctly.
So right here I'm going to add Trim back in.
And now we are validating this logic that we have it right here.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover here.
And I think I'm pretty happy with the tests we have for our job, the sidebar skills component.
So the next lesson, we can move on to implementing our actual filter jobs getter.
So I'll see you there.