All right.
So in this lesson, we'll talk about declaring types for functions, both traditional functions and
arrow functions.
And there's actually two pieces we have to worry about.
The first is declaring types for the parameters of the function, and the second is declaring the type
of the functions return value.
So let's dive right into it.
Let's say I'm going to define a function called Multiply, which will accept two numbers, multiply
them and return their product.
So in traditional JavaScript that would look like this, I would have a function, I would call it multiply.
I'm going to provide it with two parameters and let's call them A and B.
And here in the body of this function, I'm going to return the product, which means multiplying A
by B, so immediately you can see that TypeScript is not happy.
And if I hover my mouse over the two violations, it's going to tell us.
Parameter A implicitly has an any type and parameter B also implicitly has an any type.
In other words, TypeScript is unable to infer what the type of these values is, which affects its
ability to calculate whether the body of the function is performing its logic correctly.
So the syntax for declaring parameter types is basically the exact same as declaring types for variables
or constants.
We're going to put a colon followed by the actual type.
So right here for a I'm going to provide a colon in a space and then tell TypeScript that A is going
to be a number.
And right here for B, the exact same thing, a colon and a space.
And then this is a number as well.
So now I'm going to hover my mouse over, multiply, and we're going to see the exact same types.
We're going to see a number, B number.
You'll also notice on the right hand side, we're going to have a colon and number as well.
And what that is telling us is the type of the return value.
So in other words, the multiply function is going to return a value of type number.
And even though we didn't explicitly declare that the reason TypeScript is able to figure it out is
because it just does the logical thinking, right?
It says You're going to give me A and B, which I know our numbers in the body of this function are
going to multiply them.
So knowing that and B, our numbers, when you multiply two numbers together, I'm going to get a number
and then you're returning that.
So I can infer that the return value of multiply will be a number as well.
And that's how TypeScript reduces that for you.
Now, if you want to explicitly declare that the return value of the multiply function will be of type
number, we simply provide a colon after the parameter list and then declare the type of the return
value afterwards.
So right here, if I do colon then number.
What I'm saying is that the multiply function must return a value of type A number.
So if I hover my mouse over multiply, we're going to get the exact same thing we saw a minute ago.
However, right now we are explicitly manually declaring in line at the return value of multiply will
be a number.
All right.
The same rules will apply for arrow function.
So let me show you how that's going to work.
So I'm going to comment this out.
So right here, I'm going to create a concept called multiply right here.
I'm going to declare a arrow function and in here I'm going to return something.
Let's say I have two parameters.
They're going to be A and B, and right here I'm going to return eight times B, we're going to get
the exact same problem.
That's no issue for us.
The exact same syntax applies provide a colon and the type provide a colon and the type.
And now TypeScript is happy if we want to also explicitly state the return value of my arrow function
right here I provided after my parameter list.
So right here colon number.
This multiply function will produce a return value that has other type number and this syntax will also
work by the way, if we do implicit returns, remember in JavaScript, in and in TypeScript as well,
if we have a one line evaluation and we want that one line evaluation to be the final return value,
we can actually skip the curly braces and the return keyword.
We can simply do a times V and the syntax is totally valid and it's also going to be totally valid if
we leave out this number, because TypeScript can infer, given that we're feeding in two numbers and
then we're multiplying them, it can infer that the return value of multiply is also going to be a number
as well.
So this part is kind of optional.
I know some developers prefer to keep things as light as possible.
Other developers like to be explicit, to remind readers of what's going on.
But there you have it.
All right.
And once again, just like always, TypeScript is going to be helpful in many different ways.
So if we invoke multiply correctly with two arguments of the right type, like three and five, we're
not going to have any issues.
But as soon as we commit any kind of violation, TypeScript will warn us.
So for example, if I accidentally provide a string of five, we're going to see it's going to it's
going to say, hey, argument of type string is not assignable to a parameter of type number.
You told me this parameter of B was going to be a number and now you're giving me a string, so I'm
going to be unhappy and complain about that.
Similarly, TypeScript is going to complain if we provide too many arguments or not enough arguments.
So for example, if I try to provide three by itself, we can see it's going to say you I expected two
arguments, but I got one.
You told me.
That you're going to give me two values, A and B, but I only got one.
And it says here, an argument for B was not provided.
So it's validating the right number of arguments and it's also validating the right type of argument.
Similarly, if I provide too many arguments like three, five, eight, even though our multiply definition
expects only two.
Same thing types of statute is going to say, hey, I expected two arguments, but I got three instead
from you.
So once again, it's going to raise these complaints until you rearrange your code to a solution that
is actually proper.
All right.
That's how we declare types for functions, and it's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you next one.