All right.
So in this lesson, I want to show you a quick shortcut that we're going to be using throughout this
project.
So you'll notice in our file Explorer, we have this file called JS config dot JSON.
And we don't have to worry too much about this file, but you'll notice there is this section right
here called Paths and there is this key that has the act symbol in it.
This is the add symbol that you might find typically in an email address.
Right.
And you'll notice that it corresponds to an array with the word SIRC in it.
Now, SIRC, as you may notice, is a directory here, right here in our project and it stands for source.
So basically what this means is whenever we want to reference the SIRC directory in our code in for
example, a JavaScript file, we can use a shortcut of an act, sign this at some right here.
So if I go back to my main digest file and I'm just going to write a comment here, you don't have to
follow along if, for example, I wanted to reference this file.
Hello World Dot View Inside Components Inside SIRC.
What I can simply write in my import statement is at sign followed by a slash and then components and
helloworld.
So basically that outside is simply a shortcut or an alias for source for sase right here.
Whenever I use this, I simply mean go find the SASE directory.
So that's a little bit of a shortcut to allow us to write less code.
It's configured automatically for us.
Ingest config by the view Seelye when it created all of these files for us.
So as a quick example right here on line two and main that yes, you'll notice that we're making a relative
import of the app component from app dot view.
That's what this dot forward slash means.
It means from the current directory.
If instead we wanted to use that syntax, we could import directly from the top of source because that's
where our apt at view file is.
Notice that it's right here inside the directory.
So what I can do as an alternative import is right and app sign right here because that means SIRC right
SIRC slash followed by the actual name of the file which is app view.
And what I'm typically going to be doing throughout this project is relying on imports like these absolute
imports, meaning from the top of my codebase rather than relative to the file that I'm in.
I generally prefer this approach because I don't like import imports that look like this, where, you
know, we're going up to directories, then going up into another directory, etc. I don't like those
because they tend to confuse me.
I like to think of everything from the top level down.
So we're going to be utilizing this at symbol a lot.
Again, it simply represents source and from that point you can reference any of the folders or files
that you have in here.
And since all of our view components and all of our view code is going to be somewhere in the source
directory that makes it super simple for our project.
So go ahead and update line two.
But that is all there is to cover in this lesson and I will see you in the next one.