Alright.
So I am pretty happy with the text input component.
The one thing that I would like to add of course is a good test suite.
So let's do that in this lesson.
So I head to my file Explorer and right here I will look for my tests directory.
And there we have a unit folder and a components folder.
And in there we have a shared directory.
And that's where I will create my new test file.
So I'm going to mirror the directory structure of my components.
And here I'll call this file.
Text input dot.
Test, dot.
Just same protocol as always.
I'm going to name the component and then the dot test.
Dot just extension that just requires.
Let's create that file.
I'm going to drag it over here to the right.
So I have it side by side with my implementation and let's work through the usual steps.
So first up, we need to import either the mount or shallow mount function.
I'm going to import mount.
It really doesn't matter in this scenario because our component does not have any child components that
it's rendering.
It's just a plane input.
So it doesn't really matter in this scenario.
So I'm going to import mount and that is going to come from the test utils library, from the view organization.
Then I need to import my component under test, which of course is my text input component that is going
to come from my source directory, the components folder, the shared folder, and then my actual text
input component itself for the file name.
Then I'll use just describe function.
We are describing the text input component.
That's what we are testing.
We'll provide an arrow function for the second argument and here I'll provide a test.
So it.
And what does it do?
Well, I think a good description here that is generic and doesn't go too much into the implementation
is something that we'll talk about what the component does and that component really communicates that
the user has interacted with it.
So how about something like this?
It communicates that user has entered a character that way.
I'm not getting super deep into things like emits or view specific things.
I'm just saying, what's the responsibility of this text input component?
And what I really want to test is that as we enter text into the input, I want it to be sending a message
up with that information.
We really want to test this thing right here because the rest of it is kind of a plain HTML element
that doesn't really do much right to testing the classes here is kind of pointless because they're kind
of fixed in stone is nothing like user specific about them.
The real value of this component is as the user types of letter, it emits a message upward.
And so that's kind of the core heart of what I want to test here.
So let's go ahead and instantiate our component.
So content wrapper, we're going to pass it into the mount function and that will be our text input
component.
And remember we have to props in this component placeholder is optional while model value is required.
So the parent component that instantiate the text input needs to give it a model value prop.
In this scenario, we don't have a parent component.
So the way we simulate that is by providing that second configuration object to the mount function here
we can provide a property of props and then within the object we provide the props.
Our keys or our properties are the props and their values are the respective values.
So for example, I can provide my model value prop and I could set it equal to a starter value of an
empty string.
Right.
And this is totally fine.
We talked earlier about how we don't want to customize things like the components data because that
is reaching into the components implementation.
In this case, we expect text input to be instantiated by a parent and be provided a model value prop.
This is exactly how this component is meant to be used.
So we are not violating the user contract or testing the component in any different way.
We are actually working with it the way we expect it to be worked with in the real world app.
So there's nothing wrong with adding the customization of the props to provide it.
Okay, so what I'd like to do is to find the input element that is right here.
I could use the data test attribute, but since this component is so simple, I'm okay with just searching
for the plane input element.
If expanded later, I might change the test, but for now I think it's okay to just search for input.
So here I'm going.
Just do wrapper defined and instead of providing a data test attribute or any attribute, I'm just going
to provide a string of input and that tells vue test utils to look for the first HTML input element.
So it's basically going to find this thing right here and assign that to an input constant.
Okay.
So at this point, I'd like to introduce you to a special method that is available on our wrapper object,
which as a reminder is vue test utils taking our component and then wrapping it with a whole bunch of
extra functionality such as defined method to query, such as the text, the method to get the components
text.
It's almost like an additional level or layer of functionality and that's the advantage of using Vue
test utils is it gives us all that extra help with interacting with our component.
Well, a available method on the wrapper object is emitted and what emitted will return is an object
that shows every event that that component or that element has emitted.
So let me show you this in action.
I'm going to.
Console.log.
The result of calling emitted.
I'm not going to call it on input.
I'm going to call it on wrapper.
So wrapper emitted right here.
And let me go ahead and start our test runner.
So right here, I open up my terminal and I'm going to start just in watch mode.
So let's run NPM, run, test, colon watch and we're going to see before we interact with our input.
Obviously there's no emitted events yet, so what we're going to get right here is an empty object.
There have been no events that have been logged, so nothing has been tracked.
So what we didn't need to do is to simulate the user entering a character into our text input, or more
specifically, this specific input element within our text input component.
Well, if we have an input element available, we can actually call a helper method on it called set
value.
And it does exactly as the name describes it sets a value inside that HTML input element the exact same
way as us in the browser clicking into that input and typing character on our keyboard.
So right here on my input, which is the reference to the native H2 now element, right?
This is no longer our view wrapper object around our component.
This is a reference to our specific HTML input that we have identified using the fine method on this
one.
I can call this set value method and this is our first time using this, I believe, and I can provide
a sample value.
So let's say the user types in a character like the Capital Letter N, right?
So after this, what I'm going to do is console.log the exact same method invocation of wrapper dot
emitted and we can compare the before and after.
So here you can see we start out with the empty object and here is where we get the new output.
So the way this works is that the properties of the object are the events.
So notice we have an input event right here that is the native kind of browser like event that is kind
of the native thing that happens when a user types a letter into the input box.
But then because we're also going to automatically trigger this handle input method that we defined
and because the component is going to emit this update model, value, message or event, we can see
it present right here.
So that is the property, that is the events that this component has emit.
Now the value is going to be an array of arrays and that might be a little bit confusing.
But the reason we need an outer array is because we may have multiple emissions.
And what vue test utils is going to do is keep track of each one.
The reason we need internal nested arrays is because a component may emit more than one thing at a time.
So imagine right here we emitted not just the targeted value but another string.
For example, in that case, this first internal array would store the end and then that second emitted
value.
So each internal array represents one emission.
And all of the arguments that we passed to the Emit method and then the outer array represents every
single emission event.
So just to, to reiterate, the outer array stores, all of the events and each nested array represents
one single event.
A really easy way that I can show this to you is by pretending that we type in another character.
So let's say after we set the value of and we type in another letter of why, so we expect now that
the input is going to have an An and Y.
So if I look here.
We're now going to see here is our array representing two events because there are two nested arrays.
There are two times the component emitted.
The first array represents the arguments for the first emission, which is a single letter n, and then
the second array represents the arguments for the second emission, which is and Y.
And then we talk about arguments again.
We're talking about the consecutive values that we pass right here to the Emit method.
So for example, if I arbitrarily put a number to here and I save this, you're going to see that each
array is going to have the actual emitted value, plus that extra argument of two that I provided right
here.
That's why we need an internal array, because the array can store any number of elements, just like
we can emit any number of arguments.
Right.
While the outer array represents the entire collection of emissions.
So.
What we'd like to do, of course, is to compare this output array with what we expect the the messages
to be that the component is going to emit.
So here's what I propose we do.
I propose that we reach into this infinite object right here, which we see here, get the array that
is attached to update, model value and verify that it has the shape and structure of what we expect.
So let's do a couple of things here.
I'm going to remove my console.log.
Let's say that I provide one more value here, which is, see.
So we're going to get to NYC.
Let's say the user is searching for a job in a location in New York City.
So what I'd like to do now is I want to get my emitted method, I want to invoke it.
So I'm going to get this thing right here and then I want to index or access this property.
Now, this property is a little unique because it has a colon, so we can't just access it using dot
syntax like so, but we can access it using square brackets and text.
That is a totally normal syntax in JavaScript to access the property.
So right here as a string, I will type that I want the update model value property from my emitted
messages object right here.
So now I'm going to get the value, which is the array of arrays on the right.
And of course, I want to compare that to what I expect to see.
So I'm going to expect that my messages array is going to be equal to an array that I specify when whenever
we compare arrays and just we have to use the to equal matcher instead of the to be matcher because
the to be matcher text restrict equality which also cares about object identity, which means the same
object in the computer's memory.
In this case, the structure of our arrays is the same, but there are two separate arrays.
So in those situations, the two B matcher will fail because it's going to say it's not actually the
same array and it's going to yield a failure.
We want to compare the actual quality of the array.
So what elements are storing?
Are they the same even if those arrays are totally separate copies somewhere different in the computer's
memory?
So long story short, we need to use that to equal matcher here.
And of course, we expect an array of arrays.
So let's start with the outer.
And then we expect a nested array for each individual emitted set of emitted arguments.
So our very first array is going to be the very first emitted event when the user types an end.
So we expect the character end, right?
That's going to be our first array then for our second nested array.
At that point, the emitted event and the value that we're going to provide right here should be and
why.
And finally, for the third array, for this third event right here, the text input component will
emit again or should emit again.
And we expect that event to target that value at that point will be NYC.
So this should be the array of arrays of those consecutive messages that text input will emit.
All right.
And we're interacting with it three times just to be a little bit safe to make sure that it's not like
deleting our old content or doing anything like that.
We're just testing in a couple of times in succession or succession to make sure that everything is
working just fine.
So in sequence we expect and why NYC and we can see here that the test is indeed passing.
And so for example, if we only interact with the component twice, we're going to get a failure because
we're only going to have an array of two emitted values versus an array of three, so three interactions.
So we have an array of three arrays and that's how we test it.
And I think I am pretty happy with this.
I think this is a good place to leave off and I think this covers the responsibility of what text input
is supposed to do.
So with that, we are good to wrap up the section which we will do in the very next lesson.