Okay.
So the next file in our store directory that we're going to convert to TypeScript is going to be our
getters file.
So right here I have getters.
J.S. I'm going to open that up and immediately I'm going to change its name to have a TypeScript extension.
So right click, choose, rename and let's give it a TSC extension.
All right.
So as a reminder, a getter is just a method that receives the current view store state as its first
argument, and then it returns some kind of computed value from that store state.
So luckily the state parameter they each one of our getters implements is going to be the exact same
interface as what we did in the Mutations file.
It's going to be that global state interface that describes our view X Store State.
Now also recall that whenever we have getters that we want to accept additional arguments unlike mutations.
The way we do this with getters is we have our original getter method, define a returned function,
and there is that function that implements the additional parameters that we can then provide as arguments
whenever we actually use the getter elsewhere.
All right.
So notice here, TypeScript wants us to define what state is going to be and also what job is going
to be in this returned function.
Then we return from this getter method, for example.
So we're going to need to import global state, and we're also going to need to import another interface,
which is our job interface as well.
Let's do that first.
So right here I'm going to import global state and that is going to come from our source directory that
is related to view.
So it's going to come from store and then the types file in there.
And then as far as the jobs interface, we can import that here import job that is going to come from
our API folder.
So right here from the source directory, the API folder that types file in there.
There we go.
All right.
So now let's go through every single one of our methods and update state to be using the global state
interface.
So the state parameter here is going to be of type global state.
Same thing for this state right here.
Same thing for the state right here.
And same thing for this state right here.
All right.
Now, there's something cool that I want to show you about how powerful TypeScript works.
I remember that TypeScript is really smart, especially when it gets into really nested objects.
So notice, for example, that here in this first getter called unique organizations, we are iterating
over each one of our jobs.
So because we provided global state, TypeScript knows that the state is going to have a property called
Jobs.
Let me just open up global state as a reminder.
So TypeScript understands that we have an array of jobs, but it also understands that each array,
each array object is a job with its own property.
So notice that when I hover my mouse over job right here on line 15, you can see that TypeScript has
correctly inferred that it is a job object and thus it's going to validate that organization is a valid
property, a string property on that job object.
So once again, TypeScript is super smart because it can go all those levels deep.
It knows that our state object has an array of jobs.
It knows what an individual job looks like because we are iterating over an array of them.
So it assumes we're iterating over a one job at a time and it knows that a job must have an organization
property, because that's what this job interface right here that we are referencing in our global state
interface references.
And that's really the beautiful part of TypeScript.
That's when, you know, when our brain forgets all these details.
This is super helpful for TypeScript to remind us.
So if we want, we can manually specify that this is going to be a job right here.
But we don't need to, because TypeScript has everything it needs in order to make that correct assumption
or calculation anyway.
All right.
So moving on, we have these two getters right here that return functions.
Each one of those functions except a job argument.
So right here, we're going to provide our job interface as the type of this parameter right here.
Because here TypeScript has no clue.
TypeScript just says, Oh, you're returning some function that accepts a parameter called Job.
I don't know what that is in that case.
Please tell me.
That's why it's raising the error right here.
So as always, a colon followed by the type.
Our type is job.
And our type right here is job as well.
All right.
As far as this violation, we're going to get back to this in the next lesson.
There is one more thing I want to do to close this lesson off.
You'll notice that if I hover my mouse over the letters, we're going to get the entire collection of
types for this complex object.
And notice that, for example, for the unique organizations getter, we are properly annotating state
as global state.
But TypeScript is assuming that the return value is going to be a set holding unknown values.
And that's because TypeScript doesn't understand that our set is actually going to be one that consists
of strings.
Even though job and it's organization property is a string at the moment that we create the set on line
14, TypeScript has no clue what values this set will contain.
And since we're creating it like so here and then returning it on line 16 Typekit TypeScript assumes
its default, which is a set of unknown values.
In other words, as a reminder, unknown is kind of that value that's a little bit better than any,
but basically just any values.
And we can be a little bit more specific here in communicating explicitly to TypeScript that not only
is it a set, but more specifically it's a set that's going to hold strings.
All right.
And the way we can do that is by using that feature called generics.
Remember, the way generics work is we provide the opening and closing brackets, the less than sign
and then the greater sign.
And then we provide a type as well for that generic.
And that allows us to have a more specific type.
Remember earlier when we were learning about TypeScript, we saw how we could use generics to have our
function, accept an array of any type of value.
And that required us not to have to implement three identical functions, for example, one for an array
of numbers, one for an array of strings, one for an array of booleans.
Instead of duplicating that, we can simply define a generic input, and a generic is just basically
a type parameter.
So the set implementation in JavaScript and in TypeScript enables you to provide a generic to specify
what is going to be the values that that set is going to hold.
So right here after the set keyword, I'm going to provide my less than greater than sign and I'm going
to specify that this is going to be a set of strings.
All right.
And down below here for unique job types, that works very similarly.
This is also going to be a set of strings that has a more specific types that's a little bit better
than just a generic set.
So right here, I'm going to provide my generic in line, make sure not have this terrible autocomplete.
There we go.
All right.
And now notice when I hover my mouse over getters, it's going to tell us a unique organization's is
a method that accepts a state parameter that is going to have the global state interface.
And now it's going to be a lot more specific.
We're returning a set of strings, and the reason that's helpful is wherever we're going to be utilizing
a getter like this in the component.
Now, TypeScript knows that not only are we dealing with the set, but we're going to be dealing with
a set of strings.
So, for example, if we iterate over that, that set of strings and try to do something that is not
permitted on a string or something like that, TypeScript will still notice that we're giving it more
specific details that it can utilize in its type checking.
All right.
So if TypeScript makes the incorrect inference, if it makes the incorrect assumption, and if you need
to provide a little bit more clarity, feel free to add it.
Otherwise, if TypeScript is making the correct inference such as it did with Job right here, there's
really no reason to add that additional explicit type unless you really want to.
All right.
So that takes care of a lot of our getters file.
And in the very next lesson, we'll tackle this parameter right here.