All right.
So a couple lessons ago, we learned about interfaces and how they can help us reduce duplication.
When it comes to shared object types, as it turns out, we can also use interfaces to reduce duplication
when it comes to function type definitions.
So let me give you an example.
Let's say I have a program where I have two functions.
My functions are going to be multiply and sum.
My multiply function will accept two number parameters, multiply them together and return the product,
while my sum function will accept two number parameters, add them together and return the sum.
So my code would look something like this.
Here is my multiply arrow function and here I'm going to declare two parameters A and B.
They're both going to be of type number.
And then my return value of this error function will be number as well.
And right here I'm going to use an implicit return to return the value of eight times B, so I'm multiplying
A and B together.
This is totally valid.
TypeScript syntax.
Now below I'll define a very similar function called Sum, and sum is going to have a very similar type
definition.
It's going to accept two parameters.
The first is going to be a number, and the second is also going to be a number.
And the final return value of my sum function is also going to be a number.
The only difference is we're going to add A and B together instead of multiplying them.
So once again, as always, we can see a little bit of duplication.
And the duplication here is not in the actual logic of the implementation of the function.
The duplication is in the type definition.
Both of these functions have a very similar type.
They are both a function that has a parameter list that is two parameters long.
It takes a first parameter, which is a number.
A second parameter that is a number, and then it produces a return value that is also a number.
So that in itself is a specific type of function definition, right?
Because there's many different ways that we can have a function.
We can have a function with three arguments or five arguments.
We can have a function with a number of return value, a string return value, an array of return value.
So even this combination of types right here is its own unique kind of type definition.
In the same way that we saw a couple lessons ago with our interface, how a video game character objects
shape was something that was reusable.
The same principle applies here.
This combination of types is in itself a reusable definition, and so we can extract it to an interface.
And the benefit of doing that is that we can then reuse that interface in many different places throughout
our app and not have to retype all of this code and also get the benefits of type safety.
So let me show you how that's going to work right here.
I'm going to use my interface word.
Remember, that is a built in TypeScript keyword and then we have to give each interface a name.
So I'm going to call my interface to number math func basically a function that has a math function
that involves two numbers, right?
A nice descriptive term that can describe what I want to apply it to below.
Right?
The way that we provide a type definition for a function is inside these curly braces.
We write our parentheses to represent our function arguments and their types, and then afterwards we
provide a colon and then provide the return value of my function.
So here what I'm going to do is I'm going to say the exact same thing as below.
My function is going to have a parameter called A, which is going to be a number.
And then the second argument will be parameter B also of type number.
And then the function is going to produce a return value of type number as well.
All right.
So I'm using the interface keyword, I'm giving it a name and I'm describing what a type of function
definition could look like.
Right.
There's many different ways a function definition could look.
This is an example of a two number math func right.
So now the advantage of this approach is we can get rid of all of these explicit types by simply telling
TypeScript that Multiply is going to implement or honor the two number math func interface.
So let me show you how that's going to work right here.
I'm going to get rid of this explicit declaration of number and same thing right here and same thing
right here for my functions, return, value type.
And notice that TypeScript complains because by default it doesn't know what A and B is.
It's going to assume that it's an any type and that's not good.
That's a TypeScript violation that defeats the entire purpose of TypeScript.
But what I can do is tell TypeScript right here that Multiply is going to honor this interface right
here.
The way I do that is providing a colon and then of course writing the name of my type.
In this case, it's the interface above.
So this is going to be a two number math func.
So notice automatically that the errors are going to go away because TypeScript now knows that A and
B are not going to be of the any type.
TypeScript now knows that these are going to be of type number because multiply must honor the two number
math that I told TypeScript it was going to be.
So if I hover my mouse over multiply you can see it's going to be of type to number math func and what
does that type?
It is a function right here that accepts two parameters of type number and also returns a number.
So TypeScript understands that this function is going to live up to this contract, this promise.
And the advantage, of course, is we can have a lot less code, a lot less typing, and also a lot
more reusability.
So some is also a two number math func.
So we can once again provide to number math link right here.
And that spares us the need to explicitly declare all of these types right here because TypeScript is
automatically going to infer them.
So just like that.
And there we go.
So whenever we have a situation where a, a function has a very similar signature or rather multiple
functions or multiple methods in your program have a very similar signature.
You can extract that common in, you can extract a common type definition that common function logic,
the parameters and their types and the return value.
It's type to its own interface that you can then reuse throughout all of those multiple functions,
sparing you the need to duplicate that code and duplicate that logic.
All right.
That's interfaces for functions.
That's all there is to cover here.
And I will see you in the next lesson.