Okay.
So here I am in our job filter as sidebar component.
And before we wrap this section up, there is one more thing I'd like to do.
I want to move this logic over here or this slice of the template, starting with our top level accordion
for the organization section.
I want to move all of this into its own separate view component.
The reason I want to do this is because I anticipate otherwise the job filter sidebar component will
start to get really large, especially as we start to add checkboxes right here for our job types and
checkboxes right here for our degrees.
Before we get to that complexity, I do see an opportunity to extract a chunk of UI to its own separate
file, and I think it'd be a good idea to do so.
All right, so I'm literally going to copy and paste this code into its own separate file.
Now, you may recall that earlier in the course we talked about the idea of the View Style Guide.
The View Style guide, by the way, is just a set of recommendations or best practices from the View
Development Team.
And one of the recommendations that they have is that when you have child components that are closely
coupled to the parent, in this case, this new component that we create will be a child of job filter
sidebar, and it is directly related to it.
It is an actual filter in the sidebar.
What the View Style Guide recommends is including the parent's component name as a prefix in the child's
component name.
So whatever name we give to this, we should also prefix it with job filters.
Sidebar.
So I'm going to call this new component job filter, sidebar organizations.
All right.
So right here, I'm going to open up my file explorer and my components.
Job results, job filters, sidebar feature folder.
I'm going to create a new file called.
Job filters, sidebar, keeping the prefix of the original parent name, and then the actual component
will also have organizations as part of its component name.
This will be a dot view file and from my sidebar I can literally cut and paste this.
Just remember that you also have to wrap everything in a template tag before you paste.
So template paste that here let prettier format it.
And then before we call it a day, we do have to provide just the default configuration here.
So I will provide a script section.
And remember, we are using an accordion component right here at the very top level.
So we do need to import that and register it with this components, local components.
So I'm going to import accordion that is going to come from these source directory components, shared
accordion.
Then I'm going to export default my configuration object.
We're going to give this component a name of job filters, sidebar organizations, and then I'm going
to create a components property set to an object where I register accordion.
And that should do it for us.
All right.
Now that I have this set up, I can go back to my job vector sidebar component, and we need to import
it and use it.
So down below, in my script section, right below these shared components, I'm going to import my
new job filters, sidebar, organization's component, and that is going to come from the source components,
job results, job filter, sidebar, job filter, sidebar, organizations that view file.
And then I'm going to just simply copy this right here, paste it inside our components object.
And then of course we have to use it.
We can use it right below our other two accordions right here.
I'm simply going to render job filters, sidebar, organization instead of camel case.
I'm simply going to provide a dash in between every subsequent word.
We can make this a self-closing component and save, and we should see the error go away below.
I think this is going to be organizaciones.
There we go.
Now we are using all of our locally registered components.
We have removed that huge slice of UI and placed it in a simple component.
And if I go back to my browser and refresh this page.
Just to make sure everything is still working as we expect.
Now we have isolated just this chunk of logic to its own separate component.
All right.
So this has been an introduction to slots, and I will see you in the next lesson where we're going
to do a quick review of this section.