Okay.
So the next directory that I'd like to create within my components folder is going to be a job search
directory.
And in there I'm going to put my headline, my hero and my job search form components.
So basically what we've been working on over the course of the last couple of sections.
So right here in Components, I will create a new folder.
I'm going to call it job search.
That sort of describes the feature that we've been working on and the components that make up that feature.
So I am, of course, going to drag my headline into there.
And yes, Victor, you can change it wherever you can find it.
And I'm also going to drag it looks like it's also asking me for permission here.
We're going to save it and come back to it later.
Let me also move my hero component into job search.
Okay.
That looks good.
All right.
Let me save that.
And let me also move my job search form component into job search as well.
And then we'll go through the components manually to make sure that things remain normal.
So let me just go into here.
Okay.
View.
Let me see if there's anything going on here.
So here we are importing our headline component from components job search, headline view.
That is correct.
And as far as job search from that view, that is not updated.
I think the reason we have this kind of discrepancy is the order in which we move our components into
the folder.
They may auto update, but maybe when we moved hero, the job search form was still in its outer level
and Vader doesn't know to account for that.
So now our job search form component is also in the job search folder.
So let's add it here.
Job search slash job search form.
That looks good.
I want to ask to move on to my app view component.
I know there is some use of this here.
So right here we are getting our hero from components job search hero dot view.
That looks good to me.
Okay.
And then let's assume we got everything here, but we will come back to it if we need to.
In tests unit components, I want to create a complementary job search folder and into here.
I want to move my headline that test, that just file.
There we go.
Let's open up headline that.
Test that.
Yes, immediately.
Here we can see we are importing headline from components headline.
That is no longer where it is at.
It is now inside the job search directory.
So like that and let's try running our tests again.
So I'm going to open up our terminal.
And I'm going to run and PM run test colon unit.
Let's run our tests once and see if there is anything missing or anything we forgot.
And looks like everything is working so far.
Again, the tests are not a perfect indicator because there may be some imports somewhere that we're
not testing.
But for now, I'll treat this as being a good sign and we'll continue to refactor in the very next lesson.