All right.
So let's begin this lesson by running our alternate test command, which is going to be NPM run test,
colon unit.
This, of course, is not going to run just in watch mode.
But in this mode, we are going to see a code coverage report.
And we can see right here that the profile image has a few uncovered lines, more specifically, line
number nine.
So what this is telling us is there is no test in our test suite currently that is running through line
number nine in profile image.
And to actually be more exact, this is a little bit of a distorted statement.
There's really nothing that is going through profile image at all right now.
And I want to talk about why that is, because the changes that we made in the previous lesson did affect
our code coverage.
So previously we were full mounting our main NAV, which means that all child components were being
rendered in a test.
And we of course were focused on sub nav in the previous lesson.
But our main nav component also has this profile image and action button child components as well.
So when we switched our tests to shallow mounts view stubbed out these components, right?
And as a result the tests never fully rendered the profile image and never fully rendered the action
button in the tests for the main NAV.
Now that can be okay if we have separate tests for these components and their functionality.
But given that we were previously rendering a profile image in May, now we had the coverage for that
because our code was running through that components code.
Once we shifted to shallow amount, we lost that code coverage.
Now, as a quick reminder, 100% code coverage is an ideal, but it's not a perfect standard standard
in the real world, there are certain situations where you don't necessarily have to feel guilty if
you have, you know, 90% test coverage or 95, there's certain elements that are difficult to unit
test or certain elements that don't really benefit from unit tests.
So let me give you an example here.
If I open up my profile image component, there's really not that much business logic that is going
on here.
We have used a component of view, which is the data, but it really is just a hard coded URL that is
not changing.
So there's really no difference between this design versus simply putting the image link right here
as our direct is our C value.
And if that was the case, we basically have a hardcoded image tag, right?
There's no real variation or user interaction or any business logic.
It's basically the equivalent of a DIV or an H1.
It's just something static that is always going to stay the same.
So if I were looking at something like this, I'd say, it's okay if the profile image isn't tested.
It's not necessarily a bad thing if it is, but it's not the worst thing in the world if it isn't,
because there's not that many ways that this component can go wrong or behave unexpectedly.
With that said, if we want to achieve 100% test coverage, we can write a very basic test for profile
image, and that's what we're going to do in this lesson.
So let's go ahead and head to our.
Tests, directory tests, unit components.
And in here I'm going to create a test for our profile image.
So I'll call this file profile image test dot js.
And I'm going to put this on the right hand side.
We should be pretty familiar with the drill by now.
I'm going to import a function and there are no actual nested child components in here.
So it doesn't really matter whether we use mount or shallow mount.
I'm going to use shallow mount in this case and I'm going to import it from view test utils.
I'm going to import the component I'm testing, which is called profile image that's going to come from
the top at side, which is the source directory components profile image.
Let me make sure I have that correctly profile image.
Let me describe what I'm testing, which is going to be the profile image.
And for a very simple test, you're going to see this sometimes in very various code bases.
The simplest test you could write is basically checking that if you mount the component using view that
it renders that it basically exists, that nothing has gone wrong in the mounting process, basically
standing up this component and making sure that everything is A-OK.
So here I'm going to write simply it renders.
All right.
So right here, we're going to do a concert rapper and we're going to shallow mount our profile image
component.
And as a reminder, this rapper is going to return a the component mounted and wrapped in a helper object
that has a whole bunch of methods for interacting with that component.
And as you may recall, one method that is available is exists that's simply going to return true if
that value exists, whether it be a component or a node within the component, such as an HTML element
when you're searching, right?
It's basically just double checking that it's not a undefined or null or absent value.
So if we successfully shallow mount the profile image component, the exists method on the wrapper should
return.
True.
So I'm just going to put to be true here, save this file and let prettier do all that wonderful print
ification.
I don't even know what the right word is there.
Let me go ahead and rerun NPM run test unit.
And this should bring us to good test coverage for our profile of each component.
All right.
So we have perfect test coverage for all of our components, but this can be a little bit misleading
as we'll find out in the next lesson.
There is one more thing I'd like to test before we close off this section.