All right.
So in the previous lessons we learned about the VON Directive, which allows us to react to a user event.
In this case, we reacted to a user click and we told Vue to invoke a method called Handle Click whenever
the user clicked on our button, our optimal button inside our action button component.
Now, as it turns out, whenever Vue invokes any method that we provide to the VON Directive, it will
automatically pass in an event object as the very first argument to that method.
So when I was first starting out with any kind of front end library and I heard the word event object,
I started to get kind of confused.
It seemed kind of bigger, overwhelming in scope.
But an event object is actually pretty simple.
It's a plain JavaScript object that just has a lot of information about the event that just happened.
Right.
So you may not think there's a lot of information going on whenever we click on a button in a page.
But there is actually a lot that the browser and JavaScript are keeping track of.
For example, the event object for a click event will have information like the coordinates of where
the user clicked, the x and y coordinates where the user actually clicked on the button.
If you think of the the browser window as a two dimensional plane, right, you can click on the top
right corner or the bottom left corner, and the click event will keep track of the exact coordinate
where you click.
Now, that isn't specifically important to us right now, but it just goes to illustrate what an event
object is storing.
It's just information, it's just metadata, some additional information about what happened in that
event, and sometimes you may care about that.
So, for example, if we're dealing with another kind of event like let's say a user typing text into
an input field, each time the user presses a character on their keyboard, that is an event, right?
It's not a click event, but it's still an event.
It's some kind of change or some kind of thing that is happening on an application, on a web page.
And in that type of scenario, in an input event, we may want to talk to the input or the event object
in order to find out what it is that the user just typed, right?
Because the event object is in a store, that kind of information.
So depending on what kind of event it is, the event object will have different characteristics, different
properties.
But the at the end of the day it's just a plain JavaScript object with that information.
So right now there's nothing that I want to extract from this event object.
There's no data that I need from it, but I just want to show you how it works.
So again, as a reminder, Vue will automatically pass in the event object as the very first argument
to any method we define.
We simply did not write that parameter out, so you didn't do anything with it.
But right now I can type an event and this parameter name is totally up to us.
We can call it whatever we want, but it must be the first argument.
So I'm going to call this event and I'm just going to console.log the event object so we can see it
in our browser console.
All right.
So I'm going to save this and I'm going to transition back to Google Chrome and I'm going to click the
sign in button and we're going to see this pointer event.
So this is views representation of a click.
And if I open this object, you'll see it's just plain key value pairs, right?
Properties and values just like we're used to in JavaScript.
So if I scroll down, you're going to see properties like client X and client Y which look to be some
kind of coordinates.
There's also layer X and layer Y, offset x, offset Y.
These are all, of course, dealing with the two dimensional plane and the idea of axes right x axis,
which moves left to right and y axis which moves up and down.
So there's a whole bunch of these additional pieces of information that we have here.
Most of them even I don't know what they do.
The important thing is to understand that they're all bundled up here in this event object.
That's all an event object is.
It's just information about what transpired.
And every time that we use the vision directive and we provide a method name view is going to pass in
that event object automatically as the very first argument.
And then we can take that event, that object, and do something with it in the body of the method if
we want to.
We're going to see this more in action later in the course when we deal with input events.
All right.
But for now, we don't need anything here so we can go ahead and get rid of this console.log event and
get rid of the event parameter as well and just leave it like so.
And we'll come back to this method in the next lesson when we add more functionality to it.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.