All right.
So there's one more thing that I forgot to do in the previous lesson, and that is clean up our action
button.
We no longer need the methods property.
We introduced it solely for the sake of example.
And right now we have a method that does nothing in it.
So we can go ahead and remove the entire methods property right here.
And since we no longer have a handle click method, we can go ahead and remove this von click handler
here as well.
So I'm going to remove this line, save this file, and that clears us to go back to our main NAV.
We're going to practice the same concepts that we just talked about in the previous couple of lessons.
So I'm going to scroll down here to our configuration object for our main nav component and here below
our data method.
I'm going to define my methods property, just like we did an action button a few lessons ago.
So I'm going to define methods and going to set it to be an object.
And in this object I'm going to define any methods that I want to be available to my main component.
All right.
So what method do we want here?
Well, I want a method that is going to log the user in.
And how is it effectively going to do that?
Well, it needs to access the is logged in property on my data object and flip it to true because once
this becomes true, then the component will re render and it will display the profile image instead
of the action button.
So I'm going to define a method here called log in user.
Again, this name is up to me.
And then here in this method body I need to find a way to reference this property of is logged in.
The way that we can do this is by referencing it directly on the this keyword.
So I'm going to write it out first and then we're going to talk a little bit about it.
So this followed by a dot and then the property which is is logged in.
All right.
So this is a common point of confusion in JavaScript because what that word refers to can change or
vary depending on the context in which it's used.
Usually when you're defining a class, this will refer to the instance of the class, the actual object
that we're going to create from the class template.
Now in this situation, if this was a regular JavaScript setup, this would actually not work.
We would not be able to access an arbitrary is logged in property that is coincidentally existing on
the returned object from another method.
Right.
This this would not work in traditional JavaScript.
The reason it works here is because Vue takes a look at everything that we've wired up within our data
method.
And by that I mean the properties that we've configured here, and it makes them available at the top
level of the view object itself, the view configuration object to be more specific.
So on to this keyword here, we can access any of these properties, we can do this, accompany this
URL, this, that menu items, this that logged in, etc. And if we want to overwrite any of these values,
all we have to do is provide an equal sign and assign a new value.
All right.
This is no different than how we would overwrite these properties if we defined them on a custom class.
What is different is that we can access this is logged in property, even though we're not automatically
assigning it to this instance.
Manually view is doing that behind the scenes for us.
So again, View behind the scenes is looking at what we return from the data method.
It's taking all of these properties and it's making them available on the this keyword, which refers
to the view configuration object.
So this is how I can reference any piece of data which is logged in.
And now of course what I want to do is flip it to true.
So I'm going to provide an equal sign here and flip it to true.
Now, just like we saw in the previous lesson, this is not going to change anything.
Honor UI because just because we have a method doesn't mean that view is going to run it or invoke it
automatically.
We have to get view to run or invoke this method based on a user action.
Well, what is that action going to be?
It's going to be the user clicking on our action button.
So let's do that right now.
I'm going to scroll back up to where I have my action button right here and I'm going to add my von
click syntax.
It's the exact same syntax that we talked about in the previous lessons.
The difference here, of course, is that we're applying it on a view component rather than on an HTML
element.
In the previous lesson, we applied it to a button h HTML element.
Now we are applying it to an action button view component.
However, the same logic applies.
Basically what Vue says is if you click on anything that belongs to this action button component.
So if we had, for example, this component consisted of a div with another div with a button inside
it.
Anything that we click that comprises the action button will trigger the event representing a user click.
So the key takeaway is that we can add the VON Directive to either a view component or a core H2 element.
All right, the syntax is the exact same and let's practice it in both options right here.
So the first option is the on followed by the click event that we want to react to, followed by an
equal sign and then the string.
And here, of course, we provide the method that we want the click to invoke or to run for us.
So when the user clicks anywhere in an action button component, what do we want to run?
We want this method to run.
Log in the user.
So we're going to put log in user right here without parentheses.
We do not invoke it.
We told you that it should invoke it whenever the user clicks the button.
Once again, this is totally valid syntax, but View and the view style guide prefers that we use the
shortcut.
And again, the shortcut is going to be this app sign.
So I'm going to remove the von colon and just put the ad click here, save this and prettier will adjust
it back to one line and that should do it.
So let's now head to Chrome and observe this in action.
All right.
So let's see this change in action.
I'm going to go ahead and click on the sign in button.
And this is going to invoke the logon user method, which is going to change the value of the is logged
in data property which will force the component to re render which will trigger the AVF and v else directives
to swap in terms of which one is going to value to true, which in turn is going to replace the blue
action button component with our profile image component.
Here I go.
3 to 1 and.
There we go.
It's loading a little bit slowly on my computer, but let me refresh and try again.
Hopefully it'll be a little faster this time.
There we go.
That slowdown was not due to view.
It was due to my Internet connection fetching that image.
But now you can see it is working.
When I click the button view renders and the image pops up.
We can also observe this change in our actual elements panels.
If I go back again by refreshing the page and I take a look at my header component and keep expanding
this, we're going to be able to find eventually our button right here.
Keep your eye on this HTML element as I click the button in 3 to 1.
You can see the automatic swapping that occurred if you replace that with the image tag in each HTML.
Again, that is the root HTML that lives inside our profile image component because view components
the browser does not understand.
But what a view does is translate those components into pure HTML that the browser does understand.
All right.
And one more place where I want to show you how this change works is, in our view, devtools.
So once again, I'm going to refresh the page.
And the reason I'm refreshing the page, of course, is because I have no way of getting back to my
original state.
Right now, there's no way for me to, quote, log out and bring my is logged in property back.
But of course we can define another method to do that that will flip that is log in property backed
back to false.
So I have to refresh the page to reset all of my data properties to their original values.
And now let me click on May now and we can see here the is logged in property is set to false.
Previously we were we were modifying it directly from the view DevTools, which again is not ideal in
the real world because there's no way for the user to do that or to know that.
But now, from a user perspective, when the user clicks this, which is logical, we're going to see
this value change.
So this should change from false to true.
And there we go.
We can see it changes this property, which again forces view to re render whenever view observes that
any property on our data has changed.
It doesn't have to be is logged in.
It could be any of these four properties.
And that is true for any component.
Whenever Vue sees that the data properties have changed, it re renders that corresponding template
swapping in or re-evaluating anywhere where that data property is being used, whether it's being interpolated
or whether it's being used as a part of a logic for such as RDF statement, right, or a V force statement
anywhere where it's being used, it reevaluates that bit of HTML and dynamically replaces the correct
elements in your page.
All right.
So that is the vision directive used on a view component and also an example of how it can overwrite
a component's data using a method.