Okay.
So let's add some more tests for our job listings component.
The next thing that I'd like to test is when the user is on the first page of job results.
They should not see a link to the previous page of results, and they should see a link to the next
page of results.
In other words, page two.
So in my job listings test file, I'm going to scroll all the way to the bottom and I'm going to add
a new describe function to describe the scenario under which I'm testing.
So when the user is on first page of job results and here I'm going to provide my arrow function, and
I think our two tests here are going to be pretty similar.
So I'm going to write out their descriptions just to start things off, and then we'll populate them
side by side with one another.
So the first thing we want to test is when the user's on the first page.
It does not show link to previous page because of course there is no previous page.
I'm going to provide the arrow function here in line and then immediately below I'll add another one.
It shows link to next page.
Now of course, all of this is assuming we have at least or more than ten job results, but we do have
that hard wired in our Axios call above to return 15 jobs.
So this should hold true.
Okay, so now let's set up our tests right here.
Begin by creating my query params.
So Con square params is going to be an object with a page property.
And I have of course, I'm going to assign it to a value of one where on the first page, then I'm going
to create my root object and I'm going to get it by invoking my create root factory function, passing
in my query params.
Perfect.
Then, of course, I'm going to create my wrapper by shallow mounting my job listings component.
And of course to register that root object, we need to supply it as part of our configuration.
So I'm going to invoke the create config function as my second argument to shallow amount and I'm going
to pass in my round object and that is going to get us up and running and we're going to have the exact
same setup for our second test.
It's still the exact same criteria of being the very first page of job results.
So right here I'm going to paste that code.
And then of course, what I want to look for here is the nonexistence of a previous page link, and
here I want to look for the existence of a next page link.
So right here I'm going to say convert previous page and in my wrapper I'm going to look for a data
test attribute.
So remember to provide these square brackets and I'm looking for a data test at and I'll provide it
with a name, let's say previous page link.
All right.
Now, when the users on the first page of job results, it does not show link to previous page.
So if I invoke the exists method on what this returns.
If view test utils is not able to find any valid HTML element that fits this criteria of having this
down test attribute then exists will return false.
So it should not exist.
So this should be a false.
I'm going to copy and paste this code below and you always have to be careful when copying and pasting
just because you might accidentally leave some old information around.
So in this test, we're not concerned about the previous page.
We're concerned about the next page.
So I'm going to change this to next page and I'm going to look for a date.
It has to at boot of next page link and on the line below.
This will also be next page.
Except the difference here is when we're on the first page, the next page or page two should exist.
So this should be true.
I am going to save this and I'm going to run my test suite with NPM run, test, colon, watch.
And we're actually going to see that one of our tests does not pass or both of them now, actually,
because we don't have the data test attribute, we're getting a little bit ahead of ourselves, but
that's fine.
So of course, all we have to do is scroll up here and add the data test at boot to the router link.
That's the thing that's actually rendering our dynamic links to either the previous page or the next
page.
So right here after class, I'm going to add my data test attribute just for the test.
And here, of course, it's going to be previous page link.
And down below, it's also going to be a data test attribute set to you.
Next page link.
The exact same thing I have in my test.
Save that.
Let's let the test rerun and we're going to see we have a failure.
We're actually going to discover that this is due to a bug in our logic.
We're going to figure out that bug in the next lesson.
But I also want to walk you through the process of how I tried to solve this problem because I wasn't
sure of what was happening.
So my first thought as to what was going wrong was that it had something to do with the resolution of
our mock function.
So when we're worried, when we're thinking about this router link rendering, it's dependent on the
value of the next page computed property.
So what I did is I scroll down and I looked at the next page, computed property to remind myself and
here we are reliant on the jobs data property and of course that jobs data property is populated by
our mock return value from Axios.
So if I scroll up in my test file as a reminder, we're telling get to be simulating.
We're pretending to be a promise that resolves to be an object with a data property with an array of
15 items.
My first thought was for some reason this promise was not resolving in time to update the component
and update the jobs property.
We had this issue before it and you may recall that we used the flush promises function in order to
solve this problem that ensures that all of our promises in the test resolve and thus update the component
accordingly.
So my first thought was that jobs was simply out of sync, and since I had flush promises already imported,
I thought to myself, Well, let me try scrolling down to that function that is failing.
And if I take a look here, it's on this test when users on the first page of job results shows link
to next page.
So I immediately identified it as this test right here.
And what I did is I made this an async test.
And of course after I mount the component, I have to wait for that promise to resolve in order to get
the jobs and update the jobs data property.
So here is where I awaited the flushing of the promise, or in other words, the resolution of the promise.
So I awaited that flush promises function to complete its execution.
Save this and I was saddened to discover that our test suite was still failing.
All right.
So I'm going to show you how I debugged this issue in the very next lesson.