Alright.
So in the previous lesson we got rid of the warnings that were appearing when we were running our test
suite for our main nav component.
And that was because our main nav component was rendering a global router link component.
We replaced that global router link component with a stub, with a substitute with a replacement, which
was this router link stub component that we can get directly from view test utils.
Of course, the reason why it is available is because this is such a common operation that the test
utils team felt it was a good idea to include it.
Now what we have now is pretty decent, but one issue that a person may have with it is the duplication.
We have this extensive setup in every single test that involves us shallow, mounting the same component
and then providing that configuration.
Now, as I've mentioned earlier in the course, duplication is not necessarily a problem, especially
if it makes the test easier to read.
So in this scenario, we understand what each test is doing and we understand it without having to scroll
up or down in the file.
We can just see what we are setting up, what are the configuration settings and then the actual assertion
that we're making.
With that said, if you're adamant about reducing duplication, there are a couple of ways that we can
do so.
And one option is the before each function, which we explored earlier in the course, what before each
allows us to do is to run some kind of function before each test.
So before each function call.
And what we can do in that, before each function is set up our components, set up our wrapper, basically
extract this duplicated code.
So we only have to write it once in our test file instead of in every test.
So here's how it's going to work right here.
I'm going to declare a before each function invocation.
This is a function built into Gest and it accepts a function as its argument.
So I'm going to provide an arrow function in line, and this is the function that we're going to run
once before each test.
More specifically, this is the function that Gest will run for us.
So let's begin by copying and pasting our code from any test below.
So this consort wrapper code that starts up the shallow mounting of our main nav component.
Now the issue here is that we are in a function scope, which is a block scope.
And when you think of the words block, all that really means is the start and end of a pair of curly
braces.
So the function body of the arrow function is an example of a block, and any variables are constants
that we declare in the body of a function are only going to last as long as that block exists.
So while we will run this code every single time before a test, we're not going to have any way to
get access to our wrapper constant because it's going to be gone as soon as the before each function
concludes.
So we need a way to preserve this wrapper.
We need a way to preserve this return value of the shell amount function so that we can reference it
in every test because we can't simply start using wrapper here in line because just in JavaScript are
not going to know what wrapper is.
It's a constant that only exists as long as this function is done running, but not afterwards.
So a very common solution that you'll see is that people will declare a variable in an outer scope because
a function will retain access to variables in any outer scopes, which means scopes that are at a higher
level up.
So outside of the ID function here, we have our described function and its function body.
So anything that we put here will be available in any of our IT functions.
They're going to be able to outreach outside.
To have access to that variable are constant.
So what people typically do is they just say let wrapper, so they declare a variable but do not assign
it a value.
And then indeed before each function they overwrite that wrapper variable with the invocation of the
shallow mount function.
So what's going to happen here is every single time before each runs, once before each test, it's
going to overwrite this variable at a higher scope with the new component that's been shallow mounted.
So we're still going to have independence between our test files or our test suites or our tests more
specifically, because each time we're going to create a new, shallow mounted main nav component and
that new mounted component we're going to keep reassigning back to this wrapper variable.
So we ensure that there's no pollution between tests because for every new test we just create a new
wrapper and reassign it to an existing variable.
The variable stays the same, but the reference that it's storing stays different for every test.
It's a brand new component, so we can do whatever we want with that component.
So with this approach, we now have this wrapper variable that is available.
So in every test we can get rid of the mounting of our component.
So in this test you can see we now have expect wrapper text to match and this wrapper is going to reference
this variable which will have the assignment of the shallow mounted main nav component from the before.
And so we've reduced this test down to a single line.
And same thing here.
We can remove the manual instantiation here in our and our test body.
So we're just going to assume that rapport is going to exist because the before each will set it up
from above.
So let's do that.
Let's also get rid of this content wrapper right here.
Get rid of this content wrapper right here.
And get rid of this concert rapper right here.
I'm going to save this file and hopefully everything will pass and it looks like everything is good.
So once again, whenever any test references rapper, what they are referencing is this variable that
is declared way above here whose value is being assigned in the before each function that is running
once before each test executes.
Okay, so there are, of course, advantages and disadvantages to this approach.
As I mentioned, the reduction of duplication can be argued to be an advantage because the test suite
is shorter.
But whenever somebody is trying to understand what a test is doing, they may scroll down and look at
this and say and say, okay, I'm working with something called a wrapper, but what is that wrapper?
What is the actual component that I'm working with?
I may have forgotten.
How have I configured the settings for that wrapper?
What did I provide?
What stubs did I set up?
And if you ever get confused or you forget, you have to scroll up all the way to the top to remember
what is going on.
Now, if you have a short test file, that may not be a problem.
But in the real world I have seen where this approach can get pretty nasty, where a file may have 300
lines of test code and they may even nest different variables at different levels of execution.
And it becomes difficult to figure out what a value actually means, where it's coming from, where
it's declared.
You have to scroll up and down.
And I would argue the benefit is sometimes the cure is worse than the actual problem, because you have
you may have you may potentially have less duplication, but you may still make the test suite harder
to read and reason about.
Right.
Duplication is prominent, but it's a kind of a simple problem to understand.
You can see the commonalities between tests in every test.
Here you have solved one problem, but you've also in many ways created a different one, which is that
you may potentially make the test suite harder to interpret and understand and require a development
of the piece together the parts of how or what a test needs in order to be able to execute.
So it's a system of tradeoffs and advantages and disadvantages.
I'm not going to always advocate for one thing as being the absolute best way.
I want to expose you to as many different thoughts and methodologies as I can, but that is one way
that we can reduce duplication.
And in the very next lesson, I'll show you another way.