Okay.
So the next component in line is going to be our job listings component.
So let's open up job listings, dot view listings with the S at the end.
And as a reminder, this is the component that actually renders the individual job listing components.
Once it gets that list of filtered jobs from view.
So as I scroll down here, we can see we still need to incorporate TypeScript into this component.
And of course, we've been moving towards a reality where just about every file in our code base is
using TypeScript.
So apologies if some of these lessons or some of these concepts are repeated.
That is the end goal is to move as much or just about all of the code base to TypeScript as possible.
So sometimes it's going to introduce new ideas and sometimes it's going to be more of the same.
All right.
So in this case, this component should be more of the same.
We're just going to follow the exact same protocol as always right here.
Let's add Lang and let's add.
Let's import, define component.
And right here, we're going to invoke that defined component function passing in our object.
And before I say that, everything is good because it looks like there are no violations.
One helper thing that you can do is just hover your mouse over some of these constants to verify that
the types of annotation is correct.
Because remember, TypeScript is going to go into the actual composable that we're utilizing here and
use those return values as the basis for what these constants should be.
So for example, filter jobs is going to be a computed ref.
We know that is the type for a view reactive object and we can see it inside.
It's going to wrap an array of job objects, which is perfect.
Current page is going to be a number wrapped in a reactive object grade.
Max Page is the same thing.
Previous page is going to be the same.
Remember, it can be either number or undefined because it may either be the number of the previous
page or if there is no previous page it will be undefined instead.
Same thing with next page and display jobs right here is similarly going to be a array of jobs wrapped
in a view reactive object.
So it looks like all the infinities look relatively correct by typescript initial guess.
So really there's nothing more left to do in this file.
So with that we can move on to our test file.
So job listings that test docs drag that over to the right.
Scroll up here.
And as always, let's change the extension here to T.S..
So job listings that test that.
Yes.
And we can see down here we're going to get the familiar mock return value issues, not a problem.
So we have three composable is being imported here and we are marking out each one.
So we basically have to use that as keyword three times.
So right here, just to make sure we organize this related code next to each other, I'm going to say,
do we need to mark this one out?
Yes, we do.
Some const use filter jobs.
Mark is going to be use filter jobs as just mark.
And now below that const use fetch jobs dispatch mark is going to be used fetch jobs dispatch as just
mark as well right here we're going to say const use current page mark is going to be the use current
page, imported function above, but with a different type of just mark right here.
We're going to do const use previous and next pages.
Mark is going to be our use previous index pages function but with a manually declared type of just
mark.
All right.
So now we have these ideas, constants and everywhere where we're using the functionality below like
mark return value, we want to include the new references to the objects that TypeScript recognizes
as having a just mark type.
So right here, use filter jobs mark use current page mark, use previous index pages mark.
There we go.
Scrolling down, basically going to be the same thing everywhere.
So this is going to be a little bit of just scrolling through and adding mark to the end of all these
things.
Looks like it's not happy about use current page never mind my editors is slow apologies right here
same thing.
In fact, I could probably start copying a couple of these, but for now, let's write it out.
Let me copy one of them.
Like use filter jobs, mark.
Let me go ahead and replace that right here.
Let me add.
Mark here.
Let me add Mark here.
And a couple more left to go right here, Mark, at the end.
Right here, Mark at the end.
Right here.
Right here, Mark.
Mark and Mark.
All right.
There we go.
And one more.
Always, always one more at the very end of the scroll.
So three more mock functions here that we have to replace with the correct constant references with
the right types.
There we go.
And now it looks like our file does not have any types of violations.
So we can run NPM run, test, watch.
And see if everything is working correctly.
And it looks like everything is working correctly.
From our test suite, it also looks like we're not actually using the the used fetch jobs dispatch function
below to to mock it out in order to call a method like mock resolve value or mock return value.
We can see here that my editor is saying it's declared its values, never read.
So I think we can remove this.
We don't actually need to mock it out or rather declare its type.
And let's let the test suite be run again and everything still works perfect.
All right.
So that completes our refactor of the job listings component.
And I will see you in the next lesson.