Okay.
So in this lesson I'd like to introduce another helper function from the View Library and it is called
map actions.
So you may have noticed there is this trend of helper functions.
They all begin with the word map and then they help us do something with translating the view store,
whether it be the state, the mutations, etc. to app properties on our component.
Right.
So earlier on we explored map state and map mutations.
Let's just do a quick review of what those to do for us here.
In this component, we can see we're using map state.
What that does is it maps or in other words, connects the view store state to local properties on our
job listings component local computed properties to be more specific.
So when we do this code, we're letting view X help us by defining a this dot jobs property immediately
on job listings so we don't have the manually defined a method to do that.
Similarly, what does map mutations help us do?
It helps us connect existing mutations to a component.
Let me just open up our actual store files so we remember, right?
So Map State connects these things right here.
If we were to use map mutations that allows us to have automatic methods in our component that basically
will run mutations for us.
So if we use map mutations and we for example, provide the log in user constant, we're going to have
a method on a component called this, that log in user that's going to run this mutation for us.
Right now, when it comes to actions, we have a single action called fetch jobs and we are dispatching
that action in our mountain lifecycle.
But as you might guess, this is a very common operation in view.
We will always call the dispatch method with the name of some kind of action that we want to run.
So wouldn't it be really convenient if we had a method on our component called fetch jobs?
And that method would know that it should simply call the dispatch method on our store and pass in this
string argument of fetch jobs.
Well, as it turns out, View provides us with a function called map actions that does the exact same
thing.
The reason it's called map actions is it because it maps or connects view store actions.
These things right here two methods on our component.
So we're simply translating something from our view store to our component wherever we use them.
Right.
Map State connects this stuff to our component as computed properties.
Map mutations connects these methods to component methods and map actions connects these methods to
our component methods.
So let me show you how this is going to work and scroll up and I'm going to import map actions.
It's also going to come as a named export from the top level of view X.
And right here, let me show you this code side by side.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to come at this out.
What I'm going to do below is I'm going to define my methods object.
This is regular view syntax.
Here is where we can define our component methods and here I'm going to invoke map actions.
And just like map state and map mutations, this function returns an object with properties and I want
to make sure ID structure those properties.
So what this object returns is going to be a bunch of methods and I'm going to make those top level
methods in my methods.
Object for the job listings component.
What I provide to map actions is an array of the actions that I want to make available to the job listings
component.
It's the exact same API as we saw earlier from Maps State.
Here's an example of Map State with jobs.
Here's we're going to do map actions, an array of the available actions.
We currently only have one action represented by the fetch job's name or constant, which we already
have imported into this file.
So I'm simply going to provide fetch jobs here.
Okay.
So I know this is confusing.
So let me reiterate what this is doing.
What this is doing is creating an automatic method on our component called this dot fetch jobs.
Right?
And if I provided an additional argument here like A or B, assuming we had those actions, we would
then have similar methods on our job listings component of this dot A and this that B, so this creates
an automatic fetch jobs method on my job listings component.
And what does that method do?
It does exactly what we're doing here on line 73 for us.
Behind the scenes, what we're telling view is, Hey, we're going to need a fetch jobs method.
It's going to be an action, which means it's going to be some message you dispatched to the store and
it's going to have this name so view.
And you know, okay, you're giving me an action.
The only thing I can do with that is talk to The View Store.
How do I dispatch an action to the bookstore?
I need to call the Dispatch method on my store object.
This is basically a syntactic sugar or in other words, a simpler and cleaner way to doing this view
X will create a method on job listings called this that fetch jobs which will dispatch the fetch jobs.
Action to our view store.
So just because we've defined that method doesn't mean we're actually doing anything with it.
We need to invoke it in our mountain lifecycle.
Look.
So here, instead of dispatching the fetch jobs action directly, we're going to do it indirectly by
simply invoking my fetch jobs method, which is automatically defined for me on the component.
With this code right here, I would not have this method if this line did not exist.
Now we have a fetch jobs method that will dispatch the effects jobs action to the store.
All right.
You have to be careful here.
You have to make sure here you do not provide any state or any mutations.
You have to provide actions in the same way as with map state.
You have to provide a valid piece of state in the same way that with map mutations, you have to provide
valid mutation names.
So don't accidentally pass the wrong thing with map actions.
We only provide action names and you create methods with equivalent names, honor component so we can
get rid of this line.
It leads us to a little bit of a cleaner code because we don't need to worry about the dispatch method
or how this store operates.
And if I save this, you're going to see all of our test bill pass, because under the hood view X is
doing the exact same thing for us.
It's still talking to the store, it's still invoking the dispatch method, and it's still passing the
argument to fetch jobs to it.
But it's doing it automatically in a method that it auto defines for us called fetch jobs available
on this component via this keyword.
That's what map actions does.
Hopefully that has been helpful and I will see you in the next lesson.