Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to introduce you to a super cool feature of TypeScript, and it is generics.
And the easiest way to understand generics is to see the problem that they solve.
So I want to immediately get into writing the code and then we'll provide the more in-depth explanation
later.
Before we get there, though, there's one configuration setting you have to make in your playground
to ensure the code that we're about to write doesn't trigger an error.
So go ahead and click on this button right here, test config.
And that's going to bring up a configuration screen where we can set some of the settings for the playground.
And you should see a category called Gsx.
And most likely when this playground initializes, it's probably going to have a value of react right
here.
That's not a problem, but make sure that you switch it to the value none.
So Gsx should be equal to none.
And once that is complete you can close out of the configuration window and everything should work in
this lesson.
Okay, so on to the problem.
Let's see.
The problem we have here is we want to write a function that accepts an array as an argument and then
returns a copy of that array.
Right?
So basically clones the contents of the array, very common operation, especially if you're dealing
with something like functional programming.
So if I was a regular JavaScript programmer, I might write my implementation like this.
I can say content copy array is going to be an arrow function and it's going to accept a parameter,
let's call it array.
And what it's going to do is copy the values of that array into a brand new array.
And one really easy way to do this in E6 is to implicitly return an array.
And right here I'm going to use the spread operator to spread out all of the elements or values in my
array parameter, put them into this new array and then immediately return it.
All right.
So it's a really simple, elegant one line way to copy and array.
The JavaScript interpreter would say, This is totally fine.
Unfortunately, TypeScript is not going to be happy with this.
And the reason it's not happy is, of course, because it doesn't know what the array parameter is.
It says parameter array implicitly has an any type, and because we haven't told it that it's an array,
it can't validate that something like this spreading operation is valid.
So let's see today, our problem that we're trying to solve is that we're trying to make a copy of a
string array.
So our simple solution might be to say, okay, this array parameter is going to be a string array,
and that solves the problem for the day.
And so we're very happy.
But let's imagine we run into another problem the very next day.
Let's say our boss comes to us and says, Well, I'd like you to write a new function or use your existing
function, but I want it to accept an array of numbers and I want it to create a copy of that array
of numbers.
Well, we have a function now that's going to have a very similar implementation, but it accepts a
different type of array, an array of numbers versus an array of strings.
So how would we solve that problem?
Well, there's two solutions.
And one of them and neither of them really is actually that great.
One option is we could tell TypeScript that array right here is going to be either a string array or
a number.
Right.
And there's a way to do that syntactically.
But that's obviously not scalable because what happens the next day, if we have an array of booleans
or an array of arrays or an array of objects or an array of job objects, right?
Each type of object is different in TypeScript.
So if we keep saying all of these either or situations, we're quickly going to balloon this function.
It's going to be pretty complex to understand.
And the second solution, which is just as well not as great and not scalable, is to simply make multiple
functions.
So maybe the simple solution I might think of as, Oh, I'll make this function called the copy string
array, which will allow me to create a separate arrow function called the copy number array.
And it's going to be the exact same except for my array parameter.
I'll change that to be a number array and then I'll simply write the exact same logic to make a copy
of that number array.
So once again, the problem with this approach is it's not scalable.
What happens if we want to copy a boolean array?
What happens if we want to copy a array of objects and so on and so forth?
We can't just write a a new function every single time we have an array of something else, right?
It's not scalable, it's redundant.
And it's for these kinds of situations where we have functions that have the exact same implementation
but only vary in the type of some of its parameters that we can use generics to solve this problem.
So why are they called generics?
Well, the name is actually kind of ingenious.
And I want you to think about what the word generic means in the real world.
The word generic basically means not specific.
Right.
When you think about the words like generic cereal, right.
Or generic newspaper, you're talking about something that is not special, right?
It's not specific.
It's not known.
It's kind of generic.
Right.
It's meant you don't care about it.
It's sort of the same principle here.
What generics allow us to do is to define a function that's going to accept a generic type.
And basically a generic type is a nonspecific type that we don't know in advance.
And we're only going to know it when we're going to invoke that function.
All right.
That's a lot to take in.
So let me show you the syntax and how it's going to work.
So I'm going to remove this second function right here and I'm going to change this back to being copy
array.
And what I want to do is I want to allow my copy array function to accept a generic type argument.
So rather than being specific about string right here, I want string to be some kind of type that I
cannot predict in advance.
Rather than being a specific type like string or number or boolean.
I just want to call it a generic type, some type that I don't know yet.
Right.
And in order to specify the my copy array function will accept a generic type as an argument.
What I do is before the parameter list, I provide this pair of brackets.
It's the less than sine followed by the greater than sine.
And in here what I define is the parameters for the expected generic types.
All right.
Now you can actually define whatever name you want, and here you can almost think of it as being very
similar to the parameter, the parameters you define within the parentheses.
So this can be whatever you want, but the common community convention you're going to see is to give
each type a single letter name.
And the most common one you're going to see is Capital T.
And the reason that is common is because T is short for type.
So what have we done here?
We've said that whenever anybody invokes copy array later, we're going to expect that invocation to
give me a more specific type than just capital T, give me a concrete type like string, like number,
like Boolean, etc..
I don't know what that's going to be in the future, but t is going to be its generic representation,
almost like the standard for that eventual real type value.
Now, whatever that eventual invocation gives me as T, I can then utilize in, for example, my parameter
list right here.
And for example, in my return value.
So let's get rid of this string right here and let's think about this problem.
Whenever I invoke copy array later, I promise to provide something of type T, an actual type like
string.
If I know that T is that, then I can say that the parameter array will be of type t array.
Right.
So once again, I don't know what T is going to be in advance, but I'm going to expect an invocation
to tell me and I'm going to say that this is going to be an array of some type called T, right?
T is my generic name for something that will be specific later.
And I also know that whatever t is, the array that I accept will be an array of t, and then the array
I return will also be an array of t, whatever it happens to be.
So if I want to explicitly declare a return value here, I can do a colon and then say the return value
will be of type array of t.
All right.
So this is generic.
Why is it generic?
Because it's not specific.
We don't know what it is.
But what I'm telling TypeScript is whatever t will be, understand that array is going to be an array
of that and the final return value will be an array of that type as well.
I don't know what t is, but I'm going to say whatever it is, you're going to have an array of it as
a parameter and an array of it as the return value of this function.
So now down below, as I mentioned, we can invoke copyright.
And before we provide the parentheses to provide the parameter, what we need to do is to specify what
T is going to be.
So right here, I'm going to provide the exact same pair of brackets.
And here is where I provide a more concrete value.
So, for example, let's say I now want T and this invocation to be the concrete type of number.
So moving from a generic type of T, which is kind of ambiguous to a more specific type of number.
So what TypeScript is going to do behind the scenes is going to basically look at copy array and substitute
number wherever it sees T.
So behind the scenes type type, which is going to say, okay, now I have a copy array function.
My array is going to be of number or my array parameter is going to be number eight and my return value
is going to be of type number array as well.
And all of that happens because we told TypeScript to substitute T right here with this number.
Number is the specific type argument for this generic T type argument that we specified here.
So now.
We've we've told TypeScript that the the type will be number, which means this array parameter will
be expected to be a number array.
So right here, I'll be able to provide something like a number array.
You can see even in the highlight that TypeScript understands it should be a number.
Right.
And that will return a number.
So I can provide a sample array like one, two and you can see the function is going to work just fine.
No errors.
But what is the beautiful part of this approach is we can substitute any specific type to replace the
generic type.
So for example, what if I want to copy an array of strings?
Not a problem.
I'm still going to use copy array.
But now for the specific type to replace teh above.
I'm going to say that for this invocation I want to be literally a string type rather than the my generic.
I want to be a string.
So once again, TypeScript is going to say, okay, you've told me that this is straight, that this
is a type string.
So I know the array parameter will be a string array and I know the return value must be a string array
as well.
They can perform the same validation as if we had simply written out string in line.
All right.
So right here I can say invoke this copy array function.
You can see it now expects a string array and I can provide an array with values like Hello and world.
Right.
And you guessed it.
How would we treat a boolean array?
Exactly as you might expect.
I have to tell TypeScript that the value of my T type is going to be a more specific type of boolean.
And so now when we invoke this, you can see TypeScript figures out that it needs an array parameter
of type boolean array and a return value should also be boolean array.
And it's going to validate that our logic holds as we run.
This function's right here an array of true false, and you can see our errors go out.
All right.
So that is the benefit of generics.
They allow us to write more reusable functions.
And the way they allow us to make more usable functions is by providing generic type parameters.
We say, hey, whenever we're going to run this function later, we must provide a more specific type
for some parameter.
That is a type that I would define here.
It's not the same thing as our regular parameters right here.
Right, because our regular parameters are inputs to the function here.
This think this t is a more generic typescript thing where typescript needs to be told what the more
specific value of this generic t will be.
Whenever we invoke the function.
As far as the name right here, this can be anything else.
This could be whatever we want.
It can be type, it can be, you know, kind of type.
It can be whatever we want.
But the common convention you're going to see is a single character, and most often it's going to be
T because T is kind of short for type.
All right.
That's what we're doing here.
Hopefully this makes sense and hopefully it helps explain the benefits of how generics can offer a lot
of reusability in your code.
Again, the reason the call generic is because this type of T is generic.
It's not specific, it's not concrete, it's abstract, it's generic.
And we provide a more concrete type when we actually run the logic of the function.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.