Okay.
So we now have two brand new getters in our Getters file and we've written the complimentary tests for
those two new getters.
However, we're not actually using them anywhere.
So in this lesson, we're finally going to make all the pieces come together.
We're going to utilize our two new getters in our filtered jobs getter, and that's going to allow us
to significantly cut down the code here.
So here's the first thing I want to introduce.
We can actually receive a reference to every available getter as the second argument to a getter method.
All right.
So what I'm going to do here is for my filter jobs getter after my state, I'm going to provide a second
argument and I'm going to call it getters.
The second argument to any getter method is an object that has all of the getters on it.
So you can think of this parameter as being equivalent to this complete object right here.
This entire getters object is what we can pass in as the second argument to a getter.
Now I want to make sure that we're not confused between this syntax and the syntax that we have and
the two getters above.
Whenever we need a getter that accepts a custom argument from us, we need to define a getter that returns
a function.
And in that function we define our arguments or our parameters for those arguments.
In comparison, in the original getter method.
If we provide a second argument after the state, that second argument view X will always provide the
complete object of getters.
So on this getter object, we're going to have every getter with c above filter jobs by job types,
include job by organization, include job by job that, etc. This is a reference to the very object
we are in with all of these getter methods.
So knowing that, we can now simplify our code below because we have all of this filter logic captured
right here.
So let's delete lines 49 and 50.
And right here, I'm just going to delete my former implementation.
Bring it down to justice.
So for my very first filter, what do I want to do?
I want to use the getter I have above called include job by organization.
I'm still iterating over status jobs.
I'm still providing JavaScript with a function for my filter method that's going to be used to filter
my jobs.
So I know I have my complete object of getters represented by my getters parameter.
My second argument to a getter method above and on this getter object.
What are going to be my available getters?
All of the ones I have above.
So I'm simply going to use my include job by organization getter from above and here I'm going to invoke
it.
And keep in mind it's a little bit confusing because if we look up, we're going to think that we're
invoking this thing right here which accepts State as its first argument, and that's the exact same
way it is in a test suite.
But behind the scenes, what Vue is going to do whenever we use this getter syntax is it's automatically
going to invoke the getter for us and pass in the view X Store State.
So what it's actually going to be returning to us here is the function that we define right here so
we can directly pass in our job right here.
And that is going to represent this function right here that we're going to get as the return value
of the include job by organization getter.
I know it's a little bit confusing because this syntax that Vue uses behind the scenes is a little bit
different from how we manually test it in our test suite, where we treat it as a plain JavaScript method.
But the short takeaway is View X will automatically invoke the getter method passing in the state,
and the function that it returns back is that we're actually going to have access to here and what we're
actually invoking and passing the job into.
I'm going to repeat the exact same logic below.
So I'm going to remove my former code here, remove my closing curly brace here.
And right here, I'm going to do getters.
What getter do I want to access?
The one I just defined above called include job by job type.
Invoke that which is the function of that getter returns.
And I want to provide that function with the job that I'm currently iterating over.
Right.
I'm going to save that.
And that is our new code.
All right.
So what have we done in filter jobs?
In filter jobs?
We have accepted a second argument with all of our getters, and we've used two of those getters to
help us filter down the individual jobs that we are iterating over.
When we use the filter method, we're going to get JavaScript to iterate over an individual job, which
is exactly what each of these getters accepts or expects.
They are a method, but a method that returns a function that accepts a single job.
And the beautiful part about this design is notice how we've separated the logic of checking for organizations
away from the logic, from checking from job types.
So in this getter right here, this getter knows about one piece of the view store state selected organizations,
and it knows about one property organization on every job object.
And we've completely decoupled that and separated that from the logic of these selected job types array
and the job type property on an individual job.
So we've kind of gotten the best of both worlds.
If we think back to our original implementation, where we had just two separate getters.
Filter jobs by organizations, filter jobs by job types.
We've kind of captured that filtering logic for a single job across these two getters.
And so this filter jobs getter can simply act as this composite getter that simply combines those different
bits of functionality together, right?
So everything should still work in the browser blitz validate.
I'm going to go back to my browser.
And I'm going to expand organizations and expand job types.
I'm going to filter for organization like YouTube.
You can see YouTube works if I add another one like edit view root.
I'm assuming it's going to expand.
There we go.
If you root a YouTube, I'm going to filter for only full time jobs.
We see it works in the right.
Intern jobs as well.
Part time jobs.
You can do it.
Remove YouTube.
Everything seems to be working as a navigate across these different checkboxes and check them so everything
is still working.
We have the exact same solution that we had when we started this refactor.
However, to me it's a significantly smaller cleaner.
We've separated the responsibilities and the filter logic to smaller getters, and we learn more about
how we can use more advanced getter features in view such as defining getters that accept arguments
and such as relying on other getters within a starter getter.
So in this starter getter method, we are using the second argument to get our getters object and using
those supplementary getters to handle smaller bits of responsibility, to handle smaller bits of filtering
logic.
All right.
Lots of small, simple methods is the way to go and makes your code significantly easier to read.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.