Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to make a small refactor in our main nav component.
You may have noticed right here that when we invoke the commit method, we are passing a string in line.
We are typing this log in user string which represents the mutation we want to run on our view.
X4 Now imagine hypothetically that we ran this mutation from three or four different components.
Whenever we write a string in line like this, we always open up the possibility that we can make a
typo, that we can include an extra character or exclude a character or type the wrong casing, etc.
And especially if we have multiple places or multiple components in our app that are issuing the same
mutation, we always introduce the possibility of a typo.
So one way that we can solve this is by creating a constant that stores the correct mutation name and
then simply referencing that constant anywhere where we want to commit that mutation, and that just
reduces the chance of error.
So let me show you what we're going to do.
We're going to open up our store index file.
This is where we configure our store.
And at the very top here, I'm going to create and export a constant and I'm literally going to call
it log in user.
And all it's going to be is just that string of log in underscore user.
So this is where I have to be super careful that I typed the name of the mutation correctly.
In fact, one optimization that we can make here is we can use this string right here as the name of
our method right here.
They are exactly the same, and I know that.
But it's going to be a dynamic reference to whatever we have here, and that just ensures that wherever
we use this log in use are constant.
Even if this is a typo, we're always going to reference a valid mutation on our store.
So what I mean by that is, let's say we accidentally made this log in users.
Well, once I replace this property with a dynamic reference to a constant, which I can do as a reminder
with my square brackets.
So here I'm going to reference my log in, use our constant above, which is going to be whatever string
this is.
Let's say hypothetically, this is nonsense, right?
In that case, we now have a method called nonsense on our mutations object.
So wherever we use the log in user constant throughout the app, as long as we know that we must always
commit a mutation by providing a string referenced by a constant.
Even if this is something like nonsense, it's still going to reference a valid mutation on our mutation
object, and there's now no chance of an actual typo because we're always going to reference something
that has to be an actual valid mutation method.
All right.
That's the advantage of this approach.
So I'm going to change this back to log in user.
And we still have a logging user method on our mutations object.
We're just getting its method name from this constant right here and now that allows me and Main NAV
to import that constant.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to scroll up to where we begin.
Our script section of the component.
So right here and what I'm going to do is I'm going to import the log in user constant and that is going
to come from my top level source directory.
And then we have our store folder and there is where we have our index that Yes.
File with that exported constant of log in user.
So now I'm going to scroll down and instead of writing this string in line and opening it up to typos,
I'm just going to pass in the log in user constant, which is going to be a reference to a method that
I can guarantee will exist on the mutations object because we have dynamically referenced that constant
as a property right here rather than writing out logging user here in line.
Hopefully that makes sense.
But with that we have completed our refactor.
We have extracted the log in user string to its own constant.
And now if we have any other mutations throughout the app or rather any other mutations to the store
that will use the log in user mutation, we can continue to use this log in user constant and reduce
the chances we have of a typo in our component.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in next one.