Okay.
So I think now is a good time for us to see how things are looking in the browser.
But before we get there, there's one thing I forgot to do in the previous lesson in our job filter
sidebar component.
You'll notice on line 19 we have this accordion child component being rendered, and this was intended
to be sort of the placeholder for the eventual checkbox group.
It's basically just an accordion component that doesn't have anything inside it and it has a header
of degree.
So we've replaced this visual logic with our actual checkbox group right here.
So we no longer really need this accordion, so I can go ahead and remove it right here.
And if I scroll down, let me see if accordion is being used at all elsewhere in the component and it
doesn't look like it is.
You can see right here, if I hover my mouse, it says type.
The accordion component has been registered but not used.
So we can go ahead and remove accordion right here and remove accordion from the imports as well.
All right.
So we are still using accordions, but they are nested within the checkbox group component.
Component.
If I go in here, you can see here is where we're using accordion, so we'll keep it in here, but we
no longer need it directly in job filter's sidebar.
Okay, so with that, let's check in on our browser.
So I'm going to navigate to Chrome and refresh the page just to be safe.
And there we have that.
We have our job types, we have our organizations.
Let's see what happens when we unfold the accordion.
Four degrees.
All right.
It doesn't look like we have any checkboxes.
So what is going on here?
Well, the good news is the page isn't crashing and we don't have any errors.
So what's actually going on here is that we've never actually initiated the API request to fetch our
degrees themselves and thus there are no unique degrees to render checkboxes for.
So as a reminder, if I go back to my code base.
We have an action in our actions to follow.
It's right here.
That action is called fetch degrees, and that is the asynchronous action that uses the Get Degrees
API function call to get that array of degrees from an end point and then commit the receive degrees
mutation to save it to the View Store.
But there's nowhere where we're actually initiating this action.
And remember, the technical word for initiating an action is dispatching it.
So in other words, there's nowhere where we're dispatching the fetch degrees action, so we're never
kicking off the API request.
So we can perhaps use the Fetch Jobs Act action as an inspiration for what we want to do with fetch
degrees.
So the way that works as a reminder is if I open up my job listings, component listings with a plural
s, what we're doing in this component is we're using a composable function called use, fetch jobs
dispatch, and we're feeding it into our on mounted IT lifecycle hub in our set up method right here
in line 52.
If I go further into this actual composable function, what does this composable function do?
It talks to the bookstore and it dispatches the exact action that it wants to do, which is fetch jobs.
This is the exact same name as we have in our actions.
File this action right here.
So that's the composable function that kicks off the actual asynchronous actions.
Fetch the jobs.
So similarly, what we're going to need to do is to come up with a composable function, and its whole
responsibility will be to actually kick off the or the dispatch of the asynchronous action, which will
kick off the entire cycle of making the API request and saving the data.
All right.
So I'm once again going to open this file and I'm also going to open up my composable test that that's
out.
And luckily, we're already going to have tests for the use fetch jobs dispatch right here.
And we can basically make a new test that's going to be very similar.
So right here, I'm going to describe the new composable function.
I'd like to define and let's call it use fetch degrees dispatch.
All right.
So it's going to dispatch an action to the U.S. store and that action is going to fetch degrees.
And what is this composable responsibility?
It sends call to fetch degrees from API.
All right.
Our test is going to be very similar to the one above, because what we're basically testing here is
that the dispatch method has been invoked on our store with the correct argument.
And that argument, of course, is a string representing the action that we want to start running.
Right.
So right here, I'm going to define a dispatch, and that is simply going to be a just mock function
that can track if it's been invoked and with what arguments.
Then we have our use store mark to represent the return value of use store.
We're going to mock return here so that we replace the default implementation with our own.
And all I want to do here is have an object with a dispatch method.
So right here on line 39, for example, in the previous test, we're returning an object with a dispatch
method, and that dispatch method is a just mock function.
So when line 40 runs, the test will run through that logic, and then the just mock function will understand
that it has been invoked once with an argument of fetch jobs.
So we're going to do something very similar here.
We're going to invoke our new composable function.
It doesn't yet exist, but we can assume it's going to be called something like used fetch degrees dispatch.
So if I scroll up all the way to the top of this file, we can import that non-existent function right
here.
Use fetch degrees at dispatch.
All right.
And then down below, just like in the test above, I'm going to invoke it.
So use fetch degrees of dispatch.
And just by invoking it once, it should run through the eventual logic.
And that eventual logic should have a communication with this dispatch mock function right here.
So after my new composable is done running, what I expect is that my dispatch mock function above should
have been invoked, number one.
And number two, it should have been invoked with the right argument, which is the name of the action
that I want to run.
And with this composable, of course, the action that I want to initiate is going to be fetch degrees.
So right here on my just mock function, I expect it to have been called with the following argument,
and that's going to be a string of fetch degrees.
All right.
Save that.
And with that, we can go ahead and create our implementation.
So in order to dispatch this action to our UCS store, obviously we're going to need the action name
and that is available, luckily, as a constant.
So if I scroll up all the way to the top of the file, your notice, you'll notice here that we are
importing Oliver constants.
We already have a fetch degrees constant in this file because we wrote it in order to define the corresponding
action in our actions test file right here.
So in composable stats I'm going to import my fetch degrees constant and then down below.
In this action section I'm going to define my new composable function.
I'm going to call it the exact same way I called it on the right hand side.
So my test expects it to be called use fetch degrees dispatch since that is what it is importing.
It's going to be an arrow function that accepts no argument.
And what I'm going to do in the body of this function is, of course, talk to my UCS store, which
I can get access to using the use store composable function from view passing in the key.
And so now I have a full store object.
That store object is going to have a dispatch method, right?
And in the real world, this is how we initiate an action.
But in our tests, our dispatch method is now going to be replaced with a just mock function that can
track that it has been invoked.
And of course, I need to provide here a string representing the name of the action that I want to run.
I want to run this action right here, fetch degrees.
So right here, I'm going to provide the imported constant of fetch degrees.
Save that.
Let's let our tests run.
And you can see everything is passing.
All right.
So now that we have our new composable function that initiates the action, that makes the request,
we can then use it in our job listings component, and we're going to do that in the very next lesson.