Okay.
So our View Store now has a selected organization's property that's going to be an array of the user's
chosen organizations to filter by.
And of course, we also have the corresponding mutation to receive that array and overwrite that property
in our view store.
So now we have everything we need in our view X Store in order to filter our array of 100 jobs down
to only those that have an organization that is in our selected organization's array.
So what we have here is ultimately derived data.
We need to take our original array of jobs and we need to filter it down to a smaller array of jobs
that is derived data.
It is not an original piece of data.
It is not something that we are creating from scratch.
Rather, it is something that is dependent on other pieces of our view stored data.
So for these kinds of situations, the optimal thing that we need is a getter.
Because remember, a getter is like a computed property on a component.
It exists to watch other pieces of data and react whenever they change.
And that's exactly what we want to do here.
Whenever the user selects a checkbox, we're going to update the View Store State to have a updated
array for selected organizations, and we want that to be able to filter our jobs array.
And that filter array is ultimately the jobs that we want to present on the right hand side of the page.
So no new data here, just derived or calculated or computed data.
So we're going to write a letter to capture those jobs that fit that criteria.
And as always, now we're going to use TDD, so we're going to write our test first for our getter and
then we're going to implement it.
So on the left hand side, I have my store and all of the view stuff.
On the left hand side I have my index that test, that just file and I'm going to scroll down here.
We're going to find our getter section.
So here's mutations and here's getters.
Right now we only have one for unique organizations.
So within this, getters describe.
BLOCK I'm going to write another describe.
And we can come up with a simple name for our getter.
Let's call it filter jobs by organization.
This is going to represent the jobs that we're going to filter based on having a matching organization.
All right.
So right here, I'm going to provide my arrow function.
And then my description.
So what does this getter do?
It identifies jobs that are associated with the given organizations.
Okay.
So as a reminder, we're going to need to use two pieces of the View Store State in order to arrive
at our final filter jobs.
Right.
We need a jobs property and we need a selected organization's property.
So I'm going to need to create a sample view store state here as a JavaScript object that has those
two properties we don't really care about is logged in.
So we're not going to worry about that, but we do need to worry about these two.
So right here I'm going to create a JavaScript object called State.
And we know that our state object is going to need to have a jobs array.
And it's also going to need to have a selected organization's array.
Okay.
Now, as a reminder, selected organizations is going to be a array of strings.
So, for example, let's just populated with two sample companies.
Let's do Google and let's do Microsoft.
And that means in our jobs, Ray, we're going to need a couple objects here.
And as you might guess, what we want to check is if we have a job that has an organization of either
Google or Microsoft.
We want to include it.
And if it has an organization that is not one of those two, we do not want to include it.
So, for example, I can just define a job object.
And of course, we could give it all of the properties that a real job has, like an I.D., like a title.
But we don't really care about those properties because after all, we're ultimately going to be using
to filter is going to be the organization property.
That's the way it is in debate at JSON and that's the way it's going to work in the real world.
So for these job objects, in my opinion, I don't think we need to add anything beyond an organization
property that is enough to verify that the test and the getter are going to work as they're supposed
to.
For example, I can have a job with an organization of Google.
And later on and on the next line, I want a job that has an organization that is neither Google or
Microsoft just to verify that we are correctly removing this object from our filter to.
So maybe I'll have a organization of Amazon.
So this object should not be included.
And finally, for our third object, I'll have an organization of Microsoft.
So as you might guess, what we're going to test for here is ultimately that we filter down this jobs
array to just two objects, the organization with Google and the organization with Microsoft.
So we are testing the we are correctly using this arrest strings to filter this array of objects.
All right.
So down below.
I'm going to say that I'm going to assume on my getters object, which is already imported into this
file, that I'm eventually going to have a getter called filter jobs by organization.
The exact same name we gave our test description of above.
And this getter, like all getters, is going to be past the current view store state.
So this is going to be the current state which we have represented by our sample JavaScript object above.
And what do we want this getter to return to us?
We want it to return an array of jobs that fit this criteria.
Right?
So right here, I can simply write something like.
Filter jobs.
All right.
And then what do I expect that filter jobs rate to be just an array of two organizations.
So right here, I expect my filter jobs to equal an array.
And it's going to be a derived piece of data dependent on this jobs array.
I want to have my original object with an organization of Google because that should be included.
And then I also expect to filter this job with an organization of Microsoft.
So that is what I want the final result to be.
I'm not writing the implementation yet.
I'm just writing what it should return.
That is the whole point of TDI.
We don't know how our eventual getters going to implement this logic, but we know that our logic is
successfully implemented if we're getting this result.
If we if we start out with our entire view store state and what we get back is an array of the jobs
that fit the criteria of belonging to an organization that the user has selected, which is represented
by these selected organizations.
Array of strings right here.
So if we get this, we know that our logic is correct.
So now we can follow TDD to get to our working solution.
So right here we can see the very first error that JavaScript is telling us is we don't have a function
by that name defined.
So we can start by defining it in our actual view file.
So right here, we're going to need to define a constant since we're going to be using constants all
over the place to define our method names.
So right here I'm going to write another export ID constant, and this one will be called the filter
jobs by organization, the exact same name we chose in our test and the string value of that constant
will be the exact same filter jobs by organization.
In fact, the more I think about it, we're actually filtering jobs by more than one organization organizations.
So I think let's change this all to be plural.
So right here, filter jobs by organizations, filter jobs by organizations right here or organizations
right here.
We have plural and right here filter jobs by organizations as well, because in theory, we can filter
multiple jobs by multiple organizations.
So I think this is a little bit more technically accurate.
Okay.
So we now we have the constant and we can use it in our getters object right here, which is just a
bunch of getter methods.
So our getter is going to be called filter jobs by organization.
It's going to be a method and it's always going to accept the current store state as the first argument
view is going to automatically pass it that information.
So we're going to get the real state object.
So for the purposes of our test, you can think of it as this object right here.
So we have our state and now we need to use that state as it is to filter to get to this array that
we want right here.
So how do we do this?
Well, we know on our state object either right here or right here that we have our jobs property.
So let's start by accessing state to jobs.
And how do we filter down an array to a smaller subset of elements in a new array?
Well, we talked about it in the previous lesson.
We can use the filter method.
So right here I want to invoke filter to get back a brand new array and I'm going to iterate over every
individual job object in the real world.
It's going to be an array of 100 jobs in our test suite.
It's going to be an array of three jobs, but no problem.
Same concept.
We're going to be iterating over one job at a time.
Okay.
What do I want to do with every job?
Remember that every job is going to have an organization property.
I want to access that organization property.
I want to get Google, for example, and I want to check whether this string is included in my selected
organization's array.
The way I can do that is by using the includes method on an array.
The includes method in JavaScript is invoked on an array.
It accepts an argument and it tells you whether that argument is in the array.
It returns true or false.
So from my state, my view is state.
I have on that state a property called selected organizations.
That's my array of strings.
And on that array I want to invoke my includes method that will return true or false depending on whether
the argument is in the array or not.
And my filter method expects a true or false.
So includes is a perfectly valid thing to use here.
And what string do I want to look for in my selected organization's array of strings?
I want to take the current job object I'm iterating over.
I want to get its organization string, and I want to see whether my selected organization's rate includes
that organization.
So of the 100 jobs that I iterate over, go to each jobs organization property, get that string and
double check whether that string is in the array of selected organizations.
So I'm going to save this.
And then the other very important thing to do here, because our test is going to fail in just a moment,
you're going to see that is, of course, we are filtering correctly, but we're not actually returning
this returned array that filter gives to us.
So the filter method is going to return an array of the jobs that fit the criteria.
I'm going to return that.
Save that and we'll see if that works.
And indeed it does.
So now we are correctly filtering our original jobs array from out of state to only those arrays that
have an organization.
It's only those jobs, rather, that have an organization that is a string that is also found in our
selected organizations array.
And in the real world, of course, each job is going to be much more complex than this.
It's going to have ten or 11 or so properties, however many we defined in DB in our JSON.
But we don't care because this logic in this test verifies that the core structure of how our implementation
works is valid.
If we added 11 more properties to each job object, it wouldn't make a difference to how our garner
is filtering because all our Gardner cares about is the organization, property and any given job object.
All right.
So with that, we now have a getter to get these filter jobs based on the current view extra state.
So of course, the next step is finally rendering on the right hand side of the page.
The filter jobs.
As soon as the user has selected a checkbox, we're going to take care of that in the very next lesson.