Okay.
So the next thing that I'd like to do is to perform another refactor.
What I'd like to do is to move this logic right here, this selection of the next array element out
of our headline view component.
I want to move this into a separate helper function somewhere else in our code base.
Now, why do I think this is a good thing to do?
Well, right now, there's really no other use cases where we need to select the next item from an array.
But this is something that I can imagine other components on our site eventually needing, right?
Having some kind of an array of values and needing to select the next value.
And more importantly than even that is this idea of keeping our component as lightweight as possible.
Right?
If this logic doesn't need to live in the component, then we can definitely extract it out.
And the advantages we can then unit test the logic for this function without needing this encompassing
wrapper of the headline component.
We make the components smaller.
We reduce its responsibilities.
We isolate this logic so we can test the headline component separately and independently of this logic,
and then test this function logic separately and independently from the headline component as well.
So we split things up.
You have to always be unafraid to make lots of small objects or small things, small responsibilities
in programming, because it's a lot easier to reason it out and test when you have lots of small functions,
classes, etc. components compared to large components that do many things right.
So we'll talk later about testing things like set interval and stuff like that.
For now, I want to move the logic of the function that we pass to set interval out of this component.
Now I do want to retain some aspects of this function, but I also want to abandon others.
So, for example, this selection logic of getting the next element from the array makes sense to me
because that is replicable and applicable somewhere else.
I can easily imagine it being used for some kind of other flashing selection of text somewhere in the
app.
In comparison, our array of actions is something that does feel like it belongs in headline.
It's the headline component that should know about these action verbs, but maybe it should not know
about how to find the next one.
In other words, other components in the app probably will not use this collection of actions.
So I'd like to write a function that I can provide a array of words to and isolate just this logic to
that function.
Right.
It's kind of a tough concept to explain in terms of where do we put responsibilities.
But the ultimate goal, as always, is re-use, right?
How can I isolate the things that are common somewhere else while keeping the things that are unique
in their original location so this feels distinct and related and important to the headline component.
This array based logic does not necessarily pertain to headline.
So this is what I want to move out.
All right.
So what we're going to do is we're going to follow a TDD approach, test driven development to write
a test for this function logic.
And then we're going to slowly migrate this code from headline to our eventual utility, a JavaScript
file.
So let's begin by creating that file.
So right now, I'm going to create a new directory in our source folder and I'm going to call that folder
utils, and that is short for a utility.
So a utility function is just a helper function that helps us do something outside and component necessarily.
So right here I'll create a new JavaScript file and I'm going to call this file next element in list
dot.
JS.
This is going to be the name of our function as well, so I'll give that file the same name.
So in here, since I do want to follow a TDD approach, I don't want to write any explicit code.
The only thing I'm going to do right now is define the core structure of this function and then export
it.
So I'll use the console keyword.
I'll declare my next element in list function.
I'll make it an arrow function.
And for now, it's just going to accept no arguments and have an empty function body.
All right.
So just the base infrastructure for an arrow function and below I will export default.
This next element in list function.
All right.
The next thing I'd like to do is to start wiring up our test suite.
So in our tests directory, we have our unit folder.
And this is still going to be a unit test because it's targeting one small unit of the application.
But of course it's no longer a component.
So within my unit directory right here, I'd like to create a folder called Utils, mirroring the structure
that we have in our source directory.
And in my utils directory here, I'd like to create the next element in list dot test.
Gorgeous file.
All right.
Let me go ahead and move this test file to the right so we can see it side by side with my implementation.
And of course, we do not need our mount function because we're not actually dealing with any view components.
But we do need to import our original next element in list function.
So right here I'm going to import next element in list.
In fact, my code automatically did it for me, but it's going to come from our source directory, which
is the app sign, then the utils folder and then the file is called Next Element in list.
All right, so let's write a described function and we're going to test the next element in list function.
And I'm going to write a description here in an IT function call.
So what does this function do?
It locates element in list and returns the next element in list.
So I'm going to provide an arrow function as my second argument here, and then let's wire this up.
In fact, let me give us a little bit more real estate here as well on the right hand side.
Perfect.
So let's begin with a list of arbitrary values.
I'm going to give it a name of list and I'll just keep it simple.
I'll just have an array of five simple character strings.
So I'll do a, B, C, D, E, and let's say the current value that I'm on will be C.
So I'll define a consort called value and I'll give it a value of C, and of course, I expect my next
element in list function to be able to take this current array as well as take the current value and
return the next one in line.
So if my current value is C, I expect the return value to of course be D, right?
This is mirroring the exact same idea we have in our headline component.
So of course we can expect using a to the approach that we're going to feed the list to our function,
we're going to feed the value to our function, and we're going to get a return value back which are
assigned to a constant call result.
And then below we can say that we expect result to be a certain value and what do we expect it to be?
The next string in line of course is going to be D, so I'm going to add a D here, let prettier add
some logic and let's go ahead and test this.
So I'm going to bring up my terminal right here.
And let's go ahead and run just in watch mode.
So it's going to continue running as we make changes.
So NPM run, test watch and just should locate the change files.
And there it is running next element to list.
And of course, it's going to fail as it should.
And if we scroll up, we can see it expected a result of D, but it received undefined because a function
with no implementation or no explicit return value will return undefined by default.
All right.
So we know that this function is going to take two parameters and we can call them the exact same name.
We have four constants on the right hand side.
We're going to receive some kind of list and we're going to receive our current value.
So I'll say list value right here.
And then we can go ahead and head to our headline component and copy most of this logic to that file
and it's going to copy these lines and then we'll see if we need them.
So going back to next element and list, I'll copy these lines.
It's kind of getting hard.
Let me, in fact, reduce my ed size.
That might make it easier.
Okay, that's perfect.
Okay, so we first have this line of our list of actions.
We no longer need this because we are going to get that list of strings as our list argument.
So we do not need this line anymore.
Then we no longer have a list of actions, we just have a general list so I can change this actions
reference to my list argument and of course we are finding the index of the current value.
So it's no longer going to be this that action.
It's going to be whatever is the current value represented by my value argument.
Let me remove this comment.
All right.
And then, of course, we're going to have not next action and not next action index, but really next
value index and next value, because they're not specifically tied to actions on our headline, they're
just a value within an array.
All right.
So this is also going to be next value index.
There is one mistake that I have in my implementation currently, but we're going to leave it and we're
going to see how TDD helps us discover it later.
So here we are indexing into my actions list.
Of course, that actions list no longer exists.
We just have a regular list.
Okay, so index into our list at the next value index that's going to give us our next value.
And then of course, we need to return next value.
So let's save this and see where we are.
Our implementation is working just great, but it's always a good idea to test for edge cases.
And edge cases, of course, refer to situations that you're less likely to encounter but are still
potentially possible, right?
They exist on the edge of something.
So in this case, if we look at our array, we have most of the same kind of test, right?
A is going to go to B and B is going to go to see and C is going to go to D and writing duplicate tests
for that kind of logic is redundant and doesn't help us.
The one edge case, the one different scenario from the rest is what happens if we are on the last element
in the array.
So if we have a list and our value is E, we expect the next value to be A That is a different bit of
logic.
So I want to test that in a separate test.
So right here I'll add another describe and I'll set the context for this test.
So when element is at the end of the list, what do I want to test that it locates next element at start
of the list.
Perfect.
So I can keep a very similar test setup to what I have here.
I'm going to copy this below.
Of course, the difference here is instead of a value of C, I want to test for a value of E, and so
my results should no longer be D, it should be the first element in the array because I want to loop
back around to the beginning.
So this should be a and this is the beautiful part of t d is we're going to test for this edge case
and we're actually going to see a failure.
And that means that something is imperfect about our implementation.
So you can see here that we are expecting a value of a, but instead we're getting a value of B, so
we can take a look at what's going on here.
And one thing that is the actual source of the error is right now we are feeding in a list of five elements
in comparison in a headline, we were providing an array of four actions and our original implementation
was doing the modulo of four because it was always assuming that our list would have four elements.
Now our lists length could be dynamic because this function could in theory accept a array of any length.
So we to need to take the module, not a four, but of the list length.
And again, the reason we applied the modulo in the first place is to ensure these situations that we
do not have a index that is beyond the final index value of the array.
So we're going to take our current index, we're going to add one to it.
And then by taking the modulo of the array length, we ensure that we're always going to have an array
index position that is a valid index position and is the one we want, which is next in line.
So rather than taking the module four, I want to take the modulo of my arrays length.
My array is represented by my list argument and I can get an arrays length by accessing the length property.
So just very quickly, to reiterate, let's say we have a value of E here.
So in that case, E is going to be found at index position for in my list.
All right.
So index position for plus one gets us to index position five, which does not exist in this array.
However, index five Devorah modulo two by the list length is going to be five modulo five.
That leaves a remainder of zero because five goes evenly into five and that remainder of zero is going
to be the value of my next index, which is index zero, which is my a string.
So that works exactly as we'd like it to work.
So when I save this, we should see that our tests are now passing and we've captured that edge case
and ensured that our implementation is not directly connected to the explicit logic of our headline
component, where we have an array of four elements.
All right, so this is a good place to leave off.
In the very next lesson, we're going to go back to our headline component and reuse this next element.
Enlist logic in the component body.