Okay.
So we have a mystery on our hands.
The very last test for our job listings component is failing this one right here.
So let's try to debug it.
The very first thing I did is I focused exclusively on this test by changing this function from it to
fit.
And that, of course, just simply stands for focus on this test.
So what we're telling just here is whenever it runs this file only run this test right here.
Don't worry about running the other ones.
We don't want to run the other ones when we're debugging because that of course slows down the feedback
loop.
By focusing exclusively on this test, we can only have just rerun this one and then quickly test whether
our change or our solution fixes the problem.
So I'm going to save this and we're going to see the test rerun and it's still failing.
And another benefit of focusing exclusively on this test is we can eliminate the possibility of pollution.
So now it's a lot less likely that some other tests setup is affecting this test because why don't we
run it in isolation by itself?
It's still failing, right?
So something must be going wrong here.
So my first thought was let me try using console.log to look at a couple values right here that might
be relevant, such as next page or max page.
I began with the jobs property because of course, as a reminder, this next page computed property
is the one that determines whether this router link that we want to render does it's dependent on this
v if directive.
If the scenario is to a truth value, then this router link will render.
And that of course is what we're looking for in this data test strip.
So my first guess was VRF for some reason is evaluating to false and that's why this thing is not rendering
in our test.
Well, if we scroll down to this implementation, we'll see that the way that it can return false or
a false value is if this expression evaluates to false.
Because if this ternary expression evaluates the false, then we are returning undefined.
And that of course will cause the VRF to not render.
So I thought that something was going funky here in this implementation.
The very first thing I did is I console.log this the jobs that left because I was just curious what
that value was.
Even though we tried doing the Flush Promises solution, I was just wanted to make sure that we were
not, you know, going crazy here.
So here you can see we have two console.log values and they're what we expect when the component first
mounts, mounts as it's making that fake API request, it has zero jobs.
And then we can see here when the component receives those jobs from the promised resolution, the job's
property updates to 15.
And remember, that happens when we call flush promises right here.
So by the time we run this code on line 82 to look for next page link this that jobs should already
be an array with a length of 15 of those job objects.
So something is going wrong here.
All right.
But we do have the correct jobs.
We've correctly received them.
So, of course, my next thing, my next step was to look at the values of next page and max page.
So right here, I'm going to console.log next page and I'm going to output it with next page.
And then right below it, I'm going to console.log Max Page.
And I want to take a look at Max Page.
And in case there are multiple outputs, I always want to make sure I look at the last one because that
reflects what happens when I resolve the promise and get my jobs.
So here is where our bug is.
Take a look here for a second and see if you can figure it out.
So we are on page one, of course, and we're getting 15 total jobs, right?
So our next page is simply one more than our current page.
So one plus one is two?
That's correct.
Our next page is two.
Then we do the check here to check if the next page is permissible because it happens to be less than
or equal to the max page.
So if our next page is less than or equal to the next, the max page, which should be two in this case.
Right, because we have 15 jobs.
So there should be up to two pages because each page can have ten jobs.
Our max page should be two.
However, you'll notice here that our Max page is actually 1.5.
So what's going on here?
Well, this evaluation right here, JavaScript is performing floating point division.
So the length of the jobs array is 15 and 15 divided by ten is 1.5.
Right?
So this is where our mathematical logic is wrong because if we have 15 jobs, in fact, if we have 11
or 12 or 13 or 14 or 15 jobs, etc., our max page should not be 1.1 or 1.2.
It should actually be rounded up to two.
Right, because we can have as many as 20 jobs on two total pages.
So what's happening here is this floating point division is not rounding up to the next integer to the
next whole number, to the actual max page of two.
And thus when JavaScript is evaluating, it's saying, well, two is not less than or equal to 1.5,
it is greater than.
So this is a value adding to false, which of course returns the undefined, which makes Vaf evaluate
a false and not render the router link.
So the data test attribute is never present, which means our test does not find it, and thus our test
fails.
So what we need to do in JavaScript terms is we need to take this floating point number and we need
to round it up to the next hole number, the next integer.
The reason we missed this earlier is just a matter of coincidence, because in the real world our jobs
are array from our fake back end was returning 100 jobs and 100 is perfectly divisible by ten, so there
was nothing left over.
This is a situation.
We have some jobs left over.
We have 15, so only five can fit on the second page.
But that doesn't mean that the max page is 1.5.
The max page is still two.
So in JavaScript, the way that we can round a floating point number up to the next integer is by using
the seal or ceiling method on the math object.
So right here on the math object, capital M there is a method called seal and you could see it returns
the smallest integer greater than or equal to the numeric argument.
So if we give it 1.1, we give it 1.2, we give it 1.51, 1.6.
It's going to rounded up to the next whole number in this case, two, and that's going to solve our
exact problem for us.
So I save this Max Page is going to properly evaluate it to the next page is now going to be two.
Two is still equal to two.
So this evaluates to true we return the next page.
That is a truth value that makes the f value to true.
Render this root or link with the data test attribute.
Our test is able to find it and thus this exists now evaluates the true and we can see this is all passing.
So if I remove my focus and try to run everything all at once, there we go.
Everything in our job listings component is passing and this is a great example of how tests can really
help you capture something that the real world may not always make a parent.
Right?
We just happen to have 100 jobs being returned.
So we missed this detail of what happens when we have a couple jobs that we can render on a given page.
But we were able to identify this issue by having a lot of diverse, different tests that test for different
things.
All right.
So super happy with this bug.
This is a really fun bug to debug and I will see you in the next lesson.