All right.
So let's go ahead and write some tests for our new action button component.
So right here in my Tests Unit Components folder, I'm going to create a new file and I'm going to call
it action button.
Test that.
Yes, I'm going to follow the same protocol as we followed, which is just going to be the component
name, followed by tasks.
All right.
And I'm going to open it side by side so we can keep an eye on our original file as we write our code.
All right, so let's review everything that we learned about testing.
The first thing we need to do is to import our mount function from the view test utils library.
That's going to allow us to mount or instantiate or bring up our components outside of the browser environment.
So right here I'm going to import a named export called Mount and that comes from the app view slash
test dash utils library.
Okay.
That brings us to Mount Function.
We also need to import our actual components.
So I'm going to import action button.
That's going to be the default export.
So I do not need to wrap it in curly braces.
And then we can specify its location in our project.
We know our very top level is represented by ACT the assignment.
And when I talk about top level, I'm talking about my source directory where my code for The View project
lives.
So within the source directory we can see it right here.
We need to navigate into components and then import action button that we use.
I'm going to import that.
I'm going to import action button.
And there we go.
All right.
So let's create a describe block or a describe function that's coming from just I'm going to describe
my action button and provide a second argument of an arrow function.
And in here, I'm just going to write my first test.
What's the first responsibility of this button?
Well, I think it's supposed to render some bit of text, so I'm going to write that literally as a
text or as a test description.
Text and test are very similar words, so I'm going to put my IT keyword in here, my hit function.
And my first argument is a descriptive string.
It renders text.
All right.
So I'm going to provide my arrow function and I'm going to declare a contact called Wrapper and I'm
going to mount my action button.
That's a prerequisite for just about every test we're ever going to write with you.
Now, we have props in the real world that we feed into action button and they are text and type.
So how can we simulate the passing of those props in a test given that we don't have a literal parent
component that is rendering action button?
Well, once again, we can turn to our second argument to the mount function, which is a configuration
object.
So I'm going to pass in that argument right here.
All right.
And right here, I'm going to provide a key of props.
That's the key we want to use here, as well as a value of an object.
And in the object, we can write to the actual props that we want to provide.
So let me provide a text prop, and I'm going to give it the value of I'm so clickable.
So again, the value here of I'm so clickable is up to us.
The actual prop name must be text because that's what we defined right here.
And for my type prop, I'm going to define it as primary.
And say of this.
So I just want to take a quick moment here to talk about why I think this is okay.
Earlier, we talked about the idea of trying to avoid things like the data method in our configuration
object in a test.
And that's because we're reaching into the implementation details of a component.
In this case, I think it's okay because this is how our action is designed to work in the real world.
A parent component will pass in these two pieces of information and the action, but needs them in order
to work.
An earlier analogy I made is that props for almost two components what inputs are two functions?
They're like arguments that we give.
So if action button is a function, it needs these two arguments.
It needs these two props in order to operate.
So this is not going so deep into the action by the implementation.
This is providing this component what it needs in order to operate even before we build the action button
component.
If we were to follow a TDD style, we might assume normally it would be a fair assumption to make that
if we're going to have a generic button, that we're going to need some kind of text to give it in order
to render.
Now we may choose a different name for our prop.
If we were using TDD, we might have chosen like button text or inner text or whatever.
That's totally fine.
In this case, we are hardcoded to our eventual implementation and our actual prop names that we chose.
But this to me is not an offensive violation.
This is how the component is supposed to work.
So I'm totally okay with that here.
Okay.
So what do I want to fundamentally test?
Well, I want to test that.
My text of I'm so clickable, which I give to the button is somewhere in the output of the button.
So what I can do here is use the familiar text method on my wrapper.
This is going to give me all of the text that is rendered anywhere within the body of my action button
component.
And I want to use that to match matcher, which is just going to check whether the wrappers, text or
the action button's text contains whatever it is that I pass in here as an argument, whether it contains
this substring of text.
And I want to check again that somewhere in my action button's text there should be the text and so
clickable.
So whatever value you provide here, make sure you write it in here as well.
It doesn't matter if it's I'm so clickable or anything else.
As long as the two of them match, let me go ahead and bring up my terminal and we'll see if we can
run this test.
I'm going to run it using the test runner that continues to watch for changes in my code.
And that's going to be NPM, run, test, call and watch.
We set up this script in our package that JSON.
So let's go ahead and run that and run just and watch mode and it passes, which is great.
And just to show you how it fails to make sure that our test is actually not returning a false positive,
we can do something like this, we can return something different like I'm so clickable.
See if that fails as we expect it to.
And there we go.
We can see that we expected the substring of I'm so clickable, but all the text that exists within
an action button is I'm so clickable.
So that's perfect.
All right.
Okay.
So that sounds good to me.
Let's go ahead and write our second test.
The only other test that I want to write here is making sure that we're applying the right CSS class.
I'm going to write my description here.
What is the action button do?
It applies one of several styles to button, and maybe that's being a little bit too detailed because
I am mentioning two button.
Maybe I can just say it applies one of several styles, but I think this is okay for now.
So once again, I'm going to go ahead and mount my action button and here I'm going to do something
a little bit differently this time around, but that's only to show you an educational experience moving
forward.
The reason I am going to do this is because I'm going to assume it might be an issue that you run into
some day in your own views.
And that's this let's say that I obviously care about the props existing and I care about the type existing
because a type of primary is going to determine the styles that I'm going to apply to the button.
So because it is the focus of my test, it's reasonable for me to expect that I'm going to remember
to provide a type prop set to primary, and that's going to affect what I'm testing for.
However, it's reasonable as well to expect as a developer that I'm totally going to forget about the
text prop that this component expects.
And that's because for the purposes of this test, what I'm testing about is styles and sizes.
I may totally forget about the text prop and the fact that the button renders it.
All right.
So we're going to come back to how view is going to alert us that we're missing the text prop in just
a second.
So what I want to do here is I want to look for a button within my template.
And this is a little bit of a violation from earlier because I mentioned it's a good idea to use data
test in order to test for non explicit HTML elements just to be a little bit more resilient towards
change.
In this case, it's a very simple component, very small with a single h html no button.
It's literally called action button.
I know it's not perfect, but in this scenario I'm going to be okay just using the find the method on
my wrapper to look for a literal h html element.
If you want to do this with the data test attribute, feel free to do that.
That's probably the better way to do it.
But for now I'll forgive myself.
So I'll create a contact called Button on my wrapper.
I'm going to have a find method.
I can use it to find HTML elements or CSS classes or whatever I want.
I'm going to search for the first occurrence of an HTML button element.
Right?
That's going to give me a separate view test utils wrapper around the first HTML button that Vue test
utils finds.
And on that object.
We're going to have a method called classes.
All right.
So to that class method, I'm going to provide a string of a class that I expect to find.
So given that I'm passing in a prop with a type of primary, I'm going to expect there to be a primary
class on this button.
Okay.
And then this I expect to evaluate to.
True.
It's going to value to true.
If the primary class exists among the buttons classes and it's going to add value to false if the primary
class does not exist among the buttons classes.
So here, because I passed in a type of primary, I'm going to write to be true the to be matter checks
for strict equality.
It's totally okay to use it with our booleans.
So I'm going to say that somewhere in the first button that you find in the action button component,
it's going to be the only button, in fact, because it's the only one we have here.
Find that button view test utils.
Check the kind of seasons classes that it has applied to it and make sure that primaries in that list
of classes are all right.
And I'm just going to mandate that that's true.
All right.
So this is going to pass as well.
We know that we are applying a primary.
Yes.
This class I can just vary this test up.
I can even do something like change this to false.
And we're going to see the test says you expected it to not be found, but I have found it, which is
great.
The test is working as expected.
Alternatively, if I have something like something like a typo here and I pass in a type of primaries,
then we expect to see us class of primaries.
But that's not going to work because we're only going to have we're checking actually for a primary
class when now the component is going to have a primary class.
Right.
So everything is working as expected.
I've just ran a few failing tests to make sure my code is properly reacting to these changes.
I'm going to switch this back.
And there we go.
And that's really all there is to cover in this lesson.
We wrote some basic tests for action button.
Notice at this point that the output is not complaining about the missing text prop.
We're going to fix that and now test up ahead and I'll show you how to do that in the next couple lessons.
But for now, this is a good place to start.
The only other quick discussion that we may have is should we test the action button with a different
value for the type prop?
Like should we write a separate test with type set to secondary?
And I would argue that there's really no benefit because there's no different code or different logic
that we're running through.
It's always going to evaluate to this line right here.
So we're really just testing the same thing.
Whatever type we passed in as the seasons class that we want to apply in the real world, obviously
there will be multiple types of type.
There will be primary, secondary and whatever other values that we can pass in.
But as it stands right now, we're testing that view is running through this logic and doing the right
thing as far as CSS class application.
So I don't think there's any advantage to writing a separate test for another value of type.
I that's really all there is to cover here.
So I will see you in the next lesson.