All right.
So the changes that we added in the previous lesson will get our existing test for our job filter sidebar
to fail.
So in this lesson, I want to fix this failing test and I also want to add a new one for the functionality
that we just added.
So the reason that our existing test in this file job filter sidebar, that test that's the reason why
it's going to fail is because we now introduced the idea of use, root and use store.
And even though the wrapped up in this function, this function will run because we are passing it to
our on mounted lifecycle hook.
So this logic will run as view test utils as mounting a component.
But of course we don't have a real store and we don't have a real route.
And so this logic is being broken, right?
There is no browser.
So what we need to do here is simply import those functions, mock them out, and have them return suitable
objects to play the role of a root and a store.
The same story we've told throughout the course.
So right here we're already marking out view X from an earlier example.
So right here, I'm going to import you store.
Just to be more specific and allow myself to mock it out specifically later.
So the use store is going to come from view X, then I'm going to mock our view X and then I'm also
going to declare you store mock, which is going to be used store as a type of just mock.
Then in order for coverage of my use root function right here, I'm also going to need to import use
route that is going to come from view router.
Same logic right here.
I'm going to mock out the entire view router library and then I'm going to tell TypeScript that there
is going to be a concept called user out mock, which is our existing just mock function represented
by user out, but with TypeScript explicitly knowing that its type is just mock.
All right.
So first up, let's get this existing test to pass.
All I'm going to do is basically provide mock return values for use store news route that are good enough
to fulfill this contract.
Because all this test is testing for is that the component can be rendered normally.
So right here, let's begin with use store mock and I'm going to invoke mock return value.
And all we really need for this object is for it to have a commit method.
So that line 63 works.
So right here, I'm going to provide a commit method and that can just be a basic just function.
That's a perfect little way to take care of that responsibility.
Now, as far as our route object, we can mock out as well.
So user out mock dot mock return value providing an object.
And remember that we don't actually need to have a real property that's optional, but we do need to
have a query property that's always going to exist and we do need to be able to access it in order to
be able to potentially reference a row property.
So we can almost test this side of the logic in this test.
So what I'm going to do here is just provide a query object set to an empty object that's going to allow
role to evaluate undefined and fall back to an empty string.
And then in the second test that I add in just a moment, we can actually double check that the extraction
is actually working logically and correctly by providing a valid real property.
So you can see that this is enough to get my former test to pass and now we can write our new one.
So right here I'm going to say it reads query params to filter initial jobs for user pass and an arrow
function right here.
All right.
And it's going to be very similar to what I have above.
So I think what I'm going to do is just copy.
My first three lines right here.
We're going to modify them slightly.
We do want to make sure that we are committing the right arguments.
So what I'm going to do is make sure that this reference is available as a constant above.
So content commit is going to be a just mock function and I'm going to use S six referencing here to
just reference my constant above.
For my query object, I will provide a row property and just to celebrate, of course, let's make our
role view because the user is of course always interested in finding view jobs.
Then I'm going to show them out my component.
And what I expect to have happen is this function will run on mount.
So I expect that my commit method should have been called.
So I'm going to say that just mock function should have been called with arguments.
The first argument is going to be update skills search term, which is my mutation, right?
That's this logic right here.
And the second value of role, of course, is going to come from my query object in the row property.
So because that is set to view right here and the second argument for the search term should be view.
It's a save that.
And that should get the entire test to pass.
Give it a few seconds to run.
And there we go.
In fact, this code is giving me a little bit of a warning here that I'm not using wrapper, which makes
sense because we don't actually need to reference rapper later.
So I think we'll get away with just doing a regular shallow now.
So let's remove that just to be a little bit cleaner.
And that's kind of a better communicator that we don't really care about the return value.
We just want a shallow amount, the component to force the mutation to run from the on mounted life
cycle hook.
All right, so everything is passing, and I feel much better about this component.
All right.
So let's wrap this section up in the very next lesson.