Okay.
So I have a good feeling that this is going to be the last one where it all comes together.
We're going to be able to filter the jobs on the right hand side of the screen as the user selects a
checkbox.
So on the right hand side here, I have my view store file in index stacks, and on the left hand side
I've opened up my job listings component.
It's been a little while since we've been in here, so let me just do a quick recap right here on line
number five, we are using the V four directive to iterate over something called display jobs and to
render a job listing component for each job.
A job listing component is just that card that we display on the on the page that has the title, the
location, the bullet points, etc..
So what is display jobs?
Well, if I scroll down to my script section.
We'll see that display.
Jobs is a computed property.
And what it's doing is it's selecting the first ten jobs from this jobs right here.
Now, where is this that jobs coming from?
That property is coming from maps state as a reminder map state as a helper function from view X that
connects our view X store state properties directly to component computed properties.
So this job string right here allows us to have access to this jobs array right here on the right hand
side, we take this array of 100 jobs and we make it available as this dot jobs in our job listings
component.
So for example, if we have 100 jobs here, we get that array via this type jobs, then we use the slice
method on that array of 100 jobs to get the first ten.
So now our situation is a little bit different because we still want to show ten jobs per page.
However, we only want to show ten jobs from the original batch of filtered jobs, right?
We want the jobs that matched the organization that the user has filtered by.
So just to give you a hypothetical example, let's say we have 100 original jobs.
Then when the user selects an organization, let's say 40 of the original 100 fit the criteria.
We're going to get those 40 jobs in this component eventually and we still want to get the first ten
of that batch.
So we still need to keep this logic somehow, but we're no longer going to be able to rely on this type
jobs because we're going to replace this with our filter jobs rather than our original array of 100
jobs.
The same principle applies in this computed property right here.
Here we're using the the length of the jobs rate to calculate the next page.
We need this because we need to figure out if there is a next page based on there being any more jobs
left to show.
We still have the exact same logic.
We want the user to be able to navigate back and forth between pages, but now we don't care about the
length of the original jobs array.
We want the length of our filtered jobs array because that is what's going to determine how many pages
there are that we want to show.
So let's start refactoring this component and moving it in a direction where we are relying on our filter
jobs instead of our original jobs.
So I'm going to begin by commenting out this line of Map State.
It's just going to be a reminder that we eventually want to remove this.
And when I scroll up here, I'm going to remove Map State because we're no longer using it.
So instead of using Map State to connect a piece of components state to a view store property, in this
case jobs.
I want to use my getter, my filter jobs by organization getter, because this getter is going to give
me this smaller array of jobs that I want to display.
I no longer want to show this array of jobs.
I want to show this array of jobs.
It's still an array of job objects at the end of the day, because we're calling filter right here on
state jobs.
But it's a smaller subset.
It's a smaller collection.
It's an array that's going to have a smaller number of jobs because when the user filters, they're
going to select a smaller collection of the original larger collection.
So I know I'm going to need to use this getter.
And the easiest way to connect a view X getter method to a component method is by using the map getters
helper function.
So right here I'm going to import map getters.
And then I want to import the constant with the getter that I want to connect to this component.
So that's going to be this getter right here.
Filter jobs by organizations.
So right here where I'm importing fetch jobs from my store index, just file.
I also want to import my filter jobs by organizations constant.
And as a reminder, we can still keep fetch jobs because fetch jobs is simply the action we're calling
right here to do the original API request to get that batch of 100.
So we're still going to keep map actions and we're still going to keep fetch jobs.
That's just for the original API request.
All right.
So now we need to use this getter in my component.
So the easiest way to establish this getter as a component method is by using map getters.
So right here, I'm going to restructure the properties or alternatively destructor the methods that
are on the object that map getters returns to me.
So I'm going to invoke map getters and then I'm going to provide map getters with an array of the getters
that I want to make available on this component as computed properties or computed methods.
So of course, the getter that I care about here is called filter jobs by organizations.
So simply by using map getters, what I've done here is now this component has a this that filter jobs
by organization's computed property or method, however you want to call it.
And that is going to be this return dye right here, this filtered array of jobs.
All right.
So now I want to use this throughout my other computed properties that we're formally relying on this
to jobs.
So, for example, in next page, this computed property, I was referencing this the jobs which I got
from Maps State.
I no longer have this state jobs available because we committed our maps state.
However, because I used map getters above online 50, I now do have this dot filter jobs by organization.
Right.
And it is a computed property, so we can simply reference it as a regular property.
It's technically a method that's going to run behind the scenes, but we do not need to provide the
parentheses.
So we filter jobs by organizations.
Array is what we're going to get here and then we're going to take it's land and divided by ten, and
that's going to calculate the max the max page that we can show similarly right here displayed jobs.
We want to slice the first ten jobs from a given array.
But what is that given array?
It's no longer our original jobs array that we got from View X.
It's now our filtered jobs rate that we're going to get from our getter.
Which getter?
The one that we have available now under this keyword called filter jobs by organization, the exact
same one that we enabled right here.
So just to reiterate, if we did not have line 50, if we did not use map getters, we would not be
able to write line 62 or line 69.
We need to make that getter available.
And the easiest way to do that is to use map getters and this structure, that method that you X will
give to us.
And of course what that method is going to do behind the scenes is automatically run the getter for
us and pass it to View Store State.
All right.
So with that, we are good to remove maps.
They were no longer using it and we don't actually need to alter anything within our template because
display jobs, which is what we're using v4 to iterate over that property is still the same name.
So right here we're still iterating over displayed jobs the computed property.
However, how displayed jobs arrives as at its array is different and that's what we've altered.
So right here, instead of relying on jobs, we're now referring to filter jobs by organizations.
So our template doesn't need to change because our template was simply iterating over whatever array
we gave it.
Now we're just giving it a smaller array that we're getting from a getter instead of from the original
view text store jobs state.
And with that, we have made a significant amount of progress.
So let me take you to the browser and show you how this is going to work.
And we are going to actually run into a bug.
Let me refresh this page.
We are going to run into a bug.
And the bug right now is that we do not actually see anything on the page.
Okay.
We're going to talk about why this bug exists in the very next lesson.
However, let me show you something else that's interesting.
If I expand my organization section right here and I select an organization like YouTube, lo and behold,
all of a sudden we get what we want.
Take a look at these jobs right here.
View tube.
View tube, view tube.
Keep scrolling down.
You can see we're getting all the YouTube jobs and then we have our next page.
If I go to page two, scroll all the way to the top.
Once again, we get YouTube of YouTube, YouTube, etc..
If I select another organization here like Point of View, once again, if I scroll down, we can see
that every job belongs to one of those two organizations.
So here's YouTube.
Here's point of view.
Here's YouTube, YouTube, YouTube.
Let's see if I can find another point of view.
Here it is.
So we are seemingly correctly filtering.
And similarly, if I scroll back up and I eliminate an organization like YouTube.
Well, now we only see the point of view jobs instantaneously.
All right.
So it looks like our code is working.
We're going to talk more about the error and or the bug in the next lesson.
But I just want to take a quick second to walk through the flow of how everything is working.
So the page loads right.
And the component makes a request to get the 100 jobs.
It stores them locally in the store state.
Right.
Then what happens is we as a user select a sample organization.
We use V model to store that information.
I believe our component was the job filter, a sidebar organization's component.
We store that information locally and then we also ship that data up to the U.S..
We run our mutation.
We give it that new array, in this case, an array of one string, and we save it to our view store.
So whenever the View Store state changes, whenever we run this add selected organizations mutation
and we get this store to update to have a new state for these selected organizations property.
Our getter is keeping track of that.
And because our getter is reliant on jobs and selected organizations, as soon as any one of those changes,
it knows to be reactive and it knows to rerun.
So the getter says, Hey, you changed the selected organization's rate.
I'm going to rerun this, gather this getter reruns.
And at that point of view access, which component is relying on my getter?
And that is our job listings component.
So because our job listings component is connected to this getter, using the map getters function whenever
the filter jobs by organizations getter array changes.
This component knows to render.
So it says, okay, I started out with 100 jobs.
The user then filtered.
I now have, let's say, 40 filter jobs.
That logic has changed.
So now I need to rerun this logic, which of course changes the array that displayed jobs returns.
Because displayed jobs shows the first ten of the filter jobs by organizations array, which itself
is a getter array that has changed and thus the component changes this it renders and now what we iterate
over in display jobs is the new batch of ten that is its own subset of ten from the subset of filtered
organizations.
That is a subset of our original view store state in the jobs property.
All right.
So it's a really complex sequence of events that happens, but hopefully it makes logical sense.
There's a lot of steps, but hopefully the logic makes sense that the View Store updates it communicates
those changes to any component that cares about it.
The component renders and now our getter is influencing what we are seeing on the screen.
Right.
So our implementation is very, very, very close to working.
And the very next lesson, we're going to talk about why we saw that bug of not seeing any jobs when
the page first loaded.