Okay.
So I have opened up our Gators file and as a reminder, we still have our two old getters filter jobs
by organizations and filter jobs by job types.
And we have captured all of this logic in our new getters down below, both our inclusion getters and
the final filter jobs getter.
So we are almost at the point where we can remove these two getters from this getters file.
However, we need to still look through the code base to see if there's anywhere else where we are using
them.
So I'm going to bring up my VS Code search with command shift F and I'm going to look for filtered jobs
by just to get that kind of prefix at the very beginning.
And we'll notice there's one location where we're still using it and it's in the sub nav component.
So if I open up my sub nav component as a reminder here, this is the sub nav that appears below the
main nav.
The main menu we are still using are filter jobs by organizations getter and obviously we do not want
this one.
We now want our filter jobs getter because that is going to reflect the most accurate number of filter
jobs after we apply both the organizations filter and the job types filter.
So let's open up the corresponding sub nav test file in sub nav.
That test that J.S. Let me bring up my terminal and let me quickly start running NPM run, test, colon
watch.
And there shouldn't be anything failing right now.
But you'll notice in our test we are still using the old filter jobs by organizations getter right here.
So I'm going to follow a TDD approach.
I'm going to fix the tests first.
So right here I'm going to provide this getter right here a filter jobs replacing it in my first test
and down below.
It doesn't look like we're doing anything here, so that's just fine.
That's just going to lead to a test failure.
But that's exactly what we expect because our test is providing a gara filter jobs while our component
is still relying on the getter a filter jobs by organizations.
So obviously when we're mounting this component in our test suite, view says, hey, I don't know what
this is.
The scatter right here that you're registering doesn't exist from the monster you've given me, so it's
causing a failure.
So everything is predictable and we can edit our implementation to make the tests pass.
So obviously right here, instead of importing our former getter, we want to import the name for our
new getter and that is going to be filtered jobs.
So import filter jobs from our constants file right here to the map getters function.
I'm going to provide that constant name that is going to give us that getter as a computed property
on this component.
And finally, we're using it above right here.
We are taking the length of that array because that becomes the number that we're displaying in the
sub.
Now, I'm going to change this to filter jobs as well, which we now have available as a computed property
on our component thanks to map getters.
Save this.
Let's let the tests rerun.
Gave it just a second here.
All right.
So everything is passing as far as our tests.
And if I head back to the browser, let's try it out.
So I'm going to expand job types, expand organizations.
I'm going to reveal my sub nav by signing in as a user.
Here we have 100 jobs matched.
And as I select a job type, the right hand side filters.
And this number up here, updates as well as I select only the view to jobs, the jobs to the right
filter and the number up here updates as well.
And keep an eye on that number as I select some sample organizations and job types.
And then as I remove them, once again, that number will continue to update with every single.
Selection that I make.
All right.
So our implementation is working, our tests are passing.
We are in a really good shape right now.
And then the very next last thing, we can go ahead and finally remove those original two getters.