Okay.
So let's fix all of our type violations in the GETTERS Test Suite.
And of course to make that process super easy, we're going to reuse our factory functions that we've
extracted to the Utils file in the previous lesson.
So right here in getters that test starts.
I'll begin by importing create job as well as create state.
And that's going to come from the utils file in the same directory.
So I'm going to do a relative import.
I'm going to use a dot slash and in the current directory I'm going to find the utils file.
All right, so let's navigate through everything we have here and adjust the arguments appropriately.
So here we're going to have not one, but two violations.
Number one, our state is missing some of the required properties because we need the other three.
But in addition, these job objects don't fulfill the job interface.
So all we can do is use create job to create some sample jobs that fulfill that job requirement and
then also use create state to populate all of the additional properties that our state needs.
So what I'm going to do here is start by extracting all this logic out and by all of this, I mean the
jobs logic.
Let me move that out here.
So I'm going to put this here and assign this to a constant jobs variable right here.
And now I have an array of my example fictional job objects, but I need real job objects.
So what I'm going to do is in line here.
I'm going to invoke, create job.
But what I'm going to do is also keep the original objects I had, because I do want to clarify for
the purposes of this test that the organization, property and its value matters because that's what's
going to affect the result I see down here.
So once again, we're going to use create job here to get an object just like this one.
But the only property we're going to overwrite is organization.
And then the entire test can be understood from here without necessarily needing to to go into this
file and understand everything else that a job has.
So right here, I'm going to wrap this object in a create job function call that's going to pass that
config object in right here.
I'm going to create another job using create job passing in this custom config object.
So now I have three jobs, then I'm going to need a state object.
So what I'm going to do to create a state object is invoke my create state factory function.
And of course, the only property that I want to customize here is going to be jobs.
So I'm going to provide jobs and I'm going to use E-6 syntax to reference the jobs array that I have
on the above.
So what I'm going to get is a state object with four properties.
One of them is going to be jobs and the other three properties are going to come from my state function
right here, which provides the initial starting state.
And then I'm going to to structure those additional properties here as well.
So now we're going to be able to feed in the state exactly as the unique organization's getter method
expects it.
And this should be good enough.
We're going to apply the exact same logic to our test below.
It's right here.
We need a view store state that honors the global state interface, and we also need job objects that
honor the job interface.
So once again, I'm going to move this logic out.
It's right here.
I'm going to sign this.
The cons, the jobs and an array of objects with a single property of job type is not enough because
those do not fulfill the job interface.
A job needs all of these other properties as well.
So what I'm going to do is pass these configuration objects into create job.
That's going to give me a full job object.
However, I'm going to specify that these jobs are going to have these respective job types full time,
part time and full time, which is going to communicate to a future reader that these values matter,
that these properties affect the final result, the final return value, which is the set of those job
types.
All right.
So right here State, I need to make sure I have a valid state object.
So I'm going to call create state.
And I do want to overwrite that valid state objects, jobs, property.
So I'm going to overwrite that jobs property with the jobs array of valid jobs I've defined right here.
Pass that in and that should do it.
All right.
Moving on to the next one, these should be a little bit simpler because these only rely on state.
So once again, we have kind of a small subset of state.
Our state does have a selected organization's property, but it also has three other properties.
Well, I can create those three properties automatically by wrapping this in a create state function
call that's coming from our util file on the right.
So now create state will give me an object with those properties and I'm going to only overwrite selected
organization.
There we go.
Same thing applies for job.
In order to make this a valid job, I'm going to pass this into Create Job.
And now you can see there's no more violations because TypeScript understands that we have satisfied
that state is going to be global state and job is going to be a valid job.
All right.
Same rule down here for my state right here, I'm going to use create state.
So wrap this in a create state function call right here.
I'm going to wrap the next line in a create job function call.
There we go.
That's going to make that error go away.
Scroll down.
Going to be something very similar down here.
Once again, create state.
Once again this is going to be create job to get a job object.
Same rules down here create state.
We're now going to have a valid state that honors the global state interface right here by using Create
Job.
We're going to have a job object that honors the job interface, making them suitable arguments to this.
Get it right here.
And finally, we get to filter jobs.
It looks.
Let's look at the violations here.
It looks like state right here does not fulfill what's expected of it.
So we're going to have to do something very similar to what we did above.
So here we have our sample job object.
I'm going to wrap this in Create Job.
That should solve that problem.
In fact, the idea here I don't really think is that important.
I'm just going to provide a title here.
I don't really know at all if these properties are relevant.
But for now, there's no harm to including them anyway.
So let's say we have a job with the title property right here.
We're going to need a real estate, so I'm going to invoke create state.
And for my jobs array, I need a valid job object, which I'm going to have with job right here.
And so that is going to fulfill that requirement.
The additional three properties are going to be provided by my factory function.
It will add them on.
And so we can see all of our typescript violations are now gone so that I can bring open my terminal.
And let's run our entire test suite because it's been a while since we checked in on the whole thing.
So that should cover our getters test file, which is now in TypeScript.
It should also recover our mutations test file, which is now using the utils that we provided.
So because those changes affect a lot of different files, it's a good idea to run the entire test suite
and we're going to give it a couple of seconds.
And it looks like everything is looking good.
There's mutations that test, that test, and there's getters that test, that test.
And we can see everything is passing just fine.
We do have a little bit of code coverage issues, which means we're not covering everything in our utils,
but for now, that's fine.
Our core tests right here are actual assertions are passing as expected.
All right.
So phenomenal, fantastic progress and lots more fun to come up ahead.
So I will see you in the next lesson.