All right.
So this is going to be a fun lesson.
We're going to delete a whole bunch of code.
So here I am in my Getters Digest file and the old two getters that we were previously using to individually
filter either for selected organizations or for selected job types, are now no longer relevant.
So this getter right here filter jobs by organizations.
We're no longer using it anywhere in our code base and any of our components because we have replaced
this logic with this filter jobs getter down below, which itself is reliant on these two getters up
above.
The same thing applies to this filter jobs by job types getter.
We are no longer using it, so we are good to completely delete and remove these two getters from our
code base.
All right.
So let's begin this process in order that the very top of the file.
I'm going to delete the two constant imports.
So our names from the constants file.
So let's delete filter jobs by organizations and filter jobs by job types.
Delete those two lines.
That's going to highlight the exact to get our method methods that we want to delete.
So right here, I'm going to delete filter jobs by organizations like that.
And right here, I'm going to delete filter jobs by job types.
Let's go ahead and delete that.
Save that.
Maybe remove some of these line breaks and in case prettier does not save that.
All right.
Let's move on now to our constants.
Just file right here in constants just so we can remove the previous constants which are no longer being
used in the code base.
So right here, filter jobs by organizations, remove that constant right here, filter jobs by job
types, remove that.
All right.
And if I look in my code base for filter jobs by.
We can see the only place where we still have a reference to those former getters is in the test suite.
So you guessed it, we can go ahead and remove the tests for those former getters as well because they're
no longer part of our code base.
So right here, let's go to our getters that test, that just file right here this entire described
block for filtered jobs by organizations.
Scroll all the way down to here and press the delete key.
And there we go.
And as I scroll down here, here's one more test file or test specifically for filter jobs by job types.
This big described block that has a whole bunch of tests in it.
Delete that entire describe block here we go delete that save the file so prettier does its formatting
and now we have the tests for only the relevant getters.
We can see the results here on the left hand side have reduced to zero.
So there's no more reference to this former getter in our code base.
And if I go back to getters, just to show you, take a look at how elegant this Getters file is.
We have a bunch of really small getter methods.
They're each basically a couple of lines long and they work pretty well, pretty elegantly, pretty
simple to read, especially if a method is only three lines.
Another engineer can pretty easily read it and understand it.
And we have most or all of these getters fully tested.
So if an engineer wants to understand how they're meant to be used and how they work with The View XT
or state, we have a perfect test suite to show those developers, so perfect example of these getters.
Nice lightweight methods that talk to the View Store State and derive some kind of data from it.
So just to play it safe, let me once again run my entire test suite right here, NPM run test, colon
unit and hopefully everything should still pass.
But as always, it never hurts to find out.
So let me run everything.
Give it a second.
There goes running pretty quickly.
So the good news is all 20 of our test suites, that means our test files are passing and all 61 tests
within them are passing as well.
So everything is looking great.
But you might have noticed we have a little bit of code coverage missing.
So right here, it's telling us for the getters just file, we're missing a test that is covering lines
29 through 31.
So if I scroll down here, you'll notice that lines 29 through 31 are the filter jobs getter.
This one right here.
So we have written two tests for the two inclusion getters right here.
But we have not actually written any test for our filter jobs getter.
That is the last thing we need to add a test for in order to make our code coverage perfect at 100%.
So we're going to take care of the test for this getter in the very next lesson.