Okay.
So the next file that I want to target is going to be our actions file.
So right here I have actions, J.S. and this is available in the source store directory.
And as always, let's convert this file to TypeScript.
So I'm going to change its extension from J.S. to T.S. and as we'll see, this will cause just one single
violation.
And it is that TypeScript does not understand what context is.
You can see here parameter context implicitly has an any type.
So we have to be a little bit more specific.
So all we really need context to be is an object with a commit method.
And we need to make sure that that commit method has the right type definition for these two arguments
right here.
Now, in reality, the context object is a little bit more complex than that.
It actually has a lot more properties and methods on it.
But I would argue for the purpose of this method, all it really cares about is having the commit method
be properly defined.
And the smaller that you can keep your interfaces out, rather than committing to very large interfaces
that demand a lot, generally the smaller interfaces that you commit to, the more flexible and adaptable
your code will be.
So what I'm going to do is actually import an interface that's available from the View Library.
So the View Library, The View Library, The View or library, all of the dependencies that we've added
will have their own interfaces defined within them just for our use in TypeScript.
So previously we've defined all of our interfaces ourselves within our project.
But there's also other ones that we can simply reuse, and there's no need to type them from scratch.
So right here at the very top, I'm going to import an interface and it's called Commit and it's going
to come from the View Library.
Now, if you want to see what this interface looks like, what you can do is hold your command key and
then click on to commit.
And on a Windows computer, this may be the control key, but once you click into this, it'll actually
take you to the what's called the definition file.
And this is actually going to be within our view repository, repository or view Xcode based within
our Node modules directory.
So you can see right here we are going straight to the definition of the interface for commit.
So this is not code that we have written.
This is code from the Official View Library that we downloaded from NPM.
And this is the interface that defines the COMMIT method and defines its parameters and return value.
So for example, the first argument to commit is the mutation you want to run.
Here is the definition.
That parameter is called type and it expects a type of string, right?
So the parameter is called type and this type is string.
A little bit confusing, but there you go.
So basically, this is the exact same typescript code that we've been used to writing.
However, somebody else has written it for us.
Now down below, you'll see there is an interface specifically for the context object.
So this is something we could import if we really wanted to use it to define the context parameter that
we have in our actions file.
But I argue this interface is a little too big and bloated for the simple implementation we have now.
So instead of using this one, which itself uses the commit property, I'm going to define my own smaller
interface that also has a commit property or a commit method, but I'm still going to use the commit
interface from the view X type definition file.
So let me show you how that's going to work.
Instead of using this context right here.
Instead, in my actions test file, I'll define my own interface called context.
And the only thing my context object is going to need for my fetch jobs action to work is to have a
commit method right here.
So right here I'll say that I want a commit method.
And for my type, that's obviously going to be a function or equivalently a method.
But rather than write out all of that in line, I'm simply going to use the commit interface that I
imported from view.
Because this is itself an interface that defines a specific function, that takes specific parameters
with specific types and returns a specific value.
So this is the exact interface of the commit method that we're utilizing here.
It's coming directly from view.
So it's better than anything I could type here in line and more reliable.
It's right here for context and going to provide my context interface from above.
So I'm simply saying this context object will be of type context.
And what does that mean?
That means this context object will have a commit method.
Keep in mind if we do anything else with the context object such as invoke another method are our implementation
or our definitions will no longer work because TypeScript will say, You've only told me about a commit
method.
You haven't told me about your second method that you're invoking.
In that case, we may rely indeed on the actual action, context, implementation or rather interface
that we have right here from the View Library.
But for now, the simplest interface is enough to get everything to work.
And since we're only using the commit method, I want to create the smallest possible applicable interface
I can, which is just a basic interface with a single method rather than the comparable interface that
we just saw in the other file.
With six different properties and methods that I don't care about, the more I lodge that complexity
into my type definition, the more difficult it will be.
For example, in our tests, because our tests will have to honor the real world interface rather than
this smaller, simpler one that can also fulfill the same role.
All right.
So with that, the violations in our actions test file go away and we are going to proceed to the next
lesson.
I'll see you there.