All right.
So congratulations on reaching the end of another core section.
And as always, let's take a few minutes to review everything that we learned in this section.
We learned that we could use the computed function from the View Library in a different way for all
of our previous uses of it.
We of course pasted a function and in that function we reference some kind of reactive object so that
whenever that reactive object changed, the function would rerun get the new computed value or the new
reactive value, and that's basically the sole purpose that we would use it for.
We also learned of this new syntax where we could pass an object with a get and a set method, and those
get and set methods basically create the logic for reading and writing some kind of reactive state,
some kind of reactive value.
But the beautiful part about this approach is it did not necessarily have to be local component state.
So what we did is we used get and said to connect the logic for reading from the View Store as well
as writing to the View Store through the way of a mutation.
And this solved the problem we saw in the previous section where we had to manually keep our component
state in sync with our view or state.
We did that by keeping a local component state and then having to commit a mutation whenever it changed.
And then we also had to use the subscribe method to make sure the component state was informed whenever
the view store state changes.
Now of course that solution exists in view, but it's generally not considered the best solution because
it's much more manual.
This approach is a lot more automatic because we can simply sync the components local state to be reliant
on view, text or state.
So we used the V model directive with the return value of this computed function.
And that way we did not have any duplicate data, we did not have any multiple sources of truth.
We simply used the View Store State to track the user's current input in the skills search term property
and to update our input whenever the user changed it and have that two way data binding.
But between the template and the view store, instead of all the previous examples where we used to
a data binding between the template and the local component state.
So as a reminder in the get method, we declare the logic for determining the current reactive value.
So in our implementation aren't reactive value was the skills search term property on our view store.
So whenever it changed our component new to react and so in the set method we declared the logic for
setting the next value.
So in our case it was setting the next value of the skills search term property on our store.
That was how we updated that reactive value.
And in order to do that, we of course needed to commit a mutation to the bookstore.
So it's the same read and right logic as using, for example, ref in a component, except we now can
connect it to something external like a view store state.
And that's the most common use case for using this get set method terminology inside the object that
we passed to the computed function.
In addition, the second primary thing we learned about was input modifiers.
I believe earlier in the course we may have also talked about the number input modifier, but regardless,
it was a good chance to either relearn these concepts or introduce them for the first time.
So we first learned about the lazy input modifier.
We can simply add it on to the end of the V model directive.
So the model got lazy and what that does is it only takes action to update the data, whatever that
happens to be.
It can be local component data or as we saw it can be if you store data.
The point is it updates the data when the user stops typing and clicks outside or when they press enter.
And the reason this is advantageous is because we don't need to get view to work so hard to keep track
of every character, the user types.
So in this example, rather than committing a mutation with every single keystroke, we reduce the total
number of mutations.
So the user can just type the search term, press enter, and then we commit one final mutation, one
mutation, and that's it with the final skills search term value to populate in the store, we also
explored the trim input modifier.
What that does is it removes whitespace from both ends of the text input.
You can also combine multiple input modifiers together.
You simply put a dot after each one.
So V model dot lazy dot trim and we saw that applied.
Both of those modifications to the data and trim was especially a cool one because it ensured that any
whitespace would be left out, which of course gave our user a better experience of having a search
term that is more likely to match some job title.
All right.
So those are the new concepts introduced in this section.
Hope you've had fun and I will see you in the next lesson.