All right, so in this lesson, I'll introduce you to the just mock function, which will allow us to
mock out or replace JavaScript functionality within our components.
Before we get there, though, I'd like to give you an example, an analogous example for why mock functions
exist in the first place.
So if you think back to our sub nav component and our tests, you may recall that we used this setup
right here where we established stubs and we talked about this idea of stubs being a replacement for
a real component.
So in this example, on the right hand side, we stubbed out or replaced the font awesome icon with
some other implementation because for the purposes of this test, we didn't care about that component
and its internals.
We just wanted to test our sub now.
And the beautiful part about this approach, of course, is that it makes things easier to test because
it gets rid of dependencies such as these external components that come from totally different libraries.
The more that we can focus on the core, a unit under test, whether it be a individual component or
an individual method, the more it becomes easier to test because our scope is smaller and more isolated.
Right?
So this idea that's captured by stubs and also captured by these shallow mount function which stubs
out every child component, this kind of spirit is embodied by the just mock function, right?
So if we go back to our headline component, which I have here on the left hand side, you'll notice
that we're using a bunch of built in JavaScript functions.
We have clear interval and set interval being used right here.
Now some JavaScript developers some time ago wrote the logic for these respective functions, right?
The internals of set interval know how to take a function and a duration in time in milliseconds, and
they know to run that given function, that interval or every time that that passage of time happens.
Right.
But for the purposes of us in caring about what the headline component does, we don't really care about
how those developers built out the logic of the set interval function.
All that we care about is that we use their code and we give set interval what it expects.
The expected arguments of a function and a millisecond duration and set interval will take care of that
logic.
So I would argue for the purposes of testing the headline component, while we do care that we rely
on declare interval and set interval functions, we don't really care on how those functions are implemented.
That's some other developers problem that some other developers test.
All we really need to care about is headlines interaction with those functions, namely that it provides
them with the right arguments.
But we don't necessarily have to test the specific logic of set interval and clear interval in our tests
for headline component, right?
Otherwise we'd be testing core JavaScript functionality instead of headline component specific functionality,
right?
So how can we solve the problem that our implementation has these functions but we don't actually care
about how they're implemented?
Well, just functions basically stub out or mock out or replace these functions the exact same way that
we stubbed out our components right here.
So imagine we tell just our test running framework that as it renders this component and it runs into
a use of clear interval or set interval, imagine we tell, just don't worry about the complexity of
that function, but whenever you see it, just replace it with a much simpler function that we have
control of and that we can manipulate and test.
Right?
And that way we don't have to deal with the complexity of worrying about things like the passage of
time.
Right.
Waiting 3 seconds to check whether the interval did what it's supposed to do.
We can replace set interval and clear interval with functions that emulate that behavior or replace
that behavior but aren't the real thing.
And we can still test the component and how it works by playing around with these substitute functions,
with these standard mock functions, stub functions, whatever you want to call them, I just call them
replacements for the original implementation and that will allow our tests for headline again to be
much simpler, to write, to be decoupled, and to test the right thing.
Our business logic what we have in headlines that view, what we wrote, what we care about versus what
some JavaScript developers wrote decades ago for a set interval.
All right.
So in order to understand this concept, we're going to introduce the just mock function in isolation.
So I'm going to show you how it works in a test, and then we're going to show you how to actually use
that function to replace clear interval and set interval in upcoming lessons.
And these ideas are going to permeate throughout the entire course because we're going to be using mock
functions a lot to replace real functionality in many different parts of our view app.
So to begin, what I'd like to do is to create a test file for our headline component.
We don't have a test var for this yet.
We did not follow a TDD approach, but that is fine.
So of course we have our test directory, we have a unit folder in there and then we have a component.
Directory within unit.
And here is where I want to create a new file and it will be my headline dot test that component test
file.
Perfect.
So I'm going to drag this over to the right hand side here.
In fact, we don't even need it, since we're not going to be writing exactly headline specific tests
yet.
We're just going to be showing the justice function in isolation.
But let's pretend as if we are writing a real test.
I'm going to import my mount function from view test utils and then I'm going to import the component
I'm testing, which is headline and that is going to come from the source directory components headline.
And what I want to do next is invoke my described function.
And what I'm describing is what I'm testing, and that is the headline component.
Let's provide an arrow function as my second argument.
And for now, I'll just do a separate described lock and say that this is just a just playground.
So this is not specific to our headline component, and we will remove these tests later.
This is just for learning about core, just functionality.
So I'm going to write a description here.
It tracks whether it has been called.
So I know this is a little bit confusing right now, but let me describe what it is that we're going
to do here.
We're going to utilize something called the just mock function.
And it's basically a function that can play the role of anything.
It can play the role of a real function.
It can play the role of a class.
Essentially, is this fake stub.
You can think of it like that.
It's a function whose implementation we can customize, a function that we can tell to return any value
that we want, etc..
Right.
And almost think of it like a blank canvas for defining a function that can do whatever we want for
the purposes of replacing a real function somewhere down the line.
Now, one of the super cool things about this just mock function is it can track interaction with itself.
What I mean by that is whenever we invoke this function, the just function can keep track that it has
been invoked, it can keep track of how many times it has been invoked or called.
It can keep track of what arguments it was past each time it was been in and has been invoked.
Right.
So it keeps a state inside of it that knows how many times our program has interacted with that function.
Okay.
Let me show you an example of this in action.
I'll declare my mock function.
I'll sign it to a constant called mock function.
And the way we actually create this mock function is by referencing our top level just library, which
is available in this file as a global constant.
And on this library, we can access the F and function, and that is short for mock function, F and
for function.
So we do need to invoke this and now we have a mock function, right?
So it's almost treated like a regular function.
In fact, where I can show you is I can actually console.log the invocation of mock function and invoke
it just like a plain JavaScript function.
I believe it's going to return undefined, but we can show you that it works just like a regular JavaScript
function that we might declare in our program.
So if I go ahead and execute and PM run test watch our just test runners should notice this new file.
It should run headline that test.
And you can see here here is the console.log.
So the function returns undefined.
So you can almost think of it like we have this base function defined.
It doesn't do anything yet and it returns undefined.
Right?
Almost the same thing as if we did something like this.
Here's an example of almost the equivalent thing, but of course the benefit of our just mock function
is that functionality to track its own calls.
So what I can do here is I can invoke my mock function once, and then I can assert, for example,
that the mock function has been invoked at least once.
So here what I'm going to do is I'm going to expect and I'm going to pass in my mock function by itself.
And there's this new matcher or assertion that I'd like to introduce you to.
Previously we export things like to be or to equal.
There is a special sequence of assertions that we can make just on a mock function.
So for example, I have one that is to have been called and just like that name suggests it double checks
that the mock function has been called or in other words has been invoked, has been run, has been
executed.
So we are running this function on line number nine.
So our assertion will pass.
So when I save this file, you're going to see that the assertion passes because the mock function has
been called.
But in comparison, if I comment out line number nine, then our function will never have been called
and now this expectation will fail.
You can even see here in the output it says, I expected a certain number of calls greater than or equal
to one.
So I expected you to call this function to invoke it at least once, if not more.
But I actually received zero real life calls when the logic of the test runs, right?
So that is the big advantage of the just function is that it can keep track of its own invocations and
also how it has been called.
Let me give you another example.
Let's say I invoke my mock function with arguments like one, two, three, right?
Again, this is almost like a function that can be whatever function we want.
And in the real world, our functions can take parameters.
And in this example, let's imagine that mock function is this magic function that could take any number
of arguments, and I'm invoking it with three of them, 1 to 3.
And those are just arbitrary values.
Well, now I can assert not just that the.
Function has been called, but the function has been called with those arguments.
So, for example, I can assert that the function has been called with the exact arguments.
One, two, three.
All right, so when I save this, we're going to rerun and we're going to see that the tests pass,
because indeed, we do have an invocation of this function with those exact same three arguments.
But let's say I instead invoke it with 1 to 5.
Now, our tests are going to fail because Jess is going to say, yes, you did invoke this function,
but I expected you to invoke it with the arguments.
One, two, three.
And instead, what I saw when I looked at your code is that you actually only invoked it with 1 to 5.
Right.
And even if it's partial.
So, for example, if I invoke the function with one, two, five, but I test that it's been invoked
with one, two, that's also going to fail because Jess is going to look for an exact match that the
exact arguments that you passed in add to the function are what you're testing that it has been invoked
with.
So that is the core benefit of using the just knock function is that I can keep track of how many times
it's been interacted with, right?
Now, of course, in isolation this isn't particularly helpful, but start thinking about things like
imagine that we replaced clear interval right or set interval with a mock function like this.
In that scenario, what we can do is mount our headline component, interact with it, and knowing that
our clear interval function is this mock function that can be whatever we want.
All we can do is test the interaction of the headline component with our mock function.
We can say, Hey, headline, did you talk to clear interval at least once?
Did you pass it the expected arguments that we expected you to pass to it?
And in that regard, we are correctly testing the interaction of headline with those built in JavaScript
functions without worrying about their specific real life complex implementations.
Because we've replaced them with this kind of generic template of a function called the just function.
So this has been a quick introduction to the just mock function.
It's okay if you don't see the full benefit of this yet.
We're going to continue diving a lot more into mock functions throughout the course, but this has been
a general introduction to this functionality and in the very next lesson we're going to see how we can
actually stub out or mock out our core JavaScript functions that we have in our headline component.
So we're going to write our headline component tests in the very next lesson, and I will see you there.