All right.
So the changes that we introduced in the previous lesson are going to predictably break our tests for
the job filter sidebar organizations component.
So as always, let's reuse the same techniques we've learned to get these tests passed.
It's right here in my test suite.
Let's import all of our dependencies and mocked import for our tests.
So I'm going to import use store and that's going to come from view X.
Immediately after that, I'm going to mark out the U.S. then I'm going to import use router and that's
going to come from Vue router.
Make sure I spell this with a lowercase V, then I'm going to mark out the router.
Then my component is relying on my use unique organizations composable function that is coming from
that directory or that file store comparables.
So in the next line, I'm going to mock that out as well.
So at slash store, slash composable is awesome.
So now we have our create config factory function.
This was formally mocking out the dollar sign store and dollar sign router properties under this object
representing the or the this keyword of representing the component.
We're no longer using this so we can remove that.
And thus remove the parameters right here and now we can move through our tests and refactor them to
use our new marks.
So right here, what this test cares about is rendering a unique list of organizations for filtering
jobs.
So all this really cares about is that our composable function right here gives it a set that it can
work with.
We no longer need the full store and getters.
So what I'm going to do here is, say, use unique organizations.
And I want that to make return value.
And that is going to be my set that I formerly had right here.
Let's copy that.
Paste out right here.
Remove my former store.
As far as the router, I don't think we're going to need it at all because the default mac function
returning undefined is going to be fine.
The only place where the router needs a push method as a reminder is right here in this function.
But in this test, we're not running this function, so we're never going to get to this code.
So even though we don't have push on undefined, we're never going to reach this code.
So this test doesn't have to worry about it.
So I'm not going to need a router here.
The default use router.
Return value of undefined will work for this test right here.
Remove these two arguments that are no longer needed.
Save that.
There we go.
All right.
Moving on to the next one below, I'm going to copy my unique use, unique organization's marking from
above.
There we go.
This test does care about the commit method right here.
So I am going to keep commit right here as a named constant.
But I'm going to change where it is coming from.
So I'm going to take you store.
I'm going to mark its return value to give you back a sample store object or a mark that's going to
have a commit method that's going to be our just mock function above.
Thus we no longer need dollar sign store.
Now we will need router to be a somewhat valid object here because here we are testing in the test the
user clicking the checkbox.
We can see here we are clicking which means we are going to run through these two lines.
So even though our focus is the commit method, we do care about having push because if we have undefined,
the test will simply break because it's not going to reach the end of this function without an error.
So I do in this test need to make sure that I do provide a valid value for your router.
So I'm just going to do the simplest thing that makes sense, which is providing an object with a push
function or push method set to a basic just function that is going to be good enough to get this test
to pass.
Get rid of that line.
We no longer need it and get rid of these two arguments to the create config factory function.
We no longer need them.
There we go.
Same logic down below.
So I'm going to copy this mocking out from above.
Now this test is similarly going to click on the check box, but this one cares about the router, not
the store.
So for you store, I'm going to make a return value and all I care about is that I have some comment
method on it, but I don't need to assign it to a separate constant because I'm never going to check
in on it on it later.
So just like that, that takes care of this thing that we formerly had.
So let's delete that.
We still want to keep push as a constant because we're going to reference it later right here.
However, we're no longer going to wrap it up in Dollar Sign Rooter.
We're simply going to provide it in our use router mock return object.
Make return value is going to be an object with a push method set to adjust function that we defined
above.
Delete this line because we no longer need it.
Delete these two arguments because we no longer need them.
Everything is becoming a little bit cleaner and written on one line.
Save that, let everything run and beautiful.
We have 22 passing test suites and 68 passing tests in less than 3 seconds.
So hopefully you can also get a sense of how these three factors that no longer require us to come up
with these complex mock objects for the store are making our tests even simpler and shorter.
Right, because now these simple one liners can kind of get to the heart of what we need without needing
to get super knowledgeable about all those nested things that we've extracted, for example, to composable.
So our test suite has also become a little bit leaner and meaner as a result of the composition API.
Everything is kind of just one basic line of code as far as the set up of the interaction and then the
assertion.
All right, that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.