Okay.
So the next component that we're going to target is going to be job filter side checkbox group.
So this is the component that we were rendering in the previous lesson in our job filter sidebar.
This is the one that actually iterates over that set of unique values and render is a checkbox for each
one.
And I promised this time around that when we convert this component to use TypeScript, we are going
to discover some new problems that we're going to have to figure out over the course of the next couple
of lessons.
With that said, let's go through our usual protocol.
So right here script is going to have a lang attribute set.
It's and right here I'm going to import define component, make sure to import that from the view library.
And right here I'm going to invoke defined component and pass in my actual configuration object.
And when I finish with this parentheses and save, it looks like apparently there are no issues, but
there is actually an issue that is hiding.
Take a look at what happens when I hover my mouse over the store constant.
Now, of course, my expectation is I should be getting back the View store.
And that store has of course many properties.
It has the state property, it has getters, and within the state property it has the specific view
store state that is custom to my app.
So unfortunately, when I hover my mouse over store, we're going to see it's going to have the top
level store type, which is actually coming from view X.
But unfortunately that internal generic which says any does not actually have my actual interface for
my store.
As a reminder, if I go into my store index that's filed, bringing this over to the right, remember
that here we are actually configuring create storage, rely on that interface called Global State,
remember?
And that is the interface that actually has the four properties that our state actually needs.
So if I go, for example, I think it was our types file in the store directory.
This is the actual interface for my store.
It has these four properties, is logged in jobs, selected organizations and selected job types.
And even though we properly have that configuration being inferred right here when we configure the
store in the index data.
So unfortunately when we use the use store function from view X in our actual component, it doesn't
seem to be interpreting this information.
It doesn't seem to be understanding that it has a more specific store than simply any.
In other words, what I want to happen is I want it to recognize that it has a store that wraps our
global state interface.
So that way it can validate that when we access properties on our store, in our component, they must
be of these types and also, you know, go one level down, which means not just that you have a property
called jobs, but that jobs is an array of job objects, each with their own individual valid properties.
Because if we lose this connection whenever we use you store, then we lose all the benefits of this
type checking within our component.
And there are many components throughout our app that are using the use store composable function.
So starting in the next lesson, I'm going to take you to the Official View documentation and show you
the recommended approach that's going to be able to associate together our actual custom store interface
right here.
Global State with the use of the use store composable function from the U.S. We'll start tackling this
problem in the very next lesson, and I'll see you there.