All right.
So we saw in the previous lesson that we had some failing tests in our test suite.
So what I want to do now is run the entire test suite, not just the changed files.
So I'm going to run NPM, run test colon unit, and that is going to run every single test that just
can find.
And we're going to see what's failing.
So I'm going to let this run for a couple of seconds and we're going to see right here.
The good news is, is we have one failing test suite.
What that means is we only have one file where the tests are failing.
So just about everything is working correctly.
We just have one failing test suite and in the test file we have eight tests that are failing.
The good news about it being one file is that it likely means that it's isolated to just that component
or that section of the code base.
And we could fix it by fixing something in this file.
So if I scroll up all the way to the top here, we're going to ignore all of this output for now.
You're going to see that the failure is coming from the job listings that test, that file.
The good news here is that it's not coming from our tests for the View Store.
So all of our getter logic, all that stuff is still correct.
Something is going wrong in the job listings component, and that's the one that we were just working
on.
So let me show you this.
I'm going to open up the component.
Here it is, job listings, plural dot view.
And then I'm also going to open up the corresponding test suite and that's going to be job listings
dot test.
Yes, I'm going to drag it over to the right hand side.
And I want you to focus your eyes here on this create store factory function on line 13.
So it might have been a little while since we've been in this test file.
But as a reminder, we use these factory functions to create mock view objects.
We're not using a real store in our tests because we want to keep things really simple.
And so we typically create mock stores which are just plain JavaScript objects that play the role of
a view store.
For example, they may have a state property, they may have a dispatch method, they may have a commit
method, etc..
And so this is the factory function that is creating our sample view store.
Now take a look here.
In this mock view store, we have a state property and we have a jobs property inside it.
The reason we have this is because in our former implementation, you may recall that we were using
the map state helper function and we were providing it with a string of jobs because we wanted to reference
the jobs property, honor, view X Store and make that available via this state jobs.
So even though we were using a mock JavaScript object, we still needed the same setup.
So that map state could say, look at the state property, look at jobs, take that property and make
it a part of the component via the this keyword, this state jobs.
We're now we're no longer using the jobs property on the state object.
It doesn't matter whether that state object is coming from view or from a mock object, we're not using
it at all.
Instead, we're relying on a getter notice here.
We're relying everywhere on filter jobs by organizations.
That is not a piece of state that is a getter.
We're now using map getters to get that getter that's going to give us an array.
And we're using that array here to calculate the length.
We're using that array here to slice the first ten jobs, etc..
So the problem here is not a big one.
The problem is that our tests are suited for our previous implementation, which was relying on state
and we're no longer relying on state, relying on getters.
So all we need to do is fix up our create store function here and perhaps any future references down
below to state to instead rely on a getter, right?
Or at least a mocked up version of a getter.
So you may recall earlier in the course I showed you that on any single component, we have access to
this the dollar sign store.
And of course, that is our view store object.
And on that object we have, for example, a state property.
We are we have a commit method, we have a dispatch method, etc. These are all the things that we've
been marking out.
Well, we similarly have on a real view store we have a getters property that gets us access to the
entire Getters object of methods.
We showed you this a little bit earlier in the course, so all we need to do is we need to modify our
mock store right here to have a getters property.
Because if we have a getters property and if that object has a filter jobs by organization's property,
then we're going to be able to suit this component's implementation again without relying on the real
view store.
So if we know that in the real world View X has a store that has a getters property, in our mock store
right here, we no longer need a state property so we can delete that.
We just need a getters property.
And of course we can have multiple getters, which is why getters is going to be an object.
This is the exact same design that they have in view X, but again, we're just keeping it simple by
using a simple JavaScript object.
So in order for a component to work, we just need a single getter to exist.
What getter do we need to exist in order for map getters to work right here?
Well, we need to have a getter exactly.
Called filter jobs by organizations.
And in the real world, what is this getter going to return to us when we use it?
On The Real View Store, it's going to give us back an array of filter job objects.
Well, for now, let's just provide an empty array.
Just a sample array.
Because we need something to return, right?
We need some kind of property to assign.
And let's see how far this gets us, because as long as we have this getter right here, then this map
getters should work.
We're going to get back an array from it.
And so this that filter jobs that organizations right here should now evaluate to an empty array, which
is fine because the length property will exist on it.
And right here, filter jobs by organizations is going to be this empty array, which is also fine because
we're still going to be able to call the slice method on an empty array.
So I'm going to save this and right here I'm going to run NPM, run, test, colon, watch.
We're going to run just again and watch mode.
You're going to see it's going to rerun the job listings component file, which is the exact one that
we want.
And you'll notice we've reduced it down from eight failures down to two.
So simply by changing this store detail that our component needs to work, we've already eliminated
six of those errors.
So if I scroll up, we're going to see we still have a couple failing tests right here.
This one creates a job listing for a maximum of ten jobs, and this one shows a link to next page.
So let's scroll down to those specific tests and fix those errors.
So if I scroll down here.
This one is fine.
This one is where we're failing.
It creates a job listing for a maximum of ten jobs.
Okay, so here's where we have to get a little bit more specific because our getter needs to actually
return a certain amount of jobs in order to test that.
We have exactly ten jobs rendered right now are filter jobs by organizations.
Getter is going to return an array of zero.
So we obviously cannot check that we have ten job listings on the page.
So all we need to do is customize the getter to instead return an array of 15 objects.
Right?
So luckily we created our create store function right here to be very customizable.
Remember, we can provide the config object right here and we do structure its properties so we can
provide a configuration object with its own getters property with its own filter jobs by organizations
array set to whatever we want, and that will override this default implementation in our factory.
So scroll down right here.
We're no longer going to need the state, right?
Because we don't care about the state.
What we instead need is going to be a getters property and that's going to be an object.
And in our object we're going to have our filter jobs by organizations, property, the exact same one
we have above, but that's by intent.
And here I'm going to copy this property that I have right here, because previously we were using this
idea of having 15 jobs to populate the original U.S. store state.
Now, I just need 15 jobs to get from filter jobs by organizations.
And if I cut and paste this right here.
And remove this and save.
We should see that this test is going to pass and indeed it does right here.
So just as a reminder of what we're doing here, this test is testing that we create a job listing for
a maximum of ten jobs.
So we get some kind of array, let's say 215 jobs, and we need to narrow that down to slice it down
to ten.
So previously we were getting that array of jobs from our state, from the jobs property.
Now we're getting it from our filter jobs by organizations get it.
But the logic remains the same.
We're going to create that getter to return exactly 15 jobs in this case.
We're going to fill an array with 15 empty objects.
But that is good enough because we don't care about what those objects hold.
We just need an array of 15 of them.
So our V4 directive is going to end right over something instead of an empty array.
And then we're simply going to test this slice logic here that's going to use the index to select the
first ten elements and the first ten jobs from that array and iterate over them to create ten job listings
component.
So the core heart of this logic remains the same.
We're managing a component.
We're finding a given data test attribute, which represents a job listing component.
This one right here, and we should still expect to see ten from them.
The only thing that we needed to alter is the setup to get the component to such a state where it would
have an array of something to select.
Ten from our original implementation up here is not good because we can't filter ten from an array of
empty jobs.
Here we can filter ten from an array of 15 jobs.
But the key differential is we're getting the jobs from a getter instead of from our original state
property.
It was that big change in our component that broke all of our tests.
And so we need to update any one of our reliance here on the state to now rely on a getter that is sufficient
for what that test needs.
So if I scroll down here, we're not doing anything unique with our getters right here or right here.
And if I scroll down to the failing test, which is shows link to next page right here, we can see
once again we are failing because we are relying on our default getter up top.
In order to have a next page, we need to have at least 11 jobs.
We need to have more than ten.
So right here I can follow the exact same approach as I did above.
I can provide my getters property, I can provide my getter that I need to exist called filter jobs
by organizations.
This needs to be an array of at least 11 jobs.
So I'm going to copy my former logic here.
To create an array of 15.
15 is just arbitrary.
This would work with 11 or 12 or however many.
I'm just going to do 15 here and I'm going to remove my former state reference.
So right here we now have a getter for the component to rely on.
That getter is going to give the component an array that fulfills the requirements for this test to
pass.
And everything is working great.
Now all of our tests are now passing just fine.
However, I do want to scroll down to show you that there is one more test right here.
In fact, two more, I think that are still relying on the former implementation of state.
So it looks like the default implementation of the getter is okay, but I just want to copy our code
from above to remove any form a reference to this former implementation.
So I'm just going to copy this logic right here of store equals create store and I'm going to replace
this reliance on our mock store state.
And right here, I'm going to do the exact same thing.
I'm going to save that.
Let everything we run for.
All of our tests and job listings are passing.
I'm going to shut this process down using control C on a mac.
It might be the same on windows.
And then I'm going to once again run NPM run test colon unit because I once again want to run everything.
Make sure that all of our tests are passing completely.
Let's give it a couple of seconds to run and there we go.
So we have 16 test suites or 16 test files, which have a total of 53 tests.
All of them are passing.
So again, to summarize what we learned in this lesson, the reason that our tests for the job listings
component broke is because previously job listings was relying on that state and a piece of York state.
Now job listings is relying on map getters and a getter from our view store.
So in order to have a mock store that satisfies that implementation, that satisfies that interface
that this thing needs in order to run, we need to have a store with a getters property with the getter
that this component needs, which is filtered jobs by organizations.
We can customize it to be an array of an empty array and an array of one job ten jobs, however much
we need.
The point is, we need this getter to exist so that this line right here works to give some kind of
object that has a length property right here and a slice method right here.
As long as we provide an array, we do not need to use a real view store.
We can just use an object with a getters property that has a filter jobs by organizations property set
to an array.
We do not need to involve the real complexity of the book store.
We just need an object that is good enough to play that role, to play that part, to be sufficient
enough to satisfy what the component is looking for.
And because we switched our implementation so drastically, our old tests were expecting something totally
different.
They were expecting the component to be reliant on the store state.
Now we're relying on the store getters.
Once we updated that, you can see most of our tests changed pretty easily.
We just had to change the set up, but the assertions themselves stayed the same and that is a good
sign that we are testing for the right thing, that we are testing the rendering of the correct thing,
the presence of the correct element, etc. All we needed to change was the setup in our test, which
is perfect because that is a reflection of the real world implementation.
That's similarly changed to rely on something totally different from View X.
So I'm really happy with that rather limited amount of work that we needed to do to get all of our tests
passing again.
All right.
So with that, we have completed fixing our failing errors and in the very next lesson, we can write
some more tests.