Okay.
So on the left hand side, I have my getters file and on the right hand side I have the corresponding
test suite.
So let's write a new test for our filter jobs getter right here below all of these describes.
I'll add a new describe and we're going to test filtered jobs.
Let's provide the arrow function here and then our test is going to be an IT function call.
What is this getter responsible for?
It filters jobs by organization and job type.
All right.
So I'm going to provide the arrow function and let's have a quick discussion about how we're going to
handle this test.
Our filter jobs getter is reliant on two other getters right here.
And my question to you is, do we need to use the real world implementation of these getters in order
to test the functionality of filter jobs?
Do we need to run through this real world logic?
My argument is no.
Why?
Because the logic that these two getters is running through is already captured by the tests right here,
include job by organization and include job by job type.
And if we were to use the real world implementation, that actually creates more points of failure.
Imagine, for example, that we have a bug and include job by organization and we use the real getter.
When we're testing filter jobs, then our filter jobs test would fail because the logic in this getter
is broken.
But there's nothing actually broken in our filter job's getter.
It's simply relying on a second piece of functionality that itself is broken.
So the more that we can separate our getters, the more that we can separate and decouple and test our
different units in isolation, the more we can identify where the actual failure is occurring.
So from the perspective of the filter jobs getter, all it needs is a method called include job by organization
that's going to return a boolean.
Why a boolean?
Because the filter method here depends on having a function that returns a true or false.
The same rules apply for include job by job, tight job type filter jobs needs an object of getters,
and each one of those two getters is a basic function that returns a boolean.
And as long as we fit that interface, we don't actually have to use the real implementation here.
We can just use a mock implementation and check that filter.
Jobs does what it's supposed to do, that it returns a filtered array.
So we're going to write that test and we're also going to check that filter.
Jobs interacts with the getters in the right way that invokes each one of them and that it passes in
the correct argument, which is an individual job.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to begin by defining my two mock getters.
So right here, my first one will be include job by organization, and we can basically set up our mock
function any way we like.
We can even do something like a basic JavaScript arrow function that always returns true.
This would work because this would fit the interface of what this getter is supposed to do.
But just because I want to eventually track what it's been invoked with, I'm going to use the gest
function instead.
Remember, remember the advantage of this?
Is that a just function, a mock function here can track how many times it's been called and with what
arguments.
Now, the only problem right now is when it's invoked and just the mock function will return.
A default value of undefined and undefined is not going to work because then we're going to get undefined
right here when we substitute our mock function.
And that's not going to work with filter.
Filter needs a true or false.
So the way that we can specify the return value for this just function when it's invoked is by invoking
a method on it called mock return value and passing in the return value we want.
So in this case I just want a boolean of true.
So basically what we're saying here is whenever we get to any part of a program where include job by
organization is invoked like so that's basically going to return the value of true.
All right.
So I'm going to do the exact same thing with my include job by job type.
I'm going to set up this mock getter that I'm eventually going to incorporate into my test.
It's going to be a just function, and when we invoke that function, it's going to track that it's
been invoked and it's also going to invoke or return value of the value.
True.
You may remember earlier in the course that we used a similar method called mock resolved value.
It works the exact same way, except mock resolve value is for asynchronous promise resolution.
So the just function behaves as an asynchronous promise that resolves to give you a value in comparison.
Our getters are synchronous plain JavaScript operations, so we don't want to mock a resolved value
or an async value.
We want to make a regular function return value.
So that's why we do mock return.
So mock return value is for synchronous return values.
Mock resolve value is for promise, resolution values.
All right, so we have our two mock getters.
Let's capture them in a new object called Mock Getters.
So right here I'm going to provide include job by organization and include job by job type.
And this is going to be the second argument that we're eventually going to pass to our filter jobs getter.
So we have our second argument now.
We also need to come up with our state or our mock state.
So right here, I'm going to begin by defining a sample job.
Let's make an object with an idea of one and a title of best job ever.
All right.
And in order for our filter jobs getter to work, what do we need?
We need a jobs property on our state object.
And that has to be an array, because an array is what has a filter method on it.
So right here I'm going to define my mock of U.S. state.
So.
One state is going to be an object with a jobs property, and that must be an array.
So I'm going to provide an array and in here I'm going to put the job that I defined above just to have
something that we can filter through.
All right.
So we have a mock state.
We have an object that is good enough to play the role of a U.S. store.
And it state we have an object here that is good enough to play the second argument.
It's simply an object.
It's going to have these properties, which means when filtered jobs is going to access those properties
right here, instead of getting the real getters, it's just going to get our just mock functions which
are good enough to play that role because they're just plain functions that are always going to return.
True.
And that's all that filter jobs needs in order to get to its conclusion, to get to its end without
any problems.
So now the next thing I want to do, of course, is to run that getter.
So right here, I'm going to do content result and I have my getters imported into this test file via
getters.
I have my filter jobs getter and I need to provide it the two arguments that it expects.
It needs a state and it needs a collection of getters.
So for my state, I'm going to provide the state that I defined above and for getters, instead of giving
it the real getters object like view or view X is going to do in the real world.
In our test suite, I'm just going to give it the sample JavaScript object of mock getters.
This object right here, which has the two getters that this getter of filter jobs needs to run.
We've once again decoupled the implementation of filter jobs from literally having to rely on these
two real getters right here.
All right.
So let's assume that this is going to be a function that always returns true.
And let's assume that this is going to be a function that always returns true.
Thus, if we filter with true and we filter with true, the final return value of filter jobs is going
to be the same original array.
So the first thing I can do here is check that I expect result.
To equal an array.
With my job object with the exact same values.
And that's going to verify that we ran through all of our filter methods right here, and then we produced
a return value of an array from our getter that was based off the original jobs.
Right.
So that takes care of one of the things that I want to test.
The other thing that I want to test, and this is the primary reason why I used just functions right
here, is because I want to make sure that our filter jobs getter correctly talked to the corresponding
getters right here and pass them the right arguments.
If I use the plain JavaScript arrow function that always returns true, this logic would work, but
I would not be able to test that.
I have correctly invoked those functions in comparison with a just function I can see right here.
I'm going to say I expect my include job by organization mock function to have been called with.
Which is going to verify not just that it's been invoked, but that it's been involved with the right
argument.
And so what I want is at some point during the running of my filter jobs getter, I should have invoked
this getter or this mock getter in my test, and I should have invoked it passing in the sample job
that I have right here.
In theory, as we're iterating all over all of our jobs, we're going to pass in each one of our jobs.
Right.
If we have an array of 100, we're going to invoke the include job by organization getter 100 times
and pass in 100 different job objects.
But for the purposes of testing a single interaction, an array of one job is enough to validate that
this logic is doing what it's supposed to do.
That's one of the reasons why I extracted Job two, a separate constant, simply so I could reference
it down here below and make sure that I'm calling the getter with that exact job.
So right here, I'm going to add a very similar test.
I expect the my include job by job type.
Getter will also have been called with.
The job object.
All right, I'm going to save this and all of our tests are going to pass.
Let me show you how they could fail.
So, for example, if we were following a TDD approach and we built this test out, but we forgot to
add this last line, we would still have a gathering of returns, a valid array.
However, this test would fail because it would say, Hey, you told me that at some point you expected
me to rely on the include job by job type getter, and you expected me to call it with an argument of
job.
I did not receive any calls.
Number of calls, zero when I expected one call with this job object.
So we are validating not just that it's working, but that we are relying on the right getters, that
we are transferring responsibility to the correct getters.
And the way we're doing that is by replacing our real world getter implementations with mock getters
in our tests.
What is a mock getter?
It's a basic just function that can track its invocations.
It's just always going to return the value.
True.
Why does it always have to return the value?
So that our original logic here can work with filter.
Filter needs the getter to return a true here so that this function that we pass in line provides a
boolean that this can use to filter.
So we do need to make our mock getters behave similarly to the real thing.
It can't just be a random object.
It does have to play the role of the real object.
So it does have to have the same name.
It does have to have the same type of return value.
But it doesn't need to be the real getter in order to test filter jobs.
This is good enough.
All right, so I'm going to save this once again.
And now we can see all of our tests are passing right here.
I'm going to run our entire NPM run test unit command to run the entire test suite, double check everything
one more time.
Give it a second to run.
There it goes.
And we can see we have basically perfect test coverage for all of our components, for all of our view
stuff, etc..
All right.
So lots of great progress and I will see you in the next lesson.