Okay.
So on the right side of my screen, I've opened up my main now test suite and this is the test that
is failing.
You may recall that this is the test where we are testing that the commit mock function that we have
used to replace the stores commit method.
We are testing here that it has been called with the right argument of log in user whenever the user
clicks on the log in button.
And if we look at our test value right here, we can actually see right here in this receive section
that when we run this code, we are still receiving log in user correctly as our first argument.
However, we're also seeing the second argument that the test is receiving when it runs this component
and it's this object with a property of is trusted set to false.
So this, I think is an internal implementation detail that is specifically related to how map mutations
works.
Basically, to summarize, our code is still really working.
We really care about the right mutation being issued right here and we are still receiving.
It just is just failing because we told it to expect one argument in our in our mock function and instead
it's receiving to the expected string and some kind of configuration object.
So one option to fix this is to simply copy this object right here and to add it as the second argument
right here and basically saying that's what we expect it to be called with.
But that starts to get a little bit into more of the nitty gritty details of how Matt mutations works.
So there is a simpler solution, to be quite honest with you.
I don't know why it works, but it does.
And so I'm going to stick with that approach here.
So we know that we have a log user method.
We know that we are referencing it here, right here in our click handler.
And we know that Vue automatically runs this for us behind the scenes.
Well, we can actually force the manual invocation of this method in line.
Vue automatically does it behind the scenes, and I'm guessing that's where Matt Mutations feeds in
additional information.
So what I'm simply going to do is manually invoke this method in line by providing a pair of parentheses
the same way we do to any JavaScript method.
And when I save this and the test rerun, you're going to see that forces the map mutations method to
run this method without providing any of the additional arguments that we receive.
All right, sorry, I can't offer you a better explanation, but whenever you see that is a trusted
issue, simply manually invoke the method in line.
The way I found the solution was simply by stack overflying that object and saying something like,
you know, testing view x map mutations seeing is trusted false.
And I found a Stack Overflow page that said, Hey, just manually invoke that method in line and that
will solve the problem.
All right.
So now our test is back to running and we haven't modified any of its actual core logic.
We are still testing the heart of it, which is that the commit method is being called with the right
mutation name.
Even though we're using the helper map, mutations function from view X.
The implementation under the hood is still the same.
It's still defining the exact same log in user method we would have defined.
It's still calling the commit method on the store with the right mutation name.
So our our implementation has changed, but our test is still passing, which is a good sign that our
tests are decoupled from our implementation and that they're testing the right thing.
They're testing the interaction of our main NAV component with our store without caring about the specifics
of how the main NAV is doing it, either through our own methods or through the methods created for
us by map mutations.
So our implementation changes, but our tests have stayed the same, and that is a good sign that they
are testing the right thing.
All right.
So with that correction, we are good to wrap up this first introductory section to view X.
So I will see you in the next lesson.