All right, so in this code, I have opened two components side by side.
On the left, I have job filter sidebar organizations, and on the right I have job the sidebar job
types.
And as a reminder, these both render a collection of checkboxes.
When the user selects the checkbox, they send a message to the View store to collect the array of strings
representing the user's choices and commit salutations.
And every single time we've had to edit one file here, we've basically added the other one as well
to make similar changes.
And obviously this is starting to become a pretty laborious and monotonous process.
So I think the time has come to make an effort to consolidate these two very similar components into
one reusable, more generic component.
Now, it may strike you as being a little bit late in the process, almost like we've had this frustration
or pain earlier.
But I would argue that's not necessarily a bad thing.
I would rather have duplication first and make sure we're feeling the pain of something and kind of
confirm that two components are very similar and can be consolidated into one.
I'd rather do that than try to prematurely optimize, try to make one component early on, because I
tend to find that that leads to worse code in the long run than simply having a little bit of duplication.
Duplication isn't the worst thing in the world.
Duplication allows you to confirm that two things actually work the exact same way, thus allowing you
to combine them many times.
What you think is duplication isn't really duplication, it just has the illusion of that.
So you want to make sure that you're actually repeating behavior, not just lines of code.
It's when you have duplicate behavior that you can remove that duplication and isolate it to just one
element, for example, one component or one function.
So in this case, I think we do have sort of the confidence now to say that this is very similar so
we can try to build a reasonable component.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to pick one of these components.
Let's do the one on the left, and I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to call my new component job filter sidebar checkbox group, which is a nice generic name.
And I'm basically going to copy the code here into that new component and then I'm going to navigate
through the file and anything that is specific for it.
For the organizations component, I'm going to try to make it more generic in the new component.
So basically I'm going to have my template here on the left where I'm starting from and the right I
hope to arrive at a more generic component that isn't using specific things related to this original
one, such as the concept of organizations, for example.
All right.
So with that said, let me create a new component in my job builder sidebar directory right here in
components job results.
So right here I will create job filters, sidebar, checkbox group, dot view.
And immediately what I'm going to do is drag it to my right.
And I'm going to collapse my navigation.
And as I mentioned, I'm going to copy and paste all of my content that I have on the left hand side.
All right.
And then we'll simply keep them up so we can kind of compare them as we move along.
So online, too, we run into our very first specific thing.
The accordion is the component that provides the collapse ability and expanded body.
And when we are rendering the accordion in this original component, we are providing a prop called
header, which is the title that appears at the top.
Well, now we can no longer use the string organizations because that is only specific to one of our
actual checkbox groups, the organizations one.
We need a way to make this a lot more dynamic and flexible.
So given that this is a simple piece of text, one really easy way that we can enable this to be dynamic
is to allow it to be a prop.
So the parent that is going to render my job filled your sidebar checkbox through component will provide
a header prop and that's what I will pass down to my accordion component and that's going to allow it
to have whatever text we want.
So right here, I'm going to replace organizations with header.
And of course that by itself will not work because that's going to provide a string of header.
So I'm going to bind this using the colon syntax V bind.
And we have not defined the prop definition for header just yet, but let's put that on our to do list.
We need to make sure that now this component is going to accept a header prop which will be a string,
and we're simply going to pass down that dynamic prop value to the next component, which is accordion.
All right, let's move on down.
So we have our div.
That's fine.
All of this setup is basically just tailwinds.
So that's totally fine.
And here we get to our list item iteration using the V4 directive.
So obviously the concept of an organization is not generic enough, it is too specific.
So let's change this to something more flexible.
So I propose that we simply replace this with the word value.
And for this thing that we're iterating over instead of unique organizations, I'm simply going to call
it unique values because I eventually imagine that this component will do, for example, both unique
organizations and unique job types.
So kind of a more parent term for that that's more generic and reusable is something like unique values.
And then we'll talk a little bit later about how we're going to get those values into the component
of.
For now, we're just taking care of renaming the words the terms in our template.
So right here, I'm going to change this organization.
And how about the one on the next line as well to be value.
So right here, value and value for the key.
And this is going to be value in unique values.
And again, if you're confused, we have not yet defined what unique values is, where it's coming from.
I'm just setting up everything I need.
So I'm going to assume that I'm going to iterate over something called unique values.
And I'm probably going to assume at this point that it's going to be a string as well.
And I'm simply using that as the basis for my V for variable name and as my unique key.
It's right here.
Similarly, everywhere where we have organization, I need to change that to value.
So right here we're going to do value.
Right here we're going to do value right here.
We're going to do value right here.
Our label is going to be for value right here.
A data test attribute is going to be value.
The thing we're going to interpolate is going to be our value variable from above.
So there we go.
And we also have a couple of things like our V model association.
This is selected organizations.
So I'm going to change this now to be selected values.
And right here in sort of select organization, which is our method we invoke when a change event occurs.
In other words, when the user clicks the input, I'm going to change this, the select value.
So we can pause here for just a quick second to compare the left and right hand side.
Hopefully, that all make sense.
Basically, whenever I have a more specific thing on the left here, I replaced it with a more generic
term value.
All right.
That's all I've done.
The reason this now looks a little bit different is because the cleanup or the replacement of organization
with value has also caused pretty hard to remove some lines.
That's why it looks a little bit shorter.
But fundamentally, the code is really the same here.
I've just changed the term that I'm using in line.
All right.
So with that, we can move on to the script sections when you scroll down in our original component
and scroll down here as well.
All right.
So for now, I'm going to keep all these imports and then I'll remove them as needed.
So starting here with our actual configuration object, we obviously need to update things here as well.
So we can no longer have a name of sidebar organizations, but we can add a name of checkbox group right
here.
We are still going to need to keep our accordion components because that's going to enable the collapse
ability up top.
So that's totally fine to keep in here.
And then for our setup method, let's take a look at what we can do here.
So we're still going to need a store.
And the reason we're going to need a store is because in both components we are committing a mutation.
We'll talk about how we can make that dynamic in just a second.
But we still need the store in order to invoke the commit method, and we still need the router in order
to invoke the push method.
So here, instead of selected organizations, obviously I now want this to be selected values.
This is going to be my starter starter.
Right.
And here we run into another issue where formally we're using the composable function.
Here, we're using use unique organizations.
And in the other component, which is job types, we're getting we're using use unique job types.
So we once again have a problem here where we have a dynamic piece of data that we need to iterate over
the iterable collection that we're using right here in the V4.
So once again, because we have dynamic content here, what I'm going to do is feed it in as a prop.
So the parent that is going to render job filter side by checkbox group will figure out how to provide
something called unique values to my component when it's being rendered.
So we're not going to leave that responsibility in this component.
We're going to make this component except that as a prop.
All right.
I'm going to remove this line.
So now we have two things we have to remember to make props.
The first is that unique values.
And the second, of course, is going to be the header that we just talked about a few minutes ago.
All right.
Let's move on down.
So we have selected values.
Now we get to the select organization function.
Obviously, this can no longer be called select organization.
Let's call it select value.
We have our store and we want to call the commit method.
But of course, our our mutation name here is not guaranteed.
It's not going to be necessarily add selected organizations, for example, in the job type's component,
it's ads selected job types.
So once again, we have basically a string that is varying from every eventual component that we want
to to use this thing.
So I propose one more time that we allow the parent component that renders the checkbox group to provide
me one more prop that's going to represent the mutation.
So let's say I'm going to get this prop and how can we configure are set up method to receive props.
Remember that is going to be the very first parameter in the setup method.
So here I'll define props and again I'll expect my component from the parent component to pass in that
string.
So let's assume for now that our props object is going to have a mutation property and that is going
to be the string, and we're going to commit that mutation, whatever the parent tells me to commit.
That's the mutation I'm going to commit.
And here, of course, we know no longer have selected organizations, but we do have selected values.
Keep in mind that is still a reactive object because we're using RAF here.
So we do need selected values that value a little bit confusing because we have values that value.
But this is still correct.
And finally, luckily, this logic of invoking push with this path of the job results page is going
to stay consistent because no matter which checkbox the user is using or in other words, whatever filter
they're applying, we always want to bring them back to this page.
So this looks good.
All right.
So here we obviously have some names that no longer exist.
We obviously want to make selected values available.
That's what we defined right here.
And that is directly connected to our remodel right here.
And that is going to be the array that stores the actual strings and then obviously sends them off to
the relevant mutation.
All right.
Unique organizations is no longer going to exist, and unique values which we replace that with is going
to be a prop, will define that in just a moment.
And finally, select organization no longer exists as a function, but select value does.
So I'm going to replace this with select value and that makes sense.
So select value right here.
This change event will invoke this function that we're now making available as a direct property on
a return object.
All right.
So with that, we can see that these former imports are no longer being used, which makes sense because
they were directly from our organization's component when we copied it.
We obviously can have a generic component that knows about this specific composable function or this
specific mutation because that is too closed end, that is too focused on this functionality rather
than than the generic when we want.
So we can go ahead and remove these former imports that are no longer used.
And then the final thing that I want to do, of course, is to set up that props object, because as
a reminder, everywhere where we had a little bit of specific content, we want to now make that dynamic
and customizable by having the parent provide it.
So whenever we set up props, remember we create a props object right here, and that's where we specify
everything that the parent component will be able to provide for us.
And props can be required or they can be optional.
In this case, we will make all of our props required.
So starting from the top, just reviewing.
Remember the first thing our parent needs to give us is some kind of header string and that's what we're
going to take and immediately pass down to the accordion component.
So our parent will pass in a prop to checkbox group and checkbox group will take that prop and pass
it down to accordion.
So right here, the first thing my parent will give me is a prop called header.
Remember, we can provide a configuration object for each prop here.
I can say that the type, the data type of header will be a string and then I can provide a required
key set to true, which mandates that whenever a parent component renders checkbox group, it must give
me that prop is not optional, is required.
All right.
The next two things I'm going to need are unique values, which is going to be the thing we're iterating
over.
And then the last thing is going to be the actual mutation, which we're using right here.
So unique values is the next prop.
Provide the configuration object.
I'm also going to make this required and the reason we need to make it required is because we're going
to need something to iterate over here for this v4 to render the checkboxes.
So the whole purpose of this component is to render checkboxes.
If we don't give it anything to iterate over, then there's nothing for this component to do by itself.
So we will mandate that this prop is required.
All right.
Now, as far as the type, remember, we're only using this twice, once for our organizations, once
for our job types.
And both of those those scenarios, we're iterating over a set of strings.
So for now, we're going to leave this to be set.
That technical implementation may not be perfect because later on we may want to iterate over something
else like an array, but we'll worry about that later because for now, our two implementations or in
other words, the two components that were replacing this one as well as job, they'll just sidebar
job types, they both use sets.
So this reusable component is good enough for now to solve the duplication we have right now.
We don't want to super optimize it to solve every possible future problem, especially those that don't
exist yet.
So this is good enough for now.
It'll replace our two existing components just fine.
And finally, we want to make sure that the parent component provides me my mutation and whatever string
the parent gives me.
The mutation name is exactly what I'll get from my props object and tell this store to commit.
And that will allow each parent to customize the mutation, which again will make this component more
reusable.
So this is going to be a string.
And once again, it's going to be required because I need a mutation.
I need to be able to tell the view next door what has changed.
All right.
So this is a good place to start in this lesson.
We kind of created this reusable component, and we can obviously try to make it a reality and actually
use it properly in the very next lesson.