Okay.
So in the previous lesson we updated our actions file.
Let's now update our test file for our actions to be in TypeScript as well.
So right here in my tests unit, store directory, I'm going to change actions that test that yes.
To actions that test that T.
S and we'll see what kind of problems we have to solve.
Okay.
So it looks like we only have one issue.
And you can see here that TypeScript does not understand Microsoft value.
And if I hover my mouse over this, you can see property.
Microsoft value does not exist on type.
And then it's giving us the actual function definition, a function that returns a promise.
So what's going on here?
So what's going on here is we imported get jobs, which is our API function call in line number three.
As a reminder, here is what that function looks like.
So this is what TypeScript sees.
And the problem is TypeScript does not understand that when we use this syntax of just mock online number
four, we are replacing our original get jobs implementation with a just mock function.
TypeScript doesn't understand that we're doing that.
It still thinks it has the original get jobs function and the original get jobs function does not have
a microsoft value method on it.
So that's why TypeScript is complaining.
TypeScript doesn't understand that the mock function that we now have after line four does have mock
resolved value.
And that's what Get Jobs is at this moment of execution.
Just or rather, TypeScript still thinks it has this get jobs function right here, which is our own
regular function that does not have this method.
And that's why TypeScript is complaining.
So what we basically have to do is communicate to TypeScript that line number four effectively changed
the type of the get jobs function to be a just mock function.
And here's what we're going to do on the line below here.
I'm going to declare another constant and I'm going to call it get jobs mock.
And on the right hand side of an equal sign, I'm going to reference my get jobs function and then I'm
going to use the as syntax that I introduced a little bit earlier in the section.
Remember, as is a keyword that we can use to tell TypeScript to treat something as something else.
Remember, this isn't always perfect because we are kind of telling TypeScript to trust us.
We're telling TypeScript that we know something that it does not.
And thus TypeScript should treat one thing as another thing, even though it naturally doesn't want
to.
But in this scenario, I think it's okay because this is indeed a scenario where TypeScript doesn't
know something that we indeed do know.
We know that I'm line number four.
We're going to replace get jobs with a different type of object.
So now we can tell TypeScript we've done something that we know is going to convert a type of get jobs.
Let me explicitly communicate that to you so you can understand that as well.
So right here, what I'm going to say is get jobs, treat that as a just mock function.
And the way I do that is I have just automatically available in all my test files and on my just object.
There is a type called mock.
So what I'm going to say is get jobs as just mock.
And if I click into this, you're going to see I'm going to go into the actual type definition file
in the just library.
And you can see it is an interface.
It is a type that describes a specific function.
So all I'm saying to TypeScript here is I know you get jobs as a regular function, please treat it
as just mock instead.
Please treat it as this interface rather than the interface you can infer from the function that's important.
All right.
Now, to be clear, get jobs, mock and get jobs are both references to the exact same function.
We have not changed anything as far as implementation here.
What we have changed is how TypeScript receives that type of get jobs.
Right.
So if we got rid of this second half and you think about what this core line is doing, all we're doing
is creating another name of get jobs mark for an existing entity, it will just get jobs.
So we're not creating any new function, we're not creating any new value, we're not creating any copy
or anything like that.
What we're changing is the type recognition for TypeScript.
We're saying this thing called get jobs.
TypeScript view its type as something else than what you think it is.
Please view it as a just mock.
All right.
So now right here where we are referencing get jobs, we can reference get jobs mock because TypeScript
knows that this it's going to treat as a just mock function which indeed does have a microsoft value
method on it.
And thus it's not going to complain because it knows that that object does have the method that we're
invoking here.
Now, here on line 22, we can use either get jobs or get jobs mock because remember, they're still
referencing the exact same function in terms of practical JavaScript technicality.
Right.
All this is is a different name for the same object with a different type interpretation.
So right here, we don't actually have to update get jobs to be get jobs mock because from the perspective
of the test suite, when it runs because of just mock, this is already going to be a mock function
and thus it's still going to be able to track whether it's been called.
So in other words, when I do this logic right here, I'm still targeting the exact.
Same function that I have referenced by the get jobs name.
This line of syntax exists solely for the purpose of TypeScript, and because TypeScript only views
get jobs mark as being of the right type, even though it's the same function underneath the HUD because
TypeScript only views this thing as having the right type.
That's why I have to reference get jobs, mark.
Whenever I call a method on that object, but not whenever I actually test that it has been invoked
properly.
All right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
And with that, we can see there are no more violations.
And I can head to my terminal and run our entire test suite and everything should hopefully pass the
right here.
NPM Run Test Colon Unit.
Let's run everything to be safe.
And that should complete our modification of our actions file and the corresponding test file to Typekit.
So here we are running all of our components as well as all of our typescript and view related logic.
Give it a few seconds here and we can see everything passes.
All right.
So once again, this syntax, the syntax tells TypeScript to treat something or more specifically,
its type as something different that we explicitly specified.
So TypeScript wants to treat, get jobs type as the type, an inverse from the original function, which
is just a function that accepts no parameters and returns a promise where instead telling TypeScript,
please don't treat it as that.
Trust us, we know what we're doing.
Please treat it as a just mock function instead of a just mock function.
And that interface has its own separate interface with its own separate defined methods such as mock
resolve value, which allows TypeScript to say, okay, I know that get jobs.
Mock has a mock resolve value method because I'm treating its type as a mock object rather than the
original type, and thus it's going to permit this operation right here.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.