Okay.
So congratulations on reaching the end of another core section.
We did a lot in this section.
We built a brand new feature entirely in TypeScript, and there may not have been that many new view
concepts that we explored, but we certainly got a lot of opportunity to practice with existing view
concepts and view concepts and of course, write all of our code in TypeScript.
All right.
So with that, we have completed our user story, which we introduced in the first lesson.
As a user, I'd like to filter jobs by my level of education so that I can apply to positions for which
I am qualified.
So let's quickly review all the steps that we took in order to complete this user story.
The first thing we did is we built a degrees endpoint using JSON server and that simply returns an array
of degree objects.
This was a little bit of a different approach compared to our previous implementations.
For example, for job types and organizations, we simply iterated over the existing jobs.
Here we imagined that we had a business constraint and needing a separate endpoint that would provide
us with the data that would form the basis of the checkboxes that we rendered onto the screen.
Of course, in order to store the degrees that we got from our API function call, we also needed to
add some new properties to our bookstore.
So we created a degrees property to store the actual array of degrees.
And then we also created a selected degrees array in order to store the user's actual checkbox selections.
All right, so multiple pieces of your store state that we added in order to accommodate this feature.
All right.
In order, of course, to change those pieces of your store state, we needed to write mutations.
Mutations are methods that update the bookstore store state.
So we needed to write a mutation to update our degrees array and also to operate update our selected
degrees.
All right.
We also wrote New Getters.
One of our sample getters was the include job by degree getter, which validated whether or not a job
fit the criteria of inclusion in the filter jobs.
Right.
Remember that Filter Jobs was its own getter that relied on a bunch of smaller helper getters to do
its responsibility.
We also wrote new async action.
It was called Fetch Degrees, I believe, and the responsibility of that asynchronous view action was
to actually make the API request to the degrees endpoint.
So again, an action does an asynchronous operation like reaching out to an API or maybe reading from
the file disk.
And when it's done, it commits a synchronous mutation to update the View Store State.
All right.
We also wrote new composable functions to interact with View X.
We did that, for example, to interact with our new getters.
We also did a couple composable functions to actually send off or dispatch the action to make the API
request.
And so we saw how those composable functions can either interact with vue's reactivity system or return
completely reactive objects using things like computed.
And those reactive objects and those composable functions, we can reuse across multiple components.
In fact, speaking of reuse, we also reused general components.
So earlier in the course we tried our best to make the job the filter sidebar checkbox group component
pretty reusable, and we saw how easy it was to add another instantiation of that component in this
section.
This new checkbox group component that we added was of course responsible for rendering the degrees
checkboxes.
And we also saw how we could test those components while marking out their dependencies, such as their
own composable functions that we used in the setup method.
Finally, perhaps what I'm most proud of in this section is this entire section.
We used TDD or test driven development the entire way through.
So we used test driven development to drive every implementation.
We wrote the test first.
We described what the function or the method or the component was responsible for doing.
And only after we wrote a failing test, then we actually introduced a working implementation.
All right.
So hopefully we were able to move through the section a lot faster than previous sections because we
already built a lot of good infrastructure and reusability earlier on, a lot of good patterns that
were very easy to simply copy and kind of adjust slightly in order to accommodate a brand new user feature.
All right.
So I'm really proud of the work that we've done in this section.
I really hope you've learned a lot and I will see you in the next lesson.