All right.
So while I was playing around with our application, I discovered a bug.
So I want to show you that bug right now.
And then we're going to spend this lesson and the next one fixing it.
So as a reminder, we display only ten jobs on the right hand side, even when we have a filtered collection
of jobs.
So, for example, if I scroll down here, we'll see ten jobs.
Then the user is able to navigate to the next page by clicking next.
And the way that we keep track of what page the user's on is by using our query params right here.
So we have page equal to two.
So I'm going to use this feature to navigate us to, for example, page eight.
So we're going to get to the eighth page of job results.
And given that there are no filters now, everything still works because we have 100 jobs.
So we have at least eight pages of results.
But take a look at what happens when I expand job types and I filter for a job type.
For example, I'm going to click part time on the right hand side.
You'll notice we're going to get a blank page.
So why is this happening?
Will notice that there are only 25 jobs matched.
That means that only 25 of our 100 original jobs are part time.
Well, in order to show 25 jobs, we only need three pages.
Page one, page two.
And then the jobs end on page three.
But we were originally on page eight when we made this filter selection, and there is no logic that
forces the user back to the first page of job results to see the latest most up to date collection of
filter jobs.
So what we need to do as a very simple solution is any time the user selects any kind of filter, either
in job types or in organizations, because the logic can also apply here, we need to make sure that
we navigate them back to the first page of job results.
Now, one really easy way to do that is by simply using the original URL link without any query params.
So for example, if I just simply go to slash jobs, slash results, I'm always going to go to page
one.
So what we need to do is every time the user reacts to a click, every time the user checks a checkbox
or uncheck set for that matter, any time we react to that change event, we simply need to force the
router to navigate to this URL and that should solve our problem.
So let's try it out and going to head to VS Code.
And as a reminder, we have two components where we have this logic.
Let's start with our job types collection of checkboxes.
So I'm going to open our job filter, sidebar, job types, component right here and right here.
We have this method called select job type.
As a reminder, this method is what we invoke on every input change event.
In other words, on every checkbox click we run this select job type method and here is where we commit
the ADD selected job types mutation in order to send the data to the View X Store.
So here is a perfect location for me to navigate the user.
And luckily this is going way, way, way back when in the course.
But you may recall that because we have view router in our project, every component is going to have
access to a dollar sign router object.
That is the view writer and we can use that to navigate the user around the app in order to navigate
the user to a new route.
We invoke the push method on that router object and then we can provide a variety of inputs here.
One option is a plain JavaScript object with a name property set to the name of the route that we want
to send the user to.
So as a reminder, we can find all of our routes in a special file called the Router Index.
More specifically, the index file in the router folder.
I'm going to drag this over to the right hand side and we can see here we have an array of four routes.
Every route has a path and that is the URL.
So here is the one we want slash job slash results.
And every route also has the name.
So the name for this second route is job results.
So if we provide that exact argument to this string right here, job results, that should do it every
time the user clicks a checkbox for anything, selecting or selecting.
We're going to run this logic to navigate them back to slash job slash results, which will always be
page one.
So this should be a working solution.
The only problem, of course, is, as you can see here, it is getting our tests to fail.
More specifically, our tests in the job filter, sidebar, job types component, which it sort of sort
of makes sense because there's nowhere in our test suite currently where we are acknowledging this dollar
sign root or property view route or adds it for us in the component.
But of course in our test suite it's up to us to provide a mock object to represent that router.
We previously were not doing that, so that's why we're running into an issue here.
What our test is telling us is I cannot read the property push of undefined, which means this the dollar
sign router is evaluating two undefined, which makes sense because we didn't define that mock object
in our test suite.
Let's go ahead and do that right now.
So I'm going to open up my job filter sidebar job type's test file.
And as a reminder, what we have here on the top is a create configure factory function and it currently
accepts a mac store which we are providing to this mock object right now.
As a reminder, anything that we pass to this mock property is going to be a global property on the
component.
So because we provide the same store here, the component will now have this dollar sign store.
Well, similarly, if we want a Vista dollar sign rooter property, we need to provide one right here.
So I'm going to go with the simplest solution I can here.
I want to require each test to pass, create config, whatever router object it wants to use.
So right here I'm going to provide a router parameter with no default argument and whatever.
Any test gifts to me as the router object I'm going to provide right here as dollar sign router, which
of course will ensure that whenever we mount the component, we're now going to have this thought dollar
sign router available.
So right here, for example, in our very first test, before we mount the component, we can create
a dollar sign router object and by itself a single JavaScript object or an empty one is insufficient
because it's still not going to be good enough to play the role of a real router, because a real router
needs to be able to have a push method.
So we need to make sure that our object is going to support a push method.
So we're going to define push here and here.
You can do something as simple as, for example, wiring up a basic JavaScript method, a basic arrow
function, etc. But what I think is a really easy thing to do here is to simply use a just function,
because that's a perfect way to introduce a mock function for situations like this.
So right here, I'm going to make this a just function.
Just fan with parentheses.
And then as a reminder, we have two arguments to create config.
So now that we've created a router in this test, we need to make sure we pass it in as a second argument
to create config.
So create config will take the router that we give it in this test and it's going to set it up as dollar
sign router in the component saved up and we're going to basically repeat the exact same logic down
below.
So right here I'm going to say I need a dollar sign router object.
It's going to be a plane JavaScript object with a push method.
I'm going to make that a just function which is invoke able and thus can behave like a method.
And I'm going to pass in that router object, save that and you can see our tests are both passing.
So this is really great.
We got our old failing test to pass.
However, we are still not testing the new functionality on line of 52.
We got our tests to pass because previously in our older tests we were clicking on a checkbox, so we
were running through this method logic.
So we needed dollar sign router to exist and our previous code is running through it.
However, there's nowhere where we're actually testing line 52, so let's write a new test that's going
to validate that.
Whenever we click a checkbox, we are properly calling the push method on the router with the correct
argument of this object.
So this is going to be the second thing that happens when the user clicks the checkbox.
The first is this test right here.
It communicates that user has selected checkbox for job type.
That is coming from our line 51 here that talks to the view next door.
So the first thing I want to do here is I want to create a described above my second test just to make
sure I encapsulate related tests within their own describe.
So here I'm going to provide a describe of when user clicks checkbox.
I'm going to provide my arrow function here and then I'm going to drag my second test here into that
described.
BLOCK So let's cut and paste it right here and let's.
Paste it inside my describe save that it looks like I've lost a it's statements Let me return back make
sure you include that actual test it right there.
It right there.
Apologies for that small mistake.
Paste the right here.
Save that.
Okay, so we still have two tests passing, but notice we have now that top level describe description
of when user clicks checkbox.
So here is where I want to add my second test inside that when user clicks checkbox, describe for the
second responsibility that's going to happen.
Whenever the user selects a checkbox, we're going to navigate user to job results page to see fresh
batch of filtered jobs.
All right.
So I'm going to provide an error function here.
And our test here is going to be very similar to the one above.
As a reminder, what we're doing in the test above is we're creating a mock store, we're creating a
mock router, we're mounting the component, then we're expanding the accordion element right here.
Because remember, all of our checkboxes are housed in that accordion.
So we're revealing that content.
Then we are finding a sample checkbox and checking it, or in other words, clicking on the logic that
we want to do in our new test is going to be very similar.
We still want to perform all of these actions.
The only thing that we want to switch up is the actual assertion here.
This test is worried about the commit method being called.
We're going to worry about the push method being called on our router object.
So let's copy most of this test starting from line 38 all the way down to line 53.
I'm going to copy that and paste that below.
And then modified slightly to fit our test.
So right here, we're going to start by declaring a commit method that to be a just function.
We still need this in order for the not mutations logic to work, but we no longer need to keep track
of commit in a separate constant.
So what I'm going to do is just remove this line and make the just function declaration in line like.
So no difference in technical implementation, but it spares the need to avoid an extra constant that
I don't want people to get confused by.
Right.
Here we have a router declaration.
And what I'm going to do to isolate the push method, just to indicate to future readers that it probably
has importance, is I'm going to assign it to a separate constant.
So right here, I'll do content.
Push.
I'll make that a just function.
And in the router object, set up a below.
I'm just going to use S6 syntax to declare a push property that references our push.
Just function above.
I'm still going to mount my component.
I'm still going to create a config with our Mac store and our Mac router and I'm still going to click
on the accordion to expand it.
That is an asynchronous operation we can see here.
The click takes some time to run because we have an awake keyword, so we need to make sure that we
make our test function async.
So right here, I'm going to add the async keyword.
Save that.
Then we're finding a sample checkbox input.
This is the full time checkbox that's coming from one of our available, unique job types of full time,
and then we're checking you.
So after all of this completes, we should expect that our select job type method will have run and
that we will have invoked the push method on our router object.
So luckily I have my push method above in a push constant so I can take that just mock function and
I can test that it has been invoked by using to have then called width.
Now this is not only going to check that the function has been run or invoked, it's also going to validate
that it's been called with the correct argument.
What argument do I care about?
An object with a name property set to a string of job results?
I'm going to save that and we're going to see that our test is passing.
So we are correctly validating that if we wanted to follow a TDD approach, that's totally fine.
We would have simply written this test first marking out our router, and then we would have introduced
this line right here on line 52.
In fact, we can temporarily comment out this line to show us that the test is failing, and that is
a good sign because that means our new line here is providing the implementation the test is looking
for.
The test is looking to have pushed invoked with an argument of name set to job results.
Instead, we're currently getting a failing test where just is telling us that it had no calls whatsoever.
So this is what a TDD failure would have looked like, which would have prompted us to introduce the
router available from Vue router right here.
Make sure to call its push method and give it the right object representing the right path.
And now we see all of our tests are passing.
So let's navigate back to the browser to test this as a quick reminder, we do not have this functionality
set up for organizations yet.
We're going to do that in the next lesson, only for job types.
So for example, what I can do very quickly is navigate to a certain page of results, let's say page
two or maybe page three.
And then notice whenever I select a job type like part time, you'll notice we're going to automatically
navigate to page one at slash job slash results.
So we're always going to go to page one.
So if I select another job type here, like temporary and then go to something like page two, maybe
even page three, no matter where we are, as soon as we deselect or select anything, we're always
going to be taken back to the first page of results and there's always going to be some results there
from our filter jobs.
All right.
So we've taken care of this bug, but only for one component.
We're going to repeat this logic for organizations in the next lesson, and the logic is going to be
pretty similar.
So I will see you there.