Okay.
So we are making lots of progress in converting all of our UCS logic to be in TypeScript.
So the next file that I want to focus on is composable gotchas in our source store directory.
Here is where we have a whole bunch of composable functions.
The first three right here deal with talking with specific getters from the View Store and then this
final composable function right here.
Dispatches and action, the fetch jobs action to view X.
All right, so let's go ahead and change this file.
So right here, let's right click, choose rename.
And I'm going to change the extension from J.S. to T.S..
All right.
So after a quick second, we can see the initial bit of good news is that it doesn't look like we have
any errors, which is a good sign.
However, we're going to discover that the type inference is, in other words, what TypeScript thinks
are the proper return values from these proposals is not going to be quite right.
So let me give you an example here.
If, for example, I start with use filter jobs, this is going to return a computed function called
return value, which remember is a reactive object.
But more specifically, it's going to be a reactive object that wraps this return value of the getters
and it's filter jobs.
And as a quick reminder, what filter jobs represents is an array of job objects.
Right?
So in other words, what we're returning here is a reactive view object that's internally storing an
array of job objects.
And if I hover my mouse over use filter jobs, we can see the return value on the right is computed.
RAF And that is kind of the parent category or parent type that is representing that view reactive object.
But you can see in the generic syntax that it thinks that the internal value that the reactive object
is kind of wrapping is any.
In other words, TypeScript doesn't understand or can't infer that what we're returning here is a reactive
object, wrapping an array of job objects.
It doesn't understand that internal part, that internal value.
So what we need to be here is more specific.
We need to tell TypeScript that we are using computed.
So you are correct that it's going to be a computed ref or in other words, a reactive object, but
it's going to be a reactive object, wrapping a more specific value, which we will now provide to you
explicitly.
All right.
So in order to tell it that we're going to have a job array, we need to, of course, import our job
interface.
So what I'm going to do right here is I'm going to import my job interface.
And that's going to come from our source directory API and the types test file in there.
And then let me just show you if I click into this computed function and I go directly to the type definition
from my view library, we can see that the computed function accepts a generic, which means it accepts
a type as an argument.
In other words, whenever we use computed anywhere in a typescript file, we can use this bracket syntax
and provide the type that we want to represent.
And what that type will represent is the type of the value that the reactive object will wrap.
So we do not have to specify the reactive object that's kind of the outer layer, right?
But using a generic, we can specify the type of the internal value that that reactive object will wrap.
So in other words, using a generic is how I want to specify that this computed object will wrap an
array of jobs.
So right here where I use computed before I use my parentheses, I'm going to provide the opening and
closing curly brackets or whatever you call them, less than sine, greater than sine.
And remember, the argument here for these generics always has to be a type.
So it's not an actual implementation.
It's a type.
And again, this type represents what the reactive object will hold as its internal value, the type
of that thing.
So once again, we're going to have a job array.
It's not just a job, so make sure you don't just write job.
It's going to be a job followed by these square brackets.
That means a job, right?
So now we can see if I hover my mouse over use filter jobs.
It understands that computed that it's going to be a computed reactive object.
The type of that is computed rest.
And more specifically, it's going to be a computed reactive object that wraps an array of job objects,
and each one of those job objects will implement the job interface.
All right.
Let's move on to the next couple of examples.
So right here, similarly, use unique job types and use unique organizations.
Think that the composable is returning a computed reactive object, which is great, but unfortunately
it thinks it can be any internal value or any type within that object.
And that's not true.
These two getters, as a reminder, are going to return set objects and more specifically, sets of
strings.
Right.
If I go into my getters test file as a reminder, these two getters right here, let me see what they
are right here.
They create sets of strings and then they return those sets of strings.
And we are going to be returning here in our composable, a reactive object, wrapping a set of strings.
All right.
So once again, we're going to apply the exact same syntax after computed.
I'm going to put my less than sign in my greater than sign my brackets.
And then in here, I'm going to specify that I'm going to have a set.
But as we're going to see, this is not going to be enough.
If I hover my mouse over this, we're going to see generic type set t requires one type argument, right?
So in addition to telling TypeScript that we're going to have a set, we need to be even more specific
and tell it what is going to be the type of value that that set is going to hold.
Right.
So right here, we need to put another pair of brackets so that we provide the generic type argument
for this set.
So right here, I'm going to provide less than and greater then and right here, I'm going to say that
this is going to be a set with type shrink.
So it's going to be a set consisting of string values or string types.
And then the computed function is going to return a reactive object that is storing that set of string
types.
There's almost three different levels of type definition.
One is the most highest level.
The return value is a computed object.
Okay, that is a type.
But can we be more specific?
Yes, it is a computed reactive object.
Storing a set.
Great.
Can we be even more specific?
Yes.
It's a computed reactive object.
Storing a set of string values.
That's how deep and nested we can get with TypeScript.
And now if I hover my mouse over the composable, you can see it finally understands that the use unique
job types composable function returns a computed graph object and inside it's going to be holding a
set of string types.
Luckily for the use unique organizations composable, it's going to be the exact same thing.
So right here, after the computed function, before the parentheses will provide our brackets, this
is going to be a set and then TypeScript is going to be unhappy.
It's going to say, okay, I understand you're going to give me a set, but I need to know a set of
what is right here.
I'm going to write another pair of brackets for my set declaration and I'm going to provide a generic
type here as well.
String is my generic type for my set, and set with string is my generic type argument for computed.
So computed accepts a generic type argument and set accepts a generic type argument.
And now we're combining all of them together in one right now as far as use fetch jobs dispatch, I
don't think there's anything we're going to have to do here.
This function doesn't take any parameters, and it also doesn't.
Return anything?
There's no return, he would write here.
It simply dispatches an action to the store to start the API call to fetch two jobs.
So you'll notice if I hover my mouse over this, you can see it has the word void and all that void
means it's it's a type that signifies that the a function does not have a return value.
That's what void means.
The function is void or does not have an actual return value, and that is correct.
So the inference here is correct.
So there's nothing more that I need to provide because TypeScript has figured it out correctly.
All right.
And with that, we have completed typing out our types for our new composable to asphalt.
I'll see you in the next lesson.