Okay.
So our job filter sidebar checkbox group component is in a really good shape.
So now let's update the corresponding test suite.
So I'm going to open up job filter, sidebar checkbox group dot.
Test dot.
Yes.
I'm going to drag this file over to the right and immediately I'm going to open up my file Explorer.
And that's going to show me the location of the file right here.
I am, of course, going to rename it to give it a test extension for TypeScript.
And there we go.
And let me collapse my menu on the left.
And as I scroll down, we're going to see the familiar issues right here.
TypeScript does not understand that we have just mock functions for the use store and use router or
functions that were mocking.
So we, of course, have to provide the separate declarations up above.
So right here where we have our use store import as well as the mock out, I'm going to add an extra
line.
And I'm going to say const use store mock is going to be use store, but treated as a different type
of just mock.
And down below here can't use root or mock is going to be use router but also as a just mock type.
And now all we have to do is replace all of our previous uses of use store with use star mock and use
router, whether use root or mock.
So scrolling down here, we're going to do use store mock here, use root or mock scroll down.
Same thing here.
You know, the drill probably would be easy to do this with the find and replace as well.
But no problem at all.
All right.
So that's going to make those issues go away.
And then we're going to see actually a brand new issue here.
We can see here that we are invoking a method called set checked on this piece of template that we are
pulling out here.
In this case, it's the full time input, which is the HTML element that corresponds to this data just
attribute.
And you can see if I have on my mouse, you can see property set checked is private and only accessible
within the class.
So what this basically means is this is part of the object's private interface, which means it's a
method that the developers of view test utils don't actually want you to use.
You're technically able to use it because in JavaScript there is no real concept of privacy.
So TypeScript says, Hey, this is something that they really want to be private.
You really shouldn't be using it.
And if I press command on my Mac and click into this, you're going to see the entire typed declaration
for the actual test class or the test dom wrapper to be more specific that Vue test utils is utilizing.
And you can see right here that set checked is private, which means it's part of the internal implementation
of this DOM wrapper class.
It's a method that the developers, if you test utils, want to use in their own code to help make things
simpler for them.
But they don't really want us to be using it on our end.
And by the way, this is another great feature of TypeScript.
It's TypeScript telling us, hey, there's probably a better way to do this, because the way you did
it is kind of violating what the developers, if you test utils want you to do.
It's violating the public API that they want you to utilize.
Luckily, the solution for this is going to be pretty simple.
Instead of invoking the set check method, there is an alternative method we can invoke and it is going
to be called.
We see here in my notes it's going to be called set value.
It's right here.
Instead of set checked, it's going to be set value and we're going to provide that with a boolean representing
whether we want the actual input to be checked.
Because remember, this is a checkbox.
So by providing a value of true, that is equivalent to you checking the checkbox.
So right here we are clicking to expand the accordion.
We are finding the checkbox with the data test actually a full time and then we're setting its value
to true, which basically means we are checking it.
Same logic here.
This is setting it to be checked.
So right here I'm going to say set value is true.
And that is the exact same thing to set a checkbox for the purposes of this test.
And of course, the actual assertions here are verifying that the proper commit mutation has been called
and as well as the navigation using the Router's push method.
So with that, we should not have any more errors here, and it looks good.
So I'm going to bring up my terminal.
And as always, I'm going to run and run, test, call and watch.
And it should detect the changes in our test file, which now has a test extension.
There is our file.
Let's let it run and everything is passing perfect.
So that completes the refactor of the checkbox to component.
And I will see you in the next lesson.