Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we explored the benefits of tailwinds.
Yes.
And in this lesson, we're going to use The View Seelye to add it to our project.
As you'll see, it's going to be a super simple setup process.
So the first thing I want you to do is to open up your command line or your terminal and navigate to
your job search directory where we have our project.
And I recommend shutting down the running server if there is one.
And when I say running server, I mean if you still have the output from NPM run Serv where we are actually
transpiring the View app and showing it in our browser, I want you to shut that process down.
Typically on a mac that's going to be something like command or command C and on a Windows Machine,
I imagine it would be something like control the or Control C and in case that doesn't work, you can
always just close your terminal application and relaunch it and that should do the trick regardless.
Here is where we want to be.
I am in the job search directory and nothing is running and we're once again going to use our View Sealy
program and the command we want here is going to be ADD.
And as you might guess, this is going to add a dependency to our project.
And the beautiful part about the view.
Seelye In comparison to just a plain NPM install is this will not only download and fetch the dependency
but also create some basic set of files, some basic boilerplate code to get started.
So that is the advantage of usually it is specifically designed to add a technology to a view project
and so it's not going to have support for every package, but in this case it does have support for
tailwind.
So what we want to add here is view add tailwind.
So go ahead and press enter here.
And that's going to start the process of installing the plugin fetching dependencies.
It's also going to give us this option right here.
Tailwind is going to have a configuration file in our code base called Tailwind.
That configs will take a look at that at the end of this lesson.
And this is offering us an option as far as the starter configuration that we want so we can keep this
option of minimal.
So just press enter again.
And that of course is actually going to start the process of downloading the actual tailwind NPM package
as well as creating all of the files.
So as always, this might take a couple of seconds to run, but it's going to complete right here.
And with that, we can jump into the S code and see all the files that it has generated for us.
All right.
The first thing we're going to see is in our source directory in assets, we have a new Tailwind Access
file.
And as I open this file, you're going to see a slightly unconventional syntax.
It's just going to be at tailwind base components and utilities.
We'll never have to worry about this file again.
But basically what this is doing is using a special syntax to import all of tailwinds available to us
as classes.
So basically what we're doing here is all of those hundreds, if not thousands of utility classes that
we saw in the previous lesson, the classes that deal with margin and padding and font size and all
that stuff, this is basically loading them all in and they're going to be available to use automatically
simply with with this code right here.
All right, then the other file that's been affected here is Main Dogs.
And if I open that file here, you can see here in this file where we are bootstrapping the view application
as a reminder, here's where we are loading our starter app component and connecting it to that dev
with an idea of app.
Here you can see on line three we are importing our new tail.
It's just as class and simply by doing that we are registering all of those CC utility classes to be
available to be used in our code base.
Notice here that we are using a relative import.
We can once again be consistent and use the app symbol.
So remember the assets directory is directly in the source directory which we can represent with the
app sign.
So right here I can do the app sign followed by the remaining code and that is going to be the exact
same file reference.
All right.
So that takes care of importing the styles.
And then, of course, this post post the SS config that she has filed, we will never have to worry
about it again.
But it's another kind of configuration file related to post the SS, which as I understand it, is its
own other separate SS translation pipeline.
Basically, we're not going to need to touch this file ever again, so don't worry about it.
The file that we will be concerned with throughout the course is going to be this one right here tailwind
dot config data.
Yes.
And here is where we are going to be able to extend and manipulate how Tailwind works.
So Tailwind gives us a lot of success classes out of the box, but it doesn't give us everything we
need.
And here's where we can, for example, add custom colors, custom fonts, things like that.
And you're going to see it's actually going to be incredible because Telemann is going to take the configuration
settings that we give it and it's going to generate automatic new CAC classes for us out of the box.
And that's one of the most incredible features that I was totally impressed by when I was building this
course out, was seeing how tell when, just took the configuration I gave it and then created these
helper classes on top of all the ones that it ships with.
So it makes it super simple to just add a whole bunch of class classes in line to an element and then
see the impact immediately with minimal effort.
All right.
So we're going to explore this file in greater depth throughout the course, but that's all there is
to cover in this lesson.
And I will see you in the next.