Okay.
So let's continue practicing with the ideas we introduced in the previous lesson.
And as always, I hope that by introducing more components, we're going to get a chance to be exposed
to more types of problems that we may run into when integrating TypeScript into a view component.
So the next component that I want to focus on is Main NAV.
So I'm going to open up Main Navigate View and here is that component right here.
This is our top level menu at the top of our app and you can see that we're still utilizing the options
API in our script section.
Right here we have our data method, our computed properties, etc..
So let's go ahead and add TypeScript type checking to this component.
So we know it's a two step process.
The first thing I need to do is to add Lang right here.
So script, we're going to add the Lang attribute and set it to TTS.
And then the next thing I'm going to do is import.
Define component.
And that's going to come from our top level view library.
And then I need to make sure that I invoke this function and pass in my configuration object right here
as my default export.
So right here, define component.
I'm going to open up my parentheses here and make sure I close it off below.
Save that and it looks like we have no errors, which means TypeScript is going to be working out of
the box.
I do want to show you that TypeScript is indeed working and as as just like in the previous lesson that
you do not have to follow along with this code I'm about to write.
This is just for example.
But what I'm going to do here is I'm going to add a new method called nonsense.
And you'll notice up above that we have a menu items array in our data, and each object within menu
items has a specific object type.
It has a text property set to a string and it has a URL property set to a string as well.
So let's see what happens when I tried to push in a different type of value into my menu items.
Right.
So right here, I'm going to access this that menu items and that's totally valid syntax in the options
API and menu items is an array.
So push is going to be an absolutely valid method to invoke on that array.
But let's see.
I try to put in a value like five.
As soon as I do this, you can see the typescript violation pops up and if I have my mouse over it,
it will say argument of type number is not assignable to parameter of this type.
And what is that type?
It's the exact object type that TypeScript has inferred from our menu items.
Right.
So Typekit says, Hey, I looked at all the objects in that array and I know they have this shape.
They have a text value that is set to a string and they have a URL property that is set to a string
as well.
Five.
That type of number does not match this type of object you've given me.
So I'm going to raise a concern that this is not a valid operation.
So this is proof to us that TypeScript is indeed working.
So I'm going to get rid of this nonsense method, since it was just for the sake of example.
And that should make these errors disappear as well.
I'm not quite sure why they're appearing, but as soon as you get rid of that method, they're going
to be back to normal.
Okay, so everything is looking good in this component.
So the next thing I want to do is update the corresponding test suite as well.
So I'm going to open up Main now that test that just opened that file on the right.
And of course, the first thing we're going to do here is open up our file explorer, which will identify
the file.
And I, of course, want to change its extension from just to TSP.
Let's do that and let's see what kind of errors we encounter.
It looks like TypeScript is only going to show us one thing it's unsatisfied with, and that is in our
create config factory function.
As a reminder, we are still using the options API in this component.
So that's we're using the older way we introduced to mark out the View Store, which is represented
by the Dollar Sign Store property on this keyword within the component.
So this is how we were mocking it out earlier and the way we set up this logic is that every test right
here can pass in the custom object that is represented by store here.
So each test can specify what it cares about.
And of course, TypeScript is unhappy because it doesn't know what store is.
It says parameter dollar sign store implicitly has an any type, so we have to be a little bit more
specific about what this is.
So as always, even though even though we have things available from the view and the view libraries
like an official store interface, I argue we don't need to use the real store interface because it's
only going to add more complexity than we care about in this test.
In these tests, if we look, for example, at our very first test right here, all that dollar sign
store needs to be is an object with a state property and that state property needs to have a certain
shape as well.
And that is going to be actually our global state interface.
I can show you as a reminder what that interface looks like.
It's that interface with four properties is logged in jobs, selected organizations like the job that
they can see here for the purposes of what the main NAV component cares about, it only cares about
the is large and properties and I don't want to require it to always have to use the global state interface
because then in every test I'll have to provide these three additional properties which have nothing
to do with the component under test.
Right.
Similarly, if we think about the actual Vue store interface, the store and not the state, remember
that the store is this complex object that has a state property and also has methods like commit, methods
like dispatch, right?
It has the getters property and all of those things matter to the real Vue store in its official interface.
But for the purposes of this test, we don't want to say that this has to be a honoring the view store
interface, because if it did, we'd have to provide all of those additional properties, commit dispatch
getters, etc., even though they're completely irrelevant to this test.
Right?
And we don't want to make this test big and bloated and have to define all of these definitions and
parameters for things that are completely useless to what May Naifeh cares about.
So here's what we're going to do to solve this problem.
We're going to define an interface right here for this store parameter, and I'm going to call my interface
mock store.
I'm going to keep this in this file for now.
But if we later on determine that it's reusable, we can certainly move it to a helper file.
And so what does our mock store need to have?
All it needs to have as I look through all of these tests to confirm that they are pretty similar,
all that are store needs to have is a state property, right?
And then what is our state property going to be equal to?
It's going to be equal to our global state.
However, to ensure that I'm able to feed and things like this where it's only one out of the for profit.
Instead of all four, I'm going to use the partial global state.
I'm going to use the partial type from TypeScript to make all of these properties optional so that TypeScript
can validate that is logged in, is a valid property still and still set to the right type of boolean,
but not mandate that all of these have to be present in every test that I write.
So the syntax is going to look like this right here.
I know that I'm going to need to have a state property and what is going to be the type of that state
property?
In my Mac store, I'm going to use the partial keyword, provide my brackets right here and here.
I need to import global state, which is this interface on the file on the left.
So right here I'm going to import global state and that is going to come from my source directory store
types.
And so right here I'm going to provide a global state.
It's the mock store interface right here.
Make sure I take this correctly.
Global.
All right.
So my mock store interface is going to be an object that just has a single state property, which must
be an object that is going to resemble this shape.
However, all the properties are going to be optional, right?
So all that's left to do is right here to type out this dollar sign store parameter.
I'm going to say it's going to follow the type of mock store above.
It's going to implement that type.
And there we go.
So now there's no other errors because TypeScript validates.
Yes, this store fits the mock store interface you told me to expect.
It has a state property and it has an object right here that honors the partial global state interface
right here.
Again, the partial keyword is critical because if we didn't have partial, it would be fully global
state.
And then TypeScript would complain that we don't have jobs, selected organizations and selected job
type properties right here on this declaration.
And we don't care about those properties in this test because they're not relevant to me now.
So I don't want to include them here.
All right.
So with that, we can save the file.
It doesn't look like there are any other violations.
And right here, I can run, NPM, run, test, call and watch.
And since I make commit at the end of every lesson, this should only identify that our main test failed
because that is the component that we've changed.
And you can see all of our tests are still passing.
All right.
That's one more example of converting a component to utilize.
TypeScript and I will see you in the next lesson.