Okay.
So in this lesson we're going to introduce JavaScript set objects.
A set is a special data structure that was first introduced in E6.
So if you are comfortable with sets, you can feel free to skip this lesson and in the next one we're
going to apply these concepts to view.
But in this lesson, if you're unfamiliar with sets, you can join me in our Playground Digest file,
and I want to show you how this object works in general.
As a reminder, our playground file is where we simply play around with JavaScript and new ideas outside
of the scope of our project.
All right, so feel free to empty this file in case it has any content in it already.
All right.
So let's talk first about the problems that sets are supposed to solve.
And I want to do that by talking about problems that other data structures in jobs could solve.
So we know that we have arrays in JavaScript, and the problem that arrays solve is keeping things in
order.
The advantage of an array is that it maintains that certain things follow another right.
That's why we have index positions.
That's why we have the concept of order arrays exists that we can keep things in align objects in JavaScript
exists for another reason and that is association.
So the whole idea of having a property and a value is that we are associating two things together.
We're creating a connection between an identifier, a key or a property with the corresponding value.
So those are the two problems that arrays and objects solve.
A set solves a different problem in programming, and that problem is uniqueness.
Neither an array or an object can guarantee uniqueness, right?
An array can store the same value multiple times, and an object can store values that are duplicates
as well.
So we need some kind of object that will allow us to very easily have uniqueness, which means prohibit
duplication, prohibit duplicate elements from being stored within it.
So that is all a set does.
It's a data structure that can store things but maintain that there are no duplicates within it.
All right.
A set should be assumed to be unordered, so you should not assume that you can, you know, keep some
kind of order in line or that you can index into it based on a certain index.
It has no concept of that, like an array, but it does have a concept of uniqueness.
And one other advantage of a set is it's a lot quicker to look up the presence of an item in a set than
it is in an array.
The way that it's coded under the hood because it doesn't have to worry about maintaining order is it's
a lot easier to find whether an element exists in a set than whether it exists in an array.
I don't want to go super deep into the computer science ideas and the data structures and algorithms
ideas on why that is.
But just trust me that it's a lot faster to find whether an element does or does not exist in a set
compared to an array.
All right.
So with that said, let's just show you the basic syntax of a set in JavaScript.
So right here, I'm going to declare a concept called numbers.
And in order to create a set, there's no special syntax like, you know, curly braces for an object
or square brackets for an array.
We have to use the built in constructor function.
So I'm going to use the new keyword and I'm going to create a new set.
So capital S set and then make sure that you provide the parentheses.
This creates a set object from the base.
Good asset class, right?
So we have an empty set object that has nothing in it.
The way we can add elements to a set is by invoking a method called ADD.
So right here I'm going to invoke ADD and I'm going to provide whatever value I want.
So this will be a set of numbers.
So let's start by adding the value five and on the line below I can re invoke the add method and add
another number like ten.
And finally on the line after that I can add another value like 15 and then afterwards I'm going to
console.log numbers so we can see the set in our console and I'm going to run this file using node and
then the file is within the source directory playground docs.
Okay.
So in this output we're going to see set three and that three in parentheses indicates the number of
unique elements in my set.
So my set has three unique elements.
What are they?
We can see that in the curly braces here on the right.
Don't confuse this for an object.
This is just a syntax that Node uses to output the set.
The unique elements in our set are five, ten and 15.
Okay, so what happens when we try to add a duplicate element to our set?
Well, JavaScript is simply not going to add it right.
We're not going to get any kind of error.
We're not going to crash the program.
JavaScript is simply going to say, I already have this value.
My responsibility is to keep the set's elements unique, so I'm not going to add it.
So right here, numbers that add, I'm going to try to add five again and on the line below, I'm going
to try to add 15 again.
And if I console.log, the value of my numbers set afterwards and I rerun this file, you're going to
see we have the exact same set as we did originally, because the whole idea is that a set maintains
uniqueness.
It prohibits any duplicate values from being added.
That doesn't prevent me from adding a new value, right?
I can totally add, for example, a new value like 25.
And if I take a look at this operation afterwards, once again, we're going to see a new set.
And now we have the.
Value 25.
So totally okay to add new values, but JavaScript is going to prohibit duplicate values from being
added.
That is the whole reason why we use a set and it's a really great data structure for maintaining that
and also for looking up the presence of a value within that collection of unique items.
All right.
So with that said, we can move to the very next lesson where we're going to use sex in order to create
a unique collection of the organizations that our jobs belong to.
I'll see you there.