Okay.
So we are now able to use TypeScript within our job search view app.
And there's a lot of places that we want to add TypeScript code to our components, our composable functions,
our test suite, our view logic, etc. There's a lot of ground to cover, but I think a good place to
start is actually going to be in our DB JSON file and I want to bring this file up as a reminder.
So this is our mock backend that we have configured with Jason Server and the whole app kicks off by
making a request to get this array of job objects right here.
So here is a sample job object and will notice that a job object has a similar shape.
Each job object has a similar structure or as we said in the previous lesson or a previous section,
we can call it a similar interface.
Each job has an ID that is a number.
Each job has a title that is a string.
Each job has a minimum qualifications, property that is a string array, etc. And I think it'd be a
really good idea to create an interface for a sample job because that job object, that job data type
appears in many different locations within our app.
It's used in our view store, it's used in our get jobs function that actually gets the response.
It's used in our components which render a job listing for every job object.
And so we're going to get a lot of benefits just by defining an interface and having view, validate
that we're using it correctly.
That, for example, whenever we access minimum qualifications, we have to use that as an array because
it is an array, right?
So let's define an interface for a simple job object and I'm going to do that right here in my source
API directory.
I'm going to create a new file here called Types that.
Yes.
And the purpose of this TypeScript file will be to simply store various TypeScript types, not necessarily
for everything in my app, but for those functionalities that are related to my API.
The definition of what a job looks like to me comes from the API.
It comes from our mock backend, right, or our backend in the real world.
And so to me it kind of makes sense to put this logic in a API folder and then types that yes is a very
common name for a file that just has various TypeScript interfaces and things like that.
There's not going to be any actual code in here.
You're just going to be a lot of various types of related interface declarations, right?
And so in most code bases you might see multiple types files, you might see types files at the top
of the source directory within other folders.
It's really up to you to define how you want to structure and organize these things.
There's no single right answer to me.
The idea of what a job is lives in our API, so I'm simply creating my types.
That's file in there.
All right, so I'm going to drag my DB, that JSON file over here to the right.
I'm going to keep types that's open on my left.
And all we have to do is look at a sample job object and describe what that shape looks like, what
properties does it have, and what are their types.
So right here, I'm going to begin by exporting an interface.
The export keyword is just regular typescript, regular JavaScript to export something out of this file.
And we're going to export an interface.
And an interface, of course needs a name which we provide after this is a job interface and we provide
a pair of curly braces.
And as a reminder, the way this works is we put the property and then we put the type it has.
It's a simple as that.
So we're going to have an idea and every job and remember, we don't typically put the actual value
in here, we put the type, right.
So among all of our ideas, whether they are one or two or three down here below an idea is going to
be a number three.
Do ID call a number.
You can put a semicolon at the end, but prettier should automatically add it for you anyway.
And so that's an example of one field declaration or one property declaration.
We're going to do the exact same thing for everything that we see on the right hand side.
So title is going to be a string.
Organization is going to be a strong as well degree on the right hand side is going to be a strong as
well job type is going to have the data type of string as well.
Locations is going to be a string array.
And remember the way we write that is string followed by a pair of square brackets, string array.
Just like we can see here, minimum qualifications on the right hand side is also going to be a string
array.
And then we also have preferred qualifications and that is also going to be a string array.
Finally, we have a description which is also going to be a string array and then date added.
Which is a regular string.
All right.
It's not technically a date because remember here, it's not a any kind of date object.
It's just a string.
All right.
So this is a sample interface, right?
We haven't used it anywhere, but we've declared the basic structure, what a job is going to look like.
And now we can utilize this interface in various parts of our app.
All right.
So a good place to start.
We're going to continue exploring how we can add TypeScript to various different features.
Our app, both the components to the functions, to the compose, builds all of that in due time in
this section are mostly going to focus on the view side of things.
And we've made a really good start here in this lesson by defining the interface for a job and exporting
it out of this file so it can be imported and used by many other places around the globe.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.