All right.
So now we know the next feature that we're going to be building, we're going to be adding a sign in
button on our main navigation menu.
So we might be tempted to open up our main nav component and start writing the HTML and the logic there.
And I don't think that that's necessarily a bad idea, but what I propose we do instead is create a
new component called Action Button.
The thing about buttons is they tend to be pretty common and very frequently used across the website.
So if you take a look at the Google Careers site, you'll see the same button style, the same button
design used all over the website, because many times there's many different buttons that a user can
click on to accomplish different things, different calls to different actions.
Right?
And so the whole purpose of you is to build lots of small reusable components, small chunks of the
UI that we can place here and there and there and there.
And I think a button is a perfect little small, reusable chunk of the UI, and so it makes sense to
package it into its own component.
So the point at which you decide, Hey, I need a new separate component, there's no right or wrong
answer.
It really depends on where, where you feel right about it.
Sometimes you can start wiring up a button into a component and then maybe you start building out a
second component and realize you need the same button with the same styles.
And at that point, you may extract that to its own separate component.
And there's nothing wrong with that waiting until you have duplication before you isolate what is common,
that's totally fine.
But in this case, I think I feel comfortable creating a new action button component already.
All right.
So let's go ahead and head to our components folder.
And here we're going to create a file called Action Button Dot View.
It's another view component file.
And what do we need in a file like this?
Well, of course, we start with our template tags at the very top.
Here is where we define the HTML for the view component and we need to place something inside here so
our s lynch doesn't complain.
So let's place a basic button and here I'll put the text sign in for now just to put something on the
button.
And this is really all we need.
But as always, it's a good idea to set up our basic configuration object for this component.
So right below our template tags, we're going to write our script tags.
Here is where we can write any JavaScript that we want.
And of course our standard protocol by now, which we followed in May now as well, is to export default
a plain object.
And this will be our configuration object for our action button component.
The only thing I want to add here now is a name property and I'm going to set that equal to action button.
And again, the reason I'm doing this is so that this name is going to appear, in my view.
DevTools Whenever I look at my app in the browser, it makes it easier to distinguish which components
are actually appearing on our screen.
I do have one small Iceland violation at the end here and all that it really wants.
Here is a line break.
So I'm going to add that.
Save the file and we are all good to go.
So now that we've created our action button component, we can go ahead and render it once within main
NAV.
Remember, we can render view components within other view components.
In fact, that's what we're doing in our app component.
This is where we imported main NAV and rendered it for the first time.
We're going to do the exact same thing, but in main NAV we're going to import action button and then
use it here in the template.
So you may have forgotten what that process looks like, but it's pretty simple.
Here in our script section, we're going to import our view component.
So right here I'm going to import action button.
Let's provide the from keyword and we want to start at the top of our SIRC directory.
So I'm going to place that at sign and then I want to look inside my components folder and in there
I'll find my action button.
That view component.
Right now, importing a component is not enough by itself.
We have to configure it to work with Main NAV and we do that with an additional property on main navs
configuration object and that property is components.
I'm going to put components here that I'm going to set to a JavaScript object.
And as you may recall, the way this works is the key or the property that I write here will represent
the tag that I use in my HTML template.
So for example, if I put something like block here and set it equal to main nav, then wherever or
rather action button.
My apologies then wherever I want to render an action button, I would simply write the tag block with
the opening and closing brace.
Right now, typically what you want to do is give your component the exact same name as it's actually
called, just to avoid confusion.
So what a lot of people do is just put something like action button like so and then we don't need the
quotes here and then we end up with something like this.
And of course using s syntax we can consolidate this to just action button.
And this is basically the protocol we're going to be following for the remainder of the course.
I'm just going to be giving my components the same tag name as the component name.
So I'm going to write all of my components like this.
But just as a heads up again, this is a JavaScript shortcut for a more complex operation where we are
assigning the tag name to the component that we're going to render in our template.
All right.
So this gives us permission to render as many action buttons as we want in our main NAV.
But we have an issue.
And the issue here is kind of obvious.
The yes lint launcher is going to tell us you've registered action button, but you're not actually
using it.
So it's kind of wasteful because we're importing it and registering it, but not actually doing anything
with it.
So let's go ahead and render this action button on to the screen.
So I'm going to scroll up here.
And what I want to do is find my nav section.
This is where we have a navigation menu and I actually want to add my button after the entire navigation
section.
So I'm going to add a div here just to create a container for my new action button.
And I'm going to apply some tailwind styles to this div.
I'm, I'm going to make it a Flexbox.
I'm going to vertically align the items within the Flexbox using items center.
I'm going to play the full class to give it 100% of height compared to its parent.
And then in order to actually push this div to the right side of the screen, give it space between
our menu items and the right hand side of the screen.
I'm going to apply a class called MLA Auto.
What that does is apply margin left auto.
That basically means, as it applies enough margin automatically on the left hand side to push this
element, this div to the end of its parent container.
And its parent container, of course, is this top level div that stores the hyperlink with the company's
name, the nav bar.
And now finally this right hand div.
So this will just push this div all the way to the right hand side of our main top level nav bar.
All right.
And then here we can go ahead and render our action by component.
Now, remember, we registered it as action button, so we can totally use this syntax when we render
this component meaning capital A, capital B.
But Vue also creates a kabob case version of the component name behind the scenes.
So we can either write this action button or we can write this action button all lowercase with a dash
between every two subsequent words.
Right?
And of course, we can have either an opening tag and a closing tag, just like an element.
But in this case, since we don't have anything to render in between the tags, we don't need the closing
tags.
We can make this a little bit simpler by just rendering one and then putting the slash at the very end
that accomplishes the exact same thing.
So we're going to render one action button onto our screen.
Let's take a look at what this looks like.
So I'm going to navigate back to my browser and there we go.
We have bubble careers, our NAV and right here perfectly, we have a very plain button.
It's not styled yet, it's not dynamic yet.
It doesn't react to user clicks yet, but it displays the sign in text.
So this is a good first step.
All right.
So we've created a new action button component.
We've rendered it in our main NAV.
Next step, we're going to go ahead and style it and then start working on the actual logic to sign
in and replace it with a profile image.
So I'll see you in the upcoming license.