All right.
So the first thing I want to do in this section is to create a new component called hero.
Hero spelled her0.
But I'm not talking about a hero like Spider-Man or Superman.
I'm talking about a hero in terms of web development.
And when we're talking about a hero, we're typically talking about a banner image or really just a
big section of the page that's sort of the first focal point that the user is going to pay attention
to.
So in this case, right below our main navigator sub, now this big chunk of white background, I want
to take this entire section and represent that as a component and I'm going to call that a hero.
And I just want to show you, if I go to my Google Careers websites, you have a better sense of what's
going on here.
When I'm talking about the hero, I'm talking about this section right here.
So it's not just the the headline right here and the prompt and the form.
It's the entire kind of encapsulating container around that idea.
It's sort of the first thing you want your user to focus on.
It's big, it's bold.
It kind of declares a statement and it's kind of the primary point where they want you to focus your
eyes.
And this is a common web design idea across different websites.
As another example, I can take you to the official Apple home page and you'll see we have a similar
idea of a hero that advertises the iPhone 13.
So it's this big glaring image with an obvious headline, iPhone 13 pro.
Same idea.
Here they have the the main nav, maybe a sub nav with some additional directions.
And then they have this big container.
Right.
And the whole page as you scroll down is kind of split up into these sections, if you will.
And those are all almost like mini heroes, right?
The same idea here.
When I create a hero, I want to represent this big chunk right here.
All right.
And then inside there, we're going to start building out the individual elements like our headline,
this prompt and our form and things like that.
All right.
So let me go to my Visual Studio code text editor and let's go ahead and create a new component in our
SLC Components folder.
Right now, I'm just stuffing all of my components in here, but we might organize them in a better
way later.
And I'm going to call this component hero view.
All right.
By this point, this should hopefully be familiar.
Let's go ahead and wire up a view component.
I'm going to create a template tag before I forget.
I'm going to wire up a script tag below it.
And in our template tag, we have to place some content.
What I'm actually going to use here is an element called Main that is basically like a div, but it's
used to identify, especially for things like search engines and search engine optimization.
It's used to identify the main section or the main focus of the page.
So our content really begins with our hero, right?
Not really the nav or the sub.
Now that's the primary focus point of our page.
Our main content is here where the user can actually see the prompt, where we're inspiring them to
apply to our company and then provide us with their role and their location.
Right?
That's the core functionality.
That's the beating heart of this website.
So that is the main content.
So I'm going to wrap that in a main tag instead of a regular do.
And in here, I'm also going to apply a section tag because there may be multiple sections in here.
And again, a section is again very similar to a div identical basically when it comes to the technical
implementation, it's just a box on the screen, but it's a little bit more semantically correct because
it identifies that we are breaking something up, not just into a box, but into a section that may
potentially be one of many different sections, distinct pieces of organization or logic.
Within this higher level container.
You can basically think of it as a dead within divs, but just with a little bit more semantically better
names.
And in here, I'm just going to put some arbitrary text that we can double check that this is appearing
on our screen.
And I'm just going to write I Can Be Your Hero, Baby.
It's a throwback to an early 2000s pop hit.
Okay.
So the other thing I want to do in my script section is export default, a JavaScript object.
And here I'm just going to provide a named property and I'm going to call this component hero.
Let's add a line break at the very end, and that looks good to me.
So now, of course, I want to render this component somewhere and we're not going to render it in May
now because this is not actually part of the main NAV.
This is right below the main now.
So if I actually go to my app component, we have not been here in a while, but as a reminder, this
is the launching point for our entire view app.
This is where everything kicks off and all this component is doing right now is just rendering the main
nav component.
So what I can do is simply render the main nav and then try to render my hero directly below it.
And let's see if that works out.
So right here I'm going to import my hero component from at components hero dot view.
And then of course I had to register as a local component in my app component so that my app component
can render it.
So now we can render the here a component anywhere in my template.
Generally, it's considered best practice to not have multiple what they call root elements, which
means we don't just want to put hero side by side here with May NAV because there's multiple top level
elements, so to speak, or multiple top level components.
The general best practice is to only have one most top level element in any given template.
So in other words, what I'm trying to say here is we can wrap these two components inside a larger
div, just so that we have one top level parent element that is kicking everything off.
And so we have one root of the pyramid, if you will.
So right here, I'm just going to wrap these two in a div and that ensures that we will have only one
root in this component that may not be even technically required in view anymore, but it's generally
best practice.
So you can easily focus your eyes as well and say, okay, I know what this component is.
It's just a container, a div, and it must contain some additional components within it.
Okay, so now we have our main nav component being rendered and we're rendering the hero component below
it.
So in theory, it should appear below it.
But let's see what happens when I navigate to my browser.
Well, as it turns out, unfortunately, we do not see our hero.
Right?
That's nowhere to be found.
Even if I tried to expose my sub, now it's nowhere to be found.
So is it not rendering on the page?
Well, let's dive into our chrome console and let's go into my elements, Inspector.
And if I go here, here is my top level div with the idea of apps.
So this is where my view app launches itself.
And there we have a div that is our top level div that is rendering the main NAV as well as the hero
that we just created.
And then we get into the HTML for our main NAV.
So here we actually do see our main element that we just added.
And if I open this up, here is our section with I can be your hero baby.
So it looks like everything is actually correctly being rendering, being rendered on the screen.
But unfortunately, our content is being hidden behind the fixed nav that our main nav is rendering.
So we're going to see how we can fix this problem in the very next lesson.