Okay.
So I promise that we'll return to this code momentarily to start writing our first code.
But I did want to show you this feature in The Real World on the Google Careers website.
You'll notice here on the left hand sidebar, we have all of these categories, and I can expand any
one of them independently to have a list of checkboxes that I can select.
And as soon as I select one, for example, bachelors right here and part time right here, we're going
to see the jobs on the right hand side.
Filter themselves to only include these categories.
So in other words, these are the jobs that have a bachelor's requirement that are part time.
All right.
The first thing we're going to start building out in this section is this kind of top level header right
here.
What do you want to do as well as the clear filters button?
It may be a little while before we get back to all of this, but I do want to start building this basically
from top to bottom.
So if I click the clear filters button, by the way, that is going to remove all of those filters.
And then once that is complete, I can also collapse each respectable accordion like so by clicking
that carrot.
So as many times as I want, I can expand it and then collapse it.
All right.
And where we are currently in our app is we have this sidebar section kind of delineated and marked
out, but we have to start building it out to have all those accordions right here.
So that's where we're going to be moving towards.
So with that said, let me go back to the code and let me open up a file we have not touched in a while
and it's going to be the job filters sidebar.
This is the code that creates that left hand sidebar with a certain with right here and right now it
has nothing in it.
So let's start adding some content.
I'm going to remove this text of job from the sidebar and I'm going to add a section and I'm immediately
going to provide a Tailwind class right here.
I'm going to add some padding on the bottom with the PB five class padding bottom of 1.25 ram or equivalently
20 pixels.
And in here I'm going to create a div and I'm going to make this a Flexbox.
So I'll attach the flex class and I want my flex children to be arranged in a row.
So I'm going to add the flex row class.
And finally, I want to space out the children with equal spacing in between.
So I'm going to use the justify it between talent class and that is going to create spacing, equal
spacing between all of my flex children.
I'm only going to have to flex children within my flex box and they are going to be an three as well
as another div.
Okay.
On the H3, we're going to add a couple more classes right here.
I'm going to add some margin on the Y axis.
So only going up and down using the M Y series of classes margin wide.
And so I'm going to do my four to add 16 pixels of margin on the top and 16 pixels of margin on the
bottom.
The next thing I want to do is a class called tax base that's just going to use the default font size
of 16 pixels.
And then I want to have a little bit of bolding.
So I'm going to add the font semi bold class that is going to give it a font weight of 600.
So a little bit of bolding.
And here's where I'm going to write my text, the exact same text we have on the Google Careers website,
which is What do you want to do?
All right.
Afterwards, we have our dev on this.
Dev.
I'm going to create another Flexbox.
I want to vertically align the flex children of this Flexbox.
So I'm going to apply the items center class.
And finally, I want a little bit of a smaller text for the children inside.
So I'm going to use the text as some class and that gives it a little bit of a smaller font size 14
pixels inside this div.
I actually want to use a button and I want to reuse the action button component that we've used previously
in the course.
So how do we wire up another component?
This may be a little bit of a review, but in our script section we have to import the component we'd
like to use.
So in this case, I'm going to import action button and that comes from our source directory components
shared.
And that's where we have our action button component.
And then in order to register it with my job filter sidebar, I have to add that component's property
set to an object.
And here I'm just going to provide action button which allows me to use action button anywhere in the
template of my job filter sidebar.
So within this div, right here is where I'm going to render my action button component with a self-closing
tag and an action button component.
As a reminder, I'm going to open it right here on the right hand side.
It requires two props.
It needs a text prop, which is the actual text that the button displays, and then a type prop which
specifies the type of button we have a primary button and a secondary button.
And in this scenario, we actually want a secondary button.
That's the style we want, and that will avoid the default prop value of primary.
So right here, I'm going to provide my text prop and I'm going to provide it with a string of clear
filters.
And then for my type prop, I'm going to provide a string of secondary.
And because these are basic string arguments, we do not need to use the V bind syntax.
In other words, the colon.
We can just provide regular string arguments, save that.
And if I go back to my browser, we can see we're starting to build out that top level functionality.
What do you want to do?
As well as the Clear Filters button, it does have a little bit of a different style compared to the
Google career site when I hover over it, but I'm okay with that for now.
We've sort of built out this top level navigation of our sidebar, and we can move on to building our
accordion components in the follow up lesson.