Okay.
So attached to this lesson as a resource, you'll find a DB that JSON file and DB is short for database.
So what I'd like for you to do is to download that DB JSON file and place it at the top level of your
job search project.
So you can see right here, I have my file explorer open in this code.
And here is where I have my DB, that JSON file alongside all of the other configuration files.
All right.
So go ahead and download that, put that into your project and then it will take a quick minute to talk
about exactly what this file is doing for us.
So this is going to serve as our data for our mock back, and this is what JSON server makes it super
easy to do, and that is to define a fictional endpoint on a server and then have our app hit that endpoint
and just get back data in the form of JSON.
So let me collapse this file so you can see exactly what's going on.
You'll notice that in this file, which is more than 2500 lines, there is just one top level key,
which is jobs set to an array.
And what this key is, is the endpoint that we want to establish on our Jason server.
So our JSON server is going to be running in our terminal on a separate port.
Our view app is running an 8080 while JSON server is going to run on our port 3000.
So you can almost think of it like two different apps running on our computer at the same time.
And our goal is for The View app to hit the JSON server app, right.
And so the key that is here that defines the endpoint that we want to have on that server.
So because our JSON server is running on localhost 3000, we're going to be able to go to local host
3000 slash jobs.
And when we do that, we're going to get this response back, this array of tons of data representing
our jobs.
So this name is totally up to us.
For example, if we had users here, that would make our end point slash users.
And if we had, you know, nonsense here, that would make our End Point slash nonsense.
And you can have as many endpoints as you want on your fake server.
So I'm going to change this back to jobs.
And then of course, what this will return is an array of 100 objects and each one represents a simple
job.
And we're going to be using these objects to render job listings in our app.
Just to quickly walk you through what all of these attributes are, properties are on a job.
We have a unique ID for the job.
It's identifier.
We have its title.
We have the organization and organization assault.
So sort of like a small sub company within the larger company.
So Google has something like six or seven smaller companies within it that you can filter when you look
for jobs in their site.
Similar idea here you have the degree requirement.
For example, master's or bachelors, you have the job type, for example, intern full time, part
time, etc. You have locations which is actually going to be an array of one or more strings, and each
string represents a city.
So these are the possible cities where you can have this job or applied to this job.
And then we have two arrays, one for a minimum qualifications and the other for preferred qualifications.
Now the preferred qualifications array is really only going to be used on an individual job page.
So on the Google career site, if you click into a job, you'll see both the minimum qualifications
and the preferred ones.
We're not going to be showing these preferred qualifications on the page where we see all the jobs,
but they're here in case you want to display information for a single job.
Then similarly we have description and this is just going to be a couple of sentences about the job
and we're going to add this together to the job listing.
And then finally they added it, which reflects the fictional date that this job was added to our job
service.
And we basically have 100 objects like this in our jobs array.
So there we can see A2, 83, 84, 85 all the way to 100, and they each have all this random data.
So I make it make it really easy for you to kind of have the sample data to work with.
We don't have to generate any data.
We don't have to create 100 job listings on our page.
We're going to be hitting this fictional back and we're going to have it return this array of jobs,
and then we're going to render 100 job listings on the screen from it.
That's all there is to it.
Jason Stavros is going to make that super easy for us.
So the next thing we have to do is to set up a Jason server.
And in order to do that, we want to go to our package JSON file.
And what we're going to need to add is a script to launch Jason Server.
Remember, it is a separate library, it is a totally different ecosystem from Vue.
And so we need this thing running in the background so that the View app can hit this server.
So what we're going to do is add a new key called backend and this name is up to us.
I'm just going to call it backend.
So this means we're going to run NPM, run back in from a terminal and the command we want to run is
this.
First we're going to use JSON dash server that is now available within our project because we installed
it in the previous lesson.
And then I want to add a special flag here, which is Dash, Dash watch very much like the just watch
flag.
What this will do is it's going to monitor our DB that Jason filed for changes so that if we update
that file this will automatically update as well so that the server relaunches and we get the most up
to date data so we don't have to go back and relaunch Jason's server from the terminal every time we
make a change.
DB Jason, it will be done automatically.
And then the final thing we need to add here is just the name of the file that is going to provide the
data to Jason Server.
And that of course is simply DB that JSON.
And since it is in the same directory, we can type it out like so and that will work out of the box.
All right.
So that says that everything we need in the very next lesson, we're going to get the server up and
running and we're going to actually make this request in the browser so you can see exactly how it works.
So lots of fun to look forward to and I will see you in the next lesson.