Okay.
So just a quick note on the components that we're going to create over the course of the next couple
of lessons.
If you look at the job results page on the official Google Careers website, you'll notice there's two
distinct sections.
There is this sidebar here where we have the filters for the jobs such as the job, location, the degree,
the type, etc..
I'm going to call this section or this component.
The Job Filters Sidebar component.
It is a sidebar.
It is not part of the main content and its job is to provide filters.
So I will call it the job filters, sidebar.
And then this main area right here with the gray background that has all of the results.
I'm going to call that the job listings component because it stores all of the job listings.
All right.
So we're going to start with those two top level components.
We're going to render both of them on our job results view.
And then later on, we're going to start building out smaller components for things like an individual
job listing itself.
So let me navigate back to the code.
And here we have my file explorer.
We have our source directory components.
I'm going to create a new feature folder for our job results page or our job results feature to be more
specific.
So right here in components, let's create a new directory and I'll call it job results, and then I'm
going to start doing something new.
I'm going to start nesting additional folders within a feature folder.
There's nothing necessarily limiting us to just one top level folder inside components.
We can nest as much as we want for the purposes of organization.
So in job results, I'm going to create a new folder itself called Job Filters Sidebar.
And this will deal with any components that have to deal with that sidebar on the left for filtering
jobs immediately within that folder.
Job Filter Sidebar.
I will create my top level job filters, sidebar components.
So this is going to be the one that kicks everything off on the left hand side.
But any related components that deal with the sidebar, I will also place within this same directory.
So let's call this component job filter a sidebar dot view and let's write some code.
So right here, let me blow this up.
We'll start with our template.
We'll keep things super simple for now.
So I'll just add a div that says job filter sidebar.
And of course, let us define our script section and export default to a JavaScript object with a name
property.
And I will give that name property job, filter, sidebar.
Let's add a line break right here.
And this is a good place to leave this component in its starting state.
Okay.
So the next thing I'd like to do is to render this job filter sidebar component in our job results view.
So I'm going to head to our views folder right here.
As a reminder, these are our top level pages, if you will.
These are the top level parent components that are going to kick everything off on a given root or a
given path.
So we want to access our job results view.
This is our page that will render below the NAV whenever we navigate to slash job slash results.
And we obviously have some additional leftover code here that we can basically delete.
This was just experimenting with Vue router.
So I'm going to get rid of this right here.
I'm going to get rid of this method and then let's import our new component and render it within our
template.
So in my script section, I'm going to import my new job filters sidebar component that is going to
come from my source directory components, job results, job filter, sidebar.
And then the component self is called job filter sidebar as well.
We also need to register it in our components object right here.
So we'll create that and registered job filter sidebar.
At this point, we should use it somewhere in our template.
So right inside this div I'm going to render with a self-closing tag the job filters sidebar component.
Closed it off like so and that should be enough.
So if I navigate to my browser and head back to my actual app and we go to the jobs page right here
at slash job slash results here we have that view being rendered and that is rendering our job filters
sidebar component.
So everything is looking as we expect.
If I navigate to my view dev tools, we'll see.
Here's our job results view and here is that job filter sidebar.
We do of course need to apply some styling later to make it occupy just a portion of the screen, but
that is a good place to start.
And in the very next lasting lesson, we can create the complimentary job listings component which will
render on the right side.
So I will see you there.