Okay.
So here I am back in our job search form component.
And as a reminder, when the user submits the form, in other words, when the user provides a role
and the location and clicks the search button, we run a method right here called Search for Jobs.
And that method down below is right here.
And what it does is it talks to the view router, which is available via the dollar sign router property
and it evokes the push method on the router to navigate the user to the job results page and also create
some query params based on the values that they have entered into the input fields which have also made
their way into the components data.
So they're basically wiring up the URL that they need to navigate the user to to show them the job results
that they care about.
So this presents an interesting challenge for us because we know in our setup method that we do not
have access to the this keyword and we also thus don't have access to the dollar sign router property
which represents the view router.
Right.
Remember in our old implementation, what Vue router does is it automatically makes itself available
on every component via this property the exact same way that, for example, view X makes its store
available via a this Vista dollar sign store.
But now we don't have the this keyword.
So where are we going to get our router from in order to emulate this functionality?
Well, as it turns out, we're going to be able to use helper functions from other libraries to give
us access to the pieces of data that we need.
So let me show you the solution right up top here.
I'm going to import a function not from view, but from the view router library.
And that function is called use router.
And make sure to import it from the View Router Library because it is not part of the core view library.
It is specifically related to view router, which is how we navigate around the app.
So these functions, these helper functions are called composable.
And basically what they allow us to do is get access to important pieces of information within our set
up method.
There's sort of these helper utility functions that we can invoke as needed in as many components as
needed.
They are reusable, so it works like you might expect in our setup method right here.
I'm going to invoke the use router function.
And what that is going to give back to me is the view router object automatically.
So I can simply assign this to a variable like connect router.
So this is the exact same object that I have represented here with this, the same router, and I can
use it in the exact same way.
So knowing that the rest of the steps should hopefully be pretty clear.
So we know that our component needs a search for jobs method or function to exist.
So we need to make sure we export or return something called search for jobs from this object right
here.
So right here, let's define that.
And as we know, to replace methods in the options API, we use plain JavaScript functions in the composition
API.
So right here, I'll define an arrow function in line.
I'll call it Search for jobs.
There's my arrow function.
And before we even write the body so we don't forget, let's just automatically provide search for jobs
right here so that it becomes available to the template.
All right.
It's as easy as that.
So now when the user submits the form, we're going to run these search for jobs logic that we define
in this function's body.
And here we want to copy the logic we have right here.
So we're going to take our router, we're going to call the push method, and then we're going to provide
the object that we see below.
So name represents the route name that we want to direct the user to.
We want to take him to the job results root and then remember the query property here creates the automatic
query params at the end of the URL.
So this is how we provide things like role equals, you know, developer and location equals New York.
This is what we attach to the end of the URL string when we go to the job results page.
So we're going to need to create the exact same two properties that we see below role and location.
The question is how do we get the current piece of information that we need right here?
While you might think it would be as simple as role, and that's a good way to start.
Unfortunately, it's not quite correct because remember, role is not just the plain string from what
the users type into the input.
Role is a reactive object that is monitoring a string in order to actually get the up to date value
of that string inside that reactive object.
We have to use the dot value property.
So that value will give us the actual string whenever a search for jobs executes, which will be whenever
the user submits the form, at which point the role and location reactive objects will have the most
up to date string from the most up to date user input in the text fields.
So similarly, I'm going to add on location and to get that piece of information, I'm going to talk
to my location reactive object that's returned by the ref function.
On that object we have a value property to get what we what we care about.
And once again, even though we're using value here, when we use role and location in our template
right here, we do not need to provide the value extension because view knows automatically how to make
that connection with the actual HTML template.
We only need to use that value right here in our JavaScript section.
So with that we have defined the function that's going to run.
When we submit the form, we have made sure to return it right here.
So we have replaced all of the original functionality that we have here.
So we can go ahead and remove the data method and the methods object right here and there we go.
Now the component is using the new composition API.
And once again the benefit is that we can see a lot of the data together.
We can see that it's being used right here.
We can lump together pieces of functionality together and just to show you that everything is working,
I'm going to take you to the browser right now.
So here's my role.
Let's type in something like developer.
Let's type in a location like NYC.
And when I navigate using the search button, everything is still working.
We are correctly navigating the user using Vue router, which means that use router function worked
as expected and we are still creating the correct query params.
Using that app object, we provide it to the query property and also that means that we are getting
the right most up to date string values from the text inputs on the previous page and providing them
right here.
So we haven't created any new functionality, but we have updated our old component to now use the composition
API.
Everything is still working.
All right, so whenever you need to use router functionality in a component is simply import the use
router function from Vue router, you invoke it in the body of your setup method and it's going to give
you a reactive router object that you can then work with in the body of your setup method.
And with that, I will see you in the next lesson.