Okay.
So before we start working on our action button component, there is one point that I'd like to reiterate
that I mentioned earlier in the course, and that is that each view component is independent.
That means it tracks its own data, its own state, independent of what other components are doing.
And that is a good thing because it prevents one components changes from accidentally affecting another
component.
Each one is its own isolated island, and each one keeps track of its own internals, its own data,
etc..
So for example, here we have our main NAV component, and if I scroll down here as a reminder, we
have this data method which configures the data that the component has and can use in its template.
And currently in our app component, we are rendering one main nav component.
We'll imagine that we rendered three main nav components side by side.
We'd have three nav bars right next to each other.
So what would happen is in that scenario, each one of those main nav view components would receive
a separate copy of this data to put it in another two terms.
Or in other words, the three main components would not share one data object.
Rather, they would each get their own copy, their own isolated chunk of this data, which means that
the changes in data in one main NAV, such as, for example, the triggering of the log in user method
would not affect any other main nav components.
Let me show you this in action.
And just for this lesson, you do not have to follow along since I'm going to revert all the changes
that I make anyway.
This is purely for the sake of example.
So what I'm going to do here very quickly is I'm going to remove some CSS classes.
This is just to ensure that our main NAV components can render side by side with each other.
So I'm going to remove these classes right here and then I'm going to navigate to my app dot view component.
And here is where we are importing the main nav component and rendering it once in the screen.
So I'm going to copy and paste this code two more times below and save.
So now we have three main nav components rendering side by side and that is totally valid in view because
of course the benefit of view is just this.
We have these reusable chunks of the UI that we can use as often as we want and we do not have to rewrite
the HTML for them again.
So if I go to my browser now, I will predictably have three separate main nav components being rendered
and here in my view devtools, I can actually see them side by side here.
Here's the first one, here's the second one and here's the third one.
And you'll notice for each main nav component, the view devtools is going to show us the data on the
right hand side.
This data again is independent and isolated to each respective main nav component.
So what do you think is going to happen?
When I go to my first main nav and I click the sign in button and trigger a change to the is logged
in property.
Well, let's take a look on the very first component we're going to change the value of the is logged
in property to true which will cause a view to re render that component and replace the sign in button
with a profile image.
However, notice that the is logged in property for the other main nav components is still going to
be false and that is expected behavior and good behavior because as I mentioned, each component is
isolated and independent from each other.
So we can't accidentally do a thing here and accidentally have it pollute or affect us.
Totally different component elsewhere.
The components are each reusable, independent, isolated chunks of the UI and so changes in one do
not affect the other.
So similarly, if I were to go to my third main nav and click this time and button, that would change
the internal data or the internal state of this main nav component.
The third one, but the second one still keeps its original state, and in fact the first one still
keeps its original state as well, because the first one has also not been affected by the click of
this former button right here.
All right.
That's all there is to take away from this lesson.
It's that the components keep their own independent state.
They are all isolated.
They each have an independent copy of the data.
We still have to define the data because we define what information that component should contain inside
it.
That might change and that might affect the UI, whether it be through things like interpolation or
directives.
But each component keeps its own copy of that logic, its own methods, its own data, etc. And that's
an important thing to know as we start building a lots of reusable components that we can use over and
over.
We don't have to worry about one change accidentally affecting other components of the same type.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.