Okay.
So in this lesson, we'll create a new header containing a component whose responsibility it will be
to center a bunch of content.
And of course, that content will be dynamically provided using the slot component and the parent component
giving whatever it wants.
All right.
So as a quick heads up, I am starting to record this lesson and probably all follow up lessons on a
new computer.
So it's possible that there may be some visual mismatches in voice code.
I apologize for that.
But the view content itself is going to stay the same.
So for some reason the colors don't fit or the font looks a little bit off, or the theme has a bunch
of different colors here and there.
Again, I apologize for that.
It's a technical requirement because my old computer is not working very well.
All right.
So with that said, I am going to open up my source directory, my components folder, my shared folder,
and here I'm going to create my new view component.
I'm going to call it header container, dot view.
It represents a header stored in a container that centers that content.
All right.
So as always, we're going to need a template and we're going to need a script section.
And we can knock out script right now.
So I'm going to export default and object with a name property.
And that name property will be equal to header container perfect.
And then within my template, I'm going to create a top level div and I'm immediately going to add some
tailwind classes to it.
We're going to make this Occupy 100% of the parents with by giving the full class.
Then I want to add a border on the bottom.
So I'm going to use border B to do that.
I want my border to be solid.
So I will add the border solid class and I want to use the brand gray, one color that I specified in
my tailwind config file.
So I'm going to add border brand gray one that is an automatically available class.
Then within this div, I'm going to add another div and I'm going to provide some classes here as well.
I'm going to center this div by providing margin on the left and right hand side as much as the browser
wants to add to center this in the middle and I'm going to add the Amex auto class or margin auto class
on the X axis.
In order to do that, I also want to add some margin on the top and bottom.
So I'm going to add the AM Y margin on the Y axis classes.
I'm going to do m y 16, which should give me a 64 pixels of margin on the top and 64 pixels of margin
on the bottom.
And then perhaps the most important class here, I'm going to add the text center class, which will
add a text line of center to whatever content I place inside this div.
And of course that is going to be the dynamic content.
And as we mentioned here, we don't just want one slot, we want to one is going to be for the top level,
the title, if you will, the primary text or whatever content my, my parent component wants to give
me.
And then I'm going to create another slot for the subtitle, the second bit of content underneath.
All right.
So I'm going to start with my top little slot, the exact same syntax we introduced in the previous
section.
However, the difference here is I'm going to give my slot a name and the way I do so is with a name
prop.
So right here in line is going to provide a name prop and I think an appropriate name here is something
like title.
This is the title content.
And then if I want to provide any default or fallback content, we know how to do that.
Now we're going to do that right here in between the opening and closing slot tag.
So maybe we can do something like sample title.
And again, Vue is only going to use this fallback content if the parent component does not provide
anything for this slot.
All right.
Now, what about for a second slot?
Well, it's going to be the exact same syntax.
We're going to open up a new slot component.
We're going to close it and then we're going to give it a name prop set to a totally different value.
So how about here we give it a name of subtitle.
And we'll give it some fallback content like sample subtitle.
So what we have enabled now is a parent component to be able to provide not one but two custom pieces
of HTML to inject right here.
And of course, we're not obligated to have our slots right next to each other.
We can have a slot here.
Then we can have some more HTML in between right here.
And then we can have an additional slot below.
And that is the real power of this design and view is you can keep that commonality in your component,
but also define multiple sections or slots where you can plug in custom content.
That's why it's called a slot, because it represents a portion of the UI or a portion of the component
that you can slot in that you can stick a piece of HTML into.
Right.
Just like the word slot means in your everyday use.
It's a place to put something.
So here we have two slots right next to each other and the parent component will be able to provide
both of them or either of them or none of them because we have some fallback content to rely on in case
they don't.
All right.
So we've set up the basics of this component.
And in the very next couple of lessons, we're going to start using this component throughout our app.