Okay.
So welcome to the official TypeScript playground.
As a reminder, you can access this web page by going to typescript lang dawg slash play.
And here's how this application works.
On the left hand side, we have a code editor, and in here we can write valid typescript code immediately
as soon as we write our typescript code.
The right hand side will show us the resulting compiled JavaScript.
So this on the right hand side is the JavaScript coming from our typescript.
Keep in mind there is a lot of valid TypeScript code that is going to look very similar to existing
a JavaScript code.
So here's a perfect example and here you can see they're declaring a concept and then they're console.log
it and the JavaScript equivalent is exactly the same.
So many times TypeScript and JavaScript will look virtually identical.
However, as a reminder, TypeScript allows us additional syntax that we can do, and that syntax will
not be shown in the JavaScript side of things.
In addition, on this right hand panel here, there's a couple of helpful things you can do here.
So right here we can see there's an errors tab where you can see any violations in TypeScript in your
code.
And here is the logs section.
Whenever you run the file on the left, all the console logs will appear here on the right.
So, for example, if I press the run button right here, we're going to see that console log of Hello
World appear right here.
All right.
But the most important part of this page is really looking at the resulting JavaScript.
Okay.
One other thing before we start writing some code, you'll notice here there is the choice of the TypeScript
version that you want to run.
Most modern versions of TypeScript introduce new features, but the coarse syntax of the language,
the real fundamentals that we care about are basically going to stay the same.
So we don't really have to worry about the exact version number.
And if yours doesn't match mine, that's totally fine.
Just select the latest version you see here, because why not work with the the latest and greatest,
right?
So with that said, let's delete all the code on the left hand side and let's write a sample JavaScript
variable assignment.
So what I'm going to do here is declare a first name variable and I'll assign it to my name of Burrus.
You are more than welcome to you.
Of course, write your own name instead.
So notice again on the right hand side that the equivalent JavaScript is exactly the same.
So what can we do in TypeScript that we cannot do in JavaScript?
What we could do is assign types or annotate types.
Basically what that means is we're going to tell the programming language, the type of something in
our program.
So if I want to tell TypeScript that first name is a string and will always be a string.
Here's what that syntax looks like, and it's going to be a uniform syntax for all of TypeScript.
After the thing that we are declaring, we put a colon and then a space, and that space is just for
aesthetics.
And then we write the actual data type.
So in this case, this is a string which I'm going to write in all lowercase.
So again, a type like a string is not a concrete value, right?
Boris is a concrete value.
String is a type five is a concrete value number is a type.
We're describing the data type.
We're not describing the implementation.
So in this case, we have told TypeScript that first name will always be a strength.
So take a look at what happens if I try to reassign first name to some something else of a wrong data
type, such as a number in JavaScript.
This would be totally valid code, but in TypeScript it is not permitted.
So if I hover my mouse, you can see TypeScript tells us that type number, which is the type of five,
is not assignable to the type of string.
That's what you promised me when you declared what first name was going to be right.
As another example, if we try to do some kind of operation with a string that is not promise, permissive
or allowed, TypeScript is going to complain.
So for example, if we tried to multiply our string by a number, this is totally valid code in JavaScript.
And when I say valid, I don't mean that it's not going to trigger an error.
It probably will trigger an error, but not until we actually run the code.
In comparison, TypeScript will tell us there's an error before the file even runs and we have to fix
it in order for TypeScript to compile and allow itself to be run.
So right here you can see it's going to say the left hand side of an arithmetic operation must be of
some type, including number.
So a string is not a valid thing that we can multiply by.
As another example, let's say we have a file that is 100 lines long and we declared first name way
up above.
And let's see, we get confused and think that it is an array instead of a string.
We may try to invoke a method like push which only exists on an array.
And once again TypeScript will tell us, Hey, the property push does not exist on the type string which
you told me first name.
It's right.
And that's where TypeScript really shines.
Now, of course, you might be looking at a really simple and contrived example like this and saying,
Yeah, but that's kind of obvious.
I'm not going to make stupid mistakes, like reassigning first name to a value of five, and you are
absolutely correct.
But where TypeScript is really going to shine is when we have a lot of complex nested data structures.
That's where it becomes really easy to get confused.
So imagine you have, for example, a function that returns a promise that resolves to be an array of
objects.
Each of those objects having ten properties and one of those properties being an array of strings.
Right?
It's in those situations where you might.
Make mistakes like accessing a property on the wrong object or forgetting that you have an array instead
of an object here, or vice versa.
It's when you're dealing in that nested complexity that TypeScript is going to be a lot smarter than
us and warned us when we're making simple mistakes like this.
Obviously, when we have two lines in our editor, it's not as apparent, but promise.
But I promise you, believe me, I'm really large projects.
TypeScript is going to catch you a lot of times.
There's many times where I've been coding and typed which are told me, Hey, that thing that you think
is, you know, type X is actually type Y.
And it forced me to recalibrate and realize where my mistake was.
All right.
So let me show you a couple more examples of this annotation syntax.
Let's say I have a number and let's call it age and assign it to the age variable.
I'm just going to make it 30.
Once again, the way we annotate a type is we put a colon, then the type afterwards.
So for example, for a number we just write lowercase number.
For a boolean, it's the exact same syntax.
So for example, I can have a variable called is handsome.
I'll set that to a boolean boolean like so and then I'll sign it to a value of true.
And the same rules apply.
So if I try to assign as handsome to false, that's going to be totally valid because that is a boolean.
If I tried to assign a to something like an array, then TypeScript is going to complain because it's
going to say, hey, an array is not of type boolean, so I'm not going to permit it.
All right.
One other cool thing about this annotation.
Syntax is we don't need to assign an initial value.
If we give it a type annotation, for example, this syntax in line three, TypeScript knows it has
a variable that must be a boolean.
So it's not going to allow anything else.
It's just going to complain because now we've told it that it has to be a boolean throughout the program,
so we can't make mistakes like this.
Finally, to close this lesson off, I just want to show you two special examples, which is undefined
and null.
The thing that makes those two unique is that the type is actually going to be the exact same as the
value.
That is an exception to this example right here because undefined is both an actual value in JavaScript
and it's type in TypeScript is undefined as well.
There is no parent category, right in the same way that you can have infinite strings and they're all
going to have different numbers of characters and say different words, but they're all strings where
similarly an infinite number of numeric values, but they're all a type number undefined in JavaScript
is kind of its own construct.
There's nothing that is, you know, it doesn't have a parent category or any related siblings or anything
like that.
So the type of undefined is undefined.
The way that's going to look is the exact same as the syntax above.
So for example, if I have a variable like what the future holds.
I can assign it a type of undefined and then actually give it the value of undefined and that will work
just fine.
And the exact same rules apply for NULL.
So for example, if I have available call nothing.
I'm going to assign another type of null and assign a value of no.
So these are kind of general exceptions to the rule that a type is not the same thing as a value.
In this in this two scenarios, it's kind of little bit more blurry, but it hopefully makes sense because
these are JavaScript related constructs, while string number and even boolean is a little bit more
open ended.
Even Boolean has two possible values true and false, undefined and null can only really be themselves.
So that's why the type is the exact same as the value.
All right.
That's really all there is to cover in this lesson.
And that's really the heart of what TypeScript helps you with.
And we're going to keep exploring more of this language in this playground over the course of the next
couple of lessons.
So I'll see you there.