Okay.
So the next component that I want us to focus on is job listings.
It's going to take us a couple of lessons to refactor this component, to use the composition API,
because it has a lot of things going on inside it.
So as a quick reminder, this is the component that renders all of the job listings on the right hand
side.
It gets that from display jobs, which we'll talk about in just a second.
And this is also the component that renders the buttons on the bottom that navigate to either the previous
page or the next page.
As we can see when we scroll down, there is a lot of logic to this component.
We're using a getter right here.
We have a whole bunch of computed properties to calculate the current page, the previous page number,
the next page number, and then the display jobs, which as a reminder, is the ten jobs that depend
on the page that we're on.
So even after our filter jobs getter gets those jobs, we then narrow them down to the right.
Ten.
On the first page we show the first ten.
On the second page we show 11 to 20 and so on.
Then we also have a async mounted lifecycle hook where we're calling a method called fetch jobs.
And Fetch Jobs is actually a View X action.
So we haven't talked about how to deal with actions yet in the composition API.
As a reminder, an action is basically an asynchronous method that does some kind of logic, and then
when that async logic is done, it commits a mutation.
So in this case, this action in view X makes the actual async request to fetch our jobs, and then
it commits a separate mutation to save those jobs to the View X Store.
So we're going to replace all of this logic using the composition API.
And in this lesson, I want to begin with this section right here, our mounted lifecycle hook and the
action that it is dispatching.
So right here, as always, we're going to comment out everything we have.
And then oops not delete the comment.
I have to be very careful with my silly fingers.
Okay, so right here I'm going to define my setup method.
And we know that we're going to need a couple of things.
First up, in order to talk to the store.
We're going to need to get the view store, which we can get using the use store function.
And then we're also going to need to run something on component mount.
So we're going to need to import the same function we used in the previous lesson, which is on Mount
It.
So at the very top, I'm going to import.
On mounted and that's going to come from view that is a core view function.
And then on the line below where I'm currently importing map actions and map getters, we're no longer
using those.
So I'm just going to remove that and instead I'm going to import use store.
All right, so here in the body of my setup method, I'm going to get access to my store by invoking
use store.
And then the question is, what do we pass into our on mounted function invocation?
So here is where we pass the function that we want the component to run.
Whenever it mounts in this case, we want the component to do is to run an action or dispatch an action
is the technical term and that action is called fetch jobs.
So as a quick, quick reminder, because I realize that might be helpful, here is the async fetch jobs
action that we want to dispatch.
It's going to get the jobs and it's going to commit the mutation.
So you may recall that map actions here, which gives us a method called fetch jobs on the component
that is running the action.
You may recall that map actions is a little bit of syntactic sugar over something we're able to do by
ourselves in the same way that map getters makes it super easy to define a getter in the same way that
map states does, not mutations does the same thing.
Map actions behind the scenes is calling a method on the store called dispatch, and dispatch accepts
an argument of the actual mutation we want to run or I'm sorry, the action that we want to run, because
dispatching is for asynchronous actions while committing is for synchronous mutations.
That's the difference between actions and mutations.
So we use the dispatch method for an action and the name of our action here is fetch jobs.
And we already have the constant imported for that action.
So this is basically what I want to do.
Whenever the component mounts, I want to dispatch the async action to the View Store.
The book store will take care of running that async operation, fetching our jobs, saving it, and
then those jobs are going to come back to this component once we get access to them through filter jobs.
So what I'm going to do is store all of this in a function.
So right here I'm going to declare an error function in line called fetch jobs.
I'm just going to make it an arrow function in line and I'm going to implicitly return the value returned
by this.
Not that we need it, but it doesn't really hurt.
Doesn't offer any advantage or disadvantage.
The point is that I now have a named arrow function called fetch jobs, and that's what I want to run
whenever job listings mounts.
So I'm simply going to provide fetch jobs here in line.
We do not need to invoke it.
Just provide the function or the procedure that you want view to run whenever it mounts the component.
So once again, if you are going to mount the component, it's going to run fetch jobs.
Fetch jobs is going to dispatch an action.
The action will take care of the actual asynchronous API request.
All right.
So this brings us a little bit forward.
So with that, we are good to remove our former mounted lifecycle hook and our method.
We no longer need that logic.
And in the very next lesson, we will continue chipping away at this and removing some of this former
options API functionality and replacing it instead with our composition API.
So I will see you there.