Okay.
So here I am in my job listings component and as a reminder it is in the mounted lifecycle look that
we are making the request to our MOC back into our JSON server.
Here is where we're wiring up the URL.
We're fetching it with Axios and then once we get that response of jobs, we're saving it to the local
jobs data property on this component.
So this is the logic right here that I want to extract.
And one place where I want to move this logic is the view store, but another place that I want to move.
This logic is to a separate helper function that's just going to take care of the actual API request
itself.
So this part right here.
So let's wire up the files we need for that.
And then we're going to try building out most of this using a TDD or test driven development approach
just because it's been a little while since we use that and I do want us to flex that muscle when we
have the opportunity.
So what I'm going to do here is in my project directory, in my source folder, I'm going to create
a new folder called API.
And so this folder is going to have a bunch of helper files.
Each one will make a request to a different endpoint.
Right now we only have one end point in JSON server in our backend, which represents the jobs end point.
So for now, I'm just going to create a single file in here and that file is going to be the name of
our eventual function that will also do the job of fetching the jobs.
So I'm going to call that file and that function get jobs.
So right here, I'm going to call this file, get jobs, jobs.
Eventually, it's going to use this code we have right here.
But we'll get to that in just a moment.
So before we move further, I do want to make sure that I create the corresponding test file for my
eventual API function.
So in my tests unit directory, we're not testing the component or the store or anything like that.
So I want to create a new folder in here called API.
I'm once again going to mirror the directory structure I have in my source directory.
And just like I have a file right here called Get Jobs in this API folder in my test directory, I'll
create a new file called Get Jobs that test docs.
All right.
And let me move it to the right hand side here, and I'm going to keep my implementation on the left
hand side.
Right now, we're getting a failing test suite, but that's simply because we have no tests to run.
So I do want to give you a quick reminder of how marking works, because we're going to be marking out
Axios in our test the exact same way that we market Axios.
Whenever we test the job listings component, we don't actually want to make a real request to our mock
backend in a test because number one, that takes time and number two, that makes the test complex
because we have to spin up a separate backend to be able to receive that request.
And number three, you know, that async request can go wrong.
It can take 5 seconds, it can severely slow down the speed of our test suite.
So whenever we're testing something asynchronous, we basically need to pretend as if we made an API
request, but then intercept it and immediately just return our own mock data, the exact same principles
that we've talked about earlier in the course.
So I just want to show you here, this is a reminder of something we talked about earlier.
If I import Axios from Axios, Axios is the NPM library that we added that allows us to make API requests.
And if we console.log Axios right here, we're going to see that we're going to get the original Axios
object.
This is the actual complex JavaScript object that we're getting from the real world implementation of
the Axios library.
This is some other developers code and as a reminder, we can use this syntax right here on the global
gest object that we have available in every test file.
We have that just object.
It has a method called MOC and we can pass a string argument of Axios right here.
And what that is going to do is mark out the properties of that imported Axios object.
And when I say mark out, what Jess is going to do is it's going to run through that real world library
and every time it sees a method, it's going to automatically replace it with a just mock function.
You may recall in the previous section we created a view store and then we manually overrode its commit
method to be adjust function.
This is the exact same idea, except Jess does it automatically for us.
So now, right here in our console.log, we can see instead of the former implementation, we have all
of the original methods from the original Axios library, such as get your I right here.
But the original implementation has been replaced with just mock functions and by default those mock
functions can track however many times they've been called with what arguments, etc. And when we invoke
those functions by default, by the way, they return undefined.
That's another important detail to know.
So I think that this is a good place to leave off.
It's just a good place to review the concepts that we learned about earlier in the course and in the
very next lesson, we can start using TDD to write our tests for the Get Jobs API search function.