All right.
So we ended the previous lesson with a little warning from S lint.
And if I hover my mouse over it, it's going to tell us unexpected v bind before the colon.
So let me first tell you that what we have here on screen is totally valid.
It is perfectly normal, healthy view syntax.
And I think it's best to introduce this syntax first because there's a little bit more explicit and
verbose.
We are binding some kind of data to our h of attribute.
With that said, View offers us a shortcut that we can use instead of the full V bind syntax.
And the shortcut is pretty simple.
All we do is remove v bind.
So I'm going to remove this and I'm still going to keep the colon.
All right.
So I'm going to save it.
And this is our final product.
So whenever we see a colon before an attribute in view, what that means is we are binding that value
of that attribute dynamically to something on our data.
It's the exact same idea.
It has an alternative syntax to what we just had with V bind.
It's actually the same directive under the hood.
It's just a little bit of a syntactical shortcut.
The View Style Guide, which is the kind of declarative guide on the Internet from the View Development
Team on how you should style your components.
That style guide recommends this approach because it is a little bit cleaner, although I will say the
most important aspect of your code base is consistency.
So if you prefer the V bind syntax, that's totally fine.
Sometimes I like more explicit things too, because they better communicate what the value is and somebody
can have a much easier time googling the bind and finding what it is compared to googling view.
Colon Right.
So I'm not necessarily going to say that this is a better approach, but we're going to be sticking
with this approach because s lint recommends it and so does the View Style guide.
But this is the exact same thing.
All right.
So either you bind or a colon before the attribute that you want to bind or connect to some piece of
your data.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.