All right, so let's practice a little bit with just syntax.
So here I am, back in verse code, and I'm going to create my first test file.
I'm going to do so in my tests unit directory.
So right here, I'm going to create a new file and I will call it playground dot, test dot, Jess.
So a few notes here before we proceed.
This playground, that test dogs file will be strictly for testing out various features of tests.
We're not actually going to dive into view testing just yet.
So later on we'll likely delete this file.
It only exists for educational purposes, much like our playground jazz file exists here for testing
out various JavaScript and view features.
Another important detail here is you'll notice that our file has a dot test.
Dot extension.
The way we configured our Jess config file earlier in the course allows us to have test files with two
extensions dot test that JS or dot specs.
Let me just write that out here so you can see it visually.
Dot, test, dot, J.S. and dot specs.
All right, so a plain JavaScript file with a JSS extension is not enough.
You need to prefix it with one of those two words test or spec when we run.
Just what it does is it looks throughout our project and identifies files with these extensions, and
that's how it knows that it is a test file and that it should run the code inside of it.
All right.
So let me go ahead and delete this code.
The next thing that you should know is when we run jest, it will automatically import the functions
that are available within the library that we're going to write in this file.
So we do not need to manually import anything from the just npm module.
Just will make the functions that we are about to write available to us.
In case you're curious about how can we just write these functions in line and invoke them?
It's because just will make them available.
So let's dive into the very first function and it's called Describe.
So I'm going to write out the function and I'm going to invoke it.
So the described function exists purely for organization or categorization.
It allows us to create a description for the thing that we are about to test.
So this is purely for our own organizational sake.
But you can imagine, for example, if we're testing some kind of view component, we might write something
like May NAV here in one test file and then in another test file we might describe another view component.
The idea is that we want to create some kind of category or organizational element.
You can almost think of it like a header or a chapter title in a book.
It's sort of the top level organizational name for what it is that we're about to test, because when
we run our just test suite, we're going to see a lot of different files being run and a lot of different
expectations and assertions, which we'll talk about shortly.
And so we want some kind of way to segment those outputs and categorize them.
And this is one way to do it.
It's with the described function.
So for now, we're not actually testing any actual view components.
So for now, I might describe that I'm testing, let's say, basic math.
I just want to test some basic math expressions using just right.
So the first argument to describe is a string of whatever you want, describing what you're testing.
Then the second argument is going to be a function.
So right here I'm going to define arrow function and I'm going to break it up onto the new line.
And here is where we can actually write an example of a test.
So a test begins with the function call.
So I t it.
And the reason it's called it is the first argument it expects is a string.
And here is where you actually declare in human readable terms, what is the specific thing you're testing.
So, for example, if my top level category is basic math, let's see, I'm trying to test addition
in an ingest so I might write a description like adds to numbers.
And the reason that the function is called it is specifically so that this line can read almost like
a sentence if we read it from left to right.
You can see it says it adds two numbers right and kind of makes sense.
And when we output this to our console, when we run the test, you'll see how all of this text appears
in a nice formatted and segmented way in our output.
So the ID function much like describe accepts a second argument which is also a function.
So right here I'm going to write my arrow function.
All right.
So here we are nesting this entire ID function call within our describe function, which is the second
argument to describe.
So make sure you have all of the correct opening and closing parentheses, etc..
And here within the IT function call is where we write what is called an assertion or an expectation.
So an expectation means that we expect something to happen, right?
So as an example, if I add the numbers one plus one, I expect the result to be two.
Right.
And so the way this works is we're going to introduce another function here called Expect.
And in expect we're going to put some kind of evaluation or expression or some kind of code, right?
It's whatever we want just to evaluate for us or run for us or execute for us.
So in a typical JavaScript work environment, this may be something like an object that we have and
we're going to call a method on it to produce some kind of return value.
Or we might access some kind of property on an object and check what its value is.
We can basically do anything, any valid JavaScript inside this expect function, and it's what we want
just to actually run for us.
So for now, I'm going to put the simplest thing I can think of, which is a basic mathematical expression.
Expect one plus one.
So of course, that is what we want just to run for us.
We also have to tell just what we expect the result to be, so that just can run that execution and
then compare it with the expected result.
So this expect function is going to give us back in object so we can invoke a method on the object.
And on that object we're going to have a whole bunch of different assertions which are also called matches,
and you could see the deal with all kinds of different ways that we can compare things.
So for example, we can do something like to be greater than to compare that what our expectation is
or what our evaluation is.
One plus one can be greater than something else, right?
So we're not just limited to strict equality here.
We can check for inequality.
We can check for rate greater than less than to be an instance of a specific object, to be less than
to be nan, which is not a number to be null, to be undefined.
There's all kinds of these various assertion types that we can put for now.
What we're looking for is strict equality.
We literally want to compare one plus one to the expected result of two.
So I'm going to use the matcher to be, which is what you should use for strict equality whenever you're
comparing any kind of primitives in JavaScript like strings or numbers or booleans.
So to be is its own method.
So we need to invoke it.
And then the argument we provide it is the expected result.
So of course we expect to get to right here and that is the whole basic syntax of just let me in fact
save this file.
So prettier adds all of its semicolons and gets rid of all those violations.
This is basically what a test file looks like we have a described, which means a top level category
or a top level name, and then we have multiple tests inside that describe that fit that description.
Right.
We'll add a couple more tests in just a second.
For now, we have one test.
Each test begins with an IT function.
It describes what it is that it's testing.
And then in the body of that function, we write one or more assertions or expectations.
So again, we can actually put multiple expected statements in here.
This is just the simplest example that I can think of.
One described function, one at function and one expected function.
All right.
So let's go ahead and run this file.
So what I'm going to do in this code is open up a terminal, which I can do by going to the main NAV.
You may now view main menu, clicking terminal and selecting new terminal, and that's going to open
up a terminal in this code.
It may be a different type of terminal on a Windows computer compared to a mac computer, but it's the
same idea.
It's a command prompt and it should launch you right inside your project, which is job search.
Right now, there's a specific command that you should write down, and this is what we're going to
be running to run our tests using the view seal.
In case you ever forget, you can open up package that JSON and you're going to find this scripts section.
Now in case you are curious or you don't know about the NPM ecosystem or no doubts what you can do from
the command line within a project with a package that JSON file is you can run, NPM run.
I mean, in fact, try to blow this up a little bit so you can see.
Yep, you can run, npm run.
Followed by any one of these script names.
So serve, build, test, unit, lent, etc. We can run NPM, run followed by any of those and will
automatically run the command on the right hand side.
So let me actually hide my files and give you an example.
If, for example, I run NPM, run test, colon unit.
What we're going to run is this command, which NPM knows should in turn run view as service test unit.
And the reason why we have this setup is usually the script command is going to be pretty small and
lightweight and easy to memorize, while the actual more complex command that runs can have a lot of
customized options and flags and things to configure how it runs.
So we don't have to remember to provide those flags every single time.
We just have a simple command like test unit which runs the tests for us.
So let me go ahead and shrink this again.
And when we run this, we're going to run all of the tests within our project.
So View CLIA is going to look for any file with a dot test that yes or not, dot dot just extension
and run it.
So let's see what happens.
We're going to run this command.
We're going to see that it's going to locate our playground.
That test that just failed.
Then it's quickly going to run through it and run the code.
So we can see here that we have the green pass.
And what that means is that all of the tests in the file passed, right?
Then we can see our organizational header that we provided to the described function.
So here we have basic math.
It's sort of our top level category and then we're going to see all of our tests nested underneath that
header.
So because our argument to the IT function was adds two numbers, you can see it output right here adds
two numbers and the check mark to the left of it indicates that the test passed, which means that the
expected result of two was what just got when it actually added one plus one.
Then below you're going to see a summary.
It's going to show you how many total test suites it ran.
Test suites means files.
So in this case, we had one file and the total number of tests we ran was also one and then the total
time it took to run.
All right, so let's try this example one more time.
Let's just practice with the syntax.
So within my same describe function, because I still want to test the basic math, I'm going to write
another test.
And since we're testing basic math, let's now test subtraction, right?
This is a perfect example of where you might want to use describe to provide some kind of higher level
category underneath which you can put multiple tests that fit that Category seven taste.
If I'm testing basic math, I can also test that it subtracts two numbers.
All right.
So we're going to invoke the ID function, provide a strong argument.
And then the second argument again is a function.
And in that function body, we can declare our assertions.
So let's, for example, do a an expectation here where I'm going to say expect five minus three.
Once again, we're going to get an object upon which we can invoke a method to declare our matcher.
I want that to be matcher, to compare strict equality.
And this should also be two.
In fact, let's now add multiple expectations within my function just so I can show you that that's
valid.
So for example, I can also test ten minus five and that should be equal to five.
Let me go ahead and run this test and you're going to see that we're going to have the same output.
We're going to have the basic map header, and then it's going to have the two test names underneath.
All right.
So the advantage of just as well is that it will also catch when things go wrong.
So let me go ahead and put in a incorrect value here for my expectation.
I'm going to expect this to be seven.
And when I run this, we're going to see the output when we experience a failure.
So Jess is going to show us every single test that failed.
And what it's going to do is provide this helpful output that's expected and received outputs.
And this is exactly as it reads.
It's going to tell us what it expected to receive, which is seven, which is the value that we provided
right here in parentheses, and then the actual value it did receive when it subtracted ten minus five,
which is five.
So it's going to show you what it actually got so you don't have to guess what it actually got.
And then the super beneficial part as well is it's going to show you which line or equivalently which
expect function call fail.
So if we know that ten minus five failed, we know that the expect statement above it, five minus three
evaluated successfully without error.
Now, obviously, in this case, it's basic math.
So all of this is obvious to us.
But if we ever have a really complex test where we have, you know, 100 different lines and ten different
tests and maybe multiple expectations in the same test, and our component is undergoing various state
changes.
It might actually become difficult to determine which test is failing and at what point.
So this feature is super helpful because it's going to show us with this little red arrow where or what
line the expectation failed.
All right.
So I'm going to go ahead and fix this.
In fact, what I think I'm going to do is remove this second test.
Generally speaking, you do not want to test the same thing twice.
It's redundant and it waste time.
And I would also argue, although this is a matter of personal developer preference, is that you should
generally aim to have one expect function per test.
So what I tend to prefer is lots of small tests that each test one isolated thing instead of, for example,
a very large test where you create a component, you write a test, you change the component, you write
another test, you modify the component.
Once again, you write another test.
The longer that your test is and the more expectations you have, the more it is that you're testing
and the more difficult it becomes to understand what it is that you are validating in comparison.
If you have lots of really small functions, it functions and each one describes exactly what it is
that you're testing and it has a small setup and a small single expectation.
It's pretty easy for another developer to read through your code and understand what it is that you
are testing.
So I'm going to run this test one more time.
We're going to see that everything is working as expected, and that's really all there is to cover
in this lesson on basic just syntax.
Remember, you have the basic describe function, use it to provide a organizational header and you
are not limited to a single described function.
We're actually going to see how we can that's describes in the very next lesson.
But within a described block, within its function that you provide as a second argument, you can write
your IT functions where you describe the specific test that you are testing.
And then within those functions you write your expectations.
You have some kind of evaluation which you provide to expect.
It does not have to be a mathematical operation.
It could be anything.
It can be a method call, it can be a property access, it can be any kind of JavaScript code that just
can value it.
And then you provide a complimentary matcher which specifies the type of validation or assertion that
you'd like to perform, and then the expected result.
In this case, it was to to be the both the sum and the subtraction product of these two evaluations.
All right.
That's all there is to cover.
Hopefully not too crazy, but we're going to be using just throughout the course.
So this is important information to start processing.
All right.
I will see you in the next lesson.