Okay.
So let's see how we can fix the problems that we identified with global success from the previous lesson.
So here I have my Hello World Dot view component.
That is this chunk of the page right here.
And in this file I'm going to scroll all the way down to the bottom where we have the style section.
And you're going to notice a special keyword and it is going to be scoped right here.
So this is actually the magical keyword that's going to do the trick.
As you can see in the comment right here, it says, add the scoped attribute to limit access to this
component only.
So what we can do in a view file is add the scoped keyword immediately after our opening style tag.
Now what this does is it takes all of the seasons declarations in here.
It doesn't matter whether they are element tags or class selectors or ID selectors any in here.
And it's going to limit the scope or the boundaries to which these styles are applied to only this component,
to only this file.
So what this basically means is this H3 will now only apply these styles to H3 in helloworld dot view,
not to any other component file.
Similarly, the styles for these lists and list items and anchor tags, these styles are only going
to be applied to, you know, ally and elements in the template section in this component.
They are not going to leak out.
All right.
So let's try this approach in APP.
But I also want to make an important point here, because you might be curious if we have this scoped
keyword right here.
Why are we still seeing the purple styles from the app component filter in and effect this thing right
here?
As a reminder, we have a hello world here and that is being rendered in this H1 right here with a class
of header.
And that header class is coming from our app to view file.
Well, remember, just because we have scopes in here does not mean that another component styles can't
pollute or come into this component.
So what I mean by that is these helloworld styles are scoped to this file.
These declarations cannot escape to another file.
However, another component styles can still make their way into the Hello World file.
And that's exactly what we're seeing here.
This purple styling is not coming from any anything here.
It's coming from this declaration in another file where we have not scoped the contents, and thus these
declarations are escaping across the code base and affecting the Helloworld component.
All right.
So to restate, the scoped keyword is going to limit the styles from escaping the current component
that you are in.
It's not going to prevent other components and their styles from polluting the current component.
So in our app file, let's return this back to a basic H1 right here in H1 and right here, we're going
to change this to an H1 as well and save this and everything is going to stay the exact same way because
again, this style of applying the purple color is still affecting every H1 in the app because it has
not been scoped to this component.
It is not been limited or bound to just this template.
So we are going to add the scoped keyword right here.
And when we saved this, just a quick heads up, there's going to be a lot of changes on the page.
And for now, I just want you to focus your eyes on the H1 and then we'll talk about all the other changes
after that.
So here I go.
I'm going to save it right now.
And wow, that's a pretty big change compared to the page we saw previously.
Notice that we have accomplished what we originally wanted to do.
Now only this H1 is going to have the Purple Star because this is the H1 that is in the template section
of the app component.
So we have scoped this style of H1 to apply only to elements and tags within the app component.
So because we have limited the boundaries, view only applies the style to this H1 right here.
It can no longer apply the style to the H1 and Helloworld because these styles are now scoped.
They are prohibited from escaping this component and polluting styles elsewhere.
So then you might be curious why did we lose all of the pre formatting that we had throughout the app?
Well, think about this declaration right here.
This is a bunch of CSR styles targeting an element with an IDF app.
And if you scroll up, you'll notice there is no actual element here with an idea of app.
So what was this applying to you?
Well, you may recall that in our index, that HTML file, that's where we bootstrap the entire of the
application.
We have this div right here.
And this is the actual div with an idea of app.
So before when we did not have the scoped keyword, these styles were allowed to be global.
So Vue was able to find this div right here in our index file and apply these styles right here because
they were valid because they matched the ID selector app.
As soon as we added scoped, we created a boundary to prohibit these styles from escaping.
And thus these styles could no longer affect anything throughout the app, anywhere that has an ID of
app, and that includes our index H2 Mafa.
And that's why we lost all our styles, because we're no longer applying all this logic to all the content
right here.
Right.
So, as you might guess, scoped is generally considered best practice because it honors the intent
of what a component is supposed to do.
It's supposed to be isolated, independent.
You don't want to edit one component styles and have it reverberate and cascade into ten other components.
And then you're going to be completely confused about where a given style is coming from.
Rather, you want each component to be isolated, independent, reusable puzzle piece that takes care
of all of its own needs by itself.
So throughout the course, we're basically going to be applying, scoped just about everywhere whenever
we do clarity styles, CSR styles here in the style section.
All right.
So that's really the key take away from this lesson and make sure to memorize this keyword and make
sure to remember to add it after your opening style tag right here to limit the CSR styles and scope
them to only the component that those styles are declared within.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.