Okay.
So now that we have our text input component, let's import it in our job search form and then use it
to replace our two text inputs.
So right here, I'm going to scroll down to the script section of my job search form and I'm going to
import my new text input component.
So import text input from our top level source directory, the component sub directory, we have our
shared folder and in there we have our new text input that view component file.
I also have to register the text input with my components object here to make it a local component.
So I'm going to add text input right here.
And that of course enables me to use this anywhere in the template of job search form in either the
upper camel case format or the kabob case format.
So let me scroll up and find my very first input.
This is for the job role and I will delete this in just a second.
But for now, let's write out its replacement.
So we are going to render our new text input component right here.
I'm going to render it with a self-closing tag.
And as a reminder, the component takes a placeholder prop and that is what it is going to populate
for the placeholder text in the input.
So right here I'm going to provide that placeholder prop and I'm going to feed in the same value of
software engineer.
In this scenario, we do not have any kind of dynamic value coming from data or any kind of array or
object.
We have a simple string.
And as a reminder, in those scenarios we do not need to use V bind with placeholder.
We can just pass in the prop and it's regular string argument.
So with that we can remove our former input and immediately we can start to see some.
Some of the benefits of a reusable component is that we have a lot less space being used up here and
we've sort of transferred the logic of storing the value and its changing value to this isolated text
input component.
Here is where we're keeping track of the user's interaction with the input field.
And so in the parent component, we can sort of delegate that responsibility to the text input and not
worry about anything besides rendering it and giving it a placeholder.
We also don't have to remember the styles and duplicating the styles, etc. We've isolated all of that
to this reusable component.
So it makes it, in my mind right now, a little bit cleaner, a little bit better.
So let's do the exact same thing for our input below.
So right here, well render not a plain HTML input, but our text input reusable view component.
And this also needs a placeholder.
And I, of course I'm going to give it the string of Los Angeles just like below.
And that clears me to remove the former input that was in its place.
So there we go.
We've cleaned it up a little bit and now we have our two text input components being used within job
search form.
So let me go to my browser and try this out.
So here we have the page.
Let me refresh.
You rarely actually need to refresh, but I'm going to do it just to be safe and I'm going to open up
my view.
DevTools And let me type a couple characters in both of these input boxes.
So in my role, let's say I'm looking for a view developer job and let's say in the city, I'm going
to look for Dallas.
So if I expand my job search form will notice we now have those two text input child components and
if I check into text input here, we'll notice we are indeed getting the placeholder value from the
parent.
And that's great.
And here, here's the data value property that we configured in the previous lesson and it has indeed
populated to be view developer.
And if I add something else to the end here like the developers, it will update accordingly.
And if I go into text input right here, same deal.
We have the value of the text box being kept and we've sort of isolated the responsibility of keeping
track and storing that value into our individual text input component.
Right?
So this is kind of a good sign because we've split up a problem into a lot of smaller pieces.
However, this does present us with a new problem.
Remember that our job search form component is the one that is actually storing the data property for
the location and the role.
And notice that these strings have not been updated.
Right, because we've delegated the entire storage functionality to these individual text input components
and just because they are changing values within them that doesn't meet our parent component of job
search form is being alerted to the changes in our children.
So once again, our children, our text input components are changing and they are keeping track of
those changes, but they're not relaying that message that change that event to the parent.
So we need to find a way to get the data upwards from the child text input component upwards to the
job search form parent component.
We're going to figure out how to do that in the very next lesson.