In this lesson, we'll add two more tests for our headline component.
Our first test will verify that the component is correctly interacting with the set interrupt function.
And our second test will verify that after one interval we expect the text to have changed from the
original value of build for everyone to the new value of create for everyone.
So let's begin by writing our new test.
Here, I'll declare my ID function call and I'll say it changes action verb at a consistent interval.
So this is more about confirming the interaction between the headline component and the set interval
function without worrying about the effect that that has on my actual template.
So as always, will copy these two methods from the previous test.
We want to invoke the use fake timer's method to replace JavaScript timer functions with just mock functions.
And then we want to return everything back to the original implementation by using the use real timers
method at the very end of our test.
And in between of course, is where we'll write our assertions.
So what I need to do in this test is mount my headline component.
And this time around, I'm not actually going to assign it to any constant or any variable because I
don't need that wrapper object for anything.
So what do we want to test here if we're not going to use the specifics of the headline component?
All I really want to test is that at some moment during my mounting of the component, I expect the
set interval function to have been interacted with, to have been invoked or called by my component.
The reason I expect that behavior to happen, of course, is because we have this created lifecycle
hook which will invoke the change title method.
And the change title method will interact with the set interval JavaScript function and pass it.
This these arguments of a function and a add duration in those things.
And all I really want to check at the most basic level is at some point the component has called set
interval.
That's really all I want to test.
Now, you may recall from the previous lesson that when we played around with our just mock function,
we were able to call an assertion like to have been called on this mock function because the mock function
tracks how it has been invoked, how it has been interacted with.
Well, the same concept applies here.
The only difference, of course, is that when we use fake timers, just will automatically create those
mock functions for these built in JavaScript functions.
So here I can say expect set interval, which at this juncture due to my use of the use fake timers
method should not be the original set interval JavaScript function, but its mock function replacement.
It's substitute at this point in the test.
And given that I mounted the component on the line before, if everything ran correctly and the component
ran through this code, then I should expect that it ran through this change title method and thus I
should expect set interval to have been invoked at this point by now at least once.
Right.
So I can say here expect set interval to have been called.
This is the same assertion we used earlier when we established a base mock function two lessons ago,
but now we're using it on a mock function that just will automatically set up for us.
So you'll notice when I run this test, our test will pass.
We're going to see changes action verb at a consistent interval.
However, notice that if I comment out the mounting of the headline component now our test will fail
because the test will see no use of set interval anywhere, not in its test body, not in the components
body.
It doesn't see that.
So it says, you told me that it was going to be called at least once, but I actually received zero
calls.
Our usages of or invocations of the set interval function.
Right.
So that's why we need the mounting of the headline component in order to trigger that set interval to
be hit.
But we don't actually need to save this to a constant because we're not doing anything with that mounted
component.
It just a bit of logic that needs to run in order for us to test that the component in its in its mounting
and its instantiation is interacting with set interval.
Okay.
So that was a tricky test.
And the next one's going to be even more trickier, but we're almost there.
So let's go ahead and write our next test.
And here's where I actually want to test that.
After a given interval passes, we should see new text appear in our template.
So I'm going to say it swaps action verb after first interval.
So I'm just going to test one interval because obviously we can go on forever.
The component is going to keep changing the action text every 3 seconds.
I just want to check one occurrence to make sure that it starts off one way and then in the next interval
it is something else.
And that to me gives me the confidence that the component is doing what it's supposed to do.
So as always will copy our use fake timer's method call.
And then at the very end we will use our use real timer's method call.
And then of course, we also want to manage a component.
So I'm going to copy this line right here where we are mounting it and assigning it to our wrapper constant.
And then if you think about it, what we want to do is we later on want to find our action phrase,
and that's going to be the text and we expect it to be create for everyone after an interval.
So what I'm going to do is copy this action phrase.
Put it right down below.
And let's just write our assertion right now.
Even though it will fail, we will talk about it and why it's failing.
So at some point we do expect our action phrase node and its text method, which returns the inner text
to be.
The text create for everyone instead of the starting one of Build for Everyone.
So you'll notice this test is identical to our very first test because we're not actually forcing the
component to move forward one interval.
We're basically just mounting it and we're looking at its initial state, what it looks like when it's
up for the first time.
And of course, the test tells us that it's actually receiving a string for of a build for everyone,
which is exactly what we expect, because build is the very first action verb that we start out with
right here in our data property.
So in other words, we are correctly launching the component.
We do have the right assertion in mind, but because we have mocked out the actual implementation of
set interval using the use fake timer's method, we no longer actually have a legitimate interval running
right because this is not technically in the component anymore, just has intercepted this call and
replaced that interval with its own mock function.
So what we need to do is to simulate the idea of that interval passing of that timer running, right?
And so there's a function or a method that we can call on just and I'm going to do that right after
mounting.
And it is called run only pending timers.
So just like the name suggests, it runs the timers, it runs something in your application that is
dependent on the passage of time.
It simulates the same idea as an actual 3/2 interval happening in the real world in our headline component.
So you can almost think of this method as saying, move forward to the next interval, move forward
to that next moment in time, as if an interval has passed.
Keeping in mind, of course, that we're not using a real interval because Gest has faked it out, you
know, intercepted it and substituted it.
However, because we have a pretty flexible, powerful object that can play the role of anything, we
can also get it to simulate the idea of a passage of time, of an actual interval gone by.
So when I run this, we're actually going to see that the test still does not pass and we're going to
talk a little bit about why.
So we're still seeing the original text of build for everyone in our action phrase element, which as
a reminder, is this H one right here.
That's where we have the data test, actually.
So I want to show you a little bit about the internals of our wrapper component, which is really our
headline component.
And this is not something you have to copy, but it is it is a little bit of a cool feature here in
the test.
So if you have your wrapper object from the amount function on that object, you have a property called
VM and VM is short for view model and that is just an industry term or a general kind of higher level
term that basically refers to what a component is, not specifically just a view component, but any
kind of component from any Frontier Library view model basically means that you have some kind of model
or some kind of logic or data that manages how the view works, right?
It's a similar idea here where we have our view right here in our template section and our JavaScript
configuration object right here, which is sort of the model behind the scenes, the logic.
So the view model is kind of a higher level term that's used among JavaScript developers to define this
kind of component in a kind of a higher level category description, if that makes sense.
So that's where VM comes from.
But if you don't care about those details, just remember it's VM to get access to the actual nested
component that the wrapper is wrapping around.
The reason I want to access VM is on this object.
We can actually access any of the headline components data properties, right?
So if I do, for example, VM dot action, we can see the current value of the action data property.
All right.
So if I refresh this, save the file, we can run here.
And of course, our text is still build for everyone.
That's what just is telling us.
But notice here in the console.log, we see that the the action data property is in fact create.
So what that means is, after the running of the interval, the internals of our component are actually
storing the right piece of data, which is create, write the next one in line after bill.
So what is the problem here?
The problem is that there is a mismatch between the data that the component is storing internally versus
what is actually rendered in the template.
The template has actually not been refreshed from the tests perspective.
So remember when we were first introducing this idea of what Vue does for us in the browser, we talked
about this idea that we change a property on data which forces view to re render the template.
That's like the second step.
What has happened in our test so far, because of the disconnect between the just test runner and the
View Library, which are two separate pieces of software, is just says go ahead and run the timer,
run the interval to which JavaScript and just understand what has happened and so does our view component,
at least this JavaScript section of it.
So it runs through this equivalent logic and moves on to the next array element, which is create,
but none of that triggers the component to actually refresh.
Right.
Remember, there is no Dom here, there is no actual browser.
So in our tests, when we mount, we're sort of simulating a browser like environment where we can bring
up this component, but it's not actually a real visual environment, right?
It's sort of a sandbox for us to plan.
So to summarize, what's happened is we have changed the components in turn data, but we haven't actually
told it yet to update the template and the HTML to reflect that new data.
So because our action here is not refreshed, it's simply as the original template that that was there
when the component first mounted, which has the text build for everyone.
When our test checks for that data test attribute, it finds the original template, it finds the original
H2 now and says, Hey, I'm still getting build for everyone, not create forever.
So obviously we need to do is we need to trigger the component to refresh.
We need to trigger the component to look at the data and update the corresponding HTML template to have
those latest changes.
And the way we're going to do that is actually by importing a view function from the view library.
So right here, I'm going to go to the very top of my file and I'm going to import a function called
Next Tick.
And this is actually going to come from the Core View Library.
So just from view right here.
Okay.
Next tick is a little bit confusing, but you can almost think of a tick as a refresh.
It's sort of the next moment in a component's existence.
In fact, I think the easiest thing for me to do right now is to go to the official view documentation
I have here, the the documentation for next tick, which can be a complicated thing to understand.
And even I sometimes struggle with it and I really would focus us on this sentence right here, which
tells you when to use the next tick function.
And it says use it immediately after you've changed some data to wait for the DOM to update.
Right.
And that's exactly what our tests have done so far.
We have updated the data and that that has been sort of on the sidelines because that's what the set
interval function did for us behind the scenes, or at least our mock function did.
But remember, we triggered the passage of time and thus behind the scenes we triggered view to change
its data.
However, we still have not had the complimentary DOM update, and when we run the next tick function,
what that does is it moves forward too after Vue has successfully updated the HTML, the DOM equivalent
of the component.
All right.
Or the DOM element of the component.
Because remember, a component is both the template and the JavaScript.
We've updated half of that, the JavaScript.
We have not yet updated that template.
So it's pretty simple as far as syntax right here, after we run our pending timers, after we advance
our set interval interval by one interval, we want to update the DOM.
So all I need to do is to invoke that next tick function that I imported from the View Library.
Now, this is an asynchronous action because this process takes a little bit of time.
Vue needs to scan the HTML and it needs to compare it with the data and see, for example, the fact
that we're using action here means it needs to place a new value there based on the current value of
the action data property.
That process may take a certain amount of time.
So if we don't wait for this to finish, it's possible for a test to continue running and end before
this process is done.
So what I'm saying or what all this is leading to is we actually need to use the async, await syntax
whenever we're using next tick.
We need to basically pause execution of this test until the next tick function concludes, which means
we're going to have the latest version of our HTML template, which means when we query that template
for our data test attribute, then we'll have the latest and greatest HTML.
And that's the thing that we actually want to make our assertion on.
So I'm going to make this test function.
The second argument here, async, and then I'm going to put the wave keyword before next tick.
And that basically tells just and the view test utils library to say refresh the components H2 now and
wait wait until that is done, await it until it's complete and then continue running through the rest
of the code to make sure that the assertions work.
So when I saved this, now we're finally going to get a passing test suite, and that's all there is
to cover in this lesson.
I know it's been a lot of complexity, but these are all really helpful functions and techniques that
you can utilize in your just and Vue test suites.
So just as a very quick reminder and a quick review, we use the use fake timer's method to mock out
real JavaScript timer functions like set timeout and set interval with just mock functions, replacements,
write substitutes.
But since we're not using the real thing, we also need to tell just to simulate the passage of time.
Simulate the passage of a time interval which we do using this run only appending timers method right
here.
So that takes care of the JavaScript side of things where everything updates, but that does not inherently
tell the view component to refresh its HTML.
We do that with the next tick function that we import directly from the view library that is asynchronous.
So we need to await we need to wait until this process is complete and done before we proceed to our
assertions.
Once the template is updated, then of course we can find the data test attribute, which is going to
be this H1 right here.
Then we can confirm that its new text is now create for everyone.
And then finally we will return back to the original JavaScript real time or implementations by using
our use real timers method.
All right, that's been a lot to cover, but I hope it hasn't been too crazy and we will certainly review
many of these concepts throughout the course.
So that's all there is to cover here.
And I will see you in the next lesson.