Okay.
So in the previous lesson we forced navigation whenever the user selected a checkbox in the job filter
sidebar job types component.
In this lesson, I want to repeat the exact same logic in the job filter sidebar organization's component.
So I have that component open on the left.
I have its test, we open on the right, and this time around let's switch the order.
So let's first adjust our tests and then we'll alter the implementation.
And it's basically going to be very similar to what we did in the previous lesson.
In fact, this in and of itself is a sign that maybe these two components are so similar that they can
eventually be refactored into just one component.
But we'll get back to that at a later date.
So right here in my test file, I'm going to update create config to accept a router object.
I'm going to provide my dollar sign router right here to my max.
Now every mounted component in my test suite will have access to this same router, but it's still up
to every test to tell that config function what that router object needs to be.
So right here, I'm just going to create a router object and I'm going to make sure it has a push method
set to adjust function.
Now you could argue that if you were using TDD, you wouldn't know that you would need a router object
with a push method just yet.
But later on, when you would implement your working solution, it would tell you because the push method
invoked in the real component would not exist on your empty JavaScript object, for example.
And we know this from our previous component, so I'm just going to go ahead and add it immediately
right now.
Then I'm going to provide my dollar sign router to my CRE config function.
And there we go right here.
What I'm going to do is wrap my second test in a new described lock.
So right here I'm going to say describe.
When the user clicks checkbox provide an arrow function right here.
And then what I'm going to do, of course, is drag down.
Rather drag up this entire test starting from the cut and paste it inside my describe block right here.
That's the first thing that happens when the user clicks the checkbox.
The second thing that I want to happen, and this will be my first failing test, is that it navigates
user to job results page to see fresh batch of filter jobs.
I in fact, I think I actually forgot up here to provide my route.
Object objects.
Let's take care of that.
Right here.
So right here.
Connect router is going to be an object with a.
Push method and adjust function.
I'm going to provide that to my create config.
Everything should still pass and indeed it does.
And so what I can do is once again copy the majority of this test to the one that I just declared below
right here.
Just like last time.
What I'm going to do is move this just function declaration in line.
There's no reason to assign commit to a separate constant.
And I don't want to confuse the future reader by having some kind of random constant floating around
right here.
I am going to move push to its own separate constants.
So that has some relevance in my test, which means I'm going to make this an S6 reference and it's
still going to provide the same router object to my create config factory function.
We're using a weight here, so we need to make sure we make this function async.
All right.
So we're going to expand the accordion.
We're going to click on a sample organization input that being a checkbox.
In this case, it's the Google input because we have a sample organization of Google right here.
And after we check that checkbox, what do we expect?
We expect our push method above to have been called with.
An object with a name property set to job results save that we are going to see a failure.
We are getting the just to tell us that we and it was expecting an invocation of push with this argument
but it didn't receive it.
That gives us permission to create the implementation to pass the test.
So right here in this component, I'm going to scroll down to the method called Select Organization.
And here we're going to have access to this the dollar sign router automatically because view router
is going to give it to us.
That object is going to have a push method and we're going to navigate the user to the correct page
by providing an object with a name property set to job results.
Save that, let pretty do its thing.
We can see all of our tests are passing.
So there we go.
We're going to navigate one more time to my browser to double check everything.
I'm just going to cancel this and refresh the whole page to make sure everything is registered.
So, for example, if I navigate to page two and I select a job type, we should navigate back to page
one.
And indeed we do.
If I select it, we should go back to page one as well.
If I go to another page like let's say page three here, and then I select a sample organization, like
if you and me, once again, we're taking to the first page our job results.
So we're always going to land on page one.
There's definitely going to be jobs on the first page instead of a page like eight, which we saw in
the previous lesson.
So this will address the bug as well.
All right.
So we've taken care of the bug in both this accordion and this accordion.
And with that, we are good to wrap up this section of the course in the very next lesson.