All right.
So at this juncture, I would like to run our alternate test command, which is AMPM run test colon
unit.
And the advantage of this command is number one, it's going to run all of our test suites throughout
the entire code base.
And number two, it's going to give us a code coverage report which will tell us perhaps what we've
missed in our tests.
So right here, we have an example in our headline component, which we were just writing tests for.
We can see that we are missing line 37 in our component file.
So what this is telling us is none of our tests are accessing the logic online.
37.
And if I open up my headline component and I head to that line, we can see it is that call to the clear
interval built in JavaScript function.
So why are we never hitting this line?
Because this line is only executed when the component on mounts.
In other words, when it is removed from the DOM from the view in our browser, we're not simulating
that kind of action or behavior anywhere in our tests.
So our tests are mounting the component and then the test ends.
So there's no point where we are actually tearing down or bringing down the component as if it was in
a browser environment.
So of course, what we can do here is write a test to check for just that, and we can force a simulated
takedown and then assert that the clear interval function has been invoked.
And that should be good enough.
So right here, I'll add a new test and I'll say it removes interval when component disappears.
It's always hard to write a test description in this case because you try again not to go super deep
into the implementation.
So I'm trying to represent the idea of, hey, whenever this component is done serving its purpose,
that's when this happens.
But inherently, the description is still sounding a little technical, but I'm okay with it for now.
So what we're going to do is we are, of course, going to mount this headline component.
And there is a special method available on this wrapper object that the amount function returns and
that method is called on mount.
It's exactly what you would expect in the method name.
It announced the component.
And what we want to assert, of course, is after this operation is done, we want to make sure that
the clear interval function has been invoked.
So there's one thing we're missing, of course, and that is in order to test that it has been invoked,
we need to make sure that it is, in fact, a mock function.
So we do need to make sure to grab our previous code, to use our fake timers at the very beginning
and then revert back to our real timers at the very end.
But the core of the test is this line where we can expect that the clear interval function has been
called and we can use the method here to have been called.
This is the exact same method that we used earlier right here when we were testing the use of the set
interval function when the component was mounted for the first time.
Now we're testing the other side of that equation when the component as I'm mounted.
So what I can do here is run, NPM, run, test, watch to run our tests in watch mode.
And this should hopefully pass and indeed it does.
And just to show you, if I do not on amount of the components, so if I do not simulate the tearing
down of the component, so it still kind of hypothetically in our browser from a test perspective,
we could see if we never on mount it, we never run our before on Mount Lifecycle Hook which never runs
Claire Interval and thus the test output tells us I expected that function to have been called once,
but I actually did not get that function call received at any point during execution.
So that's exactly what we want and that should take care of our code coverage issue.
So one more time I'll run this here and one more time I will run NPM run test unit to see our results.
And that should bring us in a into a better state for our headline campaign.
All right.
So everything is looking good.
As a quick reminder, of course, just because we have one hundreds here doesn't mean we actually are
guaranteed to have 100% code coverage, because there are ways that we could run through bits of logic
but not actually test them.
And all that this is testing is just that there's somewhere in your test files that are triggering something
that is running through the components.
So it doesn't necessarily mean that a block of code has been tested, just that it's been run through
the during some kind of execution.
So don't take this as like a 100% accurate description, but this is still a good place to be for where
we are.
So I will see you in the next lesson.