Okay.
So to kick this lesson off, I've expanded just about every folder in our tests directory and we can
see we definitely have a lot of TypeScript files in here and that is all fantastic news.
It turns out there's actually one file remaining in here that still has Ajax extension and that is the
test for our next element in list function.
You may recall that this is the helper function that we designed earlier.
This is the one that cycles through an array of strings in order to determine the next one in line.
And that affects the dynamic action verb that appears on the front page of the website that swaps every
3 seconds.
You may recall we built that feature out, so let me open up that test right here and let me immediately
change its extension to test.
And then let me also open up the corresponding implementation, which is going to be in the next element
in list, not just because this was a plain JavaScript file.
So let's change this to TSA as well.
There we go to for the price of one.
And let me, of course, drag my tests to the right.
Hide my.
Sidebar.
And all we have to do, of course, is to provide the types for this function.
Now, the way this is being used in our test suite as well as in our component, is we are providing
a list of strings and then looking for the current value or the current string in order for the function
to find the next one.
So as always, the test suite helps us to understand how the actual implementation works.
Here we have a list of ABCD.
We provide a string of C and we know the next element in the list should be the next string in line.
So we could certainly say here that the type of list is going to be a string array and the type of value
is going to be a string or one of the things that the array has many of.
However, I think we can make it even more flexible by using a generic type here.
And that way we can use certainly an array of strings and look for a string inside it.
But we can also make it more flexible.
And for example, look for a number inside a array of numbers.
Granted, we don't necessarily have a use case for that yet, but I think generics help us with the
flexibility to do things like this.
And this strikes me as the exact kind of utility operation that I can see as being useful for arrays
of any type.
So let's use generics here instead, and that will also offer us an opportunity to review that syntax.
So what I'm going to do here is right before my parentheses here, I'm going to declare that this function,
when invoked, will have to provide a generic type.
And remember, a generic type is just a type argument.
So here I'm going to provide my brackets and I'm going to say that this function, when invoked, requires
one generic type, and I'm going to give it the name t remember, this kind of type parameter name is
up to us, but the most common thing you're going to see is a single character, not in all uppercase.
And the most common one is T, which stands for type.
So then list, which is the first argument, is going to be an array of that value.
So what I'm going to say is whatever t is, I want an array of that.
So t square brackets means an array of whatever t is.
When the function is invoked, it can be an array of strings, it can be an array of numbers depending
on what t is.
Then the individual value that I'm going to look for within that array of T will be, of course, of
type T.
So if I have a array of numbers, then I will be looking for a value of a single number.
If I have a list of strings, then I will be looking for a value of a single string.
And what we return is the final return.
Value of this function, of course, is the next array value in line, which will also be of type T.
So right here I'm going to provide my type annotation for the return value.
So this is going to be a colon followed by 80.
All right.
One other thing I want to modify here is we're using the const here of Current Action Index, and that
is very specific to our actual use case of swapping the next action in line.
In this case, we were using the word action to describe the action verbs like build and design in code
which were on the front page.
To make this a little bit more generic so it can be applicable elsewhere.
I'm just going to change this to current value index, which sort of reflects the idea of this is the
index of the current value, and I'm going to change it right here as well.
It doesn't change the implementation, only the name.
And there we go.
So you'll notice right here in my typescript file that we are providing a string array of list and a
value of a string as well.
So because we are providing this type here, TypeScript can infer that the type of T or the type of
the generic is going to be of a string.
So you'll notice when I hover my mouse over the next element in list, you'll notice in those curly
braces or brackets it's figured out that the value of the T type, the type argument, the generic argument
is going to be type string.
It's figured that out because it's kind of obvious because we have a array of strings and a single string.
So it says, okay, this is t array and this is a single value of type T.
So obviously type T must be type string.
However, if we want to be a little bit more explicit in this test, we certainly can be.
So we can write this out explicitly by adding those brackets and then adding string in here.
So this is just explicitly writing out what TypeScript has correctly inferred and probably providing
a future reader with a knowledge of Hey, next element and List expects a generic type argument and
that reminds them exactly what purpose t serves right here.
So we're going to do the exact same thing here.
And of course, if we wanted to provide any other thing in here, like an array of booleans with a value
of a boolean that would work as well, simply because the generic supports any kind of type here.
It'll re declare the type annotation to serve the purposes of whatever t is.
All right.
So save that.
And as always, let's run our test suite.
And let's see where we get.
All right.
Headline is our a component that is utilizing that.
So it's running as well.
And there we go.
Everything is passing more good news.
We are getting super, super, super close to having just about our entire app in TypeScript.
So moving right along and I will see you in the next lesson.