Okay.
So we have made a lot of progress.
And the good news is there's only one file remaining in our source store directory that needs to be
converted to TypeScript and it is our index file.
Just like in JavaScript, if we have an index that's found in a folder, TypeScript will think of that
file almost as the default entry point into that folder.
If we ever reference that folder in an import, it's right here.
I'm going to change index dogs to index dot tips.
And luckily on the right hand side, we're going to see that there's going to be no violations.
So this file is good as is.
One super cool thing I want to show you is if I hover my mouse over store, we're going to see it's
going to have this store interface that represents our view store.
And you can see the generic type that it is storing within or that it's accepting is our global state
interface.
And you might be curious, how is TypeScript able to figure that out?
Well, remember, in our configuration object that we are passing to the create store function from
the UX, we have our state function and it is in the state function if I go to that file.
If it works, let me try this approach.
There we go.
In that state function, we specified that the return value is going to be above type global state.
So somewhere in the internals of the type of create store, the View X team wrote the logic to say,
hey, whatever the state function returns is also going to be the shape of the final store, or at least
it's state property.
So in other words, all of our typing throughout various parts of the code base in various files all
comes together because the more type annotations that we provide, the more that TypeScript is able
to understand how all these pieces work together and is thus more likely to identify any potential errors
or mismatches as far as types or incorrect methods or incorrect argument types, etc..
And we're all kind of starting to see it come together.
So congratulations with that.
Our source store directory is now completely in TypeScript and moving on in the next section, we're
going to talk about how we can convert our component files to be in TypeScript as well.
So lots of fun up ahead and I will see you in the next lesson for a quick section reveal.