Okay.
So there's still one super small feature that I would like to add in this section.
And this is going to be a throwback because it's been forever since we talked about this.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to expand my organization's accordion and I'm going to select
a sample company.
Let's do the You and me.
We can see that on the right hand side, the jobs are correctly filtering.
Now, what I'm going to do is click the sign in button.
And as a reminder, what that does is it opens up the sub nav.
And you may recall, because it's been forever ago that our subnet has a section that has the number
of jobs matched.
When we were starting out, we were building our page top to bottom.
So what we actually did in this sub nav component is we wrote down hardcoded the number of 1653.
And of course, in the real world, the way this page is supposed to work is as the user clicks, filters
and we filter the jobs on the right hand side.
That number of jobs should be reflected right here.
So in our example, we get 100 jobs.
So when the page loads for the first time, we want the sub now to have 100 jobs match displayed.
And then when we filter down those jobs by selecting an organization, we want this number to update
to show the number of jobs that we now have a match with.
Of course, as we filter, we should expect to see a lower number than 100 because we are only selecting
a subset.
But the key idea is that this number should update as the user clicks organizations.
And the beautiful part about this is we actually have just about everything we need to make this a reality.
Because remember, we have a getter called filter jobs by organizations that is a getter that returns
to us the array of applicable filter jobs that we're rendering on the right hand side.
If we use that getter to get that array and we simply take its length how many filter jobs it has,
that is the exact number that we want to display here in green.
Right.
If we have 100 jobs and there's 40 point of view jobs in this array, we'll have 40 jobs.
And the length of that array will be 40.
And that's exactly what I want to put in here.
So all we need to do is introduce our existing getter into this component of sub nav, get that array
and take its length and display it right here.
And then we're going to utilize the full beauty of UCS because as soon as the View Store State updates,
we're going to update all over the page because our new filter jobs by organizations array will be new.
We're going to update here on the right and we're also going to update the number right here.
And that is a perfect use case for view X whenever you have multiple parts of your screen that are dependent
on the same piece of data that you want to update, that you want to keep in sync.
That's why you use View X, because you extract all of that change to a higher level View X store.
So you are able to automatically update components as that store changes, right?
So what I'd like to do is to write a test for our subnet to display the dynamic number of jobs that
it's going to get from the filter jobs by organizations, array, length.
So let me transition back to this code.
And what I'm going to do is open up our sub nav component.
It's been a while since we've been in here, but here it is.
And here is my test suite for it.
And sub.
Now that test?
Yes.
And as a reminder, because it's been a while, here is our span and here is where we are hard coding
the number of 1653 or perhaps you chose a different number, but here we are hard coding that value.
So it's always going to be this.
We want this number to be dynamic and we want it to come from view X.
So currently in our components test that we have a create config function that creates the configuration
object for our mount function right here.
And right now we're only locking out one global property on the component, which is dollar sign root.
We now also want to mark out dollar sign store.
We need to provide a store because it is on that story that we're going to have our getters object with
the expected filter jobs like organization getter that we're eventually going to use in this component.
We're doing a TDD approach, so we're wiring up our tests first before we actually wire up the implementation.
We know eventually that we want to use that getter here, so we need to make sure we're providing that
getter on a mock store object.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to provide a second argument after root name, and it's just
going to be a sample store this time around.
Let me just provide a default fallback of an empty object.
So there's many different ways we can approach this, we can restructure the store properties, etc.
But what I want to do here is just provide that store right here in line as Dollar Signs Store.
So if the user does not give me a custom store, I'm just going to fall back to a store of an empty
object.
All right, then what I want to do is in each test, I want to wire up that store.
So I know eventually that to create config, in addition to passing a route name, I'm going to need
to pass a store.
So I'm going to define that store.
Constant right above here.
Constant dollar sign store.
And now we think about what our component is going to need.
Well, in order to talk to the filter jobs by organizations getter, we're going to need to have a getters
property our store.
Just like the real view X Store, we're emulating that API, we're emulating that interface on our smaller
JavaScript object.
So we're going to need a getters property.
And on that we're going to need to have the getter that we expect to use, which is filter jobs by organizations.
And that is going to give me an array.
So let me provide an array here.
And again, we can fill it up with arbitrary values.
But for now, let me just provide two sample objects.
Let's do this object right here and this object right here.
And just to make it a little bit less confusing.
Let's just give an object, a sample property, just so it doesn't come off as kind of empty and lifeless.
Let's just say ID one and ID two.
This is perhaps not necessarily necessary because as long as our array has two filter jobs, then we
should be able to take that array of two objects and get a length of two.
But still, just to provide some context.
These are supposed to be job like objects.
Okay, so now I'm going to provide that filter jobs by organizations getter on my store.
They passed down to my component.
And here we can see it.
Display's Job Count is currently testing that the job count exists and that test would still pass once
we implement this.
But I want to be a little bit more specific.
I want to validate that we are not just seeing a job count, but that that job count is equal to two.
Why?
Two?
Because that's the exact number of filtered jobs I have in my array.
So what I'm going to do is instead of using the exists method, I'm going to instead invoke on my job
count wrapper.
I'm going to call the text method as a reminder.
That's going to give me the text that is displayed to the user.
So it's going to find all the text within this job count, which is going to be the actually the div
right here with a data test of job count is what I'm finding right here on line 29.
I'm going to get the text inside that div and I expect that text to match the expression of two jobs
matched.
So we have the jobs match text right here.
But I want the 1653 to be instead expressed as a dynamic value of two.
Two being the number of jobs in my array right here.
All right.
So right now, our test is going to fail, which is to be expected.
And for the second test, we don't actually need to modify anything because remember, create config
can accept the second argument of the store.
But we have a default fallback right here, so we don't need to worry about it.
So, okay, so we are good to write our implementation and let's take a look at what we're getting right
here.
We get the exact same failure that we expect.
We expected a substring of two jobs matched, but instead we're getting a substring of 1653 jobs matched,
which makes sense because we hardcoded that value.
So let's make that value dynamic.
So what we're going to need to do is start by importing the getter that we want to utilize import filter
jobs.
By organizations.
And that is going to come from the top level source directory and the store folder.
And remember Node will look for the index just file and that is our view, a set of file that has this
concept.
And then in order to enable this getter to exist, not just as a getter method, but as a component
method that runs the getter, I can also import my map getters helper function.
So map getters from view x and I have everything I need.
So in computed, what I'm going to do is the structure, the return value of map getters invoke and
make sure to provide a common the end.
And as always, what I'm going to do is provide an array of the getters that I want to make available
to this component.
So I'm going to provide that constant right here.
And by using the map getters function, I'm now going to have a filter jobs by organization's computed
property on this sub nav component.
Now, in previous usages, like the ones we just did in our sidebar, we wanted to take this array and
iterate over and render a job listing.
Now we don't actually care about this array in terms of its job objects.
We just want its length.
However, we have the filter jobs by organizations computed property available.
If we're using it in the script section, we have to prefix it with the this keyword.
But remember, if we want to use it in our template, we can simply reference it without this, and
it will operate no differently than a regular computed property like a regular data property.
So right here where we have 1653.
We do a line break just so it's easier to read.
And what I'm going to do here is use my double curly braces to interpolate a string value.
I'm going to reference filter jobs by organizations which I have available to me as a computed property
because I use map getters and this is the whole array, right?
Is the array of however many jobs we have in our test.
It's going to be two.
In the real world, it's going to be however many we filter.
But I don't want to obviously render this array.
I want to render a number that is its length because that is the number of filter jobs.
So all I have to do is on that array, I'm going to access the length property, save that, and now
we're going to do is render however many elements we have in the array.
We can see our tests pass, which means the test is finding two jobs matched in the template, and that's
exactly what we want.
So now we're reusing this getter in two parts of our code base to render the jobs in the right and to
render the dynamic number of jobs that are matched in our step.
Now, let's now transition to our browser and see it in action.
So let's go to Chrome and let me refresh the page.
So we start from scratch.
All right, I'm going to expand to organizations.
You can see we have nothing selected here.
I'm going to click sign in.
We can see we have 100 jobs matched.
That is perfect, right?
Because we know that is the number of jobs that we are getting from our backend.
So when we start out, there are no filter jobs.
And remember we wrote that logic in the very couple lessons ago where if we didn't have any organization
selected, we are going to present all 100 jobs on the right hand side.
We did that to fix that bug where we weren't seeing anything.
If the user has no selected organizations, our filter jobs by organizations getter is going to return
the original array of 100 jobs.
And that's what we're seeing right here on the right.
And notice, because we're taking the length of that array, we're getting 100 right here.
Now, what's going to happen when I click View Tube, when I click View Tube, we're going to commit
the mutation to the View Store.
That's going to cause the selected organization's slice of global data to be updated, which in turn
is going to force the getter to rerun.
Because the getter is watching that update.
The getter is going to arrive at a new derived array of filter jobs.
Right.
And because we've now connected two components to that getter, our sub now right here and our job listings
component right here, the getter updates.
Therefore, our view X knows to communicate to both of these components that they should update and
both of these things update simultaneously the jobs in the right and the number right here.
Take a look.
I'm going to select YouTube right now.
Beautiful.
We see everything on the right hand side.
We see the number of jobs that have matched.
Once again, I'm going to select another value like point of view.
Perfect.
Our jobs, expand on the right hand side.
We now have 32 jobs matched.
I'm now going to d select youtube a jobs in the right update.
Our number of jobs matched.
And one way I can prove to you that all this is working is if we filter by every single organization
that will obviously capture every single job.
So if we add all those results back up, we're going to be back to 100.
And that's how the page starts out.
By default, having all of them checked is basically the user equivalent of having none of them checked
because we're filtering for every possible organization, which inherently includes every single possible
job, right?
So as we do, all this will notice that that number is updating.
So after several dozen and several dozens of hours apart from this feature, it's finally a reality.
We finally implemented the sudden have to have a dynamic number, but hopefully more importantly that
demonstrates the purpose of view X and how it really helps us to connect different parts of the UI,
to be able to automatically react to changes instead of having to have this component somehow interact
with this component to keep track of each other, we simply export that logic that state to this higher
level view store.
I initially described it as like a cloud that is hovering over your app and keeping track of all those
changes.
And that's exactly what it is.
By simply extracting that logic upwards, these two components don't have to interact with each other.
They simply have to talk to The View Store.
Same thing here.
This organization's collection of checkboxes doesn't need to tell this, its collection of job listings
that it needs to change, or this number that needs to change.
It simply tells you that it has a new organization.
View X three runs getters.
We run components render.
We have this.
We have that.
All right.
And we have that in a pretty simple, terse syntax.
So this is a good place to leave off.
We've accomplished a lot.
We've accomplished our original user goal of allowing the user to filter the jobs that they're interested
by by their organization.
We're going to type the section with a little bit of a refactor, and then we'll proceed on to another
one.