In this lesson, I'd like to introduce you to two just helper functions which can help us dry up some
of the code in our headline test file.
And as a reminder, when I use the word dry, that is short for the expression, don't repeat yourself.
In other words, we have a lot of duplication throughout our tests and there are ways that we can remove
that duplication to make our test suite a little bit shorter and a little bit easier to read.
Now, before we proceed, I would just like to state that duplication is not necessarily a bad thing.
It's a bad thing when you are duplicating logic or behavior, not necessarily when you are duplicating
boilerplate code, especially if that duplication, for example, is isolated, if it's independent,
and if it makes the test easier to read.
So if we look, for example, at our tests, we do have this constant duplication of the use fake timers
and the use real timers methods, and that's what we're going to clean up.
But you could argue that the advantage of those is that we can look at each test as its own isolated
unit.
We don't have to scroll up or down in the file to understand what is going on.
We can read each test from its very beginning to its very end and have everything be self contained
in that test description.
So we know everything that's going on from our setup to our tear down, right?
So as always, there's not necessarily always the best way.
There are tradeoffs and advantages and disadvantages to different approaches.
So let me show you an alternate approach here.
We're going to introduce two helper functions called before each and after each.
These are built into Gest.
And what they can do is run a bit of logic for us before each test and after each test.
Right.
And we're not obligated to use both.
We can use either one.
So, for example, we can run a consistent piece of code only before each test or only after each test
or have both.
Right?
It's up to us how we can figure it.
And so I'm going to write this code inside our described block for a headline, but not inside anywhere
else, because it's going to apply to every test within that block.
So for example, if I write my before each call here, I'm just going to invoke this right now.
It will come back to it in a second.
But what this means is the logic that I put in here is going to run once before every test.
And when I use the word test, I'm talking about each IT function call right here.
So here is one example, here is two, here is three and here is four, which means we're going to run
what's in the before each function, once before each of these four tests.
Right.
So the way this works is we pass before each a error function.
So right here I'm going to provide an error function because we need to give it a procedure.
We need to give it a sequence of one or more steps to follow.
And this is what we want to run before every test starts running.
So of course, what we can do before each test starts running is take this logic of just use fake timers
and have it run in there.
And the advantage of this is if I put this here, of course, is that I only have to write it once and
just will automatically run it before each test.
So as soon as I add this code, what that allows me to do is to clear out this line right here as well
as this use fake timers method, call here and here as well, and here as well.
All right.
So we've made each test a little bit shorter and we've consolidated the commonalities between them to
this before each function.
So we invoke that before each function, and we also pass it a function argument that specifies what
to do once before each test.
Right.
And the complementary function to that again coming from just is after each and just like its name describes,
this is logic that runs after each test.
So we similarly invoke it and we pass it a arrow function and we specify what to do after each test.
So kind of a way you can look at it is before each is for test setup or for configuring the elements
that are common or shared between tests and after each is for tearing those setup things down.
So what do we want to do after every test?
We want to make sure we return back to using real timers so I can cut and paste this line of logic right
here.
After every test, we're going to return just back to using the real JavaScript timer functions, which
of course allows us to get rid of this used real timers logic here and allows us to get rid of this
method call here and in the very last test as well.
So we have made the test suite significantly shorter and kind of a little bit more logical, you could
say.
And there are certainly advantages to this and I like this approach.
I just do want to make sure you're being exposed to different coding opinions, what another developer
might argue is now, unfortunately, in order to understand everything that's going on in this test,
to understand why clear interval has been marked out in the first place, you do have to know to scroll
up and look for other things in the file that are configuring that logic, right?
So it takes you out of that consistent flow of just being able to read a test from top to bottom and
know everything that is going on.
And especially if you have something like a test suite with 100 different lines and, you know, ten
tests and even you can set up multiple before each function calls to run with in display.
5 seconds.
So you can run an outer level before each that runs, for example, for all tests and then an inner
level before each that only runs for half the tests.
You can get really complex and nested with this set up and as you might imagine, that can actually
make the test harder to read.
You're going to have less lines of code because you're going to remove duplication, but you might increase
complexity.
And having the smallest number of lines of code is not necessarily the best metric, right?
Because the benefit of tests is to give you comfort that the code works as it does.
Right.
And it's and this approach similarly is not necessarily going to make the tests any faster because we're
basically doing the same thing or running a bit of logic before each test.
And then we're running or running a bit of logic after each test.
That's the exact same thing we were doing, but just manually and more explicitly beforehand.
Right.
So it's not like we are doing less operations, we're just writing less lines of code and sometimes
of that less lines of code makes the test harder to interpret or understand or require you to scroll
up and down to understand all the different pieces that might not necessarily be a victory.
Right?
So keep that in mind.
Always focus on developer happiness.
Focus on if the tests clearly describe what is being tested, if they're easy to understand and reason
about and do not always be afraid of duplication, it's not necessarily the worst thing in the world.
It's not necessarily a great thing to be celebrated either.
But it is something with caveats and advantages and disadvantages.
But in this lesson, we did learn about the adjusted before each and after each functions.
They each take a function and it can use that function to write the logic that you'd like to execute
before or after each test.
In this test, we will run.
And of course, we're not just limited to one method call.
We can put as many lines of logic as we want here to set up whatever we need.
You'll even see a pattern sometimes where people will, for example, mount a component in the before
each and assign it to a variable with a let keyword so that they can have, for example, a wrapper
keyword immediately available to use within each test without having to mount the component.
And again, those are all examples of how you can reduce code.
But in this scenario, I actually like having the mount in every test because again, it communicates
to other readers what it is that you're actually testing.
It's very easy to see, okay, I'm mounting my headline component in this test instead of having to
scroll up somewhere in the file and say, Oh, okay, so what wrapper represents is a mounted headline
component, right?
So again, just keep that all in mind.
I hope this has been helpful and I will see you in the next lesson.