Okay.
So I think our VEX Code is in a really good shape right now, but I've noticed that our index tags file
where we're storing all of that code is starting to get a little large, a little bloated.
As a scroll down here.
You can see there's a lot of responsibilities, a lot of methods, a lot of setup.
So what I'd like to do as one more refactor in this section is to create separate JavaScript files for
all of the concepts in this file.
First for my constants up here, then for my state, then a file for my mutations, a file for my getters,
and a file for my actions.
And then in my index, such yes file.
I'm just going to keep the initial store set up.
The goal here is to have a bunch of smaller files that better communicate all of these ideas separately.
Now, this refactor is going to actually take three lessons because we don't just need to move these
concepts to new files.
We also need to split up our test suite.
We have all of our tests in a single index that test that s file.
So we're going to need to work on that in the next lesson.
And then finally, we're going to need to go to any components that are relying on any of these methods
are constants, and we might need to fix a couple of imports given that we now are going to have new
files.
So in the third lesson here, we're going to focus on the component updates.
Let's begin by creating all of our new files.
So here in my file Explorer on the left, in my source directory in store, I'm going to create five
new files.
So I'm still going to keep all my view logic in store, but not in a single indexed just file.
So right here in store, I want to create a new file called Constants.
J.S. Then after that, I wanted to create a new file in the same directory called Select Store.
Here, my next file is going to be state that J.S. then also in store, I want to create a new file
called Mutations that's finally in store.
I want to create getters that.
Yes, and last file after that is going to be actions that.
Yes.
So we're going to have five new files here.
So let's begin with our constants file.
And I'm basically just going to drag all of these in the right hand side and copy everything from the
original file to my new ones.
In fact, let me do it one file at a time.
So let's begin with constants.
So right here from the index that just file, I'm just going to copy lines five through 11.
We have six constants right now when to cut them.
I'm going to paste them right here.
We are going to have some failures on the left hand side, but that's okay.
And another thing I'm going to do just to provide a little bit of context and clarity is I'm going to
separate my constants based on the responsibilities.
And when I say responsibilities, I'm really talking about features.
So in this case, I think there's three ideas here.
There is the idea of a user, there's the idea of jobs and there's the idea of organizations.
So I'm just going to create a line break between those three sets of constants.
And I think I'm also just going to add a small comment above each one to communicate that.
So right here, I'm just going to say user.
Down below.
I'm going down a comment that says jobs and whatever format you follow is up to you.
Some people might even say, Well, six constants, isn't that confusing?
But I can imagine that this will get pretty large over time if I continue to add new features to my
app.
So it's going to separate my constants by what they focus on.
So right here, I'm going to add a comment for my organization's constants.
All right.
So that's going to take care of my constants file.
Let's now move on to my state tags file.
So right here on the right hand side, I'm going to open up my new state DHS file and here I'm going
to copy over my function that is creating states and it's going to cut it pasted over here.
The one thing that I'm going to do a little bit differently here is rather than export it as a named
export, which I was doing previously, I'm going to make this a default export.
So I'm going to remove the export keyword here, make it a plain arrow function called state.
And right here I'm going to export default state.
All right.
So that would be the default export of that file.
The next thing I want to do is my mutations.
So right here, I'm going to open up my mutations that just file recently created.
And I'm going to drag over this object right here once again, cut and paste.
Once again, what I'm going to do is make it a default export.
So I'm going to remove the export keyword right here, which makes it a regular named export.
I want this to be a default export.
So right here I'm going to export default.
The mutations object so people can direct directly import to this object from whatever file they choose.
Now notice this is the first file in which we need some of our constants.
So I'm going to import those constants above so that this file no longer breaks.
So right here, I'm going to import the three that we need.
I'm going to need log in user.
I'm going to need receive jobs and I'm going to need add selected organizations.
And now this is going to come from our source directory, our store directory, but we can no longer
import from index that.
Yes.
And so now we have to specify the exact file where we're getting from them from which is now our new
constants that just file.
So save that and that should work.
We're going to follow the exact same process for our getters and our actions.
So let's open up our getters docs file here.
I'm going to cut and paste this logic right here.
If my mouse complies with me.
There we go.
Paste that logic here.
Let's make it a default export or move the export keyword.
Let's make it export default getters down below.
And let's import the contents we need above.
So I need the unique organisations constant and these filtered jobs by organizations constant.
Once again, that's going to come from the source directory, the store directory and my constant jazz
file saved up.
And finally, I want to update my actions file.
So actions that yes.
Is currently empty.
Let's go ahead and cut and paste this blob of logic into that.
And notice this is also the asynchronous action that is calling the Get Jobs API function.
So I need to make sure I cut and paste this important get jobs from my index, just file as well.
So let me cut and paste that right here.
Let me make this a default.
Exports to remove export right here, export default actions.
And of course, I'm going to need to import a constant as well.
Two of them, in fact, it's going to be fetch jobs as well as receive jobs.
So right here, let me import fetch jobs and receive jobs.
It looks like this code is automatically completed this for me, but I want it to be absolute.
So it's going to be from the app directory or source store constants.
Save that.
And now we can see our previous named ESX.
Names here are no longer working because they no longer exist in this file.
So we're going to need to import them and then perform the regular setup process.
So right here.
What I'm going to do is import all of the four things that we need below.
So the first one is state.
So I'm going to import the default export of state from our newly created state DHS file.
So that is the source directory store state.
Same idea on the line below for our mutations.
So import mutations.
They're now a default export.
So I don't need to wrap that in curly braces.
So from the source directory store mutations, then import getters from the source directory store getters.
Then import actions from these source directory store actions.
Save that, let prettier do all of its work.
And then what I recommend you do at this point is also restart your view def server.
It may still create some problems because we still have some broken component imports and things like
that, but it never hurts to restart just to see those errors up to date.
Sometimes when you're creating new files, that's when the view seal.
I can get a little finicky.
So what I'm going to do is do that behind the scenes and then I'll join you in the very next lesson
where we're going to continue this refactor by splitting up our test for the view X functionality into
multiple files as well.
So I'll see you there.