Okay.
So with every lesson, we move closer and closer to having our entire app in TypeScript.
So what I've done using the search feature in this code is look for all of the presences of the script
tag in my code base.
And of course, these are all the script tags that do not yet have the Lang attribute.
So these are all the components that remain that we still need to update to TypeScript.
Luckily, they're going to be pretty simple because they don't have that much complexity in them.
So let's begin in this lesson with the app and hero components.
I'm going to open up the app component and as always, provide the Lang attribute right here.
I'm going to import to component and that is going to come from view.
And right here, we're going to invoke that function.
And do that.
There we go.
Pretty simple.
And next up, we're going to do Hero as well.
So right here.
You know the drill by now.
It's almost like muscle memory at this point.
Import define the component that's going to come from view.
And finally, we need to invoke that function, passing the object.
And luckily, these components have a pretty simple setup where it's just a name property and the components
registration.
So no typescript violations here or here.
So again, more progress.
And in the very next lesson, we're finally going to take care of all of our view components.
And when I say view, I mean view as in VW, the actual starter pages for our roots are going to take
care of these four remaining components.
And with that I think our entire codebase will then be in TypeScript, so I'll see you in the next lesson.