Okay.
So in the previous lesson we broke up our view logic across multiple files.
And now I want to do the exact same thing with our view x tests in our index.
That test?
Yes.
File in our tests unit store directory.
So now I want to create a separate test file for our state, for our mutations, for our getters and
for our actions.
So let's get right to it right here.
I'm going to create a new file called State That Test.
Yes, I'm going to drag it over here to the right.
And then what I'm going to do is cut and paste this very first describe block, which has all of our
state tests.
So once again, the goal here is to just make each file a little bit smaller, a little bit more focused.
So in here on the right, we are importing our state function that's no longer going to come from these
stored directory or more specifically, the index file.
It's not going to come from a separate state file.
So right here, I want to import state.
That is our function that produces the initial view store state.
And that's going to come from the source directory store and the State Daas file.
And that's it.
So now here we can create our follow up test suite, which is going to be mutations that test that yes,
create that file.
And I'm going to, of course, copy over our described block for mutations.
So simply cut and paste that over here.
And once again, we're going to need to import mutations, which is now coming from a different file.
So we're going to import mutations from the source directory store, mutations that yes, it's no longer
coming from index.
And I think that's all we need to do in this file.
The next one in line is we can see on the left here is going to be our getters.
So right here in our tests, in it's store directory, I'm going to create getters that test that.
Yes.
And I'm going to cut and paste my entire getter section.
This is one additional benefit of using all these describes as it makes it really easy to see how the
organization works and just really easy to cut and paste all of this to another file.
All right.
So as always, we need to import our getters to right here import getters from our source directory.
Store getters.
Save that.
And only one more left to do here, which is our actions.
So right here, let's create our actions.
Test, digest, file.
There we go.
I'm going to cut this section right here.
Paste it here.
We're going to need to import our actions and that's going to be import actions from our source directory
store actions.
That's the new file we created in the previous lesson.
And you'll notice we're still getting some issues down below.
That's because remember our actions are making or single action in this case fetched jobs is making
that asynchronous call to the API to get jobs.
So when we were writing the test for it, we marked out the get jobs function that does the API call.
So you can see we have some of that marking code right here in index that test that.
Yes.
So I want to cut and paste this code as well, both of these lines.
So the first line is going to import get jobs, which is the actual API function call.
And the just mark is going to replace that with a just implementation which we then modify right here
in the before each to pretend as if it's resolving to a promise that gives us an object of a sample
job.
Okay.
So with that we have copied everything over to brand new files and we are actually good to delete our
original index, that test such as file because right now it doesn't have anything left in it.
Let's go ahead and right click here and choose Delete.
Move to trash.
And there we go.
We've now moved our former tests across four different files.
So somebody wants to see the tests for just the getters or just the mutations.
It's a lot easier to come here and understand what they are doing.
And of course, this brings up a larger discussion, which is, you know, what do we do when we have
too many mutations?
Right.
Well, you follow the same principle.
You keep breaking it down into smaller files.
Maybe you have a feature folders, you'll have like a users folder, and there you'll have the mutations
file for just the users and then you'll have a jobs folder where you'll have the jobs mutations, right?
So at this juncture with the amount of actions, getters, mutations, etc. that we have, I think storing
them across multiple files is a better step than storing them all in one file.
But similarly, you basically will adjust your code base when you feel that it becomes necessary or
when you feel that makes the code more readable.
So I think this was a step that was good.
I don't think it's now worth it to move these mutations to even smaller files.
But as your code code base grows in size, as your view project expands, it may be absolutely reasonable
to do so.
So you can consult with your team, think about what works and what doesn't work, and continue refactoring
like that.
All right.
So with that, we have completed our View X refactor, we have completed our test refactor.
The last thing that we're going to do in the next lesson is fix up all of our components.
So I will see you there.