All right, so congratulations.
We have completed another course section together.
So as always, let's review our user story, our app as it stands, and all the concepts that we've
learned in this section.
So our user story as a user, I'd like to know what I can do at the company so that I get excited about
working for the company.
And the way that we implemented this request was by building this dynamic headline, which changes the
action verb and its corresponding styles every 3 seconds.
And I'm sure we were all thinking, thinking at the very beginning of the section, Hey, this can't
be that difficult, right?
And maybe it wasn't difficult, but it required a lot of different pieces of knowledge about Vue and
about the JavaScript language itself, as well as concepts surrounding just in order to test it properly.
So even again, with such a small, isolated feature, we were able to learn quite a lot about many
different parts of the view ecosystem.
So with that, let's go ahead and start reviewing everything that we learned.
First up, we again had this idea of using computed properties to determine Dynamic Seasons classes
to apply to our elements.
Earlier on, we used the computed property to generate a dynamic tailwind high class to determine how
we needed to further push down the content of our headline in order to adjust for either the presence
or the absence of this sub nav.
So based on the conditional render of the sub nav, we needed, we needed to generate a conditional
height by which to push down our headline component.
We started off the section talking about that, and that is continuing to review the concepts we introduced
in previous lessons.
Then we started building out the headline component itself, which allowed us to introduce season grid.
Since GRID is a new way to build out templates in the browser and it allows us to build a template around
a grid layout, which means a combination of rows and columns.
And of course we used just helper tailwind utility classes and they were able to set up that grid logic
for us automatically.
All right.
Then we talked about the built in timer functions available in JavaScript.
We talked about set timeout, which allows us to run a function after a given a moment or duration of
time, but it only runs it once.
So we decided to go with the set interval function, which runs a procedure or a function at a consistent
interval.
So that means every couple of milliseconds it will re execute the function that we provide it.
And we wanted to use this logic because we wanted our action verb not just to change once, but to change
consistently at a rhythm, right every 3 seconds that we wanted to change to the next action.
And because we want to clean up that code, we also introduced the clear interval function which accepts
an interval object and stops it from running or in other words, prevents it from executing again and
again and again.
It kind of terminates it.
All right.
Then we talked about the idea of lifecycle hooks.
Vue components have many different lifecycle hooks, and they run at different moments of the components
existence.
In fact, some lifecycle hooks will run to more than once, while others will run when the component
is being mounted into the DOM or as it's being removed.
And they allow us an opportunity to inject our logic at certain points of execution at certain moments
where it makes sense.
So, for example, in order to establish our interval logic of switching the action verb, we wanted
to implement that business logic when the component is first starting up as it's being created.
So we hooked into the created hook to set up an interval to change that text in the headline every 3
seconds.
We also then used the before and amount lifecycle hook to remove that interval as the component is being
removed from the DOM, as it's being torn down.
And we also went through the view documentation so we could see some of the other helpful lifecycle
hooks that are available.
For example, every time the component updates, there is a before update, a lifecycle hook and then
an update lifecycle hook.
So you can really tie in to a lot of different points or moments of execution in order to customize
the business logic of how the components should run.
All right.
We built that logic out to select the next correct action verb from our array of four possible strings.
We started with that implementation, but then we decided to move that logic out of the component into
a separate helper utility function that just used vanilla JavaScript.
And we talked about the idea that it's often wise to move logic out of the component because it makes
the component smaller, more isolated, with less responsibilities, and it allows us to test the logic
independently of the component and the component potentially independently of the function.
Even if we're using that function, by the way, in the body of the component, we can mock it out in
tests.
Speaking of marks, we introduced the just mock function which we could create manually using this syntax
you see, just got offended that creates that mock function object and it essentially is an object that
plays the role of a function but a fake function.
And the advantage of that is we can use it as a stand in or a replacement or a substitute for a real
function, which we do not want to involve.
In our tests.
So if we have a feature that we're working on and it depends on some dependencies and we don't want
to incorporate all those features because it increases the complexity and the points of failure.
We can tell just, hey, for this real thing, replace it with something fake, replace it with something
simple that we can interact with and track so that we can isolate what it is that we're testing.
It's the exact same idea we did earlier when we talked about shallow amounts and using stubs.
A stub is a replacement for a real component.
Same principle here.
A just mock function is a replacement for a real function so that we can segment and isolate and test
in smaller pieces.
Right.
And an additional advantage of the just function is that it can keep track of how many times it's been
invoked with what arguments it's been called, etc..
So we can test interactions between the units of our program without necessarily worrying about how
the other unit does its business right.
So that moves us to the use of our just use fake timer's method which auto mocks JavaScript timer functions
such as set timeout and set interval.
And we talked about why this is a good idea.
And it is because we don't care about how the JavaScript development team developed set timeout and
set interval.
We just care that we are interacting with that separate piece of JavaScript functionality which we do
not need to test, and that our component is sending the right message to those functions so that they
can perform their logic and we can test what we care about, which is specifically our view component.
Right.
And of course, if we're going to use fake timers at the very beginning of the test, it's important
for us to clean up the work we do so that we don't accidentally persist that modification into another
test that may, for example, need to use the real JavaScript functions.
Right?
So after we marked everything out with use fake timers, we used the complementary method which is used
real timers, which returns any mock functions back to their original native JavaScript implementations.
Right.
Another advantage, of course, of taking out our timers is that in our tests we could simulate the
usage of set interval without actually having to wait three literal seconds and getting into all these
race conditions of having to wait before we can test a compliance logic.
Right.
We basically just said, let's pretend set timeout reset interval works and we'll just tell just to
simulate a replacement in its in its position and then pretend as if that passage of time has occurred.
That's when we use that just run only pending timers method.
All right.
And then at the very end, we decided to clean up our code because of how often it was using those two
helper methods to establish mock timers.
And that was the before each function and the after each functions, the before each function is expected
to function.
And it will execute that function once before each test run.
Right.
So we use it to run shared setup code for each of our tests.
And the name is perfect, right, because it runs once before each function, so before each test.
And similarly we used the after each function to execute a function after each test concludes.
So after we are done running all of our assertions and we can use after each to perform a shared cleanup.
So anything that we create in before each, we can tear down anything that we instantiate or set up
or change in before each we can bring back to its original state or return back to normal in after each.
So one thing to run before the test, one thing join after.
You're not obligated to use both or either you can use whichever one makes sense to you in a given test.
But that is how we consolidated our code and allowed ourselves to establish mock timers at the very
beginning of each test and then return it back to regular timers at the very conclusion of each test.
All right.
And that's all there is to cover in this section.
Hope you've enjoyed it.
And we will continue to the next section in the next lesson.
And we're actually going to start building out our form where the user can supply their role and their
location.
So I will see you there.