All right.
So super quick lesson here.
You'll notice that if you try to launch your app in the browser now, the app will load, but the jobs
page actually will not work.
And the reason for this is because of this change we made in our store index test file.
You may recall that we created this key that we need in order to get access to the View Store.
And we use this key in a component wherever we used the use store function to enable the proper type
checking for the actual shape of the store, more specifically its state.
Unfortunately, we also have these composable is right here in the source store composable stats function
and these also require the key to now work.
Otherwise these getters and this action right here will simply fail, which will cause the corresponding
component that relies on these composable to not work properly as well.
Luckily, the solution is going to be pretty simple.
We just need to import the key.
So right here I'm going to import the key based on the file on the right.
So that's going to be from my source directory and then the stored directory in there, which is going
to target the index file.
And then obviously everywhere where we are using use store, we simply have to provide that key and
that's going to give it access to the store.
And with that, everything should work again in the browser.
So you store, you store it, you store finally right here, you store as well, make sure you provided
the key as the first argument.
Save if you have any issues, just try to restart the view app in the terminal as well.
But otherwise this should get everything fixed up again.
All right.
And with that, I will see you in the next lesson.