All right, so congratulations on reaching the end of another core section.
So, as always, let's take a few minutes to review everything that we've learned.
This section was focused on getters in the U.S. What is a getter?
A getter is a method that uses the view store the state to arrive at some kind of computed derived data.
So the benefit of a getter is that when the view state updates, the getter will rerun.
So it is analogous or comparable to a computed component property.
You don't use it to store the primary data, you use it to store something that is dependent on the
primary data.
They also want to update whenever that original data changes.
A getter should not mutate or change or update view state.
That is the responsibility of a mutation.
So what is an example of a use case for a getter?
Well, we saw in the section that we can use the getter to get the user's filter jobs because that is
a subset of the original array of 100 jobs.
So we do not want to create a separate part of the store state such as filter jobs.
In other words, we don't want duplicate data or subset data or anything that creates multiple sources
of truth.
In our view X Store, we don't want an array of 100 jobs and an array of 60 filter jobs because if for
some reason one of those objects change, let's say, for example, somehow the job's name changes.
Well, then you have two places where you need to make sure that change is reflected.
And you never want to do that because that data quickly gets out of sync with each other.
You only want to have one source of truth in your view store state.
But if you need something that is dependent or calculated from it, you should use getters.
So Filter Jobs is a perfect example of when you should use getters, just like in a component, when
you should use computed properties whenever you want something that is coming from something else that
you want to update.
As far as testing, get our methods from view X, you test them like plain JavaScript methods.
You provide an input which is going to represent the store state and then you test for the correct output,
which is the getter doing its magic on the store state to arrive at some kind of new output.
That output can be whatever you want.
It can be a number, it can be a boolean, it can be an array.
In our example, we had a set being produced that came from an array.
That's totally fine because our getter does not reflect permanent data.
So we're not changing or mutating anything.
We're just producing new data based on existing data.
As far as the components we saw that we can use the map getters function to wire up our computed component
properties to be references to those of you x getter methods.
So view X and map getters will automatically create those methods.
Those methods will automatically invoke the correct getters passing in the store state as it currently
is as the first argument it does all of that behind the scenes and then we have access to those getters
via the this keyword.
It's the exact same design as we have with map actions and map mutations.
Of course, the only difference is we pass map getters, an array of getter names from the actual real
view store.
As we know, we have that a dollar sign store property on any view our view component and that represents
our whole view store.
So that has the getters that has the commit method to dispatch method, the state method if we ever
want the getters, we just access the getters property so we can do for example, dot getters dot filter
jobs.
However, it's much easier to use map getters because it takes care of all of that wiring up for us
behind the scenes and our tests will pass either way.
Speaking of tests, in component tests, in my personal view, you rarely have to use a real view store.
We're testing the view, logic and separate method calls for the view tests.
In our component tests, I recommend you mark out the dollar sign store global property.
You can do do that via the mock property of your configuration object that you pass to mount or shall
mount.
And then you can provide the getters property with a plain object and then have it be whatever you want.
It doesn't even have to be a method.
It can be an object.
What are value rather for that property that has whatever you need in order for that test to pass?
So you want to test the interaction between the component and the view store.
You don't need to go the full trip and test that the book stores doing everything internally because
then you're just double testing the view logic in your component tests.
We already have that logic tested in our separate, independent getter tests.
So all you really care about is that the component is talking to the right getter, getting the right
information from it, and then doing something with it in the component.
You do not have to use a real view store to capture that logic and to have that kind of test.
All right.
Similar concepts to what I've been preaching the entire course.
Finally, we saw at the very end of the section that winner view logic gets a little bit too complex.
What we can do is break it up by either responsibility.
In this case, we can have separate files for actions, mutations, getters, or what I've seen in some
code bases.
When that becomes too bloated in itself is you can start breaking things up by feature.
So you might have a users folder and then you'll have user actions, user getters, user mutations.
You don't have a jobs folder where you have job actions, job getters, job mutations, etc. So you
keep breaking it up into what feels appropriate for the size of your code base and your complexity.
As always, just follow the standard teams code base, work with what you have while identifying the
strengths and weaknesses that you see.
What makes the code hard to work with?
And then when it does become too difficult to run maintainable, then you can propose a solution, whatever
works best.
As far as organization, there's no single one size fits all view solution.
It's the same common sense solutions that you apply in any coding project.
Just break things up into smaller function, smaller classes, smaller files, and that will tend to
get better as a codebase scales in size.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this section.
In the very next section, we're going to review a lot of the view concepts we've come to know and love
by building another feature in our app.
So I will see you there.