All right.
So now that we have completed our discussion on CCS scoping in view, we need to do a little bit of
housekeeping to prepare us for the next section of the course.
Mostly this is going to consist of deleting a lot of the files that the view Seelye generated for us
that we do not need for our project.
So I'm just going to open up my file explorer right here in this code, and we're just going to start
deleting files.
So first up in the assets folder, you'll find a logo, that PNG file, that's just the view logo right
here.
We're not going to need it for our project right now so we can go ahead and remove it.
We can also go ahead and remove our Hello World View file inside the components folder.
And by the way, it's failing to compile on the right hand side because one of our components is referencing
that former logo that's totally file, that's totally fine.
It's not building because it can't find the file it needs, not a problem.
So let's go ahead and delete our helloworld that view component.
We're going to we're going to come back to APT View in just a second, but I'd also like to head into
the tests folder, into the unit folder, and you're going to find this example, that case file.
This is an example of a test file.
We do not need it right now.
And later on will create a new test file and I'll talk you through the syntax of tests at a separate
moment in time later so we can go ahead and remove that.
And then let's come back to our app file and we're going to clean it up a little bit.
So first up, we no longer have a helloworld component, so I'm going to get rid of it right here.
We no longer have our image that references that view logo whose file we just deleted.
So we can remove this.
So we can just go ahead and leave a basic H1 because we do need some kind of content within our template
tags or view will complain.
So I'm just going to do a basic H1, but you can leave whatever you want.
And I'm just going to leave a text here of Hello View.
Right here in our script section.
This is where we were formally importing the Hello World component from a separate file.
We'll talk more about components and imports at a separate point later.
But the short story here is we no longer have this component, so we no longer need to import it.
And right here in our components key, we can delete that key entirely.
So our left here in the script section of the course is just going to be a object with a name property
set to app.
All right.
And then finally, we actually do not need a style tag unless we are adding styles and we no longer
have any CSA styles to add to this component.
It's just a plain H1 so we can remove all of this content down below the style tag.
And once we save this, the View app should be able to render properly because now all the files are
present and we should be left with this super simple hello view H1 tag in our app.
Right?
And that's all we need.
We're starting from scratch.
We're going to truly build this job search app from the very beginning, from the very first component,
and we're going to start tackling that in the very next section.
We're also going to talk a little bit about a cool CSS framework called Tailwind.
That's what's next on our docket.
So lots of fun stuff lies ahead.
I will see you in the next lesson.