Okay.
So here I am in our DB dot JSON file.
And as a reminder, this is the file that we use in combination with the JSON server package to define
our mock backend.
So each key here in this JSON object represents an end point.
So we currently have to slash spotlight's right here and slash jobs.
And then of course, the value for that key is the return that we're going to get from that end point
when we hit it in our app.
So previously, when we were building the filters of organizations as well as job types, what we did
inside our app is receive the jobs and then iterate over certain properties here, like for example,
job type and organization in order to come up with those unique values that the user was filtering by.
And we certainly could do the same right here by using the degree property right here.
But just to keep things a little bit interesting and do things a little bit differently, let's now
say that it's a product requirement or a management requirement that we actually reach out to a brand
new end point called degrees.
That's going to provide us with all of the unique degree types.
All right.
So there's no necessary reason to do this.
Let's assume as frontend developers that this is simply a requirement or a constraint that we have to
deal with.
So imagine somebody comes to you and says, Hey, I'd like you to use this slash degrees, end point.
We've already built it out in some language, whatever language, you don't have to worry about it.
But we're going to give you this URL, reach out to this end point to get the JSON of degrees and use
that as your basis for filtering.
All right.
So in the previous lesson, I attached the new code that I'd like you to add to DB that JSON.
So I'm going to do that same thing right here.
It's a new degrees end point and I'm going to copy it over from my other screen.
So there we go.
Make sure when you add this degrees end point set to an array that you also provide a comma right here
to separate it from the next end point, which is spotlights.
And as you can see, all these slash degrees, end point will return is going to be an array of objects.
Each object or each degree object will have an ID set to a number and a degree property that's set to
the actual string representing the degree name like associate or bachelor's.
All right.
And we can already test that this is working in our browser because our JSON server is running in watch
mode.
So as soon as you save the DB that JSON file, it should relaunch itself and register these changes
and allow you to hit this end point.
If for some reason the following step does not work, you can simply go to that terminal tab that is
running your JSON server, shut it down and launch it again with the command NPM, run it back in.
But what I'm going to do is head to my browser and currently I have of course my view app running on
localhost and the AT&amp;T port.
Our JSON server is running on a separate port, which is going to be 3000 and then that's our actual
app.
And then remember our end point is going to be slash followed by the property that we designed in our
DB that Jason.
So we just call that end point slash degrees.
So I'm going to enter that and if everything relaunch correctly and we reach out, there we go, I'm
going to zoom in.
We can see it's the exact same array of objects that we just declared in DB that JSON.
So it looks like everything is working.
And now we have this mock backend providing this mock response from this zero.
And so in the next lesson we can start wiring up all the types of code to make the request.
Then of course register it with our components and view, etc..
All right, so I will see you in the next lesson.