All right.
So the first thing that I want to do in this lesson is to create a new file inside our source directory,
and I'm going to call it Playground Dot.
JS So the purpose of playground dogs throughout this course will be to be a playground where we can
test out different JavaScript and view concepts outside the scope of our actual job search project.
So as we introduce certain concepts that I think would benefit from some additional explanation or examples,
we're going to write out those examples within Playground.
Yes, most of these lessons that are going to use the playground that just file are pretty optional
because they're going to depend on whether you know, the concept or not.
So for example, in this case, in this lesson, we're going to talk about the E6 spread syntax for
arrays.
That's the dot, dot, dot that you place before an array in your program.
And we're going to utilize this E6 concept in the very next lesson.
So if you're unfamiliar with it, stick around.
If you're are familiar with it, if you've seen this before, you can feel free to skip this lesson.
All right.
But we're going to write out an actual practice code within playground doctrine.
Yes.
So let me hide my file explorer, and let's write some code.
Okay.
So let's declare two arrays.
One is going to be an array of fruits and one is going to be an array of vegetables.
So right here I'll do const fruits and I'll do a three element array of strings.
Let's do apple, let's do banana and let's do orange.
And on the line below I'll declare a similar array of vegetables and we can put just two strings in
here.
Let's do cucumber.
And let's do radish.
You'll notice the little orange squiggly lines at the very end that's actually prettier, complaining
that we don't have semicolons.
Not a problem if we save our gas file.
You can see that we format on save and automatically prettier will add those beautiful styles for us.
We still have these red squiggles, but of course that's coming from the fact that we are not using
our fruits and vegetables arrays.
Okay, so here is our challenge.
What I want to do is to merge together the strings within my two arrays.
So in other words, I want a new array that's going to consist of five elements apple, banana, orange,
cucumber and radish.
How can I merge or combine these two arrays together?
Well, here's what a beginner might think, which is a solution that actually will not work.
And by the way, in order to output any text which we're going to need to do when we run this program
with Node from our terminal on the right hand side, we can use console console dialogue just like we
do in our browser.
So for example, I'm going to put a console that log here and I might think to myself, Well, I know
I need a new array, so can I just put fruits in here and can I just put vegetables in here?
And will that accomplish what we want?
And the answer is no.
So let's take a look at what this gives us.
So in the right hand side, I'm going to use Node to run my file and my file is within the Astro C directory
and it's called Playground Dot J.S..
So right here, node source, playground dogs.
And when I run this, you're going to see I'm going to expand this.
That's a little bit easier to see that we actually do not get an array of five elements.
We get an array of two arrays.
Right?
We've kept the original boundary, the original array of fruits and vegetables inside, right here and
right here, inside this new array that we have generated right here.
And that's not what we want.
We want to extract those original elements and store them in a new array.
So in order to accomplish that, we need to use a special syntax and it's the dot, dot, dot syntax.
So I'm going to put it right here before fruits and then talk a little bit about what it does.
What this effectively does is it extracts all of the elements of fruits in line here.
So imagine literally just copying these elements right here and putting them inside right here where
we have dot dot fruits.
We are not making an exact copy of the array because we are not keeping the outer array itself.
We're just taking the internal elements.
In this case, the internal strings from the fruits array.
And then we're basically spreading them out in this position, in this spot, inside this new array
that we've declared with this opening and closing square bracket.
So now we're going to spread out the values from our original fruits array in our new arrays.
Let's explore the differences right here.
I'm going to rerun the file and you can see the difference between these two.
Syntax is side by side.
I've spread out the fruits array so it's elements appear as they should in my new generated array,
but I have not spread out the vegetables array so I have the complete original array inside this array
that's being output.
So of course, to complete this assignment, to get all of the elements merged in together, I need
to apply the same spread syntax to my vegetables array as well.
So right here again to practice whenever you have an array and you have it assigned to a variable,
in this case, you can place a dot, dot, dot in front of it.
And that will take not crypto but that tuck that that is going to take the elements of that array and
spread them out effectively, copy them to a new destination, to a new data source, but not keeping
the original array that they are in.
Right.
So we're basically copying apple, banana, orange, and then after that, we're copying cucumber and
radish and then we're going to consolidate all of those and store them in the new array that we have
right here with square brackets.
So I remove this right here and we run this file.
Now we've accomplished our original goal.
We have merged together the elements of the fruits and vegetables arrays into a new array.
So that's what you use the spread syntax for, primarily used to copy elements from other arrays into
new arrays while getting rid of the original array structure.
All right.
And fruits and vegetables, by the way, have not been modified or mutated in any way throughout the
process.
We still have access to them and they remain the same original arrays.
This is a brand new array that we have generated just for this line.
Fruits and vegetables remain as they are.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.