Okay.
So let's go ahead and create our new sub nav component.
Sub nav, as a reminder is short for sub navigation.
This is a secondary menu that will appear below our primary menu.
Okay.
So all of our components are within our components directory and SIRC.
So let's place our new component in there as well.
Later on, we may create some nested directories to organize our code, but right now we have a pretty
small number of components.
So I'm going to call this sub navigate view.
And within this view, component file.
What do we need?
We know that we need to start off with a template tag.
Here is where we're going to specify our HTML.
We cannot have an empty template tag, so let's put some placeholder content in here for now.
I'm just going to render a div and inside I'll put some arbitrary text like this is a seven out.
The other thing I want to add to this file is, of course, my script tags.
This is where I write my JavaScript related to my view component.
And as you should know by now, we export default a plain JavaScript object, and this is our configuration
object for this component.
For now, the only property I want to add here is name and I'm going to give it the exact same name
as the file, which is subnets.
I really see no reason to give it any other name, but in case you do want something different to render
in your view Dev.
This is where you can customize that.
I'm going to save this file to apply my prettier changes.
It also looks like it wants me to add an additional line break after my closing script tag.
So I'm going to do that.
Perfect.
So we have a new sub nav component, but of course we're not rendering it anywhere, so it's not going
to appear in the browser.
So where do we want to render this sub nav?
We want to render it directly below the main nav.
So I'm going to head into my main nav view file.
And as you may recall, there's a couple of things we need to do in order to allow the sub nav component
to be rendered here.
We have to import it here in the script section.
We have to register it with the components key of my main nav.
Basically, the components key sets the child components that the main nav component can render.
And once we've registered it here, then we can use it in the template above.
So these are all should be hopefully familiar steps, but let's walk through them right now.
I'll begin by importing my sub nav component right here.
And we know that the app sign here represents my astro seed directory.
In there I have a components folder and then there I have my new sub nav component.
So I'm going to import it like so.
And then of course we want to register it here.
I'm going to add it as another key here, sub nav comma.
And as a reminder, this is using the S shorthand where we have a key or a property of sub nav whose
value is this component.
And this of course allows us to specify the name that we're going to use for this component in our template
in case we want to use a different name.
But this is totally fine for us because I'm okay with using just sub nav by itself.
Okay.
So we are seeing a little bit of a warning here, but that is to be expected.
This is because the sub nav component has been registered but not used.
So is led to saying, hey, you're telling me that this component is going to be rendered as a child,
but you're not using it anywhere in your actual template and that's a waste of memory.
So let's go ahead and add this sub now.
So I'm going to scroll up here.
So if I go back to my design, you'll notice we have this top level header and then we have a nested
divan here.
This is our top level div that makes the box fixed, which means it's going to stick to the top of the
screen.
As we scroll down.
I want to put my sub now within this fixed div, but not within the next one, because this div right
here is taking care of our primary main navigation.
So this is where we have our links and our action button and our profile image.
I'm going to collapse this there right here and I want to add my seven have immediately below it.
So let me actually go back here.
I think I accidentally deleted it.
Let me collapse.
And right below this div right here.
Perfect.
This is where I want to render my sub naff.
All right, so it is going to be a self-closing component because we don't have anything to render inside
of it.
We're going to talk more about when we would use opening and closing components a little bit later on.
But we're going to render this component the same way we've rendered any other component.
We're just going to do some NAV, followed by the closing tag right here and the closing curly brace.
Okay, so that will render a sub nav.
And if I go back to my browser now, we should see our seven now appear and there it is.
Let me just refresh the page.
It looks like I have some left over.
There it is.
This is our sub nav rendering below our main nav.
If I go into my view component our devtools I will see my view components.
Here is my main nav component and inside it it is rendering this sub nav child component right here.
You can now see it highlighted in green.
Perfect.
So we have created the sub nav and in the very next lesson we're going to go ahead and start styling
it.
So I'll see you there.