All right.
In this lesson, we're going to add our menu items to our main nav components.
So we're finally getting closer to fulfilling our original user story.
So right below this hyperlink with our company name, I'm going to add an HTML nav element right here
and this code will automatically close it off and I want to immediately give it some tailwind.
Utility classes right here.
I'm going to give it the full class to apply a 100% height so it inherits the full height of its parent.
And then I'm going to create some space between this NAV and my company name by adding some margin to
the left of this NAV.
As a reminder, we have our M classes for margin and if we only want margin on the left, well, we
have M L classes just for that.
So right now I'm looking for an L 12.
And as we can see from the descriptive box on the right hand side, that's going to add three RAM or
equivalently 48 pixels of margin between my NAV and my company.
So we're just going to buy ourselves a little bit of space here.
All right.
The next thing I want to add within my NAV is going to be an unordered list.
So a u l and then I'm going to apply some classes here too.
I'm going to make it a Flexbox just because I want to distribute the eventual menu items within this
Flexbox.
I want to give it the same H4 class for the height.
I want to explicitly state that I want zero padding and zero margin here.
The way I can do that is with the P zero class and the M zero class.
P zero applies zero padding on all sides and zero applies zero margin on all sides.
And then finally, to avoid the bullet points that come by default with the list items in a list to
avoid those to get rid of them, there is a class I can apply called List None, and as we can see,
what it adds is the access property list style type set to none.
That again gets rid of the bullet points that crop up by default next to the items within a unordered
list.
All right.
So all that's left to do now is to add our six menu items.
They're each going to be allies or list items within our list.
So right here, I'm going to add an ally and I'm going to give it a class of H full again.
And then inside there, I'm going to add the hyperlink that's going to take us to that eventual page.
Right now, we don't have any pages on our site, so I'm going to set the attribute equal to an empty
string to to go nowhere.
So right here I'm going to add a hyperlink, I'm going to set it's off attribute to an empty string.
And then I'm also going to make sure that I provide some classes here for styling.
So my hyperlink is going to have a class a flex to make it a flexbox.
I'm going to vertically align its elements or its content with item center.
I'm going to apply H H4 to make its height 100%.
And then what I'm going to do is apply a special padding class called p y.
The the Y in this class name refers to the y axis.
Earlier on we saw classes like p x over here which deal with padding on the left and right or the x
axis.
P y is the complementary set of classes in tailwind that deal with the y axis.
So for example, if I apply py2 point five here, we can see from the box we're going to add some padding
to the top and some padding to the bottom, but we're not going to add any padding on the left and right.
So in this case, it's going to be ten pixels.
All right.
And then, of course, we actually have to provide the text that the user is going to see.
And the very first menu item on the Google career site is teams.
So I'm going to put that right here.
All right, then I'm going to copy this list item below.
And it's basically going to be the same.
We're going to change this text to location or actually location that sounds a little bit more appropriate.
Appropriate.
But then we're going to add one more thing.
I want to create some additional margin between this list item and this list item.
This list item doesn't need any additional margin to the left of it because the NAV is going to create
the spacing between it and the name of the company.
But if we do not add additional margin to this list item, it's going to scrunch up and right next to
this ally.
So I want to create some spacing between my allies, but only starting from the second one.
So I'm going to add amount here for margin left and I'm going to choose the HTML nine class, which
is 36 pixels of spacing or margin.
And this is what we're going to copy for the remaining list items because for every subsequent list
item, we want to add the same amount of margin to its left.
So in summary, we're adding left margin to every list item besides the first one because it already
has some spacing from the now.
Right.
So I'm going to copy this one.
And pace it four more times.
One, two, three, four.
Right here.
I'm going to provide my next menu item text, which is going to be life at Baba Corp..
I'm going to pretend pretend that my company is called Bobo Corp..
You can name your company, your fictional jobs company, whatever you want.
And you'll notice when I say this, prettier is actually going to give us what I think is a slightly
ugly way of representing this text within an anchor tag.
But for now, I'll forgive it.
And then moving on, let's change this locations to how we hire.
And then the next one is going to be students and our final one is going to be jobs.
So we have six menu items.
Let me save the content in my component and head back to my browser so we can observe the changes and
ooh, we are getting somewhere.
This looks pretty good.
We have our company name of bubble careers and we have these six hyperlinks which represent our menu
items from teams to jobs.
And you'll notice how we have that margin to the left of each of the menu items starting from the second,
and we don't need it to the left of the first one.
The only reason I emphasize this right now is because we're actually going to come back to this margin
a little bit later.
We're going to see how Tailwind helps us solve a problem where our first element, our first child element,
has a distinctly different style from every other child element.
We'll talk more about that in a couple of lessons.
But for now, just notice the differences in margin between the elements versus the first list item
and the company name.
All right.
But so far, this is looking pretty good.
So we are going to stick with this.
And before we complete our user story, though, we're going to see how you can help us in situations
like this.
Whenever we have that kind of redundancy of having to copy and paste similar HTML elements, we're going
to take a look in the next lesson.
Add a view directive that could help simplify all the code that we just wrote.
So I will see you there.