All right.
So the good news is that the code changes that we implemented in the previous lesson do work in the
browser.
The bad news is, unfortunately, this change will break our test suite.
So let's run all of our tests using NPM Run Test, Colon Unit.
And we're going to see right here that we are going to get a failing test for the component that we
just modified it, which is job search form.
Right here we can see one failing test.
And if I scroll up right here past all this crazy output, we're going to see it's coming from job search
form that test.
So let's open up that test file.
And this is going to be a relatively easy problem to fix.
But first, I want to talk about why we're seeing it and it kind of makes sense.
So in our previous Options API implementation, we were dependent on a dollar sign router property.
So what we did in our test is we marked it out.
We had a dollar sign router object right here with a push method that was a basic just function and
we provided it to the box property of our configuration object for the amount function so that we have
a dollar sign root or property on our available component.
Well, now we're no longer relying on this, that dollar sign router where we're relying instead on
the router that is returned by the use router function.
And so when our test suite runs, it doesn't know to use a real router, it's still going to run through
the setup method and, and use this function right here.
But it's not going to get a real router in the context of the test suite and so the entire thing is
going to fall apart.
So how do we fix this problem?
Well, we're going to use the exact same principles that we've used throughout the remainder of the
course.
We're still going to mark out the router, but how we do so is going to be a little bit different.
Instead of marking out the marks, probably right here with dollar sign router, all we need to do is
import use router in our test suite, mock it out and have this function when it's marked out and when
we can control what it does, we'll have it.
Mark return a value such as an object with a push method.
So we're going to keep the exact same ideas.
We're still not going to use a real router object because we want to decouple the tests for job search
form from not having to worry about the real view of our implementation.
So we're still going to intercept something and replace it with something else.
We're still going to mark things out in spirit.
However, instead of marking out here, we're going to mark out the use router function.
So when it runs, it's going to rely on our mark, on our substitution, on our replacement.
And right here, we're going to get the mock object that we want so that the rest of the set of method
works as expected.
All right.
So here's what that code is going to look like right here.
I'm going to import.
Use a router and that is going to come from view router.
This is the exact same code that we have in our component.
The one thing that I'm going to add that you may recall from earlier in the course when we were mocking
out things like Axios is we can do just that mark here and provide the name of the library that we want
to mock out.
So here what I want to make out is everything in view router.
So what just is going to do is it's going to run through view router and that's going to include the
use router export and now it's going to replace that with a just mock function.
So now we're going to intercept any call to use router either in this test file or in the components
when they mount.
And it's just going to be a regular just mock function that when invoked, returns undefined.
Now that unfortunately is not good enough because we don't want a mock function that returns undefined.
We need a mock function that returns an object with a push method, because we're going to rely on that
push method right here when the search for jobs function is invoked.
We have the exact same principle right here.
We had our push mock just function and we provided it on the router here.
We're going to follow the exact same principles, except we're going to now intercept our use router
call.
So what I'm going to do here first is I'm going to remove this mock section right here, and we only
have one test in this test file, by the way.
We no longer need to use Mock because we're not marking out dollar sign router so we can remove this.
And here what I'm going to do is we imported use router above.
So I'm going to take that function that is already adjust function so I can invoke the mock return value
method on it.
And that is going to set the return value that that mock function returns when it's invoked.
When is it going to be invoked when we manage our component and run the setup method?
It's going to actually be invoked right here on line 71.
So what we're basically declaring is what we want this to return.
So that router is a sign that object.
So when use router is invoked, I want it to return an object that's going to have a push method.
And of course for push here, I'm referencing the push method on line number ten.
So I'm using S six syntax.
So this push is referring to this just function right here represented by the push constant.
Then we're going to repeat the test as we usually do.
We're going to mount our job search form.
We're going to provide a value right here in the row.
Input a view developer.
We're going to provide a location in the location, text input of Dallas.
We're going to find the submit button and we're going to click it.
And then we're validating the interaction between the component and the push method of the router.
And this test is still going to test for the exact same thing, except push is now just going to be
coming from our use router router instead of our this dollar sign router router.
So we're still testing the interaction.
It's just where we're getting the router from.
That's changed.
And that's also a good piece of news in that most of our components logic or apologies for that.
Most of our test suite's logic has remained the same, right?
Even our assertion here is going to remain the same.
The only thing that's changing is this logic right here, which makes sense because we're using a brand
new implementation in our actual component so we're no longer dependent on this a dollar sign that router.
So this is a normal and expected thing that is breaking.
Our test suite is breaking because of a technical change in how the composition API works, not because
we wrote the wrong assertion or wrote the wrong logic.
So simply by making this change, I'm going to rerun every single test with NPM run test colon unit.
And we're going to see that everything should once again be back to green and indeed it is.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
We basically learned that if we want to mock out something such as the router, we're no longer going
to get it as a global property under this keyword in a component.
So thus we can't replace it that way.
We can't mock it out that way using our configuration object like we used to.
Instead, all we'll need to do is intercept calls to helper functions like use, use, router and have
those mock functions that are the substitutes.
Return whatever value we need a value that is good enough to play the role of the router and the setup
method needs right here.
So in this example, the only thing we need on the router is a basic push method and we also want to
be able to track invocations to that push method.
That's why we used a just the function here.
But push could be anything in theory can be even something like a basic JavaScript function.
As long as it's something invoke able, then that will work because that will be good enough for this
logic we have right here.
All right.
Same exact principles we've talked about throughout the course, just with a little bit of a different
look and feel right now.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see in the next one.