Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to introduce Getters in view.
But before we get there, I want to reiterate the problem that we're trying to solve.
So here in our DB, that JSON file, as a reminder, we have our array of 100 jobs and every job is
going to have an organization property that you can think of as almost like the sub company within our
larger company that this job belongs to.
So this one, as of you and me and this one has YouTube, etc..
And many jobs are going to share the same organization.
So what I want to do is create a unique list or a unique collection of all of the organizations across
these 100 jobs.
So whenever I want to have a unique data structure, the first thought that should come to mind is a
set, especially because we don't care about storing these organizations in any kind of order.
We just need a unique collection of these organizations.
All right.
So with that said, let's open up our configuration file where we set up everything for our view store.
So I'm going to open up my store index that found and here's what it currently looks like.
And I want to do a quick review of what we have here.
And I also want to do it in a way that's interesting.
I want to compare what we have here with the concepts that we've talked about in view components, plane
components.
So for example, the state that we have in our view X Store, we can look at that as very similar to
the data that we have on a component.
This is sort of our starting state.
In this case, this is the state that belongs to the View X Global Store and the components data represents
its own starting state before that component.
Similarly, the idea of a view X mutation is just a method that modifies the existing state.
This is very similar to a method in a view component.
It is able to modify the existing data.
Except in this case of course, it's global and in a component it's local.
So one thing that we're very familiar with in components by now is the idea of computed properties,
right?
We use computed properties whenever we have some kind of data that is not original, but rather is dependent
on or derived from something else.
And in this scenario, we have something very similar because we have this jobs array right here.
This jobs array is going to be populated with 100 jobs whenever action runs.
This fetch jobs action right here, which runs the receive jobs mutation right here to give it the array
of 100 jobs.
And so what we want is a unique collection of organizations based on those 100 jobs.
So that data is not original data.
It's not new data.
It is based on something that already exists in this jobs array.
You can look at it almost like a subset of this jobs array.
We could do this with vanilla JavaScript.
We can iterate over our jobs array.
We can look at every object.
We can take the property for organization and capture all those values.
There's no original data or new data being created here.
It is all dependent or derived on what we already have.
We don't want to create a separate piece of state like organizations here because that piece of state
will be directly related to jobs, which means whenever jobs changes, so must organizations.
And thus we have two sources of truth.
So why do we use computed properties in our components?
Whenever we want Vue to automatically rerun a bit of logic when some other core data changes.
Why do we use getters in view X for the exact same reason?
Whenever we want to create some kind of computed logic that is going to rerun whenever a piece of our
original store state changes.
Right.
So whenever our jobs change, we want this other thing to rerun automatically to recalculate the new,
unique organizations.
And that is a data point that is not, you know, original.
It is dependent or derived on this.
So that's exactly what we use getters for.
We use getters to define a derived piece of logic from our store state, alternate representations of
our state, or subsets of our store state.
It could be whatever we want as long as it's not original data.
All right.
So let me show you how this is going to work and then we'll talk more about the advantages as we proceed.
So what I'm going to do.
Is directly below our mutations.
I'm going to declare another object which I will export, and I'm going to call that getters.
So export concern getters, plural.
I'm going to make an empty object for now.
And before I forget, I'm going to wired up to our create store function right here.
So this configuration object can expect a getters property.
I'm going to provide it like so and so using E-6 syntax.
We're simply going to provide this object right here.
So very much like our mutations object, this getters object is simply going to consist of a bunch of
methods.
And each of those methods is going to receive the current store state.
So this object as it currently is.
And then what the getter can do is simply say, I have the store state.
Let me generate a new bit of data based on it or dependent on it.
So in a getter you should never modify store state, you should never add properties, delete properties,
etc. All you can do in a getter is use the existing store state properties to give you something new,
something else.
And that's exactly what we want.
We want a unique set of organizations from our existing jobs.
All right.
So we're going to follow a very similar protocol to what we have here.
We're going to use constants to describe the name of our getters.
So right here, I'm going to declare a new exported constant, and I'm going to call it unique organizations.
That's exactly what we want.
We want a collection of unique organizations.
All right.
And what I'm going to do in my getters object is I'm going to declare a method and I'm going to use
my square bracket syntax to access that unique organization's constant above.
Just so that I provide that string as the getter method name and just so we can reuse that constant
in case it's needed elsewhere.
Okay.
So just like a mutation, each getter is going to receive the current store state in its first parameter
called state.
And any time the state changes view X can automatically rerun the getter for us in the exact same way
that you can.
Our view rather can automatically rerun a computed property whenever data changes.
So here.
In the body of this method.
We can do whatever we want with the store state.
So let's create a set consisting of the unique organizations.
I'll begin by defining a constant called unique organizations, and I'll set that equal to be a new
set object.
And then what I want to do is iterate over my current state, take each jobs organization and add it
to the set that I've defined in the line above.
So we know that we have our current store state available via the state object that view X is automatically
going to pass in.
So that is this thing right here on that state object.
We have a jobs property that's going to be an array.
It's going to start out empty.
And then when we get the response from our mock backend, it's now going to be an array of 100.
What do I want to do?
I want to iterate over each one of those job objects.
I can do that in JavaScript using the for each loop.
We can also do this with a basic for loop, but I think this is pretty simple.
So for each is a method we can invoke and it accepts a function and that function represents what JavaScript
is going to do for each individual element that it iterates over.
So in this case, we're going to iterate over each individual job.
So I'm going to provide that as my parameter here.
And what do I want to do with each individual job?
Well, I want to get its organization, which I can do via the organization property.
This is the exact same property that we just saw in DB that Jason.
And then what I want to do is I want to add it to my set.
So right here, unique organizations is my set is set, has an add method and we can pass in the current
organization that we are iterating over.
So the beautiful part about this is if we're iterating over 100 jobs and we have, for example, six
unique organizations, then each time we try adding a duplicate to our set, the set is simply going
to not keep it.
So at the very end of this iteration, our set is just going to have an unordered collection of all
of the unique organizations across all of our jobs.
And if our jobs are changes, then the getter will rerun and generate this new derived property, this
new derived data of a set consisting of the new unique organizations.
So then the most important thing here, of course, is we have the set, but we have to actually return
it as the final return value of this getter method.
All right.
So obviously, it may not make perfect sense to you now because we haven't used the scanner, but the
idea now is in a sample component, we're going to be able to use this getter, which is going to talk
to the state and get us a set of the unique organizations which are ultimately going to form the checkboxes
that we see on the left hand side of the job results page, because we want a checkbox for every unique
organization within our jobs results because that's how the user is going to filter the jobs that they
see on the right hand side.
So another question you might have is, okay, I understand what a getter is doing.
It's basically just filtering and giving me the this derived data.
But why do we need it?
The getter.
For example, in a component, since we have access to this dollar sign store and then the state, can
we do this logic within a component?
And you're absolutely right, we can rewrite this entire logic within a component.
But the problem with that approach is that we are then isolating this logic to a single component.
Imagine that this logic is reusable.
Imagine that multiple components need to be able to get a list of unique organizations.
Now, by having it in a getter, each component is going to be able to call the same getter in the exact
same way they can call a mutation, and it's going to be able to get this exact same data structure.
And every time the state changes, it's going to get it again.
So we're once again utilizing the general benefits of UCS.
We are moving a lot of our business logic away from individual components to just plain JavaScript methods
and functions.
Up above this very similar to our mutations is very simple to test in isolation because it doesn't actually
need a component to exist.
It's just a plane method that accepts an object, then iterates over it and creates a set.
Right?
It has no construct of a view component, and thus we can isolate it, we can test it by itself, and
then we can reuse it in as many components as needed.
So that is the advantage of getters.
Yes, you can use this logic in a component, but now we've isolated it, made it more testable, and
made it more reusable.
That's why we have getters, because instead of having computed logic in each component, we can now
have the same idea but directly related to our view store state.
Here is our starting data.
Here is how we modify it and here's how we get some kind of derived information from it that is secondary
and or based off our original data.
All right.
So let me delete this comment right here that should take care of this lesson.
In the very next lesson, we're going to test this getter method.
And then afterwards, of course, we're going to wire up this getter in a sample component.
So lots to look forward to.
And I will see you in the next lesson.