All right.
In this lesson, we're going to learn about props.
And props allow a parent component to feed in custom data to a child component.
But before we get there, I want to introduce the problem that we currently have in action.
But as we mentioned earlier, we have this hardcoded text sign in right here on line 14, which means
every time we render an action button, we're going to have the same text on it, sign in.
And of course we want this to be flexible so that we can reuse this action button and reuse it styles,
but provide a different value for the text that the button is going to display.
Otherwise, of course, we would have to create a new view component for every different type of text
that we would have to render, and that would create a lot of duplication for no reason.
So how can we customize this piece of text?
Well, we can't do it here in action button because this is the actual component.
So where we can do it is on the parent component.
And just to explain the concepts of parent and child.
So they're clear the component that is rendering another component is called the parent component,
and the component that is actually being rendered is called the child.
So in this scenario, in our main NAV component, we are rendering the action button component right
here on line 34.
So the main nav component is the parent of the action button component.
You can almost think of it like a hierarchical relationship.
Main nav is one level above the action button.
So just like get an ancestry diagram, main nav is kind of one level higher.
So it is the parent while the descendant of the child is the action button component.
And of course if the action button component was rendering its own components, then those would be
the children of Action button.
So a view component can be both a parent and a child.
The one that is rendering a component is the parent, and then the actual component component being
rendered is the child.
So what we really want to do is be able to pass in custom data to our child component to action button
from the parent.
And the way that we can do that is using a view feature called Props.
You can think of a prop as an attribute that we pass to a component or alternatively an input that we
can pass to a component from the parent that renders it.
And when we pass a prop, it becomes available as a property that we can render in the template of our
child component.
It's the exact same syntax that we actually use for interpolation, the curly braces that we've used
before for data, we can reuse that here.
The only difference being here that we are not getting that value from our components data, we're getting
it from our parent props for what's called a one way or a uni directional binding.
The reason it's called unidirectional is it because it flows in one direction, it flows from the parent
to the channel.
And that's important to to note, because what that means is whenever the parent property updates,
if the parent, for example, is feeding a dynamic value as a prop to the child, whenever the value
changes in the parent, that change will flow downwards to the child component.
The reason it's called unidirectional is because changes will only flow down.
They're going to flow from the parent to the child.
They will never flow in reverse, or, in other words, from the child to the parent.
And if that's confusing, don't worry.
We're going to talk more about it as we see more examples of props.
But the basic just here is that we're going to provide action button with the text right here that we'd
like the action by to render and by rendering it here.
Every single time that we render an action by, we can provide a different piece of text for it to render.
All right.
So it's going to be a two step process.
And let's actually start with action button right here.
I'd like you to imagine that this component is going to get a prop from its parent or, in other words,
an input, a piece of data from its parent that we're going to call text.
All right.
That's just an arbitrary name I've chosen.
I'm going to call it text.
And as I mentioned earlier, we can render a prop value just like we render any data value by using
curly braces.
So let's imagine right now that we've received a piece of data from our parent.
You can almost think of it like a variable, and that variable is called text.
I'm going to render it right here using curly braces.
So I'm going to put the double curly braces and I'm going to write the word text in here.
Now, I know it's not clear where text is coming from.
And just to reiterate, it's going to come from our parent component, May NAV in just a second, but
let's pretend we have it for the time being.
So there's one more thing we need to do an action button to allow us to use this prop called text,
and that is to add an additional property to our view configuration object called props.
All right.
And props is going to be an array where we provide strings representing the props or, in other words,
the inputs that this component will receive from its parent.
So obviously, if we're using a a piece of information called text in The View right here, we need
to specify that our prop is going to be called text.
If we had more than one prop than we would simply provide more than one.
A value within this array, we can ignore this temporary s lint warning.
We're going to come back to this in just a second.
This is totally valid view syntax.
So what we have specified here is that action button expects to receive an input from its parent, which
we're going to call a prop, and that input is going to be called text.
And then whatever the value of text is from the parent, we're going to render it right here as our
button text within the timeout.
So that takes care of one half of the equation.
Obviously, the other half of the equation is going to our parent component right here, our main NAV,
which is rendering our action one component and then specifying what the value of this text prop is
going to be.
The way we provide a prop to a component is the exact same way as we write an HTML attribute.
So right here, after the values, I can provide the name of a prop.
What is the name of the prop or the input that I want to give to my action button?
I want it to be called text and then I provide an equal sign in a string and here is where I provide
the value for that text prop.
So in other words, this is the value that the action button will receive from its parent and render
right here.
So let's say right now, I'm just going to provide an arbitrary text of whatever I want.
I'm going to save this.
All right.
And that's going to cause pretty or to reform it.
And now I'm going to navigate back to my browser.
And just as expected, we now have a custom text of whatever I want in the button.
Let me go ahead and open up my view devtools so we can see how this works.
I'm going to go to view and I'm going to select my main nav and my action button and you're going to
see the view dev tools in addition to showing us the data on a component is going to show us the props.
Props and data are not the same thing.
The data is the data that lives inside the component which you specify using the data method.
The props is the data that is flowing in from the parent.
So again, our main parent is feeding in this prop called text to our action button component.
All right.
This component right here is going to feed in the prop to action.
But so, of course, the beautiful part about this design is now we can reuse or action by the component
and provide whatever text we want.
So if I simply render action button below one more time, how can I provide a different value for the
text prop?
Well, I can simply provide a text prop and give it a totally different value.
So right here I'll write something simple like different value, although it can be whatever string
we want.
All right, once again, this prop is going to flow into this component.
And when we go back to my browser, we have our second action one right here, and it has a totally
different prop of different value or a different text, that prop value of different values.
If I refresh this, I should be able to see two action buttons in my view.
Here it is.
You can see it has a text prop with a totally different string value of different value.
All right.
So that's the core idea of props.
It's some kind of information or data that we can pass down from a parent to a child, which gives us
a lot of flexibility because that child doesn't have to hard code any a values such as a piece of text
and a button.
Rather, the parent can tell the button what it needs to do or what kind of data it should use through
the form of props.
So I'm going to remove my second rendering of the action button component because we don't need it.
And then obviously to make a display in the original text, I can write sign in here.
So right here we are going to right sign in.
But the reason that this is a better approach is if we ever need to reuse the action by component,
we can now customize whatever we fit in and the button will render it.
Now our action button is more flexible, it's more dynamic.
It can serve many different purposes now as a general action, but rather than specifically being just
a sign in button.
All right, so that is all there is to cover.
In this lesson, we introduced the idea of props.
A prop is just an input that a parent company provides to a child component.
This data right now, this text prop is hardcoded.
It's always going to be signed in in this case.
But it can be dynamic, which we'll look at later.
And the key takeaway is whenever this prop value changes, that change will flow down into the action
button component.
So if the value of text changes, action by will re render its button text to reflect the change that
it got from its parent component, which just may now have now that flow of data is usually directional
or one directional, which means it only flows one way from the parent to the child.
There's no way the child can alter the value of text and send that back up to the parent.
That is impossible in view.
The only thing that is possible is for the parent component to render the value or change the value
of the text prop, and that change will flow down into our action by component.
All right.
Lots more to talk about with props and of course, lots more practice up ahead.
So I will see you in the next lesson.