In this lesson we'll talk about multiple described blocks ingest and also walk through a typical development
workflow as it comes to writing our implementation code and the corresponding tests.
So the first thing I want to do is open up my playground gorgeous file.
We created this file earlier to experiment with JavaScript code, so I'm just going to use command P
on my Mac to bring up my fuzzy file search.
You can use control p on windows and I'm going to search for my playground dot jazz file and open it
up.
If it has any code in it, feel free to delete it.
And then what I'm going to do is click and drag my playground, that test that just filed.
I'm just going to drag it to the right side of this code until it occupies this kind of right half of
the screen.
We can see it highlighted right here on my screen, and I'm going to place it here.
And the idea here is that my playground just filed.
My implementation will live on the left.
I'm going to write some code in here in just a second, and then I'm going to import the functionality
from this file into my playground, that test file, and write the corresponding tests.
In other words, I like to have my actual code and my tests side by side.
I find that it generally helps to remind me what it is that I've written and what it is and how it is
that I'm testing.
So in here, in our playground file, let's write a very simple JavaScript function.
It's going to be called even odd, and it's going to accept a number and return a string that specifies
whether that number is even or odd.
So right here, I'm going to export a constant.
It's going to be my function called even or odd.
This is not a default export.
It's just a regular named export.
Keep that in mind when we import in just a second and it's going to be a basic arrow function that'll
take a parameter called number.
And I'm going to declare my body right here.
And I'm just going to do a very simple implementation using a F statement and an L statement.
So if my number is even, which I can determine by taking the modulo of my number.
By two and checking if the remainder that's left over is zero.
If that's the case, I have an even number because there is no remainder when it is divided by two.
If that's the case, I'm going to return a string of even else.
If my number does have a remainder, I know that it is odd so I can return the string odd, save it
and will do its thing.
And now we have a valid JavaScript function.
So now let's go ahead and import it within my playground.
That test that you have file.
So right here at the very top I'm going to import and this is a named export, so I have to provide
my curly braces here.
I'm going to import even more odd than I have to specify on my file.
So from we know that we have my asterisk directory as that assigned so directly at the top level of
that folder, I have my playground file and I can import it like so we don't even need the dot JS extension.
All right.
So this is a case where we have some existing tests already that test the basic math and we also have
a new function that we write that we'd like to test called even or odd.
And there's many different approaches that we can take here.
We can create a different described block right here, for example, we can write even or odd right
here because that is that is what we're testing and we can provide a function and this is totally valid
syntax for just what I'm going to do though is show you that we can nest multiple described blocks within
each other.
So I'm just going to copy this code and just place it directly below my edit function calls and that
is totally valid syntax.
We can nest as many describes as we want inside each other.
The idea being that each one is kind of a subcategory or a sub header for the top level described that
you have in your file.
So in this case we can almost assume like even our odd is some kind of extension of basic math.
This is really up to you as a developer how you like to categorize your code that you write.
Generally speaking, what I'd recommend is you should have one test file per JavaScript file in your
project, so you shouldn't import things from multiple files generally and test them all in one test
file because the test file will get pretty bloated in size.
But even if you import just one thing, there may be different states or categories of testing that
thing.
And that's why you can use multiple described blocks to kind of nested the logic of categorization.
You know, I have this main thing A and then two things within it, a one and a two that I want to segment
and isolate for the readers benefit and for the output.
And that's why you might nest multiple describes inside other describes all right and we can get even
further even further down take this even one level higher.
So let's say within my describe for even or odd I want to describe the two situations that I might encounter
or in other words, the two branches of logic that exist in my even or odd function.
My first situation is that my number argument is even.
And my second one is that it's odd, right?
Generally speaking, what I try to avoid is something like this.
Instead of having an IT statement that reads, it indicates number is even when number is even.
So you kind of put the condition right here in the in the actual test itself.
And I think that makes the test description longer and harder to read.
Whenever you have that kind of criteria or condition or specific scenario that you're testing.
What I prefer to do is just nested under an additional describe, right?
You should not be afraid to use describe as often as needed.
So what I'm going to do here is just put another describe here.
When I'm testing my even or odd function, I want to describe when the number is even so a specific
criteria within my even or odd test.
I'm going to provide my callback function right here and I'm going to provide my IT function or my test
right here.
So it indicates the number is even this test is kind of a little bit redundant because it's very similar
to my describe, but hopefully it indicates the benefit is that when you have some kind of setup or
criteria or conditional branch, you can use a describe to segment that and isolate it.
So when our number is even, it indicates the number is even.
And that test offers another developer chance to understand exactly what it is that you're testing.
So right here I can invoke my expect function inside those parentheses I'm going to invoke even or odd
and then inside here I also have to invoke even or odd to actually give it an argument and let's give
it a valid even number like four.
And of course afterwards I can write my assertion once again, I'm going to use that to be matcher.
But this time around I need to provide a string.
I expect this to be the string of even.
All right, I'm going to save this file.
Just so prettier does its formatting.
And this is an example of a test within a describe, with an A describe, with an A describe.
So now let's write one more test for the complementary path, which is odd.
So right here after this describe but still within my even or odd, I'm going to write another describe
function call and say when the number is odd.
I'm going to say it indicates the number is odd.
Notice here that what I'm trying to do in my test descriptions is not specifically talk about the return
value, literally.
So I tried to make my test descriptions as not specific to the implementation as possible.
So to be super specific would be to write a test like this.
It returns this string odd, right?
This is a test that is not describing the user value or describing the general higher purpose abstraction
of what the function is doing.
This is a test that is reaching super deep into the actual implementation of what it is that you've
written.
And that logic should be written in your expect, because that's the actual point where JavaScript is
going to be running your code.
What I prefer is that the IT statement describes in general human readable terms what the purpose of
the function is.
The purpose of our even or odd function is to indicate that a number is even or odd.
And with the described, we say at what situation should it indicate each of those scenarios?
Right.
So then in my actual assertion in my expected statement, when I invoke even an odd with an odd number
such as three, then I write the specific implementation test that when I invoke the function, it should
be the literal string.
Odd.
All right.
So a developer can really expect to know exactly how the code works and they can read the describe,
and it's to understand the purpose of it or the benefit of your code.
All right.
So now that my tests are written, I'm once again going to open a new terminal window.
And I'm going to get rid of my playground file for now.
Just so we can see everything side by side.
And once again, my command is going to be and PM run test colon unit.
We're going to run the file.
We're going to see that it's going to identify the playground that tests that.
Yes.
File.
And now notice for each described block, it's going to nest that content one level deeper.
So we're going to start with basic math.
We see these assertions that deal with basic math.
Then we know we've gotten to some additional organizational logic called even or odd, which a developer
can figure out as a function.
And then that function has different pathways, such as when the numbers even are, when the number
is odd.
And then we again describe in human readable terms what that test tests are, what it validates.
Right.
So notice in the output, we're not actually seeing any specific technical details.
We're just seeing this nice organizational structure for our tests.
And it's going to be the exact same when we write our view components.
We're going to describe the benefit of the view component and the benefit of what it is that we're testing
without trying to reach too deep into the view component internals.
We'll talk more about the principles of testing and why that is a good approach later.
But this is the basic principle we're going to be following as we write all of our tests throughout
the course.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
And in the very next one, we're going to talk about test driven development.