Okay.
So let's take a look at how JSON the server is going to return data to us at a given endpoint.
Before we get there, though, there is one extension that I recommend you install in Google Chrome
that makes it easier to read and decipher JSON.
So if you go to Google and you search for JSON view Chrome and you had to this first link JSON view
is a Chrome extension that's going to format your JSON response so that it looks like an actual JavaScript
object and you get features like collapse, ability, expandability, etc. Otherwise if you don't have
this extension, you're just going to receive the JSON as one big string blob and it becomes hard to
figure out what the actual properties are.
So I do strongly recommend installing this extension.
You're going to see an install button right here I already have installed, but you can see that install
button.
You can press it.
And then Jason, we should automatically launch into action.
And any time you access an endpoint that returns JSON, you're going to then see that JSON response
nicely formatted.
So let's hit a sample endpoint that returns JSON, let's launch our Jason server.
So I'm going to go to my terminal and I'm going to run the command we set up in the package.
JSON found the previous lesson, so NPM run followed by our command, which we called backend.
Let me run that and you're going to see that it's going to launch JSON server, it's going to watch
Idbi JSON file.
This little guy is really happy and says hi and you'll notice here it says resources.
It's available at local host 3000 jobs.
That is the endpoint that we defined.
So let us go into our browser.
And let us now go to local host 3000 so local host colon 3000 slash jobs.
The 3000 refers to the port on your computer where this app or this server is running.
So localhost is your computer.
3000 is the port.
And then remember, we actually set up our endpoint to be specifically slash jobs.
So we have to go to that endpoint to get our jobs results.
So I'm going to access this page and you'll see it popped into place very quickly.
Just it was text originally and then JSON view formatted it into a nice response.
So here is the exact same data that we had in our DB, that JSON file and we're now able to access it
at this endpoint.
So this is just like a URL on the web, except it is a URL that is running on our computer, but it's
no different in the real world.
Somebody would give you some kind of API, URL that you can hit in your app to get data.
And here is the data that we're going to be receiving when we hit that endpoint.
And this is 100 sample jobs that we can play around with and render a job listing for in our view app.
So hopefully the benefits of JSON server are pretty clear in a parent's very cool NPM package.
And with that, we have effectively our back end and we can go back to view and start making a request
for this data and then reacting to that data when we receive it.