All right.
So in the previous lesson, we created our job search view app.
Our next step is to show this app in our web browser.
And the output right here tells us exactly how to do that.
We have to navigate into our job search folder, and this is a command that you should write down or
memorize, become very familiar with and PM Run.
Serve is going to be the command that runs the View app in our browser.
So let's go ahead and navigate into our directory with the KD command and run, NPM, run, serve.
This process can take up to a couple of seconds.
It has to build up all the files transpire them, which we talked about earlier.
That's the process for Babble.
It's going to take our view code and convert it to HTML, CSS and JavaScript that the browser can understand
it when it's done.
You're going to see this message compile successfully and it's going to give you a port on local host,
which is your computer, where you can access this app.
Now, normally what this should do is open up a web browser with the app, and if you see that, that's
great.
If it doesn't do that, then what you can do is open up your web browser of choice, in my case Chrome,
and simply navigate to this URL in the browser and you should see the app.
So let me do that right here.
I'm going to drag over my Google Chrome Web browser from the other screen and right here, right in
the URL bar.
I'm going to follow this path right here.
Local host Colon 80.
So local host colon 80 and that's going to take you to your view app and welcome.
This is a running view up in our browser.
Welcome to your Vue.js app and it's going to provide you of course with links to the UCI documentation.
It's going to tell you about some of the plugins that it automatically installed for you, some essential
links to check out the ecosystem review, which we talked about earlier.
Those are some of the related tools that are developed by the team that we're going to be working with
a little bit later on, of course.
But this is a running Vue app, right?
That's it.
That's all the earliest to cover in this lesson.
If you see this, then everything is set up successfully and we are all clear to start exploring the
code that powers the web page that you see right here.
I'll see you in the next lesson.