Okay.
So in the previous lesson we learned that from the setup method we can return a JavaScript object whose
properties will be available for us to use in the HTML template.
So if we take a quick look at our accordion HTML template, you'll notice that there's actually four
different names that we're using throughout.
That were previously coming from the script section of the component.
The first one we took care of in the previous lesson, which is header, but there's also three more.
There's open right here, which represents a method.
That open method was formerly right here.
We also have the care icon reference right here.
That is also a name and that is the name of a computed property that we have also commented out.
And we also have is open here, which was a former data property right here.
So in case it isn't a parent, in order to get all of the original functionality to work from the HTML,
we're going to need to eventually have an object with those four properties.
Header care icon is open and open.
All right.
That's where eventually we're trying to move towards.
Before we get there, I want to introduce a new problem that we're going to try to solve in this lesson.
So we know that we have a click handler.
We have a reaction to the click event right here that runs a method called Open.
What I want to do is implement that method.
And what I also want to happen is when that method runs, I want to change the header text that I display
right here in my H3.
All right.
So let's take it one step at a time.
We know that if we want this open name available to be used in our template, we have to return it as
a property in this object from the setup method.
So what I'm going to do right here is I'm going to define a basic open arrow function.
So right here, let's do open.
Let's make it a basic arrow function right in line.
And I'm going to return or rather make sure I include open as a property here.
This part is critical because this is the object that actually declares which of your constants and
which ones which ones of your variables here are actually going to be included in the available template
names to be used.
Right.
So simply declaring open right here but not including it in the object will not make it available.
But by adding open here, we are now able to use open anywhere in our template.
And actually this is enough to get our click handler to work.
So if we were to click on this div in the browser, the VON Directive would react to that click by running
the open function, which we defined right here.
Now the good news is, is this logic is already actually going to work.
That's all we need to do.
We need to define a function in our setup method and return it in the object and now it's able to work.
The only issue, of course, is that the function right now does absolutely nothing.
So let's say that I want in this function to alter the value of my header value right here.
So the only place where we have access to header in our actual setup method is right here in this constant.
So let's try a proposed idea that we think might work.
It won't actually work, but it's moving us in the right direction.
So I want to show you the the the step by step path.
Let's say we think about it this way.
Imagine that in our setup method we make header a variable by using lat instead of const, which means
we're able to reassign header to a new value.
Then when my open method runs, what I want to do is take my header variable in this setup method and
I want to reassign it to another string.
So let's say I provide a string of awesome title.
So even though this is not going to work, hopefully my intent here is clear.
I'm going to export header and I'm going to also include an export of an open function that's going
to modify the header variable right here.
So my hope is when I click this div, I hope that this will change, which will in turn change the text
in H in the H3 right here.
So just to show you this will not work, let me go to my browser and I'm going to click on Cool Title
here.
You'll see nothing is actually changing when I click this, but this is still moving us in the right
direction.
Okay.
So in order to solve this problem, we're going to need to introduce a function that we learned about
in the previous section and it is the ref function.
You may recall the what the ref function does is it creates a reactive object, an object with a value
property.
And more importantly than that, it's going to keep track of any changes to it.
All right.
So let's import ref right here and be very careful here because you want to import ref from view the
plain view library view.
Make sure you don't accidentally do it from view X.
It's coming from view right now.
As a reminder, we can simply invoke the ref function and pass in anything we want.
A string, a number, boolean, an object.
It's going to wrap that in an object that has a value property.
So here's how we're going to solve this problem.
I'm going to wrap this string in a ref function call.
So now what Heitor is going to represent is going to be a reactive object.
I'm actually going to change this to be a concert.
And what I want the open method to do where the open function is still do the same thing.
I want to change the value that is being stored inside this reactive object.
You may recall from the previous section that whenever I want to alter the internal value in that reactive
object, I have to overwrite its value property.
So I can't just do header equals.
I have to do header that value equals.
Okay.
And the rest.
I'm going to keep the same.
I'm still going to return an object with header and open properties.
Right.
Now, one thing that may be a little bit confusing is header is no longer a string when we return it.
It's an actual object, but yet we're interpolating had a right here as if it's a regular piece of text.
Well, as you can probably guess, Vue is going to be very smart about this, even though header is
technically a reactive object whenever we use it in an interpolation context like this.
What Vue is going to say is you gave me a reactive object.
I'm going to look inside the value property of that object, and that's what I'm actually going to display
on the screen.
So it's still going to display a string, a piece of text on the string, even though a header represents
a reactive object.
The benefit of having a reactive object, however, is whenever the value property changes whenever
the internal content, in this case the internal string changes.
You guessed it, Vue is going to notice that change.
It's going to notice that change because the reactive object is tracking it.
And whenever the reactive object's value changes, Vue is going to update the corresponding piece of
the template.
So whenever a header reactive object changes, Vue is going to update line eight where we are interpolating
headers value in our template.
So this is going to be enough to get the logic to work in our browser.
So one more time to quickly review, we're using header here as a reactive object that stores a initial
value of cool title.
We are declaring an open function and all that open function is going to do is change the value of that
reactive object.
So hopefully this bit is not too confusing.
We talked about these ideas in isolation in the previous section of the course.
It's very important that we return an object with both of these properties because this is where we
actually establish the properties that are available to use in the accordion HTML template.
So now we are able to use header right here and we are able to use open right here.
Open is going to run as a function.
It's going to be invoked by view whenever we click on the div.
When it runs, it's going to alter the value of the header reactive object, switching the value to
be a string which is going to alter the string that is printed or interpolated right here in my H3.
So let's switch to our browser and let's see this in action.
All right.
So we're going to start out with cool title.
Cool title.
Watch what happens when I click this.
We're going to run our open function and there we go.
It's going to change the reactive object.
We're going to change the interpolated value.
I'm going to click this one right here.
Same thing, this one right here, same thing.
All right.
So we're making really good progress here.
We've now covered two of the four names that we are using our HTML template.
And in the upcoming lessons, I'm going to keep chipping away at the other names we have throughout
this template.
So I'll see you there.