All right, so let's use test driven development or TDD to build out the next feature.
So as a reminder, what TDD means is that we're going to write a test first and intentionally failing
test that's going to test what we want.
And then using the failures that we see in our console, we're going to use that to actually implement
the real world test, and that's going to validate that we are testing the right thing, that we are
writing a test that describes the value rather than the implementation.
Okay.
So in my get jobs test file, I'm going to get rid of this console.log.
And the reason of course I have access to imported and here is because I need to mark it out.
I can assume that in my eventual implementation I'm going to be using Axios to make a request and I
need to make sure that I mark it out.
So we're not using the real Axios library when we run the test for this helper function.
So what I'd like to do is import the eventual function that we're going to write.
I'm going to assume that it exists already, because remember, with test driven development, we don't
have any actual code yet, but we write it as if we do.
So I'm going to assume that I can import a get jobs function and where is it going to come from?
It's going to come from the file on the left.
So from the source directory, the API folder, we have a get jobs file and I'm going to assume that
I'm going to have a default export, which is my get jobs function.
And below I'm going to describe that I'm test and get jobs and I'm going to provide an arrow function.
And here I can write a test description that is not specific to the implementation.
So what is the responsibility of this function?
Without knowing how it's going to work, this function should fetch the jobs the candidate can apply
to.
So right here it fetches jobs that candidates can apply to.
I provide the business value and the value to a user as well as to a product manager who might read
this without worrying about exactly how I'm going to build it out.
All right.
So right here, I'm going to assume, of course, that I'm going to invoke the get jobs method.
And I'm going to assume that this method or function, to be more specific, is going to be asynchronous.
It's going to reach out to an API, which is an asynchronous operation that's going to take some amount
of time.
So I'm going to assume that this function is going to return a promise.
And when I use the word assume, I'm basically saying I write the test in the way that I would like
to interact with my eventual implementation.
That's sort of the fun part, is that using TDD, we can sketch out how we would like this function
to work.
So I'm going to assume that get jobs is going to return me a promise.
And so I'm going to assume that I can await it right here.
And if we're using the await keyword right here, I can use async right here.
Okay.
So we have an asynchronous test that's going to run the get jobs function that will eventually define
and wait for it to complete and give us back a promise.
So what do we want to test here?
Well, if we go back to our original implementation in job listings, we really want to test that.
It's hitting this new URL right here.
In a way, we sort of cheated TDD because we have our eventual code right here.
But this is eventually going to be the code that we write in our get jobs function.
So what I really want to test now that I have mocked at Axios is that I have called the get method on
the Axios object and that I have provided the right URL to hit.
Now as a reminder, we are getting this URL by concatenating slash jobs to our base URL, which is coming
from an environment variable that we configure in our test environment.
As a reminder, we configured that environment variable in the dot envy that test, that local file.
So here we set up that environment variable of view our API URL to be HTP, my fake API icon.
So we should expect that Axios dot get is going to reach out to Mike, my fake API icon slash jobs.
Right.
That's combining this setup for our test with what we know will be the slash jobs endpoint that we defined
in JSON server.
So right here I'm going to write expect Axios dot get.
And in order to test that, a mock function has been invoked as a reminder, we can use a helper method
here called to have been called with which will test not just that Axios target has been invoked, but
that it has been invoked with the correct argument.
So what I, what I expect here, I expect http, Colin slash, slash, the exact same thing I have right
here.
In fact, I can even copy it.
That will probably be the better way.
So I expect htp, colon, slash, slash my fake API, nbc.com slash jobs.
And that's my first test simply that I am reaching out to the right endpoint.
Okay, so we're going to get a whole bunch of failures and that's totally fine.
We can now use TDD to follow these failures to an eventual implementation that works.
So right here we can see our first issue is get jobs.
Default is not a function.
So what's happening is the test suite right here is trying to import get jobs, but obviously there's
nothing in this file, so it's running into an error.
So pretty simple.
We can just define a simple get jobs error function.
And I'm not going to go any further than that because I don't want to violate TDD, I just want to define
this function and I also need to export it because otherwise the file will not be able to import it
and that's the test fault.
So all I'm doing is writing the bare minimum code to get my failure to go away and move on to the next
failure.
My first error is that we cannot import a get jobs function, so now I am defining it and exporting
it.
So now we move on to the next failure and we follow that approach until we get a passing test.
So that way we can kind of solve one small problem, one small issue at a time until we get to a valid
implementation.
Okay.
So now we're getting that we expected to hit my fake API dot com slash jobs one time, but instead we
had no calls.
Right.
So what are we testing?
That Axios stat get has been called so we can do that in our in our implementation.
So in my in my get jobs file, I'm going to import the Axios library from Axios.
Right and right here in the body, I'm going to use Axios target, which in our test will be mocked
out with a just mock function.
Right.
So for example, if I do simply Axios target and I provide nonsense.
Let's see where this gets us.
We're going to see now that the test output is telling us, hey, I did get get invoked.
The Axios get method was invoked, but I got an argument of nonsense when I was expecting this.
So once again, we can use the failure here to drive us to the right implementation.
We know that we need a specific URL, not just that get was invoked, but that get was invoked with
a specific string argument.
So right here I'm going to write out the exact argument.
I expect htp, colon, slash, slash my fake API, ecom slash jobs.
Save that and we're going to get a passing test.
So as you may recall, we have a a protocol in test driven development called red green refactor.
So we were first in our red stage, which means we have a passing error failing test.
That's why it's red.
Like a stoplight.
Basically means stop.
Then we go into the green stage, which means we get the bare minimum to get a passing test.
And then the final stage is the refactor stage where we make the implementation better while keeping
an eye on the existing test runner to make sure that we haven't broken our original working implementation.
So the reason this is not perfect is because now we've hardwired a constant URL of my fake API.
This is not going to work in the real world because remember, my fake API is something that is only
valid for our test suite.
So in our job listings component, remember we are relying on this environment variable to specify the
beginning of that of that string representing our backend, whatever it happens to be.
It can be a fake API for our test suite, but it needs to be the real JSON server for our real life
implementation and it needs to be something else if we're hosting our view up in production.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this code right here and I'm going to paste it right here,
and then I'm going to use the exact same interpolation syntax I used in job listings instead of manually
writing out.
The actual my fake API right here.
I'm going to get it from my base URL constant above, which is going to get that URL from this environment
variable which we've defined to be this value in this file.
So right here I'm going to swap this with F6 template strings and I'm going to replace this with a dollar
sign and then a reference to base URL.
So our test was passing and when I save this, our test should still pass.
So our core implementation is valid.
However, this is the refactor because this is the correct approach.
Now when we run this in production or when we run this in development, even when we look at our view
up in the browser, this is going to be a totally different string.
When we're running in development mode.
In development mode, it's going to be this string which we defined in the end v development local file.
It's going to be the URL we need to hit JSON server, which we're also running on our computer.
However, for our test files, for our test environment, we have a totally different value for the
same environment variable.
All right.
So if we simply kept my fake API here, we would reach out to my fake API in our browser in development
mode, and that would not exist and we would run into a failure.
Now we can dynamically test this part of the URL or dynamically customize it while testing the core
logic of the get jobs function, which is that it is invoking Axios get with the correct URL based on
the configuration that we provided for the test environment.
All right.
So this is a good place to leave off.
In the very next lesson, we're going to continue using TDD to further our implementation of our get
jobs function.