Okay.
So in the next lesson, we're going to start building out our accordion view component.
And in order to do that, we're going to need to add some new font, awesome icons to our project.
We're going to need icons to represent the carrot symbols on the right side of the accordion header.
As a reminder, they are those symbols, those angles almost that allow us to click the accordion to
expand it and then again to collapse it.
And we're going to get those icons from font.
Awesome.
The place in our app where we configure that is in our main J.S. File.
As a reminder, it is here in this file where we imported our face search font, awesome icon.
That is our magnifying glass that we've used throughout the app.
And so what we need to do is import and register two more icons from font.
Awesome.
So that we can use them in our components.
We need to make them available.
So right here from this library of four awesome free solid SVG icons in addition to importing f.A Search
font awesome search, I also want to import F a angle down and angle up.
Make sure you spelled those names correctly and these are the respective carried symbols.
The angle down is the carrot that points down.
The angle up is the one that points up.
These almost look like the less than and greater than sines, except they are of course, pointed down
and up.
But that's basically what those icons look like.
All right.
And in addition to importing them, we also have to register them with our font.
Awesome library here.
You can see we invoke the add method on our imported library object and pass in f.A Search.
We're going to need to do the exact same thing for our two new ones.
So right here, library add essay angle down and library add invoke that method pass in the font awesome
icon essay angle we have down.
So let's do up here.
Okay.
And if you have any issues with your app not compiling correctly, feel free to shut down your running
view server and start it up again using NPM run serve in case you have any issues, but hopefully the
view compiler will register these changes easily and you should be able to use them automatically in
the browser.
Okay.
So now that our set up is complete in the very next lesson, we're going to start building our accordion
component.