All right.
So super quick lesson here.
The first stylistic change that I'd like to do is to add some spacing or margin between these two elements,
this introductory text and my job search form component.
And where I'm actually going to do that is in my headline component.
So if I go back to my editor and I open up my headline view file.
This, of course, is where we have our action verb.
And then here's the prompt to find your next job at Bubba Corp.
And right here on this section, tag on line number two is where I'm going to add a new Tailwind class,
and that class will be maybe 16.
As a reminder, the M classes are a margin and the B is short for bottom.
So this will only apply margin on the bottom in this specific scenario.
And B 16 is equal to four REM, as we can see on the right, which is equivalent to 64 pixels.
So 64 pixels of space between the headline and our job search form, which we are of course rendering
in our hero right below the headline component.
All right.
So if we go back to our browser, that is a better starting point.
And this is where we're going to start building out the excess for our form.
Perfect.
So we'll continue with this in the very next lesson.