All right, there's one more CCS tweak that I would like to add to our button, and that is to have
it display a box shadow, but only when I hover my mouse over the button.
Usually that's a good indicator to a user that a button is clickable.
It kind of invites them to participate by changing the style of the button.
When you hover your mouse over it right now, you'll notice we are getting a pointer, but there's no
other kind of call to action to click the button and a little bit of box shadow goes a long way to help
here.
All right.
So in order to make that happen, we're going to first need to head to our tailwind config file.
So right here, tailwind dot config that.
Yes.
So we need to provide some additional configuration settings for tailwind so that it knows the kind
of color that we would like to apply to our box shadow when we render it.
So right here in this theme object, under this extend object where we have a whole bunch of additional
settings that we've provided for the font family and the additional colors.
We want some additional settings for box shadow.
All right.
So I'm going to make this an object.
And similar to how it worked for our colors up above, our key here is going to be the name of the seasons
class that we would like to have.
And what Telmont is going to do is generate some CSS classes based on what we provide here.
It may also prefix those classes with some of its terms.
For example, we saw in the previous lesson that it created a big brand blue one class, so it prefixed
our name with BG, but still the values that we provide here, it will serve as the names or partial
names of the seasons classes that tailwind generates.
All right, so I'm going to create a class called Blue because it's going to be a slightly blue block
box shadow.
And for my value here, I'm going to provide the actual styling syntax for providing box shadow.
Now, to be honest with you, I'm not particularly great with CC, so I don't know all of the settings
that we are configuring here.
But again, I simply opened up my element inspector in Chrome and looked at the real world button and
basically just copied it.
Styles So that's what you can do here.
You can copy along with me and then just trust that it's going to look as it does on the real site.
So right here we're going to write zero zero, then three pixels, three pixels.
I imagine this has something to do with the level of box shadow or the direction of the box set or something
like that.
And then afterwards I want to provide the color which is going to be this color hashtag 4285 F4.
All right.
It's this kind of darker blue color for our box shadow.
So save this file, as always.
If your app does not properly run afterwards or if you don't see these changes later, restart your
review server by canceling it and then running NPM run.
And that should reincorporate the changes from your tailwind file.
All right.
So let's head back to action button dot view and we're going to add the style as our last class to our
button.
All right.
So by default, because we named our class or our provided a name of blue tailwind is going to generate
a class for us called Shadow Dash, whatever was the name that we provided.
So here we're going to have a class called Shadow Blue.
Now, if I save this file and I take a look in the browser, we'll see that we're not going to get quite
what we want.
We do correctly have our box shadow.
We can see it right here, but obviously it is present when the button loads on screen and we do not
want that.
We wanted to only appear on mouse hover.
Well typically in case you would start applying all of those additional, I forget what they're called,
but the additional syntax to indicate that you'd only like to apply styles on hover right or on click
or on mouse over things like that.
Luckily with Tailwind, the process for adding a class but only on hover is very, very simple.
Before the Tailwind class, all you do is prefix it with the word hover followed by a colon.
So right here I'm going to do hover.
Colon.
So what this means is only apply the shadow blue style, which we just saw in the browser when the user
hovers.
All right.
And it's that simple, and it will work the same way for any other tail in class.
For example, if I change the line above to hover colon big brand blue one, what that would mean is
only on user hover apply the background of of the blue brand color that we specified.
So that's what makes Tailwind so elegant is we don't have to remember all that CSS syntax or name all
of these classes or nets them or deal with that complexity.
Whatever style we want to apply on hover, we just prefix that class with the hover keyword.
In fact, I think under the hood what this is is its own separate CSS class that tail and makes available
for us.
Again, it ships with these hundreds, maybe thousands of available classes, and we can just use whichever
ones we'd like.
All right.
So I'm going to save this.
And now when I go back to my browser, we should get what we want.
We have our regular button when the page loads and then as I hover my mouse over it.
Perfect.
We have that nice little box shadow appear around the button to indicate that the button is clickable.
Pretty cool.
Looks good to me.
So in the very next lesson, we can go ahead and start creating our profile image.