All right.
So in the previous lesson, we defined a new property on our view store state called skills search term.
And of course the intent there is for it to start out as an empty string.
And whenever the user is going to type a character into our input field in our new component, we want
to update our skill search term to reflect what they have just typed.
And so of course, in order to make changes to the View Store State, we're going to need to write a
mutation, a mutation that's going to take the most up to date skills search term and update the string
that is stored within our view X Star State.
So on the left hand side, I have my mutations file.
On the right hand side I have my mutations test file.
And of course I want to write a test for my new mutation.
I'm going to call my mutation update skills search term.
Let me scroll down a little bit here and let's see where I want to put it.
It doesn't really matter.
How about right here in between add selected degrees and clear user job filter selections.
So I'm going to describe the new mutation.
I want to add it's going to be called update skills search term.
And here's the arrow function.
And I'm going to say it receives search term.
For skills the user has.
Right.
And of course, if you come up with a better description, feel free to utilize it.
This is just my best shot.
All right.
So we're going to start out with a starting state.
Which we're going to get by invoking our create state helper function.
Remember, our Create State Helper function is relying on the original state function which we modified
in the previous lesson, so it will automatically have a skills search term property set to an empty
string out of the box.
However, I do want to provide it in line here just to communicate what this test does.
So right here I'm going to provide my skills, search term property set to an empty string, and then
we can better explain what this mutation is supposed to do.
So right here I have my mutations.
Object imported.
And I'm going to assume that it's going to have my mutation called update skills search term, and I'm
going to assume that that mutation is going to accept the starting state.
That's always the first argument to mutation.
Then the second argument is up to us, and I'm going to assume it's going to receive a search term,
a string of the search term that the user has entered in the box.
So let's say this is going to be something like the string view.
All right.
And then what I expect to happen after this mutation runs is if I look at my starting state and I look
at it skills, search term property, this should be equal to the string view, which means we've received
that string that the users typed and we've now saved it to the View Store.
Perfect.
So now we can go ahead and implement our solution.
The first thing I'm going to do is to open up my constants file.
And here we have sections for each kind of category.
So I'm going to create a new comment here for my new category, which I'll call skills and qualifications.
And right here I will export a new concept with the name of my mutation, which is update skills, a
search term set to a string with the exact same value.
Update Skills Search term.
Save that and that allows me to move back to my mutations for.
And right here, I'm going to import that new constant, which is called update skills search term.
And then, of course, I can utilize that below.
So scrolling down, I'm going to add it right here.
Update skills, search term, provide my function body.
There we go.
And of course, we're going to provide the exact parameters that this mutation expects.
The first parameter to mutation is always going to be the current view extra state.
So I'll call that parameter state and say that has a type of global state.
Then the second argument that we want here, as we defined in our desired implementation or desired
kind of happy path in the test suite is going to be a string.
So I will call that the skills search term and I will tell TypeScript that it should be of type string.
And then what are we going to do in the body of this actual method?
We're going to, of course, take our existing state and we want to overwrite it skills, search term
property to be whatever string skills search term represents, which again will be passed in by the
component when we commit this mutation.
So our goal eventually is that as the user types.
You just get this to save as these are types, we're going to commit the mutation.
Hey, the users type this new string.
Please take it and save it to the store.
And each time these are types we're going to commit a new mutation, get that updated string and update
that property and if you store.
All right.
So with that, our test is passing and that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.