In this optional lesson, I'd like to talk about the three most popular front end libraries and frameworks
in use today which are React, Vue and Angular and talk about the differences between them, especially
when it comes to technical development.
Now, one element that makes Vue unique is that it's developed entirely by volunteers.
React, whose icon you can see on the left there, is supported by Facebook and Angular, whose icon
you can see on the right here is supported by Google.
While Vue is entirely a community effort, but a better way to differentiate between these libraries
is on a scale of an opinionated versus opinionated Vue creator.
Evan, you even stated himself that Vue falls in between and react in Angular on this scale.
So let's talk a little bit about what that means.
So let's start with the right side here, the angular side, the opinionated side.
What does it mean to be opinionated, right?
Well, it means that you have opinions.
It means that you have beliefs on how things should work.
So Angular has a certain set of conventions, or we can also call them rules or standards.
And it demands that you follow those conventions in order to use the framework effectively.
A simple way that I can describe it is my way or the highway.
You have to use things the way that I tell you to use them.
And then if you promise me you're going to do that, I'm going to give you a whole bunch of efficiencies
as a result of that.
So Angular is a lot larger in scope than just view or react.
For example, Angular automatically ships with a library to make HTTP requests, to make API requests
to get data from some server.
So it comes pre-configured with that.
It comes pre-configured with a testing library.
It enforces certain design patterns for building pieces of the app.
For example, Angular requires you to write your code in TypeScript, so you're going to hear that word
a lot.
When it comes to opinionated write, it requires certain ways to write your code and there's no single
right way or wrong way.
There's just advantages and disadvantages to each approach.
So the advantage of being opinionated is that you're going to have somewhat consistent code from code
base to code base.
Angular wants you to do things a certain way.
So if you go from one Angular code base to another, you're going to start to see the same patterns.
You do have to learn more.
You have a larger learning curve.
For example, you have to learn TypeScript to use Angular.
But once you do learn that and you move to another Angular code base, you're going to be working with
the same technology, and it's used in a much more similar fashion, as I mentioned earlier.
Angular chooses the HTP request library and the testing library, but it's the same one.
So you don't have to worry about picking and choosing from project to project, but you do have to learn
with a one way of doing things.
And you kind of stick with it as you move along.
Right.
So it has a larger learning curve upfront and it gives you less freedom, less flex, less flexibility
because of its kind of standardized approach.
Right.
So it's kind of both a blessing and a curse.
The problem with opinionated software is that it's standardized and enforced.
It's less fun.
You're less likely to choose which technology you want to work with, how you want to do things, how
you want to build things.
It's angular.
It's my way or the highway.
Right.
On the opposite end of that side, you have the UN opinionated software, which is React.
React at its core is just a view library.
It's just responsible for rendering things in your browser.
So that means it has no opinions on how you should make API requests.
What API library request library should use, what testing library you should use.
React doesn't even have an opinion on routing, which means when you navigate from one page to another
in your app, how is that going to render different things on the screen?
There's multiple solutions.
React doesn't have an opinion on whether you should or should not use TypeScript.
You can, but you don't have to.
So the way to describe it is almost like the Wild West.
It's kind of a free for all.
You can mix and match a whole bunch of different libraries, whether it be testing or API requests.
You can mix and match them with React.
There's a lot of freedom that comes with that and a lot of flexibility, but also a lot of responsibility
because many times there's lots of competing different ways on how to do something.
And you have to do extra research.
You have to debate pros and cons of different solutions and going from one React code base to another.
There's not so much of a guarantee that you're going to have similar looking code.
The core React code, of course, is going to be pretty similar, but the surrounding ecosystem that
you surround react with is not going to have the same level of consistency as it would with an opinionated
choice like Angular.
Right.
So again, advantages and disadvantages with with the and opinionated react, you get more flexibility,
you get more fun.
You can play with the new library that came into fashion this year and PM, but next year might be replaced
by a different library and the React community may go that way and debate this way and choose this.
And then all of a sudden it may not be popular anymore and things change a lot more rapidly as a result
of that.
All right.
So Vue kind of lines up right in the middle and let me talk about how it's able to achieve that balance.
So Vue has a very extensive ecosystem.
That means there's a bunch of additional tools that are complementary to view.
And unlike in the React ecosystem, there are built by the View Core team, that same team that develops
Vue.
So Vue has a solution for routing.
It's called Vue router.
We're going to be learning about it later in the course.
Another example is state management, which is storing data that is global above your app, right?
Vue has a solution for that called Vue X that is developed by the Blue Team.
If you want to test Vue components or the view code that we're going to be writing, Vue has a recommended
test library that it develops called Vue Test Utils, again developed by the View Core Team.
So what's the difference between that and Angular?
Well, View doesn't require you to use these tools in the ecosystem, but those ecosystem tools are
built with Vue in mind specifically for working with Vue.
And so when you want to expand to add those new features to your app, there is a recommended set of
technologies.
So you sort of get the benefits of the angular ecosystem where you have some consistency because these
are the tools that the View team recommends that you use and that you have in conjunction with, in
conjunction with Vue.
However, there are still other options available in the open source community that work with view that
you can also use if you're looking for to try something different or had a bad experience with the way
Vue does things and wants to try something else.
So you sort of get the best of all worlds.
You have the core Vue library, which is just like react pretty and opinionated.
But then when you want to add more features and functionality to your app.
You have a way to gradually add them to your app and know that they have the support of the view team
behind them and thus have consistency and obviously optimizations for working with each other and as
you continue building out your project.
So in that way, Vue sort of accomplishes the best of all worlds and that's one of my favorite features
about it.
So the next slide that I'm going to take you to is from a slide deck by Evan.
You add a view conference that he spoke at and it reflects sort of the entire review ecosystem.
And of course, a lot of these terms may be pretty unfamiliar to you, but the way it works is like
this.
You can imagine that this bright red circle right here, this is declarative rendering.
It really is the core heart of what the View Library gives you.
And I would also say the component system around it as well.
So this red circle here is what's kind of the core view library.
If you just install view, this is what you're going to get.
And these are additional features that are commonly needed in modern frontend web apps, right?
So the angular approach of course is giving you all of these features in the singular, in a single
angular.
Framework and saying you have to use it, you have to use our solution for client side routing, you
have to use our large scale state management solution, etc., our build system, etc. React solution
is to say, Well, I'm going to give you the spread circle and it's up to you to figure out how you
want to handle all of these other elements.
There's a bunch of different solutions and options choose which one works.
And of course there's a lot of inconsistency.
Thus from React code base to React codebase, what Vue says is we're going to just give you this core
part, and if you're interested in these other features, we're going to build them and we're going
to make them optional.
So you're not required to add them like Angular does, but if you want to add them, you can and you
can add them with the confidence that they are going to work well with with Vue because they're developed
by the exact same team.
Right.
React doesn't have the comfort because the core React library is developed by Facebook, but all of
its additional supplemental libraries in its ecosystem are developed by a whole bunch of different teams
some open source, some from other companies, etc. So it's a lot more fragmented, right?
You're probably going to get a lot more innovation there, a lot more competition, etc., but a lot
more inconsistency as well.
And angular on the other end is a total opposite.
It's we're going to give you all of this.
You choose if you don't want it, then Anglo's not the right thing for you.
We'll in comparison kind of again merges the best of all worlds.
It gives you this option, which is the core of your library.
It gives you the options for anything beyond that, including the view recommended approach or the view
supported approach developed by the core team or your choice of whatever open source libraries that
you'd like to use if you prefer something different.
So that's kind of the differences between View, React and Angular.
Hopefully that's helped to clarify that opinionated versus underpinning it at scale and probably giving
you a better sense of which one you should pick for your project or for your team as you're building
your next app, right?
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
And now we can move forward with officially installing view and getting started with the framework.