Okay.
So let's move on to another component in this lesson.
I want to refactor the sub nav component.
So let's go ahead and open that file up right here.
I'm going to open up my sub nav component.
And as always, I'm going to look for components that offer us more opportunities to get familiarized
with the composition API, but dealing with other problems.
So for example, we just saw how to use the use router function with our previous component and the
sub nav component offers its own share of new problems for us to figure out.
So take a look.
This component is not that complicated.
We only have the computer section right here.
But there's two things this component is reliant upon.
Number one, here is the dollar sign root property that's provided by view router.
And just as a heads up, don't confuse this with dollar sign router.
Dollar sign router is the view router dollar sign root is an object that tells you about the current
root or in other words, the current URL that you are on.
So that's the first thing we're going to need to replace using Composition API.
And then the second thing is reusing map getters here.
And remember behind the scenes, what this is doing is talking to the View store and running a specific
getter called filter jobs in order to enable a method on this component called filter jobs.
So let's worry about replacing this functionality in this lesson.
And then in the next lesson I'll show you how to replace the getter logic.
So let's begin as always, by commenting out our old implementation.
So I'm going to comment out, computed, and as a result, I'm also going to comment out these two import
lines because they're directly related to our computed functionality.
All right.
So we're going to need to set up our setup method.
And as always in here, we're going to return an object.
All right.
So we know that eventually we're going to need something like filter jobs here because we're using that
as a name in our template.
And we're also going to need to have a name called on job results page while on job results page is
going to come from talking to dollar sign root, which no longer exists.
Well, can you guess how we're going to be able to get access to the root object within our set of method?
It's going to work the exact same way as we saw with the router in the previous lesson.
We're going to be able to import a helper function from view router that gives us access to the route
within a given setup method.
So what is that helper function called?
You guessed it, it's going to be called use root.
Once again, be very careful here.
This is not use router which we imported in the previous component.
This is just use root.
So right here I'm going to import that from a view router.
And since we have a computed property, we're going to want to watch the value of name like we're doing
right here and continue to compare it.
So whenever we have computed logic, we know that we're also going to need to get the computed function
from view.
So computed is going to come from view use root is going to come from you about.
All right so right here and setup, you guessed it, we can simply invoke just make sure I don't do
that in my return.
That was very sloppy of me right here.
If we invoke use root, we're going to get our root object, a reactive root object, and I'm going
to assign that to a contact called Root.
So just like that, we have the exact same functionality as we had via this that dollar sign root in
the options API.
So down below I'm going to define the name that I need to have in my template, which is on job results
page.
So right here on job results page and that is going to be a computed property.
So now it's going to be a computed function.
And so the or more specifically, it's going to be the reactive object that the computed function returns.
So right here I'm going to invoke my computed function.
We know that when we pass, this is a function that view is going to rerun whenever the reactive state
inside it changes.
So what is going to be our reactive state that we're watching?
It's going to be the value of the name property on our reactive root object.
And since it's reactive, Vue is going to know to rerun this function whenever that name property changes.
So right here, root that name and we're going to check if it's equal to the string job results.
All right.
So this is the exact same implementation we have right here.
We're going to implicitly return a boolean, and that's going to be the next state, the next reactive
state of this on job results page computed property.
The only thing that's left to do, of course, is to make sure we return it right here in this object.
And just like that, we've replaced the former computed property right here.
So right here we have on job results page, which expects a boolean.
Remember on job results page as a reactive object and the value property on it is what's going to actually
give us the boolean that reflects whether this condition is true or false.
But for the purposes of the template, we're welcome to use the reactive object right here in line because
Vue knows how to deal with that.
All right, so we've taken care of this bit right here.
And the very next lesson, we're going to show you how to take care of the getters.