All right.
So in this lesson will apply our initial tailwind CSR styles to our three components job results, view,
job filter, sidebar and job listings.
So let's begin with our job results view.
Currently, it is rendering our two child view components inside a div and I want to apply some tailwind
classes to that div.
So right here I'll create a flex box for my children using flex.
I want to make sure I arrange the children in a row direction so I will add the flex row class which
makes the flex direction row.
Then I don't want these elements to wrap.
In other words, I don't want my job listings to appear below my sidebar.
I always want them to stay within a single row.
So for that I will add the flex no wrap class which adds a flex wrap of no wrap.
And finally, I want to make sure that this div occupies the full width of its parent container, 100%
of the parent, or in other words, the full browser window.
So I'll add the W full class, which applies a width of 100%.
All right.
So that takes care of our top level view.
Let's now move on to our sidebar.
Our sidebar is going to be the thing on the left where the user filters the jobs based on certain criteria.
So right here, I will add some CSS classes as well on this top level div.
Let's make this a Flexbox as well.
This is going to arrange all of the possible job filters in a column order.
So eventually when we render the filters for things like job type and location and college education,
etc., we want them to appear in a column format.
So in addition to making this a Flexbox, I want to lay out the items in a column, not a row.
So I'm going to apply the flex core class which will set the direction of this Flexbox as a column.
This is not to be confused with the Flexbox that we applied on the job results view component a second
ago, that Flexbox is going to still arrange the job filter sidebar in a row compared to the job listings
component side by side.
This is a separate Flexbox to arrange the children of this dev right here.
All right, let's add some padding.
I'm going to do the P for class to apply a padding of one ram, which is going to be about 16 pixels
on the top, left, right and bottom.
That's just going to give us some space between the edges of the container and our actual filters themselves.
I want to make sure I have a white background so I can apply the big white class to give it a white
background.
Then we have a border between the job filter, sidebar and the job listings component, but that borders
only on the right side of the sidebar.
This is the border that separates that sidebar from the start of the job listings.
So what I can do is add a class called Border AR, which is short for border, right?
That's going to apply a one pixel border, but only on the right side of this box of this diff.
I want to make sure I have a solid border so I can do border solid.
And that's just to make sure it's not something like a dashed border.
It's going to be a straight one pixel straight line.
And then I can specify the actual color of that border line, and I can do that with my border class.
And we're actually going to use the brand gray, one color that we set up in our tailwind config file.
This is one of our custom gray colors.
So as always, as a quick reminder, Tailwind generates this file for us based on our configuration
in the tailwind dot config that JS file.
Finally, I want to add a width to this job for the sidebar and that's going to be 96.
That's going to add a width of 24 M and with a base size of 16 pixels, that's going to be about 384
pixel width for the sidebar on the left hand side of the screen.
Let me save that in prettier will arrange a lot of these classes kind of flowing downward.
So it's a little bit easier to read and I think that is a good place to finish up our styling for the
job filters sidebar.
Finally, we can move on to our job listings component.
Same deal here will apply some tailwind classes, but this time it will be our main element right here.
First, I'm going to apply the flex auto class.
What that is going to ensure is that this box will grow as the page with increases or shrinks.
It's going to grow in proportion.
Again, this is kind of for responsiveness sake.
We're not really building a fully responsive APS.
I'm not exactly sure how our app will look in mobile format or a smaller screen size, but this will
just help add a little bit of expandability to this content that is holding all of the job listings.
I do want to add some padding here all around my job listings, so I will add the paid class that is
going to apply a padding of two RAM or equivalently 32 pixels on the top, left, right and bottom.
So some spacing between the edges of the container and our job listings.
And then for this background, as we saw on the official website, it is that custom gray background
and we had that available in our brand gray to color so we can access the big classes which assign a
background.
But rather than using a built in tailwind background, we want to apply our custom brand gray to gray
All right.
And that's going to be the entire box.
So if I navigate back to my.
Browser.
We should now see everything looking a little bit better.
Perfect.
So now we have our job filter side by right here.
It takes up 384 pixels to the right of that.
Using the Flexbox, we've arranged the job listings component and we have it with a nice gray background
and they're kind of arranged side by side now.
And furthermore, when we start laying out our items within the sidebar, they themselves are going
to fall in in a column format within the Flexbox in this sidebar.
So this is a good place to start and we will continue chipping away at the CC and the structure of these
two components in the upcoming lessons.