Okay.
So now we have a back end end point on JSON server that will return an array of spotlight objects to
us.
The next thing I want to do is create a component where I'm going to make the actual API request to
get that information, and that will lead us to a new problem that we'll try to solve using the new
slot features that we'll talk about in this section.
So in my source components folder in job search, I'm going to create a new component called Spotlight
Dot View.
All right.
And as always, we'll provide a template and then we'll provide a script section as well.
And for now, in my template, I'm just going to begin with an unordered list, and we'll figure out
what to populate it with later.
The idea, of course, is that our spotlight sections are cards, represent list items.
It is a list of advertisements for the company, basically.
So semantically it makes sense to place them in a list.
Okay, so let's now wire up the API request and then we'll come back to the template in just a moment.
So here I'm going to export default a JavaScript object, and we're going to give it a name and the
name will be Spotlight.
And in order to store our actual data from the backend, I'm going to create a local piece of component
data.
So we're not going to worry about something like View X here.
We're going to go back to the basic principles we learned about at the beginning of the course.
We're going to store this data in this component locally.
So I will define a data method and my data method will return an object.
And here's where we configure the components data.
And so I'm going to have a spotlight's property and I'm going to set it to an empty array.
This is the exact same protocol or pattern that we did earlier when we were getting our jobs in a component.
We start off with an empty array, then we make the API request, and when we get our actual valid array
of objects, we're simply going to overwrite the local component data with the valid array.
Our component will re render and do something with that new array of actual objects, but we have to
provide some kind of starter value.
So we're going to start with an empty array.
The next thing I want to do is to make the actual request and a good place to do that is in the mounted
lifecycle hook or the mounted method.
So right here after data, I'll define that mounted method and here's where we want to make our request.
So as a reminder of how we do this, in each development environment, we have a environment variable
called view app API URL.
So I'm going to assign it to a constant called based URL.
And we can get that from process dot EMV, dot view app API URL.
And as a reminder, we defined all of those various values for this environment variable in these three
files right here at our top level are EMV files.
So this will give me a base URL.
For example, in development, I'm going to get the localhost 3000 URL which represents the port for
my JSON server NPM package.
Right.
So that's just going to get this thing.
And then of course, to the end of that, I want to concatenate the actual endpoint we defined in the
previous lesson, which is spotlights.
So my URL right here is going to be the combination of base URL plus spotlight.
So I'm going to use S6 template strings and I'm going to interpolate the value of base URL, whatever
it happens to be, and then slash spikes.
And again, just to make this all stick and make sure it's making sense.
As a reminder in our DB that Jason followed, here is where we defined a slash spotlight's endpoint.
That's why we can hit that endpoint.
All right, so slash spotlights is the URL.
Now we need to actually make a request to that URL.
We're going to do that with the Axios library.
So here in my script section before my export, I'm going to import Axios from Axios and right here
I'm going to do Axios got get providing a URL.
Now as a reminder, this method returns a promise.
So I need to await that promise until it resolves.
And in order to use a weight here, I need to also make my mounted method async.
So there we go.
This is going to give me back the Axios response object so I can assign it to a constant call response.
And as a reminder, in order to get the actual data from that response, what the backend actually gives
to us, we need to access a property on this object called data.
So a response, that data will actually get us the array of two spotlight objects that we defined in
DB that JSON in the previous lesson.
Once I have that array of objects, what do I want to do?
I want to overwrite my spotlight's data array.
So I'm going to reference this that spotlights and overwrite my empty array with my new array.
Okay, so what do I want to do in my template?
I want to iterate over my spotlight's array and whenever we iterate over an array we should know that
a good option is DV for directive and that will work great because when the component starts up we're
just going to iterate over an empty array, so we're not going to render anything to the template.
And then when the component updates the spotlight's data property with an array of two spotlights or
three or however many of the back and returns, then the component will re render and iterate over that
new array and thus render new HTML elements to the template.
So right here inside my unordered list, I'm going to create an ally a list item.
And how how many allies do I want to create?
As many as I have in elements in my spotlight's array.
If I have two, then I want to allies etc. So I'm going to use the V for directive and I'm going to
iterate over each spotlight in spotlights.
I can reference my data property in line like so.
And as a reminder, whenever we use the V for directive, we have to provide a key prop and we have
to provide a unique identifier so you can distinguish what that value or distinguish what that element
is from all the other allies.
And as a reminder, we want to bind to that because we need some kind of unique identifier and we're
going to use the ID property on each spotlight object that we are iterating over.
So I'm going to do spotlights dot ID again, as a reminder in our debate that JSON file, each spotlight
object has an ID value.
I think the first one is one, the second one is two.
And in order to reference a dynamic object property, we have to use the v bind syntax here.
Otherwise view will think that we are providing an actual string of spotlight ID.
All right, so here is where we run into a problem.
And I want you to to pause for a moment and think about what this problem is.
We want the parent component that's going to render spotlight to be able to customize the HTML and the
CC for any given card.
Right.
So if we want the parent to provide some kind of custom dynamic h html, the first thought that comes
to mind is a slot and that's absolutely the correct option.
So I'm going to put a slot here, right?
I'm going to create a slot component because I want the parent to inject dynamic HTML here to represent
each individual card.
We're going to keep the commonality of a list.
We're going to keep the semantic logic of a list item, but we're going to allow the parent to define
what each list item actually consists of.
Is it going to be a long card?
Is it going to be a short card?
Is the image going to be in the background?
Is the image going to be on the top?
We're going to let the parent define it so that the parent can customize this.
Right.
There's just one bit of a problem here.
In order to render that optimal, the parent needs some piece of information from the Spotlight object.
Right.
Let me open up.
My delight.
Jason followed to remind us one more time.
So when a parent component, let's say I'm just going to do it right here so we can create this little
space for ourselves.
And my goal here is not to confuse you.
We can imagine that line number nine is the parent component.
It's going to render a spotlight component.
And right here is where it's going to provide the slot content.
Let's say in one parent component, we want to do an H2 and let's say in another parent component somewhere
else in our app, we want to reuse the spotlight component and we want to provide an H3.
That is the beauty of slots.
The beauty is that we can provide whatever HTML content we want.
The problem is, let's say we want to put the spotlight's name or title right here.
So we want this piece of information, cloud, engineering or executive leadership for the parent to
be able to place within the H2 or the H3.
The problem is that piece of text lives in our spotlight object and our parent component that's going
to be rendering the spotlight component doesn't have access to this object, this one right here, because
it's only available in our actual spotlight component as we're iterating over it.
Right.
We have provided a place for the parent to inject dynamic HTML, but that dynamic HTML needs the spotlight
title.
It needs to literally be able to put the title right here that this spotlight object is holding, which
it will not have access to, because this is what the parent is going to be rendering.
It doesn't have access to this spotlight object right here.
So we need a way to pass this piece of information up to the parent so the parent can say, okay, I
have a spotlight object and as a title I can render it here in my age two.
And another parent that wants to render in the H3 can do the exact same thing.
It's going to have access to the spotlight object.
It can put its contents within an age three, customize it with whatever H.
Miller says it wants, but still have access to that piece of data.
So how can we provide this piece of information to the parent component that is rendering our our spotlight
component?
We do that using slot props.
And it's kind of a pretty simple idea on this slot component.
We define whatever props we want, and those props are going to be available to the parent component
that renders this spotlight component.
The parent component that's going to render the component with slots is going to receive access to whatever
props we define right here in line.
So for example, if I define a value like nonsense equals five, the parent component that renders spotlight
will have access to nonsense.
I'm going to show you how to get access to that in the next lesson, but just know that any props that
we define here the parent will have access to.
So what I propose is we define a slot prop, a prop called Spotlight.
And of course, what I want to pass up is going to be this spotlight object that we're iterating over
this thing right here.
Now, if I simply did spotlight like so, this would not work as always in view.
This would indeed give the parent a spotlight prop or access to that information.
But Vue is going to think that we're providing a literal string of spotlight.
We don't want to do that.
We want to give a dynamic reference to this object that we are iterating over.
So we need to use the V bind syntax.
So right here v bind colon, of course s lens is going to complain and prefer we use the shortcut,
which is totally fine.
So this is the syntax we're going to use.
Okay.
I realize that this can be totally confusing for several reasons.
Number one, we don't see the other half of the equation.
We don't see the parent that's going to be using this data.
We'll see that very shortly in the next lesson.
But the other part that makes it confusing is we're using a spot.
We're using the word spotlight to describe a lot of things.
Spotlight is simultaneously the name of our component right here.
It's also the variable name that we represent for the iteration and also the name of the prop that we
are defining on our slot.
And it doesn't have to be this way.
Right.
We can define whatever names we want.
Right here.
Right.
That's all up to us.
I'm just using this because I think it's the most common pattern you're going to see in the real world.
We have an array of something called spotlights.
We are iterating over each individual spotlight object, and we want to pass that object right here
to the parent some way.
And why would we give this another name?
Right.
We can give this something like, you know, information.
And the parent will have access to a piece of prop data called information that's going to be equal
to the spotlight object.
But typically, that actually makes it more confusing because we're providing two names for the same
thing.
This is a spotlight object, so it makes sense.
The parent is going to access this piece of information eventually via the name Spotlight.
That is what it represents.
But I understand how it can be pretty confusing, right?
So in short, in this component, we are going to allow the parent to render a dynamic piece of HTML
right here.
And that dynamic piece of HTML is going to be able to access a piece of information called Spotlight,
which will be equal to the JavaScript object that we are iterating over in each individual iteration
right here.
All right.
So in the very first iteration, we're going to inject the parents content and we're going to give it
this object right here.
And then in the second V4 iteration, we're going to inject the parents content as well, but give it
a different spotlight object, which is this one right here.
It's actually a very interesting design partner because because we've put our slot within a V for however
many allies we have.
That's however many times we're going to replicate the HTML content that our parent is going to give
to us.
Right.
If we have five spotlights being rendered, then we're going to reuse the parent's custom HTML slot
of content five times.
But each time we reuse it, we need it to have dynamic text injected from the spotlight object.
So we need to pass that object up right here, and that's what we're doing.
We're going to see how this all connects to the parent component.
In the very next lesson.