In this lesson, I want to introduce you to test driven development, which often goes by the acronym
TDD.
It's going to be a little bit of a mind blowing concept if you've never heard of it before or if you're
brand new to testing.
But here's the basic gist of TDD.
With TDD, we write our tests first.
We write our actual tests before we write the implementation code.
So if we think back to our previous lesson where we wrote our even or odd function and then wrote our
tests before it.
Imagine that we actually wrote our tests for that function first before we actually had any implementation
code.
A lot of people are blown away by this idea because their first response is, How can I write tests
for something for which I don't actually have any code yet?
Well, it's actually a kind of brilliant idea in that you write your test and you describe what your
thing should be called, your entity, whether it be a class or a function or method, what its what
its inputs are going to be, what you're going to provide it, and what you expect the result to be.
And the smart part about that, as you describe exactly how the program should work before you actually
write the implementation.
And there's a lot of benefits to that that we'll talk about in just a few minutes.
For now, I want to talk about the cycle of how TDD works.
It's a three step process that repeats and it's called red green refactor.
So let's start with this red circle at the very top.
This is called the red stage or the red phase.
So this is where we write a test.
We write a test that describes what a specific piece of our program should do.
The reason it's called Red is you can think of something like a stoplight.
Red means stop.
Red means do not proceed.
Red means our tests are going to be failing and they're predictably going to be failing because the
assertions that we're going to make them cannot possibly succeed or pass because we have no actual code
to properly execute.
Right.
If we're testing that, a method on an object returns a specific value and that object and that method
don't exist yet.
Well, of course, our test is going to fail, and that is the intent, because now that our tests are
going to describe the value of the software they're about to write, we can move on to the next circle
in this diagram, which is green.
In the green stage of TDD, we write the implementation code that makes the tests pass.
Right?
And the beautiful part about this design is we can guarantee that the code we're writing is actually
fulfilling what the tests expect the code to do.
It ensures that we're not going to write any additional code or any extra code or not needed code.
We're just going to write whatever is the bare minimum amount of code.
We need to get that single test to pass to run green and our just output green means go, green means
pass when it comes to test.
Now the final step is the refactor step.
So once we've written our failing tests, once we fix them with our implementation, we now have our
tests as our confidence booster, as our backup that we have the confidence to refactor our code.
To refactor our code means to improve code without changing its underlying purpose.
So now if we can come up with a slightly better implementation or a more efficient solution to the problem
in our JavaScript, we can do that and then again run the tests over and over to confirm that we are
still delivering on the tests expectation and the code is doing what it's supposed to do and what we
want it to do from the very beginning.
Right.
So there's a purpose to the code that we write.
We guarantee that it is doing the thing that we need it to do as described in the tests.
It's almost like declaring the wish of What do I want this code to do?
What do I need it to accept, and what do I need it to output for me?
And you write that you you guarantee that you're living up to that expectation.
And then once you've lived up to it, you have the opportunity to improve your code and have that test
suite behind you as backup to confirm that nothing that you added accidentally broke the code.
Right.
That's the entire cycle.
We write a failing test, we make it pass, we make the code better, then we repeat the cycle.
The whole idea is we should never be writing green code.
We should never be writing any new code unless its purpose is to fix a failing test, which means adding
some kind of new feature or functionality into our program that we've now declared a need for in our
tests.
Right.
So there are many benefits of TDD and many articles you can read that will tell you more benefits and
even some studies that will show the benefits of it over time.
But I want to quickly talk through a couple of them pretty quickly.
All right.
So, number one, we ensure we are testing the right thing.
Many times you're going to write extra code, more code that is needed.
You might have instance methods that are unused or properties that are unused.
You might produce a methods that return a values that are not actually being used anywhere.
The idea behind TDD is our tests allow us to more easily figure out what do we want our program to do
or what do we want our class to do and write it down?
Almost like making a plan.
And before we actually write any real code for what we need this code to do for us, and our tests are
the best barometer of that, rather than writing it down in some notebook somewhere where you're going
to forget, we can write that directly into our code base.
What our code should be doing are our tests in many ways are the best documentation we have because
they show you how to run the pieces of our app in isolation and they show you exactly how everything
works, how a function should be invoked, how a class should be instantiated.
They provide descriptions and they live alongside our code and are committed to source control.
So our tests are the best form of documentation, and ideal tests will describe the why rather than
the how the benefit of what a piece of code is adding rather than the specific implementation.
So the first thing is that we actually declare what we are testing and why we are building the code
that we're about to build, which ensures that we are building the right thing.
The second benefit is that we avoid duplication in our tests.
If we write a test after having written some code and we discover that our test is passing, that means
that our existing implementation already fulfills what that test claims is a new feature, right?
So if we write test one and build feature one, then we build test two and feature one already makes
it pass.
Then we're not actually adding any new logic to our app and that test is redundant and it doesn't need
to be there.
It's actually double testing something that's already been tested before.
So by getting a failing test, we can guarantee that we're actually adding new functionality to our
program.
All right.
Number three, as we talked about, we describe the why rather than the implementation.
If we don't know how we're going to build our actual code, if we don't know whether we're going to
use an array or an object or a string, for example, if we just write our tests, describe the purpose
of the code and what it expects to provide and receive.
It tends to make our tests a little bit more readable.
All right.
Number four, another benefit is higher test coverage.
Test coverage refers to the percentage of your code base that is covered by tests.
Whenever we run just that, we can actually show you a setting and a couple of lessons where Jess will
calculate how many lines in your inner code base it ran through as it was testing and just can identify,
hey, 20% of your code base you don't have a test for.
I didn't run through this code when I was running your tests.
Well, the benefits of running our tests first is that we're always going to have that test coverage.
We're going to have proper tests for our features because we're going to write the tests before we even
write the features.
Right.
So we're going to have those tests always available.
And you're going to be able to avoid those situations where developers say, Oh, I don't need to write
tests now, I promise I'll come back to it later.
And then they never do.
And you have a bunch of untested code in your code base, which is a lot more brittle, which is a lot
more subject to error write, which requires you to test it much more manually because there's no automated
way to run those tests.
Now you're guaranteeing that you're going to have a test suite behind any new feature in your app.
In addition, your test suite, which now is going to exist as a guarantee because you write it first
a good test.
We and TDD also makes code easy to refactor.
You always have that security of knowing that the tests are there to rerun.
Whenever you want to refactor there's sort of your your they keep you honest they're confidence booster
to say hey if you accidentally break something when you're adding a new feature or refactoring the code,
the tests will already be there to fail and remind you that some existing functionality that used to
work no longer does.
It's a confidence booster and again guarantees that you're going to have those tests.
And finally, another reason among many is that I found that test human development leads not just to
higher quality tests, but also to higher quality code.
There is a good correlation between easy, simple tests and good simple solutions that are not overly
complex and convoluted.
Typically, if your tests are really hard to set up, if they require a lot of spaghetti code, a lot
of boilerplate code, it's usually a sign that your implementation is also too complex and coupled.
Typically, your tests will be really small and lightweight.
You'll build a lots of really small, whether it be objects or really small functions, really small
pieces in your program that all interact the build up to a larger whole.
The more that your app consists of really small objects that each do a small thing with a single responsibility,
the easier it is to test and the easier it is to reason them out.
And typically when you when you start with TDD, you're going to have a smaller scope or focus.
You're going to describe just one unit and just one test for that unit.
So you're not going to drown in the weeds of building a super big class as you might when you as you
might do when you typically just start coding without thinking about what you're doing first.
So tests kind of keep you more focused, keep focused on one problem at a time, one input and output
at a time.
And that tends to lead, in my personal experience, to the higher quality code.
You don't even need to study complex design patterns.
Sometimes your tests when written through TDD will lead you.
A better design pattern simply because of how you're going to solve one problem at a time.
Again, your goal is not just to write a test and then make it pass.
Your goal is you can only write code if it makes a test pass.
So if we think back to our previous lesson when we wrote our even or odd function, our first test might
have been testing an input of an even number and an output of the string even.
And we would have just solved that problem and started building out that function incrementally one
piece at a time.
We wouldn't have added the logic four odd yet until we then passed our first test for evenness and then
added a new test for testing an input of an odd number and its corresponding return string.
So as you can see, it would break down the implementation into smaller steps, smaller problems that
we can tackle that are easier to scope for our brains to reason about so that we can gently build out
the implementation one at a time.
All right.
One step at a time.
That's really all there is to cover in this lesson.
In the very next lesson, we're going to see an example of TDD in this code.
And finally, to close everything off, I do want to say that I am a big advocate of TDD.
I think that is it does make you a better developer.
But I also understand how difficult it can be to simultaneously practice TDD as you're learning a new
technology like Vue.
So we are not going to be using code for every single lesson throughout the course.
We're going to be using it when it's appropriate.
So typically when we introduce an idea for the first time and then test it and typically going to write
the component out first and then show you how to test it.
But then when we start practicing more with the syntax that I think is a really good time to practice
with TDD and show you the benefits of this workflow.
So I'm going to give you both perspectives, and then you're going to be able to formulate your own
opinion on what you prefer and how you like to work.
I don't want to ever force anything down your throat.
I want to give you my opinion, other opinions, and let you make the best decision for yourself.
All right.
So in the very next lesson, we'll explore a TDD with a simple example in this code.
Pretty exciting.
And I will see you there.