Alright.
So in the previous lesson we worked on our text input component and we wrote this line of code right
here that specified that whenever the user types a character into our text input, we're going to emit
an event called Handle Input.
And again to emit an event basically means to send a message to the parent that something has happened,
that an occurrence has transpired.
Now, here's the good news.
The syntax to handle that event in our parent component is actually going to be somewhat familiar to
us, because let's take a step back and think about what other events we've dealt with throughout the
course.
Well, we've dealt with things like click events on buttons, right?
And we've dealt with regular input events right here on input fields.
And the way that view is going to handle our custom events like this one that we arbitrarily called
handle input is the exact same way.
Do you remember the directive we use to handle events?
It is the V on directive we write V on followed by a colon and then followed by the event.
And then we put an equal sign and specify the method that we should invoke whenever that event occurs.
It's going to be the exact same syntax here.
Of course, the difference is we are not reacting to a native browser event like a user click.
We are reacting to our own custom event that we have called handle input.
So right here we have our text input, the very first one where the user's providing their role.
And right here I can write Von Colon, handle input.
Okay.
So an important thing to note here is this is no longer a browser event.
Again, this is our own custom event and the reason it is called handle input here is because that's
exactly what we call that right here.
It has to match because this is the name that we gave to this event.
This parent component is going to listen.
It's going to keep an ear out and listen to different messages.
And the only message that we're telling it how to react to here is handle input.
That's why we have to give this event a name.
And the reason is because our child component can actually emit multiple events.
It can event A, an event B, an event C, and our parent can react differently to each one.
That's why we have to give the event a name, almost like a category, and then arbitrarily or optionally
any additional data.
So we are going to react to the handle input event and as we know, the shortcut for Von instead of
using this is going to be a assign the exact same syntax we do for native browser events and then we
provide an equal sign and the name of the method that we want to run whenever this event happens.
So I'm going to call this method update roll.
This method does not exist yet, but we're going to write it up in just a second.
So again, the at sign or alternatively Von followed by the name of the event that we are omitting from
the job, which is handle input.
So we're going to run an update roll method.
So let's go and define that method.
So down below, I'll scroll down to my script section.
We do not have any methods on our job search form.
Let's add them.
So right here I'll add my methods property.
And here I have to define a method.
It has to be called update roll because that is what I called it up above.
And what this method is going to receive as arguments is whatever we passed as the arguments right here.
So if we provided one argument right here, this got value, then we're going to receive one parameter
right here and I'm going to call it payload for now.
And of course, if we provided two arguments right here, then this update roll method would be invoked
with two arguments, right?
So this is the event and Vue is going to invoke this method update roll with however many arguments
we pass here after the name of the event in the child.
Okay, so let's go ahead and console.log our payload and then transition to our browser and see what
is going on here.
So I'm going to go to my browser and I'm going to bring up my console.
So don't worry about this right now.
We'll come back to this later.
What I'm going to do is type in a character here in my role and what's going to happen.
The text input is going to update to store this in the data.
It's also going to emit an event up and we're going to console.log the payload for that event right
here.
So as I type the letter H, we can see H appear.
That is the console log of my payload.
And as I type additional characters, you can see each one of those events triggers our new handle input
event to be sent from our child text input component to the parent job search for component, which
triggers our update roll method, which in turn updates the OR console logs the newly entered text.
So if we go back to our view DevTools and we go into our job search form and our first text input,
you can see we're still storing that data locally on the text input component.
But now we are sending up this event called handle input and it is reaching our job search form component.
So of course the next thing we want to do and we'll do this in the very next lesson is we have to take
that data that we receive and of course overwrite our local data within the parent job search.
Job search form component.
We're going to do that in the very next lesson.