All right.
So the next thing that we're going to do is replace all of our former computed properties with computed
functions.
So we have four that we need to recreate current page, previous page, next page and displayed jobs.
And most of the logic is going to be basically the same.
We just have to be very careful with our references because there's a lot of things here that referred
to the this keyword and we have to update it to be using our new more up to date reference.
So for example, here in our current page computed property, we're using this dot dollar sign root
from the router.
We no longer have access to this, but we can get the root object from the use root function from view
router.
So let's import that.
So I'm going to go all the way to the top here and right below use store.
I will also import use root and that is going to come from view router.
And down below in my setup method, I can go ahead and get my route by invoking use route.
All right.
While we're at it, there's something I forgot to do in the previous lesson.
We are no longer using this filter job's constant, so let's go ahead and remove that.
That's just a little bit left over.
Okay, so now we have a route and we're good to create our four computed properties, but that also
means we're going to need our computed function from view.
So right here I will also import computed from view.
All right.
So let's begin with current page.
Current pages currently computed property.
What I'm going to do is make current page a constant, and it's going to hold the return value of my
computed function invocation.
Remember, what I passed to computed is going to be a function that I was going to rerun every time
the values that it is tracking inside a change.
So here we have this two liner right here.
I'm going to express this two liner in one line because it is possible to do that.
What we're doing fundamentally is we're calling pass into the number object in JavaScript and then we're
passing in root, dot query, dot page or the fallback string value of one.
So just as a reminder, because I'm speeding a little bit quickly through this, I'm basically copying
the exact logic I have in this computed property, but I'm replacing all of my former references to
the new one.
So this dot root right here becomes replaced with my new root, which I have access to.
Otherwise I access the query property and the page property.
If we don't have that, I fall back to a string of one and the ultimate string that I end up with here,
either this one or the fallback of one, is what I passed back into this helper function to get an integer,
and then I'm going to wrap that integer in its own computed functionality.
So we're going to get a reactive current page object with a value property set to whatever the page
string is or the query proven to be more specific.
All right.
So that's going to eliminate current page right here that we can move on to doing something very similar
for previous page.
So right here I'm going to say contact previous page.
We need to re compute this every time.
One, it's dependent on changes.
So once again, I want to wrap all my logic inside a computed function and pass the function we want
to rerun each time.
What I'm going to do here actually, is I'm going to cut and paste our old code from here into here,
and then we're simply going to modify because this should be good enough to update itself.
So in our previous implement implementation, we were using this dot current page.
Obviously this no longer exists, but now current page exists above.
So we're going to access current page.
You'll notice we're going to get a really helpful error from yes lint.
And he will tell us, hey, you must use dot value to read or write the value wrap by computed.
So s lint recognizes that we're getting a reactive object here that's storing the number.
It's not the number itself.
So we can subtract minus one from a reactive object.
We need to get the actual number it's storing.
So right here I'm going to do current page dot value.
All right.
So again, to reiterate, we can use computed things in other computer things.
And root, which we got right here is a reactive object.
So because we're referencing root right here in this computer function, every time the root object
changes, more specifically the query object inside it and the page property, the current page computed
function right here will rerun.
And because we're referencing current page in our next computed function, every time current page changes.
So will so will this function rerun right here, thus updating the value of the previous page computed
object.
All right.
So we can totally nest computed reactive objects in other functions, pass to other computer functions,
and you can go as many levels down as we need.
All right.
So we've taken care of previous page.
Let's do something very similar for our next computer property, which is next page.
So right here I'm going to say next page and we're going to utilize the computed function provided a
function as an argument.
And in here, I'll copy and paste our former implementation right here and modify it accordingly.
So once again, in here, we're referencing we're referencing this dot current page.
This no longer exists, but current page does as a reactive object with a value property.
All right, once again, this does not exist, so I can get rid of that.
We no longer have filter jobs in all caps, but we do have filter jobs right here from our composable
function.
And this is the exact same thing we want.
This is our reactive object, storing our array of filter jobs.
So instead of referencing this constant, I'm just going to reference filter jobs.
But once again, this is not going to be enough in this case.
S lint is not going to help us because this logic is coming from another file.
But remember, use filter jobs is a composable that returns its own computed reactive object.
Thus, filter jobs right here does not represent an array.
It represents a reactive object holding an array.
So I need to make sure I get that underlying array by doing dot value and then I want to take the length
of that actual array, not as my filter jobs reactive object.
So once again, because we're referencing filter jobs here whenever this composable function reruns
and that will happen whenever the getter updates.
So whenever we get our updates, this composable function will rerun, it's going to re compute the
filtered jobs which we're referencing right here, which means we're going to rerun this computed function
and calculate the next value of the next page object to the reactive value.
As soon as those changes happen.
So it's almost like this propagation and event sets everything off and it is re computed by the next
thing line which forces the re computation of the next thing line, so on and so forth.
All right.
So with that, we have taken care of next page.
And the last one we have to take care of is display jobs.
So right here, very similarly, I'm going to declare displayed jobs and that's going to be the return
value of my computed function.
This is going to be the standard protocol.
Whenever we are replacing the computed properties in the composition API, we're simply going to do
computed function calls instead.
Let me once again.
Cut this.
Paste this right here.
All right.
Once again, we no longer have current page or this not current page, but we do have current page that
value.
All right.
Page number at this juncture is going to be a number because we got it from values.
So this is fine.
This is fine.
This start filter jobs is no longer.
Okay, so we're going to replace this with filter jobs from above.
Once again, filter jobs is our reactive object.
We need to get the array because it is the array that has the slice method, not our reactive object,
storing the array and tracking changes to it.
So make sure you access that value before invoking slice.
All right.
That allows us to clear up computed, but we are not done quite yet because while we declared all of
these computed function calls right here, the last thing we need to do, of course, is to make them
available to our template.
And of course, the way we do that is by returning an object with all the things we need.
All right.
So in our template, we're obviously going to need previous page and next page.
We're doing them right here, previous page.
Next page.
We're going to need current page as well.
And finally, we're going to need display jobs in order to iterate over that array of sliced jobs.
So we're going to need four properties in our template.
So we need to make sure we return all of them right here.
So right here, it's going to be displayed at jobs.
That's the one we're iterating over.
Then we have our previous page, then we have our current page, and finally our next page.
If you ever forget what your template needs it, just scroll up and see all the names that we use throughout
and then make sure you're returning all those properties from your object.
This should take care of it.
So if I navigate to my browser.
All right.
We just saw that error, but it went away, which is great.
That means you re.
Let me go to the jobs page.
We can scroll down and see that our next button is here.
If I click that and scroll down, we can see previous and next are working just fine.
So it looks looks like everything is still functional.
So we have completely replaced our former component implementation from using the options API to now
using the composition API.
Now, unfortunately, our setup method is getting a little bit bulky, but that's fine because a lot
of similar logic is close to each other.
We're going to talk more in the next lesson about how we can simplify this setup method by moving some
of this logic to separate composable functions in other files.
All right.
So we are going to start to break down this complex setup method in the next lesson.
But the good news for now is that we have refactored that old complexity.
We've kind of isolated it to a single method and we are using the most latest features in view by now
the composition API.
So with that, I will leave you here and I will see you in the next lesson.