Okay.
So we have everything we need to use the named slots that we defined in our header container component.
So on the right hand side, I have my header container view component and on the left side I have my
team's view component.
Right now we are rendering a self-closing tag for our header container.
Let's now expand it to have an opening tag and a closing tag.
So right here, header container.
And afterwards, immediately I'm going to have my closing tag right here and then I'm going to do a
line break.
So we know that if we have a single slot component in my child right here in header container, then
here in the parent is where I can customize the dynamic content to inject in that default slot.
Well, now our situation is a little bit more complex because we have two slots, one that is called
title one that is called subtitle.
So in my parent component, I have to actually specify which slot I want to inject custom content to.
Because otherwise view will not know.
So the way we do that is by adding another template tag.
So right here, I'm going to add a template tag.
Opening and closing.
And then on that template tag, I'm going to add a new view directive.
All right.
And that directive is called V slot and there is a hyphen between V and slot.
Okay.
That is a directive that allows us to specify which named slot we want to target.
So in this scenario, I want to target my title slot right here.
So the way I specify title is by putting a colon and then the name of the slot, which is title.
Okay.
So let me reiterate the word we put here after the colon has to be the exact same value we give to this
name.
Prop right here in my actual head or container component.
So if I call this nonsense right here, this would be v slot colon.
Nonsense.
Okay.
The reason we're seeing an S lint violation, by the way, is because there is a shorthand syntax for
this, which I will show you later.
But this is valid as well.
Okay.
V dash slot followed by a colon and the name of the slot we want to target.
I want to target my title slot.
Then within my opening and closing template tags, I actually put the content that I want injected in
that slot.
So for example, here I can put an H1 and let's give it a couple of tailwind classes.
Let's do w fall for 100% with let's do text dash for Excel.
That's going to give it a really large font size of 36 pixels.
And then just to make sure the font is a normal size, I'm going to do font normal or a normal weight
to be more specific.
So it's not going to be super bold, just font normal.
And here I can add some text like teams.
Okay.
So how can we target the other slot, the subtitle slot using the exact same syntax.
I create another opening and closing template tag and on the opening one I provide my v slot directive,
a colon and the name of the slot I want to target.
In this case it has to be subtitle because that is the name we gave it right here.
Here is where I provide the content for that slot.
So in this case, we may want to provide, let's say, an H2 and it will provide some classes on that
H2.
Let's say we're going to do a full again for 100% width.
I want to add a little bit of margin on the top and bottom.
So I will do m.y or margin the Y axis.
Let's do Y for let's make this a normal text size.
So I'll do a text based and then let's also do a little bit of a lighter font.
So I will do font light to decrease the font weight to 300.
All right.
And here we can put some sample text like, it's awesome working here.
Why don't you come join us?
So the advantage of this slots approach and this tailwind approach is in each paired component, we
can customize two independent slots to independent injectable chunks of HTML with their own custom styling.
And if we want to reuse the header container on any other component, we certainly can.
And we can give two completely different pieces of slot content with totally different styling, but
still keep the benefits of the header container component, which is this logic right here, the border
and the centering of the text.
Right, and the margin on top and bottom.
So we can keep the reusability of these divs while customizing the content in the middle using these
two named slots.
All right.
And that's exactly what we've done here by providing a custom H1 and a custom H2 with custom text content
and custom tailwind styles.
Right.
We have not hardcoded this into our header container.
Rather, we have allowed the parent to specify it, which allows another parent to customize it.
So now if I go to my browser.
We're going to see exactly what we expect.
We have our custom H1, we have our custom H2.
This is our title slot that we are providing content for.
This is our subtitle slot that we are providing content for.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.