All right, so let's do a quick section review will typically do this at the conclusion of every section.
Just to summarize our learnings from the previous lessons.
And this one was a pretty short section.
So of course we know that we can write our styles inside a few components style tags and inside those
style tags we can write any kind of valid access that we want.
We can target IDs, classes, age, HTML elements, etc., whatever you'd like.
It's just plain access.
But of course, the most important takeaway from these lessons is that we want to add the scoped keyword
right after style.
And what scope does is it limits the styles to just the current component.
So if we target, for example, access class, it's only going to apply the styles to that class in
that component.
If that CSC class is written in another component, the styles will not be applied.
So the scoped keyword prevents access leakage, it prevents pollution across different files.
It makes it easier to define components as they should be defined as small, isolated, reusable, independent
pieces of our UI.
All right.
That's all there is to cover here.
I'll see you in the next lesson.