Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we created our first getter of unique organizations.
So now let's add a complementary test for that method.
So as a reminder, all of the tests for our view X store constructs are stored in index that test,
that gas, that file is located in tests unit store.
And currently we have all of our tests here for the state, for the mutations and for actions.
Maybe later on we'll think about splitting it up.
But for now, let's put our getter tests in here as well.
So at the very top here, we're currently importing state mutations and actions.
Let's also import getters, which is going to represent this object that we created and exported in
the previous lesson.
And while we're at it, let's make all of these imports alphabetical just because I think it's going
to make it a little bit easier to read.
So right here, it's going to be actions.
Then getters and then mutations and then state is our final one.
All right.
So I'm going to create a new describe block and let's do it.
How about after mutations and before actions?
So right here, I'm going to describe my getters.
That will be a top level describe.
And then here in the arrow function I'll provide another describe a nested context to describe the getter
that I care about.
In this case, I want to test unique organizations which I created in the previous lesson.
Okay.
And what is the responsibility of this letter?
It finds unique organizations.
From List of jobs.
Again, trying to be pretty ignorant about the implementation, just describing the user value.
Okay.
So what do we need to test?
We need a test that we can invoke this unique organization's method, pass it a state object.
And what are the requirements of that state object?
Well, it just needs to have a jobs property that needs to be an array or something, at least that
supports the for each method.
And as we iterate over that array of jobs, a job is simply an object that has a property called organization.
That's all we need in order for this test to be run.
And that's all we need in our test.
So just because our state has a property like is logged in this test shouldn't really worry about it.
It really doesn't care about it.
It just needs a state that is good enough for the purposes of testing this getter in isolation.
So always go with the simplest test setup that you can see right here.
I'm going to define a sample state of a bookstore, and it's just going to be a simple JavaScript object.
What property do we need on it?
Well, right here we're going to be accessing jobs.
So we need a minimum of a jobs property, and that needs to be an array.
And what do the objects in the array need to have?
They need to have an organization property, because that's what I'm accessing right here.
So I'm going to create an object and I'm going to give it an organization property.
And let's set that equal to something like Google.
So again, do we need all of the additional properties that come with a job object in the real world?
Our job objects will, of course, have those properties.
But for the purposes of testing this method, no, we don't.
We don't want to make it more confusing by adding nine other job properties that we don't care about.
All this getter cares about is having an organization.
That's all I'm going to give it in this sample object.
So below I'm going to copy this thing and create another object.
And let's give it another company organization or like let's say Amazon.
And then just to make sure that I'm properly removing duplicates, I'm going to add one more final object
and give it the exact same organization of Google that just is just going to verify that we are, in
fact, removing all of those duplicate values.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a contact call result.
And how do we test that?
The getter does what it's supposed to do.
We simply invoke it as a plain JavaScript method.
No need to invoke the idea of UEC store.
We can simply test that as a regular bit of JavaScript functionality.
So we have our getters object.
Our Getters Object has a method on it called unique organizations.
That Unique Organizations Method expects a object that we call state.
It can be any object, obviously in the real world that's going to be in the U.S. store state.
But for our sake, it can be the state object above because the state object above is good enough.
It has the exact properties that we care about to be able to play the role of a view store or a view
state to be more specific for the purposes of this test.
So what do we expect to get back from this method?
In our results constant, we expect it to be a set.
So right here expect result to equal.
So what I can do here is I can provide the new set syntax in line.
And one way that we can populate a set when we're creating it instead of consistently invoking the ad
method, is we can provide the set constructor function with an array representing the values that we
want that set to hold.
So I'm going to have three organizations, but I expect my final return set to have only two elements,
right?
Because we are prohibiting duplicates.
So even though Google is listed twice above, I only want it listed at once in the set, which makes
sense.
So our final set should have the values Google and Amazon, and that's going to verify that our getter
is doing exactly what it's supposed to do, that it's iterating over the correct property, that it's
accessing the right property on each individual object, and that it's removing duplication.
That's exactly the heart of what our getter is doing, and that's exactly the heart of what our test
is testing right down to the return value.
So I'm going to save this and let's go up here.
Let's open up a new terminal window.
And as always, we can run everyone's favorite command and PM run test colon watch and we're going to
run the tests since the last commit.
For me, it's going to be only our new one and we can see that our new getter test is passing.
Now, as always, I just want to be extra confident that I'm testing correctly.
So one way we can make this fail, of course, is by getting rid of a sample line like this one.
This prevents us from iterating and just returns an empty set, and that at least should give me a failing
test, which is good, because it's verifying that our test is doing everything as it should.
So right here we are expecting in our test a set of two elements.
Instead of we're getting an empty set.
Everything here is working exactly as it should.
And let me again show you the benefits of testing.
Let's imagine that I have this line right here, but I accidentally this type organization.
So maybe at the very end, I forget the end right here and save this.
Our test will perfectly capture that because a property on a JavaScript object will return undefined.
If it does not exist but not a problem.
Our test will say, hey, this is a set that should have Amazon and Google.
It's now a set that only has undefined that tells us that something has gone wrong.
And we can see here, oh yeah, my organization property actually should have an end at the end.
So once again, tests can prove super helpful to verify that we are testing exactly what we want and
that our functionality is still present in our code.
All right, so now we have written a letter.
We have wired up our getters to out of the store.
We have tested our getters as plain methods.
I think it's now time to see how we can use the getter in a view component.
We're going to do that in the very next lesson.