Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we used our DB dot JSON file to define a degree's endpoint.
The next thing I want to build is going to be the function on the view side that makes the request to
that end point to fetch that data.
So in practice, it's going to be very similar to our get jobs function right here.
This get jobs function in our source API directory makes a request to these slash jobs end point to
get the jobs.
And we're going to need a very similar function to get our degrees.
We're going to figure out how to add it all to, for example, our view store or to our components later.
For now, I want to isolate the logic of the actual API fetch to its own function and let's have of
course call that function get degrees.
So what I'm going to do is simply make a copy of this file as well as the corresponding test file and
adjust both of them to match the differences between it, get jobs and get degrees.
So right here, let me right click on this file and let me go ahead and copy it.
And right here in API, I'm also going to paste it.
And of course, I'm going to rename this file to B get degrees.
Don't test that.
Yes.
All right.
Let me make sure I spell it correctly.
There we go.
And let me open that file on the right hand side.
And what I'm going to do in my source API folder is create a new file as well.
I'm going to call it get degrees.
That that's.
And for now.
Let me just leave it blank.
Well, basically make it a reality in just a second.
All right.
So let's first focus on a test suite, because I do want to follow a TDD approach.
So we're going to be able to keep most of this code.
We're just obviously adjusted for our new soon to be written function.
So we're going to import Axios, we're going to mock at Axios.
That sounds good to me.
Then we're going to, of course, import our new function, which is now going to be called get degrees,
something to change that name as well as the new file that we have below here.
We are going to mark out the Axios get or rather give it the specific type, which is exactly as we
should do in TypeScript here.
By the way, we're going to see an error because it's not able to see any export yet from this file.
Totally.
Fine.
We'll come back to that later.
So right here we are marking out the resolved value of the Axios get method.
And this object right here, of course, for example, resembles a sample job object or a mock job object.
So just to make it a little bit more clear and to make this resemble our real world API more closely,
I'm going to change this from title to degree, and I'm going to give it a value like Master's, and
that's exactly what a real world degree object looks like from the API.
All right.
So right here, it fetches jobs that candidates can apply to.
Let's change this to fetches all possible degree requirements.
It's going to be an async test.
I'm going to await the invocation and the resolution of the get degrees function.
And then I'm going to expect that Axios get should have been called with the correct API.
Remember that or the correct URL.
Remember that my fake API is coming from our environment variable file so that will always be the same.
What should change is the actual endpoint we hit.
So this of course should be degrees.
All right.
Down below.
Instead of extracts jobs from response, I'm going to say extract degrees from response.
Once again, we're going to invoke get degrees.
And of course, the data here, once we unravel it should be equal to this object right here.
So I'm simply going to copy and paste it right here.
So again, using our get jobs tests as inspiration for this new test, we forget degrees and I'm going
to run that.
And of course it should fail.
Right.
Of course it's going to fail because there's no function here, and that's totally fine.
All right.
So if I go back to get jobs, that yes, we can obviously use this as inspiration.
But before we do notice that what we're doing here is we're importing an interface called a job from
the types file.
And the reason we're doing that is to use that as a generic type, right here to tell TypeScript that
the Axios get method will return a promise wrapping an array of job objects.
And of course, that is beneficial because that is going to be how TypeScript understands what your
API actually returns, because it has no way of knowing otherwise.
So what I'd like to do is to go into this types file and that's going to going to be source API types.
That's and I want to define a similar interface for my degree object.
So right here, I'm going to export an interface called Degree.
And of course, the way this is going to look is exactly as it looks in our DB, that JSON file.
So each degree, as you can see on the right is going to have an ID property and that is going to be
a number.
It's also going to have a degree property and that is going to be a string.
All right.
And make sure you export that degree.
So with that, I'm going to save this file and then I'm going to come back to get jobs at times and
copy this code to get degrees that.
Yes.
And as always, we're going to modify it accordingly.
So here I'm going to import, not job, but degree.
That is our new interface.
And of course, our function right here is going to be called get degrees.
This will also be get degrees right here.
All right.
So our base URL is going to stay the same because that is coming from our environment variable depending
on which environment we're in.
It could be test, it can be prod development, etc..
And here in our generic is where we specify what our response will look like wrapped inside, of course,
that complex Axios response object.
So now as a generic type, we don't expect an array of jobs, we expect an array of degrees.
So I'm going to use my degree interface that I imported and then the square brackets to indicate that
that is going to be an array.
So an array of objects, each of them having, we're implementing the degree interface, having those
two properties that we just declared in the type slot.
Then of course, my actual endpoint is not going to be slash jobs.
It's going to be slash degrees.
And then when I get back to access response object, I'm going to actually get the data property from
it.
And that should give me, as you can see here, a degree array.
So you can see here, if I look at the typescript inference as a result of us adding the generic, you
can see that TypeScript understands that get degrees is going to be an asynchronous function that returns
a promise that resolves to give us an array of degree objects.
I'm going to save that.
Let the test run.
Here they are on the right hand side for reference.
We're verifying the right hitting the right URL.
And that we're extracting the correct property, which is data, to get to the actual heart of the response,
which is what our back end API provides that are Axios object wraps.
And you can see all of our tests are now passing.
All right, so now we've implemented the API function call to actually set your degrees and we'll continue
with this in our next lesson.