In this lesson, I'd like to introduce you to an optional second argument to the mount function within
a test.
The optional second argument can be a view configuration object, and that configuration object accepts
basically all the same properties as a regular view configuration object does.
So as a reminder, I have Main now opened here on the right hand side and as I scroll down, here is
our view configuration object for the main nav component.
We have this data method here that returns the data that is available within our component.
If we want to customize this within our test, we can do so using the second argument to mount.
So for example, I can do this, I can provide a second argument to mount with my JavaScript object
and I'm going to do a line break here and here.
I'm going to follow the exact same syntax as I have on the right hand side.
I'm going to define a data method.
And that method is going to return a JavaScript object.
And now let's say I take my company property, but for the purposes of this test and for the purposes
of this mounted main nav component just in our test, I want the company property on our data to be
Super Corp. instead.
All right.
So the way to think about this is almost like we're borrowing the HTML template from the main nav component.
But instead of keeping these properties that are originally there in the implementation, we're customizing
the data on the component in our test.
So now when we run this, we're still going to go ahead and render the component onto the screen or
into the wrapper, which in turn is going to display or interpolate the value of the company property.
But of course, we're going to get a failure because now the components text is going to be the string
super corp and our actual company name of bubble careers is not going to be found anywhere in that.
Now, of course, we can always change this to Super Corp. and that will make the test pass.
I'm going to save that and rerun the test, and then we're going to see that the tests indeed do pass.
So one small advantage of this implementation is that to a new developer, they can sort of make the
connection that the data methods company property is what is being rendered on the screen.
Right.
But that is the only advantage I see to this approach.
And I actually have an issue overall with this version of the test.
I liked our first version a lot more.
I did want to show you this option because it shows you what the second argument to the Mount function
represents and how we can use it to customize the internals of the component.
But I also want to talk about why I'm not a fan of this strategy.
So this is not an ideal test.
And I think the reason why is because this test is very closely coupled to our implementation.
This test knows too much about how the internals of the main NAV component works.
It knows details such as the fact that there is a company property on data.
Right.
The purpose of this test is simply to check that we have a company name displayed somewhere in our component.
But now our test sets up a specific criteria that it needs to know about the internals of the components
data to test something that is view related, which is some text appearing on the screen.
It's highly unlikely that we would have written this test with TDD if we hadn't written our component
yet.
We would have no clue whether our company name was coming from the data property or any other property
that we'll introduce later, or whether we simply hardcoded the text Bobo carriers or in this case Super
Corp into our actual HTML template.
This test knows a lot about what the component needs in order to work, and the reason that's bad is
because if our component changes our implementation, for example, if we were to write a hard code
Bobo careers in line instead of making it internally at the company property, this test would fail.
Right?
Let me show you an example of that.
If I were to cancel out company right here and I would have to write verbal carriers right here.
This test would fail.
Even though it still fulfills lot of the implementation, rather does fulfil the primary requirement
of displaying the company name.
All we really care about for the users sake is that our company brand bubble careers is written somewhere
in the component.
We don't really care whether it's hardcoded like so or whether it is coming in because it's interpolated
from the data property or the company property more specifically.
All we really care about is that bobble career as a summer on the screen.
And yet as soon as we change something in our component, our tests fail.
Our tests are brittle, they are flaky, they are not stable and reliable.
And the reason is because our tests are closely coupled to the actual implementation.
Your tests should show test behavior.
Ideally, they should test inputs and outputs.
What is this component supposed to do?
At the same time, your test shouldn't really worry about how your component is doing it, just what
it is doing, right?
So my preference here is to let's bring this back.
Let's bring company back here.
Let's make sure company is written back here.
My personal preference is to return back to our original test, so I'm going to delete all of this.
This was all, for example, to show you the second argument to mount.
But my personal preference is a test like this.
Notice how it's also a lot cleaner and simpler.
We just say, Hey, we want a may nav component and somehow, some way in this text, we want bubble
careers.
We don't care whether that value is hard coded.
We don't care about whether that value is coming from the company data attribute.
If we were to now add bubble careers right here instead of interpolating the company property, this
test would still pass and it would still deliver on our expectation to the user that the component is
displaying the company name.
So while I wanted to introduce the second argument as a good introduction to how you can customize a
component, and sometimes that may be helpful in a test, just if you want to quickly make sure that
everything is working as expected, maybe you can give it a different value of data just to double check
that your assumptions are correct, etc. There are ways that we can reach out to a component and change
its internal state, but generally it's not recommended to do so, in my opinion, because we are we
are making our tests know way too much about how the actual code works.
Remember, we want to test behavior instead of implementation, and when we do that, our tests will
be more likely to endure as we actually change the internals of how we build our components.
Right.
A test like this is very easy to write with TDD a test like the one that we just wrote a second ago.
You would never write with TDD, you would never know how your component is going to implement a such
a feature.
So you wouldn't be able to guess that it would be reliant on data and a company property and data.
So that's another benefit of TDD is it keeps you honest and more likely to write simpler tests that
actually check for the things that are worth caring about.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.