In the previous lesson, we started adding our menu items to our main nav component and our main NAV
now consists of a unordered list with six different list items, and we saw the redundancy of having
to copy and paste each different list item and then modify a small detail about it, which was the actual
text inside the hyperlink.
So if we once again observe the six list items that we have right here, we'll notice that they're actually
very similar to each other.
There's only two actual differences between all of them.
Number one is the text that we display right here.
And number two is the very first one does not have that EML nine class.
So that first list element does not add any additional left margin on its left side.
But other than that, these are basically all pretty close, in fact, even identical when it comes
to the classes and the two elements that they contain.
So for now, we can ignore the first one since it's slightly different and focus just on the last five.
These are all pretty much identical with the exception of the text that they displayed to the user.
Well, wouldn't it be great if we could automate this render using view instead of having to copy and
paste this five times?
Wouldn't it be great if we can just say, Hey, I want a list item, but I want it five times for these
five different values of locations, life, how we hire, etc. will view allows us to do that with something
called the V4 Directive.
It's another directive, meaning it's another special view command that we can use to help us optimize
our code and our template.
Let's take a look at how it works.
The first thing I'm going to do is navigate to the very bottom of my component.
Here we have our data object and again, all of these properties are available to use within my HTML
template.
And what I want to do here is add a new property called menu items, and I'm going to set it equal to
an array.
All right.
So this is our first value that's going to be not a string, but that's totally fine.
We can have our data object store, whatever kind of values we want.
In this array, I'm going to populate all of our unique menu item text values.
So we're going to start again with teams.
We're going to start with locations, then life at Fogo, then how we hire and students and jobs.
All right.
And when I save this prettier is going to break this up across multiple lines.
And that's totally fine.
All right.
So now what I'm going to do is scroll all the way to back where we wrote all these list items.
And for now, I'm going to keep this one since it is a little bit different.
And so we are going to duplicate the value of teams in just a second.
But I promise you, we're going to fix this issue in an upcoming lesson.
What I ultimately want to do is get rid of this and then render one single fly and tell you to replicate
or duplicate that ally for all of the elements in my array.
All right, so here's how it's going to work.
I'm going to get rid of these last four.
And for this one, I'm going to keep this and I'm going to add my directive right here in line.
My DirecTV is called V for the V for DirecTV allows us to iterate over some kind of iterable, meaning
an array or an object or anything that has multiple elements.
And for each one of those elements, we're telling Vue to create this HTML element.
So in this case, when we iterate over our menu items array, we're going to have six elements in it.
So we're going to create six allies, and they're all going to have the same classes as we see here,
and they're all going to have a nested a hyperlink inside them.
Right.
So we know we want to iterate over each thing in our menu items array.
And the syntax here is going to specify an individual element in our full collection.
Let me write it out and then we'll talk about what it means.
So what I'm going to write here is menu item in menu items.
So you'll notice the second thing here, menu items is the same as our property name here, and that
is intentional.
Here we are specifying what we are iterating over, what is our collection, what is our array.
And this is coming directly from our data method.
Then before the end keyword, we provide a temporary variable name almost for each individual element
that we're iterating over.
So we're going to be iterating over one menu item at a time, or in other words, one string at a time
over this array.
And for each one, we're going to create a ally.
And the reason why it's important to use the syntax is menu item just like in a regular for loop is
going to represent each one of those strings one at a time and we are free to use it when we want to
render its contents somewhere to the screen.
So if we take a look at what we have now, the reason this is problematic is we're going to create six
allies.
But of course each one of them is going to have the same text of locations.
And that's not what we want.
We want to dynamically inject whatever is the current string that we are iterating over.
Well, that string is going to be available via this menu item, temporary variable.
And how can we interpolate a variable value inside our template with the exact same syntax we used to
interpolate a data property earlier on.
Here we have an example of a company, so I'm going to use the curly brace syntax and now I'm going
to use a menu item that's that dynamic variable that's going to represent each menu item one at a time
as we iterate over the menu items in this array.
All right.
So at this point, I'm going to take a pause because this code is not going to work just yet.
If I go to my browser, we're going to see it failed to compile.
Our syntax is completely correct, but there's one more thing we need to add to get this to work.
And I'll show you what that is in the very next lesson.