Okay.
So let's write a second test for our get jobs function as a reminder when we call the get method on
the Axios object.
Axios returns a promise and a promise is just an object that represents an asynchronous event that will
take some time to complete.
And when that event completes, it gives us something back.
And that is called the promise resolved.
What the promise resolves to is basically the value we get at the very end of that asynchronous event.
So in the case of a get request, we reach out to a euro such as our you all right here.
Access is going to give us a promise that's going to resolve to be an object with a data property.
And let me just wrap this in a comment.
So it's very easy to see Axios and it gives us a promise that resolves to be an object with a data property,
and that data property holds the actual jobs that we care about.
The reason it wraps it in a larger object is because there's also these additional properties that basically
represent metadata about the request and the response.
But the actual value that we want from our backend is nestled in this data actually.
So the next test that I want to write wants to make sure that what we get back from the get jobs function
will be the actual array of jobs.
I basically want to parse out the information that I want from the complexity of the Axios object that
I get.
So kind of I'll let this function make the request and take care of worrying about the Axios knowledge
so that when my component calls get jobs or something else, Collins gets jobs.
It's just going to get back that array of jobs.
It doesn't have to worry about how the internals of this function work.
So I'm going to delete this comment and in my test suite I'll add another assertion.
It extracts jobs from response.
That's what I want to test.
All right.
So very similarly to our previous test, we're going to have an async test right here.
So in async function and we're going to again await get jobs are going to wait until that asynchronous
function completes.
And then I expect that that is going to give me back my jobs, my data.
So I'm going to sign the return value of my get jobs, asynchronous function to a constant call data.
And then I'm going to expect my data to be equal to some.
Now, you might be curious, what are we going to provide here?
Well, it doesn't really matter what we provide here.
As long as we mock out Axios dot, get in this test file to return the same thing.
Basically, I'm just going to replace this implementation with my own version of Axios and then verify
that whatever get gives back.
To me.
That's exactly the same thing that I'm extracting from my get jobs function.
It's kind of a complex idea, but let me show you the code and I think at that point it will make sense.
So let's just create this hypothetical array of one job that we're going to get back from our back end.
Again, we have no back end when it comes to tests, but let's imagine that we're going to intercept
that request to a backend and give us back a certain return value.
And let's say that's going to be an array here and that array is going to be an array with one job object.
And I'm just going to give that job object to properties, just so another reader looking at my code
can understand what I have here.
So I'm just going to say ID one and title of Java engineer.
Again, this is not the exact same properties that a real job may have in terms of what we defined in
DB that JSON, but we don't really care.
And I'll show you why in just a second.
So again, this test right now will will fail because obviously we have no nothing here that guarantees
that we're returning anything.
So what I'd like to do now is define a before each in my test file and here is where I'm going to set
up how my get method on my access object works.
Remember by default because we marked out Axios, if we simply were to invoke Axios target get right
here, we would invoke the just mock function that has replaced the original implementation and by default
any just mock function returns undefined.
That's not what we want.
We want a function that doesn't return undefined, but rather returns a promise that resolves to have
an object with a data property.
And that data property should be an array representing this.
So basically what we're doing is we're emulating how Axios works without actually using Axios.
All right.
So the way we can do this is remember Axios dot get is a just mock function.
On a just mock function.
We can define, for example, its return value if we want to, for example, give this get method,
whatever return value we want, we can use a method here called mock return value.
For example, I could provide a value like five.
And what that would mean is whenever my test is invoking Axios target, it would substitute five as
the return value of that Axios get method.
Now, in this scenario, I don't want a return value because that is just a regular asynchronous method.
I want an asynchronous return value or in other words, a resolution of a promise.
So right here, instead of mock return value, I'm going to use another shortcut called mock resolved
value.
So what this is saying is mock out Axios get.
And when you when you invoke that method, have it return a promise that resolves to hold a specific
value.
And what value do I want that promise to resolve to hold?
I want it to be very similar to the exact object that Axios gives me, which is an object with a data
property.
And that data property is going to be an array with the exact same information I have here.
I'm going to copy that array right here.
So now I'm still going to get a failing test because I have successfully mocked that Axios and I've
verified or I've written an assertion to ensure that I'm pulling out the right information, but in
my implementation, I'm still not pulling out that actual information from the real Axios response object,
which I have faked out with a mock object right here.
Okay.
So what do we do to get this to pass?
Well, right here, we know that this is going to give us back a promise.
So what we can do is we can await this promise to resolve.
So I'm going to use the await keyword right here.
And as soon as we use await, we need to make this asynchronous.
So I'm going to make the function asynchronous.
So remember, what a wait is going to do is it's going to wait until that promise resolves and gives
us back a value which is going to be the Axios response object.
So I'm going to assign this to a constant called response.
And remember, response is still not our data response is that JavaScript object that has a data property.
How do I get that data property and return it as my final return value of get jobs?
Well, I need to take my response object from Axios and access its data property that has the array
we want.
And if I save this, we're going to see we're going to get a passing test.
So if this is confusing, let me just demonstrate what went on here, because I know it's kind of tough
to explain and it can be tough to wrap your head around.
Basically what I wrote right here in the before each which runs before every test says whenever we call
Axios got get give us back this object as the resolution of the promise.
So when this test is running, what response represents when the test suite is running?
Is this exact object right here that we set up in our before.
So when our test is running, we get this JavaScript object with a data property.
Of course, in the real world we get back a real Axios object that also has a data property.
So it's the same mark idea that we have tested throughout the course.
We're just replacing the real world object with an object that is good enough to play the role of an
Axios response object.
And then what we're doing is we're accessing the data property of that mock object the exact same way
we would in a real Axios object.
And verifying that from this data property, we're pulling out just the array.
And that's what we care about right here.
That might get jobs function, which is asynchronous when invoked, will ultimately give me back the
array.
It's going to take care of the responsibility of not just using actions to fetch the response, but
pass the correct attribute or property from that Axios response object.
All right.
So with that, I feel pretty good about our test suite.
And moving forward, we can start starting to sync this up with our view store.