Okay.
So in this lesson, we'll practice adding TypeScript to a component that utilizes the new composition
API.
So let's start with our accordion component.
I'm going to open up accordion view.
And the good news here is that the process is going to be very similar to what we just did with the
components that used the options API.
So scrolling down here we have our new setup method.
This is our proof that everything is utilizing the new composition API, but we're going to apply the
exact same two steps.
Step one, we're going to add a Lang attribute right here set to test.
And step two, we're going to import, define component and wrap our complete configuration object with
that function invocation.
So that's coming directly from view and we already have two imports from the View Library.
So right here I'm going to add define component and right here I'm going to invoke defined component
and pass in our configuration object as the first argument to that function invocation.
There we go.
And if I save this, we'll see.
There are no TypeScript violations.
And furthermore, if I hover my mouse over some of these constants, for example, we're going to see
and be able to verify the right types.
So for example, here we can see that is open is a graph which is the view reactive object or at least
one of the one of the types for it and you can see it in the generic is also properly inferred.
The idea that it is wrapping a boolean because we provided the initial false value.
Right.
Same logic here are open function is a function that returns nothing.
That's why it has returned.
I avoid it.
That is correct.
Here we have our computer graph and you can see it's calculating.
Not just that we have a computed RAF, which is basically a reactive object type, but also that it
is wrapping a value of a string array, which is correct because no matter what we return here, it's
either going to be a string array or another string, right?
And thus if I look at the entire set method, this is not really helpful, but we're going to see that
the object and its respective properties and when I say the object, I need the return object.
All of these properties have the exact types that that it should have.
So in other words, these inferences from RAF and computed etc. were all correct.
All right.
That's all we have to do in this component.
Let's also update the corresponding test file.
So accordion dot test that just moved out to the right.
And let's go ahead and change the extension to test.
All right.
In case you import an accordion regularly and you have an error here, just make sure to add a short
view extension.
All right.
And as we scroll down here, everything looks just fine.
It doesn't seem like we have any violations here at all.
So I'm going to be able to simply say and run, test, call and watch.
If we wanted to, we could probably add a little bit more of a better type for config right here than
just an empty object which is assuming from the default.
But for now, I think this is okay.
There we go.
So everything is still passing perfect.
So that's how simple it is to update a composition API component to using TypeScript.
Of course, things might not always go as easy as it did in this lesson, but that's not a problem.
All we have to do then is just provide the right types here in line for wherever.
TypeScript does not get the right inference, and we basically fix the problem the exact same way we
do with an options API component.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.