Okay.
So let's start styling and building out our accordion component.
So here in Accordion View, I'm going to start by applying some tailwind classes to this top level div.
I'm going to add some padding on the Y axis using the py5 class that's just going to add some padding
on the top and bottom of 20 pixels.
And then I want a bottom border, so I'm going to add the border B class.
So border only in the bottom.
I want that border to be solid.
So I will apply the border solid class.
And finally, as far as the border color, I want to use one of the colors that I defined in my tail
in config file, which is brand great too.
So we have a class available now called the Border Brand gray, too.
And that will give it the exact gray that I want.
All right.
We can remove the my accordion text and then we're going to add some more content within this top level
div.
Let's begin with another div.
And here I'm going to apply some classes as well.
I'm going to make this a Flexbox with Flex.
Then I'm going to ask the children to wrap themselves as they cannot fit in line.
So I'm going to do the flex wrap class.
I want to make sure to vertically align my flex children so I'm going to do items center and then I
want to equally space out the flex children within this flex box.
So I'll do that with justify between.
And finally, whenever a user hovers their mouse over this div, I want to make sure that I change their
cursor to be a pointer so they have an understanding that this content is clickable.
So I'm going to apply the cursor pointer class and that's just going to make sure that we have that
little hand icon that appears whenever the user hovers their mouse over this div.
All right.
Inside this second div, I want to add an H3.
And for now, what we're going to do is we're going to build a specific accordion component.
What I mean by that is we're going to build this out so that it solves exactly one problem.
It's going to be our very first accordion for the organization's header, as well as all of the possible
organizations.
Later on, we're going to see how we can make the accordion more generic so that it supports multiple
accordions with different headers and different content.
But for now, I always think it's a good idea to build one specific implementation first.
So then we can think about how we can make it more generic and more usable later.
Okay, so for now I'm going to hard code and H3 value in here.
Later on, we're going to probably find some custom way to customize what the header of this accordion
is.
For now, we're going to make it hard coded.
So right here I'm just going to put the text organizations.
This is going to be the accordion that the user is going to be able to filter organizations by.
And then I'm going to add some classes to this H3.
I'm going to use text base here.
That's just going to use the default font size of 16 pixels.
And I want to have a little bit of bolding here.
So I'm going to do font symbol.
All right, then.
After.
This div this nested the right here.
I want to add another class or another div rather.
And it's going to have its own set of classes and this is going to represent my child content.
When I talk about child content, what I'm referring to is what the user is going to see when they expand
the according to when they ultimately click the carrot.
This is what I want to reveal to them.
This is content that's going to be hidden by default.
But when we expand the accordion, we're going to see it.
And when we collapse the accordion, we're going to hide it again.
So I'm going to give this a class of W full to apply a width of 100%.
And then I want to give it a little bit of top margin, which I will do with the empty five class that
is going to be 20 pixels of top margin.
And in here, I'm just going to put some sample content.
I'm just going to say child for now, this will be our child content by child again, I mean the content
that we will reveal.
Okay.
Now, obviously, it is hardcoded right now, so we're always going to see that value of child.
My question to you is, how can we make this conditional?
How can we conditionally display this child content based on the user interacting with our accordion
in order to enable this and use view features?
All we're going to do is use AVF directive that is going to be connected to data on our accordion.
So let me show you how this is going to work here in my configuration.
I'm going to define my data method and this method is going to return the JavaScript object representing
the components local data and I'm going to have a single property called is open and that property will
be a boolean that reflects whether the accordion is open or not.
When I use the word open, I mean expanded.
I mean showing that child content.
So I'm going to start this component in a is open state of false so the accordion is not open so we
do not want to show this chunk content.
And then when we flip this value, I do want to show this child content.
So what I'm going to do here is before my class, I'm going to add my if directive and I'm going to
connect it to my is open data property.
Okay.
So one more time as a reminder of how this is going to work when the component initializes is open is
set to false, which means V.F. is going to evaluate to false and we're not going to see the child content.
Then once we figure out how to invert this boolean to be true, then VRF will evaluate to true because
is open will be true and we will render that child content.
And if we're able to swap back and forth between false and true and false and true, etc., then we're
going to conditionally render the appearance of this child the content.
Okay.
So in order to be able to alter the value of this property, I need to define some kind of method on
my component.
And then we're going to see how we're going to be able to trigger that method to run.
So right here, I'm going to define a methods section.
And I'm going to define a method called open.
And its responsibility will be to invert or flip the value of the is open data property.
So we know that we can reference this dot is open here.
And what I'm going to do is whatever the current value is of this, I'm going to inverted or flip it
using the exclamation point.
So the way this works in JavaScript is if this is true, we're going to switch it to false.
And if this is false, we're going to switch it to true.
So whatever is the next value I'm going to reassign back to this is open.
So whenever this method runs it's going to invert.
The current value of my is open data property.
It's going to switch it to the opposite one whenever this method runs.
But of course, we still need this method to run at some point, and we're going to do that with a user
click.
And I'm going to register that on this div right here with this collection of classes, I'm going to
add the V on syntax.
As a reminder, we can do Veon, click here and then we can provide the method that we want to run whenever
the user clicks on this dip.
And I want of course to run the open method.
Now, of course, you may recall with the syntax, with using the VR directive, we can replace it,
replace this with a simple add sign.
So I can simply do at click right here and this should wire everything up.
So when the user clicks on this div, we're going to run the open method which is going to invert the
value of the is open data property, which is going to force the component to re render, which will
conditionally display the child.
Okay.
Before we take a look at this in the browser, there's one more thing I want to do.
You may recall that the carrot is going to change whenever the user clicks on the actual component,
right?
So when the component is in a closed state, we want to show the carrot that is pointing down.
And then when the content is expanded or when the component is open, we want to show the carrot pointing
up.
Okay, so what I'm going to do here is below my H3.
I want to render my font awesome icon.
However, what makes this particularly challenging is I want to dynamically alter what my font awesome
icon will do.
My carrot will depend on whatever my is open state is currently.
So whenever you hear that word dependent or derived, the first thought that should come to mind is
a computed property.
So I'm going to define a computed property that will determine what prop I provide to the font.
Awesome icon to dynamically customize which of those symbols I want to display here.
Okay.
So between data and methods, I'm going to define my computed object.
And here I'll define a single method and I'm going to call it carrot icon.
All right.
And here I'm going to use a simple ternary statement.
I'm going to return and I'm going to check on what is the current value of this that is open.
And if it's true, I want to return one option.
And if it's false, I want to return another option.
Now, as a reminder, what we provide to the font awesome icon component right here, which is a global
component, by the way, which is why we're able to use it in line.
We provide it and I can prop set to an array and in that array we have two string arguments.
The first one is always yes, and the second one is the actual string representing the icon that I want
to render.
So if my component is in an open state, I want to render the angle up.
Font Awesome icon.
We registered this one in our main that just filed a lesson ago.
And alternatively, if my component is not in an open state, I want to render the face angle down for
an awesome icon.
Okay, so now we've hardwired this computed property, so we need to connect it to this component right
here.
So we want to provide the icon prop to this font awesome icon component and we want to provide a reference
to our carat icon computed.
Method below.
But remember, this syntax will not work because if we do this then we will think we are providing a
string of care icon to the prop.
We need to provide a dynamic reference to an array referenced by this computed property.
So we need to make sure we use the v bind syntax and add this colon in front.
Okay.
So we have created a computer property that is dependent on whether the component is open or not.
Right.
And with that, we are good to transition to our browser and see how this works.
So I'm going to go back to Chrome and here we have our organizations according we have our bottom order
here and now because the component is in a closed state.
In other words, the is open data property is set to false.
We have the carrot pointing down.
Notice what happens when I click on this.
We're going to automatically flip it to be the other font awesome icon.
The carrot pointing up.
Notice as well that now because the VRF is evaluating to true because is open the data property is set
to true.
We're now showing the child content.
As soon as we click this again, everything is going to invert.
Our carrot is going to point down and our child content is going to disappear.
And because I'm simply inverting the value of the is open got a property in my open method we can go
back and forth.
JavaScript and Vue are simply going to switch back and forth between true and false to display that
conditional child content.
All right.
I can show you this in my view, DevTools.
If I go to view right here and I make sure I go to components right here.
And look in job results.
You and I look at the jobs up there, sidebar and here's my accordion.
You can take a look at the is open property.
It's set to false right now.
And here we have our computed carat icon property.
And you'll notice as I flip this, you'll notice this will evaluate to true and this will switch to
angle up.
And when I click it again, it's going to go back to false and angled down.
And each time I run, this view is going to recalculate automatically and reactively react.
All right.
So that is the core functionality of you.
That's what makes it so powerful.
All right.
So with that, we have created this accordion component.
It's obviously not very reusable.
It has this organizations tax.
We'll talk more about it later.
But in the very next lesson, we're going to introduce, the core subject of this section of the course
is focused on which is slots.
And slots are going to enable us to add some reusability to this accordion component.
So I will see you there.