Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to do a quick review of the default slot in view.
So as a reminder, if we create a slot component and we do not give it a name, view will assign it
a name of default.
So let me show you how this works in my head or container for my very first slot.
I'm going to remove this name prop, so I'm just going to have the slot component by itself.
View is going to assign this for a slot online for a name of default.
That means that if we have the syntax right here, then in our team's view, we can no longer use the
title name.
We have to use the new name of default.
So if I save this and go back to my browser, we're going to see that everything is still working.
Okay, let me head back to this code.
And the reason I wanted to introduce you to this pattern is because you might see it in the real world.
Now, a couple of things to know about this.
Number one, you can only have one slot without a name because you can only have one default name to
give to a slot.
So if we were to remove the name right here, we would run into problems.
So even if we're using this approach where we want to rely on a default slot, we still have to provide
any second slot, any third slot, and so on.
A name property right here or a name prop.
All right.
Furthermore, what I would argue is that if you're going to have more than one slot, I would still
prefer to give each one a name.
And the reason is because I think it's a little bit more explicit.
So, for example, a developer that's looking at our code, if we have a name here, a title going back
to our original design, well, they can see title and subtitle right here and right here.
If we return it back to its V slot of title and they can sort of easily understand the connection,
they can see title and subtitle here as well as in the component that it is rendering.
And it may make it a little bit clearer to them what's going on in comparison.
If they see the default name right here, they may have no clue what is going on.
Right, because they would have to go into the view documentation or they would have to know that internal
detail of view.
The fact that view assigns a slot without a name, the name of default.
Right.
So in my personal preference, if you have a single slot, then you can feel free to use it without
the name prop if you have more than one slot.
I think the syntax of giving each one a name is cleaner and simpler and less likely to confuse somebody.
And that way, whenever you are providing information or content to that slot, you simply use this
consistent syntax of a template tag with a V slot directive with that slot name explicitly written out.
All right.
So I'm just going to return this back to the original implementation, but I did want to do a review
of the default slot and view and how it works.
And I will see you in the next lesson.