Okay.
So before we continue chipping away at our new components, I would like to add a new box shadow to
our tailwind config file.
So let me open up that file.
And again, the reason we need to do this is so that tailwind will generate the right sized classes
for us to be able to use in our templates.
So here we already have this box shadow section.
We have a blue box shadow and now I'd like to add a new one and it will be a grey box shadow.
So Tailwind is going to generate a bunch of classes that start with the word shadow, followed by whatever
prefix we give here.
In this case, it's going to be shadow gray and we're going to provide a string argument here, and
it's going to be zero one pixel, three pixel zero.
And then for the color, we're going to use the RG be a function in CSC.
So that's red, green, blue, alpha, how much red, how much green, how much blue and then how much
opacity.
And again, I just got these values directly from the Google Careers website, so I'm just going to
invoke this function using parentheses.
And we want values of 60, comma, 64, comma, 67, and then for the it pass that we want point three.
All right, so save that and that will create the styles automatically.
If you run into any problems, check your syntax and if everything looks correct and it's still not
working, I recommend shutting down the view server in your terminal.
You can press control C to do that and then starting everything up again with NPM run serv and that
will recalibrate by re importing the Italian config file into your project in case you have any issues.
So with that we have the box shadow we need and in the very next lesson we're going to start building
out the job listing.
That's going to represent one job on our site.