Okay.
So our job listings component is now utilizing the composition API.
But as we can see, our setup method is getting pretty long and complex.
So of course one way that we can simplify it is by moving some of this logic into composable functions
that exist elsewhere in the code base.
And I would argue even if these functions aren't reusable yet, in other words, if we're only going
to use their logic in one component, I still don't think that's a problem because we still get the
benefit of having a smaller, leaner component that is relying on a bunch of separate, independent,
testable functions compared to cramming all this logic in here.
For example, this Logic Online's 59 through 62, which talks to the reactive root object and gets the
current page.
This is logic that only exists on this component, but I can easily see it being used elsewhere.
And even now it will help us to move this logic to a separate composable function that is then tested
and ready to be reused whenever it's needed.
So let's extract just this logic to a new composable function.
I'm going to open up my file explorer and in the source directory you'll remember we have our composable
folder and I'm here.
I'll create my new one, my new file, that is, and I'll call it use current page that J.S. and the
responsibility of this composable function will be to give me a reactive object representing the current
page the user is on based on the page query param that we're going to be able to get from our root object.
So right here I'm going to declare my arrow function.
I'm going to call it use current page.
And what I'm going to do for now is leave it blank because I want to remember to export default that
arrow function up above and the body of my use current page function is basically going to be the exact
same thing I have right here.
So let me copy and paste the code I have in my job listings component.
I'm going to put it right here in the body.
We are going to need to modify it slight, slightly.
So the first thing is here, we're using a current page constant to get the return value of the computed
function.
We don't want that reactive object saved to a constant.
We simply want to return that reactive object as the final computation or return value of this composable.
So right here, I'm just going to swap this with return.
And obviously in order to use these two functions, use root and computed, we'll have to import them.
So right here, I'm going to import use root and that is going to come from the router.
And then above that, our computed function is going to come from view.
It's important computed and that is going to come from view and now we're going to use computed to return
a reactive object storing a number representing the current page.
The users on remember the logic of this as well is if we don't have the page property on our queer params,
we're going to default to a string of one which this number that pass in logic will convert to a integer
of one.
And then again, it's not just the return value of a number, it's a return value of a number that is
being stored in a reactive object as returned by the computed function.
So before we utilize this in our job listings component, the next thing I want to do is quickly add
a test sweep.
So right here in my tests unit composable folder, I'll create a new file called Use Current Page.
That test.
Yes.
And let me drag my implementation to the left and then I'm going to get my terminal window open and
run npm run test to watch.
All right.
So I'll begin by importing my newly created composable, which is called use current page, and that
is going to come from source composable to use current page.
I know in here that I'm going to be using use route and then using it to get this evaluation.
So immediately I'm going to import and mark out use route.
So right here, import use route and that is going to come from Vue router.
And on the line below, we're going to do just mark providing view router.
So now use route for the purposes of this file.
And the test suite is now a just mock function.
So right here, I'm going to describe that what I'm testing is my use current page composable function.
And there's actually two scenarios where this function could run, right?
There's two pathways it can take.
Number one, our route object or more specifically, the query object.
Inside, it may have a page property or it may not.
And it's very important to test both of those scenarios because that's the both of the ways that the
function could run.
So right here, I'll begin with another describe and that's going to be when query params include page.
And down below I'll do something very similar.
I'm just going to copy and paste this.
Describe below.
And my second describe will be when query params exclude page.
So in other words, when it's not present.
All right, so let's write our first test right here.
When the queer params include the page, it returns the page.
In other words, it extracts it from the root object.
All right, so we need to have a root object here that is going to mimic the design we have here.
So it has to have a query property, which is its own object with a page property.
So right here, use root, I want to mock return value.
It's going to be an object.
It needs to have a query property.
And to fulfill this implementation and this test, it also needs a page property.
Let's set that to an arbitrary string representing any number we want.
How about five?
And then what I expect is I'm going to be able to invoke my use current page composable function and
that's going to give me a reactive object.
So result is the reactive object I need to reach inside it to get its value property.
So right here, if I go into that reactive object and gets current value, if everything's correct in
my implementation, then my logic should have gotten this string of five.
It should have passed it into number that pass it.
And I should expect this to be the value five.
Let's save that.
And we could see it passes and down below.
We can take care of the other one.
So right here.
If the career params do not include page, we're going to default to page one.
So right here we once again need to set up our use root function to return something to fit this test.
So I'm use route, I'm going to mark return value and I'm still going to have a query object because
that is always going to exist.
That is part of the use route object or more specifically the route object.
And that function gives to me.
However, I'm going to leave my query object empty because this is the case I want to simulate when
we do not have the page query param.
So this is the case where this logic is going to evaluate to undefined, which means we need to fall
back to the string of one and then get one as our final reactive value here.
So right here, same logic I'm going to do cons.
The result is going to be invoking use current page.
That's going to give me a reactive object.
Then I can say what is a result value going to be in the case that there is no query param, it should
be the number one.
All right.
So there we go.
We're going to get both of those tests passing.
And with that, we are good to move this logic into our component.
So I'm going to close our test file, move this to the right hand side, and let's start by importing
it.
So right here, I'm going to import my new composable import use current page.
It is a default export, so we do not need curly braces.
That's going to come from the source directory composable.
And then finally our file is called Use Current Page.
And all I'm going to do is replace this former logic with my new composable function.
Remember, at the end of the day, what I'm returning here is current page, and current page is also
a constant that needs to exist here because it's being used right here and right here.
So all I'm going to do to show you the before and after is comment this out.
And here I'm going to say contact's current page is simply going to be the reactive object returned
by my use current page composable function.
All right.
And this will still work with everything because we are getting a reactive object here.
So all of our old implementation, which is referencing current page value here, current page value
here and current page that value here, all of that will still work because this composable function
is still returning a reactive object with a value property.
That's why I make sure to return the actual computed function indication because we're getting the kind
of object we need for all of these other computed functions in this component to work.
All that's changed is that we moved this logic to this separate function that's tested right here.
And again, the advantage of this approach is when we test job listings, we're going to be able to
test it without having to worry about this logic anymore.
We can simply mark out the use current page composable to do whatever it needs to do.
And the other benefit, of course, is now we can reuse this logic in whatever components we want.
So with that said, we can go ahead and remove this collection of comments it outlines, save that,
and if I scroll up you'll see that that also removes the need for user out.
I'm going to remove that line as well.
We might be getting some failures here and that is totally fine.
Those failures are coming from the job listings component, which is now using the new composable that
we just implemented.
Totally fine.
We'll come back to those areas in a later lesson, but this definitely moves us in a much better step.
And we'll talk more about how we can continue cleaning up the job listings component in the follow up
lessons.
So I'll see you there.