All right.
So we now have a skills search term property on our View Store State and we also have a mutation to
update that string.
And later on, of course, we want to commit that mutation as the user types in our new input.
Of course, the reason we're storing that skills search term string in state is so that we can use it
to filter our jobs array, which is also in state.
And the previous way that we've done that, of course when it came to, for example, our organization,
our job type in our degree is we defined these smaller getter methods right here as an example, include
job by organization.
And these getter methods accepted a single job and using a specific criteria such as selected organizations.
In this case, these getters determined whether one job fit the criteria or not.
And then our filter job's getter, of course, aggregates all of these getters together to arrive at
the final array of jobs that fit all of the criteria.
And we're going to utilize the exact same logic here.
We're going to create a new getter.
It's going to be called include job by skill.
And its responsibility will be to accept a single job and verify whether or not it belongs based on
the user's skills.
Search term property being in that jobs title.
Remember from a few lessons ago, we're not going to check the description, we're just going to check
the title.
And the test should give you a better clue or a better understanding of what is going on here.
So here I have my getters that test that's valid.
Here is the tests for all of our getters.
And I'm going to scroll down a little bit here.
All of my included getter tests are kind of lumped close by right next to each other.
So how about right below this one where we have include job by degree?
I'll create a new describe.
And what we're going to be testing is our new getter, which I will call include job by skill.
The responsibility of this getter method will be to accept the state and a single job and confirm whether
or not it should be included based on a skills match.
Right.
So right here it identifies if job matches users skill.
Provide an arrow function as a second argument to it.
And we're going to begin, of course, with our starting state so we can use an example like this for
inspiration.
So I'm going to have my state and I'm going to use the create state helper function, which is available.
And of course in my state I now have a property called Skills Search Term and let's say that is set
to a string like view.
All right.
So the user searches for view in my input.
Eventually it'll make its way to my store state and that's what I have.
Then I'm also going to have a job.
And remember in this file, I'm going to have a create job helper function.
And a job is going to have a bunch of properties.
One of them is indeed a title, and let's say the title of this specific job is going to be view developer.
So in this example, the search term, the user has a view is found within my title.
So I do want to say that this job does indeed match it as a valid job to be included on the right hand
side or in the filter jobs based on the criteria of skills match.
Right.
So what I'm going to say is here's a new concept called include job and I'm going to take my getters
and I'm going to assume I'm going to have a new getter called include job by skill.
And remember, the way this works, just as we have here, is we first invoke that generate and we provide
the state.
So in this case, our state is represented by state.
And that guitar is going to return a new function.
And it has that function that accepts the actual argument that we want to pass.
So in this case, the argument we want to pass is our job, and that is going to be in the function
that is returned by the getter.
So I'm going to get that value, that function.
I'm going to invoke it immediately and pass in my job.
And what include job should give back to me should be a boolean.
So right here I expect that include job should be equal to true.
Why?
True.
Because this job should be included.
Because the user's search term a view is found within the jobs title of view developer.
All right.
So with that, we can go ahead and add our implementation.
So the first thing we need is to define a constant for this getter name.
Let's open up our constants file.
And right here in our Skills and Qualifications section, I can export a new concept which I will call
include job by skill.
And right here, I'm going to provide a string with the exact same content.
There we go.
There's our constant.
Let me go ahead and import that up here.
So right here, I'm going to add include job by skill.
And down below here.
Right.
With all my other include functions I'm going to provide include job by skill.
And I'm going to make that an arrow function in line.
So remember, the first argument is going to be our state parameter, and that's going to be a type
global state that is the current view store state.
And then I'm going to have this method, this getter method return a function that accepts a single
job of type job as a parameter.
And here is where we actually do the logic that we want to do.
So how are we going to write this logic?
Well, of course, we need to reference the skills search term.
So I know on my state I'm going to have access to skills search term, and I want to search for that
string within my job title.
So what I'm going to do here is my job object has a title property that is a string and on a string
in JavaScript or in tightlipped as well.
We have an includes method and the includes method returns a boolean based on whether it's argument
or its input is found within that string.
So what we're going to do here is invoke includes passing in the skills search term.
So if this string includes this value, we're going to return a appropriate boolean, either true or
false.
And that's the exact boolean that I want to return out of this method.
So I'm just going to return this evaluation right here.
This will be a boolean, true or false?
If the job title does include the skill search term, it will return.
True, which is exactly what I want and exactly what I'm testing right here, because view should be
included in view development.
All right.
So with that, we do see that we have a passing test and that is a good place to start.
But in the very next lesson, we're going to see how it can improve this test a little bit to capture
a couple edge cases.
All right.
So I will see you in the next lesson.