All right.
So the next thing we're going to be doing is arranging the elements of our hero within this big yellow
box.
So if I transition to the official Google Careers website, we can see here how all of this content
is primarily centered in the middle of the screen.
We have, of course, our headline with the changing text, but we also have this prompt and this form
and this image and then all kind of centered.
And we're going to be using a different type of technique in order to arrange these elements.
We're going to be using access grid.
And the reason we're doing this is because that's actually the way that Google built out this page.
So if you're new to Caesar's grid, much like I was when I discovered this feature, there's two helpful
resources that I'd like to introduce you to in this lesson that you can utilize.
If you'd like to take a little bit of a breather from the project and just brush up on your thesis.
So the first one is this website.
CC Trip.com.
If you simply search CC Grid in Google, it should be one of the first results that pops up.
It'll give you a quick introduction to what CC Great is effectively.
CC Great is a two dimensional grid based layout system.
So if you think of a grid almost like a table, right?
A table that consists of rows and columns, that's essentially what a grid is.
And that's how this new CC format allows us to arrange elements, almost like we're putting elements
within a grid.
You'll see more examples as I scroll down, but that is the basic introduction to the system and it
says below here something that I think all of us who have worked with the SS have known before.
CC has always been used to land our web pages, but it's never done a very good job of it.
First we use tables, then floats positioning in inline block, but all of those methods were essentially
hacks and left out a lot of important functionality, such as vertical centering.
Flexbox, which came out before Grid, is a very great layout tool, but it has a one directional flow
which has different use cases.
So grid is kind of the next evolution or a new tool that's available in all modern browsers that is
going to allow you to build a grid based layout.
If I scroll down here just to give you a few examples, you can see kind of a artist's drawing of how
we might define a box on the page and then later on how we might distribute elements within its.
If I scroll down a little bit more here, you can see here we can have a grid, right, just rows and
columns and they don't have to be necessarily equal width or equal height.
We can designate all of that and then specify our inner elements or our inner containers and specify
how they should fit in within that grid.
Here you can see, for example, that we can specify the width of every column.
We can make a column automatically size itself based on the total size we've put for the container.
All of those details you can learn on this page.
But again, you don't need to be a grid expert because this is not a size class, but just know that
in the very next lesson, we're going to be using a bunch of tailwind classes that apply these grid
styles behind the scenes.
Right.
And what I basically did, as always, is, is I went to the Google Careers website.
I looked at their styles and I found a way to emulate those in a tailwind CSR and its utility classes.
So I am by no means a grid expert, but I got a working version that looked good enough for me and that's
basically what I did.
And hopefully that's going to be good enough for us because of course our focus is Vue rather than CSR.
If you also want a really great website to practice the basics of grid, what I recommend is CC Grid
Garden dot com.
This website is really cool because you get to actually play a game where you align this little stream
of water in this grid with the growing plants and you can follow the instructions here and type out
the correct yes in the prompt below and allows you to have this kind of visual game to play with.
There's actually 28 different levels here and I recommend this site.
I went through this tutorial when I was learning the basics of grid.
I saw the earliest cover in this lesson and the very next lesson we're going to start applying.
A bunch of grid styles are using tailwind to our existing component.