All right.
So in the previous lesson, we learned how to use Axios to make a request to an endpoint, specifically
our jobs end point.
So in this lesson, we can wire up the same Axios logic, but within an actual view component.
Before we jump into VS code though, I do want to double check that you have two things running and
they're both required in order for this lesson to work.
Number one, you need your JSON server running and you can start it up with the NPM run back end command
and then in a separate tab, you're also going to need to run your view server and you can run that
with the command, NPM, run, serve.
Both of these are independent processes and they both must be running.
We need to run the View app to see it in our browser and we need to run our fake backend so that our
view app can make the request and successfully get data back.
So if at any point anything breaks, it's likely because one of these processes is broken and your code
for one of them is messed up.
This does double check that everything is correct and make sure moving forward for the job results page
in order to see anything for all of the upcoming lessons that deal with that page.
We do need that backend API running, so we always need that JSON server running.
If you're coming back to this course another day and restarting your learning, remember you have to
restart both of these services moving forward.
All right.
I'm going to mention in this lesson and maybe casually remind you afterwards, but just keep that in
mind.
We need these two dependencies now, always running.
Okay.
With that said, let us go back into vs code and the component I want to open is job listings, dot
view plural.
So as a reminder, this is the component that is kind of the parent component that renders when we get
to slash jobs, slash results.
Technically, it's the view component that renders this one, but pretty much the same idea.
And what this component does is it renders in ordered list.
And right now we have three job listing components being rendered.
Our ultimate intent here, of course, is to render a job listing component for every job that we get
from the back.
So if we get ten jobs from the server, then we render ten job listings.
If we get 55 jobs from the server, then we render 55 job listings.
And of course, ultimately, we want the data within the job listing the title, the location, the
qualifications, etc. to be provided by the data from the backend rather than hardcoded as it is right
now.
Now we'll come back to that problem later, but that is the ultimate intent of what we're trying to
do here.
So we want to import our access library that is fundamentally JavaScript code.
So it needs to live within our script section.
So right here I'm going to import my Axios library, import Axios from Axios.
Remember that web pack and view SQL?
I do transpire this file view component so we can use the modern import syntax of the import keyword.
And here we are importing the Axios object from the Axios library as a general best practice as well.
I like to put all of my NPM package imports above my local project related files.
So because this component belongs to me and Axios is a separate dependency that is part of the NPM ecosystem,
I try to structure those above my own files, which is job listing.
Okay, so now we have Axios imported and we're eventually going to make a request to fetch an array
of jobs.
Where do we want to store that array of jobs?
Well, we're going to need some kind of component data in order to store those jobs.
So I propose that we create a data property called jobs.
So right below components, I create my data method.
And as always, this method will return a JavaScript object and these object properties will be available
to use in my template.
And I want to create a property called Jobs and we need to provide it some kind of starter state.
How are we going to kick it off?
And because remember, when this component mounts, it's going to need to wait a second or two while
we get the jobs from our backend.
So jobs needs to be something in the meantime, as our template uses this property, otherwise everything
will break.
Well, the most logical thing to make here right now is an empty array.
So it's going to start off as an empty array.
And then when we get the actual array of job results from our API request, we're going to overwrite
this jobs data property with the new array.
So it makes sense to start with the exact same data type that you're eventually going to need, but
sort of the most simplified barebones version of it, right?
So if you're going to eventually get some kind of string, you start off with an empty string, right?
If you're eventually going to get some kind of array, you start out with an empty array, basically
an empty container or vessel for the eventual data type that you expect to receive, which for us will
be an array of jobs.
All right.
Now the question becomes, where are we going to make the API request to get this backend data?
Well, you may recall that every Vue component has lifecycle hooks and that represents a moment in time
in the components existence.
So the recommended lifecycle hook in.
Which we want to make API requests is the mounted hook.
So you may recall the way we intercept a lifecycle hook in order to execute extra code during that process
is by simply writing that lifecycle method name in line.
So in this case, our lifecycle hook is called mounted.
It is a method.
So I'm going to provide my parentheses and then the method body and anything we do here.
Vue will run after the component has initially been mounted in the browser, so added to the page in
the DOM.
And that will work just fine because when we initially mount the component onto our browser, it will
kind of instantaneously, relatively appear for the user and the jobs array will be equal to an empty
right.
So if we are rendering a job listing for every item in the array, we're just not going to see any job
listings for a brief second while we wait for that API request to complete.
But the component will still be loaded.
So it's not going to break anything.
It's not going to be a weird user experience.
We're still going to mount the component, get it up and running, and then when we receive the jobs,
we're going to overwrite this array.
The view component will re render and then display the job listings afterwards.
So mounted after the component has been placed in the browser is a good place to to right this logic.
The reason it's not a good idea to put it before in a previous lifecycle hook is because the component
may not be alive yet in the browser.
So at that point, if we are dependent on waiting for that request to complete before the component
is even rendered in the browser, the user will simply not see anything and that typically proves to
be a worser user experience.
So right here, when the component is in the browser Dom, that's when we want to make the access request.
And whenever it gets done, that's when we'll update the UI to show the user those jobs.
So we're going to do the exact same syntax as in the previous lesson.
We're going to use the access object and invoke the get method.
That method expects a URL and I'm just going to write it in line as a string.
So HTP, colon, slash and remember we're running on localhost 3000, that is our port on our local
computer and we need to hit the jobs and point at slash jobs that is going to return a promise object
so I can tap on a then method call and then the then method expects an arrow function.
And of course that arrow function will receive the response object from Axios.
That is a complex wrapper object that has a whole bunch of information about the response.
And on that object, what I really want is the data property that's going to get me the actual response
from the server, which is the array of job objects.
Now what do I want to do with this data?
I of course want to overwrite this array.
So how can I access a data property?
I can use the this keyword.
So right here I'm going to access this dot jobs and I'm going to overwrite it with the data property.
So as soon as this request completes, it can take a second, it can take half a second, then JavaScript
is going to run this function, then it's going to override the jobs data property that will in turn
force a component re render.
All right, so let's double check in our browser that everything is working as expected.
So as I navigate back to my browser and I go to my jobs page, we're not going to see any change yet
because we're still always rendering three job listing components.
We're not doing anything with our received data yet.
We eventually will, but there's still other ways that we can double check that everything is working
as expected.
For example, I can go to my network tab and I can transition to this fetch slash tab that will show
me any asynchronous Ajax or in other words, requests made by Axios that we can see when the page loads.
So as I refresh this page, we should see that request go out and there it is.
You can see the jobs request right here.
You can see it was a 200, which is a status code that means success or okay.
So when I click on this, you can see in the preview tab that we can see the actual response that that
API endpoint gave to us.
So this is the exact same thing that we have in our DB JSON file.
This is our array of 100 job objects.
Cool.
So that looks good.
We know that our browser is successfully making a request to that endpoint and furthermore, we know
that this array of jobs should now live in our view component data.
So if I go to my view developer tools and I go to my job results view and I go to my job listings component,
remember it has a jobs property and here it is, here it is storing that array of 100 objects.
Of course, each object represents a sample job and here we have a sample job and all that information.
So we can see that we have successfully saved all of that, all of that response data into our jobs
property.
And it's correct, we have the array as correctly stored rather than the response object.
So we have correctly extracted that information and that's a good step.
Obviously, the next thing we want to do is to render a custom job listing for every one of these objects,
and that's what we're going to do in the upcoming lessons.
So I will see you there.