Okay.
So we spent a lot of time wiring up our spotlight component.
Let's now render it within a parent component and provide some custom slot content.
So I'm going to render my spotlight component in my hero component, which I have open on the left hand
side.
And there are going to be a lot of tailwind classes involved.
And in order to just make this and move a little bit quicker, I'm not going to talk about each individual
one.
I'm just going to add them in sequence, because the goal here, of course, is to learn about the slots
feature, not so much about talent.
So I'm going to begin by adding a few classes here to my main element.
So I'm going to add Flex, Flex Call and H screen and I'm also going to remove edge screen right here.
And obviously the next step is to import our spotlight component and render it somewhere within our
hero template.
So below in the script section, I'm going to import spotlight that is going to come from the source
directory components, job search and spotlight.
And then I'm going to register it within my components object right here.
So spotlight that enables us to use Spotlight anywhere in the body of my hero template.
And let's go ahead and do that.
So below our section right here in our main element right after this closing section tag is where I'm
going to render my spotlight.
I'm going to make it an opening and closing tag.
And we know now that here is where we're going to render our slot content that's going to go right here
on the right hand side.
Whenever we do this v four right here.
So whatever we provide in between the opening and closing tags is going to be repeated right here for
every spotlight that we are iterating over.
All right.
Before we get there, though, I do want to add some top level classes to my spotlight.
And as we know, this will simply cascade down and applied to my element right here.
And those classes will be flex flex row.
Justify centre and PB 16.
All right.
So as we talked about in the previous lesson, we're going to pass a piece of information up to my parent
component in this case, hero.
And it's going to be called Spotlight.
How do I get access to this piece of information from my parent?
So what we have to use is that vice slot directive that we introduced in the previous section.
Right now we only have one slot component, so we could technically just provide HTML here and it would
work.
But if we want data like this piece of data that we passed up via slot props, we have to use the V
slot syntax.
So I'm going to create a template.
And as we know, we can use the V slot directive on it.
And as a reminder, the way this works is we provide a colon and the name of the slot.
And in this case, I'm going to provide the name of default, which is the name that view is going to
give the slot on the right hand side because we did not give it a name.
And the reason we need the syntax is because at the very end, we're going to introduce something new.
We're going to put an equal sign and then a pair of double quotes.
And in this pair of double quotes, we're going to define the name that we want to assign to the object
of slot props.
That view is going to make available for us to use within this template.
So let me write out the code and then we're going to talk about what I did.
I'm going to call this object slot.
Props.
The name of this object is entirely up to you.
But what this object represents, if I can just do a little bit of a common right here, is this is
an object with all of the props that we provided right here in my child.
So right now, this object will have a spotlight property set to the object that we have from our backend.
And similarly right here, if I created an additional prop here like a equals two and then B equals
three, what that would do is that would make it available right here, as in a property set to two
and a, B property set to three.
So whatever we define as slot props right here in line are bundled up in a JavaScript object.
And what we do here is we give that JavaScript object a name in this case slot props, and we need to
give it a name because we're going to reference that object in the HTML that we're about to write so
that we can take these properties and use them and use their data in the template in the custom HTML
that we provide in our parent component to inject into this slot right here.
We have passed this data up and it's going to be made available on this object that we provide after
an equal sign and the name of this slot and the name of the actual slot.
Okay.
So I'm going to remove A and B because we don't care about them.
And so basically what we're left with is an object with a single spotlight property and now we can utilize
it throughout our template.
So let me start with a couple elements, components, and then we're going to talk about the specific
use of slot props when we get to it.
So I'm going to begin with a root or link because I want to make this entire thing a clickable link
and router link is the view router component that allows us to do that.
And immediately, I'm going to provide that to prop to this.
And I'm going to navigate to the user to slash jobs, slash results whenever they click on anything
inside my router link.
And then I'm going to provide some classes here as well.
So let's do Flex, Flex Call Annex five border.
Let me save this.
And then after that, we're going to do Rounded Dash LG, we're going to do W Dash 72, then big brand
gray to then H 96.
When you save that, hopefully that pushes it onto a new line.
And it does.
And there we go.
Okay.
The first thing I want to do in this router link is render an image.
So what we're trying to do here is we're trying to render the first variant of the card that we saw
on the Google Careers website.
So this is going to be the version where we have the image on the very top and then the title below
it, the description, and finally the link to the jobs page.
So I want to render an image here and immediately I'm going to give it a class here of object contain.
And in order to provide the source attribute of the image or in other words, the URL where this image
is going to come from, we need to get this piece of information from our spotlight object.
Right.
As a reminder in our DB, that JSON file that we're fetching from in spotlight here is the image property
on a spotlight object that gives us the URL of the image we want to fetch.
So this spotlight object is what we're passing up to hero right here.
And it's available via the slot props object.
So right here, I'm going to get my slot props object right on that object.
I have multiple props because I can define multiple props right here.
So I want to specifically get my spotlight object.
And on that spotlight object, we're going to have my IMG property to get that URL.
Now, as always, this syntax will not work because view will think it's a string.
So we have to v bind to dynamically bind to our source attribute and provide a reference to this property
on this on this object, on this object which we defined right here and now we can reference that value
that string from our DB, that JSON that we have fetched in spotlight and patch passed up to our hero
parent.
Right.
And the beautiful part about this design is if another component wants to reuse the spotlight component
and do something totally different in the template, it totally can.
But now it has access to the data that the child wants to pass up to it so it can render it right here
in line.
All right.
So as another example, let's render our title what's under the actual title of the spotlight?
So right here below my image, I'm going to create a div and I'm going to provide it with a couple classes
right here.
Let's do h 48.
Let's do 6p4 and empty three.
And here I want to render an H3 and that H3 will have a couple of classes as well.
Let's do text LG and font medium.
So here in this age three element is where I want to render this spotlight title.
Where where am I getting that from?
I'm getting that from the spotlight object that my spotlight child is passing up to me that is available
to me via the slot props object.
So how do we interpolate or render some kind of text content to the screen?
We use the view syntax of the double curly braces and then we simply have to reference the property
we want.
So we have our slot props object, which we define on line 24.
That is the complete collection of props on that object.
I have a spotlight property as defined right here, which is the reference to the Spotlight object that
we are currently iterating over in our V4.
And on that object I have a title property and that's the string that I actually want to render within
my H3.
Same idea below.
I'm going to render a paragraph tagged because I want to render a paragraph for the description of my
spotlight.
So this is going to have a class of empty three and text.
So how do I get that description property off of my spotlight object?
Same exact syntax.
I'm going to interpolate that text on the screen.
I want to talk to my slot props object.
I gave it the name slot props up here.
So I have to use that name right here.
This name is up to me on that collection of props given to me from the child.
I have a spotlight property representing my spotlight object.
That object has a description property.
And there we go.
All right.
Now we're going to be able to render that piece of information finally after this dive right here,
I'm just going to create another router link.
And this is also going to go to my.
Slash Jobs slash results page.
It's going to have the text of C jobs and then it's also going to have a bunch of tailwind classes on
it as well.
P.
X six.
B for text.
Dash Esim.
Text dash brand blue one.
Save that.
And there we have it.
We have our first variation of a card.
It is providing custom HTML for the slot from the parent hero component.
So this thing right here, this entire template is what we're going to inject into every slot right
here for every iteration.
Right?
So if we're iterating over an array of two spotlights in spotlight, we're going to inject us twice.
And for each iteration, we're going to provide our spotlight object.
We're going to pass it up to the parent via a spotlight property on our object called slot props right
here.
We can access that right here and use that object's distinct title and description and image properties
to render what we want right here.
The only reason that we're seeing a little bit of an aesthetic violation here is once again, yes,
lint wants us to use the shorthand, which we totally can.
We can use the hashtag here instead of slot.
Same syntax, the hashtag followed by the name of the slot and equal sign.
And then the name we want to assign to the object that's going to store all of these props right here
that we assigned it to the slot in the child component.
All right.
So with that, we can save this and head to our browser and we should get what we expect.
So right here, I'm going to navigate to Chrome.
Give me just a moment.
Technical issues on my end.
Heading back to job search.
And there we go.
Here are our two cards.
And notice we have the image on top that is dynamically coming from the IMG property.
Here is our dynamic title.
Here is our dynamic paragraph.
Here is our routing link.
These attributes, these properties are coming from this spotlight prop that we passed up from our child.
From our spotlight component.
Up to the hero component.
We found a way to get data from our child up to the parent component that is providing that custom dynamic
slot content.
And that way we can customize that slot content to have some piece of text or information that we need,
such as a custom value for an H2 or a custom value for a paragraph.
Right?
So the parent still exerts some degree of control over how things look, but now it can mix how things
look with some content that the child will pass up to it.
All right.
And that is the beauty of slot slot props as well as what we call scoped slots in view.
So I'm going to show you how this design allows us to very easily customize the look and feel of these
cards in the very next lesson.