Okay.
So before we explore Vue router in our browser, there's one more file that I'd like to clean up and
that is app that view.
So I'm going to open it up here in this code.
And as a reminder, app dot view is the complete starting point of our app.
So just to remind you, if I open up Main.
Yes, in here we import our app component as our most top level component and that's where we kick things
off on the view app side of things.
So when Vue mounts itself to the div with an ideas app in our HTML, it fundamentally mounts or launches
the app component.
So how does that play a role in regards to view router?
Well, remember, that view is a single page app, so the page never reloads when it load to the first
time.
The user doesn't actually really navigate to a new route.
They just have the illusion of doing that and view takes care of this swapping of the components when
the user navigates to a new route.
And there's a special component that we have to use somewhere in our app that is going to enable us
to have that swap ability to have that dynamic aspect, a view, swapping our components in a given
location on the page whenever we change to a different URL.
So we're going to get there just a minute for now.
Let's clean up a bunch of extra stuff in this file that they've usually added for us.
So first up it out of this whole style section, we do not need this at all so we can remove this entirely.
And then as always, let's add our script tag and let's export default a plain JavaScript object and
we'll provide a single name property set to app.
All right.
And then here, let's delete all of this code for now and let's put a single component in here and that
component is going to be router view.
So let me write it out and then we'll talk about it.
It's going to be a self-closing component.
So router dash view.
So I'm going to close that off right here.
You might be curious, where is this component coming from?
This is a global component.
As a reminder, global components are available to be used in any of our view components.
We do not need to import it.
We do not need to register it as a local component.
It is available to be used globally, which means any, any file, any component.
So where are we getting this component from?
Actually, whenever we use this code right here, this use method and pass in the router object, the
view router library gives us some components out of the box and an example one is router view and it
registers them globally the exact same way that we manually registered the font awesome icon component
earlier in the course.
The view router does that for us automatically and the reason it does that for us automatically is because
the router view component as an example is a component that we can expect to use in any component throughout
the app, along with some other complementary components like Router Link, which we'll talk about in
a few lessons.
So what does Router View do?
Fundamentally, what router view does is it doesn't actually render anything visually on the screen,
but this is the component that is responsible for watching the URL and then swapping the dynamic content
on the screen based on what is in the roots file.
So this is the component that is tracking.
This file.
It's the component that's watching the URL and saying, okay, is the URL slash?
Is that the root?
Root?
Okay.
Then I'm going to render the home view right here.
Alternatively, this component says, okay, if the root is jobs slash results, what do I render?
I'm going to render the job results view right here.
So this component specifies the part of the page where we actually want to render that dynamic piece
of content that is based on the root.
Okay.
So let's first see this in the browser.
So if I navigate to the browser, here I am on my slash root.
Right.
And so if I look in my view devtools.
We'll see, in my view, dev tools.
Let's see if I can refresh.
This might be a little bit slow here.
Something might be a little bit funky.
Where are my components?
Where do they go off to?
We have our roots.
Where are actual components here?
Me.
See if I can select this thing right here.
There we go.
Took a little bit of a troubleshooting.
So here we have a top level router view component.
This is the one that we just rendered.
And this is the one that keeps track of the route.
So it notices that it is a slash route.
And so it knows to render which component the one we told it to render in the routes file, which is
home view.
Right.
So you might guess what is going to happen when we navigate to jobs slash results.
This is the alternate route.
So when we navigate here, we're still going to have a router view component because that is the one
that is keeping track of those changes, except it knows in the routes file that we said when the earlier
slash job slash results, it should render a totally different view, which is the job results view.
And so we see the different H1 from that different view component file.
All right.
Now, let me show you where the dynamism lies.
Let me, for example, go here and I'm going to add an H one above right of you.
And I'm just going to say, let's say above router view and then below I'll add, let's say an H2 and
I'll just say below router view and the estimate elements themselves are irrelevant.
All that is important here is that I'm putting a different output above the router view component and
a different output below the router view component.
So let me go into my browser now and you'll notice here that we have that content appear above router
view and below router view as expected.
And in the middle is where it injects that dynamic view, where it injects that dynamic component.
So you'll notice if I navigate to my home view at my root route, we're still going to keep the constant
H1 and H2 here because we hardcoded that in our apt view file it will always render.
But what the router view component does is it swaps the dynamic element.
So the advantage of this is that we can put this wherever in the page we actually want that dynamic
content to render.
And what and what syntax like this allows us to do is it allows each page to have a common aspect to
it that is shared.
So a perfect use case for something like this is our main nav.
If you think about our main nav, it does not vary from view to view.
Every single view in our app is going to have the same primary main nav, the same navigation menu at
the top.
So what we can do, for example, is in app, we can always render a may nav component that will exist
in every single route because it's not dynamic, it is part of the core app component.
And then we can use the router view component to specify to render the dynamic view immediately below
the main NAV.
So view will watch the URL and swap the proper view component in but only below the constant static
main nav which is unchanging.
All right, that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
Let's head back here and remove this H1 and H2.
That's just to demonstrate the way that router view works.
It's a component.
It doesn't render anything visually on the screen, but it's responsibilities to keep track of the path,
match it with a given route, and then render the correct component that we've specified in our collection
of routes.
That's all that the router view component does, and that allows us to inject dynamism wherever we want
into the app.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
In the very next one, we're going to take a look at another global component that Vue router gives
us, and that is router link.