All right.
So in this lesson, I want to introduce you to another data type called unknown.
And I also want to introduce you to a technique in TypeScript called type guarding.
So I have some code from the previous lesson.
I have my chameleon variable, which I have given an explicit any type which allows me to assign it
a value like five.
So unfortunately with this approach, TypeScript basically ignores whatever value we have and thus knowing
that it cannot confirm that it is a number as opposed to something like a string, it's going to allow
basically any behavior that we want on it.
So for example, on a string in JavaScript we have a method called two uppercase.
On a number we do not.
So take a look at what happens when I try to take my chameleon variable and try to invoke two uppercase
on it.
We're actually not going to get an error.
Right?
And this is sort of reinstating the point that we mentioned.
The previous lesson is when we use any, we defeat the entire purpose of TypeScript because TypeScript,
which should know, hey, if you have a number, that number doesn't have a two uppercase method.
That's something that belongs to a string.
But because we used any, we basically overrode TypeScript and said treat it like regular JavaScript,
treat it like a variable.
It can be anything at all.
So TypeScript cannot validate that our chameleon variable has or does not have a to uppercase method.
And obviously when we run this code, we're going to get the error in our window right here.
This is the exact and we expect chameleon to uppercase is not a function.
This is a common failure in JavaScript and this is what we're trying to avoid by using TypeScript,
right?
But because we used any TypeScript was not able to solve that problem for us.
So let me introduce you to another type of type that we can use instead of any here.
I'm going to use the word unknown.
An unknown is itself a type.
And just like that word means in the English language, unknown sort of means we don't know.
Right?
And unknown is actually a little less flexible than any.
And that's a good thing because any is too permissive, it's allows too many bad things to happen.
Unknown is going to say, Hey, you're telling me, TypeScript, that you don't know everything about
this type.
However, I'm going to force you to be a little bit stricter in double checking things before you execute
them.
I'm going to force you to prove to me that an operation is allowed before I let you do it.
So notice here we're now getting an error when we try to invoke to uppercase and you can see the description
here is object is of type unknown.
So a typescript is basically trying to tell us, I don't know whether Chameleon is allowed to have two
uppercase or not.
It may or it may not, but prove to me first that it can before I allow you to perform this operation.
Keep in mind the similarity that Unknown has with something like any is that we can totally reassign
to any other values.
For example, here I can totally assign chameleon to true, and on the next line I can assign chameleon
to something like an array of one to all of that remains valid, so unknown shares that with the any
type.
However, here's where things get different.
It's when we try to invoke something like any kind of method, that's when TypeScript will complain.
Okay, so how do we fix this issue?
How do we communicate a typescript that we do indeed have something like a string in the program?
And only if we have a string then do we want to invoke to uppercase, because only then we will know
with certainty that we have a string.
Let me show you how this is going to work.
You may be familiar that in JavaScript and also in TypeScript you have a special operator called Type
of.
When I use the word operator, what I mean is it can be written basically like any mathematical symbol,
like plus or minus.
It's not a function or a method that you invoke with parentheses is simply write it out.
So we have an operator called Type.
It's literally written like this.
And if you provided the name of any value in your program, such as our chameleon variable, it will
tell you the type of that value.
So when I run this file and I'm using console.log here to print out the value, you'll see this is our
old failure.
So ignore this.
You'll see that it's telling us that the type of chameleon is a number.
So basically it's telling us the type that that value currently has.
So what we can do is wrap this kind of logic in something like an if statement and let me write it out
and I'll explain what we're doing here.
So I'm going to put an if statement here and I'm seeing if the type of chameleon at that given moment
of execution in our program is equal to string.
So remember that type of operator will give me a a string that describes the type that I have and I'm
going to check if that's strings literal.
Actual content is the string string.
I know it's a little bit confusing and kind of multilayer, but here, for example, we got the type
of as a string of number.
Because of the type of number, if the type of the chameleon variable is literally a string which are
validating by comparing to the string string, then inside these curly braces, I know that chameleon
is a string and thus I'm going to be allowed to invoke two uppercase on it.
Right.
And notice when we do this, then TypeScript no longer complains even though we used unknown.
So what we have here is called a type guard, right?
And the reason why it's called a type card, the name may be intuitive and may not, but the idea is
that it's guarding against certain operations.
It's protecting us from doing something unless we validate that we have the correct type for it.
So TypeScript says, I don't know right here on line two if you have a string, but on line number three,
if this evaluates to true and you tell me in this validation that this is indeed a string, I know that
if we reach line number four, I guarantee that I have a string because you've proven it to me in this
conditional and thus I feel confident allowing you to execute to uppercase that method on it.
Right.
So what we have right here is an example of a type guard.
It's a technique where we basically check the type of something in our program.
And only once you validate that we have something that we can do an operation with, only then do we
perform the actual operation in the actual conditional in the curly braces belonging to that if statement.
Right.
And this is one advantage that unknown offered us over any and that's why many people recommend using
unknown in place of any everywhere is that it forces you into writing a little bit more of these stricter
checks.
Now, granted, of course, the best approach is to give the explicit type like in this example, obviously
we know it's a number, so numbers better than unknown.
But once again, as we mentioned in the previous lesson, if you're running through a program and you
just want to get it to work, but you also want to write in a little bit of stability.
Stability unknown is a better choice than any because it will force you to write type guards that will
enable protections like this.
So once again, when I run this, we're not going to get any actual output and we're not going to get
any actual output because the type of chameleon on line three is going to execute to be the string of
number.
Number is not equal to the string of string.
So our if statement will evaluate to false.
This logic will never run in comparison.
If I change chameleon to something else like Bobby, right?
In that case, our logic will run.
Rex, you're not going to see it because we're not console.log lists.
So let's console.log this.
But now we're going to see because our type guard on line number three will permit the action.
We're still going to watch for it, but now our conditional is going to evaluate to true.
So we're going to run this logic right here and we know it's a string.
So we know that we are allowed to to invoke the two uppercase method on a string.
And we are going to see the output of Bobby right here.
All right.
So two things we learned in this lesson, the type of unknown we declared the same way we do with any
other type, a colon followed by its name.
It's very similar to any in the sense that it permits any value.
We can make chameleon a string.
We can make chameleon a, a boolean, a number, an array and object afterwards and change its value
throughout the program.
Not saying that that's a good thing in terms of design, but saying that it is possible.
But one advantage of using unknown over any is that it forces you to use type guards.
What does it type guard?
It's basically a check to validate that we have the right type.
We guard right we protect to make sure we have the right type of type before we execute any kind of
behavior on that value and in the in the actual body or the block belonging to the if statement.
So this is an example of a type guard.
It's not some kind of fancy, you know, syntax or anything like that.
It's just an idea in TypeScript to guard against the type that you're working with to make sure what
you're doing is valid and allowed.
Another way to decrease the chance that you have the kind of error we saw in the beginning of this lesson.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.