In this lesson, I'd like to show you one more way that we can change the data of our view component
in a test.
We saw the first way to do this in the previous lesson.
We can provide a second argument to the Mount function with our own data method that can return whatever
property values we want.
Well, an alternative approach is to set the data of our component after it has already been mounted.
So after I mount my component, what I can do is call a method on my wrapper object called set data.
Pretty appropriate name for what we're trying to do here.
So I'm going to invoke set data and I'm going to feed in a plain object.
And this effectively represents the new data object.
So for example, I can use any properties here that exist in my regular main nav component.
So I may want to change, for example, the value of the company property to Super Corp.
And my expectation of course is since I am rendering or interpolating the value of company in my HTML,
it's reasonable to expect that the text within my component will feature the text super core.
So I think this is a pretty reasonable way to think about running a test like this, but we're going
to see it's not going to work out quite like we expect.
So let's see what happens when I actually run this test.
So I'm going to run NPM, run test, colon unit and we're going to see that we're going to raise an
actual error or a failure.
So if I scroll up here, you can see that we expected to receive Super Corp, but we're actually receiving
the string bubble careers.
Bubble careers, as a reminder, is the original value of the company property in my main nav component
in the actual implementation.
So it's almost like this code right here didn't work.
So what's going on here?
So this is our first introduction to asynchronous tests and asynchronous operations.
The set data method is an example of an async method.
That means it takes some amount of time to run.
It's not instantaneous.
The wrapper needs to go inside the view component, change a certain property, perhaps re render the
internals of that component in order to reflect those changes.
And that operation takes some amount of time.
So what actually happens here is when we call set data, the test doesn't wait for that to complete
before it continues running.
The operation does not block the next line of code from executing.
So as this method is still running and executing the logic, or rather you can think of it as we've
issued the method or the or the call to our wrapper to change and it's doing something behind the scenes.
But before it's done, finishing all of that operation, we're already running the next line and before
the wrappers finished changing the values in the component.
The values are still bubble careers as far as the company property and the value that we are rendering
enraged him out.
So in other words, this operation is not done running in time, so we still have the old value within
my wrapper text.
So what we need to do is tell our tests to wait until this entire operation completes before we evaluate
the next line.
Because only when this is done will the actual value inside our template be Super Corp and thus the
component and the wrappers text will then change to reflect that.
So what I need to do is make this an async function.
So I'm going to make the test async right here.
It's going to be async before the function that we feed in as the second argument to it.
And then we use the await keyword in front of the asynchronous operation.
So in this case it is awaiting wrapper.
That said data.
What we're basically saying is wait until this completes before you move on to the next line.
All right.
So when I execute this test now, we should see the result that we expect.
Perfect.
So that takes care of that issue.
And that is our first introduction to async await.
With that said, just like in the previous lesson, I'm going to attack the fundamentals of this test
a little bit and tell you about why I'm not a fan of this approach.
The reason why I don't like this is because we are artificially triggering a change in the component
in this case in the data of the component.
Right.
So why is this a problem?
It's because we're not using the component in the way that the user of our site would actually use it.
Right.
This is an artificial interaction.
This is an internal detail.
This is a method that we know about, a wrapper that we can change in our tests that are views that
our user has no clue about.
This is functionality that doesn't actually exist in our main NAV component.
Yet we have offered the user no way to change the internal data of May now.
We're starting out with a company property and for now it is always equal to bubble careers.
So that is what the user sees.
So we are interacting with the component in a way that is not reflective of the real world.
And of course, the closer that our tests come to the real world, the closer that they come to how
the users actually interact with our components, the better, because that ensures that we're actually
testing something that is real, that is tangible, that is how the user actually interacts with this
component.
So while we do have options like the set data method and the second argument to mount, I dislike them
both for the same reason.
They are artificial changes to our component and we want to be able to trigger those changes just like
the user would.
Right.
It's the difference between clicking a button, which is something the user might do versus calling
some kind of arbitrary method on an object which only we as developers can do.
Right.
So for that example, again, I think that this test is a little overkill.
And typically, similarly, you want to write this with TDD because you would never expect or know in
advance what the implementation of your component would be.
And thus you wouldn't know that you would incorporate the company as part of the data method.
It might be again, just simply hardcoded into the into the HTML.
So you would never invoke a method like this accidentally in a TDD test because you would have no clue
where the actual information would live.
So once again, this this entire lesson was purely for the sake of example and to talk more about testing
philosophies.
So what I'm going to do is remove this previous code that we wrote, and I'm also going to remove the
async keyword because we no longer need it.
And I'm going to bring this back to Bobo careers, right?
Because that is what is the purpose of the test.
It is to display the company name.
And the beautiful part about a simple test like this is we don't care how the component does it, we
just care about the value to the user.
At the user is able to observe our company name somewhere in that component.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you the next one.