Okay.
So the next thing that I want to implement in our setup method is this carrot icon name right here.
As a reminder, carrot icon in the previous implementation which used the options API.
Carrot icon was a computed property and what it does is it tracks the value of the former is open data
property right here.
And based on when whether this is true or false, it returns a different array and that array actually
becomes an argument to the font.
Awesome icons I can pop.
The idea being that we want to display a different icon depending on what state the accordion is in.
So when the accordion is closed or collapsed, we want to show that little carrot symbol, the little
angle pointing down.
And in comparison, when the accordion is expanded or open, we want to show a different carrot icon
pointing up.
So as soon as is open changes, we want this array to change so that we give font awesome icon the updated
icon that it should show.
So this is a perfect example of a computed property because it is dependent on other data.
It is not original data, it's simply something that needs to rerun whenever is open changes.
So my question to you is how can we implement a very similar functionality using the composition API?
So you might be tempted to do something like this.
You might be tempted to say, well, we can make a ref, right?
And we can start referencing an array with the exact same arguments and whenever we change is open right
here we can simply reference this ref.
Let's say this is something like carrot icon and here we can do carrot icon that value and we can find
a way to invert the array.
It has to be the new one.
So this is not really capturing the original reactivity spirit of a computed property because now we
have to manually wire up the logic that whenever is open changes, we also have to update carrot icon.
It'd be a lot easier and better if we can just get view to do the work for us.
If we can tell you whenever is open changes automatically behind the scenes know that you should rerun
and the logic for calculating a carrot icon.
That's the exact same design for a computed property in the options API.
It's not a second piece of data that we have to manually keep track of.
We could have done that here, by the way as well.
We could have we could have had a separate piece of data called carrot icon.
But the reason we used a computed property instead is because it saves us the responsibility of having
to update to things whenever is open.
Changes we only have to update is open and have confidence that Vue will take care of this computation
for us because it's keeping track of this change and automatically rerunning this logic well, to capture
the exact same spirit using the composition API, we're going to use a function that we introduced in
the previous section of the course called Computed.
So let's go ahead and import it right here.
So you may recall from the previous section of the course that the way computed works is it accepts
a function.
And in that function, we can reference any reactive object that we have in our in our program.
So we have two currently reactive objects.
We have header and and is open.
So if we reference any one of them in this function, when that reactive object changes, the function
that we passed computed is going to re run.
All right, so here's what we're going to do.
We're going to write the syntax out and then I'll show you exactly what we're going to do.
What we're going to do is basically copy the ternary logic we have right here.
So I'm going to say provide an arrow function, provide a function as an argument to computed.
This will rerun.
What do we want to track?
We want to track is open now by itself.
Remember, that is the reactive object.
We have to more specifically track its value, which is going to be a boolean, either true or false.
So when this is true, what I want to do is return an array.
It's going to be the exact same array I have here, so let me copy it.
Up here and then if is.
Opens value is currently false.
If the value on that react object is false, I'm going to return this array instead.
So what we've basically done in the body of this computer function is we have implemented the exact
same logic that we previously had in the computed property in the options API.
Watch whatever is open is.
And because we provided a reactive object here, whenever this changes, view is going to rerun this
function.
We don't have to tell it to rerun.
It knows to rerun whenever is open changes.
So what is the computed function going to give back to us as a return value?
You may recall from the previous section that it's going to be its own reactive object.
Well, that is exactly the object that we want to assign to our carrot icon name.
So right here I'm going to do const karat icon.
All right.
Now, in order to be able to use this in my template, in order to have it accessed right here in line
nine, I need to make sure that I provide it in my return object from my setup method.
All right.
So hopefully this part makes sense because this is repeating the same ideas we've gone through the last
couple lessons and providing care icon, which makes it available here.
The more complicated idea here is what is carrot icon?
Carrot icon is another reactive object.
However, it is a reactive object that doesn't start out with an initial value that we provide it like
cool title or false.
Rather, it is a reactive object that starts with a value that is dynamically computed based on the
value of another reactive object.
That reactive object being is open.
So we're basically doing here is forcing the reactive nature of a computed property, but using a functional
approach, we're telling view track is open because we gave is open here and if it flips rerun this
function.
So when is open flips to true we're going to run the function here and we're going to get this array
if is open flips to false, we're going to rerun this function, we pass the computed and get back this
array and every single time we thus run the open method we're going to flip.
The value of it is open, which is going to force care icon to rerun each time we're going to get those
updates and they're going to automatically reflect in the template.
Once again, carrot icon in our former implementation was in array.
Now Care Icon is a reactive object that's storing a value of an array.
But remember behind the scenes view knows two paths past the value of the reactive object, not the
whole reactive object itself.
So the icon prop of the font awesome icon library expects an array.
Don't worry, it's still going to get an array.
Just because we're exporting a reactive object here with an array stored inside doesn't matter.
Vue understands that it wants to get the inherent value and provide it here in the same way that it
does for header.
It gets the piece of text inside the reactive object in the same way as it does for is open where it
gets the internal boolean stored inside that reactive object.
Same idea here.
This is still going to be an array even though we're returning a property representing a reactive object
in our JavaScript section.
So with that, if we transition back to our browser.
Lo and behold, there is our original carrot.
And take a look at what happens when I click the div.
We're going to run the open method where that's going to invert the value of the is open ref, the reactive
value, which in turn is going to get our computed function that we just wrote a minute ago to rerun,
which is going to generate the new array argument for this icon right here, which is going to flip
it to the new one.
So when I click this, there we go, it's pointing up, click it again.
It's pointing down.
Same rules apply for any of these other accordions.
So with that, we are very, very, very, very, very close to getting our original implementation
and of course replacing it entirely with our composition API instead of our original options API.
All right.
So we're getting super close.
Hopefully, this has been fun and we'll continue chipping away in the next lesson.