All right.
In this lesson, we will add some custom colors to our tailwind config.
As we know, the Tailwind Utility Library provides us with many small CC classes that we can use throughout
our HTML to provide immediate styles to our elements.
We saw earlier how Tailwind has classes for things like margin and padding and font size, etc. Well,
Tailwind also ships with several classes for setting the color of things, whether it be the font color
or the background color.
But of course there's millions of possible colors that we can use.
So the Tailwind Library starts with your basic default set of colors.
It kind of gives you a very small color palette to work with.
So for example, we have a available class in tailwind called Text Black.
And as you might have guessed, if you apply that CSS class to an element, it will make the text black.
The issue with our project is that we are looking for specific styles and specific colors that are inspired
by the actual Google career site.
So in a real world example, you might imagine that our designer at our company might give us the color
scheme and the colors that they provide are simply not going to be available by default in the classes
that tailwind provides for us.
However, the beautiful thing about Tailwind is that it is really customizable.
So in this lesson we're going to add those custom colors to our tailwind config file.
And what's super cool is tailwind will actually generate automatic CAC classes for us and we'll be able
to use them just like any other tailwind classes throughout our components.
So here's how it works.
Let's open up our tailwind dot config that JS file.
So here in this code, I'm going to use command P on a mac, but you can use control P on a Windows
computer to bring up the fuzzy file search.
And I want to search for tailwind dot config.
Yes, this is our tailwind configuration file.
Earlier on we saw how we could extend some of the options available in tailwind.
For example, we added the open sans font and merged it in with the available fonts in Tailwind.
Well, we want to do something very similar here.
We want to extend the colors that are available to use in tailwind.
So right here after this font family object, I'm going to create a new property called Colors and I'm
going to set colors equal to an object.
And the way it works here is the key or property is going to be some kind of name that we'd like to
assign to a color that we're going to be using in our project.
So for example, here I'll provide my key in double quotes.
Just because it has dashes, I'm going to create a named color called brand dash gray dash one.
We can imagine that the company is our brand and this is our brand's grey color.
And the reason I'm going to put one at the end is because in many projects you may have multiple variations
of a color, you may have multiple grays or multiple blues, etc. So this is our first brand gray color.
I'm just going to call it one.
All right.
And the value that I'm going to provide is going to be the hexadecimal code of the actual color that
I want to represent here.
So the one I want to do here is going to be hashtag daddy ce0.
And you can see it's this kind of light gray color.
This is an automatic feature in my editor that you may not have available, but it shows me the actual
color that this represents.
So what this means is Talman is going to look through all of its available possible cases, utility
classes, for example, we talked about text black earlier, applying a black text.
Well, now it's going to create a access class called text brand gray one automatically for us.
So whatever we put here, it's going to append to its built in styles.
So for example, text for text, I believe another option is BG for background.
So now we're going to have an available CSS class called BG Brand Gray one, the idea being that it
mimics the exact way the classes are named in tailwind.
However, it's actually our own custom names that we specify with our own custom classes and corresponding
colors.
We're going to see how this actually works when we apply it to a HTML element in an upcoming lesson.
But for now, I want to add two more colors that we're going to need throughout the project.
So I'm just going to add another key value pair to this object.
The next one is going to be brand blue one.
We're going to have a common blue color throughout the app.
And this is going to be hashtag 1967d2.
You can see it's that blue color.
Again, these styles are taken and inspired by the Google Careers website.
So I am not a designer and I did not come up with these myself.
I just took the corresponding styles and we're copying them over here.
All right.
Next one is going to be brand green one.
We're going to have a green color in our project as well.
And the code for this is hashtag 137333.
You're going to see it's going to be this green.
And of course, when I say this file prettier will do its work and add some extra commas and that is
it.
That is all we need.
And now Tailwind will have a bunch of utility classes.
Such as?
Text brand gray, one text, brand blue, one text, brand green, one that we can use like any other
tail in class in our project.
Now, what I recommend you do, even though this is technically not required, is restart your project
because sometimes it takes a little while for Tailwind to register and sometimes it misses the fact
that we've made changes to our tailwind config file.
Not always, but sometimes.
So I just recommend turning off your project on my mac.
I just said control C on windows.
I imagine it's going to be control C or control D, press it a couple of times or even close the terminal
window if it doesn't work.
But afterwards you can go ahead and restart the project with NPM, run, serve and of course that will
bundle and transpire all of your view assets, which is going to include our tail and config file.
And that's going to allow us to register these new styles.
All right.
So now that we have these styles available in our project, we can start applying them in the next couple
of lessons.
I'll see you there.