Okay.
So we now have a unique organizations getter that is going to talk to the U.S. store and give us back
a set of the unique organizations based on the jobs that we have.
So what I want to do is take that set of organizations and iterate over it in order to create the checkboxes
that the user will be able to select on the left hand side.
So as a reminder, we have a component in our app called Job Filters, Sidebar Organizations.
And what we did a couple sections ago is we created some manual list items right here with fake organizations
like YouTube between view, etc..
So what I ultimately want to do is replace these list items with one list item for every unique organization
we have.
So we're going to need to get this component to talk to our getter to get that data right.
So how do we do that?
Well, first up, let's wire up this component to talk to a getter.
And then in the very next lesson, we'll see how we can use a V4 directive to iterate over that set
and render a dynamic piece of each time up.
So right here, it's going to be super simple.
I'm going to create a new section for my computed properties, and that seems like the most logical
place to put this, because this is not really part of the components data per se.
This is just a property that the component is going to have that is based off a getter in the View X
Store, which is itself a computed piece of data based on the View X Store state.
Right.
So there's a couple levels or layers here, but hopefully it makes sense.
There's nothing new or original about this data, which is why we're making it a computed property for
this component.
So we can give this a computed property, whatever name we want.
For now, I'm going to give it the exact same name as my getter.
So I'm just going to call it unique organizations.
And this, as a reminder, is going to be a method.
Every computed property has its own method, and whatever we return here, of course we are welcome
to use within our template.
So what I want to do here is I just want to show you the syntax for accessing the getter and using it.
And I'm actually going to show you the data in The View X DevTools in Chrome and then we're actually
going to use in the next lesson.
So we know that every component in our view app has access to a this thought dollar sign store property
that gives us the view store.
And so we have a whole bunch of things on this object.
We have our state which we can talk to, right?
We have our commit method, we have our dispatch method, etc. Well, we have a property on this store
object called Getters exactly as you might expect.
And on that Getters object, we have a bunch of properties representing the getters that we defined.
So we defined a getter called unique organizations, and that's exactly what we're going to have.
Now, here's an interesting part, a little bit confusing, but hopefully this makes this easier, even
though unique organizations is a method when we defined it in the index that just follow less than go,
we don't actually need to invoke it here.
View will automatically invoke it for us and of course pass in this state object that that method needs
in order to calculate its unique organizations.
So I'm just going to conclude it like so.
So what this is going to do is it's going to run that getter method.
It's going to pass in the state automatically, and we're going to get back that set.
It's we're going to get back that set consisting of the unique organizations.
And then that set object we're going to make available via the unique organization's computed property,
which we can use in this component's template.
So I'm going to save this for now, and then where I'm going to head is back to my browser, just to
show you this in view of tools.
So as a reminder, it's this component that we're targeting right here.
Here's where we have our for list items that are manually hardcoded.
We're going to replace this in the next lesson with names that are coming from our unique organization
set.
So for now though, I can show you that if I go to my view dev tools.
And I find that components are right here in job results view.
We have our job filter sidebar here.
We have our job filter, sidebar organizations component.
And if I go into here, you can see under computed properties we have a new computed property called
Unique Organizations.
And what does it have?
It has exactly what we wanted it had.
It has a set of six unique elements.
So what does that tell us?
That tells us in our 100 arrays from DB that JSON, there's only six unique organizations among those
100 jobs.
We have captured them right here in the set and we have connected our component called job filter sidebar
organizations to a getter.
So no need to get the view store state and perform this logic in the component.
We simply say, Hey, I know there's a getter available called unique organizations.
Use it, run it and then give it back to me and store it as a computed property in this component.
And this proves to us that all of that logic has happened.
So now in the very next lesson, knowing that we have the set of six elements, six unique organizations,
we can iterate over this and create the checkboxes we see here on the left hand side.
So we'll do that in the very next lesson.