All right.
So in the previous lesson, we teased the idea of object reactivity.
So let's see how that works with our ref and computed functions.
So let's repeat the same problem that we solved in the previous lesson, but I'll make it a little bit
more complex.
Let's say I have an object called person and person is going to have a name property set to my name
of Boris.
And right below here I'll use Lat and I'll create a variable called title and I want title to be my
name, which I can reference from the person object using dot syntax plus the concatenated prefix or
post fix or however we call it suffix of the great.
So of course if I console.log title right now we'll see Boris the Great.
There's nothing surprising there.
However, if I change the value of person, not name to Peter, predictably, my title will not update.
It's still going to be Boris the Great.
So once again, I want to create the same kind of solution as we had in the previous lesson.
I want to be able to be updating the name property on my person object and have that reflect in something
like a title variable.
Right?
So what I'm going to do is pass this entire object to my ref function from view.
So what is this going to do?
It's going to return the reactive object and that reactive object is going to have a value property
and that value property is going to be this whole object that I passed in.
So let me just show this to you.
I'm going to console.log person dot value and that is going to be my original non reactive object.
This is where it gets a little bit more complicated and confusing because we actually have two objects
floating around here.
The first one is the person object, which is what the raft function returns to us.
That's this complex view object that is tracking reactivity.
And on that person object we have a value property, which is another JavaScript object.
This one is the one that we provide it to the ref function.
It's the exact same idea as we saw in the previous lessons with strings and numbers, but a little bit
more layered, a little bit more multidimensional, which is why I can get a little bit confusing.
All right.
So what do you think is going to happen when we say let title equals person, which is our reactive
object dot value, which is our kind of nested object in there.
That object is going to have a name property and I'm going to add on the grade at the end I'm going
to console.log title and that of course should give us more s great, which is to be expected because
our first calculation tends to be accurate.
But now what happens if I do person dot value that name again reaching into my person reactive object
from view by accessing its value property which gives me my original object which has a name property
which I want to set to Peter and if I console.log title, we're going to see no change and hopefully
that should be expected by now because we know that whenever we want to have a derived calculation,
we have to involve the computed function somehow.
All right.
So how are we going to make that happen?
Well, instead of simply writing this line of code, which is always going to evaluate only once, we
need to tell you to keep re-evaluating some bit of logic whenever our person object changes.
All right.
So we can do that again with our computed function.
What do we pass to computed?
We pass an arrow function and we specify what we want to track or the logic that we want to reevaluate.
And the simple act of placing any dependencies in here means Vue is automatically going to track them.
So how do I get to my name property with my string of Boris?
I have to begin with my person reactive object.
I cannot do person not name.
This is a very common mistake.
Name is not going to be available on person in this case because our ref function always returns a reactive
object that has a value property that gives you the original thing that you said to the ref function.
So in order to get my object with the name property, I have to reference the value property on person
person, dot value, dot name.
What do I want to do with that string?
Whatever it is I want to concatenate the string the great to the end of that.
Right.
And again, this is going to return a very similar reactive object with its own value properties.
So we can actually not use the left here.
We can use cons too, because this object and the title constants reference to that object will not
change throughout the program.
The contents of that object will change.
The value property in that object will change, but the constant title will still continue referencing
the same object in the computer's memory.
So that's why we can get away with Const here.
All right.
So now this should work if I console.
A blog titled dot value because titles that value property is going to be a string.
That string is going to be Boris the Great because this is a value linked to a plain string.
Now if I change this name property again by doing person dot value, that name equals Peter.
Now if I console.log title that value my computed function will rerun view is going to get the fresh
value of person that value, that name, which is now Peter it's going to append Peter the Great.
And so we're going to go from Boris to Great to Peter in the Great and there you go.
So it's the exact same concepts that we've explored in the previous two lessons, but now of course
a little bit more complex because we're passing in an object to ref instead of a primitive value, like
a string or a number.