Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to show you how we can create a totally different looking card object by
switching up the HTML next that we have here while still relying on these slot props that we receive
from our spotlight component.
So for this lesson, you actually do not need to copy what I'm about to paste.
In fact, I don't even want to write it out because it's going to take a little bit of time.
So I'm simply going to copy and paste a collection of code I have on my other screen, and I'm going
to replace this render of spotlight with an alternative render.
Again, you do not need to copy this.
We're going to return back to our original implementation at the end of the lesson.
This this is purely for the sake of example.
So I'm going to paste my new code right here.
It is an alternate form of spotlight.
So we're still using our spotlight component.
We are still providing our slot content between the opening and closing tags.
We are still using this syntax to access the props of this slot right here and make them available via
a slot props object.
We're still using that object and its spotlight properties throughout.
For example, here we are rendering and H3.
Here we are rendering a peep.
Here we are using it to generate some dynamic styles for this div and we're giving it a background image
set to that spotlight objects, image, property, etc. So I'm going to save this and head to the browser
and we're going to see a totally different look and feel on a web page.
You can even see it change dynamically or immediately in front of us.
Here is the alternate representation of the card.
It has a totally different look and feel.
We have the long, really wide card.
We have the title right here, the description, the link down below.
So it looks completely different from what we used to have, but it's still reusing our original spotlight
component.
It allows the spotlight component to handle some of the re-usable logic, such as fetching the actual
data, such as rendering an unordered list full of list items.
So we've isolated that reusable chunk of content to its own component while allowing the parent to customize
the actual look and feel of the data data that we were able to receive from the spotlight component
through the use of slot props.
Right.
That is the key takeaway from this section.
How can we pass data from the child to the parent so the parent can use that data in the dynamic template
that it generates?
And this is the advantages.
We can have totally different designs of cards while still reusing the spotlight component for the fetching
and the semantic elements in the optimal right.
And as you might expect, we're not going to cover this in the course, but we can later on extract
this logic right here to its own separate component so that we can render one type of card for one type
of spotlight, then the other card for another.
Right?
And we can still reuse these concepts along with regular view concepts like passing props down to components
to simply give whatever component the data that it needs.
Right.
That's basically the whole idea here.
So with that, in the very next lesson, I'm going to return back to our original implementation and
we'll pick right back up by showing you some small optimizations we can do when working with slot props.