All right.
In this lesson, I want to introduce you to two flags that we can apply to just when it runs.
A flag is just a configuration setting or an option that we can enable for the test run or before it
runs our files.
In order to do that, I want to open up my package, that JSON file.
And as a reminder, these scripts right here are all commands that we can run from our command line
within the project directory.
So for example, the reason we've been able to run NPM run test colon unit is because we have that script
defined here.
And when we run that, what happens behind the scenes is that node runs this command on the right hand
side, view the service test unit.
So I'm just going to provide my flags right here.
And the first thing I want to do is to show you the watch feature ingest.
So what I want to do here is copy this command.
I'm going to paste it to the line below and we cannot have two scripts with the same name, which is
why we're getting this error.
I'm going to change this new script to test Colon Watch.
And at the very end of the actual command, these are the flags that are going to be applied not specifically
to the vehicle service, but to Jess, which is what it is running behind the scenes.
I want to add a flag that is going to enable watch mode and the syntax is just going to be dash, dash,
watch.
Again, a flag like watch is basically a configuration setting.
It is an option that we're enabling.
So what we're seeing is whenever we run NPM, run test watch, we're going to run just in a specific
watch mode.
What watch mode is going to do is watch our files for changes.
And whenever we make changes to those files, either the test files or the files that they're targeting
just is going to observe those changes and trigger a fresh test run.
And the problem that this solves is the kind of monotony of having to go into our terminal each time
and manually rerun the test each time.
That's been pretty dull so far and this will automate that for us.
So I'm going to start at this script.
I'm going to run NPM, run, test, colon, watch.
That's the new command we just added.
And you'll notice instead of completing, it's just going to hang right here.
You'll notice it's going to say no tests found related to files changed since last commit.
So behind the scenes it's actually using your gift to track which files have changed since your last
git commit and whatever files have changed is the ones it's going to run the associated tests for.
You can see right below it says press eight to run all tests so we can press a to trigger our initial
test run and it's going to run through playground.
I test that.
Yes.
And run those tests off.
Now let's take a look at what happens when we head back to playground at Jess and change some code.
So notice I'm not going to even need to go back to my terminal because this is a constantly running
process.
So whenever I change my file, such as adding Z here at the end and save it, you'll notice the test
will automatically rerun.
I'm going to do it right now and you'll notice instantly just detects that something has changed.
It executes the code and gives us the new output and our test is failing because we're getting the wrong
string for that method that expects odd.
So I'm going to erase the C save the file again and I'm going to immediately see the output rerun and
the same rules apply if I change something in a test file.
So if I change this to Z right here and save the file, Jess notices that we have a change in our test
file.
It reruns that file and immediately gives us the output.
So the feedback loop is much quicker because we don't have to go back and forth between the terminal.
It'll just show us the new output.
Right?
So I'm going to bring this back again to a perfectly passing test.
We keep in mind this process is always running, so we need to stop it.
We need to terminate it just like our View app if we wanted to stop running.
So right here I'm going to press control D on my, on my Mac machine and that is going to terminate
the process.
And now we're back to my command line.
All right, that's the watch mode.
And then if I head back to my package, that JSON, I'm going to add a different flag, but I'm going
to add it to my test unit command and that flag where that option is going to be dash dash coverage.
And what that is going to do is enable test coverage.
Test coverage, as a reminder, tells us what percentage of our code is properly being tested or in
other words, what percentage of our code our tests are running through as they're executing all of
their internals.
So let's go ahead and run NPM run test unit.
Right now, we've added that flag.
So now this command will run with that flag.
We can even see it output right here and right now we will see that below our initial output with all
the checkmarks.
We're going to get this table with a bunch of columns on the left hand side.
We're going to see all of the files, the implementation files that our tests ran through.
Right now there's only playground that, Jess, but this list will grow.
As we add more tests for different files, then we have four columns.
Percentage of statements, percentage of branches.
Percentage of.
Functions and percentage of lines, and that reflects how much of our code is covered by our tests.
So this means 100% of the statements in our files.
100% of the branches.
Which means the separate splitting logic is covered.
100% of functions and 100% of lines.
Right.
And this isn't really super helpful because we have perfect test coverage.
But let me show you an example of how this will look when we do not cover something.
So as you may recall, we have an even or odd function available and we have two tests for it right
here.
We have one that tests an even number input that produces an output of an even string and one for an
odd number output.
And of course, that's handled by these two, if else, conditions right here.
So what I'm going to do is temporarily comment out my second test, which is testing the odd number.
And if I never run this code, then there's never going to be a test execution that actually runs through
my else statement because there will never be an odd number.
So now when I run my test suite again.
Well, notice that we're not going to have good test coverage or perfect test coverage.
You'll notice in the branch column it's going to tell us that only 50% of the available branches and
again, a branch is just a splitting pass.
So basically, if statements somewhere in your code where there is a logic or a piece of logic that
may or may not be executed depending on a path in this case.
And if statement creates a branch of logic.
What this is telling us is that we've covered only 50% of our branches and that should hopefully make
sense because we have two pathways of execution and even or odd.
We have the if statement and we have the statement.
We've only covered one out of two of those, which is equivalently 50%.
So I try not to worry too much about these columns right here.
The most important column and the most helpful column is on the right hand side.
It's going to tell you which line numbers have not been covered by your tests.
This tells us line number five, which of course, is the return statement with the odd, which reminds
us, oh yeah, this is something that I should definitely have a test for right now.
This is another benefit of TD is you're much less likely to run into situations like this because in
a TD a setup, you're never really going to enter into a situation where you allow yourself to write
a test or a implementation unless you have a failing test.
So if we were writing this using TDD, we would first write this test right here for our even number.
And the only implementation that we would have permission to write would be our first if statement,
because that's the only thing that the tests would cover.
Then we would have to write a new test to cover the odd statement in order to be able to add this else
statement to our implementation.
And thus our entire test coverage throughout the process would be 100%.
As soon as we introduce a test that has a new feature, we add the corresponding implementation and
that ensures that all the new code we write is going to be covered by some test, because we wrote the
test that's going to run that code first, right?
So we're less likely to avoid this problem.
Imagine if you were not using TDD, you might have written the even or odd function first and then you
may have even decided to indeed write tests, but you may have completely forgotten to write this second
test for these for the all statement.
And thus half of your code is actually untested and brittle and not going to be caught in an error if,
for example, you decide to refactor even or odd and mess something up in the statement because you're
never actually testing that pathway of execution with a test and TDD helps to avoid issues like that.
So I'm going to comment this line back in and now when I read on everything, we should once again have
100% test coverage.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
We introduced two flags that we can add to.
Just one is the watch flag, which watches your files for changes and reruns, the test suite whenever
anything changes.
And then the other one is the coverage flag, which creates a coverage report after the test suite is
done running, which shows you what percentage of your code has been executed by tests that helps you
to fill in holes in case there's something you forgot to cover in your tests.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.