Okay.
So the next component we're going to update to support TypeScript is going to be our text input component.
So I'm going to open up a text input to view.
And here it is.
It's just the basic HTML input element with a whole bunch of bindings for things like props.
For example, here we are binding the placeholder attribute to a placeholder prop.
And as another quick reminder in this component, we are emitting an event up to the parent component
so that whenever the user types a value into this text input, we are invoking this handle input method
and emitting a message with this name and this payload, which happens to be the actual value in the
input field itself.
That's just a quick reminder of what this does.
Let's see what happens when we add TypeScript support.
So right here, as always, we're going to add our land attributes, set the test and down below I'm
going to import define component.
And that is going to come from our view library and I'm going to invoke defined component and pass in
my actual configuration object.
All right.
So we have only one violation.
And it is, of course, related to this dollar sign event parameter.
And we can see TypeScript has no clue what this is.
So it says parameter event implicitly has an any type.
So what is the proper type for this event parameter.
Right.
Well remember this represents a browser generated event and an event is just an object that stores something
that has happened in the browser and it stores a whole bunch of information related to that event.
So luckily the core typescript language includes built in interfaces for browser events.
So it's going to be as simple as referencing an interface that is going to be globally available in
every file to us directly from TypeScript.
And it is a capital E event.
So right here, a colon to declare the proper type.
And I'm going to use the word event, all capital and on a mac here, what I can do is click this using
the command button.
So hold command, press, press into this and you're going to go into the fireworks defined.
I'm also going to press enter to bring this up.
You do not have to follow along with this.
By the way, I'm going to drag this over to the right.
And this is the actual definition file.
And you can see all that event is is an interface the exact same kind of interface.
We've talked about writing manually and you can see here it represents an event which takes place in
the DOM, which means in the browser window.
All right.
So that takes care of our first violation, but unfortunately, it creates another one right here.
You can see if I hover my mouse over here, it says object is possibly null.
And to explain what's going on here in my event interface, I'm going to find the actual target property
that we're accessing.
So if I scroll down all the way here because I believe these are mostly alphabetical, there should
be a target.
There it is.
And you can see Target is going to be either of type event target or.
No, that's what that pipe means.
It means either or.
And unfortunately, if it's in that target, that it might have a value property, but if it's null,
it will not.
Right.
So basically, TypeScript is saying it could be one of these two options and one of them doesn't support
value.
And thus I'm going to complain.
However, this is the kind of scenario where we absolutely know that when handle input runs we're going
to have a target defined.
And the reason is it's a method that is literally connected to an actual input element right here.
And this input will of course have to exist on the page in order for the user to type into it and trigger
the handle input method drone in the first place.
So this is another scenario where we absolutely know something that TypeScript does not and thus we
need to tell it something that it does not know so it can better types type check for us.
So typically, as we've seen before, whenever we have to tell TypeScript to recognize a different type,
we need to use the as keyword.
All right.
So that's exactly what I'm going to do.
And this is going to require us to split this logic up across two lines.
So right here, what I'm going to say is target, I'm going to target, pardon the pun.
I'm going to specifically focus on the target property, on my event object.
And by itself, this is not creating any extra copy or anything, it's just creating a reference.
But remember, I can tell TypeScript to treat this target object as something of a different type,
and I can do that by using the as keyword.
The question is, what do I use here as that thing?
So what I want to do is in this file on the right where I have all of my definitions related to the
DOM, I'm going to collapse everything.
And I just want to show you that if I go to a prefix of HTML, for example, h10 or element, if I can
find it right here, there's going to be a whole bunch of different elements that are HTML related.
So for example, here we have an interface for an H HTML area, element h, html audio element h, html
b, r or line break element.
We have things for the HTML body element.
So there's basically an interface for every single type of element that we can write in HTML to think
things like header, div, ally, etc..
There is an interface for each one of those types of elements because each one of those has a different
number of properties accessible in the DOM when we have access to those objects as JavaScript representations,
right?
So to summarize this event, that target is going to give us an actual element from the DOM represented
as a JavaScript object.
And what we can provide here is a variety of inputs or a variety of interfaces to be more specific.
And the one we're going to want here is a specific one called HTML input element.
And that should hopefully make sense because an input element is what we know that Target will be referencing.
Target will always be referencing a valid HTML element, but types of cannot know which one it is.
It can't simply deduce that from this logic right here.
But we know for certain that it's going to be an HTML input element, and so we're going to provide
this interface to tell TypeScript that we know for certain that what you're going to reference with
this target property is not just going to be any random HTML element, it's going to be specifically
an HTML input element.
And that's important because now TypeScript knows that if it can guarantee that that's the case and
HTML input element will always have a value property.
So we're basically saying don't treat this as your former thing where you thought it was one thing or
now treat this as being certain of being.
An HTML input element or of being of that type, whatever target is on line 30, we are promising TypeScript.
We are telling it we know something.
You don't treat this as this type to not input element.
So right here on the line below, instead of doing that at Target, I'm simply going to do Target now.
And TypeScript is treating the target constant as an edge to my input element, which it knows and can
validate has a valid value property.
And because it knows this, it's going to be able to confirm that value is a valid property that we
can extract on that target object because it knows that the target object is living up to this interface
or this type, whatever properties or shape of this interface.
In other words, whatever it's defined as, it has a value property in there and TypeScript now knows
that and thus it validates line 31 as well.
All right.
So that should solve this problem.
And of course, all that's left to do is to update the test suite as well.
So I'm going to open up text input that test that just move this over, open my file explorer and update
this to be.
Yes, we're making really good progress.
I can see all of these files are moving in the TypeScript direction right here.
There's only one issue which is we need to provide a dot view extension right here.
There we go.
Save that and let's run our changed files using NPM run, test, colon.
Watch.
And it should detect the changes in text input as well as the corresponding tests.
We rerun them and.
There we go.
Everything is passing.
Awesome.
So one more component moved to TypeScript and now we understand a little bit more about how we can provide
type checking for events.
So for general browser events such as clicks, such as inputs, etc., anything that we react to with
the VR directive in view, you're going to define a method that's going to accept that browser event,
and you can immediately provide it with the type of event which should be available immediately in TypeScript.
And as a reminder, event is just an interface that is globally available.
You can see here interface event, an event which takes place in the DOM.
You don't need to import it from TypeScript or anything like that.
It's going to be available globally in any project that implements TypeScript.
And then furthermore, the target property on that event object can be many different things because
there are many different HTML elements available right paragraphs, allies, devs, etc..
And so TypeScript doesn't know what it is and thus it doesn't know what properties it has.
So what we're communicating here at TypeScript is we know that event target is going to reference whatever
HTML element the event is storing or has reference to.
We know specifically that this is an input element which we know for certain because we've built it
out to be an input.
We know something that TypeScript does not.
So we can tell TypeScript treat it like an h html input element, not just a generic H2 element that
you don't know about.
And thus typed, TypeScript says, okay, I know it is an input element and I know that that has a value
property.
So I'm going to trust that.
Since I know this type that you've told me, I'm going to listen to you and respect your wishes and
can then validate that that HTML input element interface will indeed have a value property.
I know that and I can validate that.
All right.
So with that, we have made a lot of progress, and I will see you in the next lesson.