All right.
So in this lesson, I want to do a quick review of async await syntax, which allows us to write this
promise based syntax in a much cleaner format.
If you are comfortable with async await, which we have used earlier in the course, primarily in our
just tests, you can feel free to skip this lesson.
Otherwise, feel free to stick around to take a look at what async await offers us.
So the first thing to know is that async await is still the promise based then syntax under the hood.
It is called syntactic sugar, which basically means that it is not offering any new functionality,
but rather it is a shortcut or a simpler way to utilize an existing functionality.
So under the hood JavaScript will look at our async, await syntax, and it's going to transform that
into syntax that looks exactly like this.
The only reason why async await is available is to make our lives as developers easier.
So let me show you the two syntax options side by side.
I'm going to wrap our existing functionality into a function just so I can create two separate functions
one with the promise based syntax and one with the async await syntax.
So right here I'm just going to create an arrow function called Fetch Jobs V1.
V1 is just short for version one.
It's the first way that we can make this request and in that function body, I'm just going to drag
our previous code at the bottom of this file.
I'm going to invoke Fetch Job Z one and we can just double check that it works as expected.
So I'm going to bring up my terminal and I'm going to run my node command and I'm going to run my playground
file in my source directory.
So it takes a second, then it makes a request to my running JSON server and it gets the response perfect.
Now let me show you how we can write the exact same function using async await syntax.
So I'm going to declare another arrow function called Fetch Jobs v2 and I'm going to declare this arrow
function volume.
So an asynchronous function is one in which there is one or more asynchronous operations.
What is an asynchronous operation?
It is an operation that will take some amount of time that we cannot predict in advance.
Right.
So an example of something that is asynchronous is making a request to a server.
We don't know whether it will take 1/2, 5 seconds, half a second.
We don't know.
And ultimately what we want to tell JavaScript is we can't predict how long it will take, but when
that process completes, then run this additional piece of logic.
So that's exactly what this syntax right here is doing.
This promise based syntax allows us to execute some bit of JavaScript code, such as a console.log when
the request is done running.
And that is the asynchronous operation and the promise implementation is how JavaScript solves that
problem of running some bit of code at some moment in the future.
Right?
Another example is reading a file from your file system.
You don't know whether that will take a 10th of a second or 9/10 of a second.
It's not a simple JavaScript operation.
It can depend on your computer speed.
It can depend on the size of the file.
Whenever you read a file, you typically follow the exact same syntax.
You use a promise and then tell JavaScript once, once what to do once it has successfully read that
file into memory.
Right?
So when we use async await, we have to mark the function as being asynchronous.
If the function is going to do something that is going to take some amount of time, we have to mark
the function as async.
Now keep in mind, some amount of time may be something that we as humans cannot perceive.
Right?
The request to the API may take 3/10 of a second or 1/10 of a second, and we may not be able to note
that difference as human beings.
The point is to communicate to the programming language that there will be something that, from its
perspective, can take some unpredictable amount, amount of time.
All right.
So the way this works is wherever we are doing that asynchronous operation.
In other words, whenever we have an operation that will return a promise such as the Axios get method,
we're going to prefix that with the a weight keyword.
So if you have an async function, you have to use the awake keyword somewhere.
And alternatively, if you have the awake keyword somewhere in line, that means you're doing some kind
of asynchronous operation and you need to make sure that you use the async keyword.
So these two are meant to be used in tandem.
You'll never find a function where you're going to have one, but not the other.
They're meant to be used together.
So right here I'm going to await Axios dot yet.
So I have to await something that will return a promise and the get method on the Axios library, it
returns a promise.
So this is totally valid.
Now, of course, we do have to provide get with a URL to fetch.
So I'm going to provide the reference to the URL constant that we have right here.
So this is going to get the request and it's going to return the final object, which is going to be
this response object.
So I'm going to assign this to a constant called response.
All right.
And then to emulate what I want, what I what I've done before in the previous implementation of the
function.
I'm just going to console.log response data.
So why do most few people prefer the async await syntax?
Because it tends to be a lot easier to read, right?
It reads top down, there's less nesting and it kind of reads logically as a human being would perceive
it.
It's basically says, wait until this is done, wait until this is complete.
And then whatever you get back from this asynchronous operation, save it to a response constant and
then do something with it.
The important thing to note is that JavaScript will block execution while this process completes.
So when JavaScript reaches line 12, as it waits for Axios to finish that request, it is not going
to run line 13.
So that await syntax blocks the further execution until the process completes.
So if this process fails or doesn't complete, then we're never going to actually get to line 13.
But from a user perspective, from a developer perspective, I still think this is significantly easier
to read than something like this.
Right.
So what I'm going to do below is I'm going to invoke our new function, fetch jobs v2, make sure to
invoke it with parentheses.
And when I run the file, it should give us the exact same output.
Keep in mind that this async await syntax is only available in the more modern versions of Node.js,
so you should make sure you're running a modern alts version of Node.
If for some reason, Node gives you an error that says something like I don't understand async await,
it probably means that you should update node, but let's see what happens when I run this.
You can see we get the exact same result because under the hood this is the exact same as this.
There's no technical difference.
This is just a shorthand or a shortcut by which we can implement this exact same functionality using
an alternate collection of keywords.
It is called syntactic sugar because you could say it is sweeter or nicer than this version, but there's
nothing actually new in it.
It's just a a different way to write something else that is simpler and cleaner for the benefit of the
developer.
That is all that syntactic sugar means.
Okay, so now that we are comfortable using the async await syntax, we can use it in our job listings
component to modify our fetching of the jobs.
We'll do that in the very next lesson.