Okay.
So over the course of the next couple of lessons, we're going to configure a lot of project settings.
In this lesson, we're going to start out by configuring our voice code settings.
Then in the next lesson, we'll configure a little bit of just just as a reminder is our test run.
And finally we'll configure a little bit of S lint and S lint as a reminder is our enter which checks
for violations in our code.
So before we begin with this lesson, I just want to confirm with you that you have installed the three
required code extensions that you'll need to work in this course.
So if you haven't, make sure you go to this extensions panel right here and install the following three
extensions.
Veeder is the first 1vetur then s lint is going to be the second one.
That's this one right here for Microsoft.
And finally, prettier is going to be the third.
And we need to make sure that those extensions are installed because otherwise the settings that we're
going to enable are not going to work.
Okay.
So let's now create some settings for our project.
And these settings are mostly going to configure how V code is going to work.
So India's code, you can use the following shortcut on a mac.
It's going to be command shift P and on a windows it's going to be control shift P and that's going
to bring up the command palette.
It's this little box right here where we can issue instructions to the code and I want you to search
for settings and you should be able to find a setting like this.
It says preferences, open workspace settings, the first one that's highlighted and if you press enter,
it should launch you into the screen where you can set a bunch of options for obvious code.
Now you'll notice at the top that there are two tabs user and workspace user refers to global user settings.
That means if you set the settings in here, they will apply to any project or in other words, any
directory that you open in V's code in comparison, workspace settings right here apply only to this
project, in this case our job search project.
So to make sure that I don't accidentally override any of your global user settings, make sure that
you click on workspace, and that will ensure that the changes we make here are only going to apply
in this project.
All right.
So here are some of the things we're going to add to help enhance how this code helps us write our code.
The first thing I want to search for here is format on save.
And you're going to see right here there's an option on there editor for formatting and save.
And what this is going to allow us to do is to automatically run prettier AR formatter whenever we save
a file.
And that of course makes it super easy to automatically format our code.
Now you'll notice as soon as I put a checkmark here, we're going to get a brand new folder created
here called Da Vinci Code.
And in here we're going to have a single settings that JSON file.
If I were to open that file, you'll see we have this one key editor format and save such a true and
as you can probably guess, this is simply the JSON setting representation of the visual setting we
enabled here.
So every single setting that we choose right here is being saved inside the settings that Jason filed.
So you can always edit your settings right here if you want to, but if they're also able to be edited
from the user interface, that's obviously a lot easier because you don't have to remember the name
of the settings.
Keep in mind, as we adjust every setting that we're about to adjust, each one will add a new line
to the settings that JSON file.
That's totally fine.
All right.
So we know we're going to format each file when we save it.
The next question, of course, is what are we going to format it with?
Because there are a variety of programs that can format our code.
So right here, if you search for formatter.
You're going to see this first option pop up called default for matter.
And here is where we can tell this code what we would like to format the code with.
And if I select this dropdown, you're going to see a whole bunch of options.
And of course, we want to select Prettier right here.
Now, keep in mind, if this option is not appearing for you, it's probably because you do not have
the prettier extension installed.
So make sure you do have that installed and this should pop up.
So click prettier right here and that will take care of that.
The next thing I want to search for is going to be tab size.
Typically in JavaScript projects, a common tab size is going to be two, so I'm going to replace this
four with a two and press enter and then I can go back to settings that JSON to verify that everything
is working as expected.
So I have three rules right here.
The next two rules I'm going to add, we're going to write in line because there is no visual interface
where we can accomplish this, but they should be pretty simple.
So right here, after your last key value pair, you can place a comma and the logic for the next rule
is going to be the same.
So we're going to have a key here, which is going to be a string and our key is going to be s lint
dot valid date.
And what this is is going to be an array where we tell s lint are lint or what types of files we want
it to lint.
And again, the word lint means look over for errors and violations and things like that.
So we're going to put two strings in this array.
The first one is going to be a string of JavaScript, all lowercase.
So we're telling it to lint all JavaScript files.
And finally, we will also say Vue, because we want s lint to also apply to our view files, which
we'll talk more about later.
Finally, the last setting I want to add is to address a bug that I have seen while working with the
vehicle I and its configurations.
I've noticed that sometimes prettier doesn't work perfectly on JavaScript files.
It kind of skips the beautification of them.
When we say so.
What we can do here is add a little bit more of a custom precise setting.
It's going to be very similar to what we have in line three.
But I'm going to also explicitly tell this code that for all JavaScript files, I also want the default
formatter to be prettier.
My hope, of course, is that the slide number three applies to all types of files in my code base because
prettier can work on JavaScript files and view files in HTML.
But for some reason on my end I found that it sometimes skips JavaScript files.
So I want to add a second rule that's going to be very similar to this one.
Basically, the way it's going to work is like this I'm going to create a new rule.
And so in here, in double quotes, I'm going to say JavaScript and make sure you wrap JavaScript in
square brackets.
And basically this is saying, I'm going to make a rule here for just files that have JavaScript inside
them or JavaScript files too, that I'm going to attach an object.
And here inside that object, I'm going to copy the exact same line I have on line three.
So I'm just going to literally copy and paste this thing right here.
So basically what I'm saying is make prettier my default formatter and also make prettier my default
formatter for all JavaScript files.
So this category, again on line three, should in theory encompass this category, but for some reason
it didn't for me.
And this was a solution that helped solve the problem for me.
All right.
So go ahead and save that.
And the good news is you don't have to ever touch this file again in this project.
We have enabled a bunch of these settings to help us write our code automatically format it on save,
set the default tab size so we never have to worry about it again.
Make sure that yes, that validates our JavaScript and view files.
And so with these settings we're now going to get all these benefits and we never have to worry about
it again.
If for some reason you see any issues with the JSON in here, for example, your editor is complaining.
Keep in mind, in the previous lesson, I've provided a bunch of sample code that you can copy and paste.
It's going to be this object right here.
So you can simply copy and paste that content directly into your settings.
That JSON file and that JSON blob that I provided should work just in case you've created a typo here
or something like that.
It's a way that you can always return back to a working state.
All right.
So that is our settings for the voice code editor.
In the next lesson, we'll take a look at modifying our settings for the just test runner.
I'll see you there.