All right.
So now that we've configured some extra colors in our tail and config file, we can go ahead and apply
some quick CC styles to our main NAV.
These next two lessons are going to be access focused, so I'm going to proceed rather quickly, but
I am going to talk a little bit about what each Tailwind class is doing.
So I've opened up my main NAV component.
We can go ahead and start building out some additional content in here.
So I'm going to remove my main nav text and within my header I'm going to place a div.
And we should automatically create the closing date.
And by now we should hopefully know how to apply or tailwind styles.
We can just provide a class to the DIV and use whatever talent styles we would like.
So the first one I'm going to add is fixed.
What this is going to do is apply a position fixed, which means this element, our Navarre, is going
to be positioned relative to our viewport, to our screen.
Basically what this means is our neighbor is going to stay fixed.
It's going to stay in the same position at all times, even as the rest of the page is scrolled.
We want this kind of a fixed or kind of glued to the very top of our page in order to specify where
we want this actual element to be fixed on the page.
We have to provide some additional classes.
We're going to provide a top dash zero and left dash zero.
And this specifies that the fixed element R div will be placed zero pixels from the top of the screen
and zero pixels from the left of the screen, which basically means the top left corner.
We've kind of positioned this divide to be fixed, starting from the top left corner, and then it's
going to expand out and down as as much as the content inside it demands.
All right.
So then I'm going to add a W full class, just like we saw in the previous header.
This just makes the with 100% of the parent.
I'm going to add a height of 64 pixels, which I can do with age 16.
You can see here in my tailwind, IntelliSense, it is forearm or equivalently 64 pixels and then one
more class here, BG Dash.
Right.
This is automatically available in Tailwind.
Tailwind knows that white is a common color, so it has a helper class like Big White, which, as you
might guess, makes the background of this box white.
All right, so I'm going to save this.
There's not actually going to be any changes onto the page just yet that are going to be visible.
But when we go ahead and add some more content, which we'll do in the next lesson, we'll be able to
see it appear.
In fact, let me go ahead and look at my inspector right now, just so we can take a look at what it
looks like.
And we can see the div is actually on the page right here with the corresponding styles.
There it is highlighted in blue.
And we're going to continue building out more content within this.
Now, this is going to be the box.
It's going to house our navigation.
All right.
So I will see you in the next lesson.