Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to start building out these styles for a single job listing in our job
listings component.
So right here in our main tag, let's remove this former text and we'll begin with an ordered list.
So I'm going to use the 0lh HTML element.
So technically speaking, the jobs that the user sees are going to be prioritized in a certain order.
You may not see a number to the left of each job listing, but there is still the concept of order.
So an ordered list here is a more descriptive and semantic element compared to a U, l or an unordered
list.
So we're going to go with all L here.
That's exactly how it appears on the Google website.
So let's create an ordered list and then for each one of our job listings, that is going to be its
own list item.
So I'm going to create an ally here and I'm going to immediately add a single tailwind class to that.
And that's going to be me.
Seven is short for margin bottom and seven is a class that's going to apply 28 pixels of margin on the
bottom, which is just going to create some spacing in between our subsequent job listings or in other
words, our subsequent list items here.
Okay.
So as it turns out, the entire job listing itself is clickable on the Google Careers website, and
if you click it, it goes to the specific job page for that job.
So in order to make our complete content of this box, of this job listing clickable, we need to make
it a link.
But of course we no longer have the concept of hyperlinks or tags because we have a single page app.
So what I'm going to do here is use the view router component called router link.
Remember that is the view router equivalent of a hyperlink.
It allows us to navigate to another path without forcing a page, refresh or navigation.
So I'm going to create a router link component here.
And because I want to have content inside it and all of that content is going to be clickable.
I'm going to make sure I have both an opening and a closing router link tag, and any content that I
put in here will be a child of the router link and thus clicking on any content here will navigate to
wherever the rattling says to navigate to.
So we don't have the concept of specific IDs for our jobs.
So for now, I'm going to use the two prop and I'm just going to give it an arbitrary URL of slash jobs,
slash results, slash one.
I know this isn't perfect because we don't have the idea of one to this job yet, but we need some kind
of place to direct the user when they click on the job listing.
So let's just make a go to jobs, slash results, slash one.
Furthermore, I'd like to add a couple of classes to this router link to style it.
So I'm going to make it a block element by adding the block class.
Then I'm going to center it in the middle of my job listings component by applying margin on the left
and right side.
I can do that with the Amex auto class that's going to center it in the center of my job listings component
or the outer element.
That is.
Then what I'd like to do is give it a white background, which I can do with big white.
Then I'd like to add a border around the entire box.
So I will apply the border class to give a border of one pixel.
I will make sure that border is solid with the border solid class, and the color is going to be border
brand gray too.
That is coming from our tailwind config file.
So border brand great deal.
The other thing that I'd like to do is make this a rounded box so I can add the rounded tailwind class
to apply a border radius of four pixels.
That is going to give it a little bit of a curve on all four of its edges.
And finally, in the previous lesson, we added that box shadow and the new scissors class for that
is Shadow Gray.
However, I only want to apply that when the user hovers over this box.
So in order to apply a style or a class only on hover, remember we need to prefix it with that hover
keyword followed by a colon and then the name of that CS6 class.
So on Hover I want to apply Shadow Gray and let me save this.
So we get a reformatting and we can see it.
Here we go.
Hover, colon, shadow, gray.
And remember, the reason that this word here is gray is because that's the name we used for the box
shadow as our property in the tailwind config file.
In the previous lesson.
Okay.
So this is going to be our router link.
When the user clicks on any content inside here, it's going to navigate them to this page right here.
So inside that router link, I want to add a new div.
And that div is going to be the kind of container that stores our primary heading, which includes the
job title name as well as the company and the location of the job.
So I'm going to add some quick classes here as well.
We're going to add five to you short for padding top.
So some spacing inside the box for the top to push the text content a little bit down.
I also want to add a little bit of padding on the bottom.
I can do that with the P B series of classes, padding bottom.
We're going to go with PB two here for about eight pixels of bottom padding.
I then want to add some margin on the left and right side.
So the X axis, so I'm going to apply the max eight class that's going to apply a 32 pixel.
So margin on the left and 32 pixels of margin on the right.
And here I'd like to add a border as well.
This is going to be for the kind of top section of this box where we have the, as I mentioned, the
title and the listings, and then there's a border and then you actually start the job description.
So we're going to add a border on the bottom of this def using the border B class border bottom.
We're going to make that a solid border with border solid.
And for this border color, we're also going to use border brand gray to.
All right.
So there we go.
Now, inside the div, we're going to need a header to store the job title.
It's going to be an H2 element since it's not the primary header of our webpage.
And let's type in a sample job name right now.
We're going to hard code this text and later on we'll make it dynamic when we fetch the jobs from a
sample back end.
For now, we're just kind of building out the look and feel of the job listing and hard coding some
text values.
But later on we will make these dynamic.
So for now, let's go with a real job title from the Google website, which is Technical Program Manager
Perception, Augmented Reality.
That sounds like exactly the kind of Google skill that I would never be able to do in real life.
Okay, so let's add a couple of classes to this H2 element.
We're going to add a little bit of margin on the bottom using maybe two.
That is eight pixels of bottom margin.
And we're going to make this text a little bit larger than our standard text.
So I'm going to apply the text to Excel class.
You can see that applies a font size of 1.5 RAM and then a standard pixel size of 16 pixels.
That's going to be a 24 pixel font size for this header.
So kind of prominently sitting there in the box.
All right.
So below our H2, I want to put another DIV and this is where we're going to store information about
the company that the job is at because remember, the Google conglomerate holds a bunch of smaller companies
underneath it like Google, YouTube, etc. and we're going to have the same idea here.
So for now, we're going to keep things simple, but we're going to apply a class here and we need a
little bit of margin on the right here.
So I'll add an M.R. margin right class and we'll do our five for 20 pixels of right margin.
And in here I'll put a span with the name of the intercompany within my larger company.
You can make up whatever word or company you want to do here.
I'm just going to use the word bobble since I can't be creative right now and come up with more fake
companies.
And finally below that, we want to add another div and here's where we're going to put a span with
the location of this job.
So let's say this job is located in San Francisco, California, United States.
It doesn't really matter what you write in either of these spans, as long as there's some text that
should be good.
All right.
So we've closed this div we've closed the outer div that is storing the header content.
And then we're going to put all of that within a router link to make this a clickable view router link,
which is itself inside a list item because it is semantically one item in a list in an ordered list.
So quite a bit in this lesson.
Let's take a look at what it looks like right now in the browser.
So there we go.
Looking good.
So this is what things are looking like right now.
Let's see if I can actually push the San Francisco text onto the same line as Bobo.
And I think we can do that with a couple extra classes.
So if I go back to my editor, let's see here we have our H2.
We ever div.
All right.
So what I want to do here is for these two divs right here with our company name and our city, I'm
going to wrap those in their own div.
So let me do that right here.
And then I'm going to add a couple of classes to this one in order to get them aligned on the same row.
So I'm going to make it a Flexbox and I'm going to make sure that that Flexbox goes in a row base direction
by doing flex row.
And then I'm going to apply a line middle and that is just going to apply a vertical line of middle.
So it's kind of the text is centered in the center or the middle of that.
Flexbox I'm going to save that.
Let's go back to a browser and see how that looks.
All right.
So that is getting to where we want.
Looking good.
We have our H2 with the name, we have our company, we have our location.
You'll notice as I hover my mouse, we're getting that box shadow over the entire box.
And you'll also notice in the bottom left of my chrome window, you'll see that we have that URL listed
of slash jobs, slash results, slash one.
So if we click on this, it will indeed navigate us to that job page for that job.
So things are looking pretty good.
And the very next lesson, we're going to start wiring up the job description and the corresponding
bullet points.
So I will see you there.