All right.
So the changes that we made to the sub nav component in the last two lessons are actually going to cause
our sub nav tests to fail.
But the good news is they're going to fail for what I hope is now a predictable reason.
In our previous implementation, using the Options API, we were using the dollar sign root and dollar
sign store properties.
And that's exactly what we're marking out here in our sub nav, that test, that jazz file, we no longer
have this idea of properties and that's what we're mocking out here is kind of useless.
So what we're going to do instead to get these tests to pass again is we're going to mark out, use
store and we're going to mark out use route in our test suite.
And we're simply going to replace this store object and this route object with the previous store and
route objects that we were still using but that we were providing to the dollar sign route and store
property in our mock configuration.
So again, same idea as far as our tests, but where we're actually intercepting those calls is changing.
We're now going to intercept, use store and use route instead of intercepting dollar sign store and
dollar sign route.
So right here I'm going to run, NPM, run, test, call and watch.
And I should have no changes since my last get commit.
So just to show you this failure, I'm just going to add a line break in my test suite and save and
that's going to force the rerunning of seven now.
So you can see where we have one failing test suite and two tests and in fact, everything we have in
this sub.
Now, that test file is just to test.
All right.
So how do we fix this problem?
Well, let's begin from the very top of the file.
We know that we're going to need to import the functions that we want to mark out with.
Just so let me, in fact, copy them directly from the component.
So I'm going to copy these two lines right here, 19 and 20 in our test file.
We're going to import, use, store and use route, and that's going to give us the names so that later
on we can use them and set their mock return values.
But first up, I need to tell just to mark these libraries in general.
So down below, I'm going to do just that Mark.
Let's mark out our full view library and then let's also invoke just Mark on the line below and mark
out our view router library.
So now once again use store and use root are no longer their original implementations.
They are now just mark functions, but by default just mark functions that return undefined when invoked.
And we want them to return something different.
We want them to return objects that are going to be good enough to fulfill these properties right here.
So our store object must have a getters property with filter jobs and our root object must have a name
property and that should be good enough.
In fact, that's very similar to what we previously did in our tests.
Right?
We still have the idea of a store right here.
We're just going to need to replace and intercept our calls the first step.
Let's start with our create config function right here.
We're no longer going to be using this mark section since we're no longer marking out dollar sign root
or dollar sign store.
So let's remove this entire section of Mark's right here.
So all that our config factory functions going to do now is basically just about ask them, which is
okay, so that removes the need for any parameters right here.
So I'm going to remove them completely.
This was our former implementation and we no longer need this.
All right.
So create config is just going to return a basic configuration object.
All right, so down below here, we're now going to need to intercept, use root and use store, right?
So what we're going to need here is to reference use root, which is a mark just function.
And I'm going to invoke mark return value.
And here I'm going to provide in the parentheses, in the actual invocation, what I want to use root
to return when invoked.
Well, we can see right here that all we need is a basic object with a name property.
So this is going to be an object with a name property.
And as you may recall, this test is specifically relying on having a root name of job results.
So I'm just going to copy that from below.
Job results.
And thus we can remove the need for this root name constant that was floating around.
All right.
So here is our mock view store.
The good news is we can still keep it right, because this is still the store we need.
We need a store with a getters property, with filter jobs.
And that will work for this implementation right here.
The only thing we need to change is we need to provide this mock store as our return value for the use
store function.
That way, if we return this object right here, then the rest of our setup method will work.
So instead of using store here, I'm simply going to write you store, which is a mock function.
Now, it's not the original implementation.
And I want to invoke mock return value on this to set the return value when it's invoked.
And so when my test uses use store in the setup method, I'm going to return our mock store right here.
Still no need to use the real view store.
Still the exact same mock object we set up earlier.
We're just configuring it to be returned from a used store instead of being available via this the dollar
sign store right here with create config.
That factory function no longer takes any arguments.
So we can simply remove the arguments right here.
And that's going to be the refactor for our first test.
All right.
So let's move on down to our second test.
It's going to be very similar.
So right here, we have a route name of home and we need that on a route to object.
So now we're going to get the root object by our setup method invoking use route.
We're going to intercept that user out cold and we're going to make sure that when it's invoked, it's
going to return a value that's going to be a route object.
What does a route object need to have a name property?
And what I what do I want it to be equal to for this test?
We can see below this test was using a name value of home that takes care of that.
All right.
Now, in this case, if I save this, we can also make sure to get rid of config.
This is going to be enough to actually get our code to work.
But just to be safe, because I know that we are going to be using story getters here.
I'm just going to copy this code from above just to make sure we remind people that we are marking out
the store.
Because I guess the way this is going to work is it's still going to work if you store as the default
implementation.
But let me just set up your store anyway.
Make sure it has getters.
Filter jobs don't really matter.
So let me just make it an empty array.
Save that and everything should still pass.
All right, so now we got our test suite to pass once again.
Once again, we're simply intercepting, intercepting something and replacing it with something else.
That's all a mark is.
However, we're now replacing these two function calls that our tests are using instead of using the
original properties that Vue router and Vue made available on every component.
All right.
So with that, we are in much better shape and we can move on to the next lesson.