Okay.
So the first dependency that we will need to install will be a web browser.
And in this course I will be using the Google Chrome browser by Google.
This is still the most popular browser used in the world.
I believe it has something like 65% market share.
So it is a popular, modern, up to date choice with frequent updates.
So I encourage you to use the Google Chrome browser for this course.
However, you are more than welcome to go with another browser if you prefer, such as Firefox, Safari,
Opera, etc..
All right, so if you want to install Chrome, you can head to Google.com, slash chrome in your browser
and then click download Chrome and that will give you an installer that is specific to your operating
system, whether it be Mac, Windows, Linux.
Once you get that installer, of course you can follow the instructions in that installer file to walk
through the installation.
All right.
You're obviously watching this course on a browser now, so I hope this is not your first time experiencing
a web browser.
But of course, if you're unfamiliar with Chrome, this is a pretty good, solid, modern option.
And this is what I'm going to be utilizing throughout the course.
All right.
So go ahead and install that if you want.
And I will see you in the next lesson.