Okay.
So in this lesson, we're going to introduce a super cool view feature called Slots.
It's the focus of the section and it's what's going to allow us to make our accordion component super
reusable.
What slots allow us to do is to have a parent component specify a dynamic injectable slice of HTML that
can be rendered inside a given component.
So slots are optimal when we need to inject different content in between consistent other content.
Okay.
That's kind of vague and vacuous.
Let me give you a better use case right in front of us.
You'll notice here that we currently have the hardcoded text child right here.
And ultimately what we want to do in an accordion component is render some checkboxes, right?
CheckBoxes, for example, for organizations that the user can filter by.
But in another accordion component, later on down the road, we may want to have totally different
checkboxes.
For example, we may want to have an accordion for job types, in which case we're still going to have
checkboxes, but they're going to have different text.
They're going to have job types like full time or part time.
So what we really want to do is to make this content in between the div customizable.
This is what we want to be able to have feature custom content.
We want to inject something dynamic here.
Why do we want to do that?
Well, the reason we want to do that is then we can reuse this component.
We can have the accordion take care of the open, closed logic, which remains the same no matter where
we want to use the accordion.
We want to keep this logic.
We always want to have the varying care symbol.
Right.
We always want to have the idea of expandability and collapse ability.
That's something that we want to keep constant and reusable and not have to duplicate.
However, we want to be able to have something custom right here.
We want to vary the child content that we are conditionally displaying.
We do not want to copy this logic to its own component because this is perfectly reusable.
We just need to customize one small sliver of this component and it is what we inject right here.
So this content in view is called slots.
A slot you can think of almost like the word slot in real life.
A slot is kind of something you fill up or fill in, right?
If you think about an open slot on a team, like a sports team, that refers to something that is waiting
to be filled.
Right.
It's the same idea.
We can view this as what we call a slot in view.
It is a place in our component where we can customize the content that we want to provide or inject
or slot into this point right here.
The rest of the component will stay the same, but we're going to customize what we put in here and
where we're actually going to customize it is in the parent component that renders the accordion.
When we render the accordion.
The parent component can say, Please provide something here that I want you to put into this slot.
It can be an H1, it can be an H2, it can be a header, it can be a table.
It can be a bunch of checkboxes.
It could be another set of checkboxes.
But anywhere where we render accordion, we're going to be able to customize this little section right
here.
Okay.
Let me show you how the syntax is going to work.
It's going to be pretty simple, and I promise it's going to make more sense when we see it in action.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to use a special available view global component called Slot, and
I'm going to render it with both an opening and closing component tag.
So right here slot like so.
All right.
So what this says is whenever a parent component renders an accordion, it can provide slot content.
An accordion will know to place that slot content right here in this component.
So the next thing I'm going to do is I'm going to open up my job filter sidebar.
In fact, let me drag according to the right so I can show you how the logic will flow out.
Here we have an accordion.
It's currently a self-closing component.
I'm going to expand it to be an opening and a closing accordion component.
Same syntax by now, but here's how it's going to work.
I'm going to do a line break and anything that I put inside this accordion component right here as a
child, if you will know, belongs to this slot right here.
So, for example, if I put an H1 right here of Hello View will know to take this H1 right here and
inject it right here.
It's basically going to do this behind the seats, right?
The beautiful part about this design is if we want something totally different, if we want an H3 with
the text goodbye, then you will now take this thing and slotted into this spot.
Right here we are customizing this element right here while keeping the rest of the component the same.
We have gotten this perfect balance between reusability and customization, right?
We are we are reusing this collapse ability, but customizing what it actually hides and shows.
Okay.
So with that said, we have to make sure we have slot right here.
And for example, right here, I can simply write a message like, hello.
Custom content must save this and if we go back to our browser.
We're going to see now that when we expand this, we're going to see that element right here.
Hello, custom content.
So we have customized what is that hidden content that we are seeing when we expand the accordion,
when we just show you side by side, what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy and paste this accordion
component immediately below.
And here I'm going to do something different because we can talk.
We can totally have whatever we want and here we can have any text, any ailment, etc..
So I'm just going to put something here like an H2 and it's going to say totally different content for
my second accordion.
And when I go back to my browser, you'll notice we're going to have to accordion components.
And when we expand the first one, we're going to see our first bit of slotted content.
Hello, custom content.
And when I open up my second accordion, we're going to see that totally different content coming from
the H2.
We can customize just this part that is the beautiful part of slots.
All right.
So to summarize, what is a slot?
At the end of the day, it's just an available view global component that we put in the child and we
put it in the child in the template where we want to dynamically inject that custom content.
Now, that custom content will come from the parent that is going to be rendering that component with
a slot.
And the way that parent specifies what to plug into that slot, what to plug into that whole is by simply
writing that content in between the opening and closing component tag of that component that has an
available slot.
By the way, if we don't provide any content, if we do something like this, then all viewers going
to do is simply put, nothing right here.
Right?
So let me show you this.
I save that and go back to our browser and expand this.
We're going to see there's actually no content in there, which sort of makes sense because what Vue
says is it says, Hey, have given me nothing to put in the slot, so I'm literally going to put nothing
in that slot.
So basically evaluates to this behind the scenes, right?
We still have our is open div, but we don't actually have any dynamic slot content to put in there.
All right.
So there's no danger if we accidentally leave out chunk content, but if we do include child content,
we're going to inject it in that slot.
All right.
So pretty simple concept, but I think pretty difficult to describe in words.
Hopefully that makes sense.
All right.
So before we close this lesson off, let me just delete the second accordion and then we're going to
continue learning more about slots in the very upcoming lessons.