All right.
So I think you can guess what we're going to do next.
We're going to overwrite our job search, form data properties to store the data or the payload that
we receive from our child text input component.
So right now, whenever our child emits the handle input event, we're going to react to it by invoking
the update roll method.
And here is our update roll method.
It will receive a payload argument.
And that represents the second argument we provided right here in text input, which is just going to
be the string with the actual text input.
So what do I want to do with that payload?
I want to override this component role data property with that parent payload.
So this that role will get me that property and I will override it with payload.
Payload represents the string of what the user has entered because that is what I'm sending along with
the handle input event.
All right.
And while we're at it, we can practice this syntax again for our other text input component, because
remember, we have the second runtime right here and this is for the location.
Now, an important thing to note here is that these components are isolated.
So just because this text input is handling the handle input event does not mean that this one is going
to react to it as well.
And similarly invoke the update roll method.
Quite the opposite.
Each component is independent and isolated and they're only going to react to that component.
What I mean by that is this text input will know when it's itself.
This child is going to send up the handle input event, right?
It's a totally separate text input from right here.
This text input knows about only this method shooting off in its own text input component.
It is totally oblivious to what is going on to any other text input anywhere in our app.
So right here for our text input for our location, we still have to react to the exact same emitted
event and that is going to be called handle input.
So I still want to use my VON Directive syntax, so I'm going to react to my handle input emitted event
for this text input.
And unlike the first one, I want to invoke a totally different method because for this one I do not
want to invoke my update roll method that is totally different.
I want to invoke a different method to update my location.
So I'm going to call that method, update location.
So once again, in case I kind of spoke too quickly, these are totally separate text input components.
They're both going to react to the emission of the handle input event, but this text input is only
going to react to its own handle input event.
So whatever happens in the text input right here for this instantiation of that component, nothing
here is going to affect anything in our second text input and vice versa.
Nothing with the user typing in and a letter into the location input field will affect the text input
that is storing the role.
They're totally isolated and independent.
So right here we have our update location method.
So we must define a method with the same name update location, and it will similarly take a payload
parameter and we're still reusing this text input component.
But of course for our other text input for the location, this, that value in that circumstance will
reflect the input for that text input, which is the user's location.
So same payload, same string argument, but a totally separate text input instantiate component.
So right here, instead of overriding this, that role, we want to update this not location, which
is another data property on job search form.
So this, that location equals payload.
Three using the same text input component, but we are of course rendering two of them to handle the
separate responsibilities of storing the role and the location.
All right.
And with that, we can transition to our browser and take a look at what we have.
So right here, we have our role and our location.
Let's start by typing to the role.
Let me, in fact open up my first text input and we should see this value property on the text inputs
data update.
So let me for example, type, let's see, programmer.
And we should see maybe this is a little bit slow.
Let me refresh this.
We should see programming appear and there it does.
Apologies for a few dev tools not behaving.
We should see that programmer updates in VI type s here and refresh this automatically.
We can see that programmers is present right here, but if we transition to our job search form component
will notice that its role data property has also updated.
This is coming from the update roll method.
We are taking the payload from that emitted event from the child and we are overwriting the raw property
on the parent.
Similarly, if I go into this field right here and let's say a type of city like Seattle, and I'm going
to force a refresh right here, we'll see that.
Now, our job search form will have that location, data, property populated.
And remember, this is going to happen every time we type a character.
So when we type the S here, the text input component will overwrite its value and then it's going to
invoke a new or non invoke, but send out a new event called handle input with the payload of the letter.
S Our job search form will receive that event and that payload and overwrite its own data property for
location to have letter s.
Then when we type the letter E, the exact same process occurs.
The child text input component emits a handle input event.
It gives it the payload of the characters.
See, the parent job search form receives and reacts to that event and invokes its own method, which
in turn updates the location data property to BSD.
And that occurs every single time we type a character within our child.
Our child emits a message upward, the parent receives it and does something to react to it.
All right.
So that is all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.