In this lesson, I'd like to introduce another global component from the View Router Library, and that
is router link.
Router Link allows us to create a fake hyperlink to navigate to a different path.
Remember, we have a single page app, so we don't technically have pages, we don't technically have
URLs and thus we can't actually use the native HTML anchor tag, the a tag because that will force a
navigation which forces a page refresh.
So how do we provide the user with the impression of links that they can click to navigate elsewhere?
Elsewhere?
Well, we have to replace our anchor tags with these router link components, and that's all they do.
The router link component creates a fake hyperlink, so the user has the impression of navigation.
So the user has the impression of seeing the URL change, but it handles the actual concept of not refreshing
the page and simply allowing the router view to dynamically inject the correct component based on that
path.
So what router link does is it actually allows us to navigate to that path while router view swaps the
components there.
So let me show you an example here in our app component, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create
a div right above my router view and in here I'm going to use two router link components.
Again, these are global components.
They were made available to us with view router so we can use them in line.
We do not need to import them, we do not need to register.
So I'm going to do a router link and this one is not going to be a self-closing component.
So I do need to have both an opening and a closing component.
And the way it works is just like an opening and closing an anchor tag.
So in here, in between the opening and closing tag, I can put the text that I want to display.
So let's make a router link to go to our home page and another one to go to our job results page.
So for the first one, I want the text home and let me copy and paste this below and here is where I
can put the text that appears on the second link, and this text will be job results.
And then of course, the other key detail that we need to provide is the actual new URL that we're going
to be able to navigate to.
So how can we tell this rattling component where to take the user when the user clicks on it?
We do that using a special prop, right?
Because as we know, whenever we have to provide a component, any custom data, we do that via props
and props work exactly the same way as HTML attributes.
We just enter them in line and the prop we're looking for here is two, which sort of makes sense because
this is the path that we want to direct the user to.
This is where we want to go to.
So our route route, our home route is available simply by typing in a slash.
So what have I done here?
I've created this fake hyperlink that will have the text home that when clicked, will direct the user
to slash in the URL.
We are not refreshing the page.
We are not really navigating in a traditional browser sense, but the user doesn't know that these are
just simply sees the URL change, at which point what happens?
The router view component tracks that change and says okay, now I have the slash out.
I need to render the home view.
The exact same protocol is going to apply for our second router link.
We're similarly going to give it a two prop.
And of course the page we want to link to here is slash jobs, slash results.
So once again, what's going to happen?
We're going to have a bunch of text appear on the screen that looks like a hyperlink.
It's going to have the text job results when the user clicks on it.
Router link will navigate to slash jobs slash results as our path router view will observe that change
and render the dynamic component right here.
Keep in mind because our router links are right here in app view they will always render.
Much like the one in the previous lesson.
We're always going to have these two links and immediately below the two links we're going to render
whichever dynamic component the router view component wants to render based on the current path.
Okay.
And one more thing as a quick review.
The reason we do not need to use V bind syntax here with the two prop is because we're passing in a
JavaScript string.
It is not changing, it is not dynamic, it is not an array or an object or connected to the components,
data or computed properties.
It's a plain string and when you have a plain string, you can just use the regular prop syntax without
the colon because we're not binding anything, we're providing a single hardcoded value.
So with that, if we navigate back to our browser.
And refresh the page.
Now we have the two links up top.
Now it's not very pretty, but these are indeed two router links.
I have them right here.
Here's the very first one and here is the second one.
And when I click this link right here, it'll take me to the home view.
It's not very impressive or flashy, but it still takes me to the slash root.
And now when I click on this one, which is job results, notice how the URL above is going to change
to slash job slash results.
And then the the router view component takes over and says, I'm going to render the job results view
because now I'm on a different page, I'm on a different route.
Rather, the Chrome Web browser is not refreshing.
You'll notice as I switch back and forth, the result is instantaneous because the page is in actually
refreshing and no additional JavaScript is being loaded.
But the user gets the impression that they are navigating because if they observe the URL bar they can
see that it is changing in front of them.
I notice that the clicking here is an absolutely perfect, but there it is a couple of times back and
forth.
As I navigate, you'll notice how quickly view just observes the changes and replaces what is on screen,
and that is really the core heart of what the router does for us.
It just keeps track of changes and renders something differently, which gives the user the impression
of navigating a regular website.
But behind the scenes they've already gotten all the view code they need and view is just swapping different
elements on the screen.
It's just reacting again to a user event, a user clicking on a router link component and changing the
URL.
All right, that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.