Okay.
So now that we have a better sense of how your state and mutations work together, I think now is a
good time to write some basic tests for the functionality we have in this file.
So I'm going to go to my file Explorer right here.
I'm going to collapse everything in my project folder and in my test directory in my unit folder, I'm
going to create a new folder called Store.
I'm basically going to mirror the exact directory structure I have in my source directory and in this
store folder.
I'm going to create a test file for this far right here.
So I'm going to name this test file index that test that J.S. And I'm going to open it side by side
with my implementation, and then we're going to write our tests.
So let's begin by importing the core functionality that we wrote in this file.
This is really the logic that belongs to us because the rest is really the create store function which
belongs to View X.
This is the heart of our app and this of course is in another advantage of moving this configuration
to separate functions in the file.
We can now import just this logic without having to worry about the store creation right here.
So I'm going to import our named exports, which is the state function and the mutations object.
And that is going to come of course from the source directory and the store folder in there.
As a reminder, if you have an index file in a given directory, you can simply write the directory
name and node knows to look for a index that just file in there.
Okay, so here's the beautiful part about testing.
It's actually going to be remarkably easy because all this is is a plain JavaScript function and a plain
JavaScript object, right?
We don't need to incorporate all of the complexity of the View X Store in order to test this logic.
Right.
At the end of the day, View X needs a function that returns a JavaScript object, but to us it's a
basic JavaScript error function and we can test just that aspect alone.
So right here I'm going to describe that I'm testing state and I'm going to write a very simple assertion.
I'm just going to check for one property at a time.
I think it's a best practice to have simple tests that test for one thing at a time.
So I would not recommend having a test, for example, that tests for every single property.
In your view, X Store State.
Eventually, as your app scales, you might have a view store that has 20 properties, and I don't think
it's a good idea to have one large test that checks for all those properties.
Rather, I think it's better to have one test basically per property.
So here's what that test is going to look like.
I'm going to say here, it keeps track of whether user is logged in.
And all I'm going to do in the body of this test is I'm going to invoke my state function, which I
have in my left.
So concept and let's assign is to a constant called starting state and that is going to be the return
value of my state function application.
And then I'm simply going to assume that starting state is going to return an object to me.
And on that starting state object, I expect there to be a property called is logged in and that should
be equal to false.
So the advantage of this test is that it's going to double check that the property exists and also that
it has the right starting value of false.
If I was writing this test, this would be a reasonable TDD test to write in order to get this code
that we have on the left hand side.
So let me go ahead and bring up my terminal window.
And now I'm going to run NPM, run, test, colon.
Watch.
Let's run.
We have right now pretty simple tests.
They don't expect any failures.
And it passes.
That's great.
And now I'm going to add a similar test for our current single mutation method, which is log in user.
So for this, I'm simply going to add another separate describe on the same high level we can nest describes
within each other.
We can also have multiple top level describe function calls in the same test file as well.
So right here, I'll add a separate describe because it's a separate, independent category.
And here I'm going to test all of my mutations.
And then I'm going to try my arrow function as the second argument.
And here I'm going to write another describe for this specific mutation that I'm testing here, which
is log in user.
And the reason I'm doing this, of course, is later on, I anticipate that I might have multiple mutations.
And so I want a separate described block for each mutation that I'm testing within the larger level
described category of mutations.
All right.
So here's where we have another question about testing.
Do we need the the complete view X state object in order to test?
Right now, this may not be super difficult because we have a very simple store.
But I want you to imagine this scenario.
Imagine our view X Store State.
This object right here has 20 properties.
Do we need to feed in in our test a an object that actually has the full state with all 20 properties
in order to test what log in user is doing.
My answer is absolutely not.
All that this mutation is going to do is modify the value of a property on our state object called is
logged in.
So whether state has 20 properties or 40 properties or 100 properties doesn't matter because we know
the heart of this logic is just writing one property and giving it a value.
Right.
And that's sort of the beautiful part is we don't have to even care about Vue and how it processes mutations
from the perspective of what this log in user method is.
It's a method that accepts some kind of state argument which has to be an object because we're accessing
property and then it sets a property on that object.
And that's as complex as our test needs to be.
It doesn't need to go beyond that to start thinking about Vue review.
It just needs to be testing this core functionality right here.
So, for example, right here, I'm going to write the simplest test I possibly can and I'm going to
describe the value of this mutation it logs the user in, and I'm going to create a simple object to
represent my state.
Right.
So right here I'm going to say current state.
And I'm just going to say it's going to be a simple object called with a property rather of is logged
in set to false.
And you might be thinking, well, that's the exact same thing as we have right here.
What's the difference?
Again, imagine a scenario where we have an object here with 20 different properties, even if this
real life implementation has 20 different properties.
In my test, I'm still going to feed in this small object with just the one property that I care about.
Right.
And the next thing I'm going to do is simply pass it into my log user mutation.
We do not need to import a real life store.
We do not need to get a store involved because all we're testing is a basic JavaScript method.
So on my mutations import right here, which is this object, I'm going to say my mutations object has
a log in user method and I need some kind of argument to represent the state parameter.
So I'm going to feed in this state object that I defined above.
And after this method runs, what do I expect?
I expect that my state is now going to be a different type of object, so I'm going to use that to equal,
just match or I can't use to be when I'm using JavaScript objects.
And here I'm going to provide a new object.
I'm going to state that it should have an is logged in property set to true and alternative approaches.
You can simply say expect state that is logged in and compare that that equals now value equal to true.
Either approach works here.
I'm simply comparing the whole object and double checking that a different way.
So when I save this you can see everything is running.
We have a nice level of categorization here in my tests and that is actually it in my opinion.
This is a perfect, small, lightweight unit test that runs super quick and we don't need to know all
the details of how the View Store is dealing with its complexity.
When it gets this, mutations object in the shape because to us it's a simple JavaScript object and
we have everything we need here in order to test that it is doing exactly what it's supposed to do.
All right.
So that's a basic some basics on how we can test some aspects of the state and mutations in a just test
file.
Now, we can take a look at how we can connect to this view store state within a component in the very
next lesson.