All right.
So as I mentioned in the previous lesson, the advantage of the V bind directive is that we can bind
our optimal attributes to some slice of data on our component.
And so when that slice of data updates, those changes will be reflected in our template.
So let's start wiring up that logic right now so we can see it in action.
So I'm going to define a data method right here in my action button.
And as a reminder, it is an S6 method, so I'm going to define it like so.
And from this methods body, we're going to return a JavaScript object.
And again, as a reminder of the properties that we defined here are going to be available to be used
throughout the template and we're not just obligated to interpolate them, we can also use them in other
situations as we saw with V Bind earlier in the class.
So I'm going to create a property here called Primary and I'm going to set it equal to true.
All right, I'm going to save this.
And now we have the property primary available to be used anywhere in this template.
Where I'm actually going to attach it is right here.
Instead of the false, I'm going to write primary.
So this syntax can be a little bit confusing because we have a key of primary and that is just a string
in JavaScript.
This is just a static in line, a string that's literally the word primary.
But this primary right here on the right side of the colon is a reference to this data property.
So right now, what Vue is going to do when it renders this component is it's effectively going to look
at what primary is.
It's going to see that it's equal to true and it's going to substitute it like so, right?
So when the component renders, it's going to look like this.
But what is the advantage of connecting this primary key to a data property?
Well, it's the dynamism and it's the ability for Vue to react to changes.
So, for example, if we change this primary in our data to something like false, which we can do with
something like methods which we've explored previously view will detect that a slice of data has changed
and because it has changed, view will re render our template.
And as such, whatever the current value of primary will be, it will substitute right here in its place.
And that allows us to dynamically inject either a true or a false value right here on the right hand
side, which will dynamically determine whether the primary season class is applied and thus whether
these town styles appear on the component or not.
So now we can dynamically customize the CSS honor component based on the current value of data which
allows it to change and dynamically react.
Right.
That is the the beauty of a view is that we can connect data to UI so that when the data changes, so
does the UI and view takes care of that connection and that binding.
That's why it's called the V bind, because it connects data to UI and we're welcome to use it again,
either literally in a way like interpolation where we actually get the value to appear on the screen
or in a more symbolic sense where we connect it to our actual attributes like class or earlier in the
class we saw, for example, of the point is that we can dynamically bind to any vowed to attribute
so that its value is dynamically configured by whatever we specify in data.
All right.
So if I go back to my browser now, we're going to see that we're going to still have all of our styles.
The button styles are always going to be applied, and the primary class styles right here are going
to be applied because the primary data value is set to true, which means this class should be applied
by view, and we're going to see the exact same result as we've previously seen.
All right.
So that moves us one step closer to connecting our season class values to our data up data method and
our data object in our view component.
We're going to continue chipping away at this idea in the very next lesson.