Okay.
So here is a cool piece of news in our source directory in the components folder and in shared, we
have moved nearly every Vue component to be in TypeScript.
There's only one remaining.
And just to satisfy that little completionist side of me, let's take care of it in this lesson.
So let's target header container view.
And this component should be super simple because there's not even that much going on in this section.
Regardless, it's going to be the exact same process right here.
Lang equals to yes and I'm going to import define component.
Directly from view.
There we go.
Let's invoke it.
It's kind of redundant.
And I'm sort of starting to feel that pain of repetition now as a developer.
But the good news is we only technically have to do it once.
And as the component expands in the future, we don't have to do anything more.
This stays the same and this stays the same.
That's just something positive to think about in these moments of repetition.
All right.
And as always, let's update the test suite as well.
Had our container that test that genius which I'm going to change to have a test extension.
And as you can see, everything in that test folder now has a doctor's extension.
It looks like there are no issues to be found in this file.
Just make sure you have a dot view extension here in case everything in case anything doesn't work.
And here, of course, we'll do NPM.
Run, test, watch.
Now run.
Any tests that include the header container component in some way.
It looks like it's only our primary test file, which now has its extension and everything passes.
Great.
So that completes moving all of the components in the shared directory to be in TypeScript.
So one small accomplishment to celebrate.
And I will see you in the next lesson.