Okay.
So to kick this lesson off, I've opened up my job filter, sidebar component and also that test we
on the right hand side and as always, the goal of our refactor is to make our code a little bit easier
to work with.
So one of the reasons why these tests are pretty complex is because we're marking out three different
things, three different composable functions that we're utilizing right here in our setup method.
And of course, the reason all of these composable is exist is to provide one of these values right
here unique job types, unique organizations, unique degrees.
And you'll notice that the only reason they exist is to be passed down as props to their respective
checkbox group.
Unfortunately, when we render our full job filter sidebar, even though, for example, in this test
we want to only check that we're getting the checkbox group for filtering by job types, we do have
to provide our mocked up value for that use unique job types composable which makes sense.
However, all of this logic right here of mocking exists simply so that the set up method can run without
failure.
Even though this logic has nothing to do with what we're testing in here, it's simply a necessity of
wanting to test our very first checkbox group, which requires job types or to be more specific, our
second one.
But the same logic applies for every other test, right?
So right here, for example, we're running a test to check for organizations, which means we need
to provide a mock for use, unique organizations, our composable function, which returns a value that
we then pass down for our unique organizations right here.
But we also need to provide mock return values for these things so that our setup method can run it
correctly.
Right?
So basically, how can we simplify this?
How can we make this easier to understand and also simplify our test suite?
So here's what I propose.
I think that we can break up the logic in our setup method by having multiple smaller components.
And I propose that we create a separate component for job types, for organizations and for degrees.
Now, in a sense, this may be coming full circle because you may remember that originally we had three
separate components and then we tried to refactor them into our checkbox group component.
But the good news here is I think we can still keep our checkbox group component while still creating
three separate components one for job types, one for organizations and one for degrees.
And the responsibility of each one of those three components will be to simply render a checkbox group
and talk to the right composable functions to get the data that it needs in order to render this instantiation
right here.
So let me repeat that.
What I'd like to do, for example, is to create a new component, and that component will still use
the used unique degrees composable, and it will know the right mutation, but that components responsibility
will be just to render this checkbox group and provide it with the correct data.
That way, what we can do in that new component setup method is take the composable that we care about
one of these three and the mutation that we care about one of these three and simply isolate that in
that separate component.
And that way, when we test that component, we only need to mark out one composable, right?
And we don't need to worry about all the other components and then we can repeat the exact same logic
for the other two instantiation.
So in other words, create a second component to store this logic right here, the instantiation of
this checkbox group that needs its own unique job types, which comes from a composable that I will
mock out in that test.
But of course, for that component test, I won't need to worry about degrees and organizations.
And finally, in my third component, that third component will render this checkbox group and talk
to the composable that it needs in order to get the unique organizations.
And in that test, we will have to mock out that unis use unique organizations composable, but we won't
have to worry about the composable for job types and unique degrees.
So what we're basically doing is splitting up the logic of the set setup method across multiple set
of methods across three different view components.
So the whole story of kind of the refactor that we've been through, where we've come full circle is
we're trying to find the right balance of how much a component should know and how much it should do.
And ideally, if you have a small setup method and the component has a singular responsibility, the
simpler it will be to test and the simpler it will be to understand this job filter side of our component
does a lot, and that's why the setup method needs to talk to three separate composable functions because
it needs to gather data for three separate responsibilities, rendering the checkbox group for degrees,
the checkbox group for job types and for organizations.
And I think by breaking it up across three different components, we're going to get all the same benefits
and the same functionality, but making it much easier to test and reasonable.
All right.
So if that doesn't make false sense just yet, don't worry.
I hope it's going to become clearer as we actually do this implementation.
So let's make this a reality and you'll get a better sense of what I'm trying to do here.
So let's start with this degrees logic right here.
This section is what I want to extract to a brand new component.
So what I'm going to do is create a new component in my job filter sidebar directory, and I'm going
to call it job filter side.
R degrees.
All right.
I'm going to make that of you component and I'm going to drag it over to the right hand side.
And a lot of this logic is simply going to be copy and paste, and that is the good news.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to write my template tag and then what I'm going to
copy over is going to be this entire section right here, this job builder, sidebar, checkbox group.
So if we simply look at what we have right here on the right hand side, what does that tell us?
That tells us that this component needs to figure out how to provide to the template something called
unique degrees and something called ADD selected degrees.
Well, that logic all exists down here, and we simply have to extract the bits and pieces of this logic
that relate to our degrees.
So as always and right to begin by copying most of this logic right here, let's copy the script.
Lang and the defined component.
I'm going to put that right here.
And what else are we going to need?
We're going to need our job filters checkbox for component because we're entering it right here.
So let me do that and import that copy from the left.
Put it on the right.
All right.
Then what are we going to need to do?
We're going to need to export default.
And we're going to need to provide the instantiation of defined component passing in our configuration
object.
Before we forget, let's give it a name and this one will be called Job Filters Sidebar Degrees.
It's a component that is responsible for getting all the information we need to provide in order to
filter by degrees.
Then we're going to provide a component section because we are using a job filter, sidebar, checkbox,
group component up here in the template.
So we're going to provide that right here as well.
Now we're able to use it in our template.
And then of course, the other thing we need is to provide these names right here.
So I'm going to provide my setup method.
All right.
And what do we need to provide unique degrees as well as add selected degrees?
So what I'm going to copy from this file is going to be the import of add selected degrees.
So let me copy this entire import right here and let's put it right here.
And of course, the only one we care about right now is going to be add selected degrees.
So there we go.
That's going to take care of this thing.
And of course, the other function I'm going to need is use unique degrees, because that is going to
provide the unique degrees constant that I'm making available as well.
So let's find where use unique degrees is being imported right here.
So copy this logic over to here.
All right.
Except, of course, the only one we care about is use unique degrees.
So I'm just going to get rid of these first two.
All right.
Save that.
And then in our set up method, what are we going to do?
We're going to follow the exact same logic that we have right here.
So we're going to need to get our unique degrees.
So I'm going to copy this line 83 over.
So we're getting our unique degrees and then all we need to do is return an object here.
And we're going to provide unique degrees, which we have from our composable above.
And I'm also going to provide my constant add selected degrees.
All right, we're importing it above or making it available on this return object.
So now we have two properties that we're going to make available in our template unique degrees and
add selected degrees, which is exactly what this instantiation of checkbox group needs to work.
All right.
So hopefully this is starting to make sense as to how we've extracted one third basically of the setup
method to the smaller component that is just responsible for one checkbox group and gathering the data
from the composable that it needs to render this specific checkbox group right here.
All right.
So with that all, of course, we need to do is emulate a very similar process for the remaining two
checkbox groups.
And then we can replace this complex logic right here with these smaller components.
So once again, I'm going to create a new component, and this one is going to be called job filters,
sidebar, job type stock view.
All right.
So it's going to be very similar to what we just did.
We're going to practice this logic three times.
So right here, I'm going to provide a template tag and I'm going to copy over this checkbox group.
All right, so what is this checkbox group needs?
It needs its own set of names, unique job types and ads like the job tips.
So let's set that up.
So I'm going to copy this logic right here.
There's our script section.
Let's make sure we also close it off.
Let me in fact confirm that I closed that off right here as well.
We did not.
So let me make sure I add that script.
And right here.
There we go.
All right.
So now we have our script section.
We have defined component.
Let me immediately export default, the invocation of defined component passing in a name property.
And this one will be job filters, sidebar job types.
All right.
So what does this one need in order to run?
Well, it's also going to need the checkbox group, right?
Because we're rendering that right here.
So as always, let me copy this code from line 58, from the job filter, sidebar file.
Put that right here and right here under components.
I'm going to provide an object and make sure that this component can use a checkbox script.
The next thing I'm going to need is going to be a setup method.
And in here, I'm going to need to wire up an object that returns these two things.
So, of course, to get unique job types, that is the return value of using the use unique job types
composable.
So let me copy this line 81 over to here, which means we also need to import the specific composable.
So let me copy lines 60 through 70 here on the left, over to the right, and then we'll remove the
ones we don't care about.
So obviously we are going to need using these job types.
We don't need these two other composable.
And here, the one we're going to care about is going to be add selected job types.
So we're not going to need these three constants.
There we go.
And of course, for our return right here, same principle.
We're going to return an object.
We're going to make sure we have unique job types available right here and also provide the add selected
job types constant that we imported above.
There we go.
So now we have an object with two properties.
We're utilizing both of those properties right here.
And the checkbox strip component that we're rendering, we also are making available by importing it
right here and providing it under the components key.
All right.
So hopefully, once again, the second step has made it even clearer.
Well, now let's repeat the exact same logic for organizations.
So right here, a third new component called job filter sidebar.
Organizations that view once again.
I will provide a template tag once again inside the template tag.
I'm going to copy this checkbox group.
There we go.
Let me make sure I copy it correctly.
Pasted here.
All right, let's make sure we have an opening and closing script tag.
Let's make sure we add Lang equal that he has.
Here, I'm going to copy this import defined component syntax.
We're going to export default.
The invocation of defined component passing in an object.
The name of this component is going to be job filters, sidebar organizations.
We're going to need to import the component we're using above, which is the checkbox group.
So let me copy line 58 from the left, provide it right here.
And under the components key, I'm going to provide an object and then register the checkbox group.
Then we're going to need a setup method.
All right.
And what are we going to need to do in here?
We're going to need to rely on our use unique organizations, composable, as well as the ADD selected
organizations constant, which we're referencing right here on line four.
So once again, let me copy these ten lines and then remove the ones we don't care about.
So right here, I'm going to do that.
Okay.
So we care about use unique organizations.
That's going to be our composable.
And right here, we care about ADD selected organizations.
That's going to be our constant.
There we go in the set method.
I'm going to get my unique organizations by invoking the use unique organizations composable function.
And then I'm going to return that reactive object referenced by unique organizations as well as my ADD
selected organizations property or to be more specific, string constant.
There we go.
And that's what we're referencing right here.
All right.
So I think with that, things are looking pretty good.
Let me one more time double check.
That script is provided everywhere here.
So everything is looking pretty good.
Use unique degrees and add selected degrees.
Right here, it's using it job types.
Add selected job types.
Right here, it's using organizations and add selected organizations.
I think we also have a slightly different import order.
So let me move this logic a little bit above just to be consistent.
There we go.
So now we can actually incorporate these components into job filter sidebar.
And this is going to be a lot of fun.
So right here, let's begin by importing the components that we care about.
So our new components, we're going to have job filters, sidebar degrees, right?
And that is going to come from these source directory components, job results, job filters, sidebar
and finally, job filter, sidebar, degrees, dot view.
Next line is going to be import job filters, sidebar, job types, and that's going to come from the
same directory.
So source components, job results, job filter, sidebar, job filter, sidebar, job types.
There we go.
And our third one that we just created is job filters, sidebar organizations.
That's going to come from the source directory components, job results, jobs.
Other sidebar, job filters.
Sidebar organizations that deal.
There we go.
And now we need to register all of these components with our components right here.
So I'm going to do a job filter, sidebar, degrees and jobs, which the sidebar job types and jobs,
other sidebar organizations.
And now we can start the cleanup process throughout the component.
So we're no longer going to need any of these composable because we've moved their logic to the three
new components.
We're also not going to need three of these constants, which is which is the ADD selected constants.
We're still going to need to keep clear user jobs, which are selections.
So there we go.
And so we no longer are going to need a checkbox rule component because it's no longer going to exist
once we replace it.
Let's move that right here.
We're no longer going to be using these composable because we've moved each one of them to an individual
component on the right hand side, which means right here, we're no longer going to need these return
values from the composable.
And we're no longer going to need these constants right here.
So there we go.
So now we should get something super simple like this.
We only have a single thing we care about, which is clear user java filter selections.
All right.
And now all that's left to do is to remove this checkbox right here and replace all of our four former
components.
So right here, instead of all of this logic, I'm simply going to render my new component, which is
called job filters sidebar.
And this is going to be the sidebar degrees component.
It can be self-closing.
So basically what we're rendering here is this component right here, which knows all the logic for
which composable to use to get the degrees and which mutation name it needs to pass down to the checkbox
rule component right here.
We're going to replace this with a job filter, sidebar, job types, self-closing.
And right here, we're going to replace all of this with job, other sidebar organizations, self-closing.
All right, so things are looking pretty good.
We can see it definitely becomes a lot easier to read.
We sort of have this understanding that there's an accordion with a header, that it is rendering its
own component that's responsible for doing something with degrees, with job types and with organizations.
As I scroll down, it looks like everything is correct here.
We still need our accordion because we're using it.
We still need our action button because we're rendering it right here and we are keeping our setup method
now a lot cleaner.
We can immediately see the benefit because the setup method becomes a lot easier to understand.
Now all we're doing is talking to the store and wiring up a function to run as a click handler to commit
the mutation to clear selections.
But now all of that complex logic that was in here has now been spread across three different components.
So hopefully it makes sense how this makes our design a little bit simpler and we'll continue chipping
away at this in the very next lesson.