In this lesson, I'll show you how to bind our components data to our form input fields.
So let's open up our job search form component.
And here I'm going to scroll down all the way to the bottom where we have our configuration object for
the component.
And I'm going to use the familiar data method right here.
And as a reminder, the way this works is we return a plane JavaScript object and the object's properties
are available for us to use in the template and we can render them visually using interpolation.
We can use them in conditionals such as the VRF directive.
We can iterate over them with V for whatever we want to do.
The point is these data properties are available to be used in our template and I'd like to define two
properties, each of which is going to keep track of the user's entry for their desired role and their
desired location.
So for each input field, I'm going to create a corresponding data property to keep track of that user
input.
So I'll begin with role because the user will enter a role and I'm going to start this data property
off with an initial value of an empty string.
Then similarly, I'm going to have another data property called location, and that will also start
off as an empty string.
All right.
Now, what I'd like to do is to bind these properties to their respective inputs.
Now, whenever you hear the word bind or connect, the first directive that should come to mind is,
of course, the V bind directive, because the whole purpose of the V bind directive is to connect data
to our template so that when this changes, something else in our our template will update as well.
So I'm going to scroll up all the way to this input field right here.
This is our very first one for this role and the attribute that we can set on an input element that
will affect what is actually rendered within that input box is actually called the value attribute,
and that is not specifically tied to view.
That is just a general browser thing, that is something that exists on every input element.
We can provide it with a value attribute and give it a value that will render within the input.
So I of course want to attach myself to that value attribute.
Well, how can we bind or attach ourselves to this guy?
Attribute We have to use V bind so we can either use this syntax, which is the long form or the shortcut,
which is just placing a colon in front of value.
Then I provide my equals sign and the data property that I want to bind this value attribute to.
And I of course want to bind it to my role data property.
So to quickly remind us what is going to happen, this means that any time that role is going to change,
whenever that data property changes view is going to detect that change re render the template which
in turn will repopulate the value attribute to whatever is the current value in role, which will force
the input to display a different entered text.
Right.
And of course we're going to start off with our role equal to an empty string.
So there is going to be nothing in the input when the page first loads.
So if I scroll down we'll find our second input for the location, right.
And I want to do the exact same thing.
I still want to use the V bind directive.
I still want to attach myself to the same HTML attribute, which is the value attribute.
But the only difference is, is I want to bind this input to my other data property, which is location.
So as location changes, this input will render and will repopulate its value property with whatever
locations happens to be at that moment.
Okay, so with that, we can transition to our browser and see what is going on.
So let me transition to our browser and here I have my view dev tools open and you'll notice here is
our job search form component.
I'm going to click into it.
And of course we start out with these data properties being empty streets.
Well, let me try right here in my view, dev tools to edit one of these properties.
So I'm going to begin with role, which is our first input field right here.
And let's say I'm looking for a role of view developer.
So right here, I'm going to provide a string of view developer.
And as I save this change by clicking this diskette icon.
Notice how we're going to automatically populate that into our left input field.
So I'm going to save right now and there we go.
Our role has changed.
The role property that is view has we re rendered and now we're going to see that role entered automatically
within my input field.
Note that if we go to our element's inspector in Chrome, we're not going to see that value property
directly in line here in the element inspector.
So we only have type, placeholder and class.
We do not have value written, but the way we're going to see that it works is by seeing it written
right here in our template.
So let's try it one more time.
If I go to my view dev tools and I find my location property once again when I change this, we're going
to see the change reflected in our template.
So we have bound or connected our data property, our component data to our template.
So for example, let's say I'm looking for a job in Alaska.
I'm going to provide that string and save.
And there we go.
We have populated those changes in our template.
Now what we have right here is an example of one way data binding.
And I'd like to take a second to talk about why it's one way.
It's one way because it only goes in one direction.
What I mean by that is when our data changes, our template changes in response, right?
We just saw that.
However, it is not bidirectional.
It does not go in the other direction.
So what I mean by that is if I click into this template and I write something in here, like I'm going
to add a couple Z's right here, notice that changes with the template.
When I interact with a template as a user, those do not affect the original data property.
The data property is still equal to Alaska here.
So we have connected our data and our template are HTML, but only in one direction.
We can only change our data right now and see that change in our template.
We cannot change our template and see that change reflected in our data.
So going in the other direction.
And of course, when we're going in both directions, it's called bi directional because the word bi
means to like bicycle, right?
So we're only going in one direction.
And in the next lesson, we're going to show you how to establish a bi directional data flow where a
change in either location, either the template or our components data will reflect in the other half
of the equation.
All right.
So I'll show you how to do that in the very next lesson.