Okay.
So our sub nav component is looking really good in my opinion, but I argue that we can make it even
better.
So I'd like you to focus your eyes on these two lines right here.
Lines 28 and 29.
And I want you to think about what these lines would look like if we had to replicate them in another
component.
So imagine that we wanted to build another component that was going to conditionally render something
in the template based on the user being on another route like home, we have our home page which has
a route name of home.
Let's say we wanted another component that wanted to do something very similar to what we're doing here.
Use a VRF based on a reactive boolean value and render some template.
If we created that component, these two lines would look very, very similar.
In that component, we would need to import use route from view router because we would need to invoke
that to get access to our reactive route object.
We would still access the name property on that route object because that is not changing.
That is coming from view router.
The only thing that would change is we would compare the actual route that we care about.
So this string would be different, but we would still return it in a computed function so that we can
use it as a reactive value in our template.
That's the exact same practice we've been using right here.
Right.
So a lot of this logic, even though it's not that long, a lot of this logic is actually reusable.
And the cool part about Vue three is that the whole design aspect of the composition API is trying to
move a lot of logic outside of a component into simpler basic JavaScript functions.
So in this lesson, we're going to write one of those functions which are called in the view ecosystem
that called composable or composable functions.
A composable function is a plain JavaScript function that uses the reactivity aspects that Vue gives
us.
And we saw this a couple of sections ago when we were exploring functions like ref and computed in our
playground.
Yes.
File, we saw that we can use these pieces of functionality outside of any given component.
And the beautiful part of being able to do that and move the logic to functions is we have a lot of
these small, really lightweight plane JavaScript functions that are really easy to test, and then
we also gain the benefits of reusability.
We can reuse that logic in many components and really, really make a really slim set up method.
So as always, I think showing you an example will do a better job convincing you.
So let's create a new composable function.
Our first one and its whole responsibility will be talking to the root object and confirming whether
or not we are on a given route.
All right, so what I'm going to do is open up my file explorer.
And I'm going to collapse everything here and in my source directory, SIRC, I'll create a new folder
called Composable.
So this folder will house all of our composable JavaScript functions.
And here I'll create a file from my first function which I'll call use confirm route.
So our file will be called use confirm root access.
All right, so let me close this and drag this new file to the right.
And so let's start out with the basics.
So I'll define an arrow function in line and immediately export it out of this file.
So right here, I'll call my function.
Use confirm now.
And then right below it I will export default use conform route.
So this is a regular E6 arrow function.
So how do I want this composable function to work?
I want to isolate the elements that are the same from the elements that vary.
So again, if we were trying to re-use this logic in another component, the only thing the component
really cares about is the route that it wants to compare where the user is too.
So our sub nav component only wants to render specific things on the job results page.
So all he really cares about is saying this is the name of the route that I care about.
All this logic it really doesn't care about.
This is the reusable part.
So let's transfer all of this logic to our new use.
Confirm not function, but also give the function the ability to provide any route name that it wants.
So what I'm going to do is start out with the very first line here.
So if we want to use use route in our composable, well, you guessed it, we're going to need to import
it.
So import use route from view router and right here, how do I get access to my route object?
We invoke that function and we're going to get access to our route object.
And it's as simple as that.
We do not need to do this in the body of a component.
We do not need to do this in a setup method.
This is the beauty of three and the composition API is all of this reactivity can exist in plain JavaScript
functions.
So now we have access to the route object within the body of this function.
What do we want to do?
We want to use the exact same logic here.
We're going to use the computed function in order to get a reactive object that's going to track the
route, reactive objects, name property and compare it to something.
So because I need a little bit of dynamic content here, what job results is here, I am going to provide
a single parameter to my composable and it's going to be called the route name and this will be a string
representing the route that we want to compare ourselves to.
I'm also going to import computed.
And I'm going to get that from my view library.
And so right here, we're going to do exactly what we did and the component on the left.
I'm going to invoke computed.
And we know that that is going to take a function and it's going to rerun that function whenever whatever
its tracking changes.
In this case, what we're changing or tracking, rather what we're tracking the change of is the route
object.
More specifically, it's name property.
So whenever the name property changes computed will rerun this function.
And what we want to do is return the latest boolean representing if the root objects current name property
is equal to whatever root name string I provide to this composable function.
All right.
Now, by itself, this is great.
And this is very similar to what a component is doing.
However, remember that used confirmed root is not actually returning anything.
So what I'm going to do is return the return value of the computed function.
Remember, we saw this a couple of seconds ago that what the computed function returns back to us is
its own reactive object with its own value property.
And that value property in this case will be a boolean, either true or false if the given condition
is met.
But now we're simply going to determine that true or false, based on whatever root name we get passed
into this composable function, wherever it's used.
And the beautiful part about this approach is different components can re utilize this use confirmed
root function but pass in a different route, name in different components and yet get the benefits
of all of this repeated logic isolated to just one function.
One composable function in the code base.
So let me show you how this is going to work in our sub now.
Let's use it immediately right here.
What I'm going to do is to import our new composable function.
It is called use confirm root.
It's a default export.
So we do not need curly braces.
We're going to get that from our source directory.
The composable folder and our file is used.
Confirm now.
So now we imported this function right here.
Let's use it in line here, in place of our former implementation.
So I'm going to comment out lines 30 and 31.
We no longer need this, but remember, we still need our object to return something called on job results
page because that's what we're using right here.
So I'm still going to use the cost of on job results page, which formerly was a computed object or
computed reactive object.
Right.
That's what we assigned right here.
Well, how can we get the exact same computed object?
We can get it as the return value of use confirm route.
So I'm going to invoke use confirmed route right here.
And we need to provide a parameter representing the route name that we want to compare to.
And what that what is that?
In our scenario?
You guessed it.
It's just going to be our job results string.
So you might be thinking.
But Boris, we had two lines and now we have one.
Is that really that much of a benefit?
Well, I argue it absolutely is a benefit because there's actually a couple of things that we've gained
from this approach besides just last lines.
We have now isolated the logic of talking to the root.
Specifically its name property and that likely reusable logic to its own function.
Now any component in our app can reuse, use, confirm route and simply give it a string without having
to know the internal details of how use root works, without having to worry about the name property,
without having to duplicate this logic in every single component.
That's one benefit we've gained.
Another benefit we've gained is that this use confirmed root function, as we'll see in a in a follow
up lesson, is actually going to be pretty simple to test because it's nice and lightweight.
All right.
So in here, we can remove these two lines.
We no longer need them.
So our set up method gets even smaller and we no longer need to import use root because our use confirm
root function will take care of that import and that usage of the root.
So there we go.
Now we've super simplified our setup method.
And if I save this, if you go checking the browser, everything will still work just fine.
And if we run our whole test suite.
We'll see.
Everything will work just as well.
And the reason that everything is going to work just as well is because in a way, we haven't even really
changed the implementation.
Instead, we've simply isolated what what we were previously doing exclusively here to a reusable use
confirming our function, but still using the same logic.
It's still using use route and it's still giving us a computed object, which we're then returning right
here, a reactive object with a value property.
We're still returning fundamentally the same object here for our template use, but we're getting it
from a helper function.
And so now we've extracted and isolated the thing that varies or isolated, the thing that is the same
right here, while allowing each individual component that wants to reuse the use confirmed and composable
to specify its own string that it cares about.
The only thing that have cares about is comparing job results.
The rest of this logic is reusable and repeatable, so we do not want to duplicate it in any other component
that wants to have the exact same logic.
All right.
So hopefully this is giving you a better sense of what composable is allow us to do and how they work
really well.
They're basically going to be playing JavaScript functions that allow us to use use reactive ideas,
whether it be the reactive store from view, the reactive route, the reactive router, or even our
own reactive objects.
We're going to be able to isolate small bits of logic into small helper functions and then reuse them
across multiple components, which again moves more logic out of the components and lets the components
be as dumb as possible.
So they're just getting data from somewhere and simply rendering it in the template.
Whenever you have those kinds of components.
They become easier to read.
They become shorter.
They become easier to test.
And they are just focused on their primary responsibility, which is just rendering a bunch of HTML
to the screen.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.