In this lesson, I want to do a quick review of the map method on a JavaScript array.
If you're comfortable with map, feel free to skip this lesson.
Otherwise, stick around because we're going to be using this method in the next lesson on testing.
So I'm going to open up my playground digest file.
As a reminder, this file is just a little bit of a scratch pad for us to play around with JavaScript
and view concepts outside of our project.
What I'm going to begin with here is declaring an array of numbers.
I'm going to call it const numbers, and I'm going to provide it with five elements one, two, three,
four, five.
And here's what I want to do.
I'd like to create a new array consisting of the squares of these numbers.
So I want to multiply each number by itself.
So what I need to do here is apply the same operation to every single element within an array and then
return those results in a brand new array.
So of course, the old school way to do this is to use a four loop and iterate over every element.
Do some kind of calculation and then push the result into a brand new array.
The map method offers us a really convenient way to do this in a single line.
So right here I'm going to declare a new constant called squares, and I know that I need to form my
squares array from my starter numbers.
Right.
And then in order to iterate over every element, two numbers and then return the result of some kind
of operation in a new array.
I'm going to use the map method.
The map method accepts a function as the argument, and that function is going to specify what to do
with every single individual element.
So right here, I'm going to provide a inline arrow function and I'm going to be iterating over each
number one at a time.
So right here I'm going to put the singular number.
So a number is going to represent one on the first loop, then two, then three, then four and five.
And from the body of this function, I specify what I want to return for that position in our brand
new array.
So if I want to return the square of each number that I iterate over, I can return number times number,
save this.
And so I'm going to iterate over every number one at a time, take it square and return it.
And then JavaScript is going to take those five return values and store them in a new array called squares.
So if I output squares below and then I run this file using node inside our source directory, there
is our playground dot just filed.
We're going to get the squares array 149, 16, 25 and of course we can simplify the syntax as long
as we get a or as long as we provide rather a function inside the map method.
Any syntax here will work.
So for example, you may know that we can use an implicit return in a one line arrow function.
So for example, I can return number by number automatically.
Just like.
So I'm going to remove the return keyword, remove the curly braces around my function body.
And this syntax is valid whenever we have a one line evaluation and we want to implicitly return a calculation.
So this will give us the exact same result.
I can prove that by rerunning the file.
Totally valid.
And then if you also know in arrow functions that if you only have one parameter in this case we do
have only one parameter.
We do not need the extra parameters around it.
So I can actually write a function like this.
Just a number followed by my pointer sign the arrow sign.
It looks like it looks like my prettier is actually auto correcting me.
But this is totally valid syntax.
It's just that when I save the file, prettier is returning it back to its preferred approach.
But this is also valid JavaScript code.
The point is that we're feeding a function to map.
Map is running that function for every single element and then taking all of those return values and
packaging them up in a brand new array called squares.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see in the next one.