Okay.
So let's continue building out an individual job listing.
So within my router link as a direct sibling of my first div, I'm going to create another div.
So right here I'll add my second div and I'll give it a couple of classes to start.
Let me scroll down in fact, so you can see it.
Let's add a couple classes for padding.
So I will do P eight add padding on the x axis.
That's going to be 32 pixels of padding on the left and 32 pixels of padding on the right.
I'm going to add a padding on the top and bottom as well, but a little bit less so I will use the p
y or padding y axis classes and will do p four to add 16 pixels of padding on the top and 16 pixels
of padding on the bottom.
Okay.
Inside this div, we're going to have two more divs to let me write them out right here.
And my first div is going to store information about the qualifications of the job so the requirements
the user has to have in order to apply.
So in this div, I'll create an H3 and, and here we can put the static text qualifications.
And let's apply a couple of styles to this age three as well.
I'm going to add a little bit of margin on the top with the empty or margin top class, we're going
to do empty one four, four pixels of margin on the top and on the bottom.
We'll do a little bit more margin margin, bottom two to add eight pixels of margin on the bottom there.
All right.
Directly below the H3, create a new div and then here I'll create another unordered list.
This unordered list will store a bunch of allies for the actual job requirements and these will be basic
bullet points.
So on this well, I can add a couple of classes.
Let's add a little bit of padding on the left with plate.
And then what I also want is for my list items to actually have those bullet point icons to the left,
those black circles, and we can do that using the list desc class from Tailwind.
You can see what it does is it adds that class attribute list style type and set that the disk and that
is what is going to give us that those black circles or bullet points to the left of each list item.
So let's add three sample list items here.
Let's start with our first one.
This is just going to be arbitrary text that I took from the official website.
You can feel free to substitute whatever you'd like in here, but let's begin with bachelor's degree
or equivalent practical experience.
Let me copy this list item twice down and then we'll replace the content.
So for my second list item, let's write five years of experience in program management.
And for our third bullet, it's going to be a little lengthier.
Let's do this experience analyzing data.
Through querying IT database.
And then there is a little section here e.g. which means including sequel using spreadsheet software
and creating statistical models.
Again, you don't have to copy this word for word.
We just need some placeholder text for a sample jobless thing.
But this is a good amount of text and resembles the real world.
Okay, so for our second div here, what this is going to store is a link that says expand and that
link is going to lead to the job page for this job.
It's actually a very curious design because we already have a router link that is wrapping the entire
box.
So any, any place that you click in the box will take you to the same job page.
But for some reason, they set up a separate link for the box at the very bottom, and that has the
word expand.
So that's what we're going to emulate here.
So right here, I will add a class here, I will add a class of M2 to add some margin on the top, and
I will center the text in this div by doing text center.
Right after that inside the div, I want to put another router link component because we are making
a link to navigate to another route.
And for the two prop of this router link, we can copy exactly what we have right here since it is leading
to the exact page.
Again, it's a router link nested within a router link, but that's exactly how they built it out in
the real world as well.
So we're going to have a two prop here.
Our text in between is going to be the word expand.
The idea, I guess, being that you can expand this job listing to see all of its full details.
But what that really entails is navigating the user to the individual individual job page, and that
text is going to be in our brand blue color.
So I can add a single tailwind class right here.
And that is going to be text brand blue one.
Again, that color is coming from our tailwind config file.
Okay.
So we added this top div that is storing these two elements.
One is going to be the qualifications, one is going to be a router link with the text expand.
And let's take a look at what this looks like right now in our browser.
So I will navigate here and that is looking pretty good.
This is a sample job listing.
You can see the box shadow, you can see the qualifications bullet points, you can see the expand text.
You'll notice that if I click on either the entire job listing, it's going to take us to slash jobs,
slash result, slash one.
And also, if I click on the actual expand button, that's also going to take us to the exact same job
page.
So this is an example of a single job listing.
It's looking pretty good to me.
And obviously what we're going to move towards in the future is having a whole bunch of these that we're
actually going to dynamically populate using data from an API.
But this is a good place to start to just start building out the look and feel and the aesthetics of
a single job listing on our job results page.
So more on this in the next lesson.