Okay.
So this should be a quick and fun lesson on the left hand side here I have my accordion component and
on the right hand side I have the test suite for the accordion.
Now the accordion test suite doesn't have that many tests.
It only has, I believe, two.
The first one is just testing for the rendering of the slotted content and the second one is testing
for the rendering of the slot and content when the parent does not provide anything.
But there are still other tests in our test suite that are also utilizing the accordion.
So for example, as a reminder, we have our job filter, sidebar, job types, component, and here
we are rendering all of our content in this component inside an accordion component because this becomes
the slot content.
And in our actual tests for this component, we're using a full mount.
So we are rendering an accordion there as well.
So there are multiple test suites throughout our code base where we are using an accordion component
and now we've completely refactored our accordion to use the new composition API implementation.
But here is the good news.
I think both because of our good test suite as well as because of the relative similarity between how
composition API works relative to Options API and all of the analogous things that it gives us to work
with.
We'll be happy to find out that when we run our whole test suite using NPM Run Test Colon Unit, we're
going to discover a most wonderful surprise.
And I'll tell you what it is in exactly a couple seconds and you guessed it, it is that everything
is still passing.
So in other words, nothing we did over the course of the last couple lessons now no part of our refactor
broke our tests.
All of our tests are working exactly as expected.
So the good news is, is even with the composition API, our core test logic remains the same.
We're still mounting the component here or there.
We're testing some pieces of it, some interaction with it.
And by focusing less on the specific implementation and more about what the component is supposed to
do, we could get into really good situations like this where nothing breaks.
If we test what the components should do instead of how it does it, we're going to have a lot more
of these flexible tests that are not brittle, that do not break whenever we make what I consider to
be pretty drastic changes, right?
We implemented a whole new way of doing things here, a brand new API, and yet everything stayed stable,
stable.
And so that is a really good sign and a really good, you know, vote of confidence for the test suites
that we have, in my opinion.
All right.
So kind of a nice pick me up lesson to celebrate with and I will see you in the next lesson.