Okay.
So the next thing that I'd like to do is to show the user the page that they are on.
So page one, page two, page three, etc., I want to display that number at the very bottom of all
their job results.
Later on, I also want to add the buttons to take them to the next page or the previous page.
So if I look in my job listings component and I look at my displayed jobs property, we actually have
the page number right here.
These first two lines get what we need.
They talk to the root object to get the query object to get the page property and a reasonable default.
And then they convert that string to a number.
And that is the page we want.
Page one, page two, etc..
So we could of course, copy and paste this logic into a different property.
But I propose that we move this logic entirely to a new computed property and then reuse that property
right here.
And that way we can have a lot of smaller computed properties, each one with this single responsibility.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to cut this code and right here above displayed jobs are create
another computed property called the current page.
Since that is what we want.
And I'm going to paste this code right here.
And of course, instead of saving this final result to a page number constant, I'm just going return
number, send paging, passing in the page string.
It's still a computed property because it's some kind of number that is based on another piece of data
in our application, which is our root object.
So as our root object changes, the query object and its page property will change.
The current page computed property will reevaluate every time that changes and give us back a number.
So right here in displayed jobs, I want to reference my page number because I need it right here for
these calculations of my job in the indexes.
So in order to get my page number, what I can do, of course, is reference the computed property above,
which I can simply do by referencing it on my this object.
So right here, this that current page, even though it is a method above in view, we do not need to
provide parentheses.
We can just reference that property like.
So this that current page will give me this full evaluation.
The reason I'm seeing an error here is of course I need a comma right here, but that should do it.
So now we're going to reference whatever page number we get from the computed property above.
That's some kind of number.
We're going to use that number to generate our first and last job indexes, and then we're going to
use that to slice a subset of the array.
So now that I have a computed property that just gives me the page number, I can use this computed
property in my template.
I can interpolate this value to show the user the actual page number.
So I'm going to scroll up a little bit here and here is where we have our ordered list with our job
listing components.
Below my ordered list, I'm going to create a new div and here I'm just going to add a couple tailwind
classes.
I want to create some separation between this and the end of my job list, so I'm going to add some
margin on the top.
I'm going to do empty eight margin top eight to give 32 pixels of margin above this divide.
And then I'm going to provide Amex Auto to provide equal margin on the left and right side to center
this box within this div.
I'm going to add another div and I'm going to add some more classes to here.
I'm going to make this a Flexbox.
This Flexbox will eventually hold not just my page number, but also my buttons for the previous page
and the next page.
We're going to add that in upcoming lessons, but we're going to create the Flexbox container for that
right now.
So this is going to be a Flexbox that's going to arrange its elements in a row direction.
So I'll add flex row and I don't want them to wrap to a new line.
I want this all on a single line.
So I'm going to do flex no wrap.
That is my final class right here.
So three total classes on this div.
And finally within this div, I can provide a paragraph tag where I'm going to actually interpolate
the value of my current page in just a second.
So paragraph tag, let's add a couple classes here on this paragraph.
The first one is going to be text some.
That's just going to give my font here a slightly smaller size of 14 pixels.
And then I'm going to add a class here, a flex grow that's just going to allow this paragraph to grow
in size as needed depending on what's available in the flex box with within which it is located.
And so here I want to actually display the word page no matter what.
And then after page I want the number itself.
We get that from our current page computed property so we know how to interpolate.
We have to use the double curly braces and I want to display the value of the current page, which we're
going to get from our query params.
And if we don't have any query params, not a problem, we're going to fall back to page one.
All right.
So with that, we can go to our browser and take a look at this.
So here we are on page one with no create params.
If I scroll down, we're going to get page one.
That looks great.
If I apply the manual query params of page equals one, we get the exact same result.
However, if I navigate to something different like page four perfect, we get our different set of
ten jobs and now we see page four right here.
Similarly, if I go to page six, totally different set of jobs and we see page six right here.
So that looks really great.
And of course the next thing we can start wiring up is our next and previous buttons right here on the
right.