Okay.
So as I mentioned in a previous lesson, we can combine the dynamic router view component along with
some static constant content that will appear from page to page.
So a perfect, constant piece of content is our main NAV.
The user is going to see that on any route, on any view.
So what we want to do is always render the main NAV and then below it use our router view component
so it will dynamically render the custom view that that page requires, but below the consistent main
nav component.
So let's make that happen.
The first thing I need to do is I need to import my main nav component because it is not global.
So I'm going to import May NAV and we can find it in our components directory.
In the navigation folder there is my main nav component.
I need to register it with my components object.
So right here.
Main now.
And then what we can do is since our main nav will have the eventual links to navigate from page to
page, we can remove this code from the previous lesson.
We don't need these root or links.
Eventually we will add them to our May nav where we have that menu with all of the different pages.
But we don't need this code right here.
And so what I can do is render main nav right here, like so self-closing.
And generally some people consider it a best practice to have a single route element within any given
view component.
So just to enclose these two in a single parent element, I'm going to have them wrapped within a div.
So like so.
All right.
So with that, we are looking good.
We have our main NAV always being rendered no matter what, and then our router view immediately below.
The main nav will render the dynamic content.
So let's see it in the browser.
So navigating back here we go.
We start out with our job results page and here we have our main nav and there we have our subnet below
it and it is always being rendered.
And then here is where the router view component takes over and renders the dynamic result.
Let's see if I can show you that in our view Dev Tools app, it looks like I am getting pretty buggy
results throughout the entire page, or at least not refreshing.
But here we go.
So we have a router view component here and there is the job results view component that it renders.
And then I have no way anymore of navigating to my home roots.
I'm just going to go there manually in my browser tab and you'll notice right now.
That we are still rendering the May NAV, which we are always rendering in our main nav component.
And then immediately below that we are rendering our home view and that is exactly what we want.
Obviously in our home view we want to bring back the old code we had, which is the actual form and
the headline, and we will do that shortly.
But the key takeaway here is now we're able to navigate to different URLs and keep something that is
constant and also dynamically change, something that is different from view to view.
And that is all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.