All right.
So in this lesson will introduce a new feature, a view router called lazy loading.
But before we get there, I'd like to introduce you to the problem that lazy loading is trying to solve.
So what I'd like to do here in Chrome is to open up my developer tools.
And the way you can access this panel, of course, is by clicking this little icon here.
It's the little hamburger, three dots.
And then here you can go to more tools and developer tools.
And this, of course, is where we have things like the elements, inspector and the console, etc..
So here there is a tab called Network.
And the cool thing about the network tab is you can see all of the files that your browser receives
and loads as the page renders.
So what I'm going to do is refresh my homepage and we're going to see a whole bunch of files show up.
And the one that I'd like you to focus on is this app gorgeous file.
So this is actually the JavaScript code that holds our entire view app.
It holds all of the code for view as well as the component code for our homepage and our job results
page and our individual job page, etc. And I can prove this to you if I go to this preview tab.
We're going to have this weird collection of JavaScript, and this is all what Web Pack creates for
us whenever it takes our view code, which the browser does not understand.
When Webpack takes that code and converts it into HTML, CSS and JavaScript that the browser can understand,
it ends up looking like this file.
So it's not important for us to understand what all of these lines mean.
However, I can search in this file using command F and I can search for something to prove that we're
loading every component in this file.
So for example, here on this page we have this text Find your next job at Bobo Corp.
So I'm just going to look for the text.
Find your next job.
We're going to see there is a match.
And if I scroll to the right here, you can see somewhere in that JavaScript source code we do have
that text.
And similarly if I go to my job page for example, and there is this job results view header, if I
search for job results view once again, we're going to find a match and here it is.
So somewhere deep in this big chunk of JavaScript, we have all of our components and their logic nestled
together.
So what are the advantages and disadvantages of this approach?
Well, because we are putting everything together into one file, obviously the size of the file increases.
It has to store all the logic for all components.
Right?
The advantage is that the user gets everything at once, but the file size can make the file much larger
and the user may be much slower to receive it, especially if they are on a mobile connection or a slow
internet connection.
So for that reason, we always want to generally keep our file sizes as small as possible, given what
the user needs to use.
So here's a potential proposal for what we could do to shrink this file size down significantly.
What if we only load the JavaScript that the user needed for a given page?
So for example, when the user would load the front page, we would give them the code for view and
any components that they need to see right here.
And we would not yet give them the code for the job results page.
However, when the user would navigate to that page, we would send them a smaller JavaScript file that
would include the code that is needed to render this component.
And we would apply the exact same logic for the individual job page.
We would just give them the JavaScript for that page.
Well, this feature is called Lazy Loading and its name is kind of funny, but it actually makes sense
because if you think about what it means to be lazy, if you think about your lazy friends, for example,
to be lazy means you don't want to do any work until it's absolutely necessary.
Right.
And it's sort of how our loading logic here works.
We're going to tell you, don't load anything until it's absolutely critical to have it in order to
give the user what they want.
So again, on the front page, the user doesn't need the job's results page.
They don't need that code.
They don't need that HTML or that system or the JavaScript.
So we're not going to load it.
It's only when we absolutely must fetch it in order for the user to see their view.
Will we load that content?
That is what lazy loading is.
It waits until the last second possible to load the content that the user needs to see.
And of course the advantage is much smaller files and distributed over time.
And if the user doesn't visit this page, then we never give them this file.
And so the total amount of content they have to download ends up being smaller.
We don't need to give them the whole app, we just give them small bits of JavaScript as they navigate
to relevant components and relevant pages.
So it's kind of optimized to scale to whatever they actually need it to see.
All right.
So let me show you how we can implement this feature in the editor, and then we'll come back and see
how it affects our network tab.
So what I'd like to do is head back to this code and here I have my router file open router slash index
notch.
Yes.
And here's what we're going to do.
It's actually going to be kind of cool and.
Interesting.
It's not going to require a lot of code.
So what I'm going to do is comment out my imports right here.
And instead of importing those components, I'm going to create constants to represent those components.
And each constant is going to have the same name as a view, and I'm going to set each constant equal
to an arrow function.
So what I mean by that is I'll have a concept called home view, and home view will be an arrow function.
So right here, arrow function.
And we can we can of course, right our code like this.
But we also know that in iOS six we can provide implicit imports or implicit return values simply by
putting a value here.
So whatever I want this arrow function to return, I can simply write in line here without curly braces.
And what I'm actually going to put is the import keyword from JavaScript, and then I'm going to invoke
the import keyword and I'm going to provide the name of my file.
So in this case, I'm going to copy this string right here and place it like so.
So what have I done here?
I have created a function that uses the import function to load a component in, but because it is a
function, it's a block of logic that is not yet executed.
Right?
A function is like a recipe.
It's a repeatable procedure, but it doesn't mean that it has run yet.
I've just wired up some logic that can run at a point in the future when that function is invoked.
All right, so let's do this exact same logic for our other two views.
So below I'll create a job results view constant.
I will set it equal to a function and that functions responsibility will be to import a component and
return that component implicitly.
So once again, we can invoke the import function and what we do is we give it a string argument representing
the file or the view component that we would like to import.
So I'm going to copy this code right here and put it right here and then repeat the exact same logic
for our job view.
So constant job u is a constant that is going to point to an arrow function and that arrow function
is going to invoke the import function from JavaScript, same one we use here, but a different syntax
and we're going to provide the location of the file that we want to import.
Now, with all of this code written out, we can remove our former imports.
And now what we have is three functions, each of which important component.
Well, as it turns out, that's all we need to do in this file because view and it's router configuration
is going to understand the now component is not just equal to an actual view component, it is equal
to a function that loads a component.
And that is all we need to do because view is going to say, okay, you're giving me a function.
What I'm going to do is wait until the user accesses that path, that root, and only when they access
that root will I actually load the corresponding function.
Or in other words, will I invoke that function to import that component to generate a corresponding
JavaScript file and then give it to the user?
So now what's going to happen in our browser is when we go to the root, root we're only going to activate
this root.
So what viewers going to do is just import the home view component, figure out the corresponding JavaScript
in its own file, and just give us that file and that section of the app.
These two are not going to be imported until we actually navigate to those respective paths.
So let's take a look at this in our browser.
I'm going to navigate back and it's going to go to our home page and let me.
Bring this up and refresh so we can see.
So let's refresh.
Wait a second.
And here we go.
So we're actually going to get to JavaScript files.
We're still going to have app tags.
And what that is, is the core view app itself.
So the common view logic, the common view JavaScript code that we need irrespective of component,
that's what this file is going to include, right?
It's no longer going to include everything else, but you'll notice there is now a secondary JavaScript
file here and it's called Source View's Home View View Dogs.
So this is now the JavaScript file that holds the logic for all the components that this view needs
to render.
And again, I can prove this by going into a preview tab and looking for some sample text like Find
your next job and there you can find it here.
Right here is where the text is in our JavaScript and here is where it is in our page.
But most importantly, we have not yet loaded the view components for the job results page or the individual
job page.
So let me clear this output right here.
I'm going to click this little icon here to wipe that content clean, and now I'm going to navigate
to the jobs page.
So notice what's going to happen is Vue is going to give us a brand new Jaz file.
This one is called Source View's Job Results View.
So what it's done is it's now invoke that function that we configured in the router file to load in
that component and all of its dependencies as well because it is a tree of hierarchy, right, all the
child components, etc. It's going to load those in, it's going to package those up in a brand new
JavaScript file and then give that to us.
So this is the code that enables our job results page to work the way it does.
Now, the cool thing here is if I go back to my main page, we don't need to have a fresh file generated
because we already have that code from the very first time that we access this page.
This feature is called caching, and what caching basically means is the browser says I have the JavaScript,
I need to render this page so I don't need to make a fresh request to the server to get the original
JavaScript file.
Same deal.
If I go back to my job results view, you're going to notice we don't reload this file because we already
have it.
So that is a smart part of view because it's never going to request more than it needs.
Right?
And again, the advantages, if I start out on this page and don't do anything on this website and leave,
I can give the user a smaller file to just load this content without having to load the job page content
until the user actually requests it.
So we've split up a huge file from the beginning into lots of smaller files at the user, just gets
sequentially if they need them.
That is what lazy loading is.
It means waiting until the very last moment to load the required imports.
It's lazy because just like a real person who's lazy, it doesn't want to do any work unless it absolutely
has.
Right.
And again, the way we can figure out, going back to our editor is we create arrow functions for our
components.
And the arrow function uses the import keyword to specify the component that it wants to import.
And typically what you're going to see here is the component it's going to import is going to be a view
component.
And when I use the word view, I'm not talking about the library, I'm talking about the page level
component because that's where it makes sense, right?
It makes sense to to dynamically load JavaScript file for a page as the user accesses that page.
And Vue will take care of the responsibility of understanding everything in that child hierarchy that
it needs to bundle up and give to the user so they see the page render.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
In the very next lesson, we'll see how we can customize a little bit of this lazy load import logic,
but that is the core crux of the content.
So I will see you there.