In this lesson, I'd like to give you one more example of the reactive function in use.
I'd like to show you how it works with objects with multiple properties, but will discover, of course,
is that Vue makes every one of those object properties reactive.
So if we reference them in the computed function and then we change the value of those original properties,
any change will force the computed function to rerun.
So let's begin by removing RF function.
We're actually not using it anywhere in this file anymore, and I'm going to expand my person objects
slightly.
Instead of having a single name property, I'm going to have both a first name and a last name property.
And you can, of course, feel free to replace my name with your name.
So I'm going to change this to first name and then I'm going to add a new property called Last Name
and provide my last name.
There we go.
And so here in my title Constant, which is the return value of the computed function, I can no longer
reference person name, but I can reference person dot, first name and person that last name.
And what I'm going to do here to avoid concatenation with the plus sign is just use S six template strings.
So what I'm going to do is use the little tilde or tick, whatever you call it right here.
And then I'm going to interpolate the value of person dot first name in here.
This is all traditional JavaScript s syntax and afterwards I'm going to write a space as well as person
dot last name and then the great and then make sure to close it off with the little tilde or whatever
you call it, the little tick as they taught me in bootcamp right here.
So we have referencing the value of first name followed by a space and the last name and then the great.
And another thing worth noting here that I forgot to mention, the previous lesson is title is going
to be a reactive object, a regular reactive object, the exact kind that you might expect from the
ref function.
So we still need to reference value on the title constant.
Right here it is.
It is a requirement here.
Right?
We do not need to reference value whenever we are dealing with anything on person.
Right.
So right here, what I can do is change the value of person.
That first name.
I could change that to Peter for example.
And of course when we run this file, we'll see that we're going to start out with start out with Boris
pass over her the great and then transition to Peter passed through the great.
But every single property on a person object is reactive.
So here is an example of first thing and of course if I change last name, so I'll change last name
to something like Griffin and once again I will output the value of title value.
We'll see that because the computed function is tracking the object and any of the properties that are
referenced here.
If any of them change, then the computed function will rerun the arrow function.
Then we pass it and get the new value of title.
So now if I output title value afterwards, we'll see.
We've changed that once again to Peter Griffin the great right.
So every single property here now has the ability to be reactive and thus anywhere where we reference
those properties, the computed function will reevaluate, right?
If we only reference one such as person dot first name, then the computed function will rerun whenever
first name changes.
Right.
But in this case we reference both.
So view is keeping track of both of these properties and their state.
And as soon as either one of them changes, it's going to rerun this function.
It doesn't have to be both changing at the same time.
It can be just one.
And we demonstrated that with these examples where we changed the first name properties and the last
thing properties one at a time.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.