Okay.
So the next topic that I want to cover is declaring types for objects.
So let's say I have an object, call the plumber and I'll assign it three properties.
I'm going to have a name property set tomorrow, a skill, a property set to jumping and a likes mushrooms.
Property is set to true.
And so how do we assign a type to an object?
The exact same way we assign a type to any type in TypeScript.
We put a colon after the constant and then we describe what it is.
Now there is a general object type, so I'm going to write it out.
But this is not recommended because it is not as specific as we can be.
And whenever we're not as specific as we can be, we lose many of the benefits of TypeScript.
So an object is a general object in JavaScript which applies to, yes, this kind of data structure
with key value pairs, but it also applies to things like arrays, functions, custom objects that we
make from our own custom classes, etc..
So in other words, this is an okay category, but it's way far away from being as descriptive and as
explicit as we can be.
This is not just a collection of key value pairs.
This specifically is a collection of three key value pairs.
Right?
That's one specific detail.
In addition, those three key values or those three properties specifically are name skill and likes
mushrooms.
And finally, we can also get even more granular and tell TypeScript we have a name property set to
a string, we have a skill property set to a string and we have a likes mushrooms property set to a
boolean.
And all of those details are way more specific than this generic kind of parent parent category of object.
So let me show you how type typescript is going to infer the type of this object.
If I remove this annotation, I'm going to remove that and hover my mouse over my constant.
And you can see right here that this is how TypeScript is going to infer the type of my object based
on what I've given it on the right hand side.
So it's not just a generic object in the sense of a generic collection of key value pairs.
It's a specific annotation of three key value pairs names at a string skill set the string and let's
mushroom set to a boolean, right?
And we're going to reap all the benefits of having a more specific declaration or in this case, inference
like so compared to a generic one like object.
So for example, if I try to access a property on plumber that does not exist, for example, I'm a
confused name and think it's actually first name.
And of course, when I write this out, TypeScript is going to say, Hey, property first name does
not exist on the type of object you've given me right here that only has name properties.
String properties are a name property, a scale property and a likes mushrooms property.
There's nothing there called first name, but it goes even further.
Beyond that.
Let's say I access my likes, mushrooms, property, and that's a totally valid reference.
But let's say I as a developer make a mistake and assume that this is a string.
And let's say I want to uppercase it by invoking the two uppercase method.
So if I invoke two uppercase right here, once again, TypeScript is going to give me an error.
It's going to say, Hey, I know on the plumber object that likes mushrooms is a boolean and a boolean
does not have a to uppercase method.
So the error is going to say property to uppercase does not exist and type boolean.
And that's where TypeScript really shines.
As I mentioned earlier, it's kind of hard to see when we're annotating something basic like a string,
but when we have objects with other objects, with arrays with their own objects, and let's say that's
the return value of a function, etc., it's really easy as a developer to lose track of all those relationships
or have a typo or remember incorrectly the name of a property, or try to invoke a method that doesn't
exist or access the property it doesn't exist.
And this is where touch really shines.
It understands what the types are, and thus it understands what you can do with them.
And I'll show you warnings like this one right here.
All right.
So with that said, inference is totally fine and it saves us, obviously, a lot of typing.
But just to show you how we would explicitly manually declare our type for this object, what we can
do is provide a colon here as always.
And then instead of the word object, what we provide is curly braces.
And then we describe the shape of the object that we're about to assign.
Right?
So more specifically than just a general generic object, which doesn't tell us everything, it's an
object with three properties with their own data types, and that's all we have to declare in here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is declare a name property followed by a colon, and then it's type
which is going to be string.
Now you'll notice when I simply have this, typescript is already going to raise an error.
And why is that the case?
Well, because we've told TypeScript that plumber should be an object with only a name property.
And that name property set a string.
So type typescript says, yeah, of course I've gotten the name property, such a string.
But what are these two extra properties of scale and likes mushrooms?
You haven't told me to expect those, so I'm going to tell you that that is a mismatch.
So if I have read my mouse over this, you can see it's going to say the type of object you've given
me with a name set to a string, a skill set to a string and a likes mushrooms property set to a boolean.
That's not assignable to the type of object you promised me, which is an object with the name property
set to string.
Right?
So if it's one extra property or one less property, it doesn't matter.
TypeScript will identify those mismatches in the expected type and the actual value and will warn you
about them.
And that specificity that you focus on having it exactly right is way better than having a generic declaration
like just object which will apply to any kind of object in the world.
You can declare ten properties.
Five properties.
15 properties, different values, etc. Now we're being more specific.
So obviously to make this IRD go away, we can provide an additional property here and it's type.
So I'm going to write a comma here the exact same way that we separate key value pairs in an object.
We similarly separate them in a object type declaration.
And I'm going to tell TypeScript that what I'm assigning here is also going to have a skill property
also set to a string.
So what happens then?
Probably you can anticipate this error by now.
TypeScript is going to say, okay, you've told me to expect a name of a string and a skill of a string,
and I've gotten that.
But what the heck is likes mushrooms.
It's going to say that type of object with a likes mushrooms property.
Such a boolean is not assignable to a type with just two properties of name and skill.
So right here I'm going to apply likes mushrooms and I'm going to assign it to a type of a boolean.
So now a problem goes away.
So now we have the exact same three properties and just as well we have the exact expected values for
them.
So for example, let's take a look.
If there's a mismatch, let's say I do have a likes mushrooms property, but here I told TypeScript
to anticipate a boolean.
Let's say instead that I provide a value like five.
Once again, TypeScript is now going to say, okay, you told me there's going to be a likes mushrooms
property.
That's totally fine with me.
But you told me it's going to be a boolean and you're trying to assign a number here.
So it's going to say type number is not assignable to the type that I expect likes mushrooms to be,
which should be boolean.
Right?
So if I return as back to true, that's going to be just fine.
And furthermore, TypeScript is also going to catch these errors further down the line.
So for example, if I try to take my plumber object and take its like mushrooms property and I try to
set that to false, that's not going to be a problem because TypeScript says you told me likes mushrooms
is going to be a boolean and properties can change in JavaScript.
So that's totally fine.
I'm going to permit that operation in comparison, if I try to change this something like five once
again, same error, it's going to say, Hey, you can't assign that type of number that's not assignable
to a type of boolean.
Because you told me in the declaration and in your initial object values that that's going to be a boom
and that's going to really help you identify these potential errors, which are really easy to skip
as a developer down the line.
All right.
That's how we declare object type declarations in TypeScript.
And I will see you in a next lesson.