Okay.
So given that slot props are a pretty advanced and complex idea, I want to review and reinforce the
concepts of the previous lessons by creating an alternate implementation of our spotlight component.
So we're still going to use a slot props, but instead of providing a single spotlight prop, what we're
going to do is provide multiple ones.
And the way we're going to do that is by breaking up the spotlight object that we are iterating over.
All right.
And that's just going to give us more examples of the syntax and hopefully a better understanding of
what these props represent and what slot props here represents.
I know that you may have a good grasp of these concepts as it stands, but I do want to reinforce them
in case you want another review, another shot, to understand what these things mean.
So what I'm going to do in spotlight is I'm going to remove my former spotlight component and I'm going
to decide that I'm actually going to provide three props to my parent and image prop, a title prop
and a description prop.
And each one is going to extract the relevant piece of information from my spotlight object that I'm
currently iterating over in my V for loop.
Right?
So if I want an image prop, I want to do IMG here.
That would be the name of my prop and I can provide a reference to Spotlight Dot IMG.
As always, you should know this by now and I apologize for repeating it 100 times.
This will not work because we will think we're literally providing a string.
So if we want to bind to this prop so that it refers to a dynamic value, we have to use the V bind
syntax.
So now we are connecting the IMG prop to the IMG property on the current spotlight object that we are
iterating over.
I'm going to do the exact same syntax for two more props here, so I will define a title prop.
And I'm going to give it access to Spotlight that title.
So simply referencing existing properties on the objects that we define in our debate adjacent file.
Then one more prop, I'll call it description and I'll dynamically bind it to spotlight dot description.
Okay.
So previously we were passing one prop up of spotlight.
Now we're passing three up.
But the concept does not change, right?
So on the left hand side here, we still use this type of syntax.
We still create a name for the object.
It's going to store our props.
Right.
So for now, I'm still going to call it slot props.
But now slot props is an object with three top level properties.
IMG Title and description.
Right.
We no longer pass it the whole object.
So we no longer have that spotlight.
But we do have that image, that title, that description.
So that allows us to simplify some of the syntax we're doing here.
So, for example, in this image element where we are dynamically binding to the source attribute.
Now we don't have a spotlight object, but we do have a top level IMG property on slot props.
So there we go.
Slot props.
That IMG references this thing right here, which is the string from the object right here on the slot
props object.
We no longer have spotlight, but we do have a new title property.
And right here, instead of Spotlight, we have description.
And if I save this and go back to my browser.
We're going to see when you refresh that the thing still works as expected.
All right.
There we have the data.
And just to show you that the name is totally up to us.
I can change slot props to be whatever I want.
In fact, just for the sake of example, you do not have to copy this.
I'm literally going to change slot props to be a name of whatever I want.
The key takeaway that I want you to notice here is that this object name is up to us.
It's just going to represent the object of props that we define right here.
And whatever we call it here in this double quotes is what we have to use throughout.
So it's simply a matter of knowing what properties you have available on that object as they are defined
by the child component.
So once again, I'm going to save this.
Go back to my browser.
There it is.
It's working.
Refresh, just to prove it.
Refresh one more time.
Everything is still working out as expected.
The reason there's a little bit of a delay is because we're waiting for the JSON server to return the
data so that it can be iterated over.
All right.
That's all there is to learn in this lesson.
The key idea is that we can provide whatever name we want here, whatever properties we want to access
as well.
As long as we define them on the child component, so we are not obligated to pass up an object or a
complex data structure.
We can totally break it up into as many props as we want.
Of course, the ultimate goal, as always, is readability and simplicity.
If you have a lot of data, it might be easier to store it in a single object.
If you have things like this where we have three pieces of information, I don't think this is offensive.
I think this is pretty simple and it gives a reader a better understanding of what we're passing up.
It really is up to your personal preference as far as what code better communicates your intent and
what you want to pass up to the parent.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.