All right.
In this lesson, I just want to quickly clean up some files in preparation for the next section of the
course.
The first thing we can do is clear out the contents of our playground dot file.
As a reminder, this file is just a scratch pad.
This code is not directly related to our view code, so we can go ahead and remove it.
And I'm going to remove or delete the playground dot test that JS file completely just so that it doesn't
negatively affect our coverage when we actually start running tests for our components.
I want to get an accurate sense of how much of our components remain untested, and I don't want this
additional tests right here, which don't actually do our project to influence that number in any way.
So I'm just going to remove this test.
It was purely for the sake of example and learning so we can delete playground that test that.
Yes.
And leave playground bags empty.
And that's all there is to do in this lesson.
I will see you in the next one.