Okay.
So now that we have a better understanding of how slots work, we can provide as much dynamic content
here as we want to populate the internals of our accordion.
So let's begin by building out some of the template that we're going to need for our check boxes for
our collection of organizations at the user will be able to select in order to eventually filter the
jobs on the right hand side.
So in here as a slot, I'm going to provide a div.
And I'm going to immediately assign it a tailwind in class.
I'm going to give it some margin on the top.
So I'll add an empty five Tailwind class and then in here I'll use the field set element to specify
that I'm creating a field of possible choices.
And here I'm going to define an unordered list.
So a u, l and this is also going to have some classes.
I'm going to make this a Flexbox and I want the children to span in a row direction.
So I want to apply the flex row tail in class.
And finally, if there's not enough room, I want to make sure the flex children wrap.
So I'm going to add the flex wrap class.
All right.
And here we're going to define list items and each list item will represent one organization and equivalently,
one checks checkbox at the user can check to select an organization by which they would like to filter
the jobs.
Now, if I open up the debate JSON file as a reminder, every single job here is going to have an organization
key and that is going to have the name of the organization, in this case of you and me.
And ultimately what we want to do is iterate over all of these organizations, come up with a unique
list of them and create a checkbox for each one.
But before we get there, I'd like to come up with a simpler implementation.
So I'm simply going to hard code a bunch of organizations in my job that are sidebar and give each one
a checkbox, and later on we'll refactor to make that content more dynamic.
So for now.
I'm just going to create a list item.
I'm going to give it some classes.
Let's make it occupy half the width of the parent.
So I'm going to do the w-1 divided by two a class.
This is actually a class name and it's totally valid to have a C.
S class with a dash and a slash totally valid characters.
You can see that this is a tailwind class that applies a with a 50%.
So we're going to have two checkboxes on every line essentially or every row in our Flexbox.
And I also want to assign a height to this list item.
So I'm going to use the H eight class that is going to apply a height of 32 pixels inside the list item.
I'm going to have an input, a self-closing input as well as a label where I'm going to have the text
for that checkbox.
All right.
So for my input, I'm going to give it an ID of a organization.
So let's start with a sample one like view two.
And by the way, all of my organizations are terrible view puns.
So I apologize if that is offensive, but that's how I came up with the various organizations in our
DB that Jason found Soviet you.
We have to make sure that we specify that this input is of type checkbox.
It's not a regular text input, it's a checkbox.
And then I'm going to apply a Tailwind class and it's going to be am r three.
M.r, of course stands for margin, right?
So it's going to create a little bit of spacing between the input and the label.
And in the label we're going to provide the four attribute and this should match the ID above.
This is just common HTML practice.
So here I'm going to write YouTube and for the text, for the actual label text, I'm similarly going
to have YouTube.
All right.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to copy this list item and I'm going to paste it three times
below because I want four checkboxes for four organizations and they're all basically going to have
the same set up, the same style.
So right here I'm going to select YouTube.
And in this code on a mac, I can do command D to select the subsequent occurrences of that same sequence
of text.
I believe on a windows it would be controlled D but I'm not certain and I'm just going to select these
three and replace them with between.
View and meet, which is my next organization, in fact, because this will not fit on the line.
I'm actually going to cut this down a little bit to just be between view.
This is just for the sake of example.
So this is totally fine for now.
All right.
For the next one below, I'm going to replace YouTube here, here and here with ET View.
Brutal.
All right.
And finally, for the last one, I'm going to select this occurrence of YouTube as well as this one
and this one.
And our final organization is View and a Half Man.
So basically what I've done here is create an unordered list of four list items.
Each one is a checkbox with a corresponding text label all within this field set and within his div.
And again, because we provided this complete bundle of HTML within our opening and closing accordion
component tags, what that means is that view is going to copy all of this content and inject it right
here where we have our slot component within our accordion.
All right.
So we're basically doing this behind the scenes.
Let me bring this back to slot.
Let me save this and go to our browser.
And we should start to see the beginnings of our user story take shape.
So right here we have our organizations, we have accordion.
When I click this, there we go.
We're starting to see we have four checkboxes here.
We can click on and off.
We have four organizations.
And obviously the goal is whenever we select one of these, we want the jobs on the right to be filtered.
And the good news about that, of course, is that we have the organization name right here in line
here is view and me, here is YouTube.
Here is you can do it.
So the idea is when we select these, we obviously want these to be.
Filter down, that is the user feature.
And again, we are not actually accounting for the real world organizations.
We have, for example, we don't have you can do it yet, but that is because we are hard coding these
checkboxes right now.
Later on, we're going to dynamically render as many checkboxes as we need, depending on the number
of unique organizations we get in our API response.
But we'll take care of that a little bit later.
All right.
So with that, I will see you in the next lesson.