All right.
So let's wrap up this section with a quick section review.
This section was focused entirely on integrating tailwind into our project.
Tailwind, of course, is a success framework that adds lots of utility classes, readymade classes
for us to use in our project that deal with everything from margin to padding to font size to text alignment
to display, etc. instead of having to create our own access classes and remember all of those.
Yes, as properties we can just memorize a bunch of Tailwind utility classes or reference the documentation
and have this very easy process of iteration where we just simply add those classes to our existing
H2 elements and observe the changes in our browser.
Until we find something that fits what we're looking for, we can use the view SEELYE To add tailwind
to a View project, we use the View Ad Command earlier in the course, and that created a whole bunch
of files for us to work with.
And the primary one that we really should be concerned about is the tailwind dot config that JS file
and that's where we can fine tune or set some more.
My new Tailwind Options and settings.
For example, earlier in the section we added our open sans font to the project and we made sure to
tell Tailwind that it should prefer to use that font, but before it falls back to its array of regular
fonts.
All right.
That's really all there is to cover in this section.
Next up, we're going to talk about rendering data to our screen using view.