Alright.
So in the previous lesson we introduced the V if directive which conditionally renders either a component
or whatever HTML chunk you want conditionally on the screen.
And in this lesson, we're going to introduce yet another directive, which is the V out directive.
The way it's going to work is exactly like an if l statement in JavaScript.
If something is true, then we're going to render one bit of time out else or otherwise we're going
to render a totally different chunk of H2 now, or in this case it's going to be if something is true,
we're going to render one component.
Otherwise, if it's false, render another component.
And of course, what we're going to render is either an action button if the user's logged out or our
profile image component if the user is logged in.
So here I am and Main NAV.
And let's start by importing our new profile image component.
So right here in our script section, I'm going to import profile image.
It's going to be a very similar syntax to what we have above with Action Button.
I'm going to import it from our top level Astro C Directory Components Profile Image View Provide the
semicolon here and remember before we can use it we have to register it in our components object.
So right here I'm going to add profile image as another property as a reminder.
Now we can use the profile image component either with this syntax or using kabob case, which means
all lowercase and with dashes, right?
So we already have and is logged in property and that's really all we need because depending on what
boolean this currently is, that's going to determine what I want to render.
All right.
So I'm going to move up here and I'm going to remove this view of temporarily from the action button.
We'll come back to it in just a second.
And given that, I don't really want to use negation, which means in the previous lesson we took our
is logged in property and then we inverted it and it was kind of a little bit confusing because you
had to flip it.
I just prefer to think a lot more logically and positively.
So if the user is logged in, what do we want to render?
We want to render our profile image.
So right here I'm going to write my profile image component.
I'm going to instantiate it.
And since it's not going to have anything between the opening and closing tags, I can have a single
tag and provide my slash here and close my profile image like so.
And I want to apply my v if directive to conditionally render this profile image if and only if the
is logged in property is set to true.
Right.
So when the component starts up is logged in is set to false.
So the profile image will not render.
But of course the way it currently works now is action button will always render because there's no
kind of directive attached to it.
So here is where I want to apply the brand new directive I wanted to tell you about, which is V else.
So we're going to write the else.
Right here.
Like all of you directives, it's going to start with that V prefix and that is actually all we need.
We do not need to apply a separate condition here because it works just like an if l statement in JavaScript.
In other words, this is first going to be evaluated by view and it's going to check if this condition
is true.
If this condition is true, if is logged in, returns true, it's going to render the profile image
and it's not going to render the action button because the action button belongs to effectively the
else clause.
The other branch that we're never hitting.
Conversely, if our if statement evaluates to false, so if is logged in is equal to false, this evaluates
the false, which means Vue will not render the profile image component and since it automatically will
go into the L statement just like it would in regular JavaScript, the statement evaluates the true
and we're going to render an action button instead.
So we're only ever going to render one of these two components, either profile image or action button,
depending on the status of is logged in.
All right.
Let's take a look at this in the browser.
So I'm going to go back to my browser.
And of course, we don't have the functionality yet wired up to click the button and change the state
of our data.
But we can do that in view DevTools to see how this works.
So I'm going to bring up my view devtools right here, bring it up and let's take a look at this state
in our main nav component.
So we have our is logged in property.
It's set to false because it's set to false.
We are hitting the V else part of our clause, which means we're rendering the action button.
All right.
And what do you think is going to happen when we check is logged in here?
Well, is logged in is going to change to true.
Which means Vue is going to run through our HTML code again read render it and because is logged in
is now true.
It knows instead that it should render the profile image because that property connected to our data
now evaluates to true.
And as it's going to render our profile image, the else is now no longer going to be executed, so
our action button will no longer be rendered.
So we're now going to swap these two components in and out.
Let's see how this works.
I'm going to click this and.
Second.
There we go.
The reason it took a little bit to load is because we actually had to fetch that image from the URL.
But there is our link profile image on the top, right?
And if I simulate logging out, well, now we change our state.
Once again, the if else reverses truthiness.
And now we have a button.
I'm just going to click it a couple more times so you can see how quickly it changes.
And there we go with the changing of our component data, we are changing part of the view.
That is the whole point of what Vue.js adds for us as a view library.
All right.
So lots of progress here in the very next couple of lessons, we're going to talk about how we can test
this, the F and V logic within our test suite.
I'll see you there.