Okay.
So now we have our font awesome icon registered as a global component, which means we can use it in
any of our own components, including sub nav.
So here I have sub nav open and I'm going to add this icon right here in this div.
So let's remove this placeholder text.
I'm going to break this up onto a new line.
And as I mentioned, we can simply render our font awesome icon here in line.
We do not need to import anything.
We do not need to register components.
One thing I do want to do though is I want to add another div just to form a box around what I'm going
to add because I'm going to add both the icon and then the text next to it that's going to say some
number of jobs matched.
So as I mentioned in the previous lesson, we registered a component using this syntax font.
Dash Awesome.
Dash icon.
That was the first argument to the component method.
So we can use it right here and I'm going to make it a self-closing component like so again, take a
second to notice that we can now use this component right here in line in our template with no additional
imports in the script section.
This is not a local component.
This is a globally registered component.
Now by itself, of course, if we render this font awesome, icon font awesome has no clue which component
we want to use.
Right?
On the website we saw that there were 7000 potential options.
So in this case, we have a parent component of sub nav rendering a child component of font.
Awesome icon.
Well, if you think back to the previous section of the course, how can a parent component customize
details of how the child renders?
Well, you may recall something called props.
Write props are inputs or arguments that we can pass to a component, much in the same way that we pass
arguments to functions.
And the prop that we're going to need here is conveniently called icon.
And the way you can find this, of course, is by reading the documentation for this view implementation
of font.
Awesome.
So I'm going to have a prop called Icon.
And the argument for this prop is actually going to be an array right now.
As a reminder, whenever you have a complex argument here, that is not a string, right?
If it's an array or an object or a boolean, remember that we need to use the v bind syntax because
if we don't view is going to interpret as a plain string.
So for example, if I tried to specify an array here like so and I do not provide my v bind syntax,
my v bind directive view is going to think we're passing in a string with a square bracket and another
square bracket.
Right?
So we need to use the V bind directive.
And as a reminder, there's two syntactical options available.
We can either do this v bind.
That is the long form way, but the shortcut is to simply use the colon.
So colon icon makes this prop a dynamic value which allows us to feed in whatever we want, such as
an array.
Now this is going to be an array of two strings, and given that we have double quotes around it, in
order to write out these strings and avoid any issues with the JavaScript interpreter, we need to actually
write our strings in single quotes, which is totally valid in JavaScript.
Our first argument in the array is going to be f a s.
That is simply short for font.
Awesome.
I think the reason they do this is because they have their free tier and their premium tier.
And here I believe you might be specifying which one of those you want to use.
They're sort of like different folders or categories of icons.
And then the second argument here is going to be the actual font awesome icon that we want to use within
that category.
And for us, of course, we only have one registered with our library and that is search.
So we can write out search in all lowercase and that by itself should render our icons.
So I'm going to go back to my browser and lo and behold, it's as simple as that.
We have our font awesome icon appearing right here on our sub nav.
That looks awesome.
Okay, so to close this lesson off, let's go ahead and add a few more things here.
What I want to add to the right hand side of that icon is a little bit of margin.
I want to separate it from the text that's going to tell me how many jobs I've matched so I can actually
apply a Tailwind class or any CSS class on an existing view component.
So it's going to write out class here and write out a sample margin, right?
Class.
So there is a tailwind collection of classes called AMR, which apply margin on only the right side.
And I'm going to do an R three, which is 12 pixels.
So you might be curious, how does this work?
The way it works, since we're dealing with a component is view is going to take our styles and it's
going to apply them to the first actual element within the component.
So however the developers built the font awesome icon component, whatever its most top level HTML element
is sort of like we have div in this file, whatever they configured, we're going to apply this class
to that.
So it's not really applying the styles to a component since a component is kind of our own view of specific
related thing.
But it is going to transfer those styles to the top level element of that component, which is sort
of doing the same thing that way.
We don't have to know the internals.
Of how the developers built the font awesome icon component.
However they built it, whether it's a divan there or an H1 or a P, we don't really care.
We're just going to add this class to that.
And that's what we accomplished by applying the class to the component itself.
Awesome.
So that's going to add a little bit of spacing.
And then obviously the next thing I want to add is going to be the actual words that say how many jobs
we matched.
So I'm going to follow the HTML elements structure that I saw on the Google Careers website, which
is we're going to begin with a span and a closing span.
And within that span we're going to have another span.
This inner span is specifically going to be the green colored text that has the number of jobs.
So it says something like a thousand jobs matched and that thousand is going to be in a green color
while the jobs matched is going to be an irregular color.
So this internal span is is covering that number.
So here I'm going to apply a class and that class is going to be text dash brand green one.
Once again, as a reminder, brand green one is a color that we configured in our Tailwind configs class.
So Tailwind gives us this CSS class out of the box.
And as I mentioned, we have not built the infrastructure yet to actually have jobs and filters.
So what I'm going to do right now is just hard code, an arbitrary value.
And here I'm going to choose 16 of 53.
I promise you later in the course, we're going to come back and make this number dynamic based on the
actual number of jobs that the user is filtered.
But obviously, we're not quite there yet, and we're building our Web page from top to bottom.
So we will come back to this.
This is just a placeholder, placeholder value.
All right.
So after this, I'm just going to put a space here and write jobs matched.
Save this.
It looks like it's going to break it up onto a single line, or rather not break it up, but consolidate.
I'm going to remove the space at the end because I know spans can be pretty picky.
I'm going to remove this space right here as well.
I don't think it's necessary and that should be good.
So we have an inner span with our green font for the number and then we have the outer span contain
the additional text of jobs matched.
Okay.
So let's see what this looks like in the browser transition back.
And there we go.
We have our font awesome icon, which is a global view component from another library.
And now we've combined it with our own code and now we have that special styling for that number.
1653 job is matched.
Things are looking pretty good.
I can also give you a side by side comparison.
If I go to careers dot Google here and I go to jobs, we can see here what it looks like in the real
world.
It's looking, you know, pretty close, not perfect, but good enough for me.
So things are looking pretty good.
We're making lots of progress.
And I will see you in the next lesson.