All right, so let's replace our traditional promise syntax in the job listings component with the new
async await syntax.
So the first thing we need to do is declare the mounted method or the mounted lifecycle hook as an async
function.
So I'm going to add the async keyword immediately before the name of the method which is mounted.
And of course, the reason we need to market as asynchronous is because there's going to be something
in the body of this method that's going to be asynchronous, that's going to take some amount of time
to complete.
And that, of course, is going to be our Axios request.
So right here, instead of this syntax, we can say is const response, and we're going to await until
Axios can get our data.
So await Axios dot get and we're going to provide the exact same URL as we have here.
And under the hood, these two lines are basically identical.
We're going to wait until Axios completes that request and gives us back the response object.
And on that response object, we're going to have a data property.
And that data property is what we want to write to our jobs data property.
So once we have these two lines, we can remove the former implementation.
And I think that makes our code a little bit cleaner and easier to understand.
All right.
So let's save that.
Let's head back to our browser.
Let's refresh the page just to check.
Give it a second to make the request.
And then if I go into my job results view and my job listings, there is our jobs array with the 100
objects that we received from our jobs and.
Perfect.
So I will see you in the next lesson.