Okay.
So our mutations file is now a typescript file.
And the next thing I want to do is to convert the corresponding test file for mutations to a typescript
file as well.
We're going to discover that that is going to create some issues in our tests.
And over the course of the next couple of lessons, we're going to talk about different ways that we
can resolve those typescript issues.
So let's head to tests, then a unit, then store.
And right here we're going to have our mutations that test, that just file.
I'm going to open it up and I'm going to change the extension of this file from test just to test that
tests.
So we're going to make it a typescript file.
All right.
I'm going to save that collapse my sidebar and move this to the right.
And you can immediately see we're going to get a couple issues right here.
We can see that TypeScript is not happy.
So for now, let's focus on this first test right here.
It's targeting our log in user mutation.
Our log in using mutation simply takes the view store state and it flips the is logged in property to
have a boolean of true.
So here we have our state object with an is logged in property of false and then we're verifying that
after the mutation runs it has a value of true.
So that looks good.
So what is TypeScript unhappy about?
Well, if I hover my mouse over, you can see it says argument of type is logged in having a boolean.
So an object with a single property of is logged in at such a boolean is not assignable to a parameter
of the type global state.
So remember on the left hand side, we told TypeScript that our log in user mutation is going to take
an object, it's going to implement the global state interface.
And what does the global state interface has have?
It has some additional properties we can see right here type.
This object is missing the following properties from type global state jobs, selected organisations
and selected job types.
So we told TypeScript that the mutation method would take a global state object with four properties,
jobs, selected organisations, selected job types and is logged in.
But we're providing an object that only has one of those properties, right?
So TypeScript says that as a mismatch you have extra properties and I'm going to complain.
Now here's where we run into an interesting scenario because from TypeScript perspective, it's absolutely
correct.
But from our perspective as testers, I would argue that a test like this is just fine.
Why is it just fine?
Well, because this test only cares about a single property.
And for the sake of readability and for the sake of communicating what the mutation does, I think it's
fine to focus on what the property is, that it's changing.
Imagine that our View Store State had 25 properties.
Do we really want to define is logged in here alongside 24 other properties and have that super long
object in this test just so that we can verify that the mutation affected only one property.
Right.
So for the purposes of testing, I like the way this reads.
I have the starting state, I have the mutation that modifies it and I have the ending state.
Unfortunately, our starting state doesn't fulfill the exact contract that our real world mutation has.
And I still want to keep this interface right here because it's going to help us type check in other
locations throughout the app.
The places that use our mutations or for example, components are going to know what's available in
the state, they're going to know what they can work with, etc..
So I want to keep this right here, but how can we make our tests a little bit more flexible?
So there's a couple solutions available here.
The first one that I want to introduce in this lesson is called type casting.
What type casting is is what?
What we can do is tell TypeScript, TypeScript, please trust us, trust that we know what we're doing
and treat this data type as another data, type something, write out the syntax and then we'll see
the error is going to go away.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to import my global state interface, the same one we have on the
left hand side.
I'm going to import it into my test file.
So import global state and as we can see on the left, it's going to come from the source directory
store types and then I'm going to apply a special syntax right here.
After this object, I'm going to use the as keyword and then write out my interface, which is global
state.
And we're going to see that as soon as I add that this error on line number eight will go away.
So what does this syntax do?
Well, it sort of reads kind of logically from left to right.
We're telling TypeScript, treat this object right here.
This object with an is logged in boolean property as if it were a complete global state object.
It is not in fact that object.
Right?
Which is why we need to explicitly tell TypeScript.
TypeScript, forgive us.
We know what we're doing.
We're accepting the ramifications.
We know it's not a global state object, but treat it as if it were one.
Forgive us and treat this object as if it's a real global state object.
We understand that later on we may access properties that do not exist because we don't have a legitimate
global state object.
We have one that is playing that role, but we're basically telling TypeScript that we know what we're
doing.
And in this test, I think that's a reasonable assumption because we really do only care about this
is logged in property.
We don't really care for this mutation about all of the other properties on the global state interface.
So for the purposes of testing, I think this is okay, but this is one available solution that we can
use to solve the problem that TypeScript expects a more strict interface.
And our tests don't really need that for the sake of having a readable test.
All right.
So we use that as keyword followed by the type that we want Typekit to believe that this thing is or
except that this thing is Asimov.
Sorry.
So because on line number eight, TypeScript believes at that point that our state constant referencing
this object, which TypeScript now has been told it should treat as if it's global state, TYPEKIT says,
okay, state at this point is something I interpret as being like global state.
That's what this log in user mutation expects.
Okay, I have a match.
I'm not going to complain.
All right.
So that's one possible solution to the problem.
In the very next lesson, we'll take a look at another one.
I'll see you there.