Okay.
So in the previous lesson, we built our new job filter, sidebar, job types component, but we still
need to render it in our app.
So as a reminder, we are rendering all of these smaller subcomponents in a component called job filters
sidebar.
So let me open that up in verse code.
Here it is.
And as a reminder, here is where we're currently rendering the component that renders the organizational
checkboxes and we previously had the smaller accordion here with a placeholder.
And the intent here was to kind of make a placeholder for where we we would eventually place our job
types.
Well, now we have that component ready to go so we can place it right here.
So in our script section, I'm going to import our new component import job filters, sidebar job types,
and that is going to come from the same directory as below the source directory components, job results,
job filter, side bar.
And then in there we're going to go for job filter, sidebar, job types.
That view again, importing in is not enough.
We also have to register it with the local components property.
So right here, job filter, sidebar, job types, there we go.
And of course Eastland is complaining because we're not using it.
Not a problem up here in the template section, I'm going to remove the second accordion and I'm going
to render the component using a self-closing tag.
So job filters, dash, sidebar, dash job types, then make it a self-closing component like so save
that and the air slide warning should go away.
And with that we can transition to our browser and here we have it job types.
If I expand it, there we go.
We have the four unique job types from our jobs intern full time, part time temporary.
If I expand organizations that is working as well.
Both of these components are talking to individual getters from the beauty store that are talking to
the jobs slice of the view store state to get these unique jobs or job types or organizations in a set
that each respective component is iterating over.
So while these components are very similar, the kind of underlying plumbing and what they're relying
on is slightly different.
All right.
So our logic is still wired up to filter jobs from the organization selection.
Nothing is actually going to happen when we select any of these options.
However, we are going to be updating the View Store and I can prove that to you by opening up our UCS
dev tools to right here are going to go to view and then I'm going to wait until this loads right here
I'm in view X and here's root so we can see we have our new selected job types, right.
And when I select a job type like part time, remember the component is going to handle the local data
using a V model, but it's also going to invoke that select job type, I believe it's called method,
which is going to commit the mutation that's going to send that array of strings to view X.
So here you can see it's being saved.
Here's part time.
If I add temporary, you can see the array is overwritten again, then we'll add full time, then we'll
remove part time.
You can see each time I do that we are modifying the array.
So we basically have everything we need in our view store in order to be able to filter our jobs using
both criteria, organizations and job types.
That's what we eventually are going to get to.
And then very next lesson though, I do want to test just this functionality by itself by having this
filter the jobs on the right hand side.
So that's what we're going to wire up in the very next lesson.