All right.
So in this lesson, we're finally going to connect our new skills search term property from our View
X Store directly to our new job filter sidebar skills component.
Before we get there, though, I want to do a quick review of our checkbox group component.
This is one we've been building out over a couple of sections and I want to talk about some of the design
design decisions that we made that we weren't too happy with in the previous sections.
So as a reminder of how this component works, the way it works is it creates a local piece of state.
And when I say local state, I simply mean a component state existing on this component.
And that state is called selected values.
And as the user selects checkboxes, we send a mutation to the store to accept that array of checkboxes
so that the view store can store it and utilize it to get the filter jobs.
And so the problem with this approach is that it requires us to keep our data in sync, our data in
our component, as well as our data in the view store.
And that is not great because it's prone to error, right?
So we have to remember that every single time the user selects a checkbox, we have to inform the store
that that a change has occurred.
We also have to deal with the situation in reverse whenever the user committed this mutation by clicking
the Clear Filters button that cleared all of the data in the store.
However, it did not update the checkboxes because our component still had the local selected value
stored.
Thus, we had to utilize this strategy of using the subscribe method to listen for this specific mutation
and react accordingly by clearing that local array to update the checkboxes.
So this is an example of having to communicate to the store when the component changes, and this is
an example of having to communicate to the component when the store changes, right?
And it's prone to error because we have to remember to manually instrument these two pieces of code.
And so my question is, can we do better, especially when it comes to our new skills component?
And my answer is going to be yes.
So that is the first bit of good news to show you in this lesson.
Let's begin by opening up our skills component.
All right.
And so what I'm going to do here is I'm going to begin by getting our store into this component.
We know that we're going to need to commit a mutation as the user types.
Every time the user writes a character, we want to commit a mutation in order to get that skill search
term into the View X Store.
So just as a reminder and a better explanation.
Whenever the user types we want to commit this mutation update skill search term and we want to send
the data from this input right here to this mutation so that it can store the data in the view store.
All right.
So we need to get the store in order to do that.
So I'm going to start by importing.
The use store function, and that's going to come from the U.S. in order to access the store.
I'm also going to need my key.
So I'm going to import key, and that is going to come from the source directory and the store folder
of the index file there.
And then I also know that at some point I'm going to need to commit this mutation.
So let's import that constant right here.
So that constant of course is update.
Skills search term and that is going to come from the source directory store constants.
All right.
And then let's begin by writing our setup method using the composition API.
And first, I'm going to get my store.
So comp store equals use store passing in our key.
And here is the next question.
Right.
So what do we want to do here?
Well, we know, based on our earlier learnings in view that a very simple approach to creating two
way data binding in our component is by using the V model directive.
So let me scroll up here and I'm going to add a V model to this input and I'm going to provide a name
here called Skills Search Term.
Now I know that this name does not exist yet, so it's going to be our responsibility to return it right
here from our setup method.
But as a quick reminder of how the model works, it creates two way data binding, which means a connection
between our template and our data.
The reason it's called Two Way is because it flows in both directions.
When the data updates on the JavaScript or Typekit side, that change is immediately reflected in the
component and vice versa when a change is made from the template side.
In other words, when the user types a character, that change becomes reflected in the data side of
things.
So the two components here, and when I say components, I mean pieces are the HTML, the template,
and the data belong to the component.
So almost like this template section and the script section, right?
And two way data binding, which means we have a connection from this to this and from this to that
both directions.
Right.
So previously we used the model to connect an input to something like local component state.
If we were using the options API, we would use the data method and we would define something that we
would be able to overwrite.
And if we were using the composition API, we would use something like the ref function in order to
create a local piece of data that we can then update.
So that's the exact same approach we used in our checkbox group, but we saw that that had its own issues.
So what I'd like to do is to be able to connect the model and use the same logic, but I want to connect
it to our view store instead of creating two way data binding between my components template and the
data.
I want to create a two way data binding between my components template and the view store data and going
two ways, which means as the component updates as the user types, I want to immediately inform the
View Store and if the View Store updates, I want to also immediately inform the component.
So maybe a really easy visual way that I can describe this if I open it my state file is the traditional
use of model is connecting this section of the file to this section of the file.
I now want to connect this section of the file to this U.S. store.
When the user does something here, I want to commit a mutation to change this.
And when this changes is I want to make sure that information is reflected back to here.
All right.
And we're going to be able to solve that using a solution that we have not seen before.
It's going to require us to use the computed functions.
Let me begin by importing computed.
And then we know that we're going to need a name in our template called Skills Search Term.
So what I'm going to do here is just define that name skills search term, right?
And we'll provide an assignment for it in just a second.
But we know whatever we assign it to you, no matter what, we're going to need to ultimately return
it.
So it is available in our template because that is the thing that is going to connect to the model.
All right.
So here's what we're going to do.
What I'm going to do is use my computed function.
So I'm going to invoke it.
And so far, every single time that we have used computed throughout the course, we have always passed
that a function, right?
That function represents the logic for future erosion.
Whenever any part of the reactive object it references changes that function, he writes.
However, there is an alternative syntax that we can utilize with the computed function and it is passing
it an object.
Now, if you choose to pass it an object, that object must have two methods and they must be named
exactly this.
The first method must be called get and the second method must be called set.
Okay.
And the way you can think of this is as a way to provide a more complex way to both read and write data
to whatever this computed piece of state is going to be.
So in our scenario, we want our computed piece of data to be something called skill search term, and
we want to directly connected to this property right here.
So what we need to do in get is to explain, to view how to get access to this thing right here.
And in our set method, we need to explain, to view how to write to this thing right here.
Getting means reading.
Setting means writing.
And remember, we have access to our store right here.
So let's begin with get.
How do we explain to you what we want to get access to?
We want to get access to this specific property on our store.
That is our read process.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to return from this method.
We know we have a reference to our store above on line 29.
That is our complete view store.
And we also know that the store has a state property and that it's going to return the state on the
right hand side.
And on my state, I have a property called Skills Search Term.
Okay.
So what I'm doing now is I'm providing this reference to this thing right here, and because I'm wrapping
it in a computed function view is going to keep track of this thing right here.
So in other words, if this term updates in my view store, this get method will rerun it to get that
new value.
And because we've connected get right here to our remodel.
That means the component will render that value as the text input inside that input.
In other words, if I were to manually change the skill search term to a string like developer because
this logic would rerun and evaluate to developer, this input would then show the text developer.
So what I've done here with the get is create a connection from my view store to my V model in this
direction from right to left.
Now what I need to do is create a connection in the opposite direction when the user types a character
here.
I want to set the new value for skill search term right here.
Well, how do I set a new value?
I need to commit a mutation.
So in the set, I describe how this reactive piece of data called skill search term is going to update.
So it's going to be read from the store.
And in order to update it, we're going to update the store when we have access to our store.
And we know that in order to run a mutation, we have to call the commit method.
Right.
The first argument to the commit method is going to be the mutation we want to run.
And so the mutation we're going to want to run is update skills signature.
Now, that mutation, of course, requires an additional argument right here, and that is going to
be the actual skill search term.
So where do we get that from since we don't have any local state?
Well, if we follow this logic right here and we connect it to our V model view will automatically pass
the string or the latest version of the string that the users typed as the first parameter to set.
So I'm going to call that parameter value.
And it is going to represent whatever the user has typed.
So to reiterate, if the user, for example, types of letter A, then this logic will run passing in
the letter A then if the user types in another letter like L, our new string strings al so this set
method will run one more time with a value of a l.
So value is going to represent the most latest up to date value from the user typing in into this thing
here.
Now what I want to do with that value is provide that as the argument for my skills search firm.
So I'm going to pass it in as the second argument to the commit method.
Okay.
Looks like I have a little bit of a mismatch because this is skills at search term and this also needs
to be skills search term and that makes that air go away.
So what have we done here?
We have emulated the exact same functionality as the model does with local data, but instead of using
local component data with ref, we've now connected it to global data stored in the U.S. get explains
how that react of data changes or where to read it from, where to get that value from.
We told it use this property right here, know that it's this thing right here.
And whenever the user types, the model is going to run this thing right here.
And what that's going to do is commit a mutation each time the user types, a character that ships off
the latest user entry, the latest user text, the latest user string to this mutation, which in turn
will update this property right here because this property updates right here, the Get Method reruns,
which in turn it renders that piece of text in our input feel set almost as a full trip around.
I'm kind of drawing my mouse in the circle here to reflect the direction that this thing is happening.
Right?
The user is going to type a character, which is going to shoot off the set method, which is going
to commit a mutation that is going to change the state, which will force get to rerun because this
reactive reference changed, which will force this to get the latest skill search term saved right here,
which will be whatever the user typed, which is connected to the model through this skill search term
name and will thus reflect in the user's entry that they see on screen.
All right.
So hopefully it makes sense.
Even though this is a complex syntax, we're basically using the same computer logic.
We are reacting to change.
We're just being a little bit more specific as to how we read that change and how we change that change
or update that change.
So let's see how this is going to work in my browser.
So I'm going to transition to Chrome right now.
And what I'd like to do here is open up my view developer tools.
And what I want to do is keep track of the very store state.
So right here in this panel, I'm going to select View X and you can see right here that our skill search
term is empty.
And you'll notice that as I type a character here, because we connected our set method from the computed
property that's referenced by the model to this as I type the letter A that's going to commit the mutation
sending off the value of A, which is then going to override skill search term with A, which will force
that get method in our computed function to rerun.
Thus updating this and as I type more characters here, each time we're going to commit that mutation
again and thus it's going to affect the skill search term right here.
Keep in mind that this relationship exists in two directions.
We have two way data binding, and right now we're only seeing one way.
We see that when the user edits the template, we are sending off that data to our View X Store.
So the connection exists from here to here, but it also is going to exist in reverse.
So right here, if I talk to the data, which is now not local component data but view stored data,
if I change this to something else like Hello, because our get method knows that it's referencing this
property, it will re-evaluate itself, right?
Which in turn will update it and thus will update that template value right here.
So as soon as I click save, take a look.
This input field has changed.
So two way data binding between our template and our data.
When our template changes, so does our data right here in state.
And when our state changes, so does our template right here.
The connection goes in two directions.
Therefore, it is two way data binding.
Why is it called data binding?
Because our data is bound.
Bound means connected together to something.
This template is connected to this and the state is connected to the template.
All right.
And by by doing the solution, what is the advantage here?
We don't need to now keep our component state in sync with our of U.S. store state.
That is the problem we had with our checkbox group.
We needed to make sure that you store knew right here that when we check this that it also would update
this selected degrees array and that's when this thing changed.
We also needed to inform the the template that that our view store changed and now we've gotten rid
of local component state and simply allowed the V model directive to depend on the view store state
to start.
There is no more data duplication, there is no more data sync issues.
All right, so I know it's been a long lesson, but hopefully this has been helpful and it certainly
is a very cool feature of computed and that function that was introduced into U three.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.