All right.
So another day, another component, as the old saying goes in this lesson, let's go ahead and move
our sub nav component to be in TypeScript.
So I'm going to open up sub nav that view and apply the exact same principles right here.
Lang equals tts right here.
Import define component from view.
I think I'm getting a little bit quicker typing it out just because of how many times I've done so.
All right, right here.
Define component.
Invoke it.
Pass in my object save.
That doesn't look like there are any violations, which is great.
Let's open up the test file.
Sub nav that test that.
Yes.
And I'm probably going to be moving a lot quicker through my explanations because we've basically tackled
a lot of these issues before.
So, you know the drill by now.
Let's convert this to have a test extension.
And the only issue we're going to see here, there are a couple.
The first one is we need to add a dot view extension to the end of this.
That's not a problem here.
You can see we're having the familiar issue of TypeScript not recognizing that just that Mark has replaced
these original implementations with mock objects.
We know the solution for that is to use the as keyword.
So right here I'm going to do it for my two imports.
So right here for my use, confirm root import on line six, I'm going to say convert use, confirm
root mark.
And that is going to be referencing my use confirm root import, but telling TypeScript to treat it
as a different type, which is just mark.
And then we also need the one above it which is filter jobs.
So convert use filter jobs.
Mark is going to be my original use filter jobs function, but I'm going to tell TypeScript to now treat
it as a just mock instead, which is what it is, because that's what just Mark does for us.
And that means that whenever I use mock return value, I need to make sure I use my new constants.
So right here this is now going to be used confirm root mark use filter jobs mark scrolling down same
thing here.
Mark use filter jobs mark save that are issues go away that allows us to run our test suite with NPM
run test colon watch.
And that will take care of our sub nav, which appears directly below the main nav.
As a reminder is where we show the number of filter jobs by talking to the filter jobs getter.
All right.
Everything is passing.
Looking good.
And I will see you in the next lesson.