Okay.
So we made lots of progress in the previous lesson refactoring our job filter sidebar component and
creating three new smaller child components right here.
And what we're going to discover in this lesson as we refactor the test suite is that this design is
also going to lead to simpler tests.
All right.
Let me show you what I mean.
So on the right hand side, I have my test file for the jobs of the sidebar.
And here we have three distinct tests.
They allow the user to filter their jobs by job types, by organizations, as well as by degrees.
So we're basically validating the functionality that each one of these components was doing.
But previously, when we were capturing all of our composable in the setup method right here, we needed
to mock them all out for any given test.
We had three composable.
Thus we did three mock return values.
Now, the beautiful part about our new design is each one of these three components relies on its own
single composable function, which means when we break up these tests into smaller test suites for these
components in each test suite, we're only going to need to mark out one composable, right?
Because in any one of these components, for example, let me open up degrees right here, job filter
side by degrees.
In this one, we're now only using one composable.
Use unique degrees we no longer care about.
Use unique job types or use unique organizations because that logic is filtered out or captured in the
other smaller components.
Right.
So that's going to allow us to both copy the tests we have right here from sidebar to this new component
test, but also allow us to simplify the logic we have right here.
So with that said, let's begin by going back to our sidebar.
And what I'm going to do in the test file is I'm going to comment out all of this code for now.
Later on, we're going to commit it back in.
And then what we're going to do is copy these tests to new test sales.
But for now, what I want to do is write one very, very simple test, basically just a sanity check
to ensure the job filter sidebar is mounting correctly with no issues.
In fact, I'm going to use shallow amount right here because we don't really care about all the internals
of these child components.
We just basically want to get the cyber component up and running and make sure there is no problems
there.
So what I'm going to do right here is add a new test above my comment ID code.
It sets up a panel for a user to filter jobs by one or more criteria.
All right.
So that is a good place to start.
And this is simply going to be a two line test.
The first thing is I'm going to shallow amount my actual component, which is called job filter sidebar.
And on the next line, you may recall that this view wrapper object that the test utils library gives
us, it has an existing method which returns a boolean and that simply verifies that the wrapper exists,
which basically means that there was no issues.
There was no issues as far as instantiating the component, initializing it and mounting it.
So it's kind of a very simple dumb test to verify that the wrapper exists, that, in other words,
line 19 executed without any error.
So right here the exist method will return a boolean and I'm going to check whether that boolean is
true.
And if it's true, it means the component exists.
So everything worked as expected.
All right, let me save this file and we'll see if my test passes.
All right.
Give it a couple seconds to run.
And it's passing.
And now we can move on to creating test files for each of our new components.
So let's start with these tests.
From the from the top and moving on down.
So this first one is allows users to filter jobs by job types.
So the first component that is responsible for this is going to be our job types component.
So let me open up job builder sidebar, job type stock view.
And immediately what I'm going to do is create a corresponding test file.
So right here in my test unit components directory, I'm going to find job results, job filter, sidebar.
And here I'm going to create job filters.
Sidebar job types that test.
That's all right.
And let me keep this file here.
And what I'm going to try to do is basically copy and paste the lines that I care about right here into
my new test file.
And the hope is eventually to take this test as well.
So let's start from the very top.
We're obviously going to need our shallow amount functions.
So let me copy that.
Over.
Then what I'm going to do, just to keep things really simple is I'm going to copy over all of the imports
of the composable, as well as the mocking out of them or the type assignment for TypeScript for me.
Copy that over here as well.
And then, of course, we're going to clean it up because we no longer need all of these imports in
our job types component.
All we're relying on is this composable right here.
Use unique job types.
So right here, all I need to mark out is use unique job types so we can get rid of these two imports
and we can also get rid of these two mock assignments right here and keep it super simple like so.
So now we're going to have the composable, we're going to mock it out, and then we're going to create
a new icons to give it the right type for typescript sake.
Then let's actually import our new component.
And that is going to be the job filters, sidebar, job type's component, and that is going to come
from the source directory.
Let me take a look at my notes here because it has a pretty long file path.
So source components.
Job results.
Job filters.
Sidebar.
And then finally, jobs, other sidebar job types.
There we go.
Next thing I'm going to do is provide a describe block for my job filter is sidebar job types component
one of our three new components.
And in here, the basic tasks we want is this one right here.
It allows users to filter jobs by job types.
So let me commit this test back in in my job, just sidebar tester and then what I'm immediately going
to do is cut it and simply paste it right here because it's now applying for this logic.
All right.
So with that written, let me go ahead and drag this far back to the right.
So now we can compare the test file on the right with my component and then we can adjust it accordingly.
So do we need to mark out use unique job types?
We do because we're importing it, mocking it out here and we are using it in the component body.
But here is where we gain the benefits of splitting up that logic that was formerly in the sidebar component.
We no longer need these marks on lines 12 and 13.
Those organizations and Degrees Logic is now captured in our two other components that we created in
the previous lesson, and we don't need to mock it out because these are not utilized in the setup method
of our job filter, sidebar job types component, so we can immediately get rid of these two lines.
All right, then, of course, we're no longer mounting a sidebar component.
We're doing a job filter, sidebar, job types, component.
There we go.
And there's a couple more changes we have to implement.
And let me talk through them one by one.
So you'll notice here that we are passing down two props, unique values and mutation while our tests
are checking for three.
So Header was a former prop that we were passing down to a checkbox group so that that component could
pass down the header prop to our accordion.
But remember in our jobs filter sidebar, we now transferred this accordion up one level.
So our sidebar degrees component which renders a checkbox group no longer needs to pass down a header.
We are now capturing that outside of this component.
So in other words, this header logic is a test that we no longer need.
It's no longer reflective of our implementation.
So immediately I'm going to get rid of Header right here and I'm also going to get rid of this first
assertion that validates the header.
Prop receives the value of job types.
So it were valid.
And here is that we are finding our job types filter component using fine component.
We're getting its props.
We're getting two of the props.
We care about unique values and mutation, these two right here and we're validating that they get the
correct values.
The unique values right here should be coming from our composable.
And since we provided a mock return value right here of a set of two strings, that is the exact same
value we expect to pass down to that prop.
And then mutations should be a basic string coming right here from our ADD selected job types mutation
or a string constant representing that mutation name to be more specific.
Now when I save this, we're going to discover that our test is not going to pass and that is okay.
And what's actually going to happen here?
This is something that's a little bit weird, but what's happening here when I did a little bit of research
is I discovered that our data test attribute here was not actually working, even though it is job types
filter here and it is job type.
So here for some reason, when I transfer this logic over to this new test file, it was no longer working.
So what I decided to do here, since I wanted a simple solution that still utilized shallow amount,
which means I don't want to render the full checkbox to component and have to deal with its complexity.
I just want to render a stub or a replacement and then validate that I'm passing the right props.
What I decided is to simply search literally for a checkbox group component in my test.
Now, earlier in the course I mentioned, that's not really the best practice because it ties itself
very closely to the implementation.
And that's why data test is better, is because we can replace this component with any other component.
And as long as it has a date of this attribute, that's still equal to job types filter, this logic
would still work.
So I understand that the test that we're about to write is less reliable and more flaky.
But given how closely we are connected to using a singular component in this job text component, it's
basically just a wrapper around a checkbox group.
Anyway, I'm okay with directly checking for a checkbox script component literally in my find component
filter.
So what I'm doing here is instead of searching for a component with this dataset attribute in order
to search for a actual view component directly, what we can do is provide an object here as an argument,
and then we provide a name property.
And that name property represents the name we assigned to that component.
So in the case of our job filter signed by our checkbox group, that component has a name that we defined
in its script section called Job Filters Sidebar.
CheckBox group.
And so I'm going to find a component by its literal name.
There's only one component that matches that, which is this thing right here.
And if this works, let me save this and let it run.
Then what should happen is the test file should find the component.
It's able to locate it, it's able to get its props.
And I can see our tests are passing again.
The reason I had to make this change is when I was playing around with this lesson before I instructed
it, I discovered that using our data test attribute was the test utils was not able to find this component
or maybe it was able to find it, but for some reason it wasn't able to get the prop script.
This line right here was simply not working while this approach didn't work.
So again, data test is what I prefer because it's less flaky and less brittle, it's more sustainable
and it's more adaptive to change.
But this was a solution I had to implement simply so that I can do structure the correct props and check
their values.
And that's what we're going to do for our other test as well.
All right.
So that takes care of our job types test.
And you know the drill.
We're going to have to write similar tests for our other two components.
So once again, let's go back to sidebar.
Our next thing in line is going to be filter jobs by organizations.
So let's create a test file for that component.
So right here in our tests unit components, job results, job filter, sidebar directory, I'm going
to create my test file.
So this is going to be job filters.
Sidebar.
Organisations is our new component.
And then of course that test that yes, there we go very similarly to what we did earlier, we're going
to copy over basically everything here is let's copy over shallow amount.
Then let's copy over all of our imports and mocks.
And of course for our organizations component, that one is relying on the use of unique organizations
composable.
So we do need to import that one and mock it out, but we don't care about the other two.
So let's eliminate this job types one and this degrees one.
And that allows us to, of course, get rid of this line and this line.
So now we're only caring about the composable that we utilize in that component.
So right here, I'm going to import that component.
It's once again called job filters, sidebar organizations.
And that's going to come from the source directory components.
Job Results.
Job Filter.
Sidebar.
Sidebar Organizations.
Dot view.
There we go.
And right here, I'm going to describe.
Job filters.
Sidebar organizations.
And I can copy over the test I have in my sidebar, Tesla.
So right here, once again, I'm going to comment in this block of code and then I'm going to cut it
and paste it right here.
We're following the exact same protocol.
So I think I can move a little bit quicker through this test file.
Once again, we're not utilizing these composable and thus there mocks.
So we can remove line 11.
We can also remove the marking out of use unique degrees.
All right.
Right here.
We're going to mount not job.
They'll just sidebar the jobs with the sidebar organizations.
And one thing I realize, this is actually a mistake that's been lingering for a while in the course
because I was copying and pasting these tests earlier, we still kept this constant of job types filter,
probably because we based this test off our original test for job types, and that's no longer a fitting
name.
So let's change this right here to organizations filter instead.
Apologies for that.
That was once again a a mistake that comes from what happens when you copy and paste and are not careful.
That's why some developers even advocate to never copy and paste, but to write everything out manually
to make sure you avoid those mistakes.
All right.
With that said, let's follow the exact same protocol.
We no longer need a header prop, so we no longer need this test.
All right, once again, let me open up my component just so we can take a look at it.
Let me open it up on the right.
So let's open up the organizations component.
So here's a reminder.
We're using use unique organizations, so we're providing a mock return value or shallow mounting.
We want once again run into a problem of not being able to find the database attribute on this checkbox
or component.
So I'm going to look for this component manually and that should still work with the fine component
method right here.
But in order to search for component by its name, we can't just provide a string.
We have to provide an object and specify that we're looking for a component by its name and there's
only going to be one of them.
So this is super safe and the components name that we're looking for within our organizations component
is job filters.
Sidebar.
CheckBox group.
That's what we're looking for.
It's right here.
Organizations filter right here.
Organizations filter checking the values of the unique values and mutation props that are flowing in.
And that's correct.
And that's really to repeat what our component cares about.
The responsibility of the organization's component is basically to render a checkbox group and pass
in the correct props so it doesn't care about how checkbox group is going to execute its logic.
All the cares about is gathering up the required pieces, which is the mutation name and the unique
organization's to pass down.
And that's why I'm testing the props here.
I'm simply verifying then passing down the right values for the data.
And I'm going to test the logic for CheckBox Group in it's test.
The only responsibility of this organization's component is to pass down the right data for that component
to do its job.
So I'm basically testing the architecture, the setting up of the logic without worrying about the actual
checkboxes themselves.
All right.
So that completes two of our new test suites.
Finally, step three, we're going to need to do the same thing for our new degrees component.
So right here in that same test directory, I'm going to create a new file.
I'm going to call it job filters, sidebar.
And this is going to be degrees dot test.
That's.
All right.
There we go.
Let me move this to the left, claps my panel and once again, same logic.
Let me copy over shallow amount.
Let me copy over our imports of our composable and their mocks.
There we go.
So for our degrees component, we're using the use unique degrees composable.
So we don't need job types or organizations, which means we don't need these two lines saved up.
And we also, of course, need to import a new component that is going to be our job filters, sidebar
degrees component that is going to come from the source directory components, job results, job filter,
sidebar, job filter, sidebar degrees right here.
And I'm also going to double check that I add the view extension at the end right here.
I'm going to invoke my described function, tell the test utils ingest that I am testing it sidebar
degrees provide my arrow function and of course here I can copy over the final test we have right here
and make as always the necessary adjustments.
So comment that in cut it paste it right here.
All right.
Once again, we no longer need these two masks.
Those are now tested in separate components.
So delete the first two lines right here.
We are no longer mounting the sidebar.
We're mounting the John's other sidebar degrees.
Once again, we have a little bit of a throwback.
This is not really a job types filter.
This is actually a degrees filter.
So let me change that constant name right here.
Again, you know, a warning to all developers about the dangers of copying and pasting.
Once again, what I'm going to do here is look for a component by name instead of a data.
Just attribute.
The component we're looking for is once again going to be job filters, sidebar, checkbox group.
And just to prove that to you, of course I can open up the component that would probably be helpful.
So here is our job filter sidebar degrees component, same deal.
It orchestrates and fetches the required data that it needs to render a specific instance of checkbox
group.
And all we care about is the passing of the right data via props to this component.
So we no longer care about the header prop because that doesn't exist.
We only care about unique values in mutation.
Let me delete my former line that was testing the value of header.
All right, so now we have the exact same test here and everything is passing perfect.
So now we have tests for our three new components.
And also in our sidebar test, this one has become a lot simpler, which of course also allows us to
clean up some logic right here.
So let's go ahead and remove all of our former imports and mocks were no longer using these marks anywhere
because again in our sidebar that composable logic is captured in these components, not at this top
level.
And because we are shallow mounting, we don't need to worry about what these chopped components are
doing inside their bodies.
So right here, I can get rid of that.
Right here.
Perfect.
And then let's see if we actually still need to mark out view.
I think we will need to do that in order to mark out use store right here in order to get this logic
to work.
So I am going to keep the short amount.
I am going to keep out, keep the mark of UCS.
But you can see how this component has also simplified significantly and also the tests for it have
simplified as well.
So once again, have we really built anything different?
Not necessarily.
All we really did was split up the logic and the complexity of the setup method.
It's a much smaller, simpler components, and thus that allows us to write much simpler, smaller tests
that don't need to mock out that many variables.
Right.
If you're writing a test and you're discovering that you're marking out five or six different things,
you have to ask yourself, why are you doing that?
Can those five or six different mocks really be put into smaller units, smaller classes, smaller functions,
smaller components?
And that will allow you to mock out one thing or two things, right in a given test instead of having
to bundle all this logic up top.
So hopefully by playing around with this component and trying to, you know, figure out the right balance
of what do we put in a component file.
Hopefully this exercise of coming full circle of starting with three separate components, then building
a reusable checkbox group and then going back to having three separate components each one rendering
a specific checkbox group.
Hopefully, it's been a fun experience to see how these three factors help us build a cleaner and better
components.
Right.
It's a really tough question to answer, which is what is the right size of a component or what is a
single responsibility component?
That it's not something that you can always capture in a view tutorial which can just teach you about,
you know, the options API or composition API.
These are more higher level architectural design decisions.
And hopefully by reasoning through a lot of this logic, you can see how we've arrived, the components
that I certainly think are better off than what we had.
Right.
This is a lot easier to understand.
This is a lot simpler a setup method.
It's a lot simpler of a test suite to reason about right here, for example, etc..
So the amount of code we're writing and the simplicity with which we can read it is sort of communicating
to me that this is a better design than what we have.
All right.
So hopefully this has been fun and I will see you in the next lesson.