Okay.
So we only have one job listing in our job listings component, but already it is becoming sort of bloated.
There's a lot of lines of code in this file.
So as always, whenever you get a really complex component, it might make sense to break it up into
lots of smaller components.
So I propose that we move the idea of a single job listing.
So this list item starting here and proceeding all the way to here, I propose that we move that into
its own separate view component.
It sort of makes sense logically because each one of those boxes represents its own reusable chunk of
UI right on the real Google Careers website.
We're going to have a list item for every single job listing.
If we have ten of them, we're going to have this chunk of code repeated ten times.
So whenever you have that repeatability and you want to enable it to be reused over and over, it makes
sense to extract it to a component.
That way we can render that component as many times as we need and have all of this code repeated without
having to copy and paste it literally in this file.
So let's copy all of our code, starting from this ally element insider ordered list.
So from line four here to the end of my ally here in line 55 and I'm going to go to my explorer and
within my job results directory right here, but not inside job filter sidebar, just job results.
I'm going to create a file and I'm going to call it job listing dot view.
So just be careful here because it is singular in comparison to our job listings component which is
storing all of the job listings.
This is just the view component to represent just one of them.
So in here I will use my template tag and I'm going to paste the code that we copied from the other
file.
Of course it is very ugly now, but the beautiful part of Prettier and I love doing this is saving this
and seeing an auto format for it for me immediately.
So with that we have copied over that code.
Let me go to my bottom section here and add my script tag.
And we're going to export default to a JavaScript object with a name property set to job listing, add
a line break at the bottom, save that and that is a good place to leave off.
In the very next lesson, we're going to use this job listing component repeatedly in job listings.
So I will see you there.