All right.
So I do want to show you one more advanced feature related to lazy loading.
It's not particularly helpful for our app because we have a really small number of components and views.
But you can imagine that this would be pretty helpful if you have 100 different views in your app.
So what we can do is we can tell View Seelye and Webpack to gather up multiple views into a pre-configured
chunk.
And what we really mean by the word chunk is just a JavaScript file.
So the way that Vue works by default, as we saw in the previous lesson, is it creates a separate JavaScript
file for every Vue.
So one for home, one for job results, one for job.
But maybe we figure out, based on analyzing traffic to our website, that the job results, Vue and
the job view are very closely related.
So a user will always visit the first and then the second.
If we find, for example, that pattern and we say, Hey, both of these views are pretty lightweight,
for example, and we may want to consolidate them into a single JavaScript file so that if the user
visits the first one, they'll get the code for all of those components immediately.
And obviously if they have the code cached, then when they navigate to the second view, we don't need
to make an extra request for a new JavaScript file and it will be a little bit of a smoother and faster
experience.
Again, when you want to do this is sort of a matter of tradeoffs, right?
Do you want to put more code in the file to increase its size for a user benefit in certain situations?
If you discover, for example, that both files are really small?
Or do you want to hold off because the user may not visit any of those second pages?
Right.
It's really up to you to decide when is a good idea to do this.
But I do want to show you how we can consolidate multiple imports and multiple views and lazy loads
into a single JavaScript file to break from the convention that we saw in the previous lesson of one
file per view.
So here's what we do.
What we do is inside our import function we can provide a comment.
And that comment is actually what Webpack uses to identify the separation of the chunks or in other
words, the JavaScript files.
So right here before the string that specifies the component, I'm going to use this syntax, the JavaScript
comment syntax with a slash and a star, right?
And this is the exact syntax that Webpack is looking for.
And what I do here is I provide a property name, which is not up to us.
It's going to be web webpack chunk name.
And then I provide a colon very much like JavaScript objects in text and then in double quotes or a
string.
I provide the name of the JavaScript file here that I want this view to be included in.
So let's say I decide to call this file jobs, right?
Because this is sort of related to the concept of jobs on my site, right?
So this chunk, this code, the view JavaScript that is needed to render the job results view is now
in its own chunk, in web part called jobs.
And what I want to do is I also want to include my job view in that same JavaScript file, in that same
chunk.
Well, all I have to do is copy this code and put it in the import statement here as well.
So let me just copy this right here and put it here again as a comment before our actual import component
and make sure you close the comment off.
Otherwise view and JavaScript will think that the rest of the line is also a comment.
So it's going to look like that.
And because we gave both of these functions and both of these views, the same Webpack chunk name,
Webpack knows to associate them together.
And similarly, if we added a third view and we gave it the same Webpack chunk name, it would know
to associate them with this Jobs JavaScript file.
And later on, if we wanted to consolidate three other files in their own separate chunk, let's say
we have like a user page write user profile.
We might have a Webpack chunk name of user and that's its own separate category.
And whichever imports we put in that category view, Seelye and Webpack will bundle up.
So this is almost like the parent folder, even though it represents a file.
But you can almost think of this as the kind of organizational tool that we use to tell Webpack which
views to include together, right?
So you can have more than one Webpack chunk name, but those are the parent categories under which you
want to include those given files.
Now, in the case of home view, I'm not going to give a Webpack chunk name.
So it's just going to go back to its default implementation and that default file name that we saw in
the browser.
But for these two, I'm going to load a single file containing the code for both of these components.
Whenever the user accesses either of these two routes, they're going to get that single jobs JASS file,
and that's going to hold the code for both of these components.
So let's see how this works in my browser.
So I'm going to go to Chrome.
Let me clear all this and let me go to my home page and refresh and we're going to see our app file.
That is the core of your code and here is the home view code.
That's the exact same thing we saw in the.
Previous lesson.
And now when we go to the jobs page, number one, we're going to lazy load, add that new file.
So there it is.
And notice that it has the exact same name as we gave to the Web park.
Chunk name property.
It's called jobs.
Yes.
And this file will include the component code for both this page and the individual jobs page.
So if I go to an individual jobs page like slash jobs, slash results, slash six, when I go to this
page, you'll notice that we don't have anything new in the network tab because we already have this
file loaded and this file already has this content.
Again, I can prove that to you by searching in this file for sample text like job, page for job and
you'll see there is a match and here is that text that is being rendered on to the screen.
So this chunk, which is basically just a JavaScript file, includes everything we need based on what
we specify in the router file.
If we had another component and we gave it the same comment, it would also be included in this jobs
file.
And so we can have as many web pack chunks as we want.
We simply specify the category files that we'd like to use to store components, and obviously it makes
sense to group components together that are likely to be used together, which means the user is likely
to go from one component to the other.
It doesn't make sense to put in components that are super far from each other, like the jobs page in
the help page, because it's unlikely that the user is going to go from one to the other at that point.
You can lazy load smaller components as needed, but still bundle up related content in one file so
the user gets everything up front again.
It's a matter of balance.
It's a matter of looking at your file sizes and your user traffic and how the user navigates your site.
Again, that's kind of an advanced feature because it's mostly analytical and dependent on team and
code base and product, etc. But I hope that at least the syntax has been easy to understand and the
value and benefit has been easy to understand as well.
Obviously for a project this size not really that important because it's pretty lightweight as it is.
But when you're dealing with huge view apps with hundreds of components and hundreds of views, it may
make sense to consolidate and organize your code like so.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.