All right.
So in this lesson, we're going to introduce the idea of computed properties in view.
Computed properties sometimes can be a little bit confusing, not because they're difficult to understand,
but because they function pretty similarly to how our data properties work.
But they are reserved for a specific use case in view.
And that use case is whenever we have data that is dependent on other pieces of data or put in other
words, data that is derived from other pieces of data.
So what that means is in our data object right here, we want to put our independent properties, our
properties that are independent, meaning they don't depend on anything else.
They exist totally separately from anything else.
In comparison, our computed properties is where we want to put any pieces of information that are dependent
on other pieces of data that change, but only change as other pieces of data change around them that
are derived, or in other words, that come from calculations based on other pieces of information.
So computed data is dependent on some other data.
And the reason we use computed is to not duplicate the original data in an alternate format.
That's a lot to take in.
So let me give you an example in this lesson, and this example has nothing to do with our specific
job app, so you do not need to copy the code that I am writing.
It's just for the purposes of example.
So imagine that we are modeling the idea of a square on our screen and as you know, a square is going
to have a width and height, which is going to be some kind of numeric measurement.
So let's say I have two pieces of data here.
I'll set a width of ten and a height of five, and those values are just arbitrary.
Again, we're pretending that we're modeling a square on screen and let's say what we want our view
app to do is to render the area of the square on screen.
Well, the area of the square is not an independent, a piece of data, quote unquote.
It is a dependent or derived piece of data.
It is always the same.
It is dependent on the product of the width and the height.
If we multiply the width and the height of a square together, we get the squares area.
Well, here's sort of the wrong way to go about it in view.
Let's say if I want to output my area on the screen, I decide to add an area property to my data object
and set it to a value of 50.
All right.
And what I want to do, of course, is display this area on the screen.
So I'm just going to copy this button right here.
Again, you do not have to follow along.
And the only reason I'm copying and pasting it is just so we have a little bit of separation with our
original code right here.
So let's say right here, I'll have a second button and I will render the area of our square on the
screen.
So if I go back to my web browser, you'll see this second button right here and it has a text of 50.
All right, so that looks great.
But let me introduce a caveat to our design.
Let's say we want this button to be clickable.
And when we click the button, we want to double the height.
We want to double the height of the square.
All right.
So how do we how would we implement something like this knowing the features that we know in view?
Well, we can, for example, add a method that will double the value of the height data attribute.
So, for example, I can add a methods key to my view configuration object and I can define a method
of my choosing such as double height.
And we know that in these view methods we can access any property on our data object using the this
keyword.
So I can take whatever is the value of my height attribute and I can multiply it by two to double it.
And the reason we're doubling it is totally arbitrary.
It's just to come up with some example where we are modifying the height property and then of course
this will get us the new height, but we need to save it back to the height property on our data object.
So I'm going to access this start height and I'm going to overwrite it with its new height value.
So this will double the height.
Now, this will create a method to do that, but we obviously need to trigger that method and we can
do that with the V on directive.
So right here I'm going to use the shortcut syntax, which is act click as a reminder.
This is a shortcut for V on click.
It means that whenever the user clicks the button, we tell view which method to run and we want to
run the double height method.
Once again, we're going to write that method without any parentheses.
We just specify the method for view to execute.
So obviously what we want to do here is click the button and double the height, which should in turn
in a dream scenario, update the area as well, because the area is a dependent calculation on the width
and height updating.
So of course if I go back to my browser, this is not what's going to happen.
As I click this button, our height is going to update, but our area that we display here is not going
to and I can actually show you this in The View DevTools If I go to my View DevTools and I find my action
button and I update it right here with this little refresh icon, and I click the button again and refresh
again, you can see.
My height just doubled from 80 to 160.
But my area did not.
Right.
So in other words, our area property is dependent or derived from these two properties of height and
width.
But of course, it's not going to change alongside the height and width because view has no clue the
area is actually a derived property of these two.
From views perspective, we just added this arbitrary area property to data that is its own piece of
information set to 50 and nothing is changing it.
Right?
So how do we handle something like this in view?
How do we have a property that automatically updates as another property updates?
Well, you could say, can't we manually hardcoded this in our double height method?
Can we do something like this?
That area is going to be this height, times this that width.
And the answer is technically we absolutely can.
But if we go with this approach, we are following a more imperative approach.
And what imperative means is we're being a lot more manual, we're writing a lot more code.
We now have to remember that any time, either height or with changes, we need view to recalculate
the the value of the area property.
And that can be problematic because we may forget, right?
We may have a method that modifies the width attribute and totally forget that area is dependent on
it.
And you can imagine in a more complex application, we may have six pieces of data that determine another
piece of information.
And thus any time any of those six properties change, we would similarly have to update the dependent
property.
And the beautiful part of view is Vue offers us a solution for this exact problem where we don't have
to manually keep track of this kind of information.
So in other words, we can tell you to compute the value of area from scratch every time that either
width or height changes.
All right.
That's what computed properties do.
They are computed.
They are re-evaluated by view based on some kind of dependency or some kind of other piece of information
changing.
They are derived data because they are dependent on something else changing.
They are not original independent pieces of data.
Rather, computed properties are a alternate representation or a piece of information that is dependent
on some other piece of information throughout the app.
So in this case, our computed property can be something like our area property.
Instead of making it a piece of data, we can make it a computed property that changes any time, either
width or height.
Change view will keep track of those changes and automatically update area whenever we update either
All right.
So how can we make something like that happen technically?
So here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to remove my area property from my data and right below my data I'm going to add my computed
property to my view configuration object.
So again, the computed name is not up to us.
It is a built in name, much like data, much like methods, much like props.
It has to be called this.
So it is going to be a plain JavaScript object.
And I'm going to add a comma here just so we don't have an error.
And this works the exact same way as our methods object does in that we define methods in here, not
properties, but methods.
So I'm going to define a method called area.
All right?
So I'm going to do this and I'm going to provide the function body right here and in this area, method
body.
We have access to our data properties as well, just like we do in our methods down below.
So all we have to do here is return some kind of evaluation, some kind of value can be a string can
be a number, a boolean, an array, etc. It's kind of like a piece of data, but a piece of data that
is computed or derived from another piece of data.
So if I want to calculate the area, what I want to return is this dot with which I can access using
the this keyword times, this dot height.
All right.
So what we do when we write a computed method in this case, in View's terminology, is Vue says, I'm
going to keep track of anything you reference in the body of this method.
So in this scenario, we are referencing the width and height data properties.
So Vue knows that whenever either the width property or the height property update or both, but really
just either one view will rerun the area method, whatever it's being used to get.
The new calculation of area.
And the beautiful part of this approach is we no longer need this logic and Line 30 view will handle
this automatically for us.
And now, irrespective of whether we change, whether height view knows, that area depends on those
two pieces of information.
And similarly, if we had six pieces of data here, view would know that any time any of those six values
change, area should be updated.
All right.
Now, luckily, the syntax is not going to change in our templates.
You'll see here we're using our a curly brace syntax, our interpolation syntax, which we've used previously
for data properties.
But we can treat our computed methods the exact same as our data properties.
So right here we have area.
Notice that I'm not invoking that method.
I'm writing it as if it's a regular data property.
The difference is, is that this is a dynamic computed value that will automatically update when anything
here changes.
So now I'm going to keep the code exactly as is.
I'm going to go back to my browser.
When I click this button, we're going to execute the double height method view will first update the
height data attribute, which is independent, and then because the computed properties know to track
the changes in height, it will automatically recalculate the value of area.
And once those changes are done, view of course, will re render the canal and the new area will now
appear in our template.
Right.
So we use it the exact same way as we do a data property, but it is a derived or dependent piece of
data.
So now if I go back to my browser, we're going to start off here with an area 50 and a height of 160.
In fact, let me refresh.
So we go back to our original values.
So here we're going to have our height of five and our width of ten.
You'll notice that Vue will calculate the initial value to be 50.
And as I click this button one time, beautiful.
Our height has been updated to ten, which means our computed property of area has been recalculated
to be 100 and once again going to double my height.
My height is now going to go to 20, 20 times ten is 200, an area becomes 200.
And our template, which is rendering the area you can see right here is updating every single time
I click the button.
So that is the beautiful part about computed properties.
They are re-evaluating or recalculating or re computing any time something changes.
Another perfect use case of this in a real world is something like currency.
You can imagine, for example, if we are storing a piece of data that represents some amount of money,
let's say, you know, $2, but in sense, right, let's say we're storing our data in sense so we have
200 cents.
But let's say on the screen, we want to model an alternate representation of that data, such as a
dollar amount for that amount of sense.
While the dollar amount is not an independent piece of data, it's not a separate, distinct piece of
information.
Rather, it's an alternate representation or a derived representation from an actual piece of data.
That piece of data being the number of sets.
So we do not want to create a duplicate copy of that data, just an alternate representation of it,
because then we have to track two pieces of data.
And in any time one of them changes, we have to change the other one, rather, that is a perfect use
case.
To use something like a computed property, we can keep a piece of data that tracks the sense and we
can make a computed property that represents that amount of sense in dollars because that piece of data
is not duplicated, then it is simply recalculated or re derived from the original piece of data.
So that is when we use computed in view.
It's very similar to data because we can do the same things with it.
We can put it in our template visually.
We can use it to bind to a attribute using something like the bind.
We use it the exact same way as we use data, but the difference is when we use it, we use computed
when the data is not independent, when it is derived from something else.
All right.
So hopefully that's a good explanation.
And in the very next lesson, we're going to see how we can use the computer property to deal with our
access costs for our original button.