All right.
So hopefully by now we have a decent sense of how we can emit events in view.
This is how we allow our child components to communicate that something has happened to their parent
components.
Now, as I'm looking at our current design, it does work, but I do have some issues with it.
And I'm curious if we can build out a better implementation to solve those issues.
So here are three problems that I see with our current design.
The first problem is that we are duplicating data across both our job search form component and each
text input component.
So of course, the way we built it out, our text input component keeps track of the changes through
its own data property and then it emits that handle input event to the parent where the parent updates
the appropriate property, whether it be a role up here or location up here.
So that keeps the data or the values in sync between the two components.
But it still creates two sources of truth, even if those two values are equal.
It begs the question Do we need to have two places where we are storing this data?
Can we just have one location, one component that knows the value of the role and the location input?
Do we need to duplicate this data?
What is the benefit?
Because if for some reason our data gets out of sync, if our text input stores one value and our job
search form holds another while, then who do we trust?
Right.
So data duplication is generally not a good thing because we're trying to keep track of just one piece
of information, just the role or just the location.
So that's the first issue I have with the current design.
The second issue I have is with our current input code or our handle input event handler right here.
As I mentioned, the syntax works, but it's a little bit imperative versus declarative.
So if you haven't heard of those two terms before, declarative code is where we describe what should
happen and imperative code is where we describe how something should happen.
And generally the how is considered a worser way to build the software programs because it's a lot more
manual and verbose.
So in this scenario, we have to know the details of how the handle input event is going to be relayed
from the child.
We have to know the syntax.
We have to know that we're going to receive the payload in that dollar sign event object.
Of course, it's not that complex to understand, but when you compare it to something like V model
where it's a lot more declarative and Vue handles a lot of that logic behind the scenes, for us, this
approach is a little bit more imperative.
It's a little bit more verbose, specific, explicit with us having to write out this code and know
some details about Vue to make it happen.
So this is okay.
But again, I'm curious, can we do a little bit better than this?
Right.
Finally, my third problem is that our text input component offers no way to customize the starting
value of the text input, because whenever we render a text input, we're always going to have this
value data property.
It's always going to start out as an empty string and thus the input is going to render with no text
in it.
And sometimes you do want to be able to render a text input that starts out with some pre-configured
value.
For example, if the user is updating a form and you want to pre fill some of those form fields out
so they don't have to enter them again.
Right.
For example, you may fetch a record from the database that has some information and you may want to
populate the form fields automatically so the user doesn't have to type it out.
In those situations, it'd be great if our text input component was flexible enough to support starting
out with any starting value, perhaps an empty string or perhaps a preconfigured string.
Right.
So those are three problems that I can identify right now duplication of data, an imperative approach
to reacting to events, and no way to customize the starting value of our text.
There's probably more issues to be found, but those are the kind of issues that I think we can fix
by coming up with a better solution for how we design our text input.
Reusable Components.
So let's start with our data duplication problem.
And what I propose we do is instead of creating separate data on each text input component, I propose
that we feed in the data via a prop.
So what that means as our parent component in this case job search form, can provide a new prop, and
that prop will represent the current value that is within the component.
All right.
It's a little bit complicated because we're still going to need to have an interaction between our parent
and our child.
But I propose the parent will be the one that's always going to know what the current value of the data
should be, the current value of the input field, and it's going to feed it in as a prop.
All right.
Let me show you how this is going to work.
So let's stick with our text input component right here and let's go ahead and remove our entire data
object right here.
Okay.
So we're no longer going to have any data belonging to this text input component.
And as I mentioned, let's say we're going to get the value that should be rendered within the input
component from a prop.
And let's call that prop value.
All right.
So again, I'm going to configure a prop.
So I'm going to provide a new property in our prop object.
The parent component will give me a prop called the value.
That props type will be a string.
And I'm going to say that it is going to be required.
So whenever we render a text input component, whatever parent renders, it has to give me a value prop.
Okay, so here in my methods, you'll notice that we are overwriting a value property and that value
property is a data property that no longer exists.
So for now, let's delete this line.
We don't need any local data, so I'm going to delete this line.
And here, instead of providing this that value which no longer exists, well, to be fair, it does
actually exist, but it now exists as a prop.
But I of course want the latest entry into the form or the input that is.
And of course I can always get that by talking to my event object and getting its target property and
then its value property on that object.
So whatever the users just typed in, I'm still going to emit upwards via the handle input event.
However, I'm going to get it not from the local data property but just from whatever is on the event
object.
Now, a few things worth noting here before we proceed.
The first thing is you'll notice that we were previously using V Bind to bind to the valid value data
property.
So whenever the value data property changes we would update the corresponding value attributes.
So the input field would reflect that new text.
This syntax is still going to work.
We are still binding to something dynamic, something that is changing.
But now this value reference is not going to be a value data property, but to our value prop and that
is totally fine.
We use the exact same syntax.
If we get a prop from our parent or we have a data property or we have a computed property for that
matter, we can still reference any of them in our template using this syntax.
So this value is now referencing this value prop that the parent will provide.
And if for some reason the parent gives us a different value for the value prop, not a problem because
we bind as dynamic, it will automatically sense that change and re render the text input component
when the parent provides a different value for the value prop.
Okay.
Another side note that I'd like to mention is we are getting this prop called value and the general
best practice is you should never overwrite props in your child component, so you should never do something
like this that value equals.
And the reason you don't want to do that is because you're creating a data mismatch between the parent
and the child.
So props represent another component, the parent components data flowing into the child.
And if we overwrite that data, that prop in the child, but the parent still has the original value
that creates a potential problem and a mismatch.
We want to keep a single source of truth, so props should ideally only flow down.
The parent provides a prop value to the child and the child should never modify it.
It should just do something with it.
Now what happens if you need to use props to, for example, formulate a piece of data, right?
In that case, you should copy the prop that you're receiving in the child, and then you should modify
the copy.
You should never affect the parents prop that flows in because that is data that you do not control.
Right?
So you're always want to separate yourself from the prop data that is flowing in from the parent.
Right.
It's not really relevant in this scenario.
But just as a heads up, we have a value prop that is available under this thing.
And you never want to do something like this because we're overwriting a prop that is supposed to be
basically like read only data coming down from the parent.
All right.
You'll even see an error right here where it says from a slant, unexpected mutation, a value prop.
So it's a good practice to never mutate.
Props only use them.
And if you need to use them for some kind of custom data in our text input component and create a copy
of that prop or just use it separately from the original this that value reference.
Okay.
So with that, we now are depending on a value prop.
We are still emitting a handle input event with the current value from the event generated from the
browser whenever the user types letter n.
And so in the very next lesson, we're going to react to that event and see how our implementation changes
in job search form.