Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to show you a super cool optimization we can make in our hero component as
it relates to our props object that we are getting from our child.
We can actually de structure this object in line the same way that we do structure properties of an
object in E6 in regular JavaScript, we can actually do this in view.
So right here between my double quotes, I'm going to do structure the properties off that object that
I care about, some almost going to ignore giving that object a name and I'm simply going to pull out
the properties on it that I want to use in my template below.
So obviously I want the image property, I want the title property and I want the description property.
And the reason we're getting an error right now, the red squiggly is because Vue is telling us, hey,
your destruction of these properties, but you're not using them anywhere.
And the reason for that is because we still have our old references to the slot props object in these
three locations.
So let's update them here.
Instead of referencing IMG on slot props, we can now use it immediately in line like so here.
Instead of interpolating the value of the title property on slot props, we've already pulled off that
title property above so we can simply interpolate title.
And right here, instead of writing the property description on the slide props object, we're going
to de structure the exact same description property right here and we can simply write it in line,
save that, and that helps make our syntax a little bit cleaner.
Right.
And it kind of reinforces the core idea of the section is that view is going to bundle up all the props
that we passed and the child and object made available in line here.
Right?
And now we're just using JavaScript concepts on that object and everything is still going to work as
expected in our browser.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.