Okay.
So once we receive our hundred jobs from the API, we want to create a job listing component for each
one.
So whenever we have a situation where we have some kind of collection such as our jobs array and we
want to iterate over it and create an HTML element or a component for each, we know that we can use
the View V4 directive.
So right here, I'm going to remove my second and third occurrence of the job listing component.
And right here I'll keep a single job listing and I'm going to add the V4 directive to the end of it.
So V4 and we of course have to provide some kind of iteration right here.
So I want to iterate over every job in jobs.
So jobs here is a reference to our jobs data array below.
It's going to start out with an empty array.
So view is going to iterate over an empty array and not render anything.
Then when the backend returns 100 jobs, we're going to overwrite data, V0 will re render and it's
going to have 100 jobs.
So it's going to render 100 job listing components.
Right?
And then this name right here refers to the individual job object that we are iterating over.
It can be whatever name we want, but typically we're going to give it the singular name compared to
the plural collection.
So if we're iterating over jobs, we're iterating over a single job object, and that's what we want
to provide here.
Okay.
So right now we're getting an error.
And the reason for this is whenever we use V4 as a reminder, we need to provide that key attribute.
And that key should be a unique identifier that Vue can use to distinguish all these different job listings
from each other.
I need some kind of criteria that it can use to tell apart every job listing that it renders in order
to be able to perform its algorithm within where I can determine changes.
So we need to give the key attribute right here some kind of dynamic value that is unique for each iteration.
Well, every job object is going to have an ID property from the backend, and that ID property is unique.
It is the idea of the job.
So here of course we can do job that ID.
Now of course this is going to be problematic because if we use this syntax, then Vue is going to think
we're providing a string with the literal character's job.
DAT ID We need a dynamic reference to the job objects ID property, the job we defined right here in
our iteration, we need a dynamic reference to whatever is the value for tidy property.
So of course we need to use the V bind syntax by using the colon here to bind the key attribute to whatever
is the value of the ID property on the current job that we are iterating over.
So job one of 100 will have ID one, so the key will be one.
The next job in our iteration will have an ID property equal to two.
So our key will be two all the way to 100.
So we give you 100 unique identifiers for 100 unique job listings and it's all good to go.
The other thing that I would like to do is to pass down a prop to our job listing component.
Now, we don't have any code in our job listing component to react to this prop, but obviously what
we need to pass down to the job listing is the actual job data from our back end.
And that way our job listing component can take that data and render a dynamic title, a dynamic city,
a dynamic description, etc., because right now all of the text in job listing is hardcoded.
So when we go to a browser, we're actually going to see 100 of the same job listed.
We're not going to see any of the data from here back in just yet.
We're just going to render 100 job listings because our back in gave us 100 objects.
So for future proofing, when we come back to the job listing component, I'd like to pass down a prop
called Job and I want to make it equal to the current job that we are iterating over.
So I'm going to pass down the full object with all those properties that we saw in DB, that JSON,
I'm going to pass it down and here the same rules apply.
If I stick with the syntax, I am going to pass down a job prop, but it's going to be equal to the
string job.
I don't want to do that.
I want to pass down the full job object.
So I need to use the bind it to bind to this prop called job that I again have not defined in job listing
that we will define in a lesson or two.
So I will pass down the full job object and that enables us to use it in that component.
So now let's take a look at what's going on in our browser and you can see this page has already become
pretty long and you guessed that we have 100 job listing components being rendered.
Why?
Because our back end returned 100 jobs.
So we have an array of 100 elements and Vue is going to iterate over all of them with the V4 and render
100 identical job listing components.
So we are moving in a really, really good direction.
None of this data is dynamic and that's what we have to fix in an upcoming lesson.
But we are making good progress with receiving data from the backend and changing our view to react
to that data.
If the back end sent over six records, we would see six job listings.
If the backend sent over a thousand records, we would see a thousand.
And that's the beautiful part is that we're reacting dynamically to that batch of data all there is
to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.