Okay.
So with our discovery of the slot feature in view, we have moved the accordion component one step closer
to being very reusable, but there's still one bit of it that is hardcoded and that is the header right
here.
We are always hard coding organizations, which means no matter how many accordions we render, we're
always going to have this text of organizations.
And obviously this is something that we want to vary in our browser.
For example, when we render multiple accordions right here, we want one for organizations, then one
for education, then one for job type, etc..
So what I'd like to do is to remove this hardcoded code and make it a little bit more flexible.
And that of course raises a good question, which is how do we solve this?
Right.
And that leads to another follow up question, which is, do we want to use slots or do we want to use
props?
You may recall props from earlier in the course.
Props allow us to provide inputs to our components.
So what is the key difference between the props and slots?
They're kind of similar in the sense that the parent component can provide some kind of information
down to a child component like an accordion.
Well, you typically want to use props whenever you have a simple value that is not HTML.
So in this scenario, we want the parent component in this case job filter sidebar to be able to pass
a simple string down to our accordion that we're going to be able to dynamically use here.
It's a basic string like organizations or job type or education for simple inputs like that, a prop
works great.
You can use a prop to pass down a string value, a number, a boolean, even something like an array
or a JavaScript object, right?
The difference between that and props is props allow you are slots.
Rather slots allow you to pass that a whole chunks of HTML.
Here we can see a perfect use case of slots.
We are able to pass down this complex bundle of HTML with a div and a field to an unordered list and
we automatically can tell Vue to inject it right here with the slot component.
So whenever we want to pass down custom HTML, we use slots whenever we want to pass down just a custom
piece of information, like a string or a number or a boolean, we use props instead, right?
When you're dealing with JavaScript constructs, use props.
When you're dealing with HTML constructs, use slots.
That's the key difference here.
So in this case, I simply want to allow the parent component to pass dummy prop, let's call it header
and whatever that header will be, I'm going to render it right here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to define a section in my script section where I'm going
to specify the props that the accordion component is going to receive.
So, for example, let's maybe do it right here.
We'll let the East London producer tell us if it's the wrong location.
Let's define a props object right here.
All right.
And in our props object, I'm going to specify the props this component will receive.
We've done this before in the course.
This is just for validation.
I will expect the accordion component to receive ahead of a prop.
We provide this with a validation object where we specify what hetero will be.
As a prop, we can provide the type property to specify that header will be a string and then we can
use the required property to specify that the header prop is required.
The parent needs to pass in the header prop whenever it renders an accordion component.
And remember, whenever we have header now we can reference it the exact same way that we would reference
a computed property or a data property we can render in line.
We can use it for a directive like this if it works the exact same way as local data.
The difference being that a prop is not local data, it is data that we get from our parent component.
So right here, instead of hard coding the text organizations, I'm going to use my double curly brace
syntax to output whatever value I get for my header prop.
All right.
So we have taken care of the problem on one side, but obviously we also need to take care of it right
here because here is where we're rendering the accordion.
So here is where we need to provide a valid value for that header prop.
So right here in line, I'm going to do a header and I'm going to provide it with an argument of organization's
it's the exact same value as we had previously.
But now obviously we can render as many different accordions as we want and give each one a different
header prop.
So if I go back to the browser, nothing should have broken.
And indeed we have the exact thing we want.
However, and this is hopefully where it all comes together.
Here is where we use both the power of props and the power of slots at the same time.
What I'm going to do is create another accordion component immediately above my organization's one.
So I'm going to render another accordion, and this one will also have a closing tag, and we're going
to provide this accordion with its own header prop.
So let's say this is going to be something different like job types.
It's going to be another criteria by which the user can filter the jobs.
And here I can put whatever custom content I want for my slots.
So for example, I can put a paragraph tag and just say something like placeholder for now.
Save this, go back to the browser.
And now we have the best of all worlds.
We have a very reusable accordion component for the simple variations like the header text right here.
We can it in our custom prop like we did with header and we have that difference now between these two
and for the nested children that we wanted to render.
We now use slots to render completely different content for each one of those accordion components,
while still retaining the reusable aspects of the collapse ability and the expandability and all of
that logic that deals with, for example, the care icon and its replacement.
So we have isolated all of that logic to the accordion component, but also made it flexible enough
to support all of the variation in header and child content.
So that is how you can mix and match props and slots for a really, really powerful view experience.
All right.
So with that, we have made tremendous progress.
But one thing that we have completely neglected to talk about is how we test for slots.
I'm going to talk about that in the very next lesson.