Okay.
So in this lesson, I want to introduce you to yet another helper function available in view X and it
is the map getters helper function.
So let's begin by importing it at the top of our script section.
So right above our component import, I'm going to import a named function called map getters.
And this is going to come from the U.S. So you probably can guess what this function does.
But let's do a quick review of all of the other map functions that we've used previously in the course.
And just to make this easy on the right hand side, I've opened up my store index tags file where we
have all of our configuration for the View X Store.
So you may recall that we have the map state function.
What does that do?
It allows us to map properties from our view X Store, state these things right here.
It allows us to map that to component computed properties.
Right?
Similarly, we have the map mutations helper function.
What that does is it allows us to map or connect these mutation methods as regular methods on my component.
Similarly, we have the map actions helper.
What does that do?
It connects these action methods to our component as plane component methods.
The key idea behind all of these helper functions is the same.
We want to take some part of the wax and make it available as some part of the component, right?
Usually as a local property or as a local method.
And if you think about what we're doing here in the computed property, we're doing something very similar.
We're defining a method, a computed property technically, but a method on our job filter, sidebar,
organization's component.
That method is called unique organizations, and all it does is it runs another method, which is the
getter method, honor view store.
So what Map Getters does is exactly what you might expect.
It allows us to have a shorthand syntax for connecting our getter methods to being regular component
methods.
So it's going to do exactly what we're doing here for us behind the scenes, but with a much shorter
syntax.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to comment out this code just so we can compare the before
and after.
And right here, I'm going to invoke my map getters function.
All right.
Now, just like many other Mac functions, this is going to return a JavaScript object.
And what we want to do is this structure the properties off that object, so they become top level computed
properties, right?
So this is actually going to be a combination of various reactive methods.
So we're going to take those methods and we're going to bring them out.
So there are top level computed methods on our job filter, sidebar organization's component.
Then what we give to map getters is an array of the names of the getter methods that we want to make
available on this component.
So in this case, we have just one getter.
It's called unique organizations, and luckily we have its name available here as an export it constant
unique organizations right here.
So I'm going to import this string and I'm going to pass it to my map getters function.
So right here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to import unique organizations.
That is the name of the getter method that we want to make available, and it's going to come from our
top level source directory, then the store folder and remember Node.js is going to look for an index
file by default.
So this is good enough to get it to find this file on the right.
Then what we provide to map getters is an array of the getter methods that we want to make available
on this component as methods.
So if I simply provide that string in unique organizations, what we're telling view is, Hey, find
the getter called unique organizations.
Find this thing right here and make it available as a top level.
This unique organization's method on my component.
So literally what we're doing is mapping getters or in other words, connecting getter methods.
Honor of using store to component methods on our component.
So this right here is doing the exact same thing as what we're doing on lines 36 to 38 is going to use
the name of the getter as the name of the component method.
It's going to be one in the same.
There is a way to customize that, but typically I just provide an array here and provide the name of
the exact getter name as it is in the store definition file.
And the advantage of this approach, of course, is if we want, for example, five getters, we simply
provide an array of five strings.
We don't need to manually define five computed methods, each one of which simply talks to a different
getter.
It's a much more simpler, shorter syntax for accomplishing the same thing.
So now what I'm going to do is remove this former code because we're accomplishing the same result.
Save this.
The test is going to rerun it, and we're going to see everything still passes because under the hood
it's doing the exact same thing that we were just doing manually.
It's just a little bit more of a shortcut.
All right.
So to summarize, what Map Getters does is it allows us to connect our getter methods from the view
store to become regular component methods.
We invoke the function, we do structure the return value, which is an object of methods.
And what we provide to map getters is an array of strings.
Those strings represent the getters that we want to move or map over from the UX to our component.
So in any other component that we want to use this getter, we can simply use this syntax again in the
computed property section.
And then the other component will also have access to this unique organization's set of unique organization
strings.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.