Okay.
So let's write a test for our new used confirmed root composable function.
So I'll open my file explorer.
And right here in the tests unit directory, I'm going to create a new folder and I'll call it composable,
mirroring the directory structure of my source directory and in composable I'll create my use confirmed
route dot test dot J.S. Test file.
Let me collapse my explorer.
Let me drag this to the right hand side and let's begin by importing our actual tested function which
is going to be used confirm route and automatically Vsco did it for me, but it's going to be the source
directory slash composable slash use confirmed out and here we'll write our describe for use confirm
root.
And there we go.
All right.
So as always, I'm going to argue the exact same things I've argued throughout the entire course.
We do not need to use the real use root function in order to test whether use confirmed.
Root does what it's supposed to do.
Our functions responsibility is to get an object from use root, but we can simply mark out, use root
and give any object back.
And as long as that object has a name property, we're going to be able to validate that.
All of the logic in these two lines is working as expected.
So the way that we're going to mark out view router or more specifically the user out function is going
to be the same in this file as it is for the component files where we've done similar marking before.
So right here at the very top, I'm going to import use root.
That's the exact same thing I'm using in my implementation and I'm going to get that from Vue router.
And then on the line below on my global just object, I'll invoke the MOC method pass in the library
that I want to mark out, which is Vue router.
So just is going to loop through that library and it's going to mark out every single named export including
use root, which means at this point, use root is going to be a just mock function that returns undefined.
But I don't need it to return undefined.
I needed to return an object with a name property because that's what used confirmed root needs in order
to be tested.
So right here, I'm going to write my description.
It determines if page root matches specified root.
So right here, I'm going to take you route, which at this juncture is going to be a just mock function
so I can invoke the mock return value method and tell it that whenever it's invoked, for example,
when the test suite runs my function on the left, I don't want it to return undefined.
I want it to return an object with a name property and let's provide a string here like home.
Then on the next line I can define a constant like root name just to provide a little bit of clarity
on what this is.
And I'll make my route name home.
Then what I'm going to do is invoke my use confirmed root function.
This is what I'm testing and I'll pass in my root name.
So in this case, because our root name of home matches the name property on this fictional or mock
root object, we should get back a true value.
But let me be a little bit more specific because use confirmed root is not going to give us back a boolean
of true or false.
Right?
It's going to give us a reactive object returned by the computed function that is storing that value
of either true or false.
In fact, it's updating it technically whenever the computed function runs because the root object changes.
So right here, I'm going to save this to accounts called Result.
And then the very next line, when I make my assertion, it's very important to understand here that
we don't just want to assert that result is going to be the values.
True.
That is not going to be the case.
Let me just show you that failure right now.
We're going to get a failure because what result is is not a boolean.
It's the reactive object from view that is storing that value plus all the additional reactive methods.
So on the object that we get back, which is what we get from computed, I'm going to access the value
property.
And I expect that to be true.
And that's the actual test and that is what is going to pass.
So with this setup where we are marking out use route, we are still focusing on what are use confirmed
root function is supposed to do.
We are still testing that.
We are accessing the right property on the object that we are comparing to the string.
We are capturing the heart of what our function is supposed to do without worrying about the implementation
of how use route works.
Once again, the reason this is a good idea is because if hypothetically something was broken in use
root and it broke, our test would fail.
But that wouldn't be a reflection of our code being wrong.
It would be a reflection of the view team's code being wrong.
And similarly, in the actual code base for Vue router, there are tests for use root that verify that
it is doing its own responsibility.
It is not our job to test other developers and other libraries code.
We only want to test our logic and our code base.
Our code base simply says use root will give me an object with a named property and then I'm going to
compare it.
That's all this function cares about.
That's all I want to worry about in my unit tests.
All right.
And just to show this is going to fail if I change this to something like homes, we're going to get
an object with a false value, reactive instead of true.
That's exactly what we get right here.
And similarly, if we were to change this implementation right here on the left to have some kind of
error, this would fail just as well.
So that's it.
That is our simple, plain single test for our composable function.
So now we've tested it and we're good to move on.
So I will see you in the next lesson.