Okay.
So let's talk about testing our fetch jobs action method.
There's two points I'd like to make here.
The first one, and this is similar to what I talked about before with mutations, is that we do not
have to test this method or this object while using it with view x.
This is a plain JavaScript object with a single asynchronous method, and this asynchronous method receives
a parameter of context which simply has to be some kind of object with a commit method on it.
That's all that this function is in isolation, and we can test it as such.
We do not need to spin up a view store in our tests in order to unit test this functionality, because
all of this functionality by itself is regular JavaScript.
We can write this code even without including view X.
Of course, view x needs this shape of object, which is why we include here.
But we could totally write this code right here without ever creating a store, and thus we can unit
test and isolate just this responsibility to a test and just test that the method does what we need
it to do, that it makes an API call and then it takes the context argument and takes that object and
invokes the correct method on it, which is commit.
Okay, that's the first thing I'd like to say.
The second thing is, you'll remember we have this get jobs API call right here and here's the function
that implements that.
This is where we have an asynchronous request that uses the Axios library to get our job results.
And some people might be tempted to import Axios into our test file so that we can make it out.
And that is definitely a step in the right direction because we are making our unit tests, true unit
tests.
We are testing each little component or functionality in isolation and we're not coupling it with other
services.
So this separates us from the need of a back end in our test suite.
But I argue that we can do better than simply mocking our Axios.
I propose that when we test this actually method, we simply mark out our own get jobs function.
Why is this a good idea?
Well, we already have tests for this function.
We have tests right here in the get jobs.
That test file where we validate that that function does what it's supposed to do and performs its responsibilities.
So I would argue the responsibility of this action method is not to ensure that jobs does what it's
supposed to do.
It's simply to invoke get jobs.
That's all that this method cares about, that I'm going to call this asynchronous method and I'm going
to get back something from it.
And whatever I get back from it is what I have to pass along in my committing or in my running of the
mutation.
That's all that this fetch jobs action to act cares about.
So in our test, we were actually going to mock this thing out.
We're going to say we're going to pretend we have a get jobs function.
And it's going to be a promise because it needs to be an asynchronous function and it's going to resolve
to give us back some kind of array of objects.
It's going to work the exact same way the real implementation works in the in the real world.
But we're going to be able to isolate the actual implementation of how get jobs works, even though
it is our own code.
The same principle applies.
We want to separate the testing of this method with the logic of what this function does right here.
So we're going to mock this thing out, have our our mock just function, return something very similar,
and then simply test this thing in isolation.
So let's see how that's going to work right here.
I'm going to import my get jobs function and that is available from the source directory and then API
and then get jobs and then immediately below I'm going to use the familiar just mock syntax.
We use this exact same syntax to mock out Axios earlier in the course, which is a foreign dependency.
It's an NPM library, but we can use this syntax the exact same way to mock out our own imports.
So right here I'm going to provide the exact same file path, the source directory API get jobs.
And now what Jess is going to do is it's going to go into this file.
It's going to find our get jobs function.
And it's going to replace it with a just mock function.
The exact same thing it does for Axios we're doing for our own code.
All right.
So down below, I'm going to create a new describe for to testing our actions.
And that reminds me, of course, that the very top of our file right here where we import our state
and mutations from our index, just file.
I also want to import my actions object.
This is this one right here and we are exporting it so we're good to go.
And right here we can describe our tests for our actions.
And I want to make a separate describe block for our new action, which is fetch jobs.
So there we go.
We're testing that one.
And what I'm going to do immediately, because I anticipate a couple of tests here, is I'm going to
add two before each.
And in the before each I'm going to mock out my get jobs function.
Now, it is already mocked out by just right here.
But as a reminder, the default just implementation of a mock is a asynchronous function that returns
the value undefined.
We want to get a little bit more specific here into how just should fake or mock out our get jobs API
call.
So right here it's going to be get jobs.
It is an asynchronous function.
So you may recall from earlier in the course we can use the method mock resolve value.
And the reason we're able to invoke this method is because this method is available on a just mock function
and get jobs at this point is not our original get jobs function, but rather the just mock function.
This object right here is what we get back when we create one manually.
And this is what just substitutes for get jobs as the test runs.
And there is this object that has the the method called macros all value.
So we want this function to behave like a promise that resolves to a specific value.
So it's going to be very similar to our get jobs function.
It's going to return an array of job objects and for now it's just going to be an array of one object.
We don't need to be complex and let's say I give it an idea of one and a title of software developer.
Really what we are specifying here is what this should return for the purposes of our test.
All right.
And it's going to happen once before each test.
So it's going to run this logic before every test runs in this described lock.
So we're going to add two tests immediately after hour before each right here.
The first thing I'm going to test in regards to our fetch jobs action is that it makes a request to
fetch jobs.
So what I'm going to do here is I, of course, want to take my actions object and I want to invoke
the fetch jobs method on it.
This is what I ultimately want to test.
So a couple of things to note here.
Number one, this is an asynchronous function.
So when I test this, I need to await this method to complete or to resolve.
Otherwise, we're going to continue running our test and we're going to reach the end before this method
resolves and we might get the wrong result.
So I need to basically pause execution until this function is done resolving or doing its asynchronous
action.
Keep in mind our asynchronous action is now our just function, which is going to replace the real world
implementation.
So it will still resolve instantaneously, but it will still pretend to be an asynchronous event.
That takes some amount of time, but it will obviously resolve basically instantaneously.
So I need to use the await keyword right here, and that means I have to make my test function async.
Now, in addition to making this async, I also need to provide an argument to fetch jobs.
I need this context object.
Right.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to create a plain JavaScript object.
And this should be enough to play the role because we don't need the real world view.
Context.
Object.
We just need one that is good enough.
The only caveat is on this line.
We are invoking the commit method on this object and if we try to reach out to commit on this object
on the right, we're going to get undefined and then we're not going to be able to invoke it.
So I do need some kind of property called Commit, and this can be any kind of function.
We can, for example, make it an arrow function that does nothing, etc. But the easiest thing in this
approach is to simply use another just a mock function.
All right.
So to reiterate, get jobs or it will be adjustment function.
And now our context object will be an object with a single property called Commit, which represents
that just mock function, which behaves like a function that can track its own calls, its own inputs,
etc..
All right.
We just need some kind of object that can play this role.
And all I really care about in this test is this first line that I am making the call to get jobs.
So I'm going to run this logic.
And then what do I want to test?
I want to test that my get jobs function has been invoked, which I can do because get jobs is a mock
function.
So right here I'm going to pass in my get jobs reference which we imported above.
And I'm going to invoke a method called to have been called.
And all that's going to assert on my mock object is that we have had at least one call to this function,
that this function has been invoked at least once.
You may have recall earlier we did two have been called with that as another alternative, but that
is when we want to test that.
We are invoking our mock function with a specific argument.
In this case, get jobs takes no arguments that we don't care.
And of course, I forgot to pass in context right here, if that is what we want to do.
Perfect.
So I'm going to bring up my terminal and let's run this and see what we get.
So right here, I'm going to run, NPM, run, test, call and watch.
Let's see if this fails.
And it passes, which is great.
And if we were using a TDD approach, we would write a test like this.
And when we were starting out, this method, of course would have no implementation.
So it would look something like this.
I'm going to comment out the code and you can see when we come at this out, we get a failure because
it says, hey, I was expecting get jobs to have been called at least once and I'm getting no invocations.
So now the the test is failing.
In fact, simply getting this line in here without the next one is enough to get the test to pass.
And that's exactly what we want.
We want to verify that the function or rather the fetch jobs action makes a request to fetch jobs,
which it does by talking to the get jobs function.
All right.
So that's our very first test.
Let's write our next one.
It's going to send message to save receive jobs in the store.
So here what I want to test is that we are calling the right mutation.
So we're going to follow very similar principle.
We're going to create a context object.
And inside I'm going to have a commit.
I properly set to a just function.
I'm going to save this just function to its own separate, constant, because we're going to need to
reference it later.
So right here I'll do a constant called commit and that will just be my just function.
I will provide that object to the context object as a commit property.
Then what I'm going to do is copy this code from above.
I'm going to actually run my asynchronous action and wait until it's complete, which means I need to
make this an asynchronous call.
There we go.
All right.
And then what do I want to test?
I want to test this line right here that I have invoked.
Commit on my context object and pass that the right arguments.
Well, now, when I run this logic, my commit method on this object is a just function.
So I can simply expect that I'm going to have invoked the right argument, the right method on on my
object, which is commit and I've passed the right arguments.
So I expect commit my method to have been called with.
And what two arguments do I expect?
Again, the first is going to be the string of receive jobs, because that is my constant.
And the second argument of course, is going to be job listings, which represents the return value
of get jobs.
Well, earlier on in our before we specified that get jobs is going to resolve to be this array.
So this is the exact same thing that I want to provide right here.
Here's my second argument.
The key takeaway here is I don't really care what this is.
All I really care about is whatever data structure this is.
I want the commit method to be invoked with that as the second argument.
That is the core crux and what this method is responsible for.
So this could be an array of three items.
It can be an array of one item.
I don't care.
It's up to you to specify how you'd like it to work.
All I really care about is that the exact same thing that get jobs gives back to me is what I want to
pass on to my commit method on my context object.
And I also want to make sure I provide the first argument of receive jobs.
I'm going to save that everything is passing.
Let me show you that.
If I get rid of this line, if we are following it to the approach, we would get the exact right failure.
So right here we can see we have a problem.
We're going to tell the test.
Hey, we expect the commit method to have been called one or more times and we expected these arguments
and just is going to tell us, hey, I never received any call.
You never called commit, right?
Similarly, if I go back to my original code but I remove my arguments, well then I am going to successfully
call commit, but not with the right arguments.
So now you're going to see my test output will be different.
We're going to say I received that argument, the function was called, but you called it with zero
arguments and I expected it to be called with these two.
Similarly, if I provide, I receive jobs.
Here is my first argument.
Our new output will say, Hey, you gave me the correct first argument.
I've received jobs, but I was expecting a second argument of this array of job listings that you that
we expect to get back from get jobs.
Right.
So this is a good sign that our test is doing what it's supposed to do because it's catching all of
those edge cases, all those ways of this code can go wrong.
So going to save our original code and everything is passing and that is how we test the asynchronous
action that we defined in the previous lesson.
All right.
So now we've wired up this asynchronous functionality, and we're going to see how we can use it in
the next lesson.