Okay.
So super cool lesson here.
In this lesson, I'm going to introduce a new view concept called input modifiers.
So just like the name suggests, an input modifier allows us to modify how an input works.
It's something we actually add to the V model syntax right here that customizes or modifies how this
input works.
So let me give you an example.
And in order to introduce the example, I want to introduce a problem that we currently have.
So the way our logic is currently set up, every single time the user types, a character, we're going
to rerun this logic right here.
So for example, if the user is searching for the term view, they're going to type the letter V and
viewers are going to detect that there has been some change to the V model.
And because the V model knows that whenever there's a change, it needs to run this logic, it's going
to commit a mutation to the View X store with the value of V, then the user types, the letter U and
this logically runs and then the user types, the letter E and this logic rewrites.
And so a user today can be pretty quick and typing.
So those three characters can happen in less than half a second.
And thus we're going to run at three separate mutations immediately, one after another.
Right.
And as you might probably guess, this is not super efficient, because if we could be a little bit
smarter, we could probably give the user the same experience while at the same time reducing the total
amount of work our app has to do.
For example, we could simply wait until the user's done is done typing and as soon as they're done
typing then we can simply commit one mutation to the store with the most up to date value and that would
accomplish the exact same thing but not have to make the app work so hard by committing all of these
smaller mutations along the way.
Right.
Especially users typing a lot of different characters.
Like ten characters, right?
For a big A name.
Do we really want to commit ten mutations if we can make the app feel faster and speedier by just waiting
until the user's done and then committing one right?
It's kind of smart and there's actually a technical term for this that exists outside of you.
And that technical terminology for this concept is called deep bouncing.
If you want to look it up, it's D and then bounce like bouncing a ball blue and C and all that D bounce
means is basically delaying an operation up until a right moment or after a given interval interval.
And that's exactly what we want to do here.
And the good news is, is that view makes it super simple.
This is something that is so common that Vue builds it directly into its library.
And it's going to look like this right here after V model.
We're going to put a dot and immediately you're going to see that V code offers me this prompt.
This is actually all of the input modifiers that are available on our text, the v model for this text
input.
Right.
And the one we want right here is the very first one lazy.
So I'm just going to press enter to confirm it.
And that's going to be the syntax V model, then a dot, then the input modifier which is called lazy,
and then the actual reference to the reactive object that is changing.
So you might be curious, why is it called lazy?
Well, if you think about a lazy person in real life, what is a lazy person?
It's someone who doesn't want to do any work until the last possible second.
Right.
So it's actually a pretty fitting term because it's very descriptive of what's going on here.
Vue is going to delay doing any of this reactive updating until the typing is done.
And more specifically, I think it's going to be when the user clicks out of the actual input.
So the user is going to type five letters, then they're going to click out and then Vue says, okay,
I'm going to be lazy.
I'm going to wait until the very last possible moment to do work.
Now I know the user is done typing.
Now I'm going to run this logic here which is going to commit the mutation.
So it really is as simple as adding this dot lazy in our code.
So let's save that and let's transition to Chrome to see this in action.
So I'm going to go to Chrome and just to be super safe, I'm also going to refresh because I have seen
this not work earlier when I did not refresh.
So here I have skills and qualifications and we saw earlier in the previous lesson, of course, that
as we typed multiple characters, they would immediately appear right here in skill search term because
every single character, again issued a new mutation, committed a new mutation with the most up to
date value here, which updated this.
Now notice what happens is I type, for example, five characters in a row.
You're going to notice the skill search term is not going to update immediately.
So here we go.
Here is five random characters.
And notice on the right hand side that skill search term has not updated.
So we have not yet committed a mutation.
But as soon as the user either clicks out of this box or presses enter, then that lazy modifier is
going to click in the gear and I'm going to click right here and notice there it is.
So as soon as I click out of that box, then View says, okay, I've been lazy, I don't want to do
any work.
Okay, now I have to do some work.
Now I'm going to commit one mutation, right?
The same exact rules are going to apply if the user presses enter.
So for example, if I remove a couple of characters here, notice that none of those issues mutation
you can see my skill search from in the view X store is the same but as soon as I press enter that immediately
registers that and that's typically what users do.
They either press enter or tab or they click out.
As soon as Vue detects those things that indicate the user is done expressing their thought and entering
their input.
Then we're going to update that thing right here, and that's really all there is to cover in this lesson.
It's called an input modifier.
That's the actual view feature because it modifies how an input works.
In this case, we used the lazy input modifier, which delays updating the reactive data until the user
is done typing and indicates so with a manual action.
Why do we want to do this?
Because it means the app is probably going to run faster and more efficiently because we do not need
to commit a mutation for every individual character that the user types.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.