All right, so let's add a test for our newly added menu items that we used the V for loop to render.
So right here in my main NAV test file, I'm going to add another test using the ID function.
And let's think of a good description here.
How about it displays menu items for navigation?
Makes sense.
Describes the user value of what we added.
Then of course, I'm going to provide a second argument of a function.
And here is where we write our code to test the logic for mounting.
Our main NAV component is going to be pretty much the same.
So I'm going to copy the code from above content wrapper and we're going to mount our main nav component.
At this point, what I'd like to introduce you to is a special method that's available on our rapper
object called Find.
What find is going to do is allow us to search for certain elements within our template.
And when I say elements, I'm not just limiting it to HTML elements.
We can also search for things like access classes or IDs and even more specific ways that we can target
different pieces of our age to null template.
But let's start with the simplest thing that we can search for or query for, and that is a list item.
I want to find the first list item within my template.
So right here, I'm going to invoke the find method on my wrapper and I'm going to provide an argument
of a string with what's my selector.
Basically, the thing that I want to search for and what I want to search for is a list item.
Of course, due to our V4, we're going to have six list items and the find method is going to find
the first occurrence of a list item or an ally tag in my template.
So I'm going to assign this to a constant right now called navigation menu item.
And what I want to do below is just console.log this navigation menu item so we can see what it looks
like.
So right here, I'm going to run my test suite using NPM run test unit.
And we can see what that navigation menu item looks like.
I mean factories this up in case we can buy ourselves some more space we can see here it is this dom
wrapper object and that is wrapping our HTML element, the actual core ally within our template.
So this is great.
We have successfully located a list item or a list element within my template, which means our main
nav component is being rendered properly by our test.
Well, obviously we don't just want to check for one list item, we want to find all of them.
And there is a complimentary method to find called find all.
So I'm going to change this method defined all.
And as you might imagine, because we have multiple list items here, what view and view test utils
is going to do is return them within an array.
So I'm going to change this constant name to be plural because it's now navigation menu items change
this two items as well.
And let's save that and rerun our test suite and see what we get.
All right.
As I scroll up, you're going to see this array, this array of six different DOM wrapper objects.
Makes sense.
We have six menu items.
So we have six fly tags and we've captured all of them.
In this array, you can see a six total DOM wrappers here.
So, so far, so good.
Our tests are basically finding these elements that we want them to be dynamically rendered into our
into our app.
Now, there is some degree of coupling here and may not seem apparent at first, but notice that our
test explicitly knows to search for ally elements.
That is an implementation detail.
And we'll talk more about that in the next lesson.
But for now, it makes logical sense.
Hopefully we're literally searching for all of these allies.
So I think to keep the test simple for now will forgive the slight implementation detail.
We're just going to look for all of our ally tags.
So on this DOM wrapper object, there is a method available called the text and that is going to return
the text that that ally contains.
So right here on the very next line, I'm going to create a new constant called navigation menu.
Texts, for lack of a better name.
And in order to get the text from each ally, I'm going to iterate over and navigate menu items and
invoke invoke the text method on each one.
And of course, since I want the results in a new array, I'm going to use the JavaScript map method.
So I'm going to map over my navigation menu items.
I'm going to map over each item.
And what do I want to do for each item right here?
I want to call the text method.
I'm going to save this.
I'm going to see if it breaks up across a different line.
It is not.
But here's what our code looks like.
Let this go a little bit to the right.
We're mapping over our array of DOM wrappers, and on each one we're calling the text method.
Each one of these elements right here within the array.
And what this is going to do is give us the internal text.
So now I can output what navigation menu text looks like.
Right here on our test suite.
In fact, let me be a little bit more real estate for our tests right here and now.
You can see we're getting that console.log of an array of the actual text values that we are displaying
for the user.
And I think this is the most important element because it reflects what a navigation menu actually looks
like.
So I think a reasonable test here is to test that this array contains exactly what we see here on screen,
these six items in this order.
All right.
So right here, once again, I'm going to expect and I'm going to provide now my array navigation menu
text.
And for this one, we can actually cannot use the to be matcher in jest because the to be match checks
for strict equality.
So in the case of objects like arrays, it's going to look for the exact same array in memory.
And the array that we're going to create to compare against is not going to be the exact same array
that navigation menu text is.
So we cannot use to be because that's literally checking for literally the same array.
We have two arrays that are equal in content but not the same array in memory.
So the alternative matter that we can use here is to equal and that is going to account for that right
used when you have to check that two objects have the same value, same principle, but not literally
the same object.
We can do this for JavaScript primitives, and when I say this, I mean that to be matcher we can use
that for strings, for numbers, for booleans, etc. But when we start comparing either JavaScript objects
or arrays, we have to switch to the to equal matcher.
But otherwise it's the same.
We're going to invoke this method and we're going to provide the array that we want to compare with.
So I'm going to create my array here, do a line, break and enter all of my values.
So we we're going to have teams first, we're going to have locations, then we're going to have life
at Bobo.
Then we're going to have how we hire then students and then jobs.
And it's reasonable to expect with the with the exception of of course, knowing that we're going to
have a list I our list item.
Rather it's reasonable to expect that we could have written a test like this using TDD because it's
testing for the user value.
We want six menu items in this order and here's what they are.
So I'm going to go ahead and run this test.
And hopefully it should pass and it does.
So we now have two tests to display the company name and to display the menu items for navigation within
our main NAV component that covers the responsibilities of the main nav components so far.
So I'm pretty happy here.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
And the very next one, we're going to talk about how we can address this little issue right here.