Okay.
So our component is in a really good state.
We are rendering an input of a checkbox for every one of our unique organizations and the user is certainly
welcome to click and select and deselect that checkbox in our browser.
The only problem right now is we're not capturing any of that information anywhere, not in our component
and not in view X.
So the next thing that I'd like to do is to start wiring up our component, to be able to store that
information.
Keep in mind, the user should be able to select more than one checkbox at a time because they're able
to filter by more than one organization.
So we need some kind of data structure that will be able to store more than one thing.
So obviously the first one that jumps to mind is an array.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to begin by defining some local component data, and that component
data will be an array that will store all of the organizations that the user has selected.
So once they make a selection, I'm going to add it to the array.
If they d select that checkbox, I'm going to remove it from the array and view.
Makes this very easy with the V model directory.
So right here below components, I'm going to define a data method.
This is defining local component data not to be confused with view x data.
And here as a reminder, we return a object and that object represents the properties available on this
component.
And I'm going to define a single property, I'm going to call it selected organizations, just like
the name suggests.
This is the organizations or the companies the user has selected from the checkboxes.
And when that page loads, I don't want any of my checkboxes selected or put.
In other words, I can start off this data structure as having nothing inside it, so I'm just going
to initialize it with an empty array.
All right.
Now, the other part of the equation is we have to connect this piece of data to our inputs above.
So if I scroll up, here is our input of type checkbox.
And just as a reminder, we have a single input right here, but we're using this in the body of a V4
directive.
So we're actually going to have as many inputs as there are unique organizations.
However, the syntax remains the same in view.
What I can do is I can use the V model directive.
We did this earlier in the course, but we did it with a input text field.
But we can do it the same with a checkbox as well.
View is smart enough to handle that.
So what I'm going to do is use the V model directive and the argument that I give it here is the name
of the piece of data that I would like to connect this input to.
So I want to connect it to my selected organization's data property that I just defined.
And what the model is going to do for us is create two way data binding.
As a reminder, what that means is we've created connectivity or reactivity between both the data and
the template.
So when the data changes, the template will update and when the template updates, for example, when
the user interacts with it, so will the data.
So it flows in both directions.
Data Updates Template and template updates data.
It is bound in both directions.
That's why it's called two way data binding.
And the reason we're using this approach of local component data with the model is because this is the
simplest way that I can think of to connect these checkboxes to some bit of data that the component
is storing.
All right.
So with this, we're going to capture the user clicking into a checkbox.
However, we still need to tell you what we wanted to actually populate the array with.
Right?
Because obviously we want the name of the organization.
However, Vue is not aware of this.
In order to make it aware, what we need to do is to provide a value attribute to our input.
And I'm going to use the V bind syntax because the value that I want to push into my selected organization's
array is going to be the organization string that I'm currently iterating over in my V4.
So I'm going to write organization here.
So again, we're using V bind syntax because it's not literally the string organization.
It's whatever is the dynamic organization that we're iterating over from our set.
This can be YouTube, this can be Vue, can do it.
Whatever is the other unique organizations we have and providing that string to my value attribute,
just so that when the user selects this checkbox, we're going to add this thing to my selected organization's
array.
We now tell you what to add to that array.
So the beautiful part about V model is Vue will take care of a lot of it, a lot of this logic for us.
Let me show you this in the browser Vue model makes things remarkably easy.
So right here I have my page.
I'm going to expand.
Organization's nothing is checked right now and in my view DevTools I'm going to go to my job filter
sidebar organization's component and you can see we have our data here, selected organizations.
It's an empty array.
Take a look at what happens when I select a checkbox like view YouTube.
Because we used this model, we have created a connection between the template and a piece of data.
So Vue knows because we gave a D model to a checkbox.
It knows that when the user checks that checkbox, it should add something to the array.
How does it know what to add?
It knows what to add based on the value attribute that we defined.
So we made it YouTube.
So it added Vue to look what happens when we click something else like you can do it.
It's automatically going to add that string to the selected organization's data array.
Take a look at what happens when I select a checkbox.
Exactly what you might expect Vue is going to figure out, Hey, Vue Tube is no longer checked.
I should remove that value of YouTube from my selected organization's array.
And that's the beautiful part.
Using V model and local components state, we can very easily create this flow where we're capturing
all of the user's inputs through checkboxes.
And as the user selects or D selects, we can modify the selected organization's array accordingly.
So this is an example of data flowing in one direction.
The user interacting with the template updates the data, but it also goes the other way.
If something on the JavaScript side of things updates our data array, the template, the view that
the user sees in the browser will update as well.
So let me show you that in action, I'm going to navigate back to this code.
You do not have to write this code out because it's simply for the sake of example.
But I just want to show you that if we go in the other direction, if we go to the JavaScript side of
things and we, for example, provide a string here like YouTube, which is one of my sample organizations
from my response by saving this, we're saying, hey, this is our starting data.
So Vue is going to say, I have this two way connection between the data and the template.
Since you gave me some data that is reflective on the template, I need to update the template accordingly.
So if I provide a starting value here of YouTube and I go back to my browser, the page is going to
refresh.
And when I expand organizations you're going to see that YouTube is going to be checked.
So this is data binding in the opposite direction.
Our component data is effect is affecting what the template looks.
Like and then the users interaction with the template affects what the data looks like.
That's the way that the data flows in both directions.
Data to template and template to data.
So right here, you can see here is our selected organizations, right?
It starts with YouTube.
I can very easily select that.
And now we can see if view update to.
All right.
So the good news is here at the very end of this lesson, by using V model and that directive, we have
created a data binding between local component data and these six checkboxes that we have on the screen.
So now we are capturing what the user cares about.
We're capturing what the user wants to filter by.
So of course, the next step is sending this data to view X so that you can say, okay, you selected
these two companies of YouTube and view beauty.
I got to take those companies and use that to filter the jobs on the right hand side to only show the
jobs that belong to these two organizations.
So in the follow up lessons, we're gonna start talking about how we can communicate this data back
to View X.