Okay.
So let's take a little break from adding type annotations to our components and instead focus on updating
our composable functions to be in TypeScript as well.
So a nice an easy one to start with is going to be used confirm route.
So I'm going to open up that composable right here.
It's in its own separate use confirmed root file.
And as a reminder, this is a composable that accepts a string of a root name and then it returns a
reactive object that compares the string here with whatever is the current name on the root object that
the function gets from the use root helper function from view root.
All right.
So the process should be pretty familiar by now.
We're going to change this composable to have a test extension.
Right here haircuts.
And we can see only one violation, which should hopefully make sense.
TypeScript does not understand what route Nim is, so it assumes that has an any type and it needs more
specific annotations.
So right here we're going to provide a colon and this will be a string.
And that should do it.
And now TypeScript is going to be able to infer, based on our return value of this computed logic right
here, that the return value will be a computed raft, which basically means that's the interface for
a view reactive object.
That in itself is going to be wrapping a boolean, right?
So it automatically infers the correct generic as well simply from the logic of what we're doing in
here.
All right.
So that takes care of the composable.
It's also update its test file.
So I'm going to go to use confirm root that test that yes, open that up on the right hand side right
here.
Let me find the file in my test directory right here at use confirm route that test that.
Yes, I'm going to change that to be that test.
There we go.
And the only issue we're going to run into is the usual one with TypeScript not understanding our mocking
process.
So what we're going to do is replace that use route with icons called use route mock.
So right here, contact use, route mock.
And we're going to tell TypeScript that it's treat the use route, imported function not as its regular
inferred type, but as a special type of just mock.
And then down below we can use use route mock again.
It's still the same object.
The constant use mock is referencing the exact same function that use route is, but that function is
the just mock function that has been replaced by line two.
Here we're just informing TypeScript of the type update and we need a separate line to do that.
So that's why we're assigning to a brand new constant.
We can simply reference that and understand that that is the one that is the has the correct type recognition
from TypeScript due to our explicit type annotation right here.
All right.
So that takes care of the tests for that.
Let's do one more composable in this lesson.
So I'm going to move on to use current page.
There it is.
This one is the one that uses the use root helper function and accesses the query property and the page
property on that to try to extract what page of job results were on.
And then if that property does not exist, it falls back to a value of one.
All right.
So let's go ahead and convert this file to have a test extension.
Like so.
And we're going to run into another issue here.
We can see here that if I hover my mouse, it's going to say an argument of type, string or location
value array is not assignable to parameter of type string.
So basically what this is telling us is the pass int method on this object expects to receive a string
as its first argument.
You can see even in the parameter definition on the right, it's parameter name is string, which I
know is confusing, but that's how the implementation works.
Its parameter name is String and there's also a type string and the argument of this string of one is
totally normal.
But keep in mind that root does create a page could be another type of value which is this location
query value array and thus it's saying, hey, pass, it can only take a string, but your argument
can be either a string or this array.
Now luckily in our scenario, we have never run into a situation where root to create a page is an array.
In our scenario, it's always going to be a string.
We simply don't have the kind of app that could lead to an array of these location query value objects.
I honestly don't know how that could work.
I'm sure there is some kind of implementation where that query object does indeed have a property set
to an array.
The point is, within the confines of our app, we know that the page property will always be equal
to a string.
So what we can do is simply use our as syntax to tell TypeScript about that.
So right here I'm going to define a separate call page and I'm going to reference Route Dot, create
a page and I'm going to say as string.
So we always interpret it as a string type.
All right.
And then I'm going to be able to pass in page right here.
Either the page constant was typed, typescript things is a string.
So now it's going to say either string or string, that means only string.
And when it looks at the pass end type definition, it says, okay, parse.
It expects a string as its first argument.
You are giving me something that is always going to be a string.
I don't know which one it's going to be either page or the literal string of one, but both of those
are made from the same string type.
So they satisfy the definition and the expectation of what parse and expects.
All right.
So that will be enough to get the TYPEKIT violations here to go away.
So of course, we have to update the corresponding test as well.
So use current page DHCP test that just open up this thing and let's of course convert it to have a
TypeScript extension.
There we go.
And we're going to get the usual problems here.
We have issues with marking out, user out.
You can probably guess what our solution is going to be here.
It's defining a separate to convert calls called user root mark, which is going to reference the user
out imported function, which is now a just mock function and explicitly telling TypeScript to interpret
its type as a just mark rather than the default that it infers when importing this regular function
and looking at it in the file.
All right.
So right here, we're going to replace this with user reviews route mark slipping over my words today.
And right here, use root mark as well.
Again, this is still referencing the exact same mocked object.
So at the end of the day, use root mark and use the same.
So if at any point you want to test, for example, that it's been invoked or that it's been invoked
with the right argument, you can technically use any reference either one of those two names.
However, when using mock return value, TypeScript only understands this one is having that just mark
type.
So when we use mark return value, we have to make sure to use it on user mark instead of simply use
out.
Even though they're technically the same object from a referential perspective, they're different as
far as TypeScript interpretation of their type.
All right.
So save that.
And right here and PM run, test, call and watch.
Let's see if that captures our two composer bowls.
And it looks like we're using those compulsively in a couple tests and a couple of component tests as
well.
But that's fine because those components should, in theory, have isolated those composer those to
mock them out.
So it's not like a change in our actual implementation should affect those components, which is good
because it ensures that we've isolated the tests for those components separately from the tests for
the components.
But because our proposals are still being used, for example, in the imports of the components, that's
why I just thinks that those files have changed and thus feels that it's appropriate to rerun them.
Regardless, we can see that we do have the two test suites for the composer to compose.
Those right here use confirm root and use page and everything is still passing.
All right, so that's a good place to start.
In the next lesson, we're going to complete more composable refactoring to incorporate TypeScript.
So I'll see you there.