In this lesson, I want us to configure our easy limit settings as a reminder.
Easy lint is our litter.
It's a piece of software that's going to look at our code, both the JavaScript code and the view code,
and it's going to look for violations.
And violations could mean anything from errors or even things like not following best practices when
it comes to efficient code, optimal code, etc..
So to summarize, yes, lint is going to make our code better by identifying areas of improvement in
our existing code and the settings for Eastland are found in this file at the top level of our job search
project.
It's this one right here, Iceland RC Dot Jess So go ahead and open this file up.
And the first thing I want you to focus your eyes on is this extends key right here.
It's set to an array of strings and each one of these strings specifies a plug in.
A plug in is just a collection of rules, and there are various rules depending on the technologies
that we work with.
So, for example, this first plug in Vue three essential is rules specifically related to view code.
In comparison, this second one in line eight is land recommended is general s lint rules for JavaScript.
Remember, these are different pieces of technology, so there are different rule sets for each and
it is in this extends array that we specify which combinations of rules we want s lint to be following
when it analyzes our code.
So here's what I want to show you, and you do not need to follow along with this, but I'm going to
open up a sample view file in our app and it's called Hello World and I'm going to drag it over here
to the right.
And you do not need to understand everything that's going on in this file because we have not talked
about any view concept yet.
That's totally fine.
But I just want to show you an example and it will demonstrate how s lint works for us.
So you'll notice this first rule right here, View three Essential is currently in place and there are
no violations right here in this file.
What I want to do here is I want to change this to be another collection of rules that's going to be
more stricter.
So this is something you should follow along with.
Go ahead and open up your Iceland file and here change this from Vue three essential to view, three
recommended and that's how you spell recommended.
And what this rule set is going to do is it's going to look not just for the essential view violations,
which means the things that are most likely to be errors.
It's also going to look for things that are optimizations or best practices in the view community.
So the reason I want to go with the more stricter set of rules here is because I want these rules to
pop up as we build our code throughout the course so we can talk about why we have these best practices,
what problems or optimizations they're designed to solve.
So while the default configuration that usually gave us is, okay, I want to go with the harder one.
I want to go with the stricter one because it's going to offer us more opportunities to learn.
So let me show you this as an example.
I'm going to save this file and immediately Iceland is going to rerun and analyze our code.
And I want you to focus your eyes on this section in this file right here I'm going to save right now.
And you'll notice in just a second we're going to see this orange squiggly up here in this component
or in this file on the right hand side.
And if I hover my mouse over this, you're going to see the Iceland violation pop up.
It says Prop MSD requires default value to be set.
Now, right now, it's not important to understand exactly what this violation is or how we fix it.
The point that I'm trying to make is that this collection of rules in the recommended plugin is a lot
more stricter.
And that's why this rule appeared right here while it formally did not when we had just the essential
plugin.
So that's the only change we made here.
We've enabled more stricter settings so that we can talk through these violations, how to fix them
and why they matter throughout the course.
So this is the first change that I'd like you to make.
The second change is going to be in this file section right here.
And in order to provide the content right here, what I'd like you to do is to open up your just config
file that we modified a lesson or two ago.
So I'm going to use command P on a mac and I believe on windows it's going to be control P and you can
look for that just configs file.
It's found at the top level of your project and I want you to copy this array of two strings that belongs
to the test match key.
So just going to copy this array right here and right here in the S linked file in the override section,
you'll notice this object has a files properties set to an array.
I want you to take that array and I want you to replace it with the one that you just copied from the
just config file.
So I'm going to do that right here and that's what we want to do.
All right.
So once again, what this is going to do, it's going to tell us lint what our test files look like.
It's going to tell this lint that our test files can have either a dot just extension or a dot test,
that test extension.
And that's an important point worth noting here, and that is that Iceland is going to look for violations,
not just in our source code, in our implementation code, but also in our test files.
Right.
Because a violation is a violation no matter where we write it, if it is our code and we could write
it.
Yes, land should be watching out for it and making its recommendations.
I also want to show you that at this point Premier should be fully enabled and I can show that to you
in our excellent our successful.
So what I can do here, by the way, as an example, is I'm just going to move line eight right here
to the previous line.
And you can see it kind of gives this awkward syntax where we have two strings on one line and then
one string on the next.
That kind of becomes harder to read.
And as soon as I save this file, prettier will click in and it's going to reform at the file.
And as soon as I save, you can see pretty first preference is to have each array element on a single
line, or at least when the array is super long.
That's its preference and you'll see they will automatically reformat even this s land configuration
file and it's going to do the exact same thing for our regular JavaScript on our view code, our test
code, etc. and that is the beautiful part of Prettier.
We only configure it once and then it starts using its best practices to format our code in a really
beautiful manner.
All right.
So that's the only two things we need to do in this file.
Make sure you change this from Vue three essential to view three recommended, and make sure that the
files array is set to the exact same array of strings as in our just config file.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.