In this lesson, I'd like to introduce you to a problem that you may encounter when working with a reactive
object, and that problem is structuring.
So let's begin by getting rid of our title length constant and all of the references to it since it
no longer matters.
So right here in line 11, I'll get rid of that and get rid of all of these references to title.
And so we are back to where we started, where we have a person object.
We have this computed function that is keeping track of the first name and last name properties on that
person object and re-evaluating or re computing whenever those properties change.
So if you are familiar with JavaScript, you might say, Hey, this syntax right here is kind of redundant.
Can't we make it a little bit simpler by restructuring the first name and last name properties off of
person?
So let's see what happens if we do that instead.
So right here, I'm going to restructure first name and last name from person.
And again, this is valid because we passed an object to the reactive function, so we no longer need
to reference dot value or anything like that.
We should be able to d reference these properties like so like any regular JavaScript object.
And then right here we can change this to first name, since we should have the name available and change
this to last name right here and hope that everything will work out the exact same way.
So we expect to see Napoleon the Great followed by Napoleon Griffin the Great.
Well, when I run this file, we are going to see a perhaps unexpected result.
We are actually going to get the original computed value of Boris Spassky by the great.
So what is going on here?
Well, when I do structure the first name and last name properties off the reactive person object,
I do not get reactive properties.
I have reference to a reactive object called person, which is why I'm able to reference person that
first name in the previous implementation.
But this syntax actually does not work when we do structure from an object view is going to give us
the original values, which in this case are plane strings.
In other words, we lose the reactivity of the whole person object.
We go from an object to a primitive.
And I'm view does not wrap that basic primitive, that string in reactivity.
Right.
So what happens next is we have these plane string values.
So we say, here's a function computed that will always evaluate to whatever first name is and whatever
last name is.
Which are always going to be regular strings at this point of Boris pass giver.
So no matter what we do with changing the first name and last name properties on person, which are
actually still reactive, but these references to them are not.
So whenever we change the first name property on person and the last name property on person, this
does not actually rerun because it does not have a reference or a a link to the original person reactive
object.
It only has these regular primitive strings.
Right?
So this solution will not work.
And this is just a internal implementation detail from Vue.
We're going to take a look at how we can fix this problem in the next lesson.