Okay.
So in this lesson, I'd like to refactor our test suite for this sub nav component.
So on the left hand side, I have my sub nav component.
And on the right hand side, I have my sub now test suite.
Now we're good to refactor because all of our tests are still green.
In other words, they're all passing.
So what issue do I currently have with our sub nav test suite?
Well, our sub nav test suite is still relying on our former implementation of the solution in subnet.
Here you'll notice that we are marking out use route by doing this.
Just mock call the router and then we're specifying what use route mock returns right here.
So what's actually happening is we are not mocking out use confirming out our composable.
So when the test utils mount our sub nav component, we're still invoking use confirmed route, which
is going to the real actual implemented function in our code base, this one.
And because we have marked out use route, this is where we're actually mock returning and thus we are
running through the logic of this composable with the mock root object.
Right.
Now I argue that this is one step too far as far as I want to go, because the logic of the use confirmed
root function.
We already tested that in the previous lesson.
We confirmed through our test suite that this logic does exactly what it's supposed to do.
And in order to do that, of course, we marked out use route because we don't want to worry about how
the router is doing its things.
We just verified what this function is doing.
Well, similarly in sub nav, our sub nav component is not using use route anywhere.
It's only using a function that itself is using use route in its internals.
But it's not the sub nav components.
Responsibility to care or to know about how use confirmed route is performing its logic.
All the sub nav component cares about is I'm going to use the use confirming out function.
I'm going to give you a string and you're just going to give me back an object that I can use that I
can use in my V.F. directive.
So the subtext component shouldn't care about use confirmed in how it does its own internal logic.
All that cares about is its own dependence on the right function and giving it the right argument.
So even though our test suite is still passing, I argue that we can make it even better.
Instead of mocking out use route.
Let's instead mark out use confirm route.
Let's mock out our own composable function.
And by giving that a mock return value, we can still verify that sub nav is using it correctly without
having to worry about its details.
All right.
So what am I going to do right here in my test suite?
The first thing I'm going to do is remove my import of user out.
Then I'm going to delete my mocking out of view router because we no longer care about that.
And instead, what I'm going to important Mark out is going to be our new composable.
So right here I'm going to import used confirm route so that I can reference it later.
And that is coming from source composable to use confirm route.
Then on the line below, I'm going to call just Mark.
But instead of passing in a NPM library like I did with View X here, I'm just going to pass in the
complete path from for my composable.
So right here it's going to be a source composable use confirm route.
Basically the exact same thing is on the line above.
So now just has looped through our own file and it's replaced use confirm route with a default mock
just function that returns undefined.
Well, we don't want it to do that.
We want it to return to match our implementation.
A reactive object that stores an internal value of a boolean.
Well, one really easy way that we can have a reactive object with a value of a boolean is by using
vue's ref function.
So what I'm going to do is import ref right here, import ref from view.
And all that's left to do is to modify our old markings so that instead of mocking out, use root and
telling it what it should return, we're simply going to mark out, use, confirm root.
So now we don't need to worry about the details of having an object with a name property and matching
it, because that is the responsibility of our composable function.
All this thing needs all use.
Confirmed root needs is a reactive object that has a boolean inside it because on job results page is
fundamentally a boolean in its heart.
Right?
So right here, what I'm going to do is say use confirm root.
That's my new thing that I'm marking out.
Use, confirm, root, dot, mark, return value invoke that method.
And in order to provide a reactive object with a value property, which is what we're getting from computed
from use confirm.
Now I'm simply going to invoke ref right here and providing a boolean of true.
All right for the test.
The low we were.
This was when the user is not on the job page.
So it does not display job count.
So this was providing a route that did not match job results.
So in other words we need to mark out used confirm route to return a false.
This is the inverse scenario that we're testing.
So right here I'm going to say use confirm route.
And then I'm going to say make return value.
And I need a reactive object with a value property to match the return value in the actual implementation.
So right here I'm going to write ref and here I'm going to provide false.
So now we've decoupled ourselves from the logic that used confirming out is using all we're verifying
is that we are getting some kind of right thing from it and that we're using it correctly.
In fact, if you want to write an additional test, you can simply write a test that checks that use
confirm route was called with an argument of job results.
That is a totally valid thing to to write a test for but we're basically saying as long as use confirm
or out gives me a object back that works, then I'm going to verify how it works with my component.
Right.
The whole idea of this test actually is basically testing that the f it's doing is doing its job or
simply testing for the lack of presence of job count, which means we're testing that VRF is getting
a value that is false here.
Right.
And that's the subject of component's responsibility because that is the heart of its HTML.
But the worry or concern about the root handling, we already got that in a composable function.
We do not need to again test that logic here because we wrote a test for it in the previous lesson.
All right.
We can see all of our tests are still passing.
And here is where I'm going to do one more slight refactor.
So I think that what we have on the right is totally valid.
If you submitted this code in a code review, I think that would be totally appropriate.
But I'm going to deviate slightly from the original use confirmed out implementation because even though
in the real world we are getting a reactive object that storing a boolean, if we were to pretend that
use confirm route returns a plain boolean either true or false.
This logic would actually still work because on job results page would be a boolean.
True or false.
It would register with our VRF and it would render or not render.
Granted, it would no longer be reactive, but for purposes of a single test, a single test is not
currently testing how things are changing.
Rather, we have one test for displaying given a certain return value and one test for not displaying
given the other return value of false.
So given our test setup, if we actually mock return value the basic value of true right here and the
basic value of false right here.
Our test would still pass and I argue makes it a little bit easier to read.
We're basically just communicating here that we are confirming that we are not on the route that we
care about.
And this test confirms that we are on the route that we care about and that we see or do not see content
based on it.
Now, if you wanted to run a test that, for example, received a reactive object and then somehow the
component interacted with it and got a brand new value, then absolutely you would have to mark return
a reactive object from the wrath function.
That's the easiest way to do it.
But given the set up of our current test, a true or false will suffice.
We can prove that simply by making these changes and showing you that the tests do not fail.
So I'm okay with this implementation.
It isn't exactly like the real world, like the real implementation, but it is good enough and good
enough for what this component needs in order to work and in order for us to validate that it works
as expected.
So with that change, I'm going to remove RAF from here because we're no longer using it.
But now you know that that is a valid solution as well.
All right.
So there is our simplified test for our sub nav component, and I will see you in the next lesson.