All right.
So in the previous lesson, we wrote this test right here that searches for all the menu items in our
main nav component and confirms that they are displaying the text to the user that we expect.
And we talked briefly about this line right here, line 13, and why it's not ideal.
I don't want you to think that what we have here is terrible by any means.
I don't think it is terrible.
I'm just saying, can we make it a little bit better?
And by better, I mean, can we make the test a little bit more resilient to change, especially change
in our implementation?
So the issue here is that we are finding all occurrences of our list items are ally tags and that requires
our tests to have some knowledge of the implementation details of our main NAV component.
We have to know that an ally exists, right?
So for example, if tomorrow another developer goes into our main nav component and decides to change
this from an unordered list of allies to, let's say, a div of divs, well, all of a sudden our tests
would fail because the tests would no longer be able to identify the list item element for which from
which to extract text.
Right.
So that doesn't mean that this thing is likely to change or that that is likely to happen.
It just means that our tests are kind of connected more closely to our main nav component.
Right.
And you might think, well, can we substitute our ally to search for instead a class, a access class
or an ID?
And that's not actually going to solve our problem because what happens tomorrow if that same developer
goes in and changes the name of our access class?
Well, all of a sudden our tests are once again going to look for something that no longer exists.
If our if our tests have to know about an ally or an IED or a class, well, they have to know about
something that exists in the actual main nav component.
Right?
Sometimes that's inevitable in our tests.
But in this situation, I think we can do a little bit better.
So here's a solution that I propose, and this is something that's coming directly from the View Testing
Guide on their official website.
What if we had an attribute on an ally that was dedicated entirely to our tests?
It exists purely for the purposes of our tests to be able to locate that element within our main NAV
component.
It would serve no purpose to the user, and I'm sure if the user were to open up their console in Chrome
they would see it, but it would mean nothing to them and it would not change any of the actual visual
impact of the component when it renders in our browser.
But if we had a custom attribute on our ally component, for example, in this case we could use that
custom attribute to find that ally and use it in our tests.
Right?
And then we would be bound to a specific test related attribute rather than to an age HTML element or
class.
So if somebody tomorrow were to change our ally to a div, but they were to keep the same custom attribute
that we defined just for our tests, well then our tests would not fail because we would still be able
to locate that element.
With that attribute.
It would just be a different element and the same rules apply to access class.
If somebody were to decide to change access class, then we would still retain that custom attribute
that we defined on our element and the tests would be able to find it.
Now, granted, somebody could always change our custom attribute and give it some kind of value and
break our tests, but it's obviously a lot less likely for that to happen compared to a change in the
element itself or a change in the case class.
That is common, that is to Nancy assess for testing purposes, our own custom attribute is much less
likely to change.
So I know when I use the words custom attribute there, maybe a little bit confusing.
So let me show you how this is going to work in action.
So we're going to keep the majority of this test right here.
All I'm going to change is what I'm actually searching for in my wrapper.
So I'm still going to to keep my string argument here.
But instead of providing an age to my element, I'm going to start with a pair of square brackets.
So right here, a pair of square brackets.
And this is the syntax that we can use in Vue test utils to search for a specific attribute on our element.
So an attribute can be any kind of real HTML attribute such as h ref right here on our anchor tag or
our class right here, etc..
If we want to search for an element by an attribute, we can use this square brackets index.
But what I want to search for is not a regular HTML element attribute, but a custom one that we're
going to add ourselves.
It's going to be a no op, which means it's not going to do anything to the actual element in the browser.
It's just kind of an irrelevant key value pair that we're going to add to our time element.
So I'd like you to imagine that we just add an H HTML attribute to our ally called data dash test.
So that name is entirely up to us.
But this is a recommended one from the view test utils documentation because it reflects that we are
adding some kind of data to a specified piece of our template that is related to our tests.
Right.
It's not related to the user.
It doesn't have anything to do with the user value.
It's just for our tests and it's some kind of data right now in order for us to have an attribute,
just like we have here with a graph or just like we have here with class, we of course need an association
with a value right or ref equals something or class equals something.
So if this is going to be our attribute, we also have to provide it with an equal sign and actually
give it some kind of value.
This is going to happen in our actual main nav component eventually.
But here we're specifying what to look for, look for a data test attribute with a given value, and
we can provide that value, of course, as a string, but we're already in a string for our find our
method.
So to provide a nested string, I can use single quotes right here.
So data test equals single quotes and here we can put some kind of identifier or some kind of value
for this data test attribute.
This is entirely up to us in terms of the name, much like the data test name is entirely up to us.
So for here I think an appropriate name would be something like main dash nav dash list.
Dash item.
All right.
I'm going to save this.
We're going to break it off into a new line.
And you can see the full syntax right here.
We're going to find a string with square brackets.
Then inside data test equals another string of main now list item.
So you'll notice that when I run this test right now it's going to fail because nothing in our template
has an attribute of data test.
Right?
So predictably the view test utils does not discover that attribute.
So it returns an empty array and it's saying, hey, this empty array does not equal the expected array
of six strings right here.
So all that's left for us to do to pass this test is to go to our ally right here and to provide it
with this new custom attribute.
We're going to add it just like any other HTML attribute.
We're just going to say data dashed test.
That's exactly what we called it in our test.
Right.
And then what value is it going to have?
It's going to have a value of main now list item.
So remember this ally is being generated in a V for loop, which means we're actually going to have
six allies and they're all going to have the exact same equal main novelist item data test attribute.
I want to distinguish between this line right here and this line right here.
Here we're using our V bind syntax with colon.
So menu item is dynamically injected and it's going to be something different on every single iteration
here.
I'm not binding or anything like that, so I'm literally hard coding an attribute of data test and I'm
giving it the value of main nav list item on all of our iterations.
But that's totally fine for our tests because our tests are looking for all occurrences of that attribute
and our tests now don't care about whether it's a list item or a DIV or an H3 or what class it has.
It just cares about this attribute that exists purely for the purposes of the test, right?
So again, another developer can change this.
They can change this, but they're highly unlikely to change data test because it doesn't have anything
to do with whatever new feature it happens to be that they're adding or whatever feature they're modifying.
Right.
That doesn't mean our test is perfect.
It doesn't mean there's no chance for error.
But I argue that it's less chance for error because this is something that exists purely for our tests
and thus it's less likely to be accidentally modified in a way that breaks our tests.
So I'm going to go ahead and run this test suite and we should see a passing result.
And we do.
And I think we have solved the problem that we previously had, which is the connection to our implementation.
Now, you might say again, coming from a2d perspective, would we ever write a test like this?
And I'd say we'd be certainly more likely to because we would again not be concerning ourselves with
whether our implementation is eventually going to have an ally or a div.
All we're going to say is my test expects that somewhere in my component I'm going to have a data test
aptitude and that's all the test cares about.
So there is still some inherent coupling with the knowledge of this, but it's not as closely connected
to the H two balances itself.
So I think it offers a better, more stable, more likely to not break solution.
All right.
And if I had to my browser right now.
We're going to see how this reflects on our page.
If I just open up my console and I take a look at this logic right here.
You're going to see that we have this data test attribute right here, and the same for all of my actual
allies.
But it's just an arbitrary attribute that has no impact whatsoever on how this renders it exists purely
for the purposes of my test.
So no harm done.
And now we have kind of isolated the implementation logic from the tests.
The tests have to no less.
Right.
So that is definitely an improvement over what we had in the previous lesson.
So I am happy to wrap this section up in the very next lesson.