Okay.
So here is a fun question for you.
This is going to be a good chance to review the concepts that we learned about in the previous section.
We know that Props is a reactive object and we're getting it as the very first argument in our setup
method.
We also know that we want to use the type property on that reactive props object right here.
So my question for you is, can I do structure type right here in order to use it below if I simply
use ESX.
So structuring syntax.
Can I do this?
And then use type below.
The answer is going to be no.
And in fact, Iceland is going to give us this warning right here.
If I hover my mouse over it, you can see it's going to say getting a value from the props in the root
scope of setup will cause the value to lose reactivity.
Remember, we talked about this in the reactivity section of the course.
Just because we have a reactive object does not mean that any individual property that we do structure
is reactive in itself.
So when we do structure type from props, this will work.
But type is going to be the string.
It's going to be the string of primary or secondary that's passed from the parent.
It's not going to be a reactive object that is able to track changes to its state or to its value over
time.
So we're basically going to do structure a string here instead of a reactive object.
All right.
So how do we solve this problem?
Whenever we have a reactive object and we want to make all of its individual properties reactive, we
have to pass that reactive object to the to Raf's function.
So let's import two refs right here.
And remember to refs only accepts a reactive object.
It does not accept a plain JavaScript object, but in our case props is already a reactive object so
we can pass in props to two refs.
Okay.
So this is going to make the lint warning go away, but unfortunately, it's not going to get us to
a working solution.
So let's save this code and let's take a look in the browser.
We're going to see if I navigate back to Chrome.
Here is my page.
It looks like we have lost just about all of our styles completely in our button.
This isn't even the primary or the secondary styles.
So what is going on?
What is wrong with our code?
Well, you may recall that when we use two refs, we do indeed get a reactive object with reactive properties
and we are successfully just structuring a property.
But remember, now that type is no longer a string.
Type is a reactive object that is storing a string and its changes over time.
So what we're providing here in square brackets as the dynamic name of our object key here is not a
string.
It's actually a complete reactive object in order to get the actual property or the value that it is
storing inside it that it is keeping track of.
We need to access the dot value property on that object.
So remember when you do structure using the object return from two FS, you are more than able to do
structured.
This is valid syntax, but what you are going to do structure what you're going to get back in your
assignment right here is going to be an object, a reactive object with a value property.
So right here, if I'm doing the two refs approach, I have to do Typekit value.
All right.
Now, this is going to get me the string and it's going to keep the original implementation that we
had in the previous lesson.
So when our props change, we're going to be able to observe the changes to the type of prop and we're
going to able to rerun our computed function.
So we're going to get the exact same functionality in our browser.
So if I go back to take a look now, we can see our original styles are back.
And if I go to action button right here, we see if it works right here.
Looks like I'm having a little bit of issues.
Forgive the troubleshooting.
Let me refresh the page just to be safe.
All right, here we go.
So now we have our action button.
Here is our type.
Let me select the type prop and change it secondary.
Save that you can see it indeed does update here we go.
Changing it back to primary.
We can see the styles are changing, which means the CAC class object is re computing, which means
our view component is recognizing the change in prompts.
So the key takeaway here is if you ever wanted to structure props or to structure any reactive object
for that matter, and you want to be able to use the syntax, you must pass the reactive object to the
two Raf's function first.
That's the first thing you need to remember.
The second thing you need to remember is that that thing you do structure is not going to be the regular
value, like a boolean or a string or whatever it is.
It's always going to be an object with a value property, storing the original value that you want.
So if you prefer this approach, it requires a little bit more code in one way and a little bit less
on another, because if we were to simply use props, that type right here, that would work because
that entire object is reactive.
So you can keep track of any properties on it that change.
If you wanted to structure original properties in order to get this kind of syntax, that's totally
fine as well.
But you have to remember to pass the object to the two refs function and to provide value whenever you
are accessing any of those the structure properties, they are now reactive objects.
All right.
They're the exact same thing basically that we return back from the ref function just automatically
generated by Vue.
All right.
So that's all there is to cover in this lesson.
And I will see you in the next one.