Okay.
So let's write a test for our new accordion component.
So in my file Explorer, I'm going to go to the tests directory that components then shared.
And here I'm going to create a new file.
Accordion dot.
Test dot.
Yes.
And as always, let me drag it over to the right side so we can see it alongside our implementation.
So let's begin by importing everything we need from you test utils.
In this scenario, given that I am going to potentially render some child components within my slot,
I think I'm going to keep it safe and use the mount function instead of shallow amount.
Again, that can be personal preference, but for now I'm just going to stick with Mount.
That is going to come from the view organization test utils package.
Then of course, we need to import our component itself.
So accordion is going to come from the source directory components shared accordion.
And let me just add the extension here, even though it's technically not needed.
I'm going to create a described block for my accordion component.
And what do I want to validate that this component does it renders child?
So basically what I want to validate here is that if I give my accordion some slot content, it should
render it right.
That's really the heart of what this accordion is doing.
So let's begin by using our mount function to render an accordion component.
And as we know, the second argument to mount and shallow mount is a configuration object.
And it is in this configuration object that we're going to explore how we can specify slots in our test.
Before we get there though, remember that our accordion component requires a prop of header, right?
So normally we would render this accordion as a child within a larger parent like the component we were
exploring in the previous lesson, the job filter sidebar.
In the context of a test, we don't have a parent component, so we have to specify all of those details
right here in the Mount function.
So you may recall that in a test that we can provide a props object to the configuration object and
here is where we specify the value of those props.
So we need a header prop and let's provide a sample string value.
Doesn't matter what it is, maybe something like test header and that should work.
Okay.
So that's going to specify the header prop.
How do we specify slot content in order to do that in our configuration object?
You guessed it, there's going to be an available slots property and we're going to set that equal to
an object.
Now, as it turns out, this is a little bit of a spoiler, but we can actually have multiple slots
in a component.
We're going to talk about how we can do that in the very next section, but the way we do it really
is that each slot we can give its own custom name, right?
We didn't use this feature right here.
We just used the plain slot syntax right here.
And whenever we do this view automatically gives our slot a name of default.
Okay, so the way this works in this object is the properties represent the slots and the value represents
the HTML that we want to insert or inject into that slot.
So again, the slot on the left, we did not give a name, so Vue will give it the name default.
So my slot that I want to target here is the slot named default.
And again, my value for this property is what I want to be injected as that child content.
So for example here I can put something like an H three and this is all a string by the way, in here
I can put something like minus the child.
Okay.
So basically what we're doing here is the equivalent of rendering an accordion, right?
And putting an H3 here with minus the child.
The only difference is we obviously can't render a view component like this in our test.
So we have to configure using this JavaScript object right here.
Okay.
So we're specifying that minus the child in an H three element is what we want as our kind of slotted
content.
And in order to specify which slot it goes into, we use default because that is the name that view
assigns to a slot that doesn't have a custom name.
We will talk more about how we assign a custom name to a slot up ahead.
There's really no reason to give a slot a name if we only have one.
It only really makes sense if you have more than one.
Okay, so now we have our mounted accordion.
What do we want to test?
Well, I propose what we do is that we first test that we are not able to find this content anywhere
in our component.
Then I'd like to use my test to click on this div right here.
So I want to target this div, click it in order to trigger all of this logic to run, to make our component
open.
And then after I do the click, I want to verify that this lot of content then appears after I have
interacted with my component in the expected fashion.
So let me show you what the code for that is going to look like.
The first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to expect that we do not see the content.
So I'm going to invoke a method on my wrapper called text that, as a reminder, is going to give me
all of the text content that is within my accordion component.
And by text I mean any text that the user sees on the screen.
And then I'm going to use a special just syntax here.
Instead of using the to match matcher, I'm going to first invoke a method called not and on the object
that returns a rather access to property called not and on the object that that property gives me.
That is going to have its own method called to match.
What I'm basically doing here is I'm testing a negative, I'm testing and a wrapper text will not have
when I specify here not to match.
So what I expect here is that in my wrapper text I do not want to see the text minus the child.
It should not be visible yet because it's going to be hidden because of the VRF right here and it should
only be exposed whenever I click on the devil right here.
So first I'm going to validate that it does match and then at some point I can copy this and paste the
below at the very end of this operation that we're going to do in the middle.
I do want it to match.
All right.
So we're going to have kind of like a before and after the starting state and then some kind of interaction
and then the ending state.
So what do I want to do here?
I want to click on my clickable area.
So what I'm going to do is create a contact called clickable area, for lack of a better name.
And in my wrapper, I'm going to attempt to find a dot, a test attribute.
So right here, I'm going to provide a string with a data test attribute, let's call it something like
clickable area.
Again, it doesn't matter because this attribute will exist purely for the purpose of a test.
And then, of course, I want to trigger a click.
You may recall that the way I do this in a test is that I take my clickable thing and I invoke a method
on it called trigger.
And then to trigger I pass a string representing the event that I want to trigger or run on this dip.
So eventually we're going to have this data first attribute on this day right here.
So when we trigger a click, we're really triggering this logic to run, which will trigger our open
method to run.
So here I want to trigger a click on whatever element my test finds that has this data test attribute
on it right now.
This is actually going to be an asynchronous event because we need to wait for the clicks to complete
and then wait for the component to re render itself.
So the trigger method actually returns a promise.
So we need to await it.
And if we're going to use the await syntax, we know that we need to make the test function itself asynchronous.
So I'm going to add async right here.
All right.
So this should be our test.
I'm going to save this.
I'm going to open up our terminal, and let's go ahead and run our tests using NPM run, test, colon,
watch.
We should get a failure because we do not have that data test attribute anywhere.
So there is no clickable area.
So we're going to fail.
And then what I'm going to do is add my appropriate data test attribute.
So right here after my class, I'm going to add my new data test attribute, giving it the exact value
that we're looking for in our test, which is clickable area.
Save that and let's see what we get.
Okay.
So the good news is our test is passing.
So everything is working as expected.
We are not finding this text.
We are then clicking on the clickable dev right here.
It can really be any element whatsoever as long as it has the expected data first attribute and then
we are verifying that we are seeing this content and where is this content coming from?
It is coming from our slot, so we are validating that everything is working exactly as expected, both
in terms of the collapse ability aspect of our recording as well as the use of the slot that we provide
it to the accordion.
We are still getting a warning right here and you're going to see it's a warning that we are very familiar
with by now failed to resolve component, font, OSM icon that is coming again because we are using
this global font awesome icon component that we registered with our main view app.
But again, in the context of our test, we the test doesn't know what this component is.
So it gets confused.
How do we fix this problem?
The exact same way we fixed it before, right here in my configuration object that I passed to mount.
I'm going to use the global property and here what I want to provide is a stubs property.
We are stubbing out or replacing that global component with something simpler.
So right here I'm going to do font awesome icon as my property.
That is the component that I want to replace and to simply use the view test, utils, default stub
or default replacement.
We can simply do true.
So any time the test finds a font awesome like a component, it's going to replace it with something
lighter and leaner and simpler.
So some kind of stub that the view test utils library wants to provide.
And if I save and force a test rerun, we're going to see that we're going to get a passing test.
And in addition to that, we're not going to get any warnings in our console.
All right.
So that is an example of how we can test for a slot component or a slot element, some kind of injectable
content from the perspective of a test.
All right.
That's all there is to cover in this lesson.
So I will see you in next one.