All right.
So let's continue on with our original goal of replacing the main native components local state.
This is logged in data property with a full reference to the IS logged in property of our View X Store.
So here's how that's going to work.
First up, for this example computed property, we can remove the former reference we have right here.
We no longer need it.
And then the next thing I'm going to do is change this property.
Instead of calling an example I'm going to call it is logged in.
So by default this is going to create a conflict.
We can see a a red squiggly appear here, but you probably can anticipate what it is is going to tell
us hey you have a duplicated key of is logged in because we have it is logged in computed property and
we also have an is logged in data property.
Of course our goal is to remove this so we can go ahead and remove that slice of data.
As soon as you do that, you'll see that the warning will go away.
And if we scroll up, this syntax is actually going to take us 50% of the way there because we have
a computed property called is logged in.
So anywhere where we are using that former data property right here, for example for our profile image
and right here for our subnet, that's still going to be valid syntax because we can provide a computed
property to the VFR directive and is logged in is going to be a computed property that references our
view next door and the is logged in property which is going to give a boolean of true or false.
So at the end of the day, View is still going to substitute a boolean right here.
The big difference of course is that is logged in is now coming from the view store and not from a local
is logged in data property.
So the good news is we don't actually have to change anything in our template.
This is great.
We are now correctly reading from the store, we're getting a boolean and we're providing it to our
template in the way the VRF directive is meant to be used and that takes us halfway there.
The only other factor we have to deal with, of course, is that when the user presses the action button
right here, we, we run the log in user method and here we can see the method defined below in methods
and in log in user.
We're still referencing our former data property called is logged in and this is not what we want.
So in the very next lesson, we're going to swap our code here to complete the other half of the equation
that when the user presses the action button we want to issue a mutation to our store that is going
to update is logged in.
We're going to see how to do that in the very next lesson.