Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and today we're going to
finally get to analyze the NBA data. I
hope you're pretty excited about today's
tutorial and to start off what we're
going to do is we're going to have a
look at what we created last time
because that is going to help us a lot
during today's tutorial and last time we
created our own very first function. This
function is called myplot and it
requires two parameters: data and rows.
The first parameter is compulsory makes
sense because R function can't operate
without any data and rows isn't
compulsory because it has a default
value so if you don't supply the rows
that you want to visualize it will just
visualize all of the values. Now here you
can see what this function does, it takes
any data to supply and replaces it
over here and the rows that you supply
get replaced here and here as well and so
what the function does is it first
subsets the data that you supply based
on the rows that you require and here
we are using that very important feature
of subsetting in R that we talked about
in one of the previous tutorials then we
are plotting the data with the matplot
function and we're using the legend
function to create a legend and so here
I've got an example. I'm going to plot
the games of the top ten paid NBA
players for the past 10 years just by
running this one line and as you can see
there we go that's a plot. So now we're
going to do is we're going to move on to
analyzing and driving insights and I 'm
going to go to this new tab. So I've
prepared some code here already and I
invite you to follow along, so as we run
these lines just code them up in your
R studio. I decided not to write them
up one by one because we're kind of
moving now from the stage where we're
learning R and learning all these
things that we need for this analysis to
actually performing the analysis. So the
focus today is going to be on analytics
and on data science and you know doing
the analysis in smart thought through
way so that's what we're going to be
talking about most of the day today. So
let's
get started, myplot salary. What are we
going to plot here? First thing I was
interested to see was how have the
salaries of these players been changing?
So how did they actually get here to
being the top 10 players paid players as
you can see Kobe Bryant was always quite
up there at his has, has been
growing up until the previous season
2014, 2015 and his record was over 30
million dollars for one year of playing
and then here we've got the rest so you
can see that the Joe Johnson started quite
above but then the rest caught up with
him and now they're all sitting over
here, so that's how the salaries have
been changing. Now, let's a plot how much
they get paid per game. So salary divided by game and
this is where I first ran into this
conundrum that we've got some anomalies
here. What happened here? So why is who's
this Kobe Bryant and Derek Rose, so why
are they getting paid so much per game?
As we saw previously their salaries are
comparable to the others.
Well the reason here is that both of
these players were actually injured in
that 2013-14 season and that's why per
game, they didn't play that many games. So
their salary per game is quite high and
same thing salary per field goals. So
what we could do from a data analytics
point of view? We could we remove these
anomalies and then continue for analysis.
However digging further into the
basketball data, I found that these
players put so much effort into their
game that they get injured quite a lot.
So we would see discrepancies like this
throughout the whole data set and more
where we wouldn't see them they would be
still skewing our data found us
knowing it so therefore visualizing
salary and ingame statistics together
might not be the best option and the
reason for that is that salary is not
affected by injuries,
whereas in game statistics R and so
the players get paid regardless of
whether they're playing or not they have
contract but their statistics such as
games played field goals and so on. They do
get affected, so from an analytical point
of view unless we can somehow exclude
those
at the effect of injuries. We shouldn't
visualize salaries and ingame statistics
together. So let's go and look at the
in-game matrix, let's plot the minutes
played and what do we see here?
Well here we see how many minutes each
of the players played in the
past 10 years. Ok and let's plot points, so
what we see here is another thing like
we know that Derrick Rose is for instance a
great player and he was MVP and 2010-11
season but here we can see that the
points that he brought to his team dropped
over here.
What same with Kobe Bryant but
the reason for that is that both these
players are injured over here. So once
again we can see that injuries are
affecting our visualization. So how do we
fix that from like how to approach it as
data scientists and actually how do we
take injuries out of the equation?
Well we know that injuries affect all
in-game statistics right, so if you don't
attend the game you're injured you don't
attend the game but you also don't score
goals. So what we can do is we can
normalize in-game matrix by in-game
matrix and this that's what I have here.
So if we take field goals and divide
them per game rather than just plotting
field goals by themselves, if we plot
that then you will see that now we can
actually compare them so even though
some players were injured, some players
were not the your divide your calculating
how many goals scored per game so
actually per game that that they attended.
Now injuries do sometimes affect and quite
often affect players even when they're
playing but already we are extracting or
where mitigating some of that effect
that injuries have on our visualization
and so now you can go ahead and compare
their goals per game that player score
and as you can see back in the day Kobe
Bryant had a crazy amount of 13 per game
and now it's quite, is dropped quite a
lot and right now in the lead we've got
Lebron, Lebron James with about just over
nine goals per game on average. That's not
points, that's actually goals.
Ok and now let's visualize another
normalized matrix let's visualize field
goals per field goal attempts. I think that
one will be pretty interesting.
So if we look at that this is
basically the accuracy of the players, so
how many goals did they make divided by the
how many attempts do they make? So
here you can see right away that Dwight
Howard is up there up at the top and way
above all other players in terms of
accuracy and he is the fifth highest
paid player in the NBA currently. So what
does that mean? Well that means that
basically out of the balls that he
throws at the net, about 60-percent
nearly six percent actually and in a
goal. So let's see how he's going in
terms of actual attempts, so we know that
his attempts to convert very well but
how many attempts per game does he have?
Let's look at this visualization, here we
see that Dwight Howard is actually at
the very bottom.
Alright he was at the top for
conversion of or successful attempts. Now
he's at the bottom for the actual number
of attempts per game and therefore it
makes sense that he doesn't actually
score that many points per game. Even
though that his accuracy is quite high
because he makes a few attempts, he
doesn't score that many point and so
that's an inside we could derive right
away and probably basketball player
people with a lot of knowledge about
basketball could comment on this and could
say why exactly he doesn't make that
many attempts? Maybe he's on the court in a
position that is not designed to make
that many attempts or maybe it's not the
case maybe he he can start making more
attempts and then because his accuracy is so
high maybe he'll start scoring more
goals. So that's something to look into,
that requires more was as it's called
domain knowledge. So knowledge about
basketball, now we're going to move on to
some more interesting observations and
let's say minutes played per game. So I
thought this was quite interesting,
you can see that the minutes played per
game for these top 10 players has been
dropping over all. So you can see the trend
here, it's going down and I couldn't
explain that, I couldn't explain why. So I'll
understand if it was for one or two
players but over all these players seem
to play less minutes per game on average
as we move from earlier years in their
career to later years
and that would be interesting to find
out why. Ok so at the same time if we
plot the games you can see that they
have in the number of games that it may
be playing is actually pretty consistent, it's
not that they're playing more games and
therefore they're playing less minutes.
They're playing pretty much the same
number of games but they're playing less
minutes per game. So that's that's an
interesting one.
Ok so time is valuable but since
they're less on the court, less minutes
per game on the court, their times value, let's
see who uses that time most efficiently
so who scored the most field goals per
minute played? Let's run that one and
here we can see that it's actually Kevin
Durant. He is quite young and so he when
I was gathering this data I noticed that
he joined the NBA quite recently
ago like relatively recently. So he's
young and you can see that his goals for
a minute played have been increasing
with time. So looks like, I've seen
a few articles calling him the rising
star, so we'll see how it goes but so far
the data does confirm that he's
using his time on the court valuably and
that's what we're seeing and also we've
seen kind of two groups which in some
players are here and we've seen some
players over here. So other players that
fall into this group Kevin Durant, Dwyane
Wade,  Carmello, Anthony and Lebron
James very interesting to see this type
of grouping and finally one more
interesting visualization that I found was
points divided by field goal. So it's kind of
player style. So impossible you can score
a two-point goal or you can score a
three-point goals and also you'll see
that some of the the averages here
actually above three points, that's
because our field goals or our points
data includes both gold, field goals
and also includes the free shots that
they get. So we would need to subtract
the free shots points from points to
exclude that effect but unfortunately we
don't have that data in, in our data set,
so let's just bear with this. We can still
see that player's style, player playing
style is changing with time. So a good
example that jumps out right away is
Kevin Durrant. You can see that first
he used to score less points per field
goal so he was going for the two-point
shots more and then he started scoring
more points so that means you started
great for the more for the three-point
shots or he was getting more free
throws and then it dropped and then it went
up. So it's interesting to see how some
of the players have a change in style
like that or Kobe Bryant for instance
like the average dropped and then it
started going up again or what's another
one here we can see Chris Bosh, you can
see that his average was dropping
consistently and then started growing. So it would
be interesting to see what is the cause
of these changes are these trail about
their trainers telling them to change
the style or other trends in the
basketball sport that change over time
and things like that would be
interesting to observe that. Ok so there
we go, that's some analysis of the stats
that we have and what you can do is you
can perform a take a similar approach
and explore some other things because
there's so many things that we haven't
explored yet here. You can just try and
normalized different various matrices by
different matrices and a plot some of
these things and find some inside of
your own and see what you're able to
discover. I hope you found this tutorial
interesting and exciting and I look
forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, happy coding!