Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. In the previous tutorial,
we prepared our data set for analysis so
now that we have the region column in
this merged data frame and today we're
going to visualize it and first off
we're going to use the same Q plot
function, so in that way it's going to be
very similar to what we've already done
in when we were creating this beautiful
plot and therefore well first of all let
me type in for the name, visualizing.
There we go so and that's why because we're
going to be very similar, that's why I
wanted to encourage you to pause this
video and go and try to practice that on
your own to just try and create that
plot based on your what you already know
about Q plot and what we've already seen
and trained how to do. So try and create
it and then come back to the video and
we'll compare the results and now I'll
proceed to creating this visualization.
Alright so follow along with the code
and we're going to get this done and
also by the way it's not going to be
just the repetition of what we've
already done we will also learn a couple
of new tricks with Q plot, I've got some
some things I wanted to show. So Q plot,
and don't forget we need the library
GGplot2 but we've already got it loaded
so that's that sorted so data equals
merged, that's our data frame that
we're visualizing and then we've got x
equals internet users and y is going
to be birth rate so it's just as last
time.
Alright so if we run that, there
we go so now we can just copy paste and
improve our visualization step-by-step. Here
we're going to say color equals region,
remember we don't need the I if we are
mapping a variable or rather than
applying it to all of the values. So here
we go, that is pretty much the end result
that we were after with map division, but
once again we want this to look nice we
wanted to tell a story. Here it's still
very small, so let's start fixing it up
and also let's learn quite a few new things and
so first thing we're going to learn is
shapes. I will show you how to
change the shapes of these
scatterplot.
Alright so let's say I want to
paste that or actually I want to copy
that and paste that and here after
region, what I want to say is first we
need to increase the size. We use the
other I and then we want to say shape, so
I'm going to start with just one shape
and then we will explore what other
shapes exist if you run that then you
can see that we've got triangles now
right?
Looks like a little forest and so what's up
with the shape of parameter? What kind of
shapes can we have? Well I've got a small
chart prepared over here and you can have
shaped from 0 to 25 so at the start
you've got kind of like hollow shapes,
the first three then you've got these
and another holes so all of these are
pretty much hollow out up to here. The field
shapes is good to remember their fifteen,
sixteen, seventeen up to 20 and then 21.
If you ever forget, you can
always just type in R shapes in google
and this is you know you'll get one of
these pictures right away. So let's
try a couple more,
let's see how this chart will change if
we actually let's just try it right here, let's
say shape number two, the hollow triangle
and if you run that you can see that
here is a bit different and you can see
a bit better so you can see where
triangles overlapped it might be a
better option for some charts.
Let's try another one, let's try 15. 15 is
squares right and 23, 23 is hollow
rhomboid or diamonds.
Ok so that's enough playing around with
that but at least now you have learned
how to create how to change the shape of
the point in this scatterplot.
Alright so now what we're going to do?
Now we're going to, going to learn about
transparency. So that's the second thing
I want to show today is
transparency.
Alright so we're going to copy what we already
have and let's say shape number 19,
if you run that, you'll see that it's
not hollow and sometimes that they
overlap right? So sometimes you've got
overlapping shapes and that might hide
some of the dots and might misrepresent
your data.
So how'd you fix that? Well it's very
simple, you add transparency and touch
transparency, you use the parameter which is
called alpha. So you type in alpha equals
once again we're setting transparency
for all the dots and here you type in
value from 0 to 1 right? So basically
zero is fully transparent, one is fully
opaque so let's say 0.1 and let's have a
look at that. So if I run that, you can see that it's
very transparent, very likely fading can
barely see them so let's say is 0.6, see
that's already better so when they
overlap you can actually see that they
are overlapping. You can kind of see
behind the dots, so there you go and it's very
useful for scatterplots we have lots and
lots of observations, to see where there
are clusters of observations because
those areas will be darker when
observations overlap.
Ok and finally the third thing I wanted
to show you is how to add the title to
your visualization. Right now we don't
have a title up at the top so let's go
ahead and add one. It's very simple, you
just need to use the parameter which is
called main so if I type in comma main so
you can see how we are chaining more and
more parameters we've got all of this is.
All being passed into Q plot and you
can keep going for quite a while and
here we're going to say birth rate vs
something simple internet users, let's
give it some more space and let's run that,
whoops, so here you can see the title has
appeared now.
Well there we go, that's how we used a
Q plot to create another awesome
visualization and also we learned a
couple of things about Q plot, shapes
transparency and how to set the title
and we'll talk much more about
visualization further down in the course.
We will learn a even more powerful
function which is a GGplot can't wait
to tell you all about it and for us to
go through those tutorials and this
brings us to the end for today. I hope you
enjoyed these basketball tutorials and
you learned quite a lot about data
frames and also some basics of
visualization. As you can see it's not
hard at all and
can help you create very powerful
insights and I look forward to seeing
you in the next tutorial,
until then happy coding.