Hello and welcome back to the course on R
programming and today we're moving a step up.
Today we're talking about facets. Facets
layering of our visualization process so
let's move into R studio and get
started with facets.
Ok so what we're going to look at? Well
let's start by looking at our histogram
that created quite a while ago so it's
going to be R, S, T, U, V is going to be
our letter today and we're going to
recreate that histogram ggplot data
equals movies aesthetic whoops x equals
budget millions around that. That's how
V and I will say V let's add some
geometry, geom histogram, binwidth equals
10 aesthetics. We want to fill remember
want to connect the filled, so maybe let's
create like this one out.
I just create that that's how histogram
now we want to say comma aesthetics fill
equals is genre. Alright that gives us
this blurry,
that's the word. A very blurry histogram
so we want to add some boarders to it
and we do that with color and what are
we doing now? We're going to map or we're
going to set the color. If we want to
color to be consistent for all of these
bars.
That's right, we we just want to set the
color and we set our choosing the
aesthetics function so we just say color
equals black. I hope you can see how
mapping and setting is playing out in
this whole section so far. So there we go
we've got this kind of comical looking
chart which is fine which I kind of like
how it looks. So there we go, that's our
bar plot or histogram but at the same
time it's not very legible right so you
can see what's going on with the action
over here maybe you can see a bit what's
going on with the comedy but with the
drama this town of kind of histograms
they are hard to read because the the drama
wasn't because of the drama because
there because the drama is the drama,
horror,
the romance that all of these categories
they're split so far apart from each other.
So soon as you get further way this is
green bar or maroon, is that maroon? No sea
green color bar. This sea green color bar,
they're far away so you can't really
visually compare them that easily.
So what would be better and would be
actually great if it is if we had a
histogram for every one of these genres
and is that possible?
Well of course that's possible. How do we
do that? Let's let's look at that facets.
We're going to use facets to do that.
That's basically what it is, so facets
allow you to create lots of charts.
Let's copy this and we're going to say
plus so we're adding another layer and
this layer is going to be a facet grid,
so we're saying facet underscore grid
and we're going to say, so this is how to
use facets and we might take a bit of
time to get used to but what you have
inside a facet is you've got this tilde
operator and on the left you have
something that is zzz, and on the
right you have a dot right or the other
way around.
On the left you have a dot and then
on the right, you have zzz depending on
whether you want columns or rows.
So let's try this way, let's say genre
tilde dot right? So we want genre
and then we're just running because it's
either, so this way
what are we getting? We're getting genre
is the rows right? So the rows, the one
the one on the left represents rows and
the one on the right is column and then
on the columns, you just want nothing. You
just want
that's why you put the dot so genre in
the rows and the columns you just want
one column and just you know that's all
you want.
So that's we've got these histograms the
only problem here is that these are so
small you can read them at all because
this one is using up the whole axis and
the axis is uniform across all of
these histograms so how do we fix that?
Well very easy, all you have to do is
just after this at another parameter and
say scales equals in quotation marks to
say free. It's just something you need to
remember if you want to free up your
scales.
On that, you'll see that beautiful so
each one of them has its own scale and
from zero to eight, zero to five, they're
like 215 or something that and basically
now you can tell where which ones are
skewed where. So this is the budget so a
lot of money for for instance for action
movies is going around like that, 30
mark but then there is this hump over here
and the hump over here and then like here
it's pretty much all normal distribution.
Here you've got a bit of a longer tail,
here the action movies of course have
the longest tail and they have the
highest budget as well.
Ok so that is our facets, that's the
start of facets. Now let's apply our
facets to scatter plots. Alright what's
a scatterplot? So V let's use
another letter today. Let's say W, because
we're working for different plot. Now we're
saying ggplot and we're going to say
data equals movies and then I'm going to
say aesthetics x equals this is our
fairest scatterplot which we've created
like a thousand times already
audience rating comma and here we're
going to say color equals genre. Alright,
W is ready, now let's say add some points
geom point and that's right away
set the size to 3 but math said it it's a
bit bigger size three.
Well now, let's go ahead and do some
fascinating facets. So here as we know, we'll
say plus facet underscore grid then
we'll say genre until the dot.
So let's run that, ok beautiful how about
we do a similar thing but instead of on
the left
genre and on the left and the right
we'll just a year.
How about that? What happens then uh-huh
so here we've got year. That's also
beautiful and you kind of see where this
is all going, so we've got genre on the
left, dot on the right. On the left, here on
the right where is this all going Kirill?
Well this is all going to a new great
thing I'm going
do. We're gonna say genre tilde
year, so what is going to give us? Viola!
How cool is that? If this doesn't
look cool, then you don't have a heart. I'm
joking. If it doesn't look, oh that's
totally fine but I think it looks pretty
cool. So we've got the years in the
columns and the genres in the rows that
is amazing. Let's let's make it even
better. Let's add another layer now that
we know all about layering and we know
so many different types of layers
let's add it smoother. It doesn't matter
if you add it here or you add it after the
facet grid. We just add it here
whoops geom smooth and then we just say
plus, so if I run these what do we get, what do
we get haha. How amazing is that?
So now we have a smoother inside of each
one and we can look at these all the
beautiful trends.
I think that's already a great great
start and what else did we want to do
here?
Well the last thing is let's just add
the budget as a size so here we're just
going to say instead of three we're just
going to say don't forget the aesthetic
now because we want to map the side
instead of setting it budget millions
right?
Run, give it a second. Okay,
viola! So pretty isn't it? So you've
got the size and represents the budget
you've got the points which is a credit
rating the audience rating that the
smoother you've got the color and you've
got facet grid. So we've combined
quite a lot of concept that we learned
into this one amazing chart and now what
we want to do is it's nearly ready so
remember that the chart I said the
we're going to improve that chart number
one when it was just by itself. So this
is number one but still will improve and
how can we improve this already amazing
chart?
Well what you'll find is that that the
x-axis looks ok so it goes from
somewhere around 0-100 but the y-axis
for some reason goes from minus 50 to
150 so if we zoom in here you'll see
that it goes from
minus 150-150 so here as well minus 50 to
150 and why is that? Well that's because
of these bands so sometimes when there's
uncertainty these bands become wide and
it just means the confidence interval
and confidence bands actually and
because they're stretching out the chart
the chart is stretching out so what we
need to learn is we need to learn how to
zoom into our chart so that it's always
between 0 and a hundred and that's what
we're going to learn on the next
tutorial.
What a great segue. I look forward to
seeing you next time and until then
happy coding.