Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming and today we're finally at
the top. We're at the top of the food
chain.
We're talking about the theme, layering of
R visualizations and so what does that
involve? Well it involves all the non
data ink on our chart, so basically
when you change the formatting of the
text or make given colors or you change
where the label is positioned. The legend
is positioned and things like that. So
let's see how we can apply all that. Now
well that's that came unexpected that's
the beautiful chart that we created
last time and now we're going to recall
one of the charts that we created
previously and we're going to improve it
by adding a theme to it. Now ideally
you'd want to add a theme to all the
charts that we created and make them all
look stunning for the presentation but
we won't spend all the time doing this
it will take a couple of tutorials to go
through all them so we're just going to
practice on one and then in your free
time you can go back to the transfer
created and and do the same operations
because ultimately is just working with
the same types of elements on charts. You
can simply replicate the same procedures.
Ok so the letter today is 0 and we're
going to create the histogram so let's
first find it improve right, let's look
for the word improve and this one that's
the one I'm talking about. So let's copy
this line and put it in here and there
was it? This one that's what I'm after.
So let's copy this into todays
tutorial you can close the search.
Ok that's our letter O and now we want
to say O plus. Ok I've already copied the
plus, so what is this we're creating a ggplot
with data equals movies aesthetic is
the budget millions and then we're
plotting it as histogram so we're
mapping the fill to genre and we're
setting the color to black. So we are
well familiar with this histogram, it's our
favorite histogram we used it so far
many times. Alright and so now what  we're
going to do is we're going to
learn how to add a couple of things. So
first we're going to add a label right?
That's what we want to learn how to add
and label basically means the access
label, I meant now let's type that an
axis, axis labels so what we're
going to do in fact what we're going to
do is we're going to change put this
into an object so that it's faster and
let's give it a name let say H, we run that
and now if I run just H on its own
you'll see that the whole histogram is in
there because it includes both the base
layer and this additional layer and we
just saved this new combination of the
two inside H right and what we're going
to do now is on top of H we're going to
add a couple of things. So that it is so
we achieve those non data ink
transformations so let's say H plus and
will say xlab, whoops... and we actually
talked about ylab. So this should be
a bit familiar money axis right and if
we run that,  you'll see that at the
bottom is very small so if we zoom in
over here it says money axis and we change
the name and we can do the same thing we
can do plus y lab and we can say number
of movies so let's maybe put like that
its looks better.
So there we go so we have relabeled both
of the axis, that's great. Now let's
format them so there they look better
label formatting and we're going to say
pretty much the same thing and here
we're going to say plus so this might
look a bit complicated but sometimes
it's just best to remember it so theme
axis dot title dot x equals. So the title
of axis x equals element this is the
part that you have to remember element
text and here's going to be color equals
we're going to say just dark green. So
we're not mapping to anything we're just
setting it because it's just the color
of the text right so color of the text
is dark green and the size is going to be 30,
and then I want to say comma and then I
want to say access and just basically
all the 304 practice axis title dot y
equals element underscore text and here
you wanna say color equals red and
size same thing equals 30. So if I run
this, you'll see that now they're nice
and big size 30 money axis and number of
movies beautiful. Ok that's a great start
and that's what we mean by non a data
ink and now we're going to do is we're
going to make these tick marks bigger
because they're pretty small right? So
let's go ahead and make them bigger. So
I'm going to take this all of this copy
it and I'll say tick mark formatting and
so basically just inside theme. This is
the main function we can be working with
and we'll check it out just in just a
second so here we'll say axis dot text dot x
equals, let's get to the tickpoints, tick
marks, text element text and then size
equals 20 and this one I'm not going to
retype. This is going to be y. So lets
run this,
so there you go so they're much bigger now
better looking and much more legible.
Alright that's a great thing. So you're
probably getting curious about this
theme function that we're using what
else can you supply to this function
right? So let's check it out.
Alright let's zoom in into here and what
you'll see here theme elements we've got
line, rectangle, text, title, aspect ratio,
axis title, axis text, ticks line,
background a lot a lot a lot of stuff so
all of these are how you can control the
presentation of your chart and I highly
recommend you just look through them and
whatever you want to do something just
check the theme function and see what
try to guess what it would be and it'll
probably be there or you can always
check online and look for the help and
it will help you understand which
elements of the theme function you need
to tweak to get the chart that you are
after. So so far we've learned quite a
few and let's
learn a another few that we will need
for this plot so what we want is we
want to now control this legend
alright so let's do that, let's say legend
formatting, legend formatting alright. So
what we're going to do is we're going to
say comma and here I'm just gonna add an extra
space so just that we have some space
not necessarily don't have to add it.
Element, so legend title element
underscore text and here we're going to
say size equals 30 and legend dot text as
you can imagine that's the actual names
of the categories element underscored
text size equals 20 and let's not, let
end there that for now. Let's run that. Ok you
can see it's much bigger and now I'm
going to show you another thing so if
you put in this how to control the
positioning of the legend.
So what we need to do is first we want
to say a legend position, legend dot
position so I want to put it in the top
corner over here on the chart on
actual chart, legend position and that
way I want to say c11. So you can pass 0 or
1 and once again you can find all this
information in the help of theme. So 0 is
left, so 0 is the start of the
action so basically this is 0,0 this is
1,0 this is 0,1. This corner and this corner
is 1,1. So I wanted in the top right
corner.
I just run this you will see that it
gets put in the top corner but it gets
put their kind of like crooked that's
because I need to set an anchoring point
you need to say legend dot justification
equals c11 so which corner of the
legend once again bottom left, bottom
right, top left or top right you want to
put in that in this corner. I want to put
the top right corner of the legend in
the top right corner of the chart so if I run
this now,
beautiful! right? So now the legend is
actually where it's possible it's on the
chart in the top right corner and we
saved all of that
white space on the right. Ok one more
thing left and that is of course the
title of the plot. How do we add a title
to the plot?
You need to add a layer which is called
GGtitle and in the in here you type in
the title we plot which is a movie for us
is movie budget distribution and then
you and that plus back so if I run this. You
will see that the titles appeared but it's
very small so how do we format the title
itself?
Well we go back into the theme function
and here we just say plot dot title
equals element underscore text color
let's give it a color like dark blue
then we'll say size, let's put this on
a new line, size equals 40 and family
this is the font. I just wanted to show
you how you can change the actual font
and here we'll say a carrier.
Alright so if we run this now it's dark
blue, it's big and it's a different font.
Beautiful I think we've done a great job
and I think now we can with a lot of
pride take this and put it into the
final report and let's put the
resolution now let's go ahead and copy
this or I'll just save it and we'll copy
it into our final presentation over here
and viola! Everything is beautifully,
beautifully done. So we've got this final
climb deliverable with all of these
beautiful and visualizations in it and I
think we've done a great job overall.
So today we learned quite a few things
most of them are relating to the theme
function and we talked about how to add
non-data ink to our charts so he'll play
around with that check out all the other
order some of the other options that are
available to your theme and maybe see
how else you can improve this chart
and I look forward to next time until then,
happy coding.