Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming and today we've got another
exciting challenge to help us practice
the skills that we've learned and once
again we're going to be talking about
movies.
Alright so let's jump straight into it.
The movie reviews website was very happy
with your deliverable for the previous
assignment and now they have a new
request for you.
The previous consultant had created
chart for them which is illustrated on
the next slide.
However, the R code used to create the
diagram has since been lost and cannot
be recovered. Your task is to come up
with the code that will recreate the
same chart making it look as close as
possible to the original. A new data set
has been supplied. Alright so that
sounds like an exciting challenge and
before we move on to the actual
visualization I'm going to create. I
would like to show you the data set
first because that will help us
understand what's going on.
So in order to get the data set you need
to go to www.superdatascience.com/rcourse,
so R course is one word here
and if on this website you scroll down
to Section 6, then you will find the
challenge which is the PDF file with the
challenge which can download. So you can
see the image right in front of you and
also the homework data set which
will go through right now. So here's the
data set and as you can see there are
many more columns then what we worked
with in the previous challenge so let's
have a look at them and go through them
one by one. The first column is day of the
week and it tells us which day of the
week the movie was released on. Then
we've got the director's name, the genre
of the movie, the title of the movie, the
release date, the studio that release the
movie, so you've got studios like Sony,
Paramount Pictures, Warner Brothers and
so on.
You've got the adjusted gross so we've
got the gross in millions of dollars
here that's how much the movie grossed
worldwide but the adjusted gross is the
same number adjusted for inflation of
ticket prices so because some of these
movies were released long long time ago
like back and all the way back to the
nineteen-thirties obviously you have to
adjust buy a ticket price inflation to
get a comparable figure. However that
won't really be impacting us in this
specific challenge then we've got the
budget of the movie then we've got the
imdb rating the movie lens rating,
overseas so this is the overseas gross,
how much the movie made not in the U.S.,
overseas percentage so what percentage of
the gross was made overseas as opposed to
in the US. The profit in millions of
dollars, the profit percentage so that's
basically the profit divided by the
budget of the movie which is over here
and then we've got to the run time in
minutes how long the movie was and
finally we've got to the US gross, so
how much did the movie make in the U.S.
so U.S. gross and overseas gross over
here, together make up the total gross
and finally we've got the gross
percentage in the U.S., so what
percentage of the revenue was made just
in the US.
Alright so there we go, quite a lot of
columns. I know it might feel overwhelming
but let's now go on to the visualization
and see what we're talking about there.
So here's our visualization, it looks
pretty neat and actually very similar to
some of the visualization that we created
throughout the section. This is a boxplot
with a jitter in the background and what
is it visualizing? Well first of all
we've got the genre on x axis and then
we've got the gross on the vertical
axis. It's actually gross percentage US
which means it's that last column that
we were looking at what percentage of
the gross revenue was made in the US and
as you can see here for instance
adventure movies it's about just under
forty percent whereas comedy movies over
forty percent nearly fifty percent of
revenue on average is made in the US by
comedy movies. So that's what this plot's
visualizing and then you've got the
budget which is the size of the bubbles
which makes sense and you've got the
studio which is the color of the bubbles
and if you think about it. It's actually
just a combination of quite a few things
that we learned, so some aesthetics over
here and over here and over here and
then we've got some we've got a box plot,
we've got a jitter.
What else do we have? We've got something
theme so you can see that throughout
this plot, the comic sans ms point has been
used and then some of the font colors
has been have been changed and the sizes
have been adjusted so just the
combination on all the things and it's
simply a matter of going through the
steps that we learned and creating this
beautiful visualization. So there we go, if
you're comfortable with this challenge
if you feel comfortable to jump straight
into then go ahead and stop this video
and you can proceed with this homework
exercise. However as always I would like
to give you two hints, so the first hint
is going to be just a slight hint so
they feel free to listen through this
one let's go into hint number one. Hint
number one, is that you should notice
that the studio here and the genre are
not complete. So notice that not all
genres and studios are used. You will
need to filter your data frame after
importing the csv file. In the csv file,
we've got many more studios in that
and many more genres in than that. So you
will need to first filter your data
frame after you've imported the actual
data and then proceed with the
visualization. Otherwise, you will end up
with too many box plots and too many
colors. So that's a simple hint, hint
number one and as usual we're going to
proceed to hit number two. Now
hint number two is of course our fill in
the blanks exercise. Let's go and have a
look at that.
So if on this page, you download the last
file it'll be a zip file and inside
you've got an R file with the fill in
the blanks exercise and here I've got it
brought up for us so once again you just
need to look for the underscores and
replace them with what should be in
their place so here we've got all the
steps, lots of comments on what we're
doing and it should help you going to
get through this exercise even if you're
not entirely comfortable jumping into it
by yourself you should be quite ok going
through it with these fill-in-the-blank
and if at any point you feel stuck,
just refer back to the tutorials in this
section and you will definitely find
your way through
this exercise. As you can see, it's it's a
bit longer than usual but that's just
because we're adding layers and layers
and layers of visualization into R
plot and there we go. That's the
challenge for today, don't forget to
check out the solution in the separate
section at the end of the course and I
wish you the best of luck and until next
time, happy coding.