Hello and welcome back to your course on
R program.
How did you go to previous tutorial? I
hope you found it quite simple to create
variables in R and if so
congratulations because this is the goal
of this course to smoothen out that very
very steep learning curve that R
normally has and that students are
normally presented with when they're
starting their journey into R.
Alright, now that we're comfortable with
creating variables. Today we will learn
how to use them in different operations
varying from arithmetic operations to
even calling functions but don't be
afraid once again everything is
step-by-step so we will learn just the
right amount that we can handle in one
tutorial.
Alright first things first, we need to
save this file because it's always a
good skill to have to know how to save
the work you have done. So how do we save
this file that we've created here
with R code? Well it's pretty simple, if you're
on a Mac and then press command s, if
you're on a windows pc then press control s
or otherwise just click this save button
up at the top of here. So I'm going to
press command s and here you just have
to specify the name of your file. So we'll call it
tutorial 01 and click save. There we go,
that is our file saved and now we're
just going to create a new one by
clicking the R strip button over here
like we did last time and now we see a
blank worksheet over here, what we see here
is in the global environment we still
have all variables that we created last
time. Let's clean them up, now there's a
lot of ways to do it but we'll stick to
the basic one, we'll just click this broom
over here and say yes and that will
delete everything and lastly we just got
some code in the console and that's fine
let's leave it there. It will disappear as we
create more code it will scroll up and
out of our visibility.
Alright so let's start off by creating a
variable, we're going to create a
variable called A and we'll put the
value 10 into
this variable. So let's type that code
and run it, by the way I hope you're
following along because it's very
important to follow along and do the
exact same steps on your computer
because that way you will learn R much
faster than if you're just watching it.
So follow along and let's create a new
variable, this time we'll create a
variable called B and we'll put in the
value 5. Execute and as we can see we
we're reduced to this
the code has been copied into the
console and it has been executed over
here so we've got the variable. Alright,
so let's say we want to add these two
variables and put the result into a
third variable which is C. Let's go ahead
and do that,
so here we go there is the variable C
and we will assign it the value of a
plus B, very intuitive so hit return or
run and as you can see the code has been
copied into the console and we've got the
results over here. Now first off, what I
wanted to point out is that spaces in
R don't matter, as in many many or most
programming languages. So basically I can
remove these two spaces, we run the code
and it will run just fine.
The variable has been overwritten, it's
still 15. That is because the spaces, R
studio ignores spaces and they're
basically therefore your aesthetics. Now
the second thing was how do we print out
this variable? We know that the value of
C is 15 because we see it here but let's
say we don't have access to what's going
on in here then all we're left with is
the console and we can't see the value
of C in here, we just see that this
operation has gone through, how do we see
the value of C? So in other programming
languages you might have to the function
like print or print print F or alert or
other source of our functions in R
it's very simple, all you have to do is just
a print of the object name. So in this
case we'll just type in C and execute
this line and there we go we've got the
value 15, it has been printed out over
here. So that is how easy it is to get
objects to display on
your screen in R just basically print
the name of objects and execute that
line. Alright, let's move on
let's create another variable. So this
time we'll get a bit of a longer name,
we'll call it variable, variable one so far one
and we will assign it the value of 2.5
and before we execute that code let's
create a second variable right away. We'll
or let's prepare the code for a second
variable variable 2 and we'll assign it
the value of four. Now the other trick I
wanted to show you here was that in R,
you don't have to necessarily execute
all the code line by line like we've
been doing up to now.
So as you can see the carriage return is
here so if I just hit run right now then
all that will be executed is just this
line of code, but in R you can actually
highlight the elements of code that you
want to execute. So in this case, let's
say I want to execute these two lines at
the same time or not on at the same
time they will of course be executed one
after the other but I want to execute
them together. So in this case I
highlight them and hit run and as you
can see both lines have been copied into
the console and both lines have been
executed we've got two new variables
variable 1 and variable 2, so that's
how in R, you can execute bits of your
code and now actually it makes much more
sense of why we have comments so if I
wanted to put comments to this code
let's say I would say variable or one
here and here I would say variable 2
because of these hashtags, R knows that
these are comments now and if I were to
execute this code including the comments
then even though they're copied into the
console R knows that it should ignore
these two lines because they have
hashtags at the start so R will
actually only perform operations based
on these two lines that we actually want
so that is how you execute multiple
lines and how that how commons tie into
this whole coding in our exercise.
Alright so we're done with the variable
1 and variable 2, now let's go do some
operations with them. Let's say we want
to find out what
the result of their division will be. The
result of variable 1 divided by variable 2 and
let's run that line and now let's just
print out result. So as you could see it's
0.625.
Alright, so let's have 1, 1 more I wanted
to show you that not only you can
perform operations with variables and
include multiple variables in those
operations but you can actually call
functions and pass values to those
functions which are your variables.
Let's say I want to find out what the
square root of variable two is. Variable
two here is four so I would type in answer
is SQRT variable two. Now here, in this case
SQRT is a function and the brackets
indicate that the values inside are
being passed on to this function. Now
don't be worried if function seem a bit
of like a gray area to right now that's
totally fine,
we're not going to dive deep into them
now, we'll discuss them in a lot of
detailed down further down in this
course. What I wanted to show you here
was just to illustrate that variables
can be used in many different ways
including as arguments for functions. So
in this case, let's run this line and now
let's print out our answer as you can
see it is 2 which is correct.
Alright so those are our earth medic
operations and of course that's not
limit you can not only add and divide
you can multiply, you can subtract, you can
get square roots, you can basically do
any operation in R that you could
think of on your simple calculator or
even a complex calculator, but now what
we're going to do is we're going to move
onto character operations and see how we
can work with some character variables
just to illustrate that is also possible
in R. So let's start by creating a
variable called greeting and into this
variable we'll put the word hello,
so as you remember you have to use
quotation marks to tell R that you're
creating a character and then we'll
create a variable called name and into
this variable, we'll put the word Bob
so we want to create a message for bob
so let's add some lines and we want to
create a message-
We want to say hello Bob, so how do we
add these to a variable together?
Well in R, the function for adding two
strings together is called paste and to
that function, we're going to pass the
first variable which is greeting only
here and we're going to past the second
variable which is named over here and if
we execute this
Oh once again we got the error because I
did not execute these lines so how about
we run all of these three together? So if
we execute all these three, we can see that
first one execute, second and third and
now we can simply print out message over
here. As you can see, we've got hello Bob.
Alright so that's how we create and work
with the character variables as well and
once again we use the function here
don't worry if it seems a bit
complicated,
we'll talk much more about functions
further down in this course.
Ok so that is us for today. I would like
to invite you to practice with these
variables and see what other operations
you can think of so try multiplying, try
subtracting, try for instance maybe
including not just two variables but
three, four maybe five variables in one
operation and see what you get because
remember practice makes perfect and that
is the best way to learn a new
programming language and I look forward
to seeing you next time and until then,
happy coding.