Alright, so now we're going to start on
visualization process. What do you do
first? First we're going to prepare the
plots data and aesthetics layers
right. The foundation of our plot
we're going to say P is going to be
equal to or is going to contain. This
object is going to contain GGplot
data equals mov2, right? That's our
filter data set aesthetics and let's
set this aesthetics right away. The ones that
we're going to be for sure for the whole
plot here because as you can see we
actually have a few letters we've got
them box plots and then we've got the
jitter in the background but for both of
them for everything we see over here X
is always equals to genre and Y is always
equals to cross percentage US.
Now you can't say the same thing about
size or color because the box plots
don't have, are not colored by studio and
their size is not affected by budget. So
that's why we're not going to include
those aesthetics in the base or in the
foundation of our plot. We're only going
to include the two aesthetics that are
definitely going to stay constant. So genre
and cross percentage US studio, so how
we're going to do this? We're going to
say x equals genre and then what do we
want? We want to just go to the top here,
we've got the name of the column here
right so genre and y equals
gross percentage US. So if I run that, if I try
plotting it I'll get nothing because
obviously we don't have a geometry. So now
let's add a geometry right. So we'll
start by adding the simplest geometry
that we know is P plus geom underscore
point.
Alright so if I run this, you'll see that
I get these just points aligned with the
categorical variables over here at the
bottom and already you can see that
we've got the action-adventure animation
comedy and drama. So the correct five
genre is that we were after so our
filter work. Alright so obviously geom
point is not what we need. Let's try
box plot, geom box plot. You can see that
there is our box plot that's a good start
that's already looking similar to what
we have here
but at the same time you can see these
black dots. So let's just pay attention
to that, let's quickly make a note of that in
our heads that these dots are actually
part of the box plot geometry. As you can
see, we don't have any point or other
type of layer and so basically these
outliers are part of the box plot and
we'll need that information just now
when we're fixing up our chart in a
couple of steps from here.
Alright so we've got the box plot let's
add the jitter right, so in the
background, we saw jitter so let's add
that. So if I run that you can see we've
got the jitter but in this case it's on
top right we want to put the jitter in
the background so let's do that. They've
got a box on top but now they're
covering the jitter so let's give the
box plot some transparency do you
remember how to give transparency? It's alpha
parameter we're going to set it to 0.7.
Now notice that we're not
creating an aesthetic here we're not
well if alpha is an aesthetic but we're
not mapping it to anything, so we're not
using the aes function because we're
actually just setting it to a certain
values 0.7 for all of the box
plot and because we are specifying this
alpha inside the brackets for box geom
box but it's only going to be applicable
to these layers, it's not going to be
applicable to the jitter layer.
Alright so if I run that, we can see that
the box plots are a bit transparent now
which is good.
Alright so now we want to add size and
colors to the points. Remember something
that we didn't do here because the size
and color are only applicable to the
jitter layer and that's what we want to
do. So we're going to add it here, we're
going to use the aesthetic function
because what are we doing? We're mapping,
we're not setting, we're mapping. So size
equals with the size equal to budget
and color equals studio now studio we
remember that that is the correct name
but let's check with the the name for
budget is in our data set. This is kind
of the consequence of not changing the
names of your columns.
Okay well it's not enough space so we
would do something like str, just run
that quickly and finally here so there
you go budget meal.
That's the one we need, so size
equals budget meal so I can start with
that, you'll see the size increase good
and now I can add here as well
color equals studio so if I run this
you'll see that the color has appeared
and also this to your filter work
because we only have the six students
that we are after.
So there we go, that's that's a good
start where else do we need?
The other thing I wanted to show you
here is that you can still see these
black dots right, you can see there's
that black dot there's this 2 those
3 and there's that 1 and in fact
these are part of the box plots not
these are not part of the jitter as you
remember we saw in that first time when
we just added the box plot layer they
were already there and you can see that
this green point is in fact the same dot
but it's just jitter to the right and
here for every dot in the box plot for
every outline there's a dot that is
already added by the jitter. So in fact
what we need to do is we need to get rid
of these outlines we don't want to see
them because they're already present
through the jitter layer. How do we do
that? Well in the geom box plot there's a
parameter called outlier dot color and
we just need to set it to N/A so meaning
we don't want a color at all and as you
can see those dots have disappeared now
and there's no duplication of
information on our chart.
Ok good so what we're going to do now is
we're going to save this into all save
in quotation marks because uh we just
going to kind of create a new object which
will contain this whole visualization
that right. So if I just call Q here
then you'll see that the visualization
is ready and now we can proceed
with the final finishing touches because
we're nearly done here.
It's that quick. So we're just going to
do the non data ink part, we're going to
say Q move just all right Q of q+ so
just give it some little adjustments
will say xlab is the bottom axis also
xlab is going to be called genre then
we'll say ylab is going to be called
gross percentage US just like in the
chart that we saw and GGtitle which is
the title of the whole plot is going to be
called domestic gross what wasn't there. This
percentage by genre right okay so if I
run all of this and then I plot Q you'll
see that all of these titles have now
appeared and that's a good start.
Now what we have to do is fix up the
theme layer or add a theme layer we're
going to say q is q + and now we just
want to make these bigger add the colors
change the font and so on.
So how do we do this? Theme and inside
theme we're going to start by changing
the colors right? So we'll say,
access.title.x is element text , color this is the access title which is genre and its blue here
we'll say blue and the size,
well this is kind of method of
experimentation in this case very excited
study but you could sit like 20 or 25
and would be I think close enough.
Alright so that's the x-axis, let's do
the same thing for the y-axis. The colors
blue, size 30 exactly the same.
Ok so now we want axis not title but
instead we want the text so that's these
little mark here 80,60,40,20 as you can
see they're a bit bigger there than we
have and the color is still black so we
don't need color we just need the size
and it started to 20 and same thing for
Y.
Ok so let's quickly run that and see how
we go, we'll just get rid of this comma for now.
Around that you'll see that already
it's getting better.
The only thing is we haven't changed the
size of our plot titles so let's do that
quickly plot dot title equals element
text color it's actually black so
we don't need to change the color or
just a size equals 40 and then also the
legends right? The legend title and which
text,
so or I mean the text of the different
names or categories in the legend so you
can see here this is bigger and the size
all of the text is actually will just
actually changed as well. So legend dot
title is going to be let's copy this and
say 20 and here finally we'll say legend
dot text so if I run this what do we get?
Ok it looks much better so what do we
still notice? We notice that the font is
different so here is the standard font.
Here it's comic sans ms. How can we fix
that? Well one way to fix it is to in
every single one of these two say comma
family equals comic sans ms right? That's
one way of doing it and which is to run
that one you'll see that the plot title
has changed and now we have to do the
same for every single one of them but
that would take quite some time. So I'm
going to show you a shortcut instead of
typing it up every single time
what we can do is we can say text equals
and then the same thing element text and
in here will say family equals comic
sans ms and this will apply to all of
the titles and text on our plots. So if I run
this, you'll see that they have all
changed to comic sans ms. Okay viola!
Nearly finished just one time final
touch over here budget meal I needs to
be changed to budget dollar millions or
m and how do we do that? Well this is
another thing that we haven't discussed
yet but it's actually very simple so
final touch so Q dollar labels, dollar
size and we need to assign it
we're doing it to assign it we want to
say quotation marks budget dollar M.
So if I run that and I look at you now as
you can see the name of this label has
changed name of legends has changed.
Alright so there we go, that's how we
solve this challenge. I hope you enjoyed
this walk through and I look forward to
seeing you next time
until then, happy coding.