Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming. I hope you had a chance
to play around with the matplot function and
that you were able to create some
impressive chart and as you can tell it's
getting pretty exciting already. We're
working with charts, we're looking at the
basketball data. What's coming up next
right? So what we're talking about today
is subsetting. Subsetting is a very
important topic in R and actually a
lot of R users get it wrong.
In fact some R programmers can go for
years without knowing exactly what
subsetting is and how it works,
thinking that they do know it until they
run into a problem one day and then only
they find out about subsetting. So today I
want to make sure that you will never
ever end up in a situation like that and
that's why we're going to get this topic
down pat.
Alright so let's go to a new file and
the way I want to introduce this topic
is through something you already know, so
we've already talked about using this
square brackets with vectors. So let's
create a vector and in that vector we'll
just put five values, just five letters
and if we run this lecture there they
are those are our five letters. Now we
know that if we want to extract just the
first and the fifth letter, then to do it
we need to type in X square brackets
then C-1 and 5 because C-1 and
5 is just the values 1 and 5 and this
over here tells R that we
want to extract the first in the fifth
value from this vector.
Alright great, so if you want to extract
just one value, if you want extract just
the first value, then we would do a
small thing, we would type in X square
brackets 1 and we're pretty comfortable
with that already.
Now the interesting thing is that what
we are actually doing is we're actually
subsetting the vector X right? So
originally we had a vector of five
values then we have a vector of two
values and finally we have a vector of
just one value and we know that this is
a vector because we've talked about that
in R even a single variable is stored
as a vector.
Okay so every time you subset a vector,
you get a vector.
Great, but now let's look at a similar
concept with matrices because you can
also subset matrices. Let's say we look
at the games matrix that we've been
using so far and these are the games
that the players have played. Now let's
say we want to look at just a subset of
this matrix. Let's say we want to look at
the first three players or the top
player, top paid players in the NBA Kobe
Bryant, Joe Johnson and Lebron James and
we want to look at their stats or the
number of the games they've played only for
the past five years so it felt intense
2014.
How would we write that? Well it would be
very similar to what we've been doing
with the vector, we would type in games
and then we put in square brackets and
then for rows, so there's our comma, for
rows we would say 1:3 and for columns we would
say 6:10. So if we run that, we get
the first three rows and the 6th to 10th
columns. Exactly, what we wanted and this
time it looks like the subset of a
matrix is also matrix. Great!  Now let's
try another example, let's say we want to
compare the top paid player in this
list and the lowest paid player in this
list,
Kobe Bryant and Dwyane Wade. So how would
we do that and we want to compare them
across all the years the number of games
are played. Well how the way to do that
is to say games and then in square
brackets we would say C-1 and 10 right? So
we want just the first and the 10th rows
and then for columns we just leave a
blank and we've also talked about that
that if you want just a certain row,
then you just type in the row number,
comma blank in the square brackets and
that's exactly what we're doing, we just
selecting two rows here. We run that, we
get the first and the 10th row and once
again we get a matrix and one more
example like that would be if we want to
select, let's say 2008-2009, we just want to
analyze those two years and for all the
players, then we would say games in
square brackets we would type in blank comma
C and this time instead of counting out
every single column we would just type in
the names of these columns because
that's another thing we talked about we
you know that we can use names in named
objects and in this case it would be
like that, if we run that we get a matrix
again. All of the rows and just the two
columns that we wanted.
Ok so so far so good, looks like every
time we subset a matrix we get a matrix,
however it's not always the case. So
let's look at another example, let's say
we want to extract games and we just
want to extract the first row, just Kobe
Bryant, we say one comma blank and we
run that, we get something similar
something that looks like a matrix but
not a not quite so if we compare it to
this matrix here you can see that this
matrix has row names, this matrix
doesn't. Why is that? And is this a matrix
in the first place?
Well actually it isn't and we can prove
that if we simply run that IS matrix
function and we take this our new object
and we put it in these matrix function
we check we get false.
Why is that? Well because it's actually a
vector, if we check vector this vector we
get true interesting.
Ok let's have a look at another example
before we explain that.
Let's say we want games and we just want
one value, let's say we want Kobe
Bryant so the first row and 2009
to the fifth column would go games
one and five and we run that and so we
got the one value but it's not a matrix
for sure, it's a vector again.
So what is happening here? Why are we
getting vectors instead of matrices in
these two cases?
Well what's going on is actually the
square brackets have this specific
quality to the them which a lot of R
users might call the flaw but in
reality is just how the language was
designed. So what what is going on will
R is trying to guess what you want. So in
all these instances obviously you want
to matrix because you're getting a
two-dimensional object but here and here
your object is no longer two-dimensional,
so R things well maybe what you were
after was actually a vector and it
returns you a vector so in this case it's
a
named vector, it's got the elements a
name. In this case, you just get a vector
of one value 73 and why does R do that?
Well because let's remember that R is
not just a programming language.
It's a language for statisticians and
mathematicians and there's always going
to be this trade-off between programming
and following strict rules and
procedures and fast agile analysis of
data. So in this case R is guessing
that in most cases when you would want
to extract a one-dimensional object
from a matrix, you would want a vector,
you wouldn't want to matrix. So that's
why it's doing that.
How do we fix that? Well to get the
default behavior of the square brackets
and by the way the default behavior of
the square brackets and probably a
default is not the best word. The best
word here would be to get consistent
behavior from the square brackets
there's another parameter that you can
specify. So in order to get that
parameter you need to add another comma
so this is your rows then you've got
comma the columns and then there's a
parameter which is called drop and drop
by default it's set to true so what it
does is you can see here is delete the
dimensions of an aray which have only
one level. It drops unnecessary
dimensions so by default it's set to
true let's set it to false, if I run this
now, you will see that now I have a
matrix instead of just a vector like I
had here and what's going on is that R
is no longer dropping this dimension so
wroo..
R would dropping dimension where
there's it's only one. In this case, Kobe
Bryant is the only row and R would just
drop that dimension and turn this vector
into a matrix into a vector. So here I
can do the same thing, if I say drop
equals false, I run that then I get to
the consistent behavior from the square
brackets and I get a matrix. So if you
type and drop equals false then the
square brackets will always return the
same class of element or object as you
had originally in this case we had a
matrix so we're getting back a matrix.
Ok so that is how subsetting works and
it's important to know about these
things.
Just remember that whenever you're using the
square brackets, R will try to
guess what you want, if you
don't want R to guest then don't forget
about this. Let's call it a secret
argument that you can pass the square
brackets called drop and if you set
false, then you will get the same class of
object as we had originally. Hope that's
useful and I'm sure that one day this
knowledge will come in handy and now
let's move on to the next tutorial. I
look forward to seeing you there until
then, happy coding!