Hello and welcome back to the course on R
programming. I hope you had a chance to
play around with Q plot and maybe even
you attempted the challenge for this
section and what we're going to do today
is we're going to build that visualization
that we're after and now we know so much
about Q plot already and it's such a
simple tool it won't take long at all. So
let's dive straight into it. Going to
copy this comment here to create a new
section of code visualizing what we need
very elaborate name for a section.
Alright let's try it, let's start doing
it. Q plot data equals that's right
we're going to pass the data to Q plot.
Now we can freely operate with the
columns in our data and we'll say what do we
want to visualize. We want to visualize internet
users so we'll put them on the
x-axis and we want the birth rate we'll
put it on the y-axis so we'll go internet
users comma y equals birth dot
rate. Run that, viola! Simple as that one
line three components and we've got our
visualization ready. Let's go take that
to our manager.
Well of course where data scientists we
can just take it like that is it's gotta
is going to tell stories going to look
good right? So let's let's work on that.
What we're going to do? We're going to
copy this and we're going to add the
size and we're going to make them a bit
bigger. Now the size we're not mapping the
size, mapping is when we're assigning as
we discussed in previous tutorial
mapping is when we're assigning a
parameter so in this case size we would
assign it to a variable in this case we
just want to increase the size for all
these points. We are going to say size
equals I and four and that's why the I
is there because we're assigning the
size increase to every point so let's
run that, there we go. The size has increased,
good. Now what we're going to do next
we're going to let's add a color. Let's let's
color all these points to start off with
let's see how we can do that.
Let's add the color here color equals, we
already know that we need the I again
because we want the same color for all
of them and what we're going to say I
let's say red, make some space here and
run that, run that. There we go, so all the
points are red. Okay that's great now
what we want is remember that the
challenge actually asked us to
categorize the scatter plot by the
income groups of the country's so how
would we do that now. So we'll take this,
and instead of I red, we're going to use
income group. Now we won't need the I
anymore because we are mapping this
variable to the visualization. We want the
different income groups to have different
colors and maybe will increase the size
here bit because we started small. So if I
run this and i run this now
much better right? Isn't that much better?
We can see that we've got income groups.
We've got red, green, blue and purple and
we can see how they are located here so
that is already a great start and we can
now even analyze this chart. We can even
derive some insights. We can see that so
let's recall on the horizontal axis
we've got internet users right so how
many what percentage of the population
has access to the insurance from zero to
hundred and on the vertical axis we have
the birth rate. So how many children are
born for per year for a thousand people
of this population? So if you take a thousand
people, how many children for that
thousand will be born in every year and
this is the data for 2012,
so what you can see here is that the
high income group are all kind of
located here meaning that a lot of the
plant population a huge percentage over
fifty percent and in most in many cases
over seventy-five percent have access to
the internet but the birth rate is quite
low
it's somewhere between 5 and 20 or 25
then you've got the upper middle-income
the purple ones they're a bit back so
they don't have
these countries not that many not much
of the population has access to the
internet, a percentage somewhere between
for most cases between 25 and 75 for
some cases under 25 and then the
birthrate is a bit higher then the lower
middle-income, the birthrate is even
higher and access to internet is even
lower. It's more in most cases under
fifty percent of the population have
access to internet and finally the
low-income, so more very high birth rate
in at times four times as higher or five
times as high as in the high income
category but at the same time the
internet axis is very low so less than
twenty-five percent. How interesting is
that right? So as you transition from a
low-income countries to high-income
countries your internet usage increases the
percentage of people using internet
and your birth rate falls. It almost
seems like there's a correlation between
the two right? So when people don't have
introduces of course not and
correlation doesn't imply causation
right so it's a of course not we're
not proving here that there's a
correlation but it almost seems that
when people have like a lot of internet
they don't have time for children, when
people have no internet and all they're
doing is making more children so it's
just a funny observation like it but
otherwise this chart is telling a
beautiful story and this is exactly what
we are after. So congratulations, we have
solved the challenge. I hope you enjoyed
this tutorial and I hope that you're
truly proud of what you are able to
achieve using data frames and
learning about them in such a short
period of time and I look forward to
seeing in the next tutorial where we
will continue our journey into the world
of data frames and until then happy
coding.