Hello.
Welcome to this module about the integration testing.
After having introduced and discussed unit testing and individual tested
all components of the flights management application,
it is time now to analyze their combined behavior.
This is the topic of this module.
Let's dive into it.
This module will focus on showing what integrations testing means,
how to make the step from unit testing to integration testing,
and which frameworks are suitable for integration testing.
First, we'll define and motivate the integration testing.
We'll take a look at the types of integration testing and at
the approaches of integration testing.
We'll add new features to the flights management application by revealing
integration problems and by building integration tests.
Finally, we introduce the Arquillian testing framework,
and we'll move the integration test to Arquillian.
So what is integration testing?
Integration testing is a level of software testing where
individual units are combined and tested as a group.
Wherefore, in order to check the interaction between integrated units,
the fact that you need to work fine in isolation does not
necessarily mean that they also work fine together.
Integration testing is performed to expose effects in
interfaces and in interactions between components.
As integration testing types will mention,
black box testing, also known as behavioral testing,
this is a software testing method in which the internal structure
design or implementation of the item being testing is not known
to the person performing the test.
This method is named so because the software program in the
eyes of the person performing the test is like a black box
inside which one cannot see.
White box testing, also known as open box testing,
code-based testing,
or structural testing is a software testing method in which the
internal structure or design or implementation of the item being
tested is known to the person performing the tests.
This one chooses inputs to exercise path through the code
and determines the appropriate outputs.
Programming know-how and the implementation knowledge is essential.
White box testing is testing beyond the user interface.
This method is named so because the software program in
the eyes of the tester is like a white or transparent box
inside which one clearly sees.
Grey box testing is a software testing method which is a combination of
black box testing method and white box testing method.
In black box testing,
the internal structure of the item being tested is unknown
to the person performing the testing, and in white box testing,
the internal structure is known.
In grey box testing, the internal structure is partially known.
This involves having access to internal data structures and
algorithms for purposes of designing the test cases,
but testing at the user or black box level.
Grey box testing is named so because the software program in
the eyes of the tester is like a semi-transparent box inside
which one can partially see.
Our work will be of type grey box testing.
The codes for our units are known,
which means white box testing method for designing test cases.
Actual tests are conducted using the expose interfaces,
which is black box testing method.
As approaches for integration testing, we'll mention here.
Big Bang is an approach to integration testing where all or most of the
units are combined together and tested at one go.
This approach is taken when the testing team
receives the entire software at once.
So what is the difference between big bang
integration testing and system testing.
Integration testing is concerned only with the interactions between the
units while system testing addresses the entire system.
Bottom-up is an approach to integration testing where bottom level units are
tested first and upper level units step by step after that.
This approach is taken when bottom-up development approach is followed.
Top-down is an approach to integration testing where
top-level units are tested first and lower-level units are
tested step by step after that.
This approach is taken when top-down development approach is followed.
Hybrid is an approach to integration testing which is a
combination of top-down and bottom-up approaches and it is the one that we are going to use in our work.