We'll move now to the practical demonstration.
We'll start with the flights management application having no tests at all.
We understand its business logic and will present the classes that compose it.
Let's have a look at the initial application as it looks like.
It is composed of two classes, Passenger and Flight.
A passenger is described by an identifier, a name, and a country code.
The identifier kept inside the company is following the same
format as the SSN in the United States.
We have a constructor with all the three parameters,
getters, and setters,
plus ToString and the method simulating the recording of
a passenger to the company system.
A flight is described by a flight number,
the number of places, the number of passengers,
its origin and destination, and the flying state.
The constructor is receiving only the flightNumber and
the number of places initializing the passengers with 0
and the flying state as false.
Plus ToString and meta simulating the sell of a ticket,
the takeOff, and the landing.
In order to better understand the business logic,
we'll use the API of our two classes through this newly introduced main class.
We create the passenger and the record into the
system and we follow the behavior.
We create the flight, set its origin and destination,
sell a ticket for it, make it takeoff and land,
and we follow the behavior.
I think that the simple class's structure and the business
logic have been now clearly exposed.
We'll make the step to the first level of our pyramid by
introducing the unit test making our classes working in
isolation and verifying their functionality.
This is the topic of the next module. See you there.