Our demonstration will focus on introducing Cucumber into our project.
We show how to install and configure Cucumber in order to be used into the
flights management application from the IntelliJ ID.
We'll then write our first acceptance tests based on
the already existing functionality.
It is time now to effectively start using Cucumber in our
project in order to automate the tests.
We'll show how to introduce it through Maven and make it
work integration with IntelliJ and JUnit5.
Let's focus now on the installation and configuration.
In order to start working with Cucumber,
there are additional dependencies that are needed at
the level of the Maven pom.xml.
These ones are Cucumber-Java and Cucumber-JUnit.
We'll ask IntelliJ to import the changes.
We'll create a features folder where all our features will reside.
They are to be found in the test resources features folder.
We'll create our first feature here and we'll call it bonus_policy.feature.
We'll follow the Gherkin syntax,
and we'll introduce this feature named Bonus Policy together with
a short description of what it intends to do.
Then we follow the same Gherkin syntax and write the first scenario.
We'll name this scenario Passenger bonus policy according to the business needs.
Given we have three flights, these are the three flights that we know about.
When the passengers travel according to the recorded data,
then the bonus points are awarding according to the policy.
We see the keywords feature scenario given, when, then that are highlighted.
If we right-click on this feature file,
we see that we have the possibility to run it directly.
This is possible only if the appropriate plugins are activated.
In order to do this, we go to File, Settings,
Plugins, and we see here that Cucumber for Java and Gherkin are checked.
So we have run the feature.
The console shows a few important messages.
Our steps are still undefined.
We have one undefined scenario with three undefined steps.
We are provided the Java methods _____ that can implement the missing steps.
We'll ask IntelliJ to create the step definitions directly into some Java file.
By pressing Alt+Enter into the file,
IntelliJ has provided us this manual and it is helping us creating this file.
We have added the first step definition.
From the feature file, we can choose to Create all steps definition.
Of course, we'll direct them into the already existing file.
Now we have a skeleton of the scenario that may follow the given,
when, then steps.
In order to run our Cucumber test, we'll need a special class.
Now, if we run this Cucumber test,
we see that it is able to identify the features and try to run them.
Let's have a closer look at the content of Cucumber test.
It is the entry point for running the Cucumber test in JUnit.
It must be empty.
Step definitions should be in separate classes as this class has the RunWith
Cucumber.class annotation executing it as any JUnit test class will run all
features found on the classpaths in the same package.
The name of the class could be anything.
We have just chosen CucumberTest.
We see that we have provided some pretty generic steps,
given we have three flights,
when the passengers travel according to the recorded data,
then the bonus points are awarded according to the policy.
It is our first acceptance test.
We are discovering the Cucumber features and we may presume that
the business analysts are not so experienced at the beginning to
provide more than these generic steps,
but based on our previous experience and our previously defined tests,
we are able to translate them into code.
We'll no longer use Arquillian because of its current
limitations by report to JUnit5,
but we'll be able to manage the objects ourselves.
So we have as private variables, these three flights and the distancesManager.
Given we have 3 flights and we initialize here flight1,
flight2, and flight3 just the way we have done it into the previous tests.
When the passengers travel according to the recorded data,
we initialize here the distancesManager,
we browse the passengers from each flight,
and we add the distances to the distancesManager.
Then we are calculating the given points.
Then the bonus points are awarded according to the policy.
The code for this method will simply check that the expected
values are equal to the calculated ones.
We are practically mapping the previously existing
tests on an acceptance test structure.
If we run the CucumberTest again,
we may see that it is green and that we are following the already defined steps.
Which test of this kind to keep the ones that are running the container with
Arquillian or the acceptance test that we have just shown.
The answer depends on which your target is.
The previous version of JUnit version 4 had the good integration
with Arquillian so one could write tests was JUnit,
Arquillian, and Cucumber.
We hope to have soon the integration between Arquillian and JUnit5,
and until then,
we'll not mind to keep both tests into our demonstration despite some overlapping.