Our next demonstration will put everything head to head to
check the functionality of the entire system.
On the consumer side, we'll replace the provider double with the real one,
which is now fully available and, of course,
we'll test the functionality against this real provider service.
As usual, at the end,
we'll also check the code coverage to see if everything has been tested.
So from the side of the provider,
we have now received the full implementation of the DistancesManager class.
Instead of annotating the distancesManager object with spy,
we'll have to inject it.
If we go here to the pom.xml, as we no longer need the Mockito dependency,
we'll remove it and we'll tell to IntelliJ to import the changes.
As we are going to use the real passengersSet for each flight and populate
the passenger distances map based on their information,
we'll introduce this getPassengersSet method.
Moving back to the test, we'll remove everything related to mocking objects.
We'll also have to remove this passengersDistancesMap that
was previously mocking some behavior, and into testFlightsDistances,
this initially mocked behavior.
Now coming back to the testFlightsDistances test,
how do we populate the distancesManager passengersDistancesMap?
It is populated here inside addDistance.
So into the testFlightsDistances,
we'll browse all passengers from all three flights and we'll add the distances
that each one has covered into the distancesManager map.
We'll also need to add distancesManager.class to the
ShrinkWrap archive so that the DistancesManager class will
be able to be injected into the test.
Let's run the test and it is green.
In order to understand where we have arrived,
we'll run the whole suite with code coverage and the code coverage is 100%.
We have checked that we have a fully functional system.
This module has focused on introducing system testing
and demonstrating it for our project.
We have explained the motivation for the system testing,
we have explained what a consumer-driven contract is,
and we have shown system testing on the flights management application by
having mocked the provider behavior to test the consumer against this one
and by gradually replacing the mock provider with the real one and making
sure that everything works fine.
We are now prepared for the next step, acceptance testing,
where we'll evaluate the system compliance with the business
requirements and assess whether it is acceptable for delivery. See you in the next module.