We'll now go further to the additional business logic that is required.
We'll work both at the level of the passenger and of the Flight class.
For the passengers,
we would like to change the identifier format for non-US passengers.
For flights would like to better manage their statuses to
reflect more than is flying or is not flying.
The company has decided to separate the formats of
identifiers for US and non-US passengers.
The real SSN exists only for USA.
We may use an internal similar identifier for non-US passengers and
be sure that the country code will be different,
but better to avoid any possibility of overlapping.
So we may assign the not use interval between 900 and 999 for the first
3 digits of the identifiers of non-US passengers.
We write this new test and we create this non-US passenger with some identifiers
starting with 900 and we extend this test invalid SSN test.
We must make sure that identifier starting with 900 are
still not allowed for US citizens.
We run the test and they are failing as the
business logic is not yet implemented.
We are introducing this non-US identifier regex.
The SSN for the US passengers remains the same and we are having
the identifier allowing first digits between 900 and 999 for
non-US passengers with regular construction of the pattern
depending on the country code.
We run the tests and they are green.
So we have successfully implemented this new business logic.
We would like to measure the code coverage again.
We run mvn test from the command prompt.
Into the index.html file,
we'll be able to take a look at the code coverage at the level of the package,
at the level of the classes,
and at the level of individual constructors and methods.
We see that there are still a few things not yet covered.
We change this testing valid country code to use a non-US passenger
identifier and we'll try to measure the code coverage again.
We run mvn test from the command prompt.
We go back to index.html, open it into a browser,
and we see that the code coverage is now 100%.
The company would like to better manage the status of a flight.
Just saying flying may not be enough as the flight is not
flying before taking off and after landing.
So we introduced this new takenOff and landed statuses and they
are initialized as false into the constructor.
The setOrigin method will check now the takenOff flag instead of flying.
We are also introducing some getters on the newly added fields.
We are changing the testChangeOrigin and testLand tests so that they
reflect the new takenOff and landed conditions.
Let's run the tests again.
The tests are failing as the business logic is not yet implemented.
Let's add this business logic into the Flight class,
into the methods, takeoff and landed.
We run the test again and the tests are green.
We would like to measure the code coverage again and
run mvn test from the command prompt.
Into the index.html file,
we'll be able to take a look at the code coverage and now it is 100%.
And one more thing to be added to the business logic,
once landed, a flight cannot change its destination any longer.
We write this testChangeDestination test.
We have a flight from London to Bucharest,
it takes off and it lands, and once landed,
we try to change its destination.
We should expect an exception as this thing is not permitted.
We run the tests and they are failing as the
business logic is not yet implemented.
We have to do this into the setDestination method.
If a flight has landed and we try to change its destination,
an exception must be thrown.
We run the tests again and they are green.
We have successfully implemented this business logic.
We would like to measure the code coverage again and we
run mvn test from the command prompt.
Into the index.html file,
we'll be able to take a look at the code coverage and it is 100%.
This module has started by reviewing the unit testing
benefits included here writing safer code,
finding bugs early, quickly isolating the incorrect code,
introducing new functionality without affecting the existing one,
documenting the application.
We have discussed the code coverage as a metric of the quality of tests.
Then we have started to move the application to unit testing with JUnit5.
Included here, passengers, identifiers, and country code restrictions,
flights numbers restrictions, bad input values,
boundary conditions as when we have tried to sell one
more ticket than the available places.
We have added new features that were unit tested.
We have separated the identifier pattern for US and non-US
passengers and we have provided better management of the flights to
follow here the taken off and landing statuses.
Overall, we have followed the TTD approach by writing first the test,
then the code that fixes the test.
We must be satisfied by our unit testing work.
We have enabled to fix a lot of missing things and to add and validate new
functionality having as a result 100% code coverage.
The next level of the pyramid, the integration testing is waiting for us, see you in the next module.