If we inspect the current architecture of our web MVC
version of the Crypto Portfolio application,
it's effectively one big monolith,
while our React client interacts with two microservices.
In this module, let's fix and modernize the architecture.
We'll break up the MVC monolith to also use the microservices and
add another hop by adding a pricing service,
which the portfolio service will use to source current crypto prices.
This is common in many systems.
You might have a mixture of clients,
public like mobile and single-page applications that are running
on the user's browser or on their machine.
And we see applications server-side.
So to prevent duplication of code, they will often interact with microservices.
However, currently it is a bit messy.
The clients have to be aware of where all the services are,
and that can be tricky for public clients,
like mobile apps, in case you need to change the location.
Also,
configuring cross-domain resource sharing in each service for
single-page applications is also not ideal.
Additionally, the clients might be lightweight,
like mobile,
and don't need the same large payloads returned back from the services.
There might also be customizations required between each different client.
Hence,
you might have some sort of API gateway to route requests or use a
backend for frontend pattern for public clients,
effectively a service that sits between the client and the other services
and routes and consolidates the requests for the client.
Generally,
that service is owned and maintained by the frontend development teams.
From a security perspective,
you now have more endpoints to secure and more hops to cater for.
Effectively, a lot of the hops are now service-to-service with no user involved.
Some are on behalf of the user and others are not. Next, let's look at security solutions for these challenges.