Because we are using Spring Boot in conjunction with Spring Security,
configuration is straightforward.
We add the spring-boot-starter dependency and,
as our application is the client, the spring-security-oauth2-client dependency.
Next, in the application's configuration file,
application.yml, security, oauth2, client,
registration, facebook as the application ID,
and we add the client-id and secret.
One final step.
In the SecurityConfiguration class that extends the
WebSecurityConfigurationAdapter, we need to add the OAuth2 builder method.
For our demo application,
this class already exists as we are using Spring Security in
the application already with form login.
Now if we refresh the page, we get a bland default page with a Facebook link,
which we can select to initiate the OAuth2 flow with Facebook.
Easy.
Now to add Google, we need to add one other dependency,
spring-security-oauth2-jose.
This is for JWT support as Google uses OpenID Connect.
So the ID token will be a JWT.
For signing and encryption, JWT uses a collection of specifications.
JSON Web Algorithms defines the list of algorithms for
digitally signing or encryption.
JSON Web Key defines how a cryptographic key or sets of keys are represented.
Now this collection is known as JavaScript, object signing, and encryption.
Now for some reason it's pronounced as jose rather than jose.
Spring will use this library to verify the JWTs.
Now the reason for these standards is that it makes life a lot simpler.
If you are using a particular algorithm to sign your token and you
describe it with the JSON Web Algorithms specification,
then anybody reading that will know exactly what algorithm that is.
Then if you specify the signature in the JSON Web Signature format,
anyone can then read and verify that token or if you're
encrypting if you used JSON Web Algorithms.
And then if you provided the public keys that you used
to sign in the JSON Web Key format,
anybody can then verify your JWT automatically.
So there basically is a group of standards that can
allow anybody to verify your JWTs.
Next, we add the client-id and secret for Google.
That's it.
Easy peasy.
We can now login with Google.
By default,
Spring Boot allows us to also configure Okta GitHub in a similar
way by just configuring the client-id and secret.
Pretty neat, right?
All that by adding just a bit of config.
If you're like me, you're probably wondering what's going on under the covers?
How is this configured?
What decisions were made?
You will learn this in the remainder of this module as it's important to
know as no two security requirements are the same,
and you'll probably need to configure and customize the framework.
In our demo application,
Spring no longer defaults to our original form login page.
We will want to change this back to our original login page and
add Facebook and Google sign-in links to it.
Also, we have a bit of a hybrid implementation with form and OAuth2 login.
We need a way to automatically register OAuth2 users,
record their username and email, and set up and maintain their portfolio state.
Let's do this next. But first, let's see what Spring Boot did under the covers.