OAuth2 is an open standard used to protect a resource
known as the protected resource.
To understand OAuth, you need to understand the actors.
Let's use a railway analogy to help explain this.
A passenger wants to ride a train from Lewisham
station to London Bridge station.
In OAuth, the passenger would be known as the client,
the entity that wants to access the protected resource.
The train trip is the protected resource.
Now the train trip is protected by the train station.
In order for the passenger to get on the train,
they need to get through the gates.
In OAuth, the train station would be known as the resource server,
an entity capable of authorizing access to a protected resource.
In order to get through the gates, the passenger needs a valid ticket.
In OAuth, that would be known as the token.
It can be a by value where the details are visible
on the ticket or by reference,
like an eticket where the details of the trip are stored on the
server and need to be looked up to validate.
In order to get a valid ticket, the passenger needs to use a ticket machine.
The ticket machine in OAuth is known as the authorization server,
the entity that can issue the tokens.
However, before it can issue the ticket,
it needs to check with the train company on the price and
if they authorize access to the trip.
The train company is the resource owner,
an entity capable of authorizing access to a protected resource.
Now understanding these actors is key.
And OAuth2 has a number of flows that orchestrate the interactions
of these actors that cater to various scenarios.
The most popular and secure is the authorization code grant. Let's go through it with an example.