After a user successfully logs in via OAuth for the first time,
we need to register them with the site and create a portfolio.
To do this, we can use an AuthenticationSuccess handler.
Simply create a class the implements the
AuthenticationSuccessHandler and overrides the onSuccess method,
giving us access to the request, response,
and authentication objects.
Next, in our configuration adapter,
we plug in the handler via the oauth2Login method.
Now our class will be called each time the user successfully logs in via OAuth.
We need to check if the user already has a portfolio.
Now in the current version of the application,
users are uniquely identified by the username they
provided when registering with the site.
Hence, we need a unique identifier to use as the username.
For this,
we can use the value returned by the getName method on the authentication
object and look up if there is a portfolio for that user.
What is returned by this method depends on how the user was authenticated.
If they were authenticated via the form login, then it will be the username.
If by OpenID Connect, it will be the claim subject.
And for non-OpenID providers, it can vary depending on the custom implementation.
In the case of Facebook and GitHub, it's the claim ID.
This can be a bit confusing at first.
Basically,
the authentication class implements the Java
authentication and authorization service,
Principal interface, and overrides the getName method.
In the AbstractAuthenticationToken class,
you can see this class returns a value depending on
what type the principle object is. To better understand this, let's take a step back.