We have an application secured with OAuth2 and OpenID Connect.
Our users' personal data and credentials are now safely
stored away from our application's code,
and none of our application services handle any passwords.
So at best, if a hacker was able to extract any portfolio data from our services,
it would most likely be useless.
The only identifying property they would have is the username.
Now we could use a GUID identifier to make it even more anonymous.
Now in any modern application, there are multiple layers of security.
There's authentication, identifying and validating the subject and their claims.
And then there's authorization,
once authenticated what the subject can and can't do.
If we go back to our train station analogy,
if you have a valid train ticket,
then you're authorized to ride the train as a passenger.
But you're not authorized to drive the train.
That's for a qualified train driver.
Next,
we will focus on providing more finer-grained
authorization using scopes and authorities. But first, let's have some fun and poke some holes in our application's security.