Currently, OAuth2 support is scattered between a number of projects in Spring.
If you look at the Spring OAuth2 feature matrix,
there are four Spring projects with OAuth2 support,
Spring Boot OAuth2, Spring Cloud Security,
Spring 1, Spring Security OAuth 2, and Spring Security 5.
You've probably also heard of Spring Social.
This made things very confusing as to which one to use,
and it depended on your requirements.
Hence, the Spring team have decided to unify JWT Jose,
OAuth2, OpenID Connect support under Spring Security proper as of Spring 5,
which actually makes a lot of sense.
Effectively, it's rewrite.
Now currently, there still isn't full- feature parity.
If you go through the matrix, you can see the gaps.
But the plan is to unify all the projects under one.
So if your feature is supported by Spring Security 5 and above,
then use it as the other projects are in maintenance mode until
the features are migrated to Spring Security.
Okay, great.
Now that's the theory out of the way.
Let's get started into implementing OAuth2 and OpenID Connect
in our demo application in the next section.
If you have used Spring before to add a login page to your
application and thought it was easy,
you will be very pleased to know it's even easier to implement
OAuth and OpenID Connect with Spring Security. The Spring team have done a great job.