The OAuth2UserService calls the userinfo endpoint to retrieve the
user attributes and return the OAuth2User object.
We want the OidcUserService to return a custom OAuth2User object that
implements our crypto-authenticated principal interface.
To do this,
we can create a decorator to wrap the OAuth2 user and implement our interface.
Next,
we need a custom implementation of the
OAuth2UserService to return our new OAuth2 user.
We could implement the OAuth2UserService interface.
But in this case, we will extend the OidcUserService and return our custom user.
All we have to do now is to plug it into the userinfo endpoint in our
configuration class using the OidcUserService builder method.
That's it.
Spring will now plug it into the OpenID Connect authentication provider.
You could also do the same for a non- openIDConnect user service. We can now clean up our authentication success handler.