Okay, let's put on our hacker hoodie and head over to a dark, dingy basement.
If you look at the application's architecture,
the portfolio service uses the client credentials grant to request a new token
from the authorization server to access the pricing service.
Now we don't have access to the client's secret,
so we can't get the token using the client credentials grant.
And if we access the service without a token, as expected, we get a 401.
But in our React application,
it gets an access token directly from the
authorization server using the implicit flow.
So a hacker can register a portfolio,
and if they inspect the network communication,
you can see the access token received back from the authorization server.
If they include this token in their request to the pricing service,
they now get a response.
Effectively, all the pricing service is doing is checking if the token is valid,
if it's signed by the authorization server.
So any token issued by our own Keycloak is valid.
Next, our support service uses a username parameter.
Hence,
I can use the same token and just substitute anyone's
username to get their support queries or even brute force
the values with a valid query ID.
Often users can include sensitive information about
their account in support queries.
So a hacker would definitely be interested in browsing these.
If the hacker gets a valid ID, they can even post a support query.
Now with this security vulnerability,
you could even post back impersonating an admin,
asking the user what their password is. Now in the remainder of this section, let's plug the security holes in.