By default, the resource server will validate the signature,
expiry, and if you provided an issuer URI,
it will also check if the issuer matches.
In our demo application, if you recall,
the portfolio service requests a new access token using the client
credentials grant to access the pricing service.
Now the development team of the pricing service
released some code that logged this token.
If we were able to get access to these logs and try to use
the token against the portfolio service,
we'd get an error back.
However, let's look more closely at this error.
It's not an authorization error like a 401 Access Denied.
It's an application error.
The request actually got past Spring Security.
The reason it failed was that the token doesn't have the user state,
like the username, and the application actually requires that.
However, we got through security.
We could try other endpoints.
In fact,
the support service has some endpoints that allow the
username to be passed in the query.
Now the token, as per the Spring Security resource server,
has a valid signature, is not expired,
and because all our tokens are issued by the same issuer/realm in Keycloak,
the issuer attribute on the JWT also matches.
So as far as Spring Security's concerned, the request is authorized.
Now this is a classic vulnerability.
I've seen many of these time and time again when
reviewing security implementations, particularly in distributed systems.
It's often services, like the pricing service,
that get neglected as developers think what's the worst that could happen?
It only provides pricing.
However, they can become backdoors into the system,
especially when tokens are being passed around.
I've even seen many cases where unsecured services were
receiving tokens in the header from clients because the
RestTemplate or the WebClient was configured to,
by default,
include the access token on all outbound requests and some new
feature required a call to an unsecured service.
The developer just wired in the WebClient or
RestTemplate without realizing that, by default,
it was also including the access token,
hence why it's always preferred to include the token manually on
all requests rather than doing things by default.
Additionally, the exception handling is very poor in this service.
It should return a generic error HTTP code and not a stack
trace as this gives clues to the hacker.
Now one way to prevent the pricing token being used against the portfolio or
support service is to validate the audience claim on the JWT.
Only tokens intended for the pricing and support
service should be accepted by them. We will look at how to do this validation next.