If we look at the error in the console,
it says the response from the pre-flight OPTIONS request was
missing the Access- Control-Allow-Origins header.
In the Network tab, we can see it received a 401 Access Denied.
Basically, because we enabled Spring Security,
all our endpoints are now secure and blocked for non-authenticated users.
So when the OPTIONS request hit the server, Spring Security simply blocked it.
To allow pre-flight requests through,
we need to configure a SecurityConfig class,
simply a class that extends the
WebSecurityConfigurationAdapter and override the configure method.
Then with the builder,
we add the CORS filter and configure all other requests must be
authenticated and that we want a resource server with JWT enabled.
Okay,
Spring Security will now know how to handle
cross-origin and pre-flight requests.
However,
we still have to instruct Spring what requests we want to enable for CORS.
In our controller,
we can do this at the method level using the CrossOrigin annotation.
If we restart and try again, you can see the portfolio positions are displayed.
If we look at the response from our resource server,
Spring now included the Access-Control-Allow-Origin *.
Basically, the * means it allows cross- domain requests from any origin.
Now a lot of the time developers think great, that solved the error.
But that's a bad way of thinking about CORS.
It's not an error.
It's another layer of defense to protect your users from malicious scripts.
Hence, it's better to add our exact domain.
Now the header also includes our domain,
and the browser will ensure the origin matches.
Otherwise, it will reject it.
Additionally, you can configure it to specify what headers we support,
what content type we support, and add multiple domains.
So this gives you a lot of flexibility.
Now all the other requests in the controller,
like the POST, DELETE, are still blocked.
We could add the annotation to each of the methods,
or we could add it to the controller.
Spring will then set the headers for all the below method types.
You can also customize this annotation and specify what method you want,
whether it's GET or PUT, but not DELETE,
etc.
Let's now check out the headers.
This time let's add a position.
You can see the browser sent a pre-flight OPTIONS
request to the resource server,
and Spring returned that POST is allowed and additionally that
the authorization header is also allowed as our React app will
be sending the token that way. The browser then made the actual POST request and received the response.