To set up the client we created in Keycloak,
in the configuration file,
we change the Crypto Portfolio client with the new settings.
Add the client-secret.
We can get that from the Keycloak admin console under
the Credentials tab for that client.
For scope, add openid as we will now be connecting via OpenID,
and it has to be the first scope.
Now if we go over to the Keycloak admin console under Client Scopes tab,
you can see, by default,
this client will always have the following scopes
when generating the access token.
But optionally, we can request the following.
Now profile and email are default, and that's basically all we need for now.
Next is the redirect-url.
This needs to match the one we preregistered in Keycloak.
Since the provider is now Keycloak, if we click the realm in the admin console,
we will see a link to the OpenID Connect discovery document,
which has everything we need to know about the provider or the endpoints,
etc.
Now we can provide all the configuration needed separately,
like the JW keyset URI, the token URI, the userinfo URI.
All these we can copy from the discovery document.
But since we are using OpenID Connect, it'll provide us the issuer URI,
and Spring will get everything it needs from the discovery document.
We only provide the realm URI.
Spring will know where to find the discovery document because the
well-known openid-configuration URI is part of the standard.
Now in the Keycloak admin,
we can also add Google and Facebook as identity providers.
Just copy and paste the client-id and secret and
remove all that code to handle these.
Now our client just cares about dealing with one provider, Keycloak.
If we start our application, we can log in as Joe or via Google.
This login page no longer serves a purpose.
The application could just simply kick off the authorization
process with the authorization server automatically.
Now if you look at the index.html page, copy the authorize URI.
Then in our configuration adapter for the client, set it as the login URI.
Now when authentication is required,
Spring will initiate the authentication flow with Keycloak automatically.
Now Keycloak allows you to customize and style your login pages.
So you can style it to your application's look and feel,
and your users won't even know the difference.
Now one final note.
Keycloak also has adapters for Spring to make integration simpler.
It has a Spring Boot startup project.
But personally, I prefer to go with OpenID Connect. That way I'm not tied to Keycloak and can change whenever I want.