[Autogenerated] Well, hi there.
You've made it to the next module in the course.
Thanks for sticking with me.
I'm Amber is real JSON In the last module,
we got a good look at how to fetch and prepare your data.
We cleaned, we analyzed, we transformed, visualized and feature engineered.
The next step is feeding that data to an algorithm to train and then
we'll evaluate how we did in this module will tackle the next two
steps of the machine learning process.
To train the model,
we first need to talk about the algorithms to use and when to use them.
After training the model, we need to see how accurate it was.
And we'll tweak things until it's just right.
And we do that through hyper parameter tuning.
As always,
we'll go through all of these steps conceptually and then see
them in action in a demo in Sage Maker studio.
Let's dive right into the training part in the machine learning process.
We're moving right along to train a model.
We need an algorithm and let me pause just right there To make this point,
you'll sometimes hear people using the word algorithm and model interchangeably.
But that's not totally right going back to this diagram we've seen a few times.
We, of course, start with our training data and then the algorithm.
The code is going to run on that data and try to identify patterns.
The output of all of that is called the model, so the model is really the rules.
The numbers that data structures required to make
predictions is far as algorithms go.
There are a lot of them.
I've listed just a few here.
If you go out to the sage maker Developer guide,
you'll see the section for algorithms here.
Choose an algorithm.
There are built in algorithms in sage maker.
You'll notice there are quite a few to choose from Here.
You can also use machine learning frameworks and use
your own algorithms or models.
You definitely won't need to know every detail of everything here for the exam.
But I would recommend going through these built in algorithms and
understanding what they do at a high level and how they work.
These algorithm you choose is going to depend on the
type of problem you're trying to solve.
Going back to this diagram from earlier.
They're gonna be different algorithms for supervised
learning and unsupervised learning.
You saw that full list a minute ago in the Developer Guide for our purposes.
I'm just going to hit on these five built in sage maker
algorithms that are fairly common for a variety of machine
learning problems on the supervised learning side,
let's start with linear learner.
Linear learner is used for classification and regression problems as an
example for a classifications problem for a given value X,
what is why or based on past shopping habits?
Will this customer buy this product?
And over on the left here,
you'll see that we have some values for X and y and the algorithms going
to try to figure out what why is when X equals three or try to figure
out a formula like this one here for a regression problems something
like this for a given X Predict why,
like the example we saw earlier in the course about predicting
rent for a three bedroom vacation rental.
In both of these cases,
these algorithm is trying to fit the data to a line and is
trying to minimize the error or minimize the distance
between the data points on the line.
One way it could do that is using what's called stochastic radiant descent or S.
G.
D.
Grady in dissent is used frequently a machine learning.
So let me at least give you an intuition for it.
You'll hear this thing called a loss function,
or sometimes called a cost function,
which is basically how good your predictions are.
In other words,
how far away are your predicted values from the actual values and
you want to minimize thedc ost or the errors.
So for this cost function, the idea is to find the optimal point,
which is going to be the lowest point on the curve.
An ingredient descent algorithm is going to do just that.
It will descend this Grady int iterating until it finds the lowest point,
the point where you've minimized the errors in your predictions
to tie that to something in the real world.
If you're a hiker, you'll understand the concept.
Here you're on top of a mountain,
a storm moves in and you need to get to the bottom of the mountain.
A SAP.
So you're going to descend, you're gonna find the Grady into,
or the slope that'll get you down the fastest.
This is the idea behind radiant descent.
Next up,
we have the Xcode boost algorithm and this is the one that
we're gonna be using in our upcoming demo.
This is also used for classification and regression problems.
And this is an implementation of Grady int boosted trees.
It's designed for speed and performance and is very popular today,
kind of a multipurpose type of algorithm.
Essentially,
this tries to make predictions by attempting to correct
the mistakes of the models before it.
You're going to start with a training dataset,
some positive points and some negative points.
The first classifier is going to say Okay,
all these things here with a green background are positive
and everything on the blue background.
It's negative, but obviously that's not quite right.
These three plus is here are incorrectly identified.
So those three points are going to be boosted or given more
wait and passed on to the second classifier.
This one says okay,
things on the blue background or negative and things on
the green background are positive again,
we got it wrong in a few cases,
so those are going to get boosted and we continue to the next classifier.
We have a couple of more incorrect points,
but we're eventually going to correct all the mistakes and come
up with something that's correct in the end.
So that's the idea behind the algorithm.
The next algorithm is also used for classification and regression problems,
and this is the K nearest neighbors algorithm or K N n.
This makes predictions based on the K points closest to the sample point.
For example, in this diagram, the sample point is the great question mark.
If K equals to this algorithm, will search for the two closest neighbors,
and these are orange dots.
If we increase Kate equal five, though,
it's gonna look at the five closest neighbors to that point,
in which case that makes us a blue dot Can N is commonly used for concept,
search, image classification and recommendation systems.
So that does it for the common supervised learning
algorithms now onto supervised over on the right.
Starting with K means this one is used for clustering problems
where it groups data based on similarity.
The K here is a number of groups.
It'll place things into,
and you have to supply the attributes that indicates similarity.
Let's walk through an example to give you some intuition on this one.
Let's say you've been tasked with organizing a pile of books.
You have three bookshelves or groups, so RK here equals three.
We're going to say that they should be grouped by genre.
So that's these similarity attribute,
as opposed to grouping by size or number of pages or something else.
So we're going to take our first book and place it on the shelf.
Turns out that book is nonfiction, so that's going to be the name of the shelf.
Note that we didn't name the shelf first,
but we got the name based on the genre of the first book that we placed on it.
We'll take the next book, Place it on the second shelf.
This one is fiction, so that's sitting with that shelf,
and the third book will be biography.
So we have our three or K groups.
Then we'll take the rest of the books and place them into
the group where they belong by genre.
Earlier in the course,
we saw this slide that helped us cluster our customers into different segments.
Well,
this is the algorithm that does that work K means the next and final algorithm
we're going to talk about is principal component analysis,
or PCA.
This is used on unsupervised learning problems to
solve the curse of dimensionality.
That's a phrase you'll sometimes hear to mean that
you just have to many features, and it's hard to know what's important.
So this algorithm will identify important relationships in
the data and quantifies the importance so that you know
what to keep and what to drop.
In short,
you're going from something with lots and lots of features and
whittling it down to only the most important.
All right, so we've walked through some common algorithms,
and now we want to move on to training so we could get a model.
But wait, there is a very important step here,
and that's to split your data into training,
validation and test sets.
The reason for doing this is because if you passed in
100% of your data and trained on that,
you have no data left to test the model and see if
it's actually accurate on new data.
Now here I'm using a split of 70 2010,
but you'll sometimes see 80 10 10 or 70 15 15.
But regardless, you need a set of data to train the model on.
Initially, that's our 70%.
The validation set comes into play Azure doing hyper parameter
tuning and trying to optimize the model.
And then that third set the test set is to test the
final model that you decided to go with.
Okay, so we've clean, prepared and split the data.
We know what algorithm to use now we can create the training job.
To do that in sage Maker,
there's three steps you need to specify the girls for the S3 bucket,
where your training data lives,
as well as the S3 bucket to store output or artifacts that
are created during the training process.
Next, specify the algorithm you want to use and the compute or E C.
Two instances to use for the training.
And finally, you need to specify the path to the training code in E.
C.
R.
Or Elastic container Registry.
You can do all of this through the sage maker console,
and it kind of walks you through what you need to do.
But you can also do it through code and a Jupyter notebook,
which is what we're going to be doing in a demo. For now, let's take a look at evaluating our model