[Autogenerated] greetings.
I remember Israel Son and welcome to this next module in
the course about machine learning on AWS.
In the last module we looked at how to take a business problem
and frame it as a machine learning problem.
So at this point,
we should be able to start doing some actual machine learning bits.
And that's the focus of this module getting started with our data.
We'll walk through the machine learning process,
starting with an overview of the seven phases and then
really focusing on fetching data,
including the various AWS services that you'll be using.
We'll also talk about how to clean the data,
things like handling missing values, dealing with formatting and scaling issues.
And then, to prepare the data,
we'll get into what's called data visualizations and feature engineering.
We'll go through all of these steps conceptually and then also see
them in action with demos and sage maker studio.
The machine learning process will be following in this course
is one that you'll find out on the developer Guide for Amazon
Sage maker scrolling Down here, you'll see the different phases.
You will see slightly different wording out there with
other process models for example, rather than cleaning data,
it will be called sanitizing data or analyze instead of evaluate.
But this is the terminology will be using in this course,
and this is definitely an iterative process.
Machine learning isn't a once and done.
You repeat this entire process Azure building and testing your solution.
And even within the process, there are points of iteration.
For instance, you'll train your model and evaluate it,
but then you might need to start back over with some new data.
Just keep that in mind. Now let's dig into the first phase of fetching data.