[Autogenerated] Hello there.
And welcome to this next module.
I'm Amber is Wilson.
Thanks for sticking with me in the last module we talked
about When it makes sense to use machine learning and when
it doesn't in this module, we're going to go to the next step,
taking those opportunities,
categorizing them and then getting them into a form
that a computer could work with.
We'll cover the types of machine learning problems and
then work through how to define the problem in a format
that we can eventually feed into.
The algorithm will cover some core concepts and then apply
them using some real world scenarios.
Remembering back to our company Globomantics they
have a problem with customer churn.
How exactly do you think machine learning could help solve that problem?
In this example,
we're feeding in customer data things like the type of
service plan there on how Maney service calls.
They've made that type of thing.
We train the model on that data so we know what a
customer flight risk looks like.
And then, for new data,
we should be able to predict the likelihood that
that customer will leave or turn.
Now let's talk more about this piece in the middle. The algorithm