[Autogenerated] hi there, and welcome to this next module.
I'm still Amber Israel sent,
and thanks for sticking with me over the last few modules,
we've gone through the process of fetching and preparing data training and
evaluating the model and then deploying and monitoring it.
To do this.
We've been using various capabilities of sage maker,
but there's a lot more to the overall a i M l ecosystem in Amazon Web Services.
Like all of this,
we've seen a few of the things in the middle there under ML services,
things like notebooks, algorithms, training,
some optimization deployment and hosting.
But let's look at the rest of the stack.
Generally speaking,
it goes from higher level and abstracted at the top of the diagram,
where you really don't want to deal with the details
of building and training the model.
Then in the middle with sage maker, there's a little bit more control,
but sage maker still doing a lot of the heavy lifting and then the bottom
layer where your more comfortable working at the framework level and having
more control over the underlying infrastructure. Let's take a little bit deeper on the top level AI services