[Autogenerated] okay,
we've talked about how to fetch your data from various places.
Now let's talk about how to get it ready to use.
I'm going to lump these next two faces together,
cleaning and preparing because there's some overlap and
also iteration that happens here.
In a nutshell.
Though data is messy with just this little dataset, we have several problems.
The column headings, for instance, aren't consistent.
One uses underscores, and one doesn't in the first name.
We have punctuation not necessarily wrong as these are legitimate names,
but we need to make sure we can handle that.
In the state and country columns, we have inconsistent naming some abbreviations,
some blanks, some Knowles and some dashes.
Similar problem for the Zip code column,
where we have some blanks and zip codes that aren't the same length for age.
We have different decimal formats and any n or not a number
and likely a typo with the age of 450.
Or actually,
maybe that ages in months rather than years for gender here again
were inconsistent in our naming and abbreviations,
and we have blank values and for salary.
We have formatting issues, different currencies and missing values,
and it's not shown here.
But it's also common to have duplicate records or rows.
So we need to get these sorts of things cleaned up
before the data will be useful.
First, let's tackle missing data.
There's a few ways to handle this.
First, you could remove the rows or columns that have the missing data.
This is generally only a good idea, though.
If the missing data is a very small percentage of the overall dataset.
Otherwise,
you could be losing some of the richness and predictive power of the data.
You could also fill in the missing values, taking a few different approaches.
You could look at the data that is filled in and
then take the mean or median value,
and use that to fill in the missing values you could fill in.
The missing data was zeros or Knowles, and finally,
you could use imputation, which basically means your best guess.
This could be a best guess for manually looking at and knowing the data.
Or you could actually run the data through a machine
learning model to predict the value,
kind of like doing ML on the data as a way to prepare it for doing ML.
This option is typically going to give you better results
and has become a more popular approach.
Next, you'll need to handle outliers.
While dataset SSHD definitely do contain valid outliers,
they could also be a sign of typos or mistakes in the data.
And they can see cue the overall dataset.
If this happens, it becomes harder to get accurate predictions.
Generally speaking, you want to remove outliers,
but be cautious with this, because again,
you might be losing some of the richness of the data.
When in doubt,
you want to check with somebody who's an expert on that particular dataset,
so they can tell you how important or common the outliers are handling format.
This includes things like spacing, casing,
punctuation, decimal points, special characters,
currencies and abbreviations.
There's really no hard and fast rules here other than
you need to get things consistent, pick whatever the convention is and stick with it