[Autogenerated] in this course, I'm going to answer those questions.
If you're taking this course to prepare for the AWS
Machine Learning Specialty exam, you're definitely in the right place.
But even if you're not specifically interested in the exam,
this is still a great place to start your journey on
AWS machine Learning for the exam.
Let's take a quick look around the certification home page out on Amazon site.
If you scroll through here,
you'll see a little bit more about what's measured the recommended knowledge
and experience and some tips on how to prepare for your exam.
Over on the right, you'll see things like format,
the delivery method, the time and so forth.
It's growing up.
You'll see there's some sample questions available
for download and the exam guide.
Let me click on the exam guide in here.
You'll get some additional details about the exam again.
Recommended knowledge the format.
But I want to call your attention to the second page here,
where we get into the different domains covered on the exam.
You'll see there's four of them,
and these are the different areas that you'll need
to understand in order to pass.
And the reason I call out the domains here is because on Pluralsight we
have a learning path that addresses each of those.
The name of the learning path is AWS certified machine learning specialty.
And this course that you're watching right now is the first course in that path.
Now, this course isn't aligned to a specific exam domain,
but it will give you a broad overview of machine learning on AWS,
the machine learning process and different AWS
services you should be familiar with.
So it kind of touches on all four domains at a very high level.
But to dig into the details of the four domains,
you want to check out these other courses in the path.
These go into a lot more depth than I can do here.
And I'd highly recommend taking those as you prepare for your exam.
And finally the last course in the path will get into
more of the mechanics of the exam.
Some tips and tricks, study strategies and so forth.
So that's an overview of the entire path this course specifically is
organized like this course introduction where we are now.
Next up,
I'll walk you through how to identify opportunities for
machine Learning XML isn't always the answer,
so I'll give you some guidelines for when it makes sense.
After that,
we'll get into the core concepts of machine learning and
how you can take your business problems and define them as
machine learning problems.
We'll talk about things like supervised learning,
unsupervised learning classifications,
regression inputs and outputs and a lot more.
From there, we'll dive into the machine learning process,
starting with fetching and preparing your data,
getting it from various data sources, cleaning it up,
doing what's called feature engineering and getting it ready to train the model.
Then we'll actually train the model using the data and evaluate how it's doing.
From there, we deploy and monitor in this module.
We'll talk about some architectural best practices and things like logging.
Then we'll get into more details about the AWS machine learning stack.
We actually touch on some of the services,
like sage maker a lot throughout the course,
but this module will pull it all together and cover the AI layer,
these AML layer and the underlying infrastructure.
Finally,
it will wrap things up and talk about what you can do next to
continue your learning and studying for the exam.
I've built this primarily for developers,
data scientists and data engineers looking to get
started with machine learning in AWS.
If you're in another role,
maybe a product manager or business leader just generally
wanting to understand what this is all about,
you should still be able to follow along in terms
of what you should already know.
You should be familiar with the basics of AWS.
So as I'm talking about services like I Am or E C two or S3,
you should know what those are.
The demos in this course will be using Python.
You should at least be able to read Python code and understand what it's doing.
But the code itself will be provided.
So if writing python from scratch isn't your thing, you should still be okay.
And then finally, we'll be using Jupyter notebooks in the demos,
so you should be familiar with how those work I
mentioned demos a few seconds ago.
I would strongly encourage you to follow along with those
as it's really the best way to learn.
To do that.
You'll need a couple things.
First you need an AWS account and and I am admin user,
as you should know, is a general rule.
You don't want to be logging in and doing things Azure root account,
so make sure you're in I am admin Instead,
I'm assuming you have this set up, but if not,
you could get started at a w s dot amazon dot com,
and then you'll also need Amazon's sage maker studio.
Sage Maker Studio is Amazon's integrated development environment,
or IDE for machine learning.
Released.
To the end of 2019.
I'll walk you through how to set that up in just a minute.
If you're already familiar with sage Maker,
you can actually do all of the demos in Sage Maker.
Not studio.
But you'll find things are quite a bit easier in studio,
so I encourage you to use that. If you're going to follow along now, let me show you how to get that set up