[Autogenerated] Okay,
Now that we've walked through how to train and evaluate your model,
let's go do that in Sage Maker studio.
Just a reminder.
If you shut down your notebook kernel on instance,
after the last demo, you'll need to start it back up and run the code.
Up to this point,
I'm about halfway down in the notebook just below the
scatter matrix that we did last time.
And right down here in this paragraph, we are determining which algorithm to use.
So let's pick up there.
This example uses these Xcode boost algorithm,
which we talked about a little bit earlier in the module.
This is a good general purpose algorithm that handles nonlinear
relationships like we have if we go back to the developer guide
and look at the documentation for this algorithm on the top level
page for the algorithm.
If you scroll down to input and output,
you'll see the is takes in data in CSV or lib S V M format.
We have CSV, so that'll work great.
So back to our notebook,
there's actually one more step here that we need to do to convert
our categorical features into numeric features.
We did some of that last time.
But let's run this one block of code here to finish that
work apps and then scrolling down.
This next block of code is splitting the data into training data,
validation data and test data like we talked about.
So we'll run this.
And then the final thing we need to do before we can
train is to get our data into S3.
So I'll run this block of code, which is doing that.
And now we can move down to the training section.
You recall from the slides that there's a few things we have
to specify when we create the training job.
The first thing we're doing here is getting the location of the container
in the elastic container registry to run Xcode boost.
So I'll run this next block of code.
You might get a warning here about there being a more up to date version,
but for what we're doing, that's fine.
We can move on next 22.2 the CSV files that we just uploaded to S3.
These two lines of code here are doing that for us,
one for training data and one for validation data.
Next up, we scroll down here.
Here, you'll see a little bit more information about some key hyper parameters,
but let me scroll down to the code section here.
Some set up work here on top with estimator.
This is where we're specifying the instance.
We want to train on how many and where the output
should do and then our hyper parameters.
There's obviously a lot more than what we see here for
anything that you don't specify.
Sage maker will use the default values, and you'll also notice the objective.
Metric, we're specifying, is binary logistic?
This tells the algorithm a kind of problem or trying to solve.
And remember, ours is binary.
We're trying to solve customer churn, true or false.
And then the fit function is the thing that actually
creates and runs these training job, using both our training and validation data.
So let's run this block of code.
Now.
Sage maker is going out and launching the instance we specified handling
everything on the back end that we need to run the job.
This will likely take a few minutes, so I'll pause the video and come back.
Okay,
you'll see the training job has completed now Let's scroll
up and see exactly what happened here.
Go up to where we started.
You'll see starting the training job, launching the M L instances,
preparing them for training, downloading the input data,
getting that out of S3 and then downloading the training
image from the container registry.
And then when it starts running, you'll see a bunch of output.
Here in blue, I'll call out just a couple of things here,
you'll see Train are and validation error.
These are evaluation metrics that are computed by the
algorithm as its training is calculating.
This on both the training data and the validation data,
and it's trying to minimize that error you'll see appear at the top
for train are we have 0.45 for validation error,
0.73 and then as we go, those errors get a little bit smaller.
You'll see at the bottom 0.39 and 0.67 And that continues until
we get down to the very bottom scrolling here.
And the last values that were calculated are 0.24 and 0.66 In other words,
training are is about 2% and validation are is about 6%.
If you do one minus that are accuracy on.
The training is about 98% and for validation, about 94%.
So we did a little bit better on the training data than the validation data.
If this was wildly different,
say you had a 98% accuracy on training but 70% accuracy on validation.
That could definitely be a signal that the model has over fitted.
And we need to make some modifications that we talked about earlier.
Like getting more data or removing features or
stopping early source could be better.
But for the level of evaluation we're doing,
we're going to say we're happy with that and move on and
incidently all of this logging that we see up above.
This is all logged into CloudWatch as well,
so you could go back and see what happened during the training job.
At the end, you'll notice it uploaded the model and completed the training job.
Overall, it took 47 seconds,
and that's how much I'll be billed for this next section here for compile.
This is about sage maker Neo I'm not gonna get too deep into neo in this course.
Just know that neocon optimize your models for target hardware.
This means you can run the same model on multiple platforms,
so I'll run this block of code and let it do its thing.
We're telling it to optimize for the MLM,
for instance, family,
and we're also giving it the output path to Are S3
bucket to store the compiled model.
Now let's go back and do a short summary of the module.
If you don't plan to continue to the next model right away again, I'd recommend you shut down the kernel and instance for this notebook.