[Autogenerated] This was a fairly short module,
but there's a few key things you need to remember for the exam.
At the top level,
AI services go back and review the services we talked
about and understand it a high level, what each does and some typical use cases.
There are several questions on the exam about what these services do
Also know that you can use them in combination.
For example, maybe I use transcribed for speech to text,
and then I use comprehend to make sense of it for email services.
We've covered a lot throughout the course,
but one additional thing to remember is that the marketplace
is used for accessing pre built models, data sets and algorithms,
and then for the bottom tier of frameworks and infrastructure.
Just know that their support for many of the popular frameworks
and interfaces also know that elastic inference can do help lower
the cost of in prints and green grass is used for machine
learning at the edge or on I O.
T devices.
And with that, let's move to our final module,
where all recap the takeaways from the course overall and
then talk about what you could do next to continue your learning and studying for the exam