So way way back, at the beginning of the course, we introduced you to Git and GitHub as a part of the
'I am poor' challenge and that was just to show you how Git works and how you can use GitHub or our repositories
that are hosted on Github in order to download the skeleton project and to follow along with the tutorials.
Now in this module, I want to introduce you formally to how Git works and how you can use it to achieve
various powerful ends.
And I'm going to be talking about and showing you how you can use Git both inside Xcode and on the
command line to do things such as version control, well how to clone repositories, how to fork make pull
requests and merge repositories and a whole bunch of really really exciting things.
So once you're ready let's get started and let's start learning about Git.
So let's talk about version control in its simplest form.
Let's say that I create a new code file and I write a few lines in it.
Now I decide to put it under version control using Git
and let's say that I call this save point as number 1,
now this is my first version. So
later on as I progress I write maybe a few more lines of code.
And at this point I decide to make another save point and I call this my second version.
So further down the line I accidentally screw up my entire code file and it's irreparable and I get
to the point where I would rather burn my entire code file rather than having to try and fix it.
You do get into these situations because very often your code is interlinked and each class depends
on another and sometimes you can screw up in a way where you know all hope is lost and I simply just
want to roll back to the last save point.
I can do that using Git.
I can do that using other tools as well
but the most popular tool and the one that we're going to be talking about is Git.
So you can either compare your current code file so the current mess that you've made against a previous
version so that any of the save points before.
Alternatively you can simply just roll back to a previous version and it doesn't have to be the one
that was immediately previous.
You can go as far back or as far forwards as you like as long as you know which version you want.
So in the next lesson I'm going to show you version control using Git locally on your computer.
I'm going to use the command line to do this.
So I'll see you there.