All right now we're ready for challenge 7.
Now the goal of this challenge is to be able to head over to the path that's localhost:3000
/compose and be able to render a page that has the same styling as the rest of the pages with
our nav bar and our footer
and to have an h1 that says compose as the title of the page. And then we're going to have a text input
here and a button that has the text publish.
So pause the video now and complete this challenge.
Now the hint that I'm going to give you is that in order to achieve this, you'll need to include the
header and footer partials, you'll need an h1, an HTML  input element as well as an HTML button.
So that should be more enough to try to attempt to challenge again.