All right guys. I need this lesson we're going to be using what we learned so far about setting up a new
web site with a server using Node and Express to create a really simple web site that acts as a calculator,
so I can simply enter maybe two numbers, 5 and 6, and I hit calculate, and I get the result back.
Now, in the process of building this, we're going to get to create our very first web application,
and it's not just a web site anymore.
Up till now we've only been making essentially static web sites, right, where our browser will make a
request to the server and the server sends back the CSS, the HTML, the Javascript files.
And if there's any Javascript code that needs to be run, it gets run on the client side,
basically our user’s browser. And that Javascript gets sent to the browser and run when the user loads
up the web site.
Now in this lesson we're going to be making our code run server side.
So when our web site makes a request to our server, it's going to execute the code and only deliver the
outcome back to the user, so the user doesn't get to see any of the code and logic of our calculator.
It's all done on our server.
And once we grasp this concept, then we'll be able to make much faster, more complex web sites that can
do computation before it even renders the web site to be delivered to the user,
and we'll be able to interact with databases, and query, and search, and manipulate our databases, and create
much more interesting web applications.
So this is the core concept that we're going to tackle in the coming lessons of this module.
But first there's a challenge.
So head over to the next lesson and get started.