Hey it's Angela again.
And if you're seeing my video then that means you've completed another module so pat yourself on the
back
if nobody else is going to do it and congratulate yourself on really showing up and getting the work
done.
Now I want to talk a little bit about sort of going beyond your own limitations.
So in terms of my own story when my parents first relocated to the UK I was very young.
I was about 10 years old and at the time they didn't really have the foresight to teach me any English.
So when I first arrived and went to school, I couldn't say anything.
I didn't even know hello like that was the extent of my knowledge.
And it was a real struggle.
And you know there were long periods of time where I thought like you know I'm kind of just done for
now. I'm never going to be good at school because I can't understand what people are saying.
I'm really going to struggle making friends because they don't understand what I'm saying.
But you know at one point I realized well, is this the life I want to live like?
Am I just gonna be some sort of recluse
like for the rest of my life or am I just gonna go and try?
So I ended up just trying to use the few words that I had to talk to people
and surprisingly I made friends even though I really didn't actually understand what they were saying
especially things like British sarcasm and British humor.
And it was they used a lot of air quotes all the time. So you know kids can be cruel but like you are also
more willing to try as a child.
I think for somebody who's maybe a lot older as if I was at my current age going into a completely new
environment and being thrown at a task which I felt like I was severely disadvantaged against, maybe
I wouldn't have the bravery or the the ability to really just say, you know what? I'm going to overcome
this thing you know because I think as we get older it's much easier to blame a lot of things
right?
Like maybe I'm too tall, I'm too short, I'm too thin, I'm too fat, I'm too bad at English, I'm too bad at
Maths. And the number of like things that you can blame on is like limitless.
There are just so many things and everybody has different things that they focus on. But the point is
those things don't really help you especially if you decided that something you can't change like your
gender or your age is the reason why you can't do something then nobody can help you
right?
So even if those things were true like even if life would be easier if you were you know like looked
like Brad Pitt and you you know had like a really rich family or you know you had all the resources.
Like even if that was the case, I'm sure those people have their own things that they focus on.
So don't focus on things that you can't change, even if they are there.
Instead focus on the million other things that you can change.
Maybe you can wake up earlier one hour earlier than everybody else,
maybe you can work that much harder than everybody else,
maybe you will just you know like do more repetitions. And you know at the gym the people who are the
strongest are not the people who showed up with the most muscles
the first time they went to a gym. It's the people who go there every day, it's the people who are dedicated,
who are motivated.
And so I guess what I'm trying to say is that you are the master.
You can determine where your life will go no matter how old you are or how female you are or how male
you are.
It doesn't matter. Just focus on things that you can change and those things alone will make a huge difference.
So, I reckon whatever it is that you decide to do, you can do it. And I'm willing to support you every
step of the way.
And you know if you manage to get to where you are and you're able to overcome a lot of these hurdles
or you know things that stop you, then you'll become a stronger person and you can take on even bigger
challenges and bigger challenges.
You know, the world is your oyster.
So keep going and keep learning.